This is Jocko podcast number
one 26 with Echo Charles and me,
Jocko Willink.
Good evening echo from good evening and
tonight also joining us is Mr. David
Burke. Good evening Dave. Good evening.
On September 27th,
1950 approximately 60 American prisoners
who had been confined in prison were
taken into the prison yard and groups
of 14 with their hands wired together.
These men were forced to sit,
hunched in,
hastily dug ditches and then were shot
by North Korean troops at point blank
range with American m one rifles
using armor piercing ammunition
of the two seriously wounded survivors.
Only one lived to recount
the gruesome details
on of civilians estimated at between
5,000 and 7,000 and as well as soldiers of
the Republic of Korea or also slaughtered
between September 23rd and September
27th,
Sergeant Carrie h y now formally
with the 23rd Infantry Regiment.
Second Division Korea was the sole
survivor of the infamous infamous Tasia on
massacre
and he testified
at a congressional hearing and I'm
going to read some of that transcript.
Here's sergeant,
why now?
Toward the last,
they was in a hurry to leave
Tayshaun to evacuate Tasia on.
So they took approximately the last
three groups pretty close together.
I witnessed the group
right in front of me shot.
Okay.
After they were shot,
we was taken to the ditch and
sat down in the ditch and shot.
And then Senator Potter asks what
happened to you when you were shot?
Yeah,
sergeant. Why? L replies,
I leaned over against the next
man pretending I was done for
okay.
In firing.
They hit my hand.
Yeah.
Senator Potter. How were you
sitting in the ditch? Sergeant.
Why now? They was aiming at my
head. I have a scar on my neck,
one on my collarbone and another in
my hand. They hit me three times.
And you play dead? Yes sir. After
they thought everyone was dead,
they started burying us.
I came pretty close to getting panicky
about that time, but somehow or another,
I figured as long as I had some breadth,
there was hope.
In other words, you were buried
alive. That is right, sir.
I add in that whole group that I was with,
there was not a man that begged for mercy
and there was not a man that cracked
under the ordeal
sergeant.
How long were you buried alive?
That is hard to say, sir.
As I say,
I was shot around five o'clock in the
morning and I stayed in the ditch until
that evening until what time?
It was dark.
I would say approximately eight hours.
Seven or eight hours.
Now that is from a report on Korean War
atrocities written by the subcommittee
on Korean War investigations.
And I want to repeat one line
again from sergeant. Why now?
He says in that whole
group that I was with,
there was not a man that begged for mercy
and there was not a man that cracked
under the ordeal.
So think about that.
Think about the will and the discipline
of those men to be facing certain death
at the hands of the murderous enemy,
but to face death with solve them
silence and show no signs of breaking.
And I've said before that war
brings out the worst in people,
but it also brings out the best
and that is but one of thousands upon
thousands of examples of the dedication of
our military fighting men.
And I'm going to read you another
example from the same bor around the same
time,
but this one is an award citation
and it reads,
the president of the United States of
America takes pleasure in presenting the
silver star to first lieutenant armor,
Thomas Wilford Fife United States army
for Gallantry in action as a member of
company B 72nd tank battalion,
Second Infantry Division in action
against an armed enemy on 19 September,
1950 in the vicinity of young
saying Korea. On that date,
Lieutenant Phife was in command of a
platoon of tanks charged with the support
of infantry elements.
In the defense of young saying perimeter,
the enemy attacked his position
with superior numbers and a fanatic
determination to penetrate through
to the division main supply route.
The enemy attack was successful in routing
the friendly elements and inflicting
casualties to the extent
that the organization and
combat effectiveness of the
positions was completely disrupted.
Realizing the seriousness
of the situation,
Lieutenant Fife disregarded
the heavy enemy,
fire and dismounted from the protective
armor of his tank to reorganize the foot
elements.
After reorganization,
he remained on the ground and successfully
reestablished the positions by
controlling both the foot elements
and his tanks by means of radio
communications.
During this same date,
while engaged in a friendly
attack against the enemy,
lieutenant fife again displayed
gallantry by refusing evacuation.
After being wounded,
the leadership,
loyalty and gallon actions demonstrated
that day by lieutenant fife are in
keeping with the highest
traditions of the military service.
So Lieutenant Phife was under
attack from devastating enemy fire,
but he did not remain in the protection
of his tank. In fact, he did the opposite.
He exited his tank to organize
troops and stop the enemy attack.
He risked his life to lead his men.
Then he would continue to
lead even after wounded. Now,
Korea was not the first war
for Lieutenant Tom Fife,
nor would it be his last lieutenant fife
had actually already fought in World
War II.
He fought in Korea and
he fought in Vietnam.
He also received three Purple Hearts for
each of the three times he was wounded
once in each war and in addition
to the silver star from Korea,
he also received another silver star for
his service in Vietnam and a Legion of
Merit and a distinguished flying cross
and survived all that and served our
great nation for 25 years.
And I will say that it is my absolute
honor to have retired Colonel Thomas Fife
on the podcast today.
Sir,
thank you for coming on.
It's nice to be here.
I think
I listen to that story.
It brought back gears.
Quite frankly,
I'm upset just because
of the memory of that.
It was a horrible experience,
but one that had to get
done and I still remember
getting out of that tank and wondering
why in the hell I was doing it.
But
something had to done.
When you see thousands of people coming
at you and you have nothing but your
weapons
and the guys needed some help.
They just,
they were willing to
I guess, run. I don't know
what that was, what they were,
they needed leadership and that's the
only thing I could think of to get out and
try to be there with them.
And thank God we turned them around
and we were able to stop the enemy.
Okay,
you can't understand what it's like to
be there and having thousands of people
compression at you in the best you can
do is shoot your tank guns and machine
guns. And he just kept coming
and she just kept coming. I mean,
talk about discipline is, those
guys were disciplined too. And uh,
we had to get our guys together
and we did. And it was,
I think I was lucky. I
was damn lucky by the way.
My wounds weren't dead serious.
I got shot in the ass and it closed up.
The wound closed up and so
it stopped bleeding. And
for all practical purposes,
I was as good as new for a while.
So, I mean, it wasn't that
serious a wound. I mean,
I,
I'd hope to be evacuated
to Japan but didn't work.
So, so your million dollar wound turned
out to be like a 50 cent was again,
at least it was, it was, uh, you know,
you, when you, when I got wounded,
I felt the blood rush into my pants
and then it stopped.
So why not keep going so
far as that's concerned?
The wound was debt over it.
And when I finally got to the
Mash Hospital, the doctor said,
that's when we can do for you.
It's going to work.
It's way out or stay there forever.
It eventually worked his way out,
which is how I have
ended up being evacuated
when we were up in North Korea
and, uh, got to a hospital ship,
Navy hospital ship,
and they
took the piece of metal out of my butt.
And
then MacArthur just said,
general MacArthur had said,
we're going to be home
by thinks by Christmas.
So my objective is get off
that hospital ship as fast.
I couldn't get back to my unit.
And
of course the Chinese hit.
Yeah.
And so I was now trying
to get back to my unit
in the army was totally screw it
up. We didn't know where, who was.
So I ended up
to be young Yang Gland in and [inaudible]
the capital of North Korea and the
airfield was totally surrounded by fire.
We were destroying all of our
equipment and whatever else.
We I our plane,
the plane landed and I
had to go find my unit.
Nobody knew where it was. So I got
on the road and started hitchhiking.
Yeah.
That's the guy who came along who happened
to be a classmate of mine who was in
Salem car. He stopped, saw me pick me up,
don't we backed him where he was,
which was core headquarters and they
didn't know where and how am I afraid it
was. So finally he told me
back to the mash hospital,
another mash hospital and
the Mash Hospital knew where
my unit was and they took
me back to my inner in an ambulance.
I wasn't wounded.
Just a way to convey,
get me back to my unit.
I still remember those days.
Terrible experience,
but fun.
It's hard for people to understand that.
Again,
I have that discussion with people
a lot when you're saying, hey,
this was the worst time of my life
and also the best time of my life.
At the same time, let's,
uh, let's, I mean we'll,
let's get into Korea,
but let's talk a little bit about sort
of where you came from, how you grew up.
Um, starting with, uh, I
guess Sioux City, Iowa.
That's right.
Well,
I was
a kid growing up in the middle
of the United States. Uh,
I was reminded on the way over here,
I wish talking
when Pearl Harbor happened,
I was 16 or almost 16 years old.
I was in a movie theater and they
staffed the movie and he announced that
Japanese bombed Pearl Harbor.
I didn't know where Pearl Harbor was.
Now I knew where the
Hawaiian islands where,
but I didn't know Pearl Harbor was
in the Hawaiian islands. You'll,
when you're an Iowa v,
there's no oceans. Nobody,
not nobody.
You don't think about oceans.
And so here we were in this movie
and I was almost 16 as I said,
and I said, Oh hell, the world be
over before I ever get called in.
Well, that turned out to be wrong. So, uh,
as I said,
I was going through high school.
My whole objective,
why was in high school,
it's going to become a chemical
engineer and go to Cornell University.
Why?
Because my best friend's
oldest brother-in-law was,
was a chemical engineer
working in Sumatra.
What may you grown up on? Io Sumatra sound
like a pretty good thing to be doing.
So I asked who I wanted to be a chemical
engineer and I was going to go to
Cornell because he went to Cornell and
that was going to be what I was going to
do. Well, the war happened
and I suddenly became
18 and you get drafted.
It's hard for people to realize today,
every place you go,
people who are in uniform,
when people walking around
in civilian clothes,
the only people who were in civilian
clothes or those who couldn't qualify
because of physical disabilities.
So everybody was in uniform
no matter where you weren't.
So I got drafted
and fortunately
my dad was smart enough to send me off
to Iowa state before I was 18 and I got
two quarters in as an engineer.
So the army has great wisdom,
decided to debate me,
accommodate engineer,
which was a hell of a lot
better than being an infant.
But as far as I was concerned.
So I went to Fort Jackson,
South Carolina.
Now when you're from Sioux
City, Iowa, Columbia,
South Carolina is eons away.
It took us five days on a
damn train to get there.
So we got there in all of us
soldiers get off the train.
And this first sergeant got
us all lined up there and uh,
he's calling role and he
says Fifi and I l five.
And from that moment on, I was Fifi. And
so anyway,
the,
that was in March of 1944 44.
And so we went to basic training.
It learned to be a competent engineer.
And I became a demolition specialists.
Now it's hard for people to realize,
here's a kid who grows up in Sioux city,
Iowa and suddenly is handling explosives.
I had no more idea of doing
that in a man in the moon.
So
in the training,
we were primarily learning to build
bridges and take care of roads.
That was our primary mission.
But we're also,
we're taught to be instrument combat
engineers have a secondary responsibility.
And so we, uh, ended up,
uh,
fortunately going to Europe
when we were in training, we had no idea
which direction we were going to go.
But in retrospect,
I've always felt that we were lucky
to go to Europe rather than to the
southeast. However, uh,
when I got to Europe,
it was colder than hell.
I wasn't so sure that was a really big
decision, but it worked out all right.
But,
uh,
but our primary role was
to go to Europe and become,
uh, take care of the roads and, uh,
all the things that engineers do.
It's a,
you showed up there is where you
write it around the, the battle,
the bolts timeframe. Yes. I mean the bad,
the bulge was as I remember right
around Christmas time of 1944,
44.
Yeah.
And we got to the continent
right at that time.
But I unit went to Luxembourg.
Uh,
it primarily was helping
General Patton's army turn,
make a 90 degree turn and go
north to help stop the Germans.
And so the roads had to
be taken care of and,
and that's what our unit was doing.
So we prime during the,
the actual combat have best Tom.
We were working on roads and
keeping the roads open for the,
uh, Patton's army to get up there. Uh,
our unit
eventually,
uh,
eliminated the Germans,
the last Germans from Luxembourg in
the little town called [inaudible],
which is on the Yarra river right across
from the Sig free border for a secret
line. And, uh,
so the 1250 fifth engineer combat
battalion turned in an infantry outfit for
brief, very time. February 12th, 1945,
we got rid of all the Germans,
glass Germans in its
country of Luxembourg,
combat engineers. We
always, I always have to,
we'll always want to give them their
due because they continue to keep roads
open.
And when,
when when we were fighting in Ramadi
was the combat engineers primarily that
they had the duty of of mine clearance
and it was a brutal and date,
I mean obviously a highly dangerous job
for them to be out there clearing those
minds and keeping those roads open.
That's a, it's a hell of a job.
Well,
as a demolition specialists,
one of my other,
one of my jobs was mine,
Clarence and I was operating
a mine sweeper on this road
down into the valley at
the end and and behind me where the were
two tanks from the calvary unit and the
Germans could see the tanks.
I guess they could see us too,
but they sure the hell was,
she could looking at the tanks and
shooting at the tanks and a lot of their
machine gun fire wood ricocheted off
the tanks and that's how I got hit with
ricochet off the damn tank.
Got into my leg and arm.
But superficially,
I mean all I just go back to age station,
get bandaged up and back into my unit.
It wasn't,
wasn't any a hospitalization at all,
that kind of stuff.
Another 50 cent wound for it.
Exactly. I'd be, I had a lot of those.
So how long were you, so did you stay
over over in Europe until the war ended?
No, I actually, actually in March, uh,
the unit got orders for me to return
to the United States because I had
appointments in the United
States military academy.
And so my very first airplane
ride was from Lee Age,
Belgium to Paris.
And I was,
I remember going into this office in
Paris and I was dressed in my battle gear,
so to speak, and they'd looked
at me and he said, and I had,
it's still over the where I was still
wearing my steel helmet and the, and the,
I can still remember this is sergeant
scene. We've got to take care of this guy.
We got to dress him.
And so they put me in
all brand new clothes.
Two days later, I was on an airplane
flying back to United States.
27 hours later in five stops in route.
We ended up in Washington DC.
So,
and so I ended up my first
time it ever visit to Pentagon.
Here's this
19 year old PFC dressed
in brand new clothes,
walking into the Pentagon.
And I can tell you,
I wasn't sure what the hell I was doing
when I finally got orders to go to
Cornell University,
but for to get re academic,
uh,
get reoriented towards academics.
So wait,
so you had orders to west point,
but they were going to send you to Cornell
for a little while to prepare for it?
Well, no, I had
an appointment to the academy.
Okay.
If you had an appointment as academy,
in fact, this is still true today.
If you're having an
appointment of the academy,
they've take you out of combat and
bring you back some place safe.
And what they brought us back.
There was about 300 of us at Cornell,
all uh,
from different parts of the service,
whether it be army, air force,
back downstairs. It was US army,
air corps, and uh, we were there
for them to get re
acclimated to the academia. Turn
your brain back on. Yeah. Thank you.
And so that was, at this
point, did you know,
did you know you wanted to
stay in the army as a career?
Had you enjoyed your time in
Europe? And he said, you know what,
I think I'm going to do think
them to go the distance or no,
I had no, I had no idea.
It wasn't until after.
Well,
very quickly
my appointment to the academy
was an alternate appointment
and is the principal,
if he qualifies, the alternate doesn't
get to go in. My principal qualified.
So now where they do with
me in the earliest great,
infinite wisdom decided to send
me to officer candidate school.
So they sent me down to Fort Belvoir
to the engineer officer Candy School.
The army knew they're going to need a
lot of second lieutenants over in the
Southeast Asia.
And so anyway,
in the middle of officer candidate
school and warrant Japan ended.
Now what? Well, they stopped
officer caddies based,
slow it down I guess is the right word.
And,
but I continued on in, graduated, uh,
into January of 1945 and here
I wasn't out to set lieutenant.
So you've got your commission.
Yeah, and I had an and I,
and now I also had a principal
appointment to the military academy,
so whether they do it,
so they kept me at Fort
Belvoir training recruits.
And then in July they discharged me from
the army to enter the military academy
as a cadet. And July 1st, 1946
it was somewhere in there
that
I started to like the army.
Got It.
But I knew if I wanted to be an engineer,
I damn well had to get a college
education. Well, we're better to go,
going to placements, supposed to
train you to be an army engineer,
which is this case west point.
So I could,
I went onto west wine and spent
four years there obviously,
and graduated in 1950.
So you got commissioned, they took your
king mission away for four years. He got,
and then they give it back
to you at the end of 40 days.
We only rank I've ever had was in the
army with twice my second lieutenant.
Yes,
that's right.
Eh,
sir.
In West Point at this point is being
run by just all World War II veterans of
I'm sure.
Yes. In fact, a r e m
our tactical officers who were all
lieutenant colonels who had been battalion
commanders of some short in World
War II in Europe or in the air force,
tactical tactical officer of my company.
The first two years was an artilleryman.
And the second two years was, uh,
uh, uh, air force. Well,
it was US Army Air Corps became the
air force, uh, lieutenant colonel.
So it ended,
the superintendent was a Maxwell Taylor
and a common dant was guiding the
Paulding Harkins who was colonel hearkens.
He was a gentle patents,
a hatchet man.
And uh,
and the deputy commandant was a guy.
But John Kay waters who was
a general patent sending law.
So,
uh,
so they were all when
World War II veterans. Yes. And, and
as were you at the time that had to be,
was that fairly unique or was there a lot
of other guys that were prior enlisted
that were coming to west point?
Um,
uh,
my class who started about 1100 of us,
I would guess several hundred
were veterans of some sort.
Uh, Navy Army, army,
air corps. Uh, yes.
I would say about two or 200.
200 to 300.
I don't remember exactly.
Yeah.
Now when you're going through
west point, the war ends, are you,
is his war on the horizon for you or did
you guys have an attitude kind of like,
well,
you know,
we're going to go and be peace time
army officers for the next however many
years?
Or did you see trouble brewing?
No, John, no trouble brewing. I mean,
I don't think anybody really herself
what was going to happen? Korea, uh,
in fact t z,
the only thing that was trouble if he
would was the Berlin airlift happened.
While we were it could it.
And so he saw that kind of thing.
But I guess in maybe in our naivety,
we figured that nobody was going
to pull the plug and really
have the Russians attack or vice versa,
where we're going to do anything. Uh,
see. So when you graduate,
what's your next move?
What was your next move
after you graduated?
Well,
it wasn't my move.
North Korea invaded South Korea and
here generally present Predator prey.
President Truman decided
to send to US troops to Korea.
Now one of the things when you,
when you graduate a
buy order rank,
you're allowed to choose your branch
and then where you want to go.
Well,
my experience was
being in front of that tank and getting
shrapnel, I decided I didn't want
to be out in front of the tank.
I wanted to be in the tank.
So I chose,
I chose not to be an engineer's again.
I chose to go into the armor.
So I chose to go to once again,
uh,
grown up on Iowa state of
Washington was somewhere,
who knows where. So I chose
Fort Lewis, Washington.
There's a place I'd want to go visit.
So that's my first post was to
go to Fort Lewis, Washington.
Did it turned out to
be the 29th, 29th? No,
the 70 shagging tank battalion, which
was part of the Second Infantry Division.
President Truman,
while I was on my honeymoon in Canada,
decided to send a second
division off to Korea.
So in my infinite wisdom,
not knowing just what happening,
well,
I was in Canada and I called home to
wish my mother and Dad Happy 4th of July.
Oh,
G army had shin,
a telegram to my parents' house.
Shane for me,
get my ass for real estate
as soon as possible.
Well,
I'm halfway there when I'm up in Alberta,
Canada.
So we drive off to Fort Lewis.
And so I arrived at Fort
Lewis, uh, middle of July.
Now you got to,
I'm now a tank platoon leader.
Never been in a tank before.
Let me tell you actually an experience.
Most people don't want to have.
I, the only thing I had going, by the way,
many years later,
my platoon sergeant told me,
he said at that time he was my gunner.
He said,
we've fairly,
really fortunate.
We had a guy who had been
in combat in World War Two
not knowing that I didn't know
a damn thing about a tank,
but the good news is the sergeant was
smart enough to teach me how to be
somewhat of a tanker
on the ship on the way over to Korea.
So you had no, you, you showed up.
You were, you get done with your,
or you cut short your honeymoon,
you go straight to Fort Lewis and
then you immediately glowed up.
Yes.
My first tank right west from the port,
not from the motor pool at Fort Lewis to
the port of Olympia to put the tank on
the ship and goodbye.
That was my first tank.
Correct. Yeah. That's the point you made
about, you know, not just that you're,
you're sergeant was smart
enough to teach you,
but equally important is that you are
smart enough to listen and we get all
kinds of young officers and I'm sure you
saw him through the years that they're
not smart enough to listen to the
people that have the experience. And,
and that's a huge lesson learned yet
seems to always need to get learned by,
I wish I've told more people when asked,
what do you do to be successful?
I say listen to your sergeants,
listened to your sergeants,
asks them,
don't be afraid to ask because I'll
tell you their job is to make you
successful.
And unfortunately there are too many
people who don't have egos that can allow
them to do that.
No doubt about it.
They think it's going to make them
look bad when it actually yes,
it actually elevates them in the
eyes of the sergeant. Yeah. And Yup.
So your trip overseas,
you're on the ship and
you show up in Korea.
Yes.
You can't understand
what it's like to be several
miles off shore and begin to smell
what's going to be turned out to beads.
Puerto Busan where you could smell it
before he ever got there and we knew we
were pulling into and hadn't never,
I've never been to that part of the
world and my whole life and we offloaded
ourselves from the troop ship,
waited for our tanks to come on the,
on the other ships and we spent four days
in in Pusan waiting for the equipment
to come and then offloading it and
getting it ready to go into battle.
Then at what point this is,
this is like the battle of [inaudible].
This is the Pusan perimeter and this
is the beginning of it right now.
This is for those of you that don't know,
this is North Korean troops coming down,
100,000 North Korean troops coming down
and have you guys basically squeezed on
to, it's almost a peninsula. It's like
a little not have land that sticks out.
35 miles radius from the
shitty of who Sean was,
the Pusan perimeter.
That was the last character he held.
Everything else was held
by the North Koreans.
It's so when you landed there, that's
the situation they were in. Yes.
And how did you guys, and how did
you and your troops feel about that?
I don't think we were even cognitive.
How serious it was
after we loaded a tanks
onto the rail cars.
She go to the rail,
head of marrying would just,
I don't know,
the 20 miles,
25 miles from Busan where
we offloaded the tanks.
He said where I first
went into combat in Korea.
Eh,
I don't really know that.
We thought how serious it was.
It got you.
I got the impression
several days later when the
division assistant division
commander called all the
hospitals in the singer
NGLs together in a,
in a place and he's dead men.
We live or die here.
And I've thought to myself, what in the
hell did I get myself into here? Yeah.
But that's, that's what
it was. I mean, we would,
I it, you know, in hindsight, yeah.
I have read books about
what happened in Korea
and we really didn't understand that.
I mean we were just
there doing a job and uh,
I don't think we really understood
how perilous the situation was.
And at any point while you were there,
did you understand the
peril of the situation to,
or would you just in your particular
battles day by day trying to hold the line
where you were at?
Didn't it?
Was the communications is kind of not
effective enough to really for you to
understand the bigger picture?
We,
we had no idea what the bigger
picture was. I mean honest to God,
we were just doing our
job and as I said earlier,
watching these waves of
people come across it. Yeah.
Knack.
John River will never ever
go away from my memory.
I mean people were just coming,
coming, coming and all we were doing,
it was shooting,
shooting,
shooting and neighbor
just keep coming and uh,
yeah,
we managed to hold the line
and they didn't penetrate.
So No,
the answer is we didn't
understand this as a situation
as your,
were you holding the line
specifically you guys,
you are holding the line on that river.
Yes.
And so they were going to have to try
and cross that river to get through the
line. When they swimming. Where are they
taking boats with? What were they doing?
They were waiting.
It was, it wasn't that, it wasn't
it, it was pretty wide river,
but it wasn't that deep. So they
were able to wade across, uh,
yeah. And they'd be just
keep coming. I mean,
and then how long,
how long did that particular,
how long were you under intense
waves of attacks like that?
It was like a tone. Was it like
20 days or something of the whole,
the whole thing I think lasted, I
dunno, 20 days or something. That was,
was going to say,
I,
I don't know,
it seemed like forever,
but I think it was probably
over and two or three,
a couple of weeks.
Uh,
my first
involvement,
we've got off the tanks off the flat car
and then we rolled into action and my,
uh, uh, lead tank
right in front of my very eyes exploded.
We'll never forget watching the tank
commander go sailing out into the ditch to
the right and the tank exploding.
We are rounded a curve
and unbeknownst to us,
never to Russian tanks,
man by Koreans
up just draw.
And they fired at this
tank and we had him,
my Virginia was in force,
uh,
Sherman tanks and gas
engines and they fired him.
They fired into the gas tank
is Hillel thing exploded.
And so my first day in Korea combat
one tank destroyed
fire people,
which at that time tank had a crew of
five or all four of them were killed in
the tank to tank commander.
It was back in the United States.
And less than two weeks after we
left over three weeks after we left.
And that was my first
day in combat in Korea.
And uh,
so from then on we got into the,
the perimeter and spent a couple
of weeks there. I don't know.
I don't, I don't remember. Uh,
you read earlier by the citation,
it was September 19th,
which when I was one of the reason, I
know that was September 19th. So if,
because you,
what you read,
I didn't remember what exact
data dates it was. Yeah.
Cause it wasn't too long after that
happened that we had to Inchon landing and
everything broke out and
we were heading north.
So it was a couple of weeks.
I don't know.
When you were from a leadership
perspective dealing with losing guys in
comparison to when you were in World
War II and you weren't necessarily in
command of, but you're seeing people get
wounded, you're seeing people get killed.
What was your mindset? What
was your perspective? Um,
as a leader when guys
were getting wounded,
guys were getting killed and then
you had a bunch of, you know,
you were saying that your sergeant,
you,
they felt they were lucky to have someone
that had been in combat before and
then all of a sudden I know that they
were looking to you saying, okay,
well what do we do now,
boss?
Yeah. Well one thing about, uh,
in a tank,
the grooves are inside the tank and as
with the radio you could direct people to
do this and do that.
Uh,
and so I just told them what they
should be doing and they did it.
I mean, I didn't, uh,
leadership is just telling people
what they should do and they're trained
to do it and they do it. I mean, uh,
I, I learned, actually I learned,
I talked to a grownup on Iowa leadership.
I didn't even know what that was.
I learned what leadership
was all about at West Point.
And that's the major difference.
When I was in World War Two,
I was just taking care of myself.
I wasn't really too concerned
about the other guy,
what was going on.
We were all just doing our job.
That's very different when
you're in a combat situation. Uh,
and you got people
depending on each other.
And we were all dependent upon each other
when we're in a tank platoon and each
of us were trained to do a
job and they did it. I mean,
one of the,
one of the things my petunias
didn't exist prior, I
mean, on paper it existed.
It didn't exist physically.
So what happened when we were activated,
the guard house was emptied out and
we got replacements from Fort Hood,
Texas.
And that was my platoon.
One of the best soldiers in my platoon
was my loader who had spent most of his
army career in the guard house.
But you can't believe what a great
soldier wasn't. Combat. I mean,
cause he knew what he was doing and
he was trained to do it and he did it.
I will never forget those young men.
I mean,
I'm still in
email contact with my former gunner,
who's now retired as a
command sergeant major,
but he still calls me lieutenant
does. He was, he kept my ass on a
trouble, I'll tell you that. Right?
I mean he,
he taught me more about how to be a
platoon leader than anybody will ever
understand.
And
I guess the leadership training I had
at west point combined with what these
young member teaching me allowed
me to become pretty effective.
A leader throughout,
not just my military career,
but my commercial career too. I, I,
I'm a strong believer in that leadership
works not just in the military but in
commercial business.
Yeah.
You talked about leadership inside a tank.
What did you see in and how did you see
what was going on that got you to get
out of that tank and tell you that you
needed to get out of that vehicle and
start driving
and what's going on in the ground?
I wish I knew the answer to that.
I mean it just did it. I made,
I knew something had to be done and
my radio communications with these
guys on the ground wasn't working.
So you've got to, you got to communicate.
And the only way you can communicate
if the radio isn't working,
you've got to get your butt off the,
off the tank down there so you can
talk to these guys because they weren't
trying to talk to me.
I was trying to talk to them and get them
figuring out what the hell they should
be doing.
So I just did it.
I don't know what prompted me to do it.
It's a good question
cause I have no idea. You know, I talk
about that sometimes I talk about, uh,
as a leader, being able to
identify what I would call it.
I just called the void of leadership and
it's very easy to see when you are used
to seeing leadership filling the void.
When you see a void of leadership,
if you're aware to look for it,
it's really easy to see when it's
there and you go, wait a second,
someone needs to step
in here and take charge.
And so you had that instinct of hey,
there's a void of leadership here.
I got to do something and here we go.
That's right.
As much as you said to yourself at one
point I'm going to be inside that tank
and then the damn time you needed
the tank you got out of it.
Well in hindsight he had to do
what you had to do, I will say.
And then when, what, once you
guys held the line and you,
it's funny because I use that
expression a lot just talking about,
you know,
a holding your line with your personal
discipline and holding the line with your,
your subordinates.
And we use it metaphorically.
And it's incredible to see here and talk
to you about actually literally holding
the line
when you guys got done holding the
line and you had defeated that,
that onslaught from, from the North
Koreans. What was the next phase?
Move out and move north.
And we,
the first weeks we moved four or five
miles at the most [inaudible] we moved
hundreds of miles and I remember
going as fast as we could north to marry
up with the guys who invaded it inches.
And we just kept going.
I mean,
I,
I don't remember how many opportunities
we had to really get into combat.
Uh,
after we cleared the Pusan perimeter
until after we got Dorth of sill.
I mean, we, uh, the invading army,
the invasion force, uh,
invaded it pretty well,
cleared all that stuff away.
And so the city of Seoul was open when we,
we went right through it and
we kept going north.
Uh,
the enemy was retreating pretty fast and
we were just going as fast as we could
drive enough to roads
in the, uh, in fact, uh,
our unit got almost the Yellow River,
uh,
which is what about the time
they decided the take the,
take the staff out of my butt.
So I was sent back to the
hospital ship and in the heart
that's when you got shrapnel was when you
were up by the, by the Yalu River? No,
no. That's all that had
already. That's right.
That had happened earlier
and now it's coming back.
The staff was working,
no.
One of the things you got to remember
is this piece of metal is in my,
but now in a tank,
the tank commander sits,
has a little thing,
just cities,
but on while he's riding
around in the turret,
well you don't do that when you have
a piece of metal working his way out.
It is painful to say the least.
And so I couldn't hardly
wait for that to happen,
but they wouldn't let me go back to the
hospital until it got reasonably close
to the surface.
So when it got close to the surface,
they evacuated me and it was in November
of 1950 that they sent me back to the
hospital ship.
And then, then I think you covered
this, but then you got done,
the metal comes out and then you go
back again cause you're trying to,
you're thinking here to get
home by Christmas if you
can get back to your unit.
And I, I got back to the unit eventually,
but I didn't get home by Chrysalis.
In fact, they, uh, by that,
by the time I got back to the unit,
we were the second division.
It had already moved back south,
uh,
almost to the, um, the
Han River. And so I've,
I've found the unit again somewhere
south of somewhat north of the Han River,
but still we were still in North Korea,
but it was the south part of North Korea.
And were you in a situ?
W did you guys get dug in?
Because I know part of
the Korean War was like,
they dug in and it was
almost like trench warfare.
Did you enter that phase or were you
still guys still moving north and south?
Yep,
we do. Uh, as tanks we never dug in.
Now later on,
uh,
hang tin line stabilize pretty much
around the 38th parallel and there's a lot
of
digging in a defensive positions as well.
Uh,
but that was more infantry,
not not the tanks.
So how did you, how did
you end up, what was the,
what was the last phase of
you being over there like and,
and what ended up bringing
you back to the states?
Uh,
well,
the line sort of stabilized around the
38th parallel that we would go forward
and then we come back. We would
go forward, come back, uh,
oftentimes, uh, the,
we would
do patrolling I guess is the right word,
patrolling and forced
a tank company with an f to company
attached ratting on the tanks would blast
forward, uh, to some enemy position, uh,
it into a firefight,
take the ground,
and then we'd move back again.
We were just going back and forth,
uh,
around that so-called, uh, uh,
now turned out to be the 38th parallel.
But it was generally that sector.
Uh,
uh,
oftentimes the infantry would
get into a lot more heavy
firefights and the tanks would,
uh, I spent a lot of time
supporting infantry. Uh,
tax was my tank guns,
machine guns covering their
advancements forward. But uh,
dug in, no, we never, their
tanks for never dug in.
And then how long did that last?
For what, how long did you,
was your unit deployed over there
and wasn't the whole unit that,
that ended up going home?
No, no, at, uh,
at a certain point decided at people who
had been there a year would come home
and we started a rotation and,
uh,
I was one of the first ones
to rotate out of my unit
because I had some decorations and because
I'd been there a year and et Cetera,
I had a lot of points. And so, uh,
I was sent back,
I guess,
uh,
I got back to the United
States Labor Day of 1951,
so I was evacuated.
The word evacuated is probably not the
right word. We just shipped back home.
Yeah.
And then so you get back home, you know
where you are coming home from Korea,
it's obviously you at least experienced
some pretty intense stuff. And you know,
you hear a lot of times,
especially nowadays with guys coming
home from Iraq and Afghanistan with guys
struggling to readapt to,
to life back in America.
And I think it's a little bit different
because when you came home you were
still in the army. And I think that's
the best thing for veterans. You know,
if you're still in,
I think the veterans that have the
hardest time are veterans that get out and
then all of a sudden the Brotherhood
that they are used to is gone.
And the mission that they're
used to is gone. But is that,
is that what you experienced
and you came home and you,
you still had your mission of
moving forward in the army?
Yes.
I mean,
I had no feeling of not being appreciated.
I mean, uh, obviously I,
uh, when I came back, I
came back, uh, uh,
I had a daughter born while I was in
Korea, scaring the hell out of me.
I mean, I, I would have,
I still remember this
four month old child I
held for the first time,
first time I've ever held any buddy
that size scared the hell out of me.
It would be,
I was more scared about death and a
lot of the things to happen to me.
But anyway, I came
back, went to Fort Knox,
uh, when they sent me now they sent me
to school, learn to be a platoon leader.
And so, and then they, uh,
asked me if I wanted to stay there
at Fort Knox and run an officer,
candy company.
And I did.
And so we spent several years running
and Asta Candy Company and then,
uh,
they decided they didn't need it any more
officer candidate school at Fort Knox.
So they closed that down.
And I got selected to be
an aid to a John Waters.
John Waters does with General
Patton's son in law and a
wonderful experience.
Learned a lot
from a real gentleman. Uh, he was, uh, he,
he,
he was a bigger general that time became,
say two stars, but he eventually
retired as a four star general.
And, uh, but he taught me a lot about
being a, being an officer. Uh,
that's much about leadership,
but being an officer and a gentleman,
he was a outstanding
person.
And, uh, I learned from him.
I mean,
you know, when you, when
you're working as an aide,
you get pretty close to
somebody and, uh, uh,
always feel very fortunate that I
was able to be his aid and learn.
I don't know if you know,
he's the one in the movie,
but General Patents and then, uh, uh,
troops into rescue somebody
in a prisoner of war camp.
He was the one who was into prisoner
of war camp and he was wounded very
seriously there. But I mean, and uh,
it was quite a experience working
for him for several years.
That was multiple years, pardon?
Multiple years as an aide.
I vent a two and a half
years has, is eight. So,
and then as he went on to his assignments,
I went onto my assignments and,
uh,
one of the experiences I had,
in 1956,
56,
I was a company commander,
a chain
company, and [inaudible]
Germany said, yeah.
And he at that time was running the
military assistance command in Yugoslavia
and he decided to come up and visit me.
Now here's the major general,
and he's coming to visit this
captain and bomb holder Germany.
And it was,
you can't believe all the
other stuff that went on,
what the hell's he general coming to
see you for it, et Cetera, et cetera.
But anyway, we, we got
through all that. But, uh, he,
he was,
uh,
he didn't come to visit me in Vietnam
when he was Pacific commander, but, uh,
he was, uh, he took care of
watching what I was doing.
So it was,
it was an experience,
wonderful experience and a great
learning experience to be his aid.
Yeah.
I was actually an aid to,
for the admiral that was in charge of
all the seals and it was a very similar
situation for me.
It was a great guy.
And I learned aton about,
about the way the whole big machine work,
which you have no idea when
you're a young Hulu Danny,
you have no idea what's going
on behind the scenes. And,
and I definitely got to
learn a lot about that.
And the same thing you just talked about,
you know,
I had just had a great
relationship with them and, and uh,
he took care of me and my guys on
many occasions, uh, which was great.
And since he was the
admiral at one time we were,
he was a surfer and I was organizing a
trip for us to go to Hawaii and we were
going to see some of the seals
that were stationed out in Hawaii.
And the big thing I had to do is get
organized so that when we got picked up at
the airport,
there were surfboards in the vehicles
ready to take us directly to surfing.
As soon as we showed up the safe no,
people say, what do you want these sexy,
you just get the surf boards ready.
That's what you need to do for the boss.
Um, and then, so you did that, you end up,
you end up, so 56, you're over,
you're a company commander.
And what happens in between then and,
and then, uh, I was,
um,
a unit,
second harmed second armored
division and at that time,
um, and 57, uh,
they had something they were going
to rotate the fourth division,
which Fourth Armored Division,
which I had been at Fort Hood.
They rotate it to Germany in the second
armored division to go to rotate back to
port hood.
However,
I'd only been in country a little over
a year and I wasn't eligible to rotate
back.
So they
uh, uh, in her
decision for those of
us who weren't eligible,
had to be reassigned.
And I was reassigned to be at the
secretary of the general staff.
It Heidelberg,
which is US Army Europe.
So non going from being a company
commander in bomb holder Germany,
which is the end of the line,
all the way to the very
senior army command in Europe.
And I'm working now for a four star
general in his general staff organization.
And I had,
uh,
once again a chance to go from learning,
knowing what's going on down
here to watching what's going on,
very senior leadership. And, uh, it was,
it another opportunity,
uh, for a year and a half.
I had that job and it was just
a great experience learning
if you would the other
extreme of where you'd been.
That was my,
and then
rotated back to the United States
and 59 to become a math professor.
It was point would I spent four years
being a math professor and then went to
the Army Command General Staff
College at Fort Leavenworth.
And then the army decided that
they needed to have people
contracting McNamara's Whiz kids
in.
So
they figured that somebody had been
teaching math, probably could not.
So they sent me the University
of Michigan to get a degree in,
which turned out to be operations
research. But the army sent me to be,
get a degree in automatic data processing,
which they didn't have such a
thing at Michigan. But uh, Eh,
closest thing to it was industrial
engineering operations research.
So I spent two years
there getting a degree.
And then I rather than go back to
the Pentagon for utilization tour,
I volunteered to go to Vietnam.
So I,
and uh,
when you say that they will,
the army knew that they needed
someone to counteract the whiz kids.
And I've talked about the Whiz kids at,
I've covered them somewhat because the,
a lot of the people operational
on the ground said, hey, these,
these statistics that you're coming up
with don't take into account the human
aspect of these kind of,
this conflict in Vietnam.
So was that something that was felt and,
and understood inside the army at
that time? I mean, clearly it was,
yes.
That's the whole idea was to take somebody
who knew something about the army and
give him some education to these kids.
So called kids had,
uh,
and statistical analysis
and all that stuff.
And so to be the other part of the,
of the,
of the board,
and that was to be my utilization tour.
So
there's a great example of that
and it's, it's the battle. The,
I drank valley and um,
Colonel Moore talks about it,
the fact that the,
what the whiz kids basically said,
well one of the things that they said was,
okay,
we can kill 170,
uh,
Vietnamese soldiers for every
one of ours that, that they kill.
So statistically we'll just keep running
that problem over and over again and
we'll end up winning. And I always point
out and which, which everyone points out,
and I'm sure you had pointed out as well
as what they didn't take into account
is the fact that number one,
170 Vietnamese killed to the Vietnamese
was not as big of a deal as we thought
it would be.
And we also didn't take into account that
one American dead is a lot bigger than
the statisticians thought it
would be to us. And that's just a,
it's a huge tragedy to go
into that situation like that.
Well,
in fact,
I many times thought a body count was
the dumbest thing we've ever come up with
is a measure of success in combat.
And I said that I don't know how many
times and I am still convinced that was
the dumbest thing we've
done over the time.
And I was there participating
in it and it was terrible.
Yeah. So let's, let's
go to Vietnam. So you,
you volunteered for Vietnam in 1966 or 65.
66. Okay. And did he, do
they automatically say, okay,
well you're a lieutenant colonel,
that means you're going to,
you're going to take over
a squadron or a battalion.
Oh, shit was the case.
In fact, the fact that
give him the army mark credit and just
do now a nation along with everybody
else.
I was a lieutenant colonel arrived in
country and I was assigned initially to be
the executive officer of the
Combat Operation Center of Mac v,
which is the headquarters
of all in the company.
Operation Center was Westmoreland's,
uh, operation center.
And uh,
it was run by a Marine Brigadier
General Bill Jones by name.
Uh, and uh, it was a great man. I mean,
and I was his exact and uh, and we, uh,
caught, ran the war, so to speak
the word. We as a very loose term
from the coc and uh,
that was, uh, headquarters
right there in Saigon.
And, uh, it was a cushy job.
I mean, that'd be, went to
work on a regular hourly basis.
I used to go in at night once in a while
because President Johnson was going to
talk to some of the action officers
trying to find out what was happening to
these patrols that we were sending out.
That's a serious sign of Micromanagement,
Huh? Well, let me tell you,
it was micromanagement of the first order.
And I sought,
absolutely sought an in happening
more often than I care to remember.
And,
but I had one of the evenings I
met one of my former colleagues,
uh,
armor who was commanding the
first and the fourth Carrea,
the first infantry division.
And he told me he was going
to rotate home in December.
I said, can I get that job?
He said, he take me up.
And he introduced me to General
Depue who was division commander.
And I went up and I passed the test.
He'd have to know
general the Pew. And, uh,
he was a no nonsense
guy. Uh, he, he would,
people thought I was
crazy because general,
the pew was relieving Battalion Commanders
for incompetence, right and left.
And I figured, you know, if
you go up and do your job,
you're going to be okay.
It went up
and Gerald appeal energies interviewed
me and general Hollins worked,
yet it was the assistant division
commander and Hollingsworth in Busia. No,
Kaverman I mean, uh, and he couldn't,
the two of the two of them
passed on me said it was okay.
And so I got reassigned to command
of the first and fourth Camry,
uh,
in December of 1966,
which was, uh, a plum job. That was,
it was not only a plum outfit,
but it general,
the pew used to Calvary Squadron.
Like it should be used many times later.
My successors who are all
not as lucky as I was.
I mean,
I was able to
fight my unit has a unit. I had, uh,
uh,
three ground troops.
One cal,
Amina d troop was a helicopter school.
A troop had 31 helicopters in it and I
had division commander would assign a big
company here, the tank battalion
that was assigned to my unit.
And then since there wasn't
any real enemy aircraft,
he assigned the several of the batteries
of the any aircraft unit to my unit.
So I had, uh, a unit
unparalleled in history because general,
the pew believed the calvary was supposed
to go find the enemy and keep them
there until he's an
infantry could show up.
And we did it more often than not in
one of the stories I tell people.
Aye.
I'm self-styled King of the
Michelin Rubber Plantation,
which is, you know, 70
square miles of trees. And
historically there's little
communities of workers throughout the,
the, this place. And
it became these little towns
became havens for the North Korea,
for the North Coast, north
Vietnamese. And uh, uh,
so we took it upon ourselves to evacuate
everybody out of the little villages to
the perimeter of the plantation and then
took it upon ourselves to destroy the
villages because the north Dorothy enemies
were coming in at night using these
places. In Shelly, our units.
So we were destroying
all these little hamlets.
In fact,
I had an engineer company assigned to
me in one of the contest was between the
captain who was the engineer
company commander in myself.
I'd give her my chopper and he'd be
down on the ground and he was going to
implode these village.
Now if he imploded them all,
he won any of the villages.
Buildings would still be standing.
I won.
Now what did we win a beer
and more often than not I won.
He didn't win.
He didn't lose many.
But we got some in the spring of 1967
ambassador Ellsworth
bunker arrives in Vietnam.
The first unit he wants to visit is mine.
There is everybody is what in the world
of why did he pick this and why does he
come to see you?
Well,
he gets out there and all the,
now he's got a four star general
three star general and then
division commander, all wisdom,
and they were out in the middle of
nowhere. I'm briefing to ambassador.
I get it most so many
savers. He says, colonel,
I got more correspondence of my desk
from the French about what in the hell
you're doing up here destroying their
village and all the people and causing all
this commotion. What are you
doing and why you're doing it.
And I explained to him that why we were
doing it because they disabilities were
being havens for the north and they were
coming in and Shell and are killing our
troops. And I've always
remembered him. See, colonel,
he just keep doing what you're doing
and I'll take care of the French.
And I said, cat machine. I mean,
I still get emotional.
Was that that man,
that gentleman understood
what the hell was going on.
And here we talk about State Department
people not knowing what's going on.
He knew what was going on and he told
me to keep doing what I was doing and I
did it.
But I will always remember
him is I think at the time,
I'm not sure this,
he was either the oldest or next
oldest ambassador we ever had in,
in in the State Department. But he
goes out there trapping around in the,
in the boonies with me.
And it was a rare experience.
But anyway, it was a, it was
one of those days, you know,
when you really think you counted.
Yeah.
And he was, to me, that's leadership too.
You know, he, he was, he knew
what the hell was going on and he,
he was able to tell me to keep doing
what I was supposed to be doing. Yeah.
He was,
he was a great man.
So those operations,
that was that the primary
type of operation that
you'd be doing is going into
areas,
uh,
and basically disrupting
what the enemy was up to.
Basically, we, the mission
was searching, destroy,
and what we did was go find,
try to find the enemy
and then destroy him. Uh,
so in that,
in the Michelin Plantation,
we thought the enemy was not there,
but we spent, uh, there was
something called the iron triangle.
North of Saigon is about
30 miles north of Saigon.
Uh, which of of our
operational area. And, uh,
it was traditionally a haven for the,
the north end or the whoever.
Anyway,
the guys that were shooting at us,
and you never know whether the north
Vietnamese are there are constricted south
Vietnamese, but they all
look the same to me. And uh,
they still do. I, I'm never in Korea.
I couldn't tell the difference
between North Korea and South Korea.
And I still could never
tell the difference.
When you're south Vietnamese
and north Vietnamese, they, it,
it maybe there's a way,
but I never figured it out.
And so we just went in and constantly
we're searching and destroy and if we,
if we find the enemy and strength,
our job was to hold them there until
generally few and the could get his,
uh,
infantry into helicopters and bring
them in and really defeat the enemy.
Uh,
on occasion we got in more of a
firefight and we expected to be,
but we, we generally, uh,
we're pretty good at finding them in.
The tanks would roll right through this
forest and not the trees right down.
And it was,
it was no problem at all of it.
And I was in my helicopter directing you,
you could see in, you tell
the tanks where to go, uh,
in the tanks and Avycaz,
which were primarily what
the unit was all about.
And so we,
that was our job.
Yeah. So often I read about units that
were over there that never, or very,
very seldom would they see the enemy.
They would lose guys to sniper fire.
They'd lose guys to mortar fire,
they'd lose guys to booby traps.
But very seldom would they see the enemy.
And you know,
obviously there's units that
are different than that,
but it sounded like you were able to
find the enemy on a fairly regular basis.
Oh yes. Are they found us? Aye.
Aye. Aye. Aye.
You know,
who finds who is,
is not sure there's an answer to that.
But yes,
we more often that we got
in, we had contact, uh,
uh, I had, uh,
more than I would like
to remit casualties. Uh,
which didn't happen because
they couldn't find the enemy.
I can tell you they could find us,
you know,
and often remember,
uh,
somebody a long time in
my goal in my career.
Tell me something about
reconnaissance by fire. And I,
I remember with a tank you had a lot of
machine guns and you could do a lot of
reconnaissance by fire and in
trouble with Ricardo by fires.
Yeah.
You never know whether
they see you or not.
You just know there's somebody shooting
at you. Well that's good enough.
That's good enough. We don't need any,
no other, he's aiming at you or not.
Uh, when you, uh,
one of the things that also I talk
about and I've read a lot about is the
Vietnam war being very difficult from a
leadership perspective for some leaders
more than others.
But because you had draftees and,
and you had draftees, not just
draftees that got drafted in, okay,
I'm going to go do my duty.
But draftees,
they got drafted that literally did not
believe in what was happening and barely
even believed in America as a country.
How much of that did,
did you see and what do you,
what was your,
what was your leadership approach to those
troops? I saw the zero of that. I mean,
I don't know. I was just absolutely lucky.
I know I'm not that naive. I mean, uh,
I'll tell you the last few guys have been
talking to and reading about this and,
and there's something
that I've noticed a trend.
So have you heard the term millennials
about the new up and coming kids?
I know what millennials, so
people complain about, you know,
especially from a leadership perspective,
people talk to me about, well, you know,
I've got my company and
we've got these new,
these kids checking into millennials.
They're different, they're entitled,
they don't want to work as hard. And
I, I started thinking about my head,
well, basically you've got a workforce
that's a little bit different.
And this is very similar to the
draftees and Vietnam who had a different
attitude.
And what I've found from good
leaders is it didn't matter.
It didn't matter that they had
draft these. As a matter of fact,
a general Ngukurr Yama who I just
talked about when I talked to,
when I asked him about draftees,
he said,
I didn't even know who was a
draftee and who was a lifer.
I couldn't tell the difference. And, and,
uh, Colonel Hackworth wrote in his book,
he wrote, I love the draftees
because they were straight shooters.
They didn't,
we weren't trying to protect their career.
They tell you what they thought,
and you could take their input and
you could do something good with it.
Uh,
I've
said all along,
the soldiers I served with in
three different wars got better.
And they were all draftees.
I mean, I didn't never,
Sarah with an all volunteer outfit.
They were all,
no matter where I was,
they were draftees.
And they all did their job.
I mean,
I've never had anybody tell me,
uh,
wasn't their job. It wasn't, this
wasn't what they wanted to do. It was,
they just did it.
And I don't know this
leadership or I don't just,
it just the way it was. And, uh,
they were all proud to be in our outfit.
I mean
now I'm sure other people later on.
I mean,
I've heard of people later on in,
uh,
in Vietnam having little
problems with drugs and all that.
We didn't have any of
that. Now, fortunately,
I left in 1967,
so I'm not sure how
things got worse perhaps.
But, uh, I think, uh,
drugs are an issue period.
Uh,
but I don't know. I didn't have
any of that kind of a problem.
And as I said earlier, I'm
not naive. Uh, I believe in,
uh,
knowing exactly what's going on.
What you find out is walk
around and talk to people.
You don't sit in your tent
or in your helicopter.
You got to go down and talk to the guy
on the ground and find out what the
hell's going on. And that's, you know,
there's a fellow who wrote a book,
his name was Peters,
and this is many years later,
and he, he wrote the book,
it's called management by walking around
and here's a guy made a fortune just
doing what I used to do.
It's,
it's scary,
but it's true.
That's what leadership is all about,
is find out what's going on and
then using it some common sense to
tell people this is what you're supposed
to do, or give them some guidance.
But I mean,
people who used to tell me,
well, you know how to do things cause
you could order with people to do things.
And I've seen,
let me tell you some ordering a guide,
you get out of a tank to fix the track
when somebody shooting at you is not
anybody willing to just do it.
He's going to do it because he knows
if he don't get the track fixed,
we're going to get ass killed. I
mean, we're going to get going.
He's going to do it because that's his
job and that that may be leadership.
But I'll tell ya,
it's discipline that comes
from people being trained,
right and taught right and treated right.
You don't,
if you don't treat people right,
they deserve to treat you wrong.
And I'm a great believer in
treating people the right way.
Well,
I,
I'm just from hearing you
talk about treating people
the right way and listening
to people, you, you're,
you know, you say when,
when I told people to do
stuff, they did it well. Yeah.
That's because you treated them
well. You listen to him, you,
you had those relationships with your,
with your troops.
And that's what makes people,
like you said,
when you got to have somebody that's
going to go to go out and fix the track
under fire,
well that's somebody that's,
they're not going to do that just
because you ordered to do it.
You better have some,
some relationships.
You better have treated them well
and they must understand why.
The why on the mission as to
like, hey, why this is important.
So when you,
when you look back at World War II,
Korea,
Vietnam,
I was from a tactical perspective,
actually maneuvering troops.
Is there any big lessons that you
would think back of that you say,
this is something that I did consistently
or this is something that I would
never do because I knew
it would cause problems?
Hmm.
I can't think of anything.
Ah,
I'll go back to what I said earlier.
I've always believed,
and maybe it's just from growing
up in Iowa, I don't know,
just treat people like you'd like to
be treated yourself and it worked out.
Uh,
I don't know.
I told you about my first
sergeant called me Fifi
which pissed me off quite frankly,
but uh,
cause he was a guy who didn't treat
people like people like to be treated.
And I've always was amazed how much I
exalted and the fact when he got busted,
I mean w we were in England on
the way over to continent and uh,
he, he got busted for, I
don't know what reason,
but he got busted back to
him. I mean, being a private,
that's a big jump from first
sergeant founded via private.
And I was happy
because I didn't think this guy was,
he,
he's also the guy when I took the test
to see what I could be smart enough to go
to the military academies said,
what the hell are you taking a test for?
Therefore you're not smart
enough to go to the west point.
Then I always would like to be able to
say to this guy, if I ever saw him again,
I'm sure he's dead by now.
I told you so.
But you know,
uh,
if you don't treat people
like they should be treated,
they,
you deserve to be
treated the opposite way.
And, uh, I just have always practiced
or tried to practice it anyway.
And uh,
so far it's been relatively successful.
So that's a huge underpinning
of leadership from,
from everything I've seen.
Everything I've ever read,
every person I've ever talked to,
if you care about your people you care
about and you want to treat them well as
human beings, that's the underpinning
that really makes leadership work.
And it's a lot of times,
and you mentioned this earlier,
a lot of times from the
civilian side, they think, well,
in the military you can just order people
to do things and they'll just do it
because you're the boss.
And that's not true.
And it's actually when I got out of the
military and I started working in the
civilian sector, I thought to myself,
well, if, well, if you didn't want, if,
if you want somebody to do something and
they don't do it, you can just fire him.
But that's not true either.
Because guess what,
you'll run out of people really quick.
And so what you have to do is you have
to lead. That's what you have to do.
One of those,
the most core underpinnings of leadership
is really caring about the people that
work for you. And I think
the more you care about them,
and I know for me, like I,
I, I cared more about my
guys then I did about myself.
I wanted to make sure that they were okay
and that things were going to go well
for them. And that was always my
priority, my, my real priority.
And Andy,
I suppose someone that was
a very jaded might think,
well then you know, you're, you're
going to get passed over. You're not,
things are going to work out good for you
because you're more worried about your
troops. And the opposite is
actually true and my career was,
was it was beautiful and all I ever tried
to do is take care of the people that
work for me.
Okay.
Because that's the way
you get to be successful.
You know,
hiring people
are working with people. You
know, in civilian sector,
you hire people in the village a week,
whoever it was that
that was it get people.
But I what he said,
your job is to make the boss
successful and vice versa.
The boss's job is to
make Dennis successful.
And if you've worked at it works
out for both of you and to meet
leadership,
you know,
we talk about it, but it's easy if
you follow few basic principles,
you don't have to have all
the stuff that goes mean.
People write books on leadership.
You've probably written books on
leadership yourself. Yes indeed.
But the fact of matter, there's some
basics and you just expand on it.
You don't,
it isn't that magic.
If you just follow a few basic principles.
One of the things we talk about in
the book actually is simple, not easy,
because it is, there's the end. We say
that in our book as well as we're not,
we didn't vent to me this,
this is stuff that's been around and
there's no Eureka moments and we're not
claiming to have at
anything startlingly new.
This is fundamental stuff
that if you think about it,
some of it might be stuff
you already do as a leader.
Someone would be stuff that you know you
should do as a leader and just making
it clear for people to understand is,
is probably the,
the only real benefit of the book itself.
It's like, okay, this is good stuff,
but nothing,
no rocket science there.
I didn't need to be a whiz kid to
write that book. I can find it.
So did you,
you mentioned earlier when we were not
recording that you actually ended up
going back to Vietnam as and where
you a civilian at that time? Yes.
Okay.
Well,
my wife and I like to travel.
So we've traveled most of the
places in the world by now.
And she wanted to go back and
see where I had been in Vietnam.
And a nice,
wasn't too sure about that. But
anyway, we had this opportunity.
And uh,
so we went back and I went to Hanoi,
which was an experience and they go to
the Hanoi Hilton and seeing how they've
turned that into a propaganda
place and have still remember,
seen his picture on the wall of uh,
Senator Mccain and a couple of other guys,
I can't remember the names.
Another one was what high
school classmate of mine,
uh,
but day by name who was an air
force or a retired colonel,
he got the medal of honor.
But anyway,
in every showed them in these white
pants and white over shirt is if they've
read up on a barbecue, you know, Indian,
you know, everything you've
heard about this place was just,
and they showed you some of the
cages that they had people in.
We have had
to get guests on the podcasts
that were in the Annoy Hilton.
And one of them went back and was talking
us through that same propaganda went,
went back to them and only Hilton
as a civilian. And just the, uh,
the feeling he had was,
was pretty strong.
I can't imagine. I mean, uh, but you know,
when I was there, I was just seeing
it from the propaganda and what they,
cause it's,
it's a big
tourist attraction apparently
for the Vietnamese. And, uh,
so we obviously saw it
and knew what it was and,
and for what it was.
And I hear all kinds of stories
about the people that were there,
you know, but, uh,
and then we went from there to
Denang and then down to Saigon.
And, uh, I'd hired a, uh, uh,
a car and a guide to take us up,
back up to my own operational area
and Joe through the Michelin Rubber
Plantation,
which was sort of a fun experience to see.
Now it's no longer, Michelin
is a state on, uh, uh,
they took it over obviously
from the French, but, uh,
it looks exactly the same. I mean,
trees are lined up, rubber trees,
just rubber trees, rubber trees. And
people are out there
working the trees. And, uh,
I don't know if you know this,
this is an aside,
you cannot burn a living rubber tree.
It won't burn.
And I've tried hard.
I mean,
I had Flint,
I have two flame throwers in my unit and
we tried hard to burn those trees down
on the sides of the road.
Doesn't work, doesn't work.
And so anyway,
the,
but we went back up to the old
operation or a in the same place.
I was pretty close to her.
I got wounded
when I was in Vietnam.
I was in my helicopter flying over this
river and I was pretty close to where
that happened. I could do that because
I had to map coordinates of what I,
where I had been wounded before.
Otherwise I'd guarantee I'd never be
able to recognize the place. But, uh,
but I, my old, uh, base camp,
which was because I had helicopters of
where they had an airfield and now being
turned into a, a strip mall. So,
so washed all that happening.
And uh, but it was a
scene. Saigon again was, uh,
an amazing experience to see
what's what they've done.
You see all these tall buildings now,
but the one officers' club that was on
the roof of one of the hotels is still
there exactly the same. And we, my
wife and I went up and had lunch there
and
it,
my time before I went out to the unit,
I used to go up there
and we'd go up to eat.
You Watch out here and see the,
uh,
the sabers, not sabers. Um,
what do you, what do you call the
browns that are stressors? The tracers.
Thank you.
See all the tracers from being fired up,
upper back down.
And it was sort of unique experience
because you really weren't fighting a war
in Saigon, you know, it was, it was
so different from there when
you went out into the field. So,
but, uh, it was, it was fun to go
back and see what they've done.
And I was impressed with how much the
south Vietnamese have really been serious
about getting real business and
going and a lot of things happening.
Business was up north.
It's still a GRE.
It was still a grant at the
time. Very Agrarian. You, it mean
very few tall buildings,
very few businesses,
and so that you could identify and
maybe it's still the same that goes,
that was, that was 11
years ago now. But, uh,
and I don't know what's
changed to over there,
but so the north Viet Mimi's one no war,
so to speak. Uh, I say that
with tongue in cheek actually,
but they won the war.
But I'm not sure that the south Vietnamese
aren't coming back and taking over
and running the country. They certainly
have the financial strength there. Uh,
and I hope that's a way it,
eventually it will work out
well the way the rest of the world's gone.
It's in freedom and
democracy and capitalism that
eventually wins the long war.
And we've seen that worldwide. So
hopefully it'll happen for them as well.
How'd you get wounded your third, your
third time getting wounded in Vietnam?
Well I was,
I was one of the missions we had
every evening we'd go into a perimeter
and most of the time we'd be in a
perimeter around artillery unit so they
could fire at night without worrying
about getting over run.
And so I put all of our unit in this
perimeter from my helicopter flying around
and
I noticed a bunch of sand pants
evacuating the area we had.
So I thought in my John Wayne felling,
I want to go down and shoot some
of these guys. So I got to pilot,
I was flying in this case,
uh,
in a a two passenger,
I mean one passenger
bubble helicopter. And uh, anyway,
so I had this in 40,
he noted him 40 years.
It's as far as it looks
like a shotgun shell.
And so I'm up there and I'm
shooting at these guys in the Sam,
Ben,
and I'm doing pretty good,
uh, missing a lot, but he,
so one of them shot back
and my God,
it hit me in the leg.
And so I told the Jabber Pout,
take me back down to the headquarters,
which voters squat and surgery was.
And he will never forget,
he,
he took my pants away and there was
blood spray write out all the way out,
at least 18 inches from my leg.
Hit something.
They call this burger.
And he said,
this is a captain speaking to me,
colonel, you goddamn dumb, son of a bitch,
you could be dead.
So anyway,
he bandaged me up and the metal
still there still in my leg.
But,
uh,
where you, where you, are you returning
to duty though, right? Oh yeah. I mean,
I hadn't been in command more than
30 days. I was scared to death.
I couldn't be evacuated. Hell,
I had finished up my tour.
Let me,
I mean,
so one of my friends named Tim Kennedy
is a green baret and he has a TV show
coming out called hard to kill. I think
maybe we need to get, you all guys
know,
somebody might take me up on it.
Uh, I, I've been fortunate. I mean,
a lot of people got hurt a lot more
serious than I've been. Uh, uh,
and, uh, I've seen some, in fact, uh,
I've had too many her
seriously, I had, uh,
one of my, uh, my
axel was in the helicopter and got shot
up to the seat of the helicopter and all
the shrapnel,
everything went right into
his leg and he was forever,
uh, in bad shape. I mean, I mean,
I've seen a lot of people
get hurt pretty badly. Uh,
I been, I've been fortunate. I mean,
but I'm also had the attitude, I'm not
going to get shot and killed. I mean,
no, it's worked out. But, uh,
going back to, well, you know,
when I got out of that
tank to go back in Korea,
I had no more idea that I
was going to get killed,
that that wasn't going to enter into
my mind. I just had something to do.
And uh,
that may be foolish,
but, uh, it's just the way it was.
Yeah. I think if you're,
if you were thinking about
what could happen, you know,
wouldn't do anything, you
couldn't do anything. Right. Yeah.
So you're,
you wrap up your squadron commander
in Vietnam and again, I, I mean,
you were taking, how often would you
guys, you're getting in firefights a lot.
What was your,
what was your cash rate of casualties?
Like how many guys did you lose?
How many people were killed while
you were there as a squatter
commander? How many were
killed? Probably 10.
Not too many. I mean, uh,
when you have a calves,
do you know what an ache have is?
That's a personnel carrier.
I mean,
it cast has her armored calvary
assault vehicle, but it's, uh, it's,
it was the [inaudible] back in those days.
I don't know.
I don't know what they're called.
We still used [inaudible].
We used them one thirteens in Ramadi,
the same exact vehicle.
So we are very familiar with it.
We both written in the back.
Yeah,
well they're pretty well protected and
the tanks or we had patent tanks and
they're protected. So, uh, yeah,
we had casualties, uh, because in,
in a,
in a calvary troop,
we have infantry right in the outcasts.
So when he get out, he got her.
But I don't know the statistics. Uh,
I,
I wrote enough letters
but not very mean one is
more than enough, but, uh,
I, I don't remember how
many I wrote. Uh, but,
uh, cause I did that for
everybody was who's killed? Uh,
but, uh, I don't, I don't
know the statistics, uh,
not to not overburden burdened.
I mean, in this incident,
uh,
I got several people's names on the wall.
Uh,
I go there every year.
She's just to stand there.
But I don't know Jack who, I
don't know the answer. Understood,
sir.
When you got home from Vietnam,
you know,
you talked about coming home from Korea,
Netherlands in uniform,
and
you know,
we hear stories of guys coming home from
Vietnam and they literally get told,
don't wear your uniform around.
How different was the reception
from World War II Korea to Vietnam?
Well,
coming back from,
um,
from Vietnam
was a sad experience.
Uh,
we thought we've been doing a good job.
We, that we were doing the right job. Um,
and I came back to the Pentagon and
I sort of witnessed the experience
of the country being up in arms.
About Vietnam. Um,
so,
uh,
it didn't feel too appreciate it
I guess is the right word. Uh,
and yet it didn't feel like I felt
like I'd been doing a good job.
Uh,
so I don't,
I didn't have, I didn't
have any bad feelings. Uh,
most of those feelings about what was
going on came after I got out of it.
I mean,
I retired in [inaudible] 69 and things
began to go to hill in the country about
what we're doing over there.
A
while right after I got out, I guess, uh,
my job and uh,
when I got out,
I mean when I came home was in,
it's at the secretary of defense's level.
I,
I told you earlier,
the army was send me to school
to learn to it with kids.
Well, guess what? When I came back,
army sent me to be a whiz kid.
I was,
I was standing up to the
secretary and General Staff,
Helen n two ovens organization,
which was called systems analysis.
And they asked for all the whiz kids were,
and they had a representative,
the army, Navy, Air Force,
Marine Corps, all four of us.
And we were sure the other end
is a teetotaler. We were, we,
we were supposed to balance some of
these smart young men that were the quote
kids. And as I tell people,
I've never a whizzer a kid,
but I was in that organization
and if it was an experience,
they wouldn't let me
work on anything army.
And I had, because they knew
I had to go back to the army.
She, that was, and you had to,
you had to be sitting there and making
decisions that could be a against the
army,
what the army wanted as
opposed to one of the wonders,
one of the things I was involved with,
because I was involved with
the navy and the air force,
the navy wanted to build
another nuclear submarine.
Well,
there's only so many capital
ships that was by law.
So Davey,
I asked why there was,
I can't remember now, I think 13 capital
ships or whatever the number was. I, yeah,
why is that number 13?
It took quite awhile for them to figure
out the answer and it really was very
simple. You're going back to the League
of nations. Parley, introduce, I mean
1920 something when they,
they pop partly down to the
various world war of one winners.
There are number of capital
shifts. I, he called battleships,
numbers of ships that each country would
have and that's where the number came
from. Whoa. I,
Dan was just, uh, now
I learned to ask that question
because when I was going to Michigan,
one of the professors said,
he's just in statistics class.
I want to know what you wanted or watch,
not what the results are.
I want to know what the
assumptions are and know.
So I was asking this assumption,
why is your x number of capital ships?
It was just simple question. I, I
didn't know I was creating a challenge.
I mean it,
it,
it turned out to be
exactly what I was saying.
It was a strange phenomenon for them
to try to figure out why there was that
number.
I don't know what the world is now,
but I can tell you at that point,
this was the 1968, I guess. Uh,
it was, uh, a question that
they took a while to answer.
By the way,
I don't know how many capital shifts
we'll have and I don't know what to call
the day, but we have a lot more than
I think we had back in those days.
So what made you decide to retire?
Well,
I had 25 years in the military
and I decided I wanted to think
about doing something else. Uh,
part of it was I used to
listen to people tell me,
you just order people to do
things and they do it. I said,
that's just a lot of Bulani.
So I wanted to go and see
who got my, if you would, uh,
teeth on trying something
Savine would world.
So,
uh,
I signed a bunch of resumes
out and I eventually
was hired to go down to a Texas and a
fellow that hired me was retired navy
aviator, who by the way, uh,
as an aside with assigned to the
first squadron, I think it's called,
it flew jets off aircraft carriers.
Guy By name of Felix to
Blonsky was a wonderful man.
And, but if you wanted
to know what time it was,
he'd tell you how to build a watch.
So there's that.
But he, he, uh,
he hired me and our job there
no,
was to figure out how to use from Ltvs,
uh,
computer resources,
how to use these and civilian application.
And
one of the things we did
was we developed for Dallas
x's and o's that they used
to do on the job board,
on the computer screen,
and just became a way that apparently
Dallas cowboys would teach the guys how to
react to whatever plays it was.
So that was using some
of this fancy technology,
that LTV head to build something
that was applicable in Savannah life.
Well,
laying of LTV,
Lang Timko vote
suddenly got challenged
because he was creating, uh,
a huge empire
and the antitrust people got after him.
And all of a sudden,
our organism,
the part that I was in was,
went from 30 people to four. And that
was one of the four. And I don't know,
to this day,
I still don't know why they can't meet
you because I'd just been there less than
a year. But the guy who had tried
to hire me into computer sciences
previously offered me a
job with computer sciences.
I mean,
even though I had a job,
I knew that this place was not a
place that had longterm open up B.
So I went to work for computer science
as an ethnic 15 years there and,
uh, and ended up retiring from there, uh,
is one of the presidents and
one of their divisions. And, uh,
one of the things that
my bosses used to say,
I was one of the few leaders,
they had been a lot of managers,
but,
uh,
I was leading a group and
we became very successful,
much more so than I ever
imagined we could be.
It was primarily in sales and marketing.
And I had a boss that said,
who was from my BM and
strict IBM suit kind of guy,
you know, you've heard all
the stories. And he said,
he said,
if I would go back to my comrades at IBM
and tell him that I just hired a former
army colonel to piano sales,
they all think I was God damn crazy.
And so anyway,
I had a great career
computer sciences and uh,
as I said, I retired from there and
I'm not a typist.
When I was going to high school,
if you took typing, you weren't
going to college, it was back.
So this thing called voicemail
appeared to me and I thought,
so
another fill on,
I started a company in
the voicemail business,
1984. And, uh, it,
it was pretty successful and we sold it
in 1998 and I've stopped working since
then.
Well that is awesome.
I know we've kept you here for
a couple hours now and uh, um,
probably a good place to at least stop
for this, for this particular session.
Um,
is there anything else you want to say?
Anything else you want to
close out with what I can,
I can say this that I met my wife,
uh,
on my first assignment
from the Pentagon and I,
my job in the Pentagon among other things
was to control the number of troops on
the ground in Vietnam.
Congress mandated be 550,000
people on the ground.
My job was to be shared
that that number was mitt.
So when the secretary of
defense went to Congress,
he could always say that
we have never heard. So
on a quarterly basis I would go to
Hawaii and in people from Hawaii,
Thailand,
Korea,
Philippines and Hawaii would all meet
at the headquarters here up on the hill.
And we'd go over,
cause what,
when Westmoreland a lot to replace
an attic battalion was an infant.
You pertained to different numbers
and everything's different.
So we had to do all this monitoring and
keeping track of how many troops we hit.
My wife was a school teacher in California
and she was over there on a vacation
and one of my former
colleagues from Vietnam,
she knew him and some on another.
We met
for the next two years,
we dated cross country. She didn't
California, me and the Pentagon.
And I would go every quarter to the
Hawaiian islands for this meeting I'm
telling you about.
So I'd plant the meeting to be started
on Tuesday so I could fly from here to
California,
spend some time with her.
Then I'd fly off after Hawaiian islands.
And then on the way back I'd step into
the same thing and it'd be a backer.
So anyway, we got married in, uh,
19 after I got out or retired and 69.
And we got married in October 69. And, uh,
the reason I'm still living
today is because of her.
She keeps me alive, takes
care of me. I made a,
uh, so she's, she's, uh,
the principal reason that I
can sit here and talk to Ya.
Well then we'll say thank you,
you for coming on and we'll say thank
you to your wife for getting you here.
Cause uh, sir, once again,
this has just been a,
an absolute honor to
be able to talk to you,
to be able to hear the stories and the
lessons that you learned and thank you.
Well from all of us for, for
your service, your sacrifice.
And it's been an honor.
Well,
you all deserve the honor to meet
you guys.
I don't know what I'd be,
what it would be like to be in the
service today, frankly. I mean,
I see these guys,
my,
my nephew deployed six times,
twice to Iraq,
once for the Somali extraction
plus three other times,
just the flying, you know, and
now
how he did this, I'll never know,
but he never left camp Pendleton.
I mean he did.
He,
he was a drill sergeant down at MCRD,
but he'd commute back to
back to Pendleton. I mean,
his wife lived there the whole time.
He was 20 some odd years in the
Marine Corps on the same. I,
I never figured that out.
I moved around like,
but my wife would tell you
she,
she and I got married after I got
all this room for an our 17th outs.
We've only been married for
almost 49 years. I mean,
so everybody said, well, you were in
the military. We didn't do it this way.
She was never in the military. We, we
moved all the time since then. I mean,
you stay in San Diego,
I'll do my best, sir, I'll
do my best. And again,
you have to absolutely.
The troops that are out there today,
and there's a lot of troops that listen
to this guys out there hold the line and
doing those deployments over
and over again. But you know,
the work that we do today is based on
the lessons that we learn from your
generations, from the three wars that
you fought and what you passed on to us.
And it was an honor for us to
continue to carry the flag.
So thank you. See You keep
carrying it. Yes. Here. Yes sir.
And Colonel Tom Fife has departed
and obviously it is a honor to uh,
get to talk to him and thanks for
setting that up Dave. Yeah, man,
that was awesome. Much appreciated.
Three war veteran, I mean,
come on,
come on.
That's just unbelievably awesome to sit
and listen to and, and you know what,
thanks Dave for setting that up
and also thanks to everyone that,
that supports this podcast so that we
have the opportunity to bring people on
like Colonel Tom Fife and be able
to share those lessons on it,
which there was a ton in there.
So thank you all for supporting an echo.
If people do want to support,
sure.
Can you maybe fill us in
on how to do that? Sure.
Let me start with our company. Oh, or gin.
That's the company or gene
main.com is the website
there. You can get Taco had supplements,
you can get Jocko supplements, Jocko,
Super Krill oil for your joints.
Joint warfare for your joints. Don't
run out. By the way, Dave Berg, you're,
I dunno if you've ever been on the,
in the situation of running out of super
crew. When you depend on Super Krill,
it's bad situation and if you ever
want to reduce the risk of running out,
do the subscription thing, that's what
I do. Kind of subscription subscription.
Yeah.
You just get your allotted amount per
month or however often you need it.
Also pre mission supplement.
It's called
discipline. Hold on Dave, you
are firing up on discipline.
You, you said, you said to me and
I quote, I live on discipline.
It has become a daily part of my life for
sure. You've got it in the brain. Yup.
You use it before you work. Yup. You're
studying, you're working, you're prepping.
That's your go to this stuff is awesome.
I use it probably more than I should.
Yeah, it's a jet. I don't know if
there is a, some kind of uh, you know,
limitation health wise,
like if you're drinking nine
gallons and gallons. Yeah.
Jack.
All right.
Well there, there it is.
It's at the of everything.
Pre Mission preworkout pretest taking,
pre meeting,
pre Jujitsu Zoo
and now you're going to get
mad or whatever or you're
going to make you give me
your attitude because you know you make
fun of me cause I wanted it to taste
good. Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah.
You make fun of me and there's not even
that much I can say about that because
it's a legitimate thing. True
for, for me the Jocko to be like,
oh I want it to taste good. It's kind
of a weakness, right? It's kind of soft.
Right.
Well that being said,
we have another flavor coming. I'm going
to tell you what, well, first of all,
it's a two things. Well first of all,
it tastes good. Yeah, I know Bro.
Second of all it's,
it's,
it's basically Pina Colada,
but I can't call it that.
And it's like I can't do,
I can't do
that. It's going to be called the
coconut pineapple. Sure. You know,
we're not going just straight Pina
colada cause I just can't. This is not,
that's not how, no, no,
that's not out, eh. Yeah.
You did mention that and I'm impressed
that you sticking with the delicious,
a luxurious tastes
clean, you know, do that.
But that's one of those things like you
like Pina Colada, you like that flavor.
Like I've heard of people
not really liking it,
but that could have to do with the fact
that you know how like when you drink
alcohol too much and it has like a
star, like Tequila, we'll have it.
Peanut coladas is like that.
If you just drink too many of them,
you get drunk and that experience
now you can never drink it again.
Now if you smell it,
you feel off. Tequila.
Tequila is like that for sure.
During my younger years,
I had like a 14 month hiatus from
Jaeger after I had a bets bad sitch.
Yeah, so peanut clouds. I was young
and stupid. You know what young,
stupid and motivated like you know when
you're actually motivated the coroner to
do with this. That's bad.
Dumb. Yeah, but check,
if you haven't had that
experience with Pina Colada,
I would assume that that's a,
that's a pretty high rate of acceptance.
As far as deliciousness goes. In my
opinion or in my, by my estimation,
I think my hypothesis or whatever.
Nonetheless it's called disciplines,
pre mission.
This whether you love Pina Colada or
love lemon lime ish flavor with other
delicious factors in it.
That's a good thing.
But it's good because it makes your brain
more healthy and your body pre mission
preworkout pretest taking pre meeting,
pre Jujitsu,
pre workout cognitive and
physical force multiplier.
This is what that is.
So get on now.
And of course also Giza in rash guards.
Dave Burke.
Yeah. You missed the milk.
Yeah, I didn't really miss it.
I was going to save it for last but not
all. I'll get back in my lane over here.
No, because the just had a whole thing.
I was going to do it. Brash cards.
Tell me about it.
I feel like we should do the molten now
cause you've got kind of kind of brought
it up, which is you know, if for lack
of a better term it's actually it,
it is a better term. It's not
protein, it's protein powder,
but it's a better term for this particular
protein powder milk, mint chocolate.
Just because he didn't know
deeper brick here on the milk yet.
He's not on the market and just told
me he's going to get it this week.
Well I will say this, I never was into
protein powder. Aside from, you know,
you're still in high school, you're
still not, I'm still hearing the mold,
right? Correct, correct.
But this one is one of those good ones
were kind of like you and the discipline
where you're like pounding it all the
time. So I give my daughter dessert.
Oh yeah, this is a dessert straight
up, straight up desert is that good?
And don't put a couple of drops of
the dill in there. Tried to do that.
But two drops, little Manila putting
an egg and put it in the blender.
In fact, you know what? Don't do it. Don't
do it. You'll be in the same boat as me.
That's when the last, it's like a
dessert and those protein nights.
Good man cause I used to make
these milkshakes when I was young.
I'm just a homemade
probably.
Probably it nonetheless thing used to
make these milkshakes when I was young
they were,
they had vanilla egg,
like a teeny tiny piece of banana milk
and some other stuff,
some sugar in there and it was good.
It was like a solid milkshake like good,
like almost like you
bought it from a grower.
May spot is no joke when it comes
to milkshakes. Simulator, mint,
mint chocolate, peanut butter,
peanut butter, chocolate,
chocolate, peanut butter milk is on
its way. Straight up. Dave Burke.
When you get on it you're
going to stay on that.
So you're just going to be pounding
discipline and mock like all day. The way,
the way Dave Berg,
only days easier look like echo
Charles swollen six months, dude,
lifting, Jujitsu, walk, all that stuff.
Also ds and rash guards.
We can talk about that if you want,
unless you have another suggestion on
what else I should talk about at this
point. I'm, I'm saying I want
to do the right thing over here.
I know what I'm saying. Dave Berg kind
of get you up. Dave Berg. He diggy right?
I do.
I have to.
So here's the one good thing
about starting Jujitsu with
45 I discovered the one
good thing about it instead of starting
at 15 is I never had any of those
stories where I tell about
how uncomfortable the gear
is or how the rash guards
gave me, you know, are they,
these are hard to wash.
I got origin main gives time
to go from the get. Go ahead.
Someone that never had a flip phone in
1994 just woke up and they had an iPhone
six started with the iPhone 10 out
of the gate. Origin man, rash guards.
So I don't know what it's like to have
grown up with all that terrible. Gary,
you guys use what it was like.
Well that's actually good news
in my, in my opinion. You know,
because working,
not working,
but you know like working out and doing
your due to the in a junk g pry the
first gear head man.
You know how you like any like you ever
when you buy your first suit, same deal.
Like you didn't know.
I Dunno in my like I don't know how that
thought that was just like, oh I see.
Go suit on, let me go buy one. I
don't know, whatever. So same thing.
So I went and bought a g and it was like
I bought a cheap one 40 bucks. I know.
Straight up.
See I bought my first Guiyu isn't a key
I bought from the Quito store cause the
Jujitsu place, they were like, it's 100
bucks. I'm like, oh cool. Not Happening.
I'll go find a different one.
And I found that the Cheapo unbleached.
Have you ever heard of this?
Unbleached cotton that was even cheaper
than the bleach color. It's an off white.
Yeah. It feels like it's filled with
steel wool scratching getting your skin.
But that's hard. And it lasted like
four weeks. So yeah, get a quality,
give yourself an orgy gay. That was
Nikita. Quito, Quito Gig. It looked,
it
felt similar. Yeah. From the
external viewpoint to a Jujitsu guy,
but it wasn't,
and it damn sure wasn't made in America
made in Maine.
You know what's awesome is tend to know
to literally know the people because
we'd been to the factory. I know that
people that, that made those, I know them.
Yeah. I like I say, Oh hey, how are you
doing? Oh, I'm over here making a key.
That's real. That's what's
happening. Yeah. And on top of that,
not to mention the cotton,
that was a loom to right there in the
building by the way, is from America too.
That's something you, so I was talking
about Pete, about this, the cotton,
it's not all carpets. It's um,
what does it Polly, Polly, Polly.
So it's a poly cotton blend and I thought
that the two strands were different
and it's woven together.
Nome, the, they make that,
that actual thread is co cotton,
poly cotton,
the thread, the thread itself
that you weave is, that's why,
that's why you can put it in the dryer
to dry like a normal piece of clothing,
not four hours.
You call it out in yourself to hang it
up cause it's all cotton and it just
holds onto the water. Vic cast gets
out of their main America. Oh good.
So yeah. Good, good. Dave
Burke, boom. Origin G,
no history of discomfort in other geese.
No.
No Stinky area of the house where wet
ghees are hanging up for four days now.
And I'll say this for
all this stuff at origin,
everything they make is awesome on
their website that talk about the uh,
the Hoodie and they call it the
most comfortable of any ever.
I grew up a hundred
percent wearing hoodies.
If you grow up in southern California,
when it gets really cold out,
you put on a Hoodie.
The origin Hoodie is the most
comfortable hoodies I've ever owned.
So that stuff is legit. No joke. No,
no personal offense to you, Dave,
because I respect you. I do, I
really respect you as a person,
but your level of measuring comfort is
not even close to echo and echo is a sort
of the quality comfort control guy and
he has already made this statement.
So you saying is like everyone
is listening on whenever
you were in the Marine
Corps,
you know you've done some,
you know you've done some tough stuff in
your life and they're looking at echo.
They're like, wait, they have echo fits.
It's comfortable where in that
actual Steven has meaning. Yeah,
yeah, I will. But I will
say, you know, sure.
Like of course Dave Burke of course
we all knew that. You know I've, yeah,
I am the gold standard of
comfort evaluation for sure.
I think and I will second that.
It is the Hoodie and the pants by the way.
So yeah, get those as
well. All made in America.
The compression gear and rash guards,
all that.
I'm just saying there's all this stuff
on the website or did you mean.com and
get all this stuff. The hoodie,
the geese, the rash guards,
sweat pants, other stuff. A lot of
cool stuff on there. Check it out.
You want something? Get something.
Also the immersion camp.
Did you get to camp? Boom. Just
got a message from someone from Florida
young lady from Florida saying saying,
I want to go to the emerging camp,
but I won't know anyone there.
And the only one from Florida.
What do you think? Hey,
you know me kind of.
I guess if you could send me the message
or you know me probably know Jocko to
echo, you know me and that means you
know Dave Burke, no, three of us,
three people already. And here's the
good thing where when you go there,
we technically sure knew each other.
And you knew Pete.
That was the first time I met Pete.
I met probably what?
Like the first 15 minutes
we met about 20 people
and we hung out with those 20 people.
Plus the other people you meet
over the days. The whole time.
It wasn't the kind of like, oh,
I don't really know that a man.
I'm hanging over here and they're over
there. It wasn't, it's not like that.
You ever heard of those
dating sites? No. Seriously.
You put in dot. You look at, okay,
so I grew up before dating sites or
I got married before dating sites,
so I was just like,
who do the game back in the day?
Like you got to go to a place where you
can hopefully meet a girl, right? Yeah.
They've odds of meeting a girl are not
the girl that you like and that has some
sort of remotely similar interests and
you go into a bar over the hundred girls
in there and like you're lucky if
there's one of them there that's remotely
interested in what you're
interested in and you can connect.
Then you've got to meet them and you got
to go up and talk to him and all this
stuff.
It's real hard.
Then they made the match dating things
online where you put in your stuff. Yeah,
and then you meet that one person and
you connect with them and you have all
these things in common. This
situation, you think about it,
you're actually just going into a place
where everyone's into the same thing
that you're going to do.
It's like walk into a bar and
everyone likes the same stuff there,
likes Jujitsu and wants to train
and wants to hang out and that's,
that's what makes it cool.
Yeah. Yeah. No, no dating
you typically. But Hey, yeah,
that's a good point.
It wouldn't kind of,
you kind of converge on the topic of
Jujitsu and then kind of everything else
spawns from there. Yeah, totally.
It really seemed like to me,
and then everything spins back to
Jujitsu. Yeah, it was good fun.
So my input is to go,
that's what I think.
I think go when in doubt
go. It's going, I'm going,
life is going good firms
jps considering he'll go,
he'll probably end up
calling. Yeah. So we'll be,
it'll be a little ETF reunion
tour of the Zhou sheets.
Yup. Great. And when you go there
knowing zero people, you'll leave.
They're not only knowing more people,
but they'll be kind of your friends.
I will guarantee you'll have more actual
friends after you leave guaranteed to
the lady that emailed me. That's what
I think that all that, that's cool.
And even if you will
know some people there,
I say go to because you can
immerse yourself in Jujitsu.
Best Way to learn and you know,
let's face it, you're in Maine.
There's a bunch of lobster.
They serve lobster. Yeah.
That was one of the highlights
in my opinion. Anyway. Yeah,
so it is on August 26 through
September 2nd two sessions.
Go to both if you want, but yeah, two
sessions. There you go. All Levels.
Also for fitness gear going to
[inaudible] dot com slash Jocko they got
kettlebells, battle ropes, jump ropes,
all kinds of stuff. Good stuff. Very up.
You work out,
get some new gear.
It'll actually get you more in
the mood to do a workout when you,
when they gear comes in.
I guarantee that. Well,
I don't know if I can guarantee that,
but if that's how it was for
me when I got the jump room,
then all of a sudden I'm a jump roper.
It seems sane. It's good. Anyway,
a lot of cool stuff on there. A lot of
good information on there too. By the way.
If you'd beginning like kettlebells are
you beginning other workout movements
and you want to know some tips and you
know even some nutrition stuff really
good. Anyway, go there on
it.com/chocolate good way to support.
Also when you get the books that
Jocko reviews on this podcast,
I organize them on Jocko
podcast.com on the top.
You click on books from episodes and
it takes you to the page and it has,
that's right.
You guessed it.
The books by that was for
four on episodes by episodes.
You see what I'm saying? Anyway,
click on there, takes you to Amazon,
you can shop and get your books,
get whatever else do you want from Amazon,
your batteries or duct tape,
whatever. Keep shopping. Do you also,
good way to support is to subscribe to
the podcast. If you haven't already,
stitcher, iTunes, Google play, Spotify.
Do you subscribe on Spotify or Arrow?
I've been to Spotify.
There's a lot more apps for podcasts now.
Yeah,
I think I'm going to explore some of
them to Daily News of comes up daily.
Um, yeah. Well either way, the point
there is little change to their thing.
What do you mean there? There's,
there's there layout or something.
So now it pops up
different is definitely now
I know, but it's like you ever realize
when, when you the layout of something,
so this was the big thing on Facebook.
When do you get on Facebook deeper?
Do you remember? 2014
14 Dang, that's, that's,
that's pretty early environment
for school. Okay. There you go.
So were you in on Facebook when they kind
of changed the layout of Facebook from
something to something to like newsfeed
negative Jocko Jocko doesn't know
anything about this. You know what I'm
talking about at all? Huh? No I didn't.
I didn't get on Facebook troll
to till probably like 2000 I was,
might've been on,
but I didn't actively do anything on
it till like maybe a year ago. Yeah,
maybe a year and a half. So the
layout of Facebook was like, you know,
you had your profile picture and I even,
I'm just trying to remember what it was.
It was like, I don't even remember
what it was, but it was like,
I think like your wall or something
like that where it's like you're just,
you're your own stuff,
and then they all of a sudden switched
it to this newsfeed situation.
You know how like now it's like everyone's
stuff that you're basically how it is
now and they just switched it and
people were mad. It was like jade,
like change their life,
you know? They were pissed.
That's what you sounded like when you
just talked about the apples. That's,
you know, you had that same
effect on your brain. Anyway,
subscribe to the podcast
is what I'm saying.
Regardless of the layout of any iTunes
or any other applications that the layout
has or has not changed. Good way to
support also wherever youtube channel.
So subscribe to that if you want.
And if you're interested in the
Wii video version of this podcast,
once you put chocolate looks like, or Dave
Burke in this case, what he looks like.
Pretty handsome,
I think as far as handsome
ghosts or Colonel Tom five yes.
See what he looks like.
Yeah.
Typically those are the ones
that people want to see.
You know they want to see the guests.
I want to see what they look like,
what we look like. Yeah. It
kind of already know except me.
I guess they don't really know what
I look like cause I still do get,
hey you don't look like how you sound,
which is an actual thing.
You can look like how you sound like you
look like how you sound check and the
same day Burke looks how it sounds,
but it's not a one to one that's not a
face to like your voice sounds like this.
So your face is gonna look like
it's not like that. It's like your,
your voice sounds like this.
So your face can look like this
kind of real like this group,
this little variety of faith possible
faces as soon what I'm saying,
that's how it works for you. Your
voice does. I'm outside of that group.
My face is outside of
that group apparently.
So if you're interested in that
sort of thing, youtube boom.
Also got the excerpts on
there if you want. You know,
some of the lessons that chocolate talks
about, you know, you want to share them,
they're there,
they're condensed or actually they're
not condensed or just taken out it,
you know, made little videos on there. Um,
also enhance excerpts to put
some music on there. Make a more,
somebody asked for tracks,
enhanced excerpt tracks into
psychological warfare available on iTunes.
Let me, does that make sense? Yeah.
Enhance into an [inaudible] for too,
by the way. Yeah, I agree. Even a
lot of requests for things like that.
I agree,
but not from a personal
interest standpoint because
the psychological warfare
one is still very effective.
100% effective for me,
which I will talk about after I talk
about the fact that Jocko has a store.
It's called Jocko store Taco store.com.
This is where you can get the t shirts,
let's say discipline equals freedom,
like the one I'm wearing right now,
or the Jocko podcast shirt basic,
but very nice.
The one that Dave Burke is
wearing right now also missed.
Where are you telling me you got called
out with the Jocko podcast tee shirt.
Where was that?
I'm wearing this exact shirt.
I'm at Disneyworld with the
family two weeks ago from a cross.
The way I get a good evening echo,
that's the standard legit man
standard mode of is good evening echo.
Very good. Yeah, it looks
good on you. Of course.
And even if you want the
one that Jocko has on now,
the one that Jocko
always has on right now,
the one he has on right now and always
has done. You see what I'm saying? Anyway,
if you want that,
that shirt going Jocko store.com or if
you want a Hoodie or if you want a hat or
if you want to rash guard anyway,
just go in there. You can see,
you know if you want to support that way.
There's a lot of cool stuff on there.
If you want something, get something
that's called Jocko store.com also,
just like Jocko mentioned, psychological
warfare is an album with tracks.
Basically these tracks are each track.
You can get these on iTunes by the way.
So east track is Jocko telling you how
to get past certain weaknesses that you
might have,
might have on your
campaign against weakness.
So you know you're on the path, right?
We're working out, we're waking up early,
some of us, and you know we're
reading more of whatever we're doing.
Sometimes you don't want to do that.
You don't do that everyday.
You just don't feel like it on some days,
but you still should do it.
We all know that sometimes you don't feel
like it's who you're about to skip the
workout. Boom, you listened
to a certain track.
Duck will tell you why you should
skip the workout and it's effective.
You won't skip the workout. Take it
from me. I know 100% from experience.
It's what it is. Get it on
Itunes, check. You know.
Also speaking of subscribing,
I have another podcast now that's
called the warrior kid podcast.
Good one by the way. Yeah,
Uncle Jake has lessons.
The name of the podcast is where
you're going to ask uncle Jake.
Uncle Jake answers questions from little
warrior kids around the world and you
can get that, play it for your
kids. There's no foul language.
There's no talk about
the mee Lai massacre.
It's totally separate to your kids won't
get a stumble upon something that they
shouldn't be listening to that
they're not ready for yet.
So you can check that out.
Also,
Jocko white tea is available on Amazon
and if you're going to order it will then
go ahead and just go ahead and order
some more weights for your barbell too,
because you're gonna need them.
You need about 8,000 pounds worse and
that's a minimum guaranteed dead lift.
Also, there's cans of white tea coming
soon. They're gonna be here in June.
They're going to be available on
Amazon in June. Victory in a can. Yes,
certified organic. Never thought you'd
hear me say that now. Did Ya? Yeah.
Certified Organic.
There you go.
We're going to get rid of all the
horrible energy drinks that are out there
making people sick and we're going to
place it with Jock, Jocko white tea,
which is 8,000 pounds of pure power.
Let me ask you this about chocolate tea.
Would you consider making the microdose
or a version that doesn't have just a
micro dose of caffeine? If you
drink the F no, probably not.
No more caffeine. No. The,
the Jocko white tea can I think is two
servings and I think it's 30 grams total.
I'll confirm that. Yeah,
I shouldn't have said it.
Would you ever consider
making like another,
another version in the
future or anything like that?
It's something with more hype person
and more.
I don't know. I don't think so.
Okay. I don't think so. Cause um,
if you want more you can drink
more or go get something, you know,
something that's gonna make you
all jittery. That's fine. Uh,
books away the warrior kid series
to series of books. By the way,
there's two of them right now. There will
be more. I got to, I got an a note on
social media and it was
from an eight year old war.
Your kid named Addison and she wrote this,
dear Mr Willink,
I absolutely love your book
way of the Warrior Kid.
I think it's the best book ever.
You know what I'm saying? Uh,
it taught me about discipline
and commitment. Now,
every day I trained before school
and trust me, it helps a lot.
Your friend Addison. So there
you go. Listen to Addison,
pickup the way of the warrior
kid and pickup marks mission,
the second book so your kids can
get stronger, smarter, faster,
an overall.
And if you want to support a particular
warrior kid that's on the move,
making things happen,
go to Irish oaks ranch dot.
Come get some soap made by Aiden or your
kid or your kid with his own business.
He makes Jocko soap on his
farm so you can stay clean.
Don't forget about the discipline
equals freedom field manual.
I met a trooper up in Yosemite,
I was up in Yosemite. This was,
I guess it was last summer and you know,
we just started talking and I'm like, oh,
those are what you're doing up here.
And he was like,
I'm up here to get my mind right.
I was like, yeah, I don't know.
I got kind of fired up, you
know, get my mind right.
And that's the thing.
What's the thing that you,
that you kinda gotta do
sometimes get your mind right?
Discipline equals freedom field manual.
It'll help get your mind right.
They will help get your mind right.
Yeah. It'll help get your body right too.
By the way, if you get some of the
def core workouts going for sure. Uh,
if you want to listen to it instead of
read it or in addition to reading it,
you gotta get the audio version, not
audible books. It's not on there.
It's available on Amazon
music, iTunes, Google play,
other MP3 platforms.
Discipline equals freedom field manual.
Meditate on that. Also for
leadership, extreme ownership,
combat leadership for the battlefield,
for business and life.
And now you can order the follow
on book two extreme ownership.
It's called the dichotomy of leadership.
It's available for preorder on Amazon.
Barnes and noble. Local
bookstore. Hit him up.
It'll be out September 25th if you want
to get one of those first additions.
If you're a,
if you're a book person that's into the
books and you'd like to have that first
edition,
order it.
If you need backup with your team
from a leadership perspective,
whatever business you're in or whatever
leadership situation you're in,
you need some support.
You can contact my leadership and
management consulting company.
It's called echelon front.
It's me wave and JP Denelle.
Dave Burke is in the game.
The website is [inaudible] dot com
we solve problems through leadership.
That's it. That's how problems
get solved in any organization,
not some
whiz kid looking at a spreadsheet cure.
We'll assess those. That's not where
the problems are getting solved though.
We might identify a problem there.
The problem is leadership.
The problem in your organization
is leadership. We'll fix it.
That's what we do. Of
course, we've got the muster.
We're in DC right now for the muster.
Uh,
it's sold out and they all sell out.
There's one more monster in 2018
muster zero zero six in San Francisco.
October 17th and 18th you registered
extreme ownership.com. Like I said,
it is going to sell out.
If you want to come register now also
for current military law enforcement,
firefighters, paramedics,
other first responders.
We got the roll call zero zero one
September 21st in Dallas, Texas.
It's a one day one day leadership training
seminar that's specific to dynamic
and hostile environments.
Things like fires,
things like combat,
things like high speed pursuit Chase's,
that's what it's about.
You can register for that as well and had
extreme ownership.com and until we see
you at the muster, we're at the roll
call or at the immersion camp in Maine.
If you want to communicate
with us and hang out virtually,
you can find us on the interwebs.
What's yours, Dave? David,
our Burke Dave are and Burke.
Dave are,
Burke has your, the are on. There is your
Twitter handle, your Twitter call sign.
I might've snagged. Good deal, Dave,
just to make sure nobody else has.
I might've grabbed that nicely done.
Echo is at echocharles and I am at
Jocko Willink and to all the military
personnel out there
standing the global watch
for evil.
Thank you.
And to the families of those men and
women that are also serving and also
sacrificing. Thank you for what you
do to the first responders out there.
Police, law enforcement,
firefighters, paramedics.
Thanks for standing by
to get some at all times.
And also thanks to your families as well
and to everyone else that's out there
with
us facing whatever you're facing.
Life challenges, struggles, pain,
suffering on certainty.
Look at the past,
but could a guy like Tom Five,
look what he's been through,
see what men and women have gone through,
what they've been subjected to and
how over and over and over again,
we see human beings that rise
against and they overcome
to keep putting one foot
in front of the other.
Keep fighting to move forward
and keep getting after it.
Okay,
and until next time,
this is Dave,
an echo and Jocko out.