This is Jocko podcast number
one 76 with Echo Charles and me,
Jocko Willink. Good
Evening Echo. Good evening.
Usually when I write a letter it is very
much overdue and I make every effort to
get it away quickly.
This letter however is different.
It is a letter that I hoped you would
never receive as it is verification of
that terse black edge card
which you received some time
ago and which has caused
you so much grief.
Okay.
It is because of this grief that I wrote
this letter and by the time you have
finished reading it hope that it has done
some good and that I have not written
it in vain.
It is very difficult to write now
of future things in the past tense,
so I am returning to the present tomorrow.
We go into action
as yet we do not know
exactly what our job will be,
but no doubt they will be a dangerous
one in which many lives will be lost.
Mine may be one of those lives.
Well mom.
Okay.
I am not afraid to die.
I like this life.
Yes.
For the past two years have planned and
dreamed and mapped out a perfect future
for myself.
I would have liked that
future to materialize,
but it is not what I will
but what God wills. Then.
If by sacrificing all of this, I leave
the world slightly better than I found it,
I am perfectly willing
to make that sacrifice.
Don't get me wrong though, mom,
I am no flag waving patriot,
nor have I ever professed to be
England's a great little country.
The best there is.
Yeah,
but I cannot honestly and sincerely
say that it is worth fighting for,
nor can I fancy myself in the role
of a gallon crusader fighting for the
liberation of Europe.
It would be a nice thought,
but I would only be kidding myself.
No Mom,
my little world is centered
around you and includes dad,
everyone at home and my
friends and Wolverhampton
that is worth fighting
for and if by doing so,
it strengthens your security and improves
your lot in any way than it is worth
dying for to
now.
This is where I come to the of this letter
as I have already stated.
I am not afraid to die and in perfectly
willing to do so if by my doing so you
benefit in any way whatsoever.
If you do not,
then my sacrifice is all in vain.
Have you benefited mom
or have you cried and worried yourself?
Sick.
Okay.
I fear it is the ladder.
Don't you see mom that it will do me
no good and that in addition you are
undoing all the good
work I've tried to do.
Grief is hypocritical,
useless and unfair and does
neither you nor me and he'd good.
I want no flowers, no epitaph, no tears.
All I want is for you to
remember me and feel proud of me.
Then shall I rest in peace knowing
that I have done a good job.
Okay.
Death is nothing final or lasting. If it
were, there would be no point in living.
It is just a stage in everyone's life
to some,
it comes early to others late,
but it must come to everyone some sometime
then surely there is
no better way of dying
besides I've probably crammed
more enjoyment into my
21 years then some manage
to do in 80
my only regret is that I have not done as
much for you as I would've liked to do.
I loved your mom.
You were the best mother in the world
and what I failed to do in life I am
trying to make up for in death,
so please don't let me down, mom.
Don't worry or fret,
but smile.
Be Proud than satisfied.
I never had much money,
but what little I have is all yours.
Please don't be silly and sentimental
about it and don't try to spend it on me.
Spend it on yourself or the kiddies.
It will do some good that way.
Yeah.
Remember that where I am,
I am quite okay and providing,
I know that you are not grieving
over me shall be perfectly happy.
Well mom,
that is all,
and I hope I have not
written it all in vain.
Goodbye
and thanks for everything
your unworthy son
Ivoire
and
that was a letter from
private Igor Rowbury
who served in the British army
in the South Staffordshire Regiment and
the letter can be found in a book called
last letters home.
Okay.
And it was his last letter home.
He was killed
in og Nem on 17 September,
1944 and the opening action
of Operation Market Garden,
which was conceived and planned and
championed by Field Marshal Bernard
Montgomery
and this massive operation overall,
it's generally assessed as a failure,
although history has been kind in,
some people look back and fee rise that
it did have a more positive impact on
the battlefield then
was initially thought,
but nonetheless it didn't achieve,
achieve its objectives and there was
a significant amount of casualties.
And as I said,
this was Monty.
Yeah.
Montes plan is the plan that he pushed.
And as I said on the
last podcast about him,
this is one of the things
that makes him controversial,
that Qi lead this,
this operation market garden.
Okay.
And as I said on the last podcast,
he was able to redeem himself
somewhat in the battle of the bulge.
But this,
this negative was pretty impactful.
And with that,
that doesn't mean that there's nothing
we can learn from that situation.
We've covered it on the podcast, the,
that, that battle from that perspective.
And we have to learn,
we have to learn from people's successes
and people's failures just as we have
to learn from our own
successes in our own failures.
And on the last podcast we talked with
you about Monty's and view of leadership
and if you haven't listened
to that podcast yet,
it's number one 74 that kind of talks
a little bit more detail slightly about
Monte and his thoughts.
And we debated a little bit the
meaning of the word dominate,
which he kind of puts us one of these
driving forces as a leader. I was,
is the leader's ability to dominate.
And I talked about how,
I'm not quite sure where
he falls with that word,
you know, cause dominate can
have a very negative connotation.
And I actually asked for feedback in a
bunch of people, gave me feedback, and
I think I landed somewhere
kind of in the middle.
I don't think it's then dominate
with the, with the, Hey,
I'm just going to roll over my people.
I don't think that's how he meant it.
I think he, but I don't think he meant
it in like, Hey, I'm just dominate.
I dominate my skills
and that's why I'm good.
I think he meant it
somewhere in the middle. And
then I talked about the fact that one of
the other major important factors that
Monte talks about his morale,
and he wrote another little thing
about morale called morale and battle.
And I think, I actually wish I
would have covered this one first.
And this one almost trumps
the, the, the leadership,
his thoughts on leadership because I
think this is even more applicable and
relatable,
but it's,
it's good solid stuff from someone that
led to massive numbers of troops in
battle and saw a lot of war war in World
War One and World War Two obviously.
So with that morale in battle,
and we're going to jump right into it.
Here we go.
This paper is an attempt to analyze what
is at the root of morale and battle and
thereby to discover how
it can be developed.
High Morale is defined as endurance
and courage in supporting fatigue and
danger.
In other words,
the quality which makes men go forward
in an attack and hold their ground in
defense. It is the quality
without which no war can be one.
So this is, uh, this is, uh, uh,
and I'll get to this. In the end, he,
he talks about morale being the most
important factor on the battlefield.
Obviously I think leadership is the
most important thing on the battlefield,
and I'll break that
down a little bit later.
But from his perspective as a guy
that had led massive operations,
he feels morale is the
most important thing.
So without a doubt it is important.
Here we get into his thoughts on it, and
again, I think you're going to see this,
the stuff that he talks about,
morale, he seems to nail this,
I think even better than the
nails leadership. So here we go.
The quality of morality in war,
the moral stature of some men increases
and their characters grow stronger and
more close,
closely knit in proportion
to the discomforts and
dangers which they are called
upon to face.
Okay,
I said this over and over again.
War War can make you stronger.
War Can make a better person.
This is something that Peter t and I
talked about when he first came on the
podcast and we talked about families
that were slightly fractured and if they
have a, a major incident, a medical
emergency, somebody gets wounded,
somebody gets cancer. If the family's
close, it'll make them closer.
If the family's fractured, it'll blow them
apart. He's saying the same thing here.
Back to the book. Such men will
occasionally perform in battle.
Remarkable acts of selfless courage
and daring and will endure with
extraordinary fortitude and patience.
The burdens thrust upon them,
other men. However, we'll under
the stress of hardships or dangers,
surrender to fear or fatigue and will
allow their characters to disintegrate.
So it was the same thing that Peter
t was talking about with families,
and this is the same thing
with any team or organization.
You have a team that's pretty close
and they go through something rough.
They get even closer.
You have a team that's kind of fractured
and they go through something tough,
they're going to explode.
Same thing happens with people's
personalities and character in war.
This disintegration is usually,
we'll usually take the form of
a loosening of the moral fiber,
which results in timidity of
Action and slackness in appearance.
He talks a lot about appearance.
One of these guys in battle,
men who have kept a firm grip upon
themselves will appear clean and vital in
their appearance.
While those who have gone to seed will
be dirty and their appearance, we'll uh,
we'll be slovenly.
So he's one of those guys.
Okay.
If you don't look at,
and this is obviously this
is the much of the military,
they will judge you on how you look.
That's not always true.
Sometimes you get a guy that looks like
a rogue street person and he's a good
operator and sometimes not.
It depends.
Similarly,
timid officers will be found during quiet
periods in the line groveling in the
filth of some seller while they're
signalers and runners separated from the
light attempt to do their jobs by
the flame of a guttering candle.
And these latter cases,
there has been a general loosening of
the character due to a partial surrender
to fear.
So you get these timid officers that
are out there and they cower and they're
scared and they, while their troops
are up trying to do their job.
In extreme cases,
men who have become afraid have
sunk to the level of beasts,
no longer in full control of themselves.
They have become as sheep
or rabbits unable to act or
alone or think rationally.
Their instincts have
become those of the herd.
They are either paralyzed by fear
or gripped by unreasoning panic.
Such men are exceptions, but they are
a reminder of the value of high morale.
The good soldier,
the man with high morale has not
surrendered to fear and has maintained his
personal standards.
The bad soldier,
the man with low morale has
become incapable of dependent
action of independent
action and has to some extent shed
apart of his human individuality.
So this is what you get people at all
freaked out and they don't act for
themselves anymore.
There's going to fall to her.
Morale is a mental and moral quality.
It is a quality peculiar to human beings
because it is essentially the product
of a mind with a conscience.
Okay?
It is that which in battle keeps men up
on humanities level as opposed to being
a beast.
But humanities level's not high enough
because the strongest human instinct is
the instinct of survival.
Morale is also that which develops
man's latent hero wisdom so that he will
overcome his desire to take the
easy way out and surrender to fear.
Okay?
So you gotta be a little bit beyond
human because the human instinct,
the strongest human instinct is, I'm
just going to stay alive. That's my goal.
You gotta be, you gotta be more than
that. You gotta be better than that.
Okay?
It is necessary now to make
clear what high morale is not.
It is not contentment or satisfaction.
Bread for ease or comfort of living.
Okay.
Both of these container
hint of complacency and
acceptance of luxury as an end
in itself.
High morale is far more than any of these
for it implies essentially the ability
to triumph over discomforts and
dangerous and carry on with the job.
So if you're one of these leaders and
you're in a leadership position and you
think, well, you know, um, what,
how do I raise my, the morale of
my men? Give them luxury days,
give him feel.
Von Luxury days,
the o negative not happening
that that doesn't do it
back to the book. Nor is no because,
sorry, because what you have to do,
you have to give them challenge.
You have to give them discomfort or not.
You have to give them, they have to face
discomfort. They have to face danger.
And that's what increases morale when
they face nape. Triumph over that.
That's what, that's what
increases morale. A pizza.
Okay.
And find satin sheets
do not increase morale.
They might do a little surface nudge,
but they don't increase Rupp morale.
Otherwise your morale would be through
the roof, off through the rooms all day.
We'd sold it.
So the morale is so it's like not to be
confused because you do need like the
rest between six.
Right.
And it's different and you can't just beat
people down all through. Right, right.
You can't, you can't, you know, you have
to get sleep, you have to get rushed,
you have to have level of comfort
or your morale will get beat down.
But that can't be the primary aim of
you as leaders to provide comfort.
It's not like, Hey, let's boost morale by
letting people sleep or whatever. Right.
Or not letting them see, but you
know, yeah. Give him love. Give them,
give them two days off.
How about one day off and we come
back and train hard and work. Yeah.
It seems like you wouldn't,
you wouldn't give them the day off
if they don't need the day off.
Like you need the day off
for something very specific,
like some sort of a fatigue situation
or whatever. Bottom line is,
it's a dichotomy, right? Can you go too
far with comfort and pleasure and leisure?
Yes,
you can.
Can you go too far with discipline and
hardness and sternness and scarcity of
resources? Yes, you can. You have to
find a balance somewhere in the middle.
I think the point here is that
people lean towards, well,
if I want to increase morale,
I just need to give luxury to the troops.
That's the, that's the wrong way
to lean. You should actually lean,
I'm not saying go full bore,
but you should lean in the direction
of hard training, discipline,
lean in that direction.
Don't go full bore in that direction
and lean in that direction. Yeah.
It's almost like, I mean,
you'd think about it,
it seems like making them feel what?
Like empowered or strong, right leg.
That's kind of the result you're going to,
let me just break it. Break
it down for you. Real simple.
If you go and you have a good training,
Jujitsu, how do you feel when you're done?
How's your morale? Pretty
high. Morale is high.
If you sit there and watch TV all
day and you eat a pizza and a donut,
how do you feel at the end of
the day? How's your morale?
Shabby. Morales. Shabby.
You know, if you train Jujitsu nine
hours for 14 days straight. Yeah.
How do you feel broken down, right? And
then how do you feel when it's like,
hey man, day off today. Echo
all good. Hey, guess what?
I ordered some pizza for you too. It's
common. It's gonna be here in 15 minutes.
We're gonna chow down. We're
going to watch the fights. Cool.
That's a good morale boost.
We're all good. Yeah,
but you've got to find that balance.
Yeah. All right. Back to the book.
Nor is high morale achieved through
fitness or healthiness alone is important.
Not to confuse the idea of
physical happiness with morale.
The happy faces of men after a good
game of football are not necessarily the
faces of men with good morale. Morale is
a mental rather than a physical quality.
A determination to overcome obstacles
and instinct of instinct driving a man
forward against his own desires.
Oh,
driving a man forward against his
own desires. That's a good one.
That's a good one.
And he detaches the physical and the
mental part a little bit more than I do.
I think they're a little
bit more closely related.
I think that when you're in good physical
shape, it helps your mental morale.
But he goes on to say this,
which is spot on high
morale is not happiness.
Happiness may be a contributory factor
in the maintenance of morale over a long
period, but it is no more than
that. A man can be unhappy,
but can still regularly
and without complaining,
advanced and defend within the
terms of the definition. So that's,
so that's an important
thing. And again, this is a,
this is a trap that leaders
get suckered into. Hey,
if I can make my people happy
than morale's good. No, no pizza.
We'll make your people happy, but
it won't increase morale. Hmm.
It might increase morale if you can
give it at the right time for the right
reason. Do you eat Hawaiian Pizza? No.
Is that just a lie? That's a
complete violation. We don't even,
we don't even need that kind of pizza in
Hawaii, generally speaking. Correct. Well,
there you go. That's the thing. It's like
it's like Canadian making. What does,
what does Hawaiian Pizza
due to your morale?
Apparently its inhibitor.
Yeah. It's an inhibitor. Well,
you know like Canadian Bacon? Yes. Like
Canadians. Like, Hey, is this Canadian?
You know Canadian Bacon's just a little
piece of ham basically. Yeah. You go, hey,
someone from Canada and be like, Hey,
this is Canadian bacon. The lake. No,
that's him. Have you made
that up? Have you ever had an
English muffin before? Yes.
You can't get them in England
because they don't, yeah,
they just call him just like French
fries, right? Yeah. Or wait is in French.
In France. They're called
something else though. Chips.
They're now called French
fries. No, that's England.
I think they're called pawn.
All right, that makes sense.
Same deal then. All right.
This is an important other,
this again, you can see them.
I was in going through this to
figure out what I was going to,
what parts I was going to single out. I
ended up doing so much of this one. Yeah,
because almost every line is like,
yes, you need to know that. Yes,
I need to know that. I need to
remember that. So here's one.
High morale is not toughness.
This one caught me a little off guard.
Some very tough men in this war of turned
out to be very disappointing in action.
Toughness is a physical
and not a mental asset.
Tough men will occasionally perform an
isolated act of bravery. Morale however,
is not a quality which
produces a momentary act.
It influences behavior at all times.
So that's completely true.
And it's true and it's true in combat.
It's true. And training even like some,
somebody like going through what basic
seal training. There were some tough guys.
They're like tough where you go though.
That guy seems like a tough guy. Quitter.
And then, and then there's guys that
get through buds, it's like, oh,
they were toughing buds.
Like they did some good job in bonds,
but it has nothing to do with how
well you're going to do as a seal.
Like it does. It's, I would say
there's some correlation, but it's,
it's a very loose correlation.
Being a good seal buds trainee has very
little to do with being a good seal in a
seal team. And I think that sometimes
surprises people. But then again,
it shouldn't really surprise people
because being good at Budz Budz is,
is a physical evolution,
has very little to do with you,
with your mentality.
And it has very little to do with
leadership and unit cohesion.
And so to show up at a team,
what's the most important
thing when you get your team?
The most important thing when you get to
a team is to be a team member and be a
leader in that team or a follower in
that team. If you aren't those things,
you're not going to be good. You
can be super tough. That's great.
And there's times when it pays to be
tough and you definitely as a seal,
you can't not be, you can't not
have some level of toughness.
You know? When I think
about being a seal there,
stuff that you just do on a regular basis,
that when it's your life,
when it's just the way your life is,
you don't really think about it.
But when you take a step back and
you think about what you like,
when I think about my old job, and I'm
talking about going back to the 90s right?
Oh, we're going to go, we
have dive week, which is,
or dive training.
So you'd go for like four or five weeks
of dive training and you're diving two
times a day.
It's your wet suit,
your your you wetsuits wet
when you're putting it back on,
and then you're going to go get in a boat
and you're going to drive for an hour
and a half up the coast,
and then you're going to,
it's going to be dark and you're going
to put on your Drager rebreather and
you're going to get in that water again
and you're going to kick in the darkness
with bio luminescence flying around
you for three and a half hours.
You're going to get into this
random harbor, you're freezing cold.
You're going to plant.
I'll a limpid and fake limpet mine
on some big navy ships somewhere.
Then you're going to paddle your swim,
fin your way back out.
You're going to run out of oxygen.
Once you run out of oxygen are going
to come to the surface and then you're
going to swim on the surface
for another 48 minutes,
and then you meet up with that little
Zodiac boat. You get in, you're freezing,
you're exhausted,
and then you drive an hour and 20
minutes to get back to core auto.
When you get back,
you're going to debrief,
you're going to get take
care of your Zodiacs,
they're going to take
care of your dive regs.
Then you're going to take
care of your personal gear.
Then you're going to take a shower and
they're going to sleep for three hours
and you're going to wake up with
another dive mission. Tasking,
you're gonna do the same thing
again. Just cold, wet, miserable.
That's the life.
So do you got to have some
level of mental toughness?
Sure you do and every has got that.
But this part talking about like,
you know,
when you start talking about leadership
and being a team player and being a,
being a good leader and being a good
follower and being smart in tactically
sound and being a good decision makers,
those are the things that matter.
When you start talking about the
just the idea of being tough,
it's like that's cool and it's important
and everyone in the teams has that or
most people in the teams
have that baseline. Uh,
because it is a little bit challenging
too to make it through seal training.
If you don't at least have some level,
it does happen.
You get some guys where you think,
man, what happened to you or you know,
you just break down.
Some people have the idea that once they
get through seal training and they're
done, you know, you shouldn't be in seal
training to go through seal training.
You should be at seal training to,
to get to the seal teams,
to serve your country, to go into
combat, to take the fight to the enemy.
That's why you joined the seal teams,
not to see how tough you are.
So
next in brief,
high morale is a quality which is good
in itself and is Leighton and all men.
It maintains human dignity in an in
enables fear and fatigue to be overcome.
It is involved with the
idea of a conscience,
but it should be not confused with
fitness or happiness or toughness.
So he goes to pretty good
lengths to make that distinction.
Section two basic factors of morale.
It is now necessary to consider what
factors constitute the morale of the
soldier in the heat of battle.
Certain factors may be described as a
essential conditions without which high
morale cannot exist.
These four basic factors are one,
leadership to discipline.
Three,
comradeship for self respect,
a fifth factor,
devotion to cause must exist but need
need not necessarily influenced all of the
soldiers.
Finally,
there are numerous contributory factors
which are of great importance but not
essential conditions.
So that's what he's got.
The four things that you have to
have in order to have high morale.
And then the first factor of
course is leadership, which again,
he's supporting my argument
that leadership is the
most important thing on the
battlefield. If you don't have leadership,
you're not gonna have good morale.
So right there, I already got
you beat Mani. And guess what?
His second one is discipline. Where
does that come from? Leadership. Sure.
What about comradeship? That's comes with
all these things come from him. Anyways,
we'll get to that. Leadership. Morale is
in the first place based on leadership.
Good morale is impossible
without good leaders.
The quality of leadership is
one which must be studied.
Human beings are fundamentally alike
in in that very common characteristics
apply to all men in varying degrees in.
This is why such a great dichotomy of
humans is that all humans are the same and
all humans are different,
right? Like you know it's true.
How can that be true?
All humans are the same.
All humans are different and
that's a completely true statement
in battle. The most important of
these characteristics is fear.
All men are afraid at one time or another
and to a greater or lesser extent in
moments of fear,
they band together and look for guidance.
They seek for a person to give decisions.
They look for a leader in times of war.
The leader has opportunities denied
to him in peace. The difficulties,
dangers and discomforts,
inseparable from the battlefield make men
cry out for the leadership they can do
without in peace.
At such moments,
men are too weak to stand alone.
They find the burdens too great to bear
and their own selves unequal to the task.
The leader himself accepts the burdens
of others and by doing so earns their
greatest and the right or their
gratitude and the right to lead them.
So challenging times
things are going sideways,
bad things are happening.
That's when people are most
susceptible to leadership.
Hmm.
This is completely sure ever, ever seen
a team dynamic where like when everyone,
everything's going good
pretty much like you can get,
it might be hard to tell who the leader
is and then all of a sudden something
happens,
something that's chaotic or something
that's challenging happens and then you
can see that leader just rise to the top.
I've seen that a million times.
I seen that a million times in platoons
through training and how you kind of not
really knowing what's going
on, who's really good, who,
who's really running this.
Boom.
You start hitting these guys with some
down men and some IED in the training
battlefield. You'll see the real
leaders will start to step up.
Hopefully they will step up at
all, but, and this is totally true,
you see people want to be led,
people want to be led.
There's going to be sometimes a little
leadership vacuum and sometimes you got
to step in and fill that
leadership vacuum back to the book.
Consider a platoon I. E. 30 men
in action in the line. They,
the men are drawn from all
classes into all types.
They are there in the line because they
have obeyed a long series of orders,
which it was easier to obey than
to disobey, but now the test comes.
It is easier for them not to obey orders.
It is easier for them to stay where
they are behind the hail and not advance
over the crest into full view of the
enemy who lies in weight of beyond the
dominant motive force,
which drives them over
the hill is the leader.
It is his quality of leadership above
all things which inspires the men to
action. And this is one of those,
he paints that out very clearly.
You when people talk about,
well you know,
in the military of just does what you
said, cause you're in charge, right?
Oh we'll try that once everyone's
going to die. Well once you're,
you're lives are at stake.
People just don't Roger Up to say,
Oh that's hey echoes plans kind of
lame to go charge the machine gun nest,
but you know what? He's in charge. I'm
going to go do it. No, doesn't work.
You have to lead
these men recognizing their leaders,
some quality which they
themselves do not possess.
That quality is decision.
Fear makes men sluggish and indecisive,
unable to decide and act for themselves.
And this is,
this is, you know, people talk about, uh,
being frozen by fear or,
or have you ever had that thing where
you're quite sure what you're gonna do?
Like you, oh, well, I don't
know if I want to do this.
I don't know if I want to even like a,
like something stupid like a,
not something stupid, but you know, buying
a house, right? That's a big purchase.
You're going to lay down a bunch of money.
The market could go up or down.
You're committing to a
payment for 30 years.
There's not so many things in life
you commit to for 30 years. Basically.
There's only one other one.
You're getting married. Right?
Is there any other commitment?
That's 30 years, I guess.
You get a tattoo that's a lifetime,
right?
So there's these decisions that you
have to make and sometimes we don't.
Sometimes you see people don't
want to make decisions, right?
They don't want to make a decision.
What's making him indecisive
or you think about it,
what's making people indecisive is fear.
They're afraid of what that
outcome might break. Yeah.
So if you find yourself being indecisive,
instead of asking yourself,
is this the right decision
or wrong decision? Ask
Yourself, what am I afraid of?
Back to the book of the leader's power
over his men is based on his ability to
cut through this,
this fear paralysis,
and in doing so to enable
others to escape from it,
the rightness of the decision
taken by the leader is irrelevant.
Think about that from a
leadership perspective.
If there's a decision
that needs to be made,
whether you're right or
wrong is irrelevant. What you
need to do is be decisive.
What matters is that the decision should
be taken and that the leader should
shoulder the responsibility
for that decision.
The leader must convince
his men of its rightness,
even though he himself might be
maybe uncertain of his own judgment.
If the leader will decide, the men will
follow and fight. If there is indecision,
they will hesitate and flee
in short fight and survive
or fear and be slain.
The leader decides,
yeah,
moving on.
The leader's power of in of the leader's
power of decision results from his
ability to remain impersonable
in the crisis has calmness,
prevents panic,
and his resolution compels action.
It follows that this if falls from this,
that the leader must be
less fearful than his men.
He need not be impervious to fear. Since
men require a human figure to lead them,
what he must do is radiate
an atmosphere of confidence,
which will show his men that
he has less afraid than day.
He must have the moral courage to stand
firm when his men are wavering in this
respect, they will judge him by his
power of thought and action and crisis.
Fear destroys the faculty of
thought and Paralyzes Action.
The leader must continue to think longer
than his men and his thoughts must lead
to action. Oh, there you go. Don't panic.
Don't freak out. You got to stay
calm. And how do you do that?
You train for it and how do you,
and when you train for it,
what do you learn from the training?
You learn how to say, too detached.
That's what you learn how to do. That's
how you keep your emotions in check.
You don't let them get ahold of you.
The leader's greatest asset is the
ability to act normally in abnormal
conditions.
This is normal face 101 to continue to
think rationally when his men have ceased
to think to be decisive and action
when they are paralyzed by fear.
Okay,
so this is a,
that section is something you should
always strive to do from a leadership
perspective. Stay calm, don't panic.
Think about what's happening. He
didn't say it, but I'm going to say it.
Detach mentally so you don't get caught
up in the emotion and the fear and the
chaos.
Next,
the object of training must be firstly
to select those who possess within them.
The potentiality is of leadership and
second, to develop these pen potentiality.
So yes, you've got to look for
who's going to be a good leader
and then you've got a home.
That leader.
This is accomplished by giving
the leader responsibility. Boom.
My favorite cure for leadership problems
is put people in leadership positions.
A leader's character will
develop in proportion to the
responsibility with which
he has been in trusted. The more
responsibility you put on someone,
the more responsible they're going to
become. Think about the little kids,
right? Think about a little kid. The more
responsibility you give a little kid,
the more mature they're going to be,
the more responsibility
they're going to take. Yeah.
It starts with making your own peanut
butter and jelly sandwiches. Yup.
You should be doing that on your own.
As soon as it's physically possible,
you're going to make a mess. Guess what?
Then you learn to clean up the mess.
Every time you break down and you make
that PB and j for your little child,
you're taking responsibility away from
them and you're making them a weaker
human being and they
feel it and they feel it.
I made my, she's six, my daughter
[inaudible] set the table. You know,
they'll try to say yes at the table.
Yep. And she knew what it was,
but she hadn't really gone through
the whole deal before. So sure enough,
she's like, you know, she didn't
want to, but I'm like, hey, you know,
you set the table, this is
what you do. You know, you're,
you're kind of, you know,
this is your job,
this is your duty kind of thing.
So once she set like the first one yeah.
And she did it correctly,
she was rolling with it. It was her table.
She was like, Hey, I'm, I'm here. Boom.
She was making decisions. All this
donorship Oh, full lot being up. Oh yeah.
And you could tell just in her tone,
Kinda like she was super empowered.
Little six year old. Yeah. You know,
where and kind of to look on the whole
situation where this was someone who
didn't want to do it, didn't, it was
a chore. They want to do the chore,
but you know, you implement
it. You know what I mean?
In my case correctly. Do you give
them ownership? That's what you did.
Echo Charles.
You gave your daughter
your job. This is your responsibility. You
do. This is how you do it. But you do it.
You make it happen. That, and I use that
term a lot and make it up and it's weird.
I don't know what it is about that term
with my specific kids cause that's what
that feels good. Yeah. Like
you have influence over this
whole situation about it.
When you're a,
as a human being,
it's kind of weird that you
can make things happening
straight up. Right? Yup. Yup.
It's a positive thing. Yeah man.
And yeah, that's a good one.
Making it and make it up and
make it out. And you know, like,
cause and adults do this too. I do this,
we'll do this. Maybe you don't. I Dunno.
But you know how like if you
say, Hey, can you do this?
And then whether you don't want
to or you don't know how to,
you're just sketch about, you know, the
whole thing. You ask a lot of questions,
well what if this,
like people do that.
It's almost like they put a
bunch of excuses preloaded, yeah.
To indicate, hey, I can't really
do this, you know, kind of thing.
And it's almost like just maybe it's
like them being hesitant and maybe it's
everything, you know, all this thing.
So my kids will do that a lot, you know,
like all but well what is,
you know,
all these questions kind of thing
indicating they don't want to do it.
They want to throw up all this
smoke so you finally just go, Hey,
I'll do it or whatever. And I started
saying that, I was like, I don't know,
make it happen. And they just do it.
They just make it happen. It's all there.
I mean sure the job won't be the
greatest the first time kind of thing,
but they have that attitude of just
making it happen. You know, you ever,
you ever heard like the old guy
that's like when I was your age? Yeah.
Sometimes it's me. No, you just made
me think that cause I do that, Eh,
you know, I'll be like, when I was
your age, I wasn't a seal platoon.
Are you kidding me? That doesn't work
in my case. Did that ever work for you?
It does,
man will never work because you know
when one of my older kids that are my age
when I wasn't a seal
platoon, it's like, you know,
you're asking me how to do like some
such simple life thing or asking me to do
it for you. Like are you serious right
now? Are you serious right now? Yeah.
When I was your age, I was
in a seal platoon. I was
going on deployment overseas.
I had guns and radios and encryption
devices and you're telling me what you
know, whatever the thing is,
you can't make that happen.
Is that where you're at right now?
And then couldn't be what I was your age.
I always feel like when my dad or whatever
would say that and I feel like if I
say to my kid, they're going
to be thinking like it's
not cool. It's not. It's,
it's,
I'm actually saying this,
putting myself like in a little bit of
check we talked about last time, you know,
you can't just be like, well, when
I was, yeah, no, you need to be,
I need to do a better job.
But it is good.
The thing is it is good
to cause the way my,
there'd be usually my older
daughter because my oldest daughter,
cause she's the one that
actually is of age when I was in,
she actually takes it in a,
in a positive way.
Like she'll have a look on her face.
Like I am actually being like really,
really dumb right now
to be even asking this.
Like I can obviously figure this thing
out. Whatever it is. You know some,
you know the DMV.
How do you set an appointment at the DMV?
Are you serious right now? Are you
serious right now? Make it happen.
You can't figure that out. You'd never
heard of something called Google.
Think of how easy things are now. But you
can't even do that. No, not happening.
I wasn't, uh, I wasn't damn seal
platoon when I was your age.
I was responsible for stuff.
They were telling me,
you can't figure out how to
set an appointment at the
DMV. Are you kidding me?
This is what I think is the hypothesis.
I think that you saying enough
like stuff to your older daughter.
In this case where she can relate,
where resonate,
like I get what you're saying and yes,
I think that once you see what
always drew Joe's in a seal platoon,
she goes perp, she checks out. No,
that's what I need to be careful of.
That's what I need to be careful of.
The other thing I'll get from my kids,
which is more your, you know your, you
will you, you know what I mean? They,
they kind of, yeah. I'm not
like, well that's of course
you did that. And I'm like,
no, no you did not true.
It's not just like,
oh I did that because I'm more
squared away than you are. No,
you're actually more
capable than I ever was,
but doesn't need to step up your game. I
know and hit, and this is my whole point.
The thing is, you're correct with
what you're saying. You're crying,
but from the kids' standpoint,
they don't believe that. Like mine,
if my dad would tell me that kind
of stuff, I'd be like, yeah I can.
I literally think that's it.
Cause you're,
you not to say that you're tougher or your
whatever. It's like bright, you're you,
you lived in the caveman days,
leave me alone about like figuring,
but then if you're like, hey,
go make the DMV appointment,
go and Google figure it out kind of thing
that, that relates to them. I was like,
yeah, he's right. Yeah. And if she's
a grownup essentially, you know,
she's going to choose to read when
my son was like 10 years old. Yeah.
And in my son's a good surfer and I was
out surfing with them and watching them
surf and I said, you know, he was
paddling. I just caught a wave,
like beautiful wave and he's
paddling out and I said,
in a little while you're going to
be a better surfer than I what I am.
And I thought he'd say, oh, that's cool.
He looked at me like I was completely
insane and like, it was the craziest,
like it'd be like he,
you could see in his eyes,
he thought that that was not a cumin Lee
possible thing that would ever happen.
I mean, imagine that. Like that's
the look in his face and he kinda,
he kinda just completely shrugged it off.
I was like, yeah, right. Yeah. And I mean,
six months later he was better than me
and now he's just like infinitely better
than me. But to your point, when you know,
when you're looking up at dad,
then sometimes it's,
this is an unachievable thing.
Yeah. And actually that's not true.
And the young kids got to recognize that
they can outperform their lame parents
if they put their mind to it. Yeah.
And same thing that happens with
subordinates, right? You
have your subordinate on
your team and you think, hey,
you have more skill than I ever had.
You have more talent than I ever had.
If you apply it correctly,
you will be able to outperform
me without question.
And sometimes people look at you like,
oh, you're crazy. That could never happen.
It's like, no, it can happen. It
can happen. But you got to train.
That's another thing is people
think, oh, well, you just,
this is natural. No, no, no.
Oh No. Oh yeah. The on the other
thing, you know, I mean that's why,
that's another thing like when
we, when I was on with, um,
when we had captain plumb and Jim Lawn
and they were like throwing me in the
basket of being like them and
I'm like, hey guys, this is all,
just check yourselves.
I'm 47 years old and I'm barely hanging
on to like figuring this stuff out.
I'm not in the about in the game with you
guys in terms of figuring out what you
all have figured out. I mean, those
guys are leaps and bounds and,
and iteration upon iteration
of knowledge above me and,
and I'm just sitting there thinking,
take it easy. Captain Plumb. Yeah.
But again, that's just kind of a,
a matter of perspective. You know,
like things can seem so much
like they can seem like a very,
something very specific, but just
because of your perspective, you know,
you don't get a whole picture, you
know, you know? Yeah. All right. Check.
Going back to the book.
His position as the man responsible for
the lives and wellbeing of his men must
be impressed upon him
in battle is preop his preoccupation
with his men's affairs.
We'll give him less time
to think of his own fears.
The mere fact of responsibility
will increase the leaders
powers of decision and
make him confident of his
ability to handle any crisis.
So you've got to train people
in these challenging situations.
Training must also seek to equip the
leader with the other qualities which will
help him in his task. Here are those
qualities. A leader should be efficient.
He should possess self confidence.
He should be firm,
and just in his dealings with his men,
he should be clear cut and
definite in giving orders.
He should pay attention
to administrative details.
He should prepare his men and advanced
for any new experience they may have to
meet.
All these things are important,
but they can never be a substitute for
a decision in action and be calmness in
crisis.
Yeah, stay calm. Now,
one thing that I get a little nervous
about talking about decision and action is
sometimes what that means,
whether the way that translates to a young
platoon leader is not going to make a
decision right now. Hey,
everyone, you know a bone,
I'm going to jump into it and you can't
do that. You have to do assessment.
You have to look at what the
situation's going and actually you know,
you've got to have a protocol
of how you're going to make
those decisions, right?
You've got to think about way
the way it's going to go down.
You can't just jump at the first
thing that pops into your mind.
You need to think about it.
You need to think about the options.
You need to think about the
consequences of those options,
and then you need to see if you can
move in the right direction without full
commitment, right? Do you
have to occasionally make
full commitment on decision?
Yes.
If you're,
if you've got ambushed and
you're in the kill zone,
guess what? You're going to have
to do assault through the ambush.
That's what you're going to have to do it.
You're going to have to do it decisively
and powerfully and with full a hundred
percent commitment,
but if you take some rounds but
you're not sure if it's an ambush,
well, you might not want to necessarily
assault through that position,
so you need to think. You need to allow
things to develop a zoo. It's a very,
it's part of the art
of leadership was teaching
young seal leaders. Okay,
you need to let the situation develop.
Here's the problem.
Once the situation starts developing, if
you let it develop too far, it's gone.
It's out of control now, right? It's, it's
a, it's a little, it's a little problem,
right?
When you look at it,
then you need to look at the problem and
make sure you understand the problem.
Meanwhile,
the problem in some cases is growing.
If you allow the problem to grow too
much now you can't control the problem
anymore and you're going to get
crushed by the problem. If you,
if you see a small problem and you
jumped right into solving the problem,
that might,
the problem might not be what you thought
it was and you went out at the wrong
direction.
So there's a fine line like
decision and action is important,
but thoughtful decision is what
it should be. Thoughtful decision.
And the reason I'd keep trying to stress
and articulate to people that you don't
necessarily need to make a
full commitment to a plan.
You can take them,
you can take a smaller step,
an iterative step in the right
direction before you just jump in.
So that's just important to think about.
How does all that compare to making
no decision? We'll make no decisions.
The worst thing you can do,
right?
Make no decision standing
there in the kill zone,
getting overrun by the
enemy and everyone killed.
That's the worst thing you can do.
We want to at least make some
kind of a decision. Yeah.
So that's why I think he stresses.
So the importance of decision inaction
so much is because he's probably seen
people be indecisive and battle and
it's a horrible, horrible thing.
So yes, you want to be decisive, but
let's take that one little step further.
We want to have fought full decisions.
Do we want to have a mental 20
minute debate over the decision? No.
A thought can take five seconds.
You can let it sit.
You can let us situation develop for for
eight seconds and you go, wait a second.
I think this is what's happening. Let me
confirm. Do I see anyone over there? Uh,
Yup. What did the enemy fire
is increasing. You know what?
We need to make this move. Boom. You do
it. That's what we're talking about. Yeah.
Back to the book.
These are two vital attributes of a
leader with which he will succeed and
without which he will fail.
These two vital quality vital qualities
exist in varying degrees in every leader.
Those men who possess them to a limited
extent can nevertheless become adequate
leaders by being trained in the
quality's already a numerated.
Such leaders must in the
first place be efficient.
This efficiency will impress itself on
the men thereby creating an atmosphere of
confidence with which will partially
compensate for any lack of personality.
By this means training can make men into
competent but not outstanding leaders.
Okay.
There's another aspect of leadership
in its relation to morale.
The best type of leader earns
the respectful admiration
of his men because he
possesses certain good
qualities which they lack.
A brutal leader who disregards
the feelings of his men
will not infuse them with
the quality of self respect,
the morale of the troops.
He commands regardless of his qualities
as leader will not be the highest.
So even Monte who kind
of comes across as being,
you know, aloof to the
troops. He's, there you go.
The brutal leader is not going to
have good morale. Hmm. Factually
an element of self respect,
self respect.
There's a whole section on self
respect that's coming. Yeah. But yes,
if you have a dog and you beat
the dog and your a brutal leader,
the dog will not have any self confidence.
It'll be a broken dog.
You can do that with human beings too.
Yeah.
If you bark at your people and
you break them down all the time,
they won't be able to stand up.
Another way to do that in a more lower,
or should I say less brutal way,
is to do everything for him for sure.
Same thing meant no easy myself. Like
yeah, if you're setting the
table all the time, yeah.
Your daughter never realizes that
she has the capability of doing that,
handling that job.
She's tying shoes,
carrying backpacks, like all that,
you know, everything. It's like man,
if you're helping your kids,
you're hurting your kids. Yeah.
And it's, yeah. And that clarifies it
even more and it's so true. I mean,
once you kind of latch on to that idea,
you just see it everywhere. Like men,
you ever see these kids? Like, I dunno,
like a TV show or documentary type,
whether in,
I don't know,
somewhere in Asia or some village where
the four year old girl goes and kills a
snake, skins it and then walks like
in the mud for another mile back home,
cooks it for their family, you know, like
any like, Dang, that girl's for. Yeah.
And she can do like, I can't even do that
stuff, you know, kind of thing. It's a man
can put it into perspective where it's
like these are kids who are just like
making it happen.
I'm beings are so adaptable.
Like you see the little gymnast kids,
they're six years old,
iron cross,
there's crazy do an athletic
feats that are just insane.
And why is that? Well, because they
were put in that position. Yeah.
And and train hard now some of those,
some of that,
sometimes those kids trained a little
bit too hard I think. So they lose,
they can lose other aspects of their life.
But Dang,
if you wouldn't like to be able to do
an iron cross when I was six years old,
come on now. Yeah, the point still
told you remains. Yes, exactly right.
So let your kids develop and
let your subordinates develop.
Give them responsibility, build
them up back to the book. Moreover,
it is important to realize that while
men are dependent on the word of the
leader,
they are capable of much
independent action on their
own and are even capable of
making their own decisions. So this is
kind of, this is kind of funny, right?
It's Monte basically saying, look,
I've got a little surprise for you.
We'll surprise your troops. Can
actually think for themselves. Yeah.
Imagine that. And so obviously this is,
this is decentralized command, right?
This is it. And you have to
let your subordinate leaders
lead. He goes on to say,
British soldiers have much native
character in individuality.
What is required is that the leader shall
give the initial and vital decisions
along with which the men can work.
So yes,
and you know what?
This is actually,
I'm glad that glad that money said
it and that kind of funny way.
It's the same thing that we're talking
about with kids where you think, oh,
well my kids probably not
capable of doing that.
Your kid is capable of doing that.
Your kid can go out there and kill a
snake and bring it back and skin it and
cook it. You just have
to allow them the, the,
the room to, to let that happen
and give them the authority.
Empowered them to do it. Yeah. Yeah.
Fully in that.
It's so night and day to the
other actually last night. Oh,
I wasn't making chicken. Yeah, making
chicken and I usually make rice in Hawaii,
make rice with everything anyway, so
I'm like, okay, make the Eggo. Hey,
I tell my daughter she's six again. By
the way, I was like, hey, make the rice.
Here's the thing. I showed her how
to make rice maker Rice isn't hard,
but it's not like, I mean
in most some steps. Yeah,
there's some stuff for sure it
and it wasn't, well for me anyway,
before I taught her how to make rice,
it wasn't real obvious that a six year
old should be making rice, you know,
like not in a rice cooker too, by the
way. Just like on the stove regular. Um,
but I thought at that point I was like,
hey,
why can't I just show her how and teacher
how even if I don't teach her in one
day, okay. The next time we make rice,
which is just going to be soon, I'll,
we'll go over it again kind of thing.
Why should she not know
how to make rice right now?
Why should I have to do this for her
or whatever. Anyway, I teach her,
I tell her to make her rice super simple.
Boom.
Last night was the first time where
it was her responsibility to make rice.
She makes rice six years old,
makes rice boom boom. But you know what?
Our current in the right direction.
Exactly right. That's the point
is too is that you as a leader,
as leaders, the same thing. You let
your let your guys run the operation,
let your troops step up and take
control of something that you and your
egotistical maniac mind think only
your people do it. Guess what?
Your boys can get it done too.
And if they,
if they bat of 88 instead
of a hundred cool,
next time they're going to get
a 92 and then I'm after that,
they're going to get a 96 yeah.
Cause that's a big obstacle to right.
Mentally it's kind of like sure I could
teach him how to do it, but why would I?
Well yeah, you see that, you see that even
more. Is he in parenting? It's like, cool,
my kid couldn't make the rice but in,
in a team environment,
our ego,
our ego flares up because we
want to be the one. Right. Yeah.
Especially if you can do it at a 10 yeah.
Guys only do at an eight at the end of
the day and your job is done and you feel,
you feel like that's your little power.
You know, that's my little power.
It's like well you know, you really
know how to do is I'm going to come to,
I better come down and
check out how your bag,
you're prepping this stuff cause you know,
you know I'm kind of the man your
yacht, that's where it is. Yeah.
Kind of like when you like let's say
they had to like screw on some stuff or
okay I used to work at a moving company.
Right.
You know this and at the end you load
up the crates and you put them on the
truck and you have to tie in
with a certain kind of not right.
You learn how to tie that. Not the
kind that's super tight, but you,
all you gotta do is pull one string
together. Yeah. Cool little thing.
So I learned how right and yeah, one of
the the supervisor or whatever he Blake,
yeah, go tie it off or whatever
and I could totally do it.
We've been doing this for
a or whatever and then,
but he'll go and he'll
check in and he'll like,
and then he'll pull it just
a little bit more, you know,
like as it's be like the little signature
on it, a signature from the mass.
He would just say what you're doing
right there. But we do that all the time.
We like to have our own little
rice bowls. Tika Rice, right? Sure.
That's a weird term. But you've heard
that term before, right? Like it, hey,
you want somebody messing with his rice
bowl? Meaning like this is mine. Like, Oh,
I'm the guy that does this part of the
job and I don't want anyone else to know
how to do it. That's my little rice
ball. Stay out of my rice bowl.
There's a lot of rice bowls. I was
never into that. Well at least,
at least once I was actually in leadership
positions, I was very, I'm, I'm not,
I don't care. Like, oh,
you're good. You come on,
come on and grab some of this rights.
Because if you can,
if you can take my rice ball
from me, guess what? I can
go find another rice bowl.
I'll bring it in here and we'll start.
We'll have more rice. That's good man.
Because it's not as intuitive,
you know? Everyone thinks that.
Everyone thinks that they're, everyone
leans towards, Hey, I want to be the guy.
Yeah.
The ego flares up
back to the book. Good morale
can be created in a narrow
sphere by a good leader,
but a platoon or company has obviously
influenced by the general feelings
existing in a division or army. So
now we're talking, so you got multiple
layers, multiple layers above the platoon
or the company. You've got the army,
you know the division.
Good morale implies confidence in the
high command and in the plan and he
capitalized plan the plan.
A strong leader on a high level can
have a powerful influence on the general
attitude of the men. Have a
platoon. He cannot, however,
influence their movements over the last
flute, few vital yards of an attack.
On the other hand,
a strong leader on the low level can make
as men carry out a single fine attack,
but he cannot sustain
their morale indefinitely.
If there is a lack of confidence in
the high command and it's planned,
that's a challenge.
It's a challenge if your troops,
if your troops are looking at the strategy
going, what the hell are we doing?
Like you can get the guys through
one attack or two, three missions,
but eventually they were saying, hey,
what's going on? Why are we doing this?
This doesn't make any
sense and vice versa.
A leader cannot do without discipline.
Okay.
You were thinking about when I
say discipline on the podcast,
you should put some little,
every time I say it,
especially when I say something like this,
a leader cannot do without discipline,
is aim must be to create such a discipline
body of men that all his orders will
be obeyed instantly.
This habit of obeying leaders,
orders must be so instilled into his
men that they will carry on and fight,
even though he himself falls.
There's a problem with for that
statement right there, right?
The aim, this aim cannot be
achieved without discipline.
The second factor of morale is discipline.
So a couple things here. First of all,
I don't want my team to instantly
obey all my borders without question.
If I tell them to do something stupid,
I actually want them to tell me no.
On top of that,
if you think for one minute that
all your people do is obey you,
that when you die,
they're just going to suddenly sprout
leadership skills and start leading.
You're wrong.
You have to.
You have to raise them in a way and
treat them in a way that they are being
challenged as leaders themselves,
and they're being allowed to lead in.
They're stepping up and leading it,
and they're not waiting to instantly obey
everything you do. Because if you're,
if all you're doing is waiting for orders,
you're not being proactive.
You're not leading.
Decentralized Command isn't happening.
And if something happens to me,
you're going to freeze.
So this little section from Monte,
no,
I don't like it.
Discipline is something that is important.
You have to understand that
you have to have discipline,
standard operating procedures.
You have to have discipline to
stay within those procedures.
But on top of that you have to have the,
the freedom to when those procedures
aren't working to say, hey boss,
this isn't a good, here's what
we should do instead. Hmm. Now
does this mean you and I are going to
have a debate in the middle of a firefight
over what the plan is? No, because we
work together. We trust each other.
You know what I'm coming from,
I know where you're coming from and when
I make a call you're going to do it.
And by the way, if you make a call,
even though I'm senior to you,
if you make a call, guess what I'm going
to do? Get someone to do follow. Yes,
I'm going to follow you if you
like. Hey Jocko, punch. Right?
Get ready to fight these guys.
And I'm the senior guy.
But you just told me to do that. Guess
what I'm gonna do. I'm gonna do it.
I'm gonna support you. So
that's, that's what you want.
Um, you, you have to be
careful because as people,
if you have someone who's personality
is sensitive to that, yeah.
Right? And you say, Hey
Jocko, to try give, give them,
get on their flank. And my
response is, excuse me a minute,
just heard, do you think you are
actually, I'm in charge of this platoon.
Why don't you just lock it up?
We're not going to punch. Right.
And we're actually gonna move.
You know what I mean?
That's what we can get into
that situation all day long.
Guess what's going to happen to all of us?
We're all going to die.
So we have to figure that stuff out.
We have to figure out that,
that we have to work together.
But at the end,
one of us has to submit to the situation
to submit to the other person's
leadership. And by the way, there's 16
people in a platoon. In a seal platoon,
there's 30 or 40 in an infantry platoon,
it's pretty easy to get in the habit
of like, Hey, when the boss speaks,
we're all gonna submit
to what he's saying. Oh,
if the one of my platoon sergeant speaks,
okay,
well he barks out something,
guess what? We'll submit to that.
Occasionally someone else will rise
up and see something. We have to,
we have to work and train together so
that we know when we need to submit to
someone else or when we, or when
we need to say, hey, negative,
we're not doing that. We're
going over here. These are,
these are challenging things,
right?
It's think of how easy for
think of how easy it is to,
to have the Monte attitude and be really
easy for me to say right now. Like, Hey,
listen, this is what happens.
You'd have to have your men.
So discipline when you tell them
to do something, they do it.
That's the easiest solution,
right? That, okay, great.
Talk was put out the word, oh,
by the way, if I get hurt, fall the guy
that's in the second chain of command.
Okay, cool. That's easy.
That's an easy day.
Right now we're going to win every time.
No wrong cause guess what?
Occasionally me,
I'm the leader.
I'm going to make a bad decision
and somebody needs to check me.
Now are you gonna check me every
single time? No you're not.
Are you going to check
me? He, you know what?
We're going to work together so much
that if you think you know what,
I'm not sure jock was
making the right call,
but at least I'm going
to start to execute it.
I'm going to keep a heads up on to move
forward and then if I see what I think
might be a problem happening,
I'm going to say something,
but my response out of the
gate is we're going to go.
That's the kind of thing
that's going on here.
This is a dynamic environment
interacting of human beings.
It's freaking challenging,
but to blanket everyone when I tell
you to do something, you do it. Yeah.
I want instant obedience to
everything that I say. Again,
that works great.
94% of the time,
6% of the time it's an utter disaster.
And everyone dies.
So we don't want to allow for that. We
want to allow some flexibility in there.
That is harder to do.
It's harder to have that flexibility.
It's much more challenging,
but it gives you such better capability
and survivability that that's how you
want to set it up. It takes
a lot more. That's why.
That's why the more advanced you get in,
the more tactically advanced you get,
the more there is of that.
So if you go to a marine corps,
infantry platoon,
they're going to have
less pushback and less,
they're going to have more obedience,
more just straight wrote obedience
as they should. Because guess what,
an 18 year old marine,
it doesn't have as much knowledge as a
25 year old staff sergeant like aura or
the platoon commander that went to the
basic school and he's right. So there's,
you're going to have these situations
that are going to was so in a,
in a normal infantry platoon,
there's going to be less pushback.
You get into a seal platoon, well now
you've got a bunch of experience guys.
Just about everyone there has a few pumps.
The new guys aren't going to say anything,
but the guys with two or three platoons,
they're going to say, hey, boss,
not a good call. Or they're going
to give you some pushback. Why?
Because you've got a more
experienced fueled of people,
so it takes more practice to get that,
to get to be able to interact together
properly and have that flowing chain of
command that's docile and and can and
can't expand and contract and can move
from one person to the next dynamically
as a mission is happening. I mean,
there's times in in close quarters
combat where basically there's a,
there's a person at the front of the train
and that person rotates out every few
seconds.
There's tactical situations where there's
a new person making the calls every 10
seconds. Think about that.
That's tough. That's radical.
To have a new person making a
call every 10 or 15 seconds,
there's a new person doing it. How do
you do that? Well, they understand.
Everyone understands.
They understand the tactics,
they understand how we work together.
That's what we want.
As opposed to there's only one
person that can make the call.
That's just centralized
command. So again, it's very,
it's hard for me to, to, to uh,
throw this out there, right?
Cause I don't want an 18 year old
marine thinking whoa unified funnel.
Like what the platoon commander says.
I'm just going to tell them no,
that's not what I'm saying. Not what
I'm saying. I do want you to think,
yeah, I do want you as an
18 year old marine to think,
I want you to be understanding what
decisions being made to the best of your
ability.
And yes,
if you see something happening that is
absolutely not good and you know it,
you're damn right.
You should speak up and your platoon
commanders should be happy that you're
speaking up.
But if you're a guy that's going to
speak up every time a decision gets made
because you think maybe
of a different way,
that might be a little
bit better in your mind,
you're going to suffer the
consequences of number one,
the whole platoon being indecisive.
And number two,
your boss going to tell you to shut up,
cause your,
your idea that might be
8% better than his idea.
We don't have time to
discuss that right now,
so unless you see something
that's real significant, yeah,
shut up and do what you're told. If you
see something that's really significant,
okay. Hey, boss, negative.
Can't do that. There you go.
Okay.
The second factor,
discipline.
The object of disciplines is
the conquest of fear press.
This is new perspective for me that the
reason we have discipline is to conquer
fear. It's interesting, right?
Factually true to what is it that gets
you to do that thing that you're afraid
of? You have the discipline
to just drive through it
adequately to determine the best method
of doing this requires an analysis of
fear to be made.
There are two aspects of fear.
Fear can suddenly attack a
man through his imagination.
A corpse in a ditch or a grave by the
side of the road will remind him of the
peril of his position.
He will suddenly realize that he
himself is liable to be killed.
It is a function of discipline to fortify
the mine so that so that it becomes
reconciled to unpleasant sites and accepts
them as normal everyday occurrences.
Fear can also creep in upon a man
during periods of monotony in the line.
So this is the other type of
fear. There's two types, right?
The one that just jumps on
you and the other one is,
is creeps on you at such a time.
He will have the opportunity to appreciate
the dangers which pacet his life.
Fear acting through his thoughts can so
reduce a man's hard core of courage that
he will become nervous and fearful.
Discipline strengthens the mind so that
it becomes impervious to the corroding
influence of fear.
It teaches men to confine their
thoughts within certain definite limits.
Kate instills the habit of self control.
Keep your emotions in check, keep your
fear and check that requires discipline.
The basis of fear is the
awareness of danger in itself.
This is healthy
for a man who is aware of danger,
automatically take steps
to provide against it.
It is only when fear dominates the mind
that it becomes unhealthy and leads to
panic. So fear is good. We
know that fear is healthy.
We know that until you let it dominate
your mind and then it's a problem.
Men must be urged to fight
fear with courage so that
they will advance or defend
and not take refuge in fight
and flight or inaction.
Man Becomes aware of when
man becomes aware of danger,
when he feels himself opposed to
something more powerful than himself.
Right?
Man Becomes aware of danger when he
feels himself opposed to something more
powerful than himself.
In other words,
when he feels that his own armor min is
unequal to that of the enemy who oppose
him,
it is important for a man to lose his
individual feeling and to become an
integral part of the battalion,
division and army to which he belongs.
The larger the unit of which he feels
himself to be a member of the larger will
be the estimation of his own armament
and the less will be his fear.
It is here that discipline shows its value
for it can help a man to lose his own
identity and become a part of a larger,
stronger unit.
It is in this way that
discipline will conquer fear.
Got to relate to that bigger group.
You see this in like gang fights,
the one person by themselves as a coward,
but then when they have 10
of their friends, all of a
sudden they're courageous.
It's a horrible example, but it's a
reality, right? It's a total reality.
Yeah.
I used to see that in the streets,
the street back in the day,
like, yeah. You know, like
one person, myself included,
you know, your two or three of us. Okay,
we're a little bit, we got a little, uh,
we got a little, a little froggy, right?
But when there's 18 of us, all of a sudden
you're real tough, right? That's me.
When I was 15 years old, oh, I'm super
tough with all my friends. Right?
Bad. It's a bad example, but it's the
reality and I liked it. Big scraps.
This corporate sense,
which discipline creates,
helps men face the unknown.
At night.
Men in the line become
afraid of the unknown,
which stretches out in front
of them at all times in action.
They are afraid of new and terrifying
weapons which may be used against them.
They realize that these unknown
quantities may bring danger to them.
Their ability to face these dangerous
is immensely strengthened by feeling
themselves to be part of a group.
The group is known and a certain quantity
which they feel is strong enough to
stand up to the unknown,
dangerous with surround them in numbers.
The method by which the conquest of fear
is achieved is the unifying of men into
a group or unit under obedience to orders.
So he rolls right back to
obedience to orders. Monte does,
and part of the reason is he's talking
about conscripts a lot. Draftees,
not volunteers. So there's a
little bit of uh, that's what,
that's what he's dealing with now,
as we know from hack and from
General Mooka Yama like, Hey,
if you treat your people right,
doesn't matter that the draftees
men required to be United if they are to
give of their best discipline seeks to
instill into all ranks a sense of unity
by compelling them to obey orders as one
man.
This obedience to orders
is the indispensable
condition of good discipline.
Men Learn to gain confidence and
encouragement from doing the same thing as
their fellows. They drive and
satisfaction from their company,
their own identities become
merged into the larger,
stronger identity of the unit.
You know what's interesting is I'll go,
I'll even go a little bit more
hardcore against Monte. Uh,
you know what to me is an exceptional
unit is the unit where you don't even have
to give orders where you just,
where everyone knows what the intent is.
Or you give them a lay of looks like,
hey,
this is the intent and people to do what
they're supposed to do with no orders.
Yeah. That's what you really
want. You know, there's, uh,
a chapter that Lafe wrote where he's
talking about prioritize and execute and
he's talking about how it's when one
of our guys fell through the roof,
they were on a mission.
They were an Overwatch.
They ended up having to conquer a
sledge hammer through a concrete wall.
And Lafe and I were talking about,
he's like writing the chapter and he
was going to talk about like what his
priorities were and how he told the guys
like, you know you do this, you do this.
And he's like, yeah, well the thing is
I didn't tell anyone to do anything.
And I was like, yeah, check.
Cause his guys knew, oh wait,
we've got this going on,
we're going to set security, we're going
to move like the, everyone knows what.
That's what you want. And then what that
allowed life to do is I think about,
okay now bigger priorities and
that's what he wrote about.
But your troops,
they shouldn't,
you shouldn't even have to give them
orders because they should be trained well
enough to respond based on the situation
and knowing and understanding the
standard operating procedures and
knowing very quickly what it is that your
intent is as the leader.
So all you need to say is set security
and the guys get into position where
they're supposed to go. That's how
it should be. I'm not looking for,
I'm not looking for obedience.
You know what I'm looking for.
I'm looking for what we used
to call thinking shooters.
You know, I want a platoon
full of thinking shooters,
meaning that they're thinking for
themselves, they're making things happen.
They understand what
it is that I want done,
whether I said it to them or whether
we pre-brief did or whether we've been
through this, we've
drilled it, but whatever.
They know what it is that I want done
and I want my team to be thinking this is
decentralized command. When you get into
just wrote obedience, we're losing the,
the aspect of decentralized command.
And as Monte said earlier,
believe it or not,
your man might be able to make some
decisions on their own. It's like, yes,
take that a lot, many, many
steps further than that
chick
continuing on.
Men must learn to obey orders
when all their instincts cry out.
For them not to be obeyed.
They must learn to obey orders in times
of stress so that they will do so in
times of danger. They must learn to carry
out their tasks under any condition.
And despite all difficulties in this way,
mass of loose individuals with their fears
and weaknesses can be welded together
into a United whole ready to
act on the word of the leader.
So again,
what I'm saying is I don't want them
ready to act on the word of the leader.
I want them ready to act
on the fault of the leader.
Yeah.
Discipline helps men to display fortitude
in the face of fatigue and discomfort
while at the same time it
helps them conquer fear.
It enables them uncomplainingly to
triumph over difficulties which would have
overcome them in times of peace.
This constancy in enduring hardship and
fatigue is the quality which is most
frequently required of a soldier,
individual fortitude and corporate courage
or the twin products of discipline.
So there we get.
That's the,
that's the just straight positive aspects
of discipline that, that I think of,
hey, things are going to be, we're gonna
be tired. Whatever, discomfort, whatever,
fear, whatever. We have discipline,
discipline, cockers, all those things.
Discipline implies a conception of duty.
Nothing will be accomplished in the
crisis of by man without a sense of duty.
The century in and outpost holds his
ground in the face of an attack because he
has a sense of duty to those behind him.
This sense is instilled by discipline
because it teaches men to obey orders as a
matter of course,
to know that it is wrong not to obey them
and right that it is their duty to do
so
for the soldier.
This conception of duty does not embrace
abstractions such as freedom or empire
or democracy in battle.
A soldier's sense of duty extends only
to the friends who are around him and is
the job of the junior leader to
encourage this sense of duty.
Abstractions are the
sphere of a politician,
so he goes real extreme in this one
and we all have heard this before. Hey,
when you're in combat, you're not
fighting for this political ideology.
You're fighting for the man to your
left and your right. Absolutely true,
absolutely true. I would say, well,
I know that it's not just
that you have to you you at.
When, when the immediate battles
over, you need to look and say, okay,
well why are we doing this?
Oh, we're doing this because
we believe in our cause.
So to me it's both. You can't just
cast out, you know, in my opinion,
abstractions are the
sphere of politicians.
No troops need to believe
in what they're doing.
A certain type of training may induce
men to go forward in an attack simply out
of fear of the consequences of not doing.
So.
This applies only to the weakest and most
feeble of men who are of little value
in battle. This type of training
is an essential part of discipline,
but it's never be misty to
be mistaken for the hole.
So he kind of goes one way and
then the other it's like, yeah,
sometimes you're just going to have to,
you have to make people do what you want
to do because they're afraid of you or
they're afraid of the consequences.
If you have to lead through fear,
if you, if you, if you,
if your team is doing
something only because they're
afraid of the consequences,
that's a losing battle. Yell.
It's a losing the war, right?
You might win the battle,
but you're not going to win the war.
Continuing on the type of training
mentioned in the preceding paragraph,
which implies a certain harshness
and hardness has its value.
Material comforts are now so insidious
that there is some danger that this is
the old fashioned idea of disciplined
and it will be allowed to disappear.
This must not happen.
Soldiers will not win battles if
their training has not been hard.
That's a little less than
for your entire life.
Soldiers will not win battles if
their training has not been hard.
The softening influences of civilian
life must be replaced by the exacting
demands of military training.
Yeah.
Soldiers must forget the pleasures of
peace and concentrate on the realities of
war.
Isn't it funny that this,
this could be written right now
and some of the WHO, you know,
training is getting easier and all that
and tech that we always think that got
to keep it hard.
He always get,
always get to fight against the
slippery slope of things. Getting easier
in brief discipline seeks to conquer
fear by welding men into a cohesive whole
unit. United by obedience to orders. Yeah.
Okay.
No, I'm not with you. Money.
It aims to create a body strong enough
to carry each of its members through
dangers and difficulties which they
themselves would be unable to face alone.
In this way, it promotes comradeship,
which is the third factor of morale. Okay?
I much more important in my opinion
than the blind obedience of orders.
Morale,
so we're talking about comradeship now.
Morale cannot be good and less men have
come unless men come to have affection
for each other.
A fellow feeling must grow up,
which will result in a spirit
of comradeship and army
is made up of human beings
so that however much at leader
may inspire as men, however,
perfect the discipline,
morale will be hard and unsympathetic.
Okay?
If the warmth of comradeship
is not added to it, war,
the hard business is not
necessarily a grim one.
Men Muscle Laugh and joke together must
enjoy each other's company and must get
fun out of life even in times of danger.
Check this spirit of comradeship must
begin at the section or tank crew level
and work its way upward to army level.
The importance of encouraging men to band
together and identify themselves with
their units has already been emphasized.
This will be necessary to
make considerable efforts
to further this spirit of
comradeship.
Junior commanders must plan to create
this spirit in the same way they plan to
train their men and fire their weapons.
Men must not be moved from unit to unit
or even from platoon to platoon unless
there's good reason for doing it and these
reasons must be made clear to the men.
A man who has served among friends in
the same platoon for a long time will be
helped by them to face the trials
a battle he will feel around him.
His reserves of courage and
purpose upon which he can draw.
There will be a feeling of solidarity and
out of this feeling there were grow up,
a determination to advance together and
defend together and even die together
in wartime. With such heavy casualties
and constant reinforcements,
it is always found that comp,
this comradeship can be built up most
quickly by ensuring that new arrivals as
reinforcements belonged to the part of
Britain from which the unit is originally
drawn. And to which it belongs
in peacetime. So that's what, uh,
you've got to have your team join
together. And then he's saying, look,
if you've got new
reinforcements coming in,
and they came from Darbyshire and
there is a unit from Barbara shirts,
sent them to go work with
the guys from Darbyshire.
They already have a connection.
Comradeship is,
and you know who didn't do that?
The Soviets,
the Soviet Union was famous for not doing
that because they didn't want there to
be a really strong unity in the,
in the forces because then
that unity might turn into,
you know, a movement. So they
didn't want that. They would,
they would notoriously split everyone up.
You would never be with a guy
from your home town, you know,
they'd split everyone up.
This is the opposite of that.
Comradeship is based
on affection and trust,
which between them produce an atmosphere
of mutual goodwill and feeling of
interdependence.
Men Learn to have faith in each other
and to depend on each other according to
the abilities of each in a tank
crew, gun team, or infantry section.
Men do not work well together merely
because they are disciplined and well led.
They do so because they trust each other
and because they are bound together by
an affection which has never
expressed in words, but shown itself.
Indeed's comradeship is a great antidote
to fear because it gives a man friends,
a man must take friends.
A man must make friends in his platoon,
friends whom he respects
and admires in battle.
These friends will prevent
him from feeling lonely.
A man alone is a man who will find it
hard to stand up to the dangers of the
line.
A man alone is a man afraid if
he has to be. If he has friends,
he will derive strength from their
presence and he will be anxious not to let
them down in battle.
You will seek to do his fair share of
all tasks which come to his crew or
section. He will feel ashamed if he cannot
assist his friends in their duties and
maintain his place with them.
In the line, all men have,
uh, within them. A touch of, of streak,
of generosity and unselfishness,
a touch of nobility and these qualities
will be brought out in the attitude to
their friends. Friendship Causes Men's
to Gi causes men to give their best.
So you know what,
I guess we started talking about
this a little bit in the beginning.
If you're not, if you don't
want to be a part of the team,
you are going to miss this whole section
of what makes a unit to have high
morale.
If we're not friends
that hurts our morale.
So you know, they have these,
these things and the uh,
the rangers do a really good job of it.
You can peer someone out,
meaning we as peers can,
can look at someone that we don't like
or that doesn't want to be a part of the
team and we can get rid of them.
So it's called peering someone out.
We don't really the, there's not an
official system in the seal teams.
Like you can do it, but it's like,
it's a little bit case by case.
So in the in ranger school,
and forgive me Rangers if I don't
get this a hundred percent right,
but basically you have to rank your,
you have to rank everyone in your patrol.
So you've got 20 guys in your patrol,
you ranked, this guy was number one,
meaning performance wise,
this guy was number one,
this guy was number 20 if you're number
20 like a multiple times in a row,
three times zero or something,
they kick you out.
So what we have to do is we have to
work together as a team and say, okay,
you know what? It's my turn to be the
last guy. So put me as number 20 okay.
Jocularity from to put you in 20 okay,
cool. Next time it's going to be echo.
Next time it's going to be built,
next time it's going to be Mike.
So that way we all want to stay.
What we have to do is we have to
coordinate work together to rank ourselves
accordingly.
So it's real easy if none of us like
echo three lazy just to put echo at the
bottom three patrols in a row and
you're gone in the basic seal training,
we don't really have a system like that.
It takes a little bit more,
you have to be a little bit more proactive
because it's not just an existing
thing. Uh, we did have a,
my seal training class,
we had one guy that we basically
peered out, like my officers,
you know, got feedback from everyone
and said this guys shouldn't be here.
And they went up to the instructors
and the instructors got rid of him.
So it happens. But it doesn't
happen in a quite that official way.
And the only reason it wasn't performance
and was like, Hey, this guy doesn't,
for lack of a better word,
and this doesn't sound real good in this
politically correct world that we live
in now you get someone that
doesn't fit in. Yeah. Right.
Like this guy just doesn't fit in.
Cool.
We're going to get rid of him because we
don't want to have someone on the team
that's not, that doesn't want to be
part of the team. Yeah. And believe me,
this happens very seldom.
Like you've gotta be a real,
you've got to fit in in a real bit,
not fitting in a real big way to
stand out in a, with a crowd of seals.
There's all kinds of different
guys. Yeah. So can I heard,
it seems like anyway
that you could do that.
Like in a roommate situation
it'd be less official.
Like you're talking about a system. What?
That it's sort official, like you said,
hey, the ranger like, yeah, like
you say, Hey, let's just wait.
What's the ranking based on, on the
ranger thing? Well, they're saying, hey,
echo did a great job on this patrol.
I rank it was in the number
one guy on this patrol.
Jocko was number 16 so he's number 16 and,
and bill was horrible
and he's number 20 right.
You do that every patrol you go on.
So wait till it,
let's say that we weren't gonna
phase anybody out or pour or,
so they went out and what we would
do is we would just rotate. Hey, I'm,
I'm the bottom guy this time. Okay. Echo.
You wouldn't really perform at the bottom
necessarily. Oh, just on the record.
You have to force rank everyone and so
you rank k we're just going to rotate
who's the bottom one. So none of us get
it eliminated. Gotcha. And then, yeah,
yeah, it's weird. I thought what
you meant by peer someone out,
which kind of might even be the same
thing in a way where let's say you have
three roommates are full of
say four roommates and they
were like, hey this guy,
he's not fitting in and he
snores or I don't know, whatever.
And you know how roommates we're friends
typically right when you room with
someone.
Um,
and then after a while you just sorta
like not invite that one friend all the
time and sort of peer, I'm
out peer, I'm out like, yeah,
like just more than anything.
I mean in a nutshell.
Basically you just make his experience
with the group just a little less
enjoyable.
So he sorta on his own just sorts of phase
himself out and find some new friends.
Yeah. You know, just slowly,
just naturally kind of thing
where you're just like,
hey bro, where peer and you
out. Don't tell him. I mean,
I guess you could break, you know
when you break up with your friend,
you ever had to do that? Where you going
to be late? I'm a dude. No, no, no.
Not breaking up with Kitson expression.
It's an expression like where you know
how you ever had a friend who's like,
they want to be your friend
and everything, but man,
being friends with this person has just
kind of too much every day you read that.
First of all,
I don't have a lot of people that want
to be friends with me and I don't have a
lot of the long list anyways, so I really
haven't had that APP Bruh. It like,
I dunno,
like if your friend,
every time you go somewhere with them
he gets in arguments with people or gets
in fights or, or like,
I don't know, you know,
the kind of guy is he is just too much
token friend with and you've got to break
up with him or he just calls you
too much. Oh, neat. You know,
like that kind of friend anyway.
Sometimes you guys don't have a lot of,
this is making me feel real lonely
over here. I don't have it does. Maybe.
Maybe you're the one who that phased out.
I got phased out across the
board over the past 47 years.
Phased out. Could be red.
You're too intense. You're
too intense with your point,
Jocko. He's going to be all
fired up for this. Yeah,
we can't drink around him because
that's weird how people think.
They can't drink around you.
Some people do,
but no, no. I'm pretty mellow
about it. You know something.
She tried to get peered out over
here a year or two later. Anybody.
You're peered out. But there's some people
I think feel internally guilty. Right.
So they don't want me around because they
know like, oh well, um, I want to get,
I want to do horrible things
tonight to my body. Right.
And if I have Jocko having to
feel guilty about it. Yeah. Yeah. It
might be judged or that's what it is.
I think they think, oh, judging. Always
judging. It's funny cause I'm, I'm, I'm,
I'm saying that sarcastically. I
kind of really don't care. Yeah.
I don't think you've even
indicated that you cared,
like not even in a little bit. Yeah.
Little Way. It's funny. Yeah. And,
and actually I think,
I don't like to indicate,
because then the person might
tighten their track up a little bit,
then they're going to be like tougher
to deal with on the maths of justice.
The whole plans. I mean,
I'm bringing donuts Bro.
Today I have some of these work out.
So yes,
I think it's a good system that the,
that the rangers have it. And I'm,
like I said,
we have an unofficial methodology and
certainly once you get it to a seal team,
there's the same thing can happen.
Right.
You get a guy that just doesn't quote
unquote fit in and that's a real thing.
And like I said,
it's a real broad spectrum.
Like there's very few people that I know
that I know or that I've saw got peered
out.
I don't think I ever,
I think we might appeared out one guy
in like my second or third platoon,
we actually had a guy that was just like,
yeah, you really just don't belong here.
And you know, the idea
was like, hey, we need to,
and what'll happen is the noodle probably
get some safety violations, which is,
by the way, what, what will,
one of the reasons why a guy's
going to get paired out. Like, Hey,
this guy just doesn't, can't
keep it together in the
house. You know what I mean?
That's not good. We don't want them
here. So yeah, you don't want you,
because I think it's because it's not
like anyone not like anyone that says,
well you know,
comradeship is a real important part of
morale and morale is very important on
the battlefield. We never said that,
but you feel it an opportunity.
You've got some guy that just doesn't
fit in. Yeah, I can see how that can be,
especially with you guys in
the teams where it matters.
It matters like way more, you know?
It's not like you're, you know, at the,
in my case as a mover, you're going
little cruise, you know, and it's like,
man, it's just way less
at stake, you know,
being like a coat or a bit less
and stay a little bit different.
But yeah. So it makes sense
man. It totally does. Yeah,
it's end again.
I don't want people freaking out,
but I will say this.
What was it?
I was going to college when I was going
to college and I was out of the seal
teams for a little while and
this one of my professors was,
you know, like, you know, it must be
so nice to just be going to college.
And I'm like, no, it's hell. I want to go
back to the teams immediately right now,
this minute, because in this professor's
mind, you know, she's thinking, oh gosh,
think of how wonderful this must be ta
here and being educated and learning and
expanding your brain and you don't have
to do all that hard military stuff with
guns. And meanwhile, I'm
literally the exact opposite.
I don't want to do a knee thing at
college and I want to go back to the teams
immediately. And I said, no, I w I,
if I could go back right now, I would
immediately give me an f and every class,
if they let me go back and still be
but still be in the teams, I'd do it.
And she goes, why is it that you liked
so much about it? And I said, well,
everyone kind of like me.
You know,
you're hanging around with a bunch of
guys that are kind of like you. Not Exact,
but like they have the same mindset.
They laugh at the same jokes. There's,
they have the, you know, it's like
just a bunch of similar type of people,
which of course that's who you
want to hang around with it.
You want to hang around with a bunch of
people that are the opposite of you. Now.
You're not hanging around with like,
hey this person's nothing.
This person is different than me that,
oh, I don't want to hear their input. No,
I actually,
I like getting different people's input
but there's a nice kind of solid base of
like,
Hey,
you're a team guy on the team guy and
we kind of have the same kind of just
broad life perspective and that's nice
to have and it doesn't really matter
where you came from because in the teams
you get all kinds of people from all
kinds of different backgrounds,
right? You get guys from Hawaii,
you get guys from the, from the
ghetto, you get guys from the farm,
you get guys from the city,
you get guys for you guys from everywhere.
And yet all those differences
are like surface differences.
But the core dude, it's pretty much
like this dude. You know what I mean?
Like we're all pretty similar.
It doesn't matter what, you know,
kind of how you grew up or what race you
are or what religion you are. It's like,
oh yeah, disfigured. He's a team guy.
So we, we kind of get it. I kinda,
I know what you're thinking
and you know what I'm thinking.
And that's kind of cool to be around.
And that is part of comradeship and
that is part of what makes a unit tight.
And when there's an person that doesn't,
then that's,
that's problematic and
it's not just problematic.
It's problematic for the
team starts to hurt morale.
Yeah. It's weird. Not Weird,
but in football it's the same thing
but it's not the whole team though.
People gather in positions like
the wide receiver, in my case,
all the wide receivers, same deal.
They all come from different places.
Hawaii guys, mainland guys,
different part, you know,
just saw such different people.
But for some reason there are,
they all just sort of
gravitate towards each other.
You know when you go to the
cafeteria or wherever you go,
like in football camp you see,
you can tell a lot by where people sit
there on the Caterpillar's. Yay. Yeah,
the quarterbacks.
I'll sit over there behind benders and
it's so interesting given this concept
that you're talking about where you
would think most of the people from a
certain area,
maybe a certain race would gather together
and there is some of that for sure.
But for the most part it's, it's
sorts of sorts itself out by position.
It's like you see sort of the linemen and
kind of go over there and you know the
receivers are kind of like over here.
Yeah.
And it doesn't matter like w there
where they come from or their little
background or whatever because there's
this underlying interest that they all
sort of share
know core,
like a core part of their personality.
That's the same and that's
I guess the key thing here.
Get that core part of your personality
that's the same and some fundamental
characteristics of the good team guy. You
know, like there's a fundamental like,
hey, this guy is going to work hard. Hey,
this guy's going to take care of his gear,
is going to take care of the platoon.
Gary's going to knock it out,
not looking out for himself.
That's it's like a real,
the real problem.
Like if you're a yeah, you don't want to
be that guy. And so if you have those,
you know, then it doesn't
really matter what you're like.
Whatever you layer on top of that,
it's fine, it's fine. No one cares,
no one cares. Check. Next section.
The fourth factor is self respect.
No Man can be said to possess high
morale if the quality of self respect is
lacking, soldiers must be encouraged to
respect themselves at all times under all
conditions.
This quality is involved with those of
discipline and comradeship to such an
extent that it is perhaps wrong and
certainly difficult to separate them,
but no man will have high morale who
does not possess a greater quality,
greater and wider than
comradeship and discipline.
Self respect implies a determination to
maintain personal standards of behavior.
A man who respects himself will neither
allow himself to become slovenly nor his
quarters dirty, right? This is this,
this is the root of, you
know, the stereotypical,
uh,
adult saying to the kid,
don't you have any self perspective? How
could you walk around looking like that?
How could you wear that? How could you
grow your hair like that? How could you,
you know, like all those things, how
could you live in this pig sty, right?
It's all those things
boil down to self respect.
Even in action,
he will take care to see that his
personal appearance suffers as little as
possible. Montes, a bit
of a friction eastern,
I think representing that baret
that's Monte.
It is the job of the NCO to
maintain this aspect of discipline.
It is the function of the officer to
encourage and instill self respect.
So once again, who's, who's
instilling self respect?
It's the leaders and how do they do that?
So the little things that
we just talked about,
I believe you instill self respect by
doing things you just talked about,
which is giving people responsibility,
letting them figure out jobs themselves,
letting them do things.
Here's how Monte wants to do it.
The officer must've ruthlessly insist
on maintenance of personal standards.
And then he says this, this is why you
gotta. You know, Montes coming off hard,
but here we go. At the same time, however,
he must let his men understand that
he appreciates and respects them.
As human beings,
soldiers must be treated with
humanity and controlled by discipline.
So there's a, there's a balance in
his dichotomy here, right treat,
treat them good, but controlling
by discipline, but treat them good.
So he's got a dichotomy here.
If the officer does this,
he will gain the respect of his
mandarin at the same time he gives them
self-respect. Efficiency is
inseparable from self respect.
The sense of a good job,
well done, have a hard task.
Assessed with the accomplished
is indispensable to good morale.
Men must take pride in their ability
to carry out all jobs allotted to them.
They must feel that they are good soldiers
and therefore a value to other people.
That's a good little, good little
thing to sprinkle in. Especially kids,
right? Yeah. Like making you ever
been around kids that have been told,
you know, that they're worthless
their whole lives. Like that's not,
it's a horrible sight. And what do they
not have? They don't have self respect.
Men can be persuaded of
this fact by being trusted.
A man who feels he is trusted,
will feel that he's efficient and will
you will at once begin to respect myself.
This is like critical
leaders. I mean subordinates,
kids, either one. When you
start giving them that trust,
like your daughter's not old enough, but
eventually you're gonna be saying, Hey,
you're gonna stay at home.
I'm gonna be gone for about a half
an hour going to the store. Right.
And she's going to like
stand up a little straighter.
Cause it's like all of a sudden that's a
big deal. Right? That's a big deal. Yeah.
And that same thing happens with
your subordinates. Hey listen,
I'm going to be gone for a little bit.
Hold down the fort. Yeah, you got this,
they stand up a little bit straighter.
Their self respect increases
when you give them trust.
Yeah.
A man who feels he's trusted,
a man who feel he's in trusted will
feel that he is efficient and he will at
once begin to respect himself.
He will have confidence in his own
ability to fight men who are trusted,
gain self confidence.
It is the job of the officer to
convince his men that he trusts them.
So once again, it's a leadership
scenario, but it's so true.
Oh, I remember learning to drive
my dad. That's a big one. Oh yeah.
So He um,
he first he taught,
we learned on a manual transmission.
Yeah.
Are there any manual transmission
studies? Hardly. Huh. Um,
and it was a truck too, which is, it's
just harder. I mean, in my experience,
the one that we learned on,
it wasn't that easy to do yet.
And so we learned how to just do it,
you know,
just use the manual transmission
for a second, third, fourth and um,
but still not necessarily
driving like on the streets.
So the first time he told me to drive,
like on the streets,
I knew how to do the shift and all that.
He just jumped in the um,
okay,
passenger seat and he put, you
know, put me any suggested,
take us there and we're going to, you
know, where the store or whatever.
And he was just like, take us there.
It wasn't the kind of like, okay,
now what you want to do is do you
know, he, well it was nothing. It was,
he just said straight up take us there.
And I felt that,
I felt that like drives are now,
you know, and uh, Wayne and yeah,
a little bit nerve wracking,
but men way more confident than I would
done being if you would've been like,
okay, be sure to check your mail, check
your mirrors. Okay. Easy. You know,
like that kind of stuff.
None of that. He just said,
take us there. Yep. Boom. I took
us there. It was good. I liked it.
You know, dropping knowledge. Then
check self-respect as a quality which
will develop inevitably if the three
essential factors already
considered our presence.
It is true to say that without self
respect, good morale is impossible,
is equally true. To say that
if the standards of leadership,
discipline and comradeship are high,
the quality of self
respect will also be high.
So this all boils down to leadership.
Additional factor,
devotion to a cause.
It is impossible to make a d is
impossible to make devotion to a cause,
either a basic or contributory
factor to good morale.
It must stand by itself
between these two categories.
It is important to clear the mind of
some misconceptions connected with the
influence of a cause in shaping morale.
Men do not fight primarily for a cause.
They do not have,
they do not advance over dangerous ground
in pursuit of an ideal they not now
fight as crusaders may have done long ago.
They fight because they
are ordered to do so.
And they do it well or badly according
to the strength of various factors which
have already been considered. So yeah,
this is one that I'm,
again, I'm not really,
I'm not really down to down
with Monte on this thing.
I think if you've got troops that are new,
have no idea why they're fighting
and they're not fighting for a cause,
you're going to have a breakdown.
You know you're gonna have a breakdown
in your units. As a matter of fact,
he kinda said that. He said it
earlier, he said if you don't have,
remember this,
if you don't have respect for the plan
and this and the higher leadership,
well that's what it causes is it
causes like we have a plan, we have,
we are higher leadership. Who's that?
That's the leaders of our country.
That's the highest leadership.
So if you don't,
if you don't believe in that then
you're going to have a problem.
And then he says this and this again,
this is a little arrogance
coming from coming from Monte.
This is not so in the case of leaders,
some men fight some fight for
the same reason as the men,
the more intelligent because they have
cause they add heart believe in what they
fight for. Such leaders are using
the best in the army and wheel.
The greatest influence thus numerically
cause is of little importance.
But it is a powerful factor because the
leaders are greatly influenced by it.
So he's basically
saying, listen, you know,
the senior leaders have an
understanding of the cause,
and so whereas the men are just
fighting because they're ordered.
So he literally says that I had, come
on Bro, that's not, that's, that's,
that doesn't work. That doesn't work in
America. And you know, you talk like,
look at that,
that letter I read from the beginning.
That's kind of why I wanted
to read that letter as a con,
as a contradiction to
this. And as an, I mean,
what he says in that letter is like,
look,
I'm not fighting for the great of England.
He says that,
but he's fighting for the cause that
causes security for his family. Right.
So people aren't thinking about
that. You don't, you don't,
you don't say,
I'm willing to die just because some
random dude ordered me to do it. No.
You have to have a connection to something
greater than that. Otherwise you're,
you're suicidal, right? Yeah. Yeah.
I remember saving private Ryan when
he said that he, there's a movie. Yes,
he threw Tom Hanks. Right.
He, uh, he was like,
I don't know who Ryan, you know, they got
to save private. Right. Obviously. And um,
there at this part where they're kind
of questioning things, you know, guys,
morale is breaking down and you know,
things happen.
And what he says in part of
his speech was like, Hey,
I don't know who private Ryan is.
I don't know him.
So I basically questioning that
particular cause. But he said,
but if going and rescuing him earns
me the right to get back to my family,
then that's my mission. So same deal,
same deal as the letter rates that he has.
He had his caught soy. Yeah. And that
was the one who was fighting for,
yeah, back to the book. Nevertheless,
nothing which has been stated here
must be interpreted as minimizing the
influence of cause on those officers and
men who are moved by it. So then he, he,
he brings it back a little bit for these
few cause we'll be a sustaining and
strengthening factor in maybe of greater
importance to them than any of the
other four factors.
There are times when a few men will
be gripped by a cause and will perform
astonishing deeds of
heroism to further it.
Such men do not require the ordinary
bonds of discipline which unite and
strength and others, their devotion to
the cause is in itself all sufficient.
Nor do they require the same kind
of leader that has been described.
They themselves will all be leaders.
Such men may be properly described as
guerrilla or irregular for fighters
fanatically devoted to a political,
religious or national ideal.
They must not be confused with conscript
soldiers to whom this paper applies.
So there you go. I mean in America, if
you know we have all volunteer. Yeah,
but I'm telling you even it
doesn't matter if you've got it,
you've people have to understand there
has to be some kind of a deeper causes to
what you're doing or else you're
going to have real problems. Sure.
You can order people if they're constructs
and you can punish them if they don't
do what you're going to tell.
If they don't do what you tell them to do,
you can punish them.
That is a way,
but that is not going to be
a successful way. You know?
That is not going to be the ideal way.
And by way,
if you're not using the ideal way,
you may win.
But if you're going against somebody
that is using the ideal way,
that has a cause that they
believe in and on top of that,
because they have all these
other things, the the, the,
the group that has a real cause
will win every single time.
Now there's some other contributory
factors that he brings up here.
One is success. This is a real
obvious one. Success, high morale is,
is possible in defeat, but not during a
long period of defeat. On such occasions,
confidence in leaders will never be Wayne.
And the first basis will be undermined
to success will aid good morale by
creating confidence in the
leader and the in the command.
This factor requires no enlargement.
Uh,
next one is regimental tradition.
Regimental Spirit can be a powerful
factor in making for a good morale.
The more a soldier feels himself
to be identified with his regiment,
the higher will be his morale.
If the four essential conditions have
been fulfilled, it must be realized.
However,
that not only that there can be a
good morale without strong regimental
feelings,
but that regiments with a great tradition
do not necessarily always produce good
battalions.
So the the tradition,
which there's some units that have
awesome traditions and you know,
we'll being with some of those,
some of those units overseas,
I mean the first of the five
oh six obviously comes to,
comes to light and their,
their tradition,
the hundred and first airborne tradition
was so thick there that pride was in
every soldier that, that war, that,
that ace of spades at that spade
on their gear. I was like, yeah,
there's pride there.
There's tradition,
but he's saying it's not going
to replace these other things,
but it is a factor that
you can use another factor.
Again, contributory
factor, personal happiness.
A man should be happy in the sense that
his personal life should be in order.
Nothing weakens a man more than
trouble at home. It encouraging,
it encourages him to think
of home and all that.
It implies when he should
be occupied with the enemy.
It turns his mind to peace and his
desire to live at the moment when it is
necessary for him to steel himself
to face the possibility of death.
He must never be allowed to forget
that it is his job to fight.
The function is to kill
the enemy and in doing so,
he must expose himself to danger.
Anything which weakens his will to fight
and expose himself must be considered
to lower his morale.
A soldier is only a family man.
After he is a soldier,
he must look forward at the
enemy and not back towards home.
Hmm. Some realism to that. Definitely.
I think it can go either way.
I think there's times where people can
be driven to success by their family back
home. Maybe by thinking of
their family with just kidding.
You can definitely become a
distraction depending on the situation.
Yeah. It seems like when
there's a lot of risk involved,
it'll be a district is a distraction
maybe.
I think it depends on the individual.
I think it depends on the circumstances.
I think what may be
better to look,
whether it's a distraction,
not as is like what's going on at home.
That's what's more important.
If there's disruption at
home, that's a problem, right?
If you've got a guy that's overseas and
is, there's problems in the family life,
that's, that's wrong,
that's going to hurt.
Yeah. Yeah. It's weird
cause like at w, you know,
guys at work sometimes
anyway, sometimes, um,
you know, they, it's something
bad can be going on at home.
Then they'll use work to sort of cover
it up, like playing in their mind.
You know, there'll be like, hey, that like
again, sorry for another movie reference,
but there's a movie called true lies.
Arnold Schwarzenegger. I've seen those.
He goes, yeah, so Arnold, I
haven't seen it enough times.
It came out 20 years ago to be
pulling our quote storyline, but hey,
let's go with it. It's kind of beside
the point of this one. But he goes, uh,
you know,
Arnold finds out that his wife is,
or thinks that his wife
cheating on him with it.
And then the the partner Tom
Arnold, he goes, he's all,
let's just focus on work. That's what
our, that's what I always do with my life.
Turns to dog shit. I just focus
on work. Well but, and the,
the point is like some people that tell
you know something's going wrong at home,
they'll be like, you know what? I'm
just focusing on work. Screw that.
That's forget about it. You know,
I'm an immerse myself. A nice team.
Can control work.
Yeah.
Might not be able to control
your relationship that
where you think you should
be able to. Yeah. So
continuing on all soldiers do not
have morale effected by home troubles.
Some men thrive on on happiness and
fight all the more fiercely because they
hold a bitter, a secret bitterness
within them. Such men are the minority.
That's the person that you
just talked about, right. Hey,
I'm just going to go work harder.
But as such, men under the minority,
but they are a large minority.
They are reminder that happiness
cannot by itself produce good morale.
Yeah.
Next is administration of man's ordinary.
Day to day life must be
well organized with us.
Hard conditions imposed on
him and training to inculcate
discipline do not rule
out the desirability of
good living quarters and in
the line a soldiers' morale
will be much improved if the
administration administrative
arrangements are good
and if he is assured of proper conditions
with a reasonable amount of leisure
and comfort when he leaves
the Front Leisure Day,
where you at?
You at the avant
and then he says this,
but hear a warning must be given.
There is a danger today of welfare being
considered as an end in itself and not
as a means to an end.
One of the means of maintaining morale.
Welfare by itself will not produce good
morale because it is essentially soft
and it has already been stated that
morale cannot be good unless it contains a
quality of hardness. Man,
you got to remember that,
right? You got to remember that you're
not ever going to have good morale unless
there's like an element of harkness to it
and continuing on hardship and privation
are the school of the good soldier.
Idleness and luxury are his enemies.
Men will endure great hardships if
they know why and are convinced of the
necessity. Blood, toil, tears
and sweat is not for nothing.
One of the great rallying calls of the
English race Goring's cry guns before
butter expressed the same truth.
If men believe in the need,
hardships are in themselves,
stimulant to morale,
but the opposite is also true.
Let there be any suggestion that butter
can come before guns and the men will at
once choose butter.
If this happens,
there will be no morale in
this sense of the definition.
Then we get propaganda.
The uplifting effect of modern
propaganda on a soldier is perhaps a new
development or Moran's.
Morale is raised immensely by the feeling
that his efforts are appreciated and
applauded not only by his
comrades and his officers,
but also the world at large.
Got It.
Get you've got to get that
propaganda working for you.
I've had a couple of companies I've been
working with lately and one of them was
being assaulted by its competitors
and it had a better product.
It's product was doing well,
but they were getting assaulted
and they were getting assaulted.
By the way with lies. Hmm.
Like the competitors are
just making stuff up, right?
To making stuff up,
putting that word out there.
But now they're rumors on
officially, sir. And you know,
here's the thing the CEO was kind of did,
was quite sure what to do and I said,
you have the most towel,
the most powerful tool in your arsenal.
It's the truth, but you got a weaponized
that truth. You got to weaponize it.
You've got to turn it into a weapon
that you can use to crush the lies.
Because if you're doing great things
and you're not telling anyone,
you're not putting out any propaganda,
well then guess what?
No one's going to know about it. You
just lost your, your valuable weapon,
which is the truth.
If you're doing good things and your
product is better and you can prove that
it's better and people
know that it's better,
but you're not telling anyone
you're going, it doesn't matter.
You have to weaponize that
truth and get it out there.
So that's what propaganda is.
Now we are moving into
the conclusion right here
in brief,
high morale has been defined as the
quality which makes men Indore and show
courage in times of fatigue and danger.
The cultivation of morale depends
upon the training of leaders,
the inculcation of discipline,
the encouragement of comradeship
and the infusing of self respect.
The leaders must have a belief in their
cause and they must pay attention to
numerous contributory factors of
considerable but secondary importance.
And here's how he closes it out man
is still the first weapon of war
is training is the most
important consideration in
the fashioning of a fighting
army.
All modern science is directed
toward his assistance,
but on his efforts depend
the outcome of the battle.
The morale of the soldier is the
most important single factor in war.
So there he is saying it again,
the morale of the soldiers,
the most important single factor and war.
And as I said,
I will argue with that because as far
as I'm concerned, without question,
leadership is the most important thing
on the battlefield. And I'm actually,
like I said, I'm thinking I'm
right. So no offense to Monte,
but I think I'm right because
his factors to review them.
Leadership, that's the number one factor.
Well, that's leadership discipline.
Where does that come from? Discipline
comes from leadership. Comradeship.
Where does that come from? It comes
from good leadership, self respect.
Where does that come from? It I'm not,
I'm not saying that this would Monte Sang.
Monte said that discipline
comes from leadership.
Monte said that comradeship
A Monte said that self respect comes from
leadership. So as far as I'm concerned,
no offense Monte,
as far as I'm concerned,
the leadership is the most
important thing on the battlefield.
But that being said,
let there be no doubt that morale
without question is a necessity and a
requirement for victory.
And I will add this.
Morale is important,
extremely important,
not only for 18 not only for a military
unit or a business or any kind of
organization made up of people,
but morale is also
important for individuals.
For us, day to day, how is your morale?
Where's your morale ad?
Think about how you approach the
day when you're a morale is good.
Think about how you go into the day,
just like you're going into attack.
If you're, if you're going to attack
the enemy and your morale is high,
you're going to attack with vigor and
you're probably going to be successful.
If you go in to attack the
enemy and your morale is low,
you're going to attack without vigor,
without enthusiasm,
and you're probably going to fail.
Well, what about you as a person?
If your morale is low, guess
what? If you roll into the day,
you roll into your mission
and your morale is low,
likely you are going to fail.
So then the question is how do we increase
our personal or individual morale and
I think it's the same way
we improve team morale.
Yeah.
We improve our personal
morale with discipline,
with hardship in with privation and with
efficiency and with emotional control
and by facing our fears.
And of course most
important is leadership,
leadership,
leading yourself and not allowing
this leadership vacuum in your head.
Right. When I was putting seals
through training park in the Dre,
if there was chaos broke out,
there were some times where no leader
would step up and take charge and that
would create a leadership vacuum and
it was hard to tell what's happening
because no one would be saying anything.
It would just be silence and
you didn't hear anything.
And so it's hard to recognize that all
of a sudden, wait a second, there's no,
no one's leading. You don't recognize
it because it's not happening.
It's like seeing something
that's not there.
It's not there so you don't think about
it. Well, when no one's leading do take.
Sometimes it can be hard to notice that,
and I'd call that a leadership vacuum
and I teach these young seals like, hey,
when that happens, you
need to step up. Well,
the same thing can happen in your head.
You get this leadership vacuum in
your head. When you're not leading,
you're going to start to slide down the
path of least resistance you're going to
do in a slip on down that slippery slope.
You're going to walk away from discipline.
You're got to not impose hardship
him and privation on yourself,
you're not going to push yourself and
your morale is going to go down as well.
Okay.
And if your morale fails,
well
yeah.
Becomes very easy for you to fail.
Don't,
don't allow that.
Don't allow your morale to fail.
Lift up your morale,
increase your morale by
inflicting yourself with discipline,
by doing hard things,
by controlling your emotions,
by controlling yourself and by
leading yourself on the path.
Okay.
Of discipline,
which as we know
leads to freedom.
And I think that's actually all I forgot
for tonight. So Echo Charles. Yes.
Speaking of controlling ourselves
and leading our selves down the path,
I know you've got some,
let's say some guideposts on the path,
some markers on the path.
I do some signals pointing
in the right direction.
Huge to get us down the path. Yeah. So
I was thinking about this today. Hmm.
I'm watching my daughter's performance.
Little seen performance
check this morning. All good.
Um, so for whatever reason,
good, fine. It was a big group.
But what grade kindergarten though?
What grade did you give
her when she was done?
I didn't give a grade.
How's she going to know how she's
going to improve her performance?
I'll give her a, when she
gets home check. Okay, good.
What you're going to give her foot grid
up but probably f for sure because it's
a long story that's beside the
point by the way. An AF, yeah.
What'd she do? You know, just it was,
there were some things that
happen post-performance what?
That two years that,
that I didn't approve of the reason
for them telling them to do it more,
but what happened then? I
will go over that later. Um,
so the point is I'm thinking
like what is the path,
this is probably the first time I've
ever wanted you to go into detail on the
story.
Um,
did she freak out when she shy? Just
give us a global deal? She was, yeah.
So she's shy. She's performing good,
fine. Like, you know, the whole,
it's the whole class. Um, you know, I had
a like, what do you call it? An assembly.
Okay. Yeah. And so we're
talking a hundred kids on stage,
or is it just one class and there's
only 25 kids on stage and it's not even
really a stage. It's like,
okay, it's in the classroom
in real official scenario. Yeah.
So she goes, yeah, they go,
they perform good as far as
performance goes fine. You know,
she remembered the song,
she performed it in front of us the night
before and the night before that all
good.
But then they had to sit down and
then the assembly sorta went on.
So they are sitting down and I look over
and I see you're crying. Which I didn't,
I was confused, but I know my
daughter, like, she's like,
she softy like that my fault. I
know. So she's looking back on me,
looking back to me all salty and I'm,
I'm like,
I'm not concerned because I
know something didn't go wrong.
Something's happening that
she just doesn't like clay.
She's tired of sitting there or something
like that. So she's looking back at me.
I'm just like, you know, I don't give
it that much attention. Later on,
I find out as she's walking tour class,
cause after assembly they go to
their class and she's like, Oh yeah,
I didn't like how long
the assembly was going on.
That's what she said to me
and that's why she was crying.
That's why she ain't tall.
And here's the thing,
she shouldn't feel that strongly about it.
You know there's something else going
on to be honest with you, bro. Shit,
she's like a softy.
She's like us.
I like it when things don't go her way
in certain ways and she's uncomfortable
or whatever. If I were you
hard break it down like this,
I wouldn't just give her an f across the
board. I would give her like a breakout,
maybe some different different categories
I'd give her like an a for singing or
maybe a B, you know what I mean? Cause
he bribed, not hitting every note. Right.
Maybe a B minus or whatever. And
then give her presence. I to,
this is how I used to grade my kids
when they would do stuff like this,
I'd give them presence, I give him
attitude. I'd give them clarity,
Annunciation. Like there's a bunch
of things you can break it down and,
and you don't want to give her five
o was across the board obviously.
Cause she know five Oh performer
not at age six don't exist. No,
not a biker downloads. Right.
So, so, but then you say, listen,
by the way, all your performance, which
you have a, you know, you got a 3.8 on,
that's your average score.
Post-Performance behavior
had to give you a zero.
Zero. Yeah. Tears, weakness.
Don't ever let these other
kids know that you've been,
you should be avenue attitude.
I could stand out here.
It can sit out here all day
and also simply bring it check.
All right, so as this is unfolding,
no, this more to the story. Okay,
well that wasn't the point
that all the setting,
I was just thinking like, you know,
what is the, what does the path look?
What does that, is it just the stuff
that Jocko does and now we do it? No,
it's not that. Not at all actually
credit. Some of the stuff you do,
in my opinion is essential.
Quintessential. Yeah. It's
like ideal. Right. Okay.
That's what I think that's
might be missing the by a lot.
My coming into a solid Tutu
most most people. Yeah,
but that's just you being hard
on the stand on the scale.
I don't write on yourself, put it this
way. The Path is something specific,
but more than that I just, I
just realized, not realized,
but more like consciously
thought of what's not the path.
That's what that's important. So it's
like, okay, if you're doing Jujitsu,
are you not on the path?
And not necessarily you have to be doing
or neglecting some very specific things
to not be on the path. Like if you
don't care about what you're eating,
like you're just like whatever
feels sounds good tonight.
That's told the total standard
in which you base your
meals on, you're probably not on
the path. That's a big indicator.
One of the factors. And it's an area
where you need to tighten things up. Yes.
We know you're not performing optimally
if you're not eating correctly,
you know that. So we'll just say that
element is considered not on the path.
All right? Sure. So as the, and that's
just one example of many, you know,
like if you just straight up don't
exercise at all. You know, and I'm not,
and some people have active lifestyles
in general and they don't consider it
quote unquote exercise. I get it, but,
and then that's different or whatever.
But if you're inactive,
you're sedentary, that's bad.
That quality is not on the path.
See what I'm saying?
So basically what is not on the path is
if you have most of the elements of your
life is not on the path.
You'll know also,
there's also a really broad thing
because you could, you don't,
even if you're, even if you're trying,
right, that's what the path is.
The Path is trying, right. The Path is
like, Hey, I'm trunk now. I guess. Yeah.
I guess that's a little bit strong
because I can say I'm trying to work out,
but I just did it again. You're not
on the voucher. That's a good point.
Yes. But you don't have to be, you know,
doing the nine hour workout. Yeah. With,
with a six hour Jujitsu
session afterwards. No. Like,
Oh, you only had an hour.
You only had 30 minutes to train
today. Cool. Got It done quick.
I did a pretty quick, where I did 20
minutes today. That's what I got to,
I got flew in late last night. Woke
up this morning. I had another call.
So I was like, okay, cool. I'm
going to hammer this thing out.
I had that window closing too, you
know, you know the window was like,
well maybe we'll just pull.
Yeah, that's real. You know. No,
you can't let the window close.
Yup. That was a really good concept.
We talked about the Jujitsu window.
Yes. It happens with working out too.
Right?
Even though that's mostly self-imposed,
it is mostly selfimposed for working out,
but it does happen.
And if you have work to do legitimate
work, do you have meetings?
You have calls and you're
like, well, you know,
I took that one call or I woke up
this morning in all, well, you know,
I got that call and it,
wait a second, I, you know,
brushing my teeth and wait a second,
I just gotta check my email. Oh,
now the window,
it's all knowing when to just shut.
Now I'm gonna have to work out later,
which will never happen.
Don't let the window shut.
Yeah,
just jump through it and man jumps
through the window. But Hey man,
and to recognize what the Path isn't is
just important as recognizing what the
path is. Because if you're like, hey,
are you trying to like, I don't know,
what do people say? Like are you
trying to improve yourself or whatever.
Most people will say yes, they'll be
like, oh yeah, look at all the things.
But it's like you kind of know,
you know, like it's different.
You just sorta know like
if you're doing Jujitsu,
you're sort of on the path with
that alone. Maybe not fully,
but that is a legitimate element.
So when you did you get too,
if you're new or not new, whatever,
you're going to need a geek.
You know what gear we getting?
I think we all know origin
because they are the best keys.
So how are they the best keys?
Okay, so if you just put one on,
you'll sort of know. But here's the main
indicator. Won't go too deep into it.
But coach Adam [inaudible] the same
coach in way of the where where your kid,
by the way,
there's a real coach Adam.
So coach Adam puts on his
rift gooey inside out top,
get up inside out.
I think he thought it was correct and
that was indicative of just cause it shows
the stitching. You know when you're
going get set up shows a stitching.
And I looked at it, I was
like, Dang, that looks,
that looks kind of cool right there.
Because Pete was saying he took the genes
origin genes, which are now out. Uh,
and he was, he turned
around, he said, hey,
if you want to know what the quality
of these genes turned them in,
he turned them inside out and he's like,
look at what they were
working from the inside.
So now you have Adam who sees that you
put this gear on inside out because the
quality is so high that
you can't even tell.
He thought that was the
correct way to do it.
And he thought that was what was cracking.
Meanwhile,
the logo is all backwards and stuff.
So you know,
he really should have known that,
but you know,
to each their own and it
looked good either way.
So that's where we're at with origin.
We got clothing including jeans,
Jeez t shirts, sweatshirts, uh,
other stuff. And then we got supplements
as well. Yeah. Supplements are good.
Joint Warfare. I think I'm
talking to Greg Train, right?
One of our main training partners
and he has an AC joint situation.
Two sides by the way.
And I'm till am telling him if you put
together the joint or fair with the Super
Krill oil discipline every single day,
that thing he'll straight up faster,
measurably faster, hundred
percent. Then just, you know,
look at my niece situation,
which amen. I'm a believer now
you're now a believer. Yeah.
I'm,
I increased my beliefs of my own personal
kind of like wolverine healing powers,
which I have joked about performing even
though it wasn't really Joe. You know,
you know, you joke about something
but you kind of mean it. Yeah.
I feel real lucky man. Real lucky
because my knee was straight up. Yeah.
Injured. And it's not healed yet, but
Dang, if it hasn't progressed a lot. Yeah.
Yeah. And it's not like, you know,
when you're like 18 years old, uh,
maybe a lighter weight
person or something,
it's like you tend to sort of heal
faster. Let's face it, you're, you know,
you're old school and you're
not wearing a small school or
your old school and you know, what are
you walking around at two 30 to 35.
I mean that,
I'm just saying that's not an easy
racket for the knees all the time.
Meanwhile you're just boom, boom,
boom, bouncing back that fast.
That's saying a lot. Joint
Warfare, Krill oil. Uh,
get some of that.
Also the discipline and the discipline go.
I had a scenario the other
day that's actually yesterday.
Sure. Crazy flight situation,
thunderstorms, rerouting landing buses,
trains is ridiculous. Anyways, I,
I'm going into an interview on
two hours of sleep all day. Yeah.
And this is just after,
you know,
Peter a t is telling me
about all the horrible
like cognitive
that are going to give you cause
and so yeah, I took, I took like,
I took like two discipline go. Right when
I woke up I was like, all right, hey,
I got an interview and like, and then
I got there and I did a little bit of,
you know,
playing around or not playing around,
but they're like prepping
for the interview. And then
I took like three more,
so I took five. Discipline
goes, rocked it. I read it.
I was like a what? You got to a question?
Oh, let me tell you a link. So anyways,
try that discipline.
Go out.
If you need something to
focus your cognitive skills,
skills, skills, for sure
you can get some of that.
Or you can get the discipline go and you
need the discipline powder. Yeah. Should,
we've just called that pre jujitsu powder.
Yeah.
That's it's sorting itself out to be,
it kind of sounds like something
where you are. We're going to Jujitsu,
you know you're going to need cognitive
skills and you know you're gonna need
some physical skills or some physical
enhancements. Sure. So you just jump
on a couple of scoops of discipline.
Maybe three if you need to, if you want
to get nuts. Yeah, that's a good one.
That's part of my everyday now I'm pulling
the Dave Burke. Yeah, yeah, that's,
that's I was, look, there's
one thing that's good about it.
He doesn't have some crazy
amount of caffeine in it. Right?
You don't want to be all
amped up on caffeine when
you take something called the
stuff too makes me feel really good.
Well,
you just took a big hit of caffeine and
you're going to get, what's that word?
You're going to get a tolerance to it and
then it's not going to have the effect
that you want. Discipline has like
15 milligrams of caffeine per scoop.
That's not that much. So what you
feel when you feel like the zoo,
you're not really feeling, you're
feeling the other ingredients in there.
So don't, don't fool yourself into
getting all amped up on caffeine,
you know,
or otherwise.
You might as well go do meth or cocaine
or just drink some coffee, whichever,
you know, that's kind of off
the, no, I'm just kidding.
Children don't do meth or cocaine.
Don't do drugs, period. However,
if you want to do something that
gives you a sort of a addiction,
try some strawberry milk,
which is now out for adults.
It is absolutely delicious.
If you want some extra protein in
your body so you can get bigger,
stronger, faster, better,
yeah, true. And you an or,
or if you just want dessert,
if you just want some dessert,
have some strawberry milk or some peanut
butter milk or some mint Malke or some
vanilla or dark chocolate. And
there you go. Jocko white tea.
If you're into tea or even if
you're not into t really t you know,
against it.
But you know,
it's one of those things still
the Oji original Jocko, White Tea,
pomegranate, pomegranate, Chai.
No white tea.
Jocko decides to make his own
light tea with side effects,
deadlifting 8,000 pounds, I'll roll
with it. It's actually pretty good.
So yet get that. It is available
and Jocko stored now by the way,
and Amazon and you know, just go on
the Internet basically and get it.
So yeah, that's a good one. Um, speaking
is Jocko store. Jocko does have a story.
It's called Jocko store.
Just like this is called Jocko
podcast called Jocko store,
so drugstore.com that's
where his online store,
this is where you can get rash guards
for you Jujitsu to supplement your gies
from origin.
Also t-shirts Nogi correct.
You can wear a rash guard. Oh yeah, yeah.
It's kind of workouts using your rings.
If you're doing dips, if you're doing
ring pushups, if you're doing muscle ups,
you're the,
what is it,
the what Greg chain say like the
outside of your arm he's got,
he was always got the medical
term surfing your radial whatever.
You'll get all like chafed up.
Yeah.
When you're doing a bunch of muscle ops
or a bunch of ring dips or whatever.
If you weren't a rash guard, do you won't
owe jack going for comfort over here.
Speaking of comfort, if you
like, even though I got into
riding bike a little bit,
not totally, but if you were a rash
guard riding bike, like cycling,
it's like surprisingly,
I'm going to say it's surprisingly
comfortable. Functional, it's functional.
So you know, there's a lot of other
things we do with our rash guards. Um,
and actually I forgot to say this,
we forgot to say this for a while.
It does add another 19% performance
and literally everything you do,
literally
100% also tee shirts if you want to
represent discipline equals freedom. Good.
Any,
any of the layers that we've come to
exploit that the correct term terminology
makes exploit the layers anyway.
Lower the legs for sure that
sometimes you exploit the layers,
which is questionable behavior.
Don't forget to subscribe to this podcast
wherever you subscribe to podcasts.
I wouldn't think that you had listened
to this whole podcast and not subscribed
to it, but maybe you did.
Don't do that. Subscribe to it.
I didn't leave a review so I can read
your funny review about getting after it
and whatnot. Also where your kid
podcast, speaking of subscribing.
Yeah, so that's, that's not just
for the kit. That's for everybody.
If you want just simple,
straight up simple answers
to your questions that your
kids happened to beat you
to the punch and asking. My daughter has
a question from uncle Jake by the way.
Um, nonetheless you, you,
even if you're not a kid will
like this or it could podcast.
Don't forget to check out that
warrior kid that's making soap. Aiden,
Irish oaks,
ranch.com making trooper soap,
making Jocko soap.
You can use that soap so that
you can stay clean, stay clean.
Also for the video version of this
podcast if you want to it rather than just
listen to it. We do have a youtube
channel, also a excerpts on there.
If you want to,
you know,
share some elements of the podcasts
that are good takeaways individually,
share them with your friends.
It's not like, Hey, I saw this,
I got a cool idea for you.
Here's a four hour podcast,
watch the whole thing just
listened to you. You'll catch
it. I forget where it is,
but it's in there somewhere yet.
And I can listen to that on a
whim so you can just, you know,
so that's what we should have called them.
Little little video hitters. Sure. There
you go. I like that better than mcnuggets.
You're the one who made up Jocko mcnugget
doesn't mean I can't change my mind
and come up with something better on the
little video hitter. That video hit her.
You need to make more of those hitters.
Yes sir. There you go. But nonetheless,
if you are interested in any video things,
hitters,
hitters in regards to this,
but it's probably an acquired situation.
It just sounds cooler when Theo says
it and you're saying, so I'm like,
I'm used to you saying it, so that's
cool. But me saying I'm not ready yet,
but I'll get there.
And also psychological warfare that has
a bunch of little short audio hitters
that you can listen to if you need to
power through a moment of weakness.
It's on iTunes, Google play or
other MP3 platforms. Flip side,
canvas.com my brother Dakota Meyer,
he started a company. Why? Because he's a,
he's a bad ass and he
wanted to start a company.
The company that he started is making
things to hang on your wall. Art,
we'll call it with layers. Little
art with layers. The Art has layers.
Little art hitters that you
can put up on your wall.
I could tell I frustrated you
with that. No Man. Keep it going.
It's good and you get those.
You can get them from phone cause I'd
canvas.com makes all kinds of cool stuff
on that says good when it says
all your excuses are lies.
One that says time is running out. One
that says discipline equals freedom. Yeah.
So you can get those flipside, canvas.com
support my brother. It caught on.
Meyer also when you're
expanding your home gym,
your home exercise situation
really go to on it.
So go on [inaudible] dot com slash
Jocko this where you can get your kettle
bells.
Good kettlebells,
artistic art floating around
here today. Oh yeah. Big Time.
The primal bells, they got the um, the
star wars ones now. Anyway. Got that one.
I'm going to, I think I'm
making another one, man.
The kettle bells have been a huge part
of my recent workouts. That's good.
Oh yeah. Build enough
functional strength nonetheless.
You can get rings there as
well. Uh, some immunity stuff.
I say that because that's,
I've been on that recently and you see
little kids running around with cold
Keno, runny noses, but you just
hit when your kids going to school.
Your kid is just a, just a host for
disease to put it back into your house.
Little last
what you pull crying.
I know man.
F F minus any way. So yeah, I'd been
on that. The shroom tech immune,
so good on. Anyway, they get big on a
lot of good stuff on there. So yeah,
on it.com/jungle we got some books.
I have a new book coming out is called
way of the warrior kid three where
there's a will,
it is available for preorder.
Right now the publishing company needs
to know how many of these books to print.
The publishing company is me,
so if you want to have this book,
please preorder it asap so I
know how many copies to print.
The name of the book is the way of
the warrior kid three and I'm actually
putting that on the cover now.
When I made way of the warrior kid too,
I said to the publisher, Hey, can we put
way of the warrior kid too on the cover?
And they said, no, we can't do that. And
I said, well why not? And they said, well,
if people know it's the second in the
series and they don't have the first,
they won't buy it.
So we can't put that on the cover.
We don't want to hurt sales. So I
said, oh, I thought to myself, oh,
we're just trying to confuse
people so they will buy more.
I'm not trying to confuse anybody here.
Way of the warrior kid.
Three on the cover is the
third book in the series.
John Bozak,
the artist thinks it's the best book
in the series lessons to be learned.
Interesting.
There's also a way of the warrior kid too.
We're just called Mark's
mission and there's the
original way of the warrior kid
and then on top of that for your
children and possibly for you too,
we got Mikey and the dragons.
You can order that one now
for your younger kids.
Also the discipline equals freedom field
manual already talked about that one.
The audio of that is on Itunes,
not on audible,
so it's on an MP three and then extreme
ownership and dichotomy of leadership,
which I wrote with my brother Leif Babin
and we talk about leadership from our
perspective going from
the military combat,
taking those lessons learned to bringing
them back and now turning them over to
the civilian sector.
And on top of that we also
have a leadership consultancy
called echelon front
where we solve problems
through leadership.
If you want us to come to your company
and help you with your leadership,
go to echelon front.com if you want.
If you want someone on my team to come
and speak to your company, including me,
don't reach out to a speaker's bureau.
Don't Google Jocko speaking and click
on the first advertisement that pops up.
Go to echelon front.com which Ashlynn
Frog dotcom. We'll pump pop up as well,
but you might not recognize that,
so come straight to the source echelon
front.com if you need leadership help at
your company,
team or organization.
We've also got the muster May 23rd and
24th in Chicago out September 19th and
20th in Denver, getting to be
sold out, Sydney, Australia,
December 4th and fifth
looking forward to all those.
Check extreme ownership.com if you
want to get in the mix at the muster.
If you can't come to the muster
but you want to get in the mix,
go to e f online.com this is
interactive leadership training.
It is based on what we do at the muster
on getting granular on the principles
that are in the book,
extreme ownership and the dichotomy of
leadership and everything I talk about on
this podcast, it's, it's in there concise,
clear ways so people can understand it.
And then on top of that, it's interactive.
So you get put into leadership situations,
you have to learn to make decisions.
It's a great program. And if you want to
check that out, it's at UCF online.com.
And then lastly, we've got
f Overwatch, which is our,
basically it's our manning company where
we will take individuals from special
operations and the combat aviation
communities and put them into leadership
positions inside of companies that need
leadership inside their organization.
So if you're looking for leadership,
which you are,
because every problem that you have in
a company or on a team is because of
leadership.
So if you need help with your leadership,
go to eff overwatched.com
and fill out the information.
And if you want to
cruise hard with us more,
we're on the inner webs,
Twitter, Instagram,
and Facebook.
The what?
The Facebook. Uh, Facebook, you know the,
the Facebook is the original gene. Yeah.
Yeah. I didn't know about Justin
Timberlake was like, Hey, don't, sorry.
Not Justin Timberlake. Sean Parker
Parker. Anyway, he ever seen the movie?
It shows when was the
reason he said drop the,
the just Facebook. Who says that
cleaner? Sean Parker, the Napster Guy.
Oh, okay. Played by Justin Timberlake in
the movie. Uh, got it. Got It. Very good.
Well if you're on those
platforms, sure. Yeah.
Echo is echo Charles Jocko is that Jocko
Willink on all of them both keep it
simple like that and thanks to all of
our military folks out there who keep
their morale high and keep their
bayonets sharp out there on the line.
And thanks to the police
and law enforcement and
firefighters and paramedics and
EMT and dispatchers and correctional
officers and border patrol and secret
service and all the
other first responders.
Thanks to all of you for standing up and
facing evil so that we don't have to.
And to everyone else out there,
do your
okay.
Your morale,
my below from time to
time they can happen.
Okay.
Can happen to anyone.
And it does happen to everyone,
and when it does start to slip,
recognize it and then remember that
you can actually do something about it.
Like young [inaudible].
Rowbury said in that letter,
don't grieve. Don't cry. Don't worry,
or fret. Surely there's no
better way of dying. He said
fighting
then standing up,
and that is what you do.
Yeah,
you fight, you stand up, you
impose discipline on your life.
You face the things that you fear,
the things that are crushing your morale.
You face some,
and you lift up your morale
through force of will. By leading,
by going out.
Okay.
Then getting after it.
So until next time,
this is echo and Jocko
out.