Jocko.
My boss is incredibly controlling.
An Ego maniacal.
I like him already.
Ego Maniac.
I have,
I have attempted to use extreme ownership
in dealing with the people under me,
but my boss has reprimanded me
for leading. He has said he gets,
he gets to do all the leading because
he's the one in charge, quote unquote and,
and his job title is higher than mine.
I've had that happen to me before.
By the way,
if I could continue to try to lead,
my responsibilities will be taken away.
If I stepped back into the shadows,
I won't make an impact on the
people under me. What should I do?
So it's black and white.
Yeah,
in his mind seems that either step up
and lead and get fired or step in the
shadows and do nothing and everyone will
suffer. It's not, it's not that way,
right? It's not. It's not black and white.
And actually start by putting your own
ego in check because you're calling
someone at ego maniacal, but
you're, your ego is being,
being touched a little bit here,
rubbed the wrong way a little
bit because you want to lead.
And when you get told don't lead,
you got paid to and offends you.
Guess what that is? You're
here. That's your ego.
So what you need to do is maybe you like
that you liked the feeling of being in
charge. That's cool. I liked
the feeling of being charge.
Yeah, it feels good to me.
It feels normal to me when I'm
not in charge. I don't like it.
I have to consciously suppress it,
which is fine.
Sometimes you don't have to do that.
Like right in the situation here that
this guy's talking about and what you need
to suppress is you need to not
be so overt with your leadership.
He shouldn't even be able to
sense that you're leading,
but you should be leading.
You gotta be under the radar.
You gotta be covert with what
you're doing. And by the way,
while you're doing that,
you're massaging homeboys. Ego,
make him feel good about it. Making
them feel mad. He is running things.
And because,
because you can absolutely lead from
the shadows if your ego allows it.
Because a lot of times when we want,
when we lead,
we want everyone to know
that would lead him.
I want everyone to know that
I'm in charge. I don't want
them to know that. Right.
That's really hard when you're leaving
from the shadows. A lot of times,
not even the people that you're leading
recognize overtly that you're leading.
Think about that.
So the people that are actually following
you don't even know that they're
following you. They don't.
They don't consciously know it.
Maybe if they were to break down
and you give, gave him like a, Hey,
who do you think is actually
giving you instruct legal? Well,
I think that might be probably, that
seems like it's echo. Okay. Okay.
But they don't like consciously think
about it. So that's what you need to do.
You need to suppress
your overt leadership.
Not Step on the boss's toes.
Massages,
massage his ego a little bit
because if you do get your response,
do you want to help? Right?
Well, you want to be helpful.
You want to lead these people
in a great way. If you don't,
if you get your responsibilities
taken away or you get fired,
then you can't help anyone, anybody.
You're not gonna help the team at all.
So you have to be smart and you have to
play the game to win his confidence and
his trust.
So he does let you lead.
And what's going to do that
when he realizes that you're
gonna not gonna step on
his toes, that you're going to give him
the credit because he wants a credit.
He's an EGOMANIAC,
right? He's controlling.
So that's kind of what you need to do.
Now, this is the weird thing
and this came up at the muster.
People don't want to hear me say that.
If I come up against a boss, the big
ego, what you need to do is back down.
People don't want to hear me say that.
They say they want to hear me.
Say if you come up against
someone with a big ego,
what you do is you blow up to them and
you show them that they ain't got nothing
on you. Yeah, don't back down.
Don't back down to that guy with a
big ego that's weak. It's true. And,
and what I said at the muster and I said,
I said, listen, cause I could see it,
I could see it. People are like, ah yeah,
I guess Jocko isn't always as hardcore
as I thought he was because he's going to
back down to somebody with a big
ego and I said, guess what people,
this is why you feel that way.
If there was a,
a machine gun nest on a hill and there
was a bad guy in there and he's killing a
bunch of people shooting that machine gun
and everyone in the room wants to look
at Jocko and say,
Jockos brave and Jock who's tough and
Jack was going to charge that machine gun
nest and take that guy out.
Well guess what?
A machine gun belt fed weapon in
an elevated position bunkered in.
I'm not going to take that guy out.
I can't.
It's a heavily defended position.
I can't do that.
So what Jocko does is backs down.
I hide,
I get behind cover so I don't die
once I've gotten behind cover so I don't
die. I look at Echo when I say echo,
stay here. Shoot some rounds at
this guy. Occasionally distract him.
I'm going to flank him. So that
goes gonna keep undercover himself.
He's going to playing some rounds
up with a machine gun nest.
While he's doing that, I'm going
to scurry away like a little baby,
like little sneaky little squirrel.
And I'm going to go around to the flank
cause the machine gun is in a bunker,
right? So he can't see out the
sides. I'm coming up the side,
I'm going to get right to the assignment
to toss a grenade in there and kill him.
I'm going to take out the ego, but
I didn't do it. Go in head on. Yeah.
So what happens is people come and go
up against this big ego and they want to
be the hero and they want be aggressive
and they want to the default aggressive
Jocko. You say you got a chapter in
your book, default aggressive man.
I'm going to be default aggressive
against that ego. Wrong answer. Yeah,
the right answers. Indirect warfare,
the right answers, maneuver warfare,
the right answers. You flank
these people, and by the way,
if I do charge that machine gun nest or
I do attack that guy's ego, guess what?
I die or I get fired and
now I'm no good to anybody.
So it's people have this,
this desire to be the strong
hero and you have to fight that.
That's your ego. That's my ego
charging the machine gun nest.
I'm going to go do this on the man. No,
I'm actually not the man. It's a machine.
Go Nova position. I'm going to
die. You have to be smart. Yeah.
Like Glenn attack that you go head on.
Don't attack heavily defended
positions head on period.
Like you sit in training day.
You ever watch that movie
training day? No. Come on,
Ray, you've watched it anyway. He
says, the Shit is chess, not checkers.
He's not the first person that ever said,
but it was dope when he said it.
In my opinion. Nonetheless, yes.
So default aggressive isn't default
aggressive. Hey, it to hit its default.
Default aggressive in being
effective. Yes. Yes. That is really,
you're effective or ineffective, and I
see their muster, you know, I listen.
Lafe knows what he's
talking about it like that.