I have a standard mantra.
Okay?
And that is every day is a great day.
I have my faith,
my family, and live in the
finest country in the world.
I see it every day, every chance
I got. And people ask me, well,
why? You know, how can you be so positive?
And you know, why do you say that? I say,
well,
number one,
as a very young 24 year old company
commander in Vietnam in combat,
there were times I didn't know if I
was going to be alive the next moment,
much less seed and next sunrise.
When you're in those circumstances,
what is important in life becomes
real focused. And that is faith,
family, and living in the
finest country in the world now.
So then people will come
back at me and say, well,
how can you say that when we have so
much division in our country? Okay?
And I say, listen, I'm a little
bit longer and tooth than you are.
And when I was a kid,
the,
I've seen the improvements in our
society when it comes to race relations.
Now I'm a minority. So I
get it. And I told him the,
the odds of me becoming when I was a kid,
the odds of me becoming a major journal
in the United States army were slim next
to none. Okay. When, you know,
when we've had an African American
president who was reelected,
and then I tell people when
President Kennedy was elected,
that was a big deal. And, and
a lot of people don't know why.
And I say because he was Catholic,
but today that that's,
that's not a big deal. Right. And
that, that though in those days,
that was a big deal.
So I tell people every day is a great day.
I have my faith, my family, we live in
the finest country in the world. Well,
that saying was challenged about five
and a half years ago when I had some
health challenges, which I think I,
I didn't mention it earlier today.
Uh,
I was still working in the financial
services industry and I got up in the
morning or shaving and I
felt this pain in my chest.
And I mean, it wasn't a serious
pounding and I wasn't sweating,
nausea. So I didn't have a temperature.
So, uh, I thought it was something I ate,
you know, give it five minutes, it'll
go away. Right. It didn't go away.
So I told my wife, this is not good.
So I finished shaving and dressing. No,
and she drove me to the emergency room
at the hospital. So I walk in and I say,
Hey, you know, I've got this pain in
my chest. I don't know what it is.
So they do an EKG and they said,
you have had a heart attack.
Well, suddenly all these doctors and
nurses swoop into the Er, they undress me.
They put me in a hospital gown.
I'm on a Gurney and I'm on my
way to the operating room, right?
So I'm in the corridor and on this
Gurney, and I say to myself, self,
can you say today is a great day?
And I said, I absolutely can.
I survive Vietnam.
I have a wonderful wife and children
and I most importantly have my faith.
So in 24 hours,
I had three operations. The first
operation was for the heart attack. Okay.
So they do an angiogram.
They found out my lad,
which is the widow maker artery,
he was 90% blocked.
So they do an angioplasty, put a stent
in. So by 10 o'clock in the morning,
I'm a newbie cover he
room. So I'm figuring, well
that's, that's the end of it,
right?
That wasn't the end of it.
The second thing that happened was my
heart cavity started to fill up with
liquid, it's called a fusion.
So I had to go back in for an,
they had to put a hole in my chest so
they could put a tube there so they could
drain this liquid and it
filled up a bottle that took
about 24 hours to do that.
Okay. The third thing that happened
then was my kidneys failed,
so I had to go back in and they had to
put another hole in my chest so they
could hook up a day dialysis machine.
Okay.
So the standard procedure,
every time I was rolled into the
operating room is, what's your name?
What's your birthday?
How do you feel? Okay.
So I'm on the operating table and I say,
Jim [inaudible] August 3rd
44 every day is a great day.
I have my faith, my family, and live
in the finest country in the world.
I can't tell you the effect that
had on the doctors and nurses.
The first operation, the doctor said,
what is your faith? And I said, well,
since you asked me doc, I said, I'm
a Christian. Christ is my savior,
your skill physicians, skilled
nurses, but I'm in God's hands.
So whatever he decides, I'm okay
with. So let's get on with it.
So the second operation there
was a nurse and she said,
where do you go to
church? And I said, well,
I attend Willow Creek Community Church.
And she said,
I do too. So no coincidence.
The third operation,
this was the coolest thing.
There was a male nurse who is wearing
a camouflage gowned and I said,
you must've been in the
army, nick. I said, yeah.