Jocko. I want to hear your
thoughts on over detachment.
I'm a police officer and I'm sure military
personnel experience the same over
detachment defined as emotional separation
from moments which required emotional
response in family and profession.
So what are you thoughts on over
detachment? Yeah, this is definitely,
obviously I'm always encouraging people
to be able to detach because that's how
you get your emotions
out of the situation.
But this happens to what my brother
right here is talking about this police
officer's saying, hey, sometimes you
know, we think about being over detached
and is something you need to watch out
for because you don't want to go through
your life where you have no more emotions.
Cause then you're not living a life,
then you're a robot or a machine and,
and you don't,
you need to have emotions.
So what as I thought about this,
I thought,
how did I watch out for that?
And it's something that creeps in on
anybody that does anything we could add.
You don't even have to be a copper or
a military person. I mean you could do,
if you're any job that you
have where you have free,
can't just get all emotional about
stuff. Um, if you're in finance,
if you're anything you could just
become detached. So how do you do,
what do you look out for?
One thing that I did and still do
is compartmentalize and draw little
segregation between work and home.
Mm.
Um,
and there's a really easy way to do that,
especially for people that are cops
or it doesn't matter what you do,
whatever that uniform is that you
wear at work, whether you're a cop,
whether you're military, whether
you were in a business suit at work,
when you get home, take off
that uniform, take it off.
Matter of fact, if you can take it
off before you get home, you know,
leave it at the office. Yeah.
Cause you want to leave that there.
And when you get home,
put on the home clothes,
right? The t shirt, comfortable
t shirt, the flip flops,
the the shorts B,
be relaxed at home,
but be physically in a
different uniform at home.
Not even a uniform in a different
change your change your appearance and
therefore change your state of mind
a little bit different music, right?
Whatever it is that you're
listened to at work,
go to something different at home, Eh,
you know when you're going into work,
listen to the first hour of Jocko
podcast when you're coming home.
He listened to the second hour,
right? That's how we do it. Yo,
you want to have a different
attitude, a different language, right?
Don't come a home thrown around
the in acronyms from work. Yeah,
and you know I've talked about
this before. I never swore at home.
I swore like hell at work,
but I never swore home so I was using a
different language than I was completely
compartmentalizing what I was doing
at work and what I was doing at home.
And then checkout your posture. What
are you standing around your house like?
Are you standing all cross
armed and glaring at people?
Let's just ask the question.
Are you in a modified weaver stance
when you're talking to your wife getting
ready to do a quick drunk?
It's like a pistol shooting
stance. Like that's, no, no.
You know, are you, are you
digging for under hooks?
If your kids trying to give you a hug,
you know what I mean?
Are you looking to get the take
down? No. You want to relax. Right.
And another thing is
find some, uh, you know,
what's maybe maybe a group of people
that aren't involved in your work.
That can be hard. I mean,
and, and luckily for me,
my wife made friends that were
outside of the seal community.
And so I got a bunch of buddies that were,
had nothing to do with the seal teams.
They have their friends, they
were friends with my wife. Yeah.
Friends and husbands of my wife's friends.
So I had a whole group of people that
are still hanging out with all the time.
They have nothing to do with
the military at all. In fact,
many of them are as bad as far as you
could get from military personnel is one
could imagine. Yeah. And,
but that's another thing that helped
me segregate the two. Now, of course,
I'm not saying you've got
to let your guard down 100%,
cause you shouldn't do that,
but you should let it down
enough that you can enjoy life.
Um,
and
you got it attach sometimes. Now
that being said, cause it's kind of,
it is going to help you
make good decisions.
But there are also times
where it's not good.
And if you're detached and your
wife's trying to talk to you,
it's not going to be good. Yup. So
open up, you gotta show some emotions.
And one of the things about being
detached, here's a, here's a paradox.
You gotta be detached enough so that
you recognize when you're not showing
enough emotion. Yeah. You know
what I'm saying? If you're,
if you're so detached
that you being detached,
it allow you to realize that, oh my God,
I'm not showing any emotions at all.
I'm too detached.
Yeah.
So don't try and be a tough
guy that's just being detached.
Cause if you're detached enough, you'll
realize that you're being too detached.
Yep. Yeah. And there is two d, well
obviously like if you're, you know,
you're in a debate argument, fight
whatever with your girlfriend wife, right?
And you're detached, let's say, you know,
you're right. Let's say you are right.
That has nothing to do with anything
when you're arguing with you.
Generally speaking though,
in my experience, yeah,
I would agree with that in my experience.
But here's the thing though,
because when you're looking at a certain
way, I just want to make that same.
And again,
when you're in an argument with like
your wife or your close friend or any
gifts, your boss, your subordinate,
whether you're right or not is almost,
doesn't matter at all.
What matters is what you're trying to do,
what direction you're trying to move.
And is winning the argument
being right or wrong,
going to help you move in a direction to
move in? That's the real question. Yeah.
So detach for a minute and figure
out the answer to that question. Yes.
Cause I never care if I'm right or
wrong. That's not never my goal. Well,
in an argument with something,
did I say never. Okay.
I usually don't care the most for
the most park. Yeah. Yeah. And,
and I think a lot of times,
a lot of times people do care whether
right or wrong. Oh my God, they do.
They care. We'll go psycho or being right
or wrong. Yeah. One approved beyond,
you know, like a reasonable
doubt. All questions denied.
I'm 100% right. You're wrong. And
so even when people are wrong,
they'll still want to just
win the argument. Right? So
that's, that's, that's bad.
What can be even worse
is when you are right,
yet the other person is it,
let's say your wife is emotional cause,
and this is a known thing that,
okay,
the girls generally speaking,
they,
they want to know that you care more so
than they want you to fix their problem.
Like if someone has, if your
wife is having a problem at
work or something, right?
They just want you to care
that that's going on with them.
They don't want like all this tricking
advice. You know, that generally speaking,
I'm not going to category is there,
it's not black and white.
But generally speaking, so
let's say you're in a debate
or something, I say deep,
you're an argument. You're in a
fight and you know you're right in,
let's say you are right. If you're
all detached and being like, well,
here's the logic behind why I'm right and
you have this airtight case that's not
going to help your relationship.
She wants to know first off that you care.
She's mad. She said she's whatever. Do you
care about that? That's the way you win,
not the argument. That's the way you
in this situation. Yes. You know,
and so not only are you,
not only do you get out of the
fight intact as a relationship,
but you're the good guy. And really that's
part of the reason why she likes you,
because you're the good guy. That's
a wind, wind roof. So yeah, that,
that just sometimes question
why my wife likes me at all.
Yeah, yeah. No, that's, that's a,
that's it. But yeah, so detached.
So you see that but be
attached because you care. Yes.
Yes.
And show that you care.
And then when you go back
to work, your comp, Europe,
military person, you're a
businessperson. Put your uniform back on,
put your boots back on,
put your body on back on lock and
load and get back into detachment zone
and move forward. Now at the
question kind of implies this too,
and I will point this out.
I mean at work,
you also can't just be detached all the
time, cause you're, you're a leader,
you're in a leadership position.
So you can't just walk around
just detached from every, no.
You got to show emotions. You got to
relate to the people you're working with.
You've got to be a human so that they
follow you or you follow them or whatever
the case may be.
So the detachment,
you have to be detached enough
to recognize when you're
being too detached. Yeah.
Less erudite.
Yeah.