I'm a chef in a large operation kitchen.
I'm second in command overseeing a large
kitchen staff and part of a five person
management team overseeing
thing to entire account.
Recently during my last review I was
given some advice by my boss and his boss.
I'm unsure about my last two annual
reviews have gone very well and I'm on the
rise in the company.
However,
they said if it was important
for me to get or heat Harvard,
they said it was important for me to
give up some of my kitchen dog mentality
and work to showcase my artistic side
and embrace more of a star role in the
spotlight, get out of the kitchen
a bit more, gain more exposure.
Specifically with our
high profile clients.
While I appreciate their sentiment and
respect their big management skills,
their style isn't one I strive to emulate
or feel would work for me and the way
I operate.
I've always approached my work is more
of a craft than an art and I've always
like being a trench dug with my team.
My team responds to it and I get results
for the business and I feel the results
should speak for themselves.
It has propelled my career
rapidly through thus far.
So why would I want to change
and be something I'm not?
Should I heed their advice or stick to
what I do best and keep getting after it
on my terms?
Ah, it's one of those
questions. It's just funny how,
how that last statement is framed,
right?
Should I stick to what I do best and
keep getting after it as if to say,
if you say no,
you should not stick to what you do best
and you should not get after it. Right.
That's, that's the frame
there. And actually this guy,
I answered the question real tersely.
I think this came through Facebook
messages. I, you know, I said, uh,
sounds like you found a comfortable zone
for yourself and you want to stay in
their little cold blooded
response. And he's like, ah,
I knew it because as we know
in the comfort zone, there's,
there was no growth in the comfort zone.
So it's interesting this guy
is actually getting some,
some good solid and straight forward
advice from up the chain of command.
Uh,
plus I think if they have him as more of
a personality than the restaurant will
do better and they're trying to build
their reputation and your reputation at
the same time. And that seems
pretty reasonable to me. Right.
And I'm not real familiar
with the restaurant business,
but I'm familiar enough to know if you've
got a good reputation with the staff
that works at the restaurant.
It brings in more people,
like there's no doubt about
it, the, the relationship,
just like any other business,
the relationship that you build
with the customers strengthens them,
strengthens that relationship and makes
them want to come back for more. Right.
That's the way it works. And so
for them to say to you, hey man,
hey, you know, you're a good cook. We
get that, but we need a little bit more.
We want a little bit chef. We need
somebody that has, yeah, chef.
Sorry. You're good. Yeah. Yeah.
Sorry. You're a good chef. Well,
actually what I think I might've
actually purposely said that like, hey,
you're doing a good job
in the kitchen as a cook.
We don't need someone that's
just cooking the food.
We need a chef with a reputation
with a personality, right? Yeah.
There's a difference there,
right? Yes sir. So it was
called out for reason. Gotcha.
He's happy and you can see like kitchen
dog. Yeah. He's proud of that. Right.
And I get that man, I get that. I get
that. Like you're one of the boys,
you're back in the, in
the grind. Well let me,
let me ask you this or let
me make this statement.
Guess what you have to do as a CEO, as
a CEO leader, guess what you have to do?
You have to build relationships.
You have to make your
commanding officer trust you.
You have to build
relationships with the army.
You have to build relationships
with Marine Corps. You have to end.
In order to do that,
you have to like raise your,
you have to call a little bit of attention
to yourself and raise your hand and
say, Hey, this is who I am. You
have to take, this is who I am.
You have to actually have to step into
the spotlight a little bit so that you
can let people know who you are.
Because if people don't know who you are,
how do you have a relationship with you?
And if you don't have relationship with
people, how can they trust you? So, so
that's part of it, right? That's part
of what they're asking you to do. Now,
in all seriousness,
if if you really don't want to do it,
well then you can keep being the guy
that's in the back and guess what?
You're going to be mad in six months
when some other chef gets hired for a
different shift than all of a sudden
he's out making friends with everyone and
he gets promoted. And why does it get
promoted? Well, look what the guy's doing,
but he's not as good as,
he's not as good as a cook as I am.
Guess what?
They don't really care.
Being making the food is only
part of what they want you to do.
Just like being a seal. Doing, doing
missions is only part of what they,
what you need to do to do the mission.
You can't just be tactically sound.
You've got to have the relationships
built so you can work in the battlespace
that's owned by a conventional commander.
You got to have the
relationship that you can get.
Your mission's approved up the chain of
command on the special operations side.
How do you do that? You build,
you go out, you talk to people,
you get out of your comfort zone.
It's a weird thing, you know?
I'm kind of, I'm kind of
antisocial, right? Like
if you don't know me,
we're not going to have a conversation.
You know? Like we're not having
a, I'm like, it's not, I'm not,
I'm not walking up and talking
to you if I don't know you.
I'm not walking up and saying hi to you.
It's not happening.
It's not my personality. If
you say hi to me, I'll say hi.
I'm not disrespectful,
I'm not rude,
but I'm not looking to have a bunch of
conversations with people and so that's
known to me,
but that's not okay for the
business side of my life, which is,
hey, I got to talk to people
gotta build relationships. Got It.
To had to know my commanding
officer had to know, the commodore,
had to know the,
the,
the conventional battalion commander
had to know the brigade commander had to
build relationships.
Could I just talk about the
war with the brigade commander?
Well I could,
but what's more powerful that I talk
about war and I talk about where I'm from
or where he's from or what,
you know, other things. Yes.
Cause I want to build a relationship with
why? Because I'm trying to build trust.
Wah.
Why?
Because I want him to allow me to go out
there and do things in his battle space.
So that's what they're asking you.
They're asking you to step
out of your comfort zone.
It doesn't need to become
your primary focus. No.
Should you try and step out of the
comfort zone if you want to grow,
if you want to have more opportunity,
I would give it a try.
I would give it a try. If
not, you know, like I said,
if you hate it and you feel like you're
not being true to your true self,
that's okay.
Maybe your true self is meant to be the
one that's back not getting promoted.
Yeah. They need somebody to
do that. If it's not you,
it might be somebody else.
Yeah.
So another one of those tough questions
where people, you know, hit me with like,
should I just be,
should I be loyal to myself because the
obvious answer that everyone wants to
hear is like, yeah, dude,
two most important things.
You've got to be loyal to yourself.
That's the most important thing. Okay.
If that's what your priority is,
then that's the most important thing.
But guess what? Who does, uh,
who can take care of the other
kitchen dogs that respect you so much,
who can take better care of them then
you can cause if you get promoted,
if you don't get promoted.
And,
and Johnny Glamour boy gets promoted
because he's likes to go out and Schmooze
the clients and now he gets promoted and
years and now who's going to take care
of the kitchen dogs on his, on his
time, right? Not Him. He doesn't care.
He's got, he got promoted not
for taking care of his guys.
He got promoted because he smooths the
clients. Play the game a little bit.