Cool question over here. You, um,
he's leaving it. Uh, I'd like to
come to bed. Uh, good evening Jocko.
Good evening. Uh,
what lesson do you wish you would have
learned earlier in life that you now
know?
It is discipline equals freedom.
I mean, that is the thing that,
that when I connected
that together in my head,
that the fact that that applies
to absolutely everything,
that's the biggest lesson that I wish
I would have learned earlier in life.
And if I would've figured that out,
then I would've been doing a lot better
and I would've done a lot better.
I would've been a lot better of a person.
The thing that I try to tell kids,
I try and tell them that for sure.
But the other thing that I
think kids miss is kids. And,
and this is something that I
completely missed as a kid.
The actions that you take
now affect your future.
That sounds so obvious.
But when you're 14,
you just think, no, nothing. I, you
know, my life is only another 20 minutes.
So what I'm doing right now doesn't
really matter. So when I talk to kids,
I try and explain to them that
discipline equals freedom.
And then I tried to explain to them that
what you're doing right now really will
have an impact to where
you are in the future.
And I don't know if you listened
to that podcast that I do,
the warrior kid podcast that I did
in number 19 about my friend Jeff and
I talked about it on the adult
podcast as well. But you know,
it's a classic story.
I had a best friend when I was
little and we separated friendship,
not we were still friends,
but we, we, we drifted apart.
He started getting into partying and
getting into drugs and all that and I
didn't.
And his trajectory in life just
went down and I joined the navy,
which was great and it put me on
a good path almost involuntarily.
But he ended up, he ended up
killing himself and you know,
it was drugs, it was
alcohol and it was just bad.
But while I was going through
buds, he killed himself.
And what I tried to explain to the kids
on the warrior kid podcast is like the
decisions that the little decisions
that you make, they matter.
They add up and you have
to connect those dots.
Otherwise you don't know where you're
going to end up and it might be bad.