This is Jocko podcast number one
oh nine with Echo Charles and me,
Jocko Willink. Good
Evening Echo. Good evening.
Okay.
One September,
1942 the army in the field,
comrade fighters,
commanders and political workers.
Heroic defenders of Stalin Grad,
the bitter fighting for the city of
Stalin Grad has been raging for months.
The Germans have lost
hundreds of tanks and planes.
Hitler's brutalized hordes are advancing
toward Stalin Grad and the Volga over
mountains of dead bodies of their own
men and officers are Bolshevik party.
Our nation,
our great country have given us the task
not to let the enemy reach the Bolga to
disturb to defend the city of Stalin Grad.
The Defensive Stalin Grad is of decisive
importance for the whole Soviet front.
Okay.
Without sparing our strength
and with scorn for death,
we shall defy the Germans the way to
the Volga and not give up Stalin Grad.
Each one of us must bear in mind that
the capture of Stalin Grad by the Germans
and their advanced to the vulgar,
we'll give our enemies new
strength and weaken our own forces,
not one step back.
Okay.
The war council expects on
unlimited courage, tenacity,
and heroism in the fight with the
onrushing enemy from all the fighters,
commanders, and political workers from
all the defenders and Stalin, Groton,
the enemy must and will be smashed
on the approaches to Stalin Grad.
Okay.
Forward against the enemy up into the
unremitting battle comrades for Stalin
Grad for our great country
death to the German invader.
Okay,
so that is a clearly a note
from the general on the ground.
The member of the war council
of the Stalin Grodd and
southwest front Lieutenant
General Khrushchev sent to the troops
obviously that we're preparing to defend
Stalin Grad.
Now
there was another commander in the field
by the name of Paulus and he sent a
note to Hitler on 23 November,
1942 my fear since receipt of your radio
message of evening 20 to 101 events
have come thick and fast.
We have not succeeded in closing the
pocket to the southwest and West.
In pending enemy penetrations
begin emerge there.
Ammunition and fuel are coming to an end.
Numerous batteries and tanks
have shot themselves dry.
A timely and adequate
supply is impossible.
The army will shortly be destroyed unless
a concentration of forces succeeds and
totally defeating the enemy
attacking from the south and west.
For this, we must immediately
withdraw all forces from Stalin,
Grad and strong detachments
from the northern front.
Unavoidable sequel must then be a breakout
towards the southwest since eastern
and northern front can no longer
be held with such weak forces.
In this case,
we will lose much material,
but the majority of the
valuable combatants and at
least a part of the material
will be preserved.
Okay.
I retained full responsibility for this
message even if I add that commanding
generals heights, Strecker,
Hubei, Jack Mill, von side.
Let's all share this evaluation of
the situation based on the situation.
I again request freedom of action.
Hi,
my fure signed Paulus,
so the Russians were effective
in surrounding the Germans,
the German sixth army.
As a matter of fact,
250 to 300,000 men fully
surrounded now by the Russians.
Okay.
Here's what Hitler wrote back.
Six army has been temporarily
and circled by Russian forces.
I intend to concentrate the
army in the area, Stalin Grad,
north coat lube on hill one 37 hill one
35 Marineau Fucka Zit Benko stolid Grad
south.
The army may rest assured that I will
do everything to bring supplies to it
accordingly and relieve it in time.
I know the brave six army
and its commander and chief
and I am sure it will do
its duty,
signed Adolph Hitler.
So,
and we'll get into this.
Hitler over and over again is asked if
the troops on the ground can try and
escape from Stalin Grad and
over an over again. He says, no,
you cannot leave.
You will fight to the last bullet.
And on the 30th of January,
1943 Hermann goring,
who was the Nazi Reich's marshal
of the entire German racks,
or he's this senior military man of the
entire German army from 1940 until the
end of the war.
And even though Stalin
Grad had not fallen yet,
he gave this speech about their
sacrifice of these German soldiers
and he gave it, it was obviously
heard on the radio, et Cetera.
And it's spread.
And actually the soldiers on
the ground in Stalin Grad,
the German soldiers heard this speech,
and again,
we'll get more to what the reactions were,
but I'm going to read that
part of that speech right now.
It made one shutter,
but Stalin had enormous masses
at his disposal and used old men,
women and children, and did not
bother about supplies are sufficient.
Food or transport.
The Russians used the whip or the bullet.
The Germans alone could resist and
could wrestle with such an adversary.
Everything depended on them with the
greatest respect to other nations.
The Germans are the only ones in Europe
in a position to break Russia and
destroy bolshevism of
all the terrific battles.
The battle for Stalin Grad stood
out like a gigantic monument,
which would one day be regarded as the
greatest and most heroic battle in German
history. So he's referring to this
in the past tense. Once again, this,
this hasn't been,
this hadn't finished yet,
but he's referring to it like it's in
the past tense because for all practical
purposes, it was back to the document.
Every German soldier would
come to pronounce the word
stolen grind with holy awe
and remember that it was there that germ
Germany set this seal of final victory
because people that
fought like that must win.
Germany has now become the
guarantor of European freedom,
culture and life.
But for the fighters of Stalin Grad,
the Russians might have obtained their
objective. Now they are too late.
The defenders of styling
rod had obeyed the law,
which everyone must obey the law to die.
For Germany,
this law was not only binding on soldiers,
but on the whole German nation.
The Nation must not question whether it's
stand at Stalingrad has been necessary
or not.
The law had ordered them to do so.
So here the saying don't
question one question.
The sacrifice of 250,000
men don't question it.
It was of no concern to the German soldier
whether he died at stolen rod in the
African desert or Norway.
He always sacrificed himself
so that his nation might live
in ours when some people perhaps tried
to install more bid and sly thoughts into
your brains than we must always look at.
The fear they're shining.
And greatest example,
they could believe that the
Almighty had led this man,
a God sent man to pass through
innumerable dangers and become greater and
greater all for nothing that
providence had given them,
this man who had made them into
the strongest nation in the world.
These are guarantees that
justify our belief in victory.
So we're talking about Hitler here,
by the way,
as a God sent Ma'am
in difficult times are real leaders tested
and people prove their worth in hard
trials.
I,
the commander in chief of the loof
[inaudible] suffered exceptionally when I
heard of the results of the bombings,
and although I did my best
to prevent it from happening,
it must be recognized as unavoidable
and must not influence our will for
resistance.
We know a tremendous heroic song from a
match without equal that was called the
battle of the need loans.
They too stood in a hall of fire and fire
quenching their thirst with their own
blood,
but fought and fought to the last
such a fight is raging there today
because of people who can fight like that
must win.
And before these men,
a millennia
previous there stood in a small gorge in
Greece and infinitely brave and daring
man with his 300
Leah nineties stood with 300 Spartans
from a tribe known for it's bravery and
boldness
and an overwhelmingly numerical
superior enemy attacked and attacked and
attacked again and again.
Even then,
it was a rush from the Asian
east against the Nordic people.
Huge numbers of men were
available to Xerxes,
but the 300 men did not waver or falter,
fighting a losing battle,
hopeless but not meaningless.
And then the last man fell.
And in this bottle neck
there is a sentence
wanderer.
If you come to Sparta report that
you had seen us lying here as the law
commanded,
they were 300 men.
My comrades and Millennia have passed.
But today that battle,
that sacrifice still counts as the
greatest example of heroic soldiering.
And today this fight is there.
This sacrifice is there and stolen Grodd
and one day it will be sad if you go to
Germany, tell them you have
seen us lying in stolen grog
as the law commanded us to protect
the security of our people.
And as I said,
those were the words of Herman goring,
who was the senior officer
of the German military.
Okay.
At that time.
And those were his words.
And of course his words were lies.
Okay.
All of them were lies and no one knew
that better than the men on the ground.
Okay?
In and around the Russian city of Stalin
Rod nearly 1500 miles away from Berlin,
freezing, starving,
surrounded low on ammunition,
lacking medical supplies,
and lacking cold weather gear and
lacking any kind of real leadership.
And they also serve the intonation
that lacked the moral high ground.
Okay?
Does it matter of fact,
their nation's leaders lacked
any kind of morality to all,
and this is clear in the aggression
that they unleashed in the world and the
atrocities that they committed in
mass murder of millions of people.
And it's clear
that they had no morality whatsoever
based on how they treated their own
soldiers.
Okay.
Who,
like many soldiers
were men that were fighting not for
political powers or for political ideals,
created an an ivory tower,
thousands of miles away from them.
But for the ideals of a soldier himself,
duty and courage and honor,
that's what soldiers fight for.
Ed.
Okay.
The ultimate thing that they fight for
as we have heard time and time again,
is for their brothers on the line with
them to their left and to their right.
And one of those men
was named Yo Hakim
weeder.
He was an intelligence officer in the
eighth corps of the German six army.
And he wrote about his experiences in
a book called Stolen Gorod memories of
hell
yeah.
Where he recalls what he and other
German soldiers went through physically,
mentally,
yeah.
And spiritually.
Okay.
As they were abandoned by their leaders
as they were abandoned by life.
Okay.
And as they were abandoned.
Bye. Hope itself.
Okay.
Let's
go to the book
again.
This is your Keem weeder.
Yeah.
And the book is called Stolen
Grodd memories of hell.
No.
After meticulous preparations
of gigantic proportions,
the Russians with they're overwhelmingly
superior armor and cavalry forces
attacking like lightning from the north.
And the following day from the east
press star entire sits sixth army into an
iron vice.
Within three days,
the encircling ring was closed at
collage on the Dan and Co on the dawn and
constantly reinforced.
Okay.
Stunned.
We stared at our situation maps on
which medicine thick red lines of
encirclement and arrows
show the enemy attacks,
penetrations and directions of advance.
We had never imagined a catastrophe
of such proportions to be possible,
okay.
The mighty wedges of the Russian
armored columns could not be stopped.
And a myriad of highly mobile cavalry
troops' increase the muddle and confusion
in the rear of the bloody
rent front of the army.
Okay,
so you know, obviously I skipped a
little bit moving into this port point,
but at this point they're
completely surrounded, like I said,
cut off and the Russians
are applying the pressure.
The enemy appeared to be systematically
are evading our blows and to be
withdrawing into the depths of Russia.
So this is going,
he's kind of reflecting back on how they
ended up there and he says that he says
the enemy appeared to be systematically
evading our blows and to be withdrawing
into the depth of Russia.
This is what the Russians do.
It's what they did in Napoleon.
Okay,
in 1812 and they're doing it again here
and he back to the book,
taken as a whole,
this was a masterpiece of general staff
thinking today I'm convinced that those
withdrawals of what Russian forces during
the summer of 1942 or an outstanding
and Nachman of traditional
war Russian war tactics.
So Hitler got Lord in and
they didn't pay attention.
They didn't reflect on history.
And as we all, while I was,
most people know this was also Hitler
opening another front and trying to fight
on multiple fronts at the same time,
which,
which goes against a certain law of
combat called prioritize and execute.
Focus your, your forces on your most
important thing and then move on.
Hitler gets an F on prioritize and execute
back to the book it had now come to pass.
We were actually caught in a trap.
How were we to get out series as the
situation in the pocket and he refers to
this area as the pocket.
This is the pocket of Russian soldiers.
Serious has the situation in the pocket
was from the very outset in our bunker.
That was still an atmosphere of confidence
and a certain feeling of superiority,
so that's by the way,
that's how you end up in these situations
and the Germans absolutely believed
their own propaganda,
that they were the best soldiers in that
they were the master race and that the
these Bolsheviks couldn't fight them.
When you believe that,
you think you can march right into Stalin,
grab and take it and the wind is
not going to bother you immediately.
An eerie memory arose within
me and intensified my amp
apprehensive unrest with
each passing day.
It was the memory of several fanatical
statements that Hitler had recently made
in public speeches. The
German soldier. He said,
now stood on the vulva and no power on
earth could make him leave the supreme
warlord. That's a reference to
Hitler and he's got an in quotes.
The supreme warlord had
emphatically committed himself.
He had prophecized and demanded that
styling rod be relentlessly attacked and
taken in presumptuous terms.
He'd even sworn before God and history,
never again to relinquish on this
conquest presenting it as already achieved
with such an attitude as this on the
part of the supreme warlord was giving up
the vulgar and retreating
conceivable at all.
So Hitler had painted himself into a
corner with a paintbrush of arrogance and
it ended up in this situation where he's
saying, nope, we're never going to leave,
and he does not.
Back to the book,
the fate of more than a quarter million
human beings with decided over such a
distance so that the fewer
headquarters is 2000 mile,
2000 kilometers. It's like 1500 miles
distant away and they're making decisions.
This is called micromanagement, by the
way. This is called micro management.
This is not decentralized command.
This is the fourth law of combat.
From the book called extreme ownership.
Hitler gets an F on decentralized command.
He's micromanaging his troops
that are 1500 miles away.
The fate of more than a quarter million
human beings was decided over such a
distance from their Hitler repeatedly
addressed orders and appeals directly to
stolen,
wrote to the Stalin Ground Army,
which had been removed from under the
command of Army Group B and reassigned to
the newly form army group.
Don Don.
Don is a river now.
Everybody knew that they needed to perform
a military maneuver referred to as a
breakout, which means you picture your
inner circle, you're surrounded by troops.
You pick one part of that circle of,
of the people that are surrounding you
and you attack and you break through it.
It sounds like what it is,
it's a breakout.
Everybody knew that they needed to break
out. They're like, hey, we're surrounded.
We need fuel. We need water, we need
food. We don't have any of that.
We need to break out,
and so everyone was kind of prepared
to do that. Back to the book.
Our army still deposed of about 130 combat
ready tanks and about the same number
of armored scout cars and other
armored vehicles and other words.
We still had a powerful motorized
units available everywhere.
People were waiting for the relieving
signal for the breakout with fluttering
hearts.
We followed the preparations that were
taking place mainly in the western sector
of the army.
In anticipation of the expected operation.
The order had be given to destroy
all superfluous materiel everywhere,
damaged guns, tanks and trucks use this
communication and engineering equipment,
huge amounts of clothing,
files and paper,
even food where being consigned to flames,
so they all think that they're going
to break out there. Assuming, look,
we're going to break out this the only
solution right now. We're surrounded.
We need to attack one area and get out
of here. So they start going, okay,
before we leave, I'm going to burn as
fuel. We're going to burn this food.
We're not going to leave anything
for the Russians. Back to the book.
According to the decision by army command,
the retreat from Stalin Grad
was to begin on 26 November.
We did not entertain the slightest
doubt that the supreme command must be
convinced of its necessity. We counted
firmly on it's being carried out.
I will never forget how stunned
we all were. The agitation. Yes,
the petrifying,
a horror that befell us,
especially among the higher ranks
of our staff, went on 24 November.
The message came in from army that Hitler
had forbidden the plan breakout and
finally ordered the Stalin Grad army to
temporarily take up a position of all
around defense. So Hitler says, no,
you're not leaving. Oh,
you're surrounded by the way,
they're surrounded by a force of
about a million Russian soldiers, but,
but, but it's more than that
because they're surrounded
by the country of Russia.
Back to the book,
that fatal radio message from the
distant fure headquarters had come like a
stroke of lightning, forbidding the
plan, withdrawal of our northern front,
that attachment of our
forces from Stalin Grad,
and thereby the hope for the breakout.
This decision by the supreme command was
just as heavy a blow for the staff at
the army as it was for us.
We are unable to satisfy ourselves
as to why all the reports,
admonitions and requests
for our responsible of our
responsible higher staffs
who were best able to judge the events
and all the dangers they entailed had not
been successful.
So this is something that patents said
the commander on the ground is always
right. Meaning if you're sitting
in an ivory tower somewhere,
there's a guy on the ground, he's right
and you're wrong. He's on the ground.
He knows what's happening. Now, could
we come up with some exceptions to this?
Absolutely. You have better intelligence
of what's happening. You may know some,
you may be have overhead
coverage or you get,
you get air reports or you have the,
in these days you have satellites
looking at things. So yeah,
there's situations where you
might know a little bit more,
but the default thought process
should be the guy on the ground is,
is has a better situational
awareness than I do.
I'm going to go with their call and here's
Hitler saying no. Now, general policy,
who is the commander of all the,
all the German soldiers general,
Paul's back to the book General Paulus
addressed himself directly to Hitler with
a very serious and responsible evaluation
of the situation in this momentous
radio message.
He had adamantly stressed that the fact
that all his senior commanding generals
shared the conviction that because it
would be impossible to adequately supplied
the army in time,
it would shortly be destroyed unless a
concentration of all available forces
were to succeed in divine
decisively beating the enemy,
attacking from the west and the south.
So it's not just one general at
Saint Louis every but every user,
there's,
there's 250 to 300,000 Germans there.
There's a lot of senior military people.
All of them are saying,
we need to leave.
Hitler Says No. Why? Because
Hitler's just that like, no, you got,
you guys don't leave because we're
were Germans. We flight till the Dan.
It's arrogance or,
I mean it's,
it's absolutely partially arrogance
that he thinks no, we'll hold out.
It will still just when two
were us. Yeah. We'll just,
we'll just hold it out and I
think he's being stubborn and,
okay.
Yeah. He has the kind of word like
he, he made a call kind of thing.
He made a call and then they're like,
hey, we this, the call is no good.
We're going to do this. He's like,
no, I made the call. Yeah, exactly.
What's going on?
Ego.
I mean obviously Hitler has probably one
of the biggest egos of any human being
ever can hear you see it.
Yeah, sure. In full effect.
Okay.
Even though he had left,
no doubt, but in his view,
the decision promising salvation lane,
an immediate breakout in the end,
he to this talking about policy in the
end he to submitted and obeyed for him in
order was an order in spite of everything.
All that remained to us was to hope for
a rescue operation from the outside.
I will say this actually,
and there's some books that the parts
of this book that I'm not going to cover
because we just don't have time.
Well,
there's that guy that gave that
speech goring the beginning.
He had also told Hitler, Hey, no worries.
We can resupply. He was the before taking
over all the German military forces.
He was in charge of the German
air force, the Luftwaffe. Uh,
and he said, look, we can resupply these
guys. Don't worry about it. Don't worry.
And I think he probably said that at a
time when it didn't look like they're
going to get completely surrounded, you
know? Oh yeah, we'll, we supply him,
don't worry about them.
And we'll get into some of the numbers
on what they said they could do.
But that's another reason why Hitler,
Hitler thought, Oh, we can resupply.
But he also had people on the ground.
He's surrounded by, yes men. Gotcha.
So no one wants to disagree with
the boss, man. In this case,
Adolf Hitler by saying, so when he
says, look, can't we resupply them?
Yes, yes, we can respond from the air. And
also he was saying, hey, can't someone,
instead of them breaking out and
going toward back towards Germany,
why don't we have some German troops
go towards them and break into them?
That way we can open up some supply lines.
So when did he get told when he,
when he offered that solution,
he got told, yes, we can
do it. Yes, we can do it.
So he's surrounded by yes men.
And you know how he ended up surrounded
by yes men. His Ego. I don't want,
I don't like to be told, oh, you're
going to tell me no, you're fired.
Get someone in here that's going to tell
me that they can do what I'm saying.
And then that person's
going to get promoted.
And then you get surrounded by
people that want to get promoted.
Chuck
proceeding on and there was one
general that really made it,
made a significant effort.
Here we go back to the book initially,
General Vaughan side. Litz
was dumbfounded, stunned.
He accepted the order,
but in his heart he rejected it.
Particularly since he was painfully
aware that his own war hands were tied.
Not until the following day, 25,
November, 1942 did general von side,
let's react to Hitler's orders.
And his reaction was as much filled
with a sense of responsibility as it was
temperamental,
addressed to the army command.
It took the form of a detailed evaluation
of the situation that core commander
had had his chief of staff
prepare. It's surmised, once again,
all the arguments against the solid
ground army digging in and urged the
breaking out of the ring immediately.
So what's cool about this book,
they actually have this actual
document that this guy wrote.
Have you ever heard me talk on the podcast
about getting all your ducks in a row
and like, Hey, if my boss tells
me now, cool, I'm going to,
I'm going to get all the information,
I'm going to come back.
And how many agree if I'm going to make a,
uh,
a bullet proof argument and my boss is
going to agree with, because you can't,
my argument's gonna be bulletproof
because I'm right. And if I wasn't right,
then I wouldn't, I wouldn't
go this far, right? I'm not
gonna, I'm not gonna put my,
my reputation on the line
arguing something that I
don't truly believe is right.
You know, all through I'll say, okay,
well you know what, he could be right,
so you know what, I'm going to try and
execute it to my best of my ability.
In this case. Sidelights is
like, no, it's not. No. And,
and he says, okay, I'm going to perform.
I'm gonna put together this thing.
They have the document inside this book.
I would read it, but it's long. It's,
it's so detailed that it
would take too much time,
but it lays out every little detail of
why they need to break out and not in an
emotion. That's what's beautiful about
it. Not In an emotional way. Well,
maybe I just need to check myself
because maybe more emotion was needed.
But generally if you come across as
really emotional, Hitler would think, oh,
well a boss would think, oh, you're
just emotional about this echo.
You're just emotional buddy. You just
need to calm down, carry out the orders.
So he didn't he, he played the role or
he, he used the strategy of just calm,
this is what's going on.
This is what needs to change or this
is what we need to do and if we don't,
it's going to be catastrophic.
Back to the book in the
emergency situation,
intensified by the o k h and o cages
over commandos date eight or switches,
the supreme high command of the German
Army General Vaughn side lifts demanded
from the commander in chief of the army
that he act immediately against orders,
in other words, against Hitler. So, so
sidelights when silence got told no,
he's like, no, listen, we need to do
it anyways. That's how passionate.
So now he's starting to get a
little bit emotional and passionate.
He declared it to be an imperative duty
to the army and the German people to
obey the dictates of conscious and to
seize the freedom of action that had been
forbidden in order to prevent
threatening catastrophe.
The memo was passed on by army command,
but had no effect whatsoever.
And so they had to suffer the additional
pain that in the final analysis they
could,
but give in and fulfill the bidder
soldierly duty to obey against their own
better insight.
Now I will tell you that as Napoleon said,
if you execute a plan
that you know is wrong,
you are culpable for
executing it and these guys,
they would not stand up against it.
Like
back to the book,
we were all deeply disturbed and full of
despair and in our hearts even outraged
what was being demanded of
us normally contradicted.
All military experience at win against
every soldierly feeling and robbed of has
any hope of any hope of being able to
save ourselves by breaking out under her
own power.
Okay.
In the last week of November when the
formations that had been heavily damaged
during the initial retreat where hastily
and with great difficulty establishing
themselves on a new main
line of Resistance Army
issued a grave order of the
day. I can still remember
the exact wording it started.
Six army has been surrounded.
This is not your fault
as always, you have fought bravely
and tenaciously up to the moment.
The enemy had you by the neck.
It went on to point out
that the hard fighting,
suffering and deprivations that would
still be demanded of the troops and which
they would have to endure for
a time in hunger and frost.
Trusting in the help from outside
that had been so definitely promised.
So Hitler did say, Hey, I'm going
to send help from the outside.
Don't worry about it.
You stay put.
Finally mentioned was made of the
relief operation to which Hitler had
personally committed himself
psychologically clever
and calculating the appeal
ended with the encouraging words,
promising consolation and salvation.
Hold on the fure,
we'll get you out this final sentence.
Appealing so strongly to emotion,
which injected a new tone into the
previously factual and sober language of
military orders gave rise to
discussions among our staff.
It made me realize on top of
all that had already happened,
how great the sacrifice was going to be
that would be demanded of the troops.
By the way,
these guys traveled there and
had a really hard time of it.
They know how hard it was
for them to get there,
and now they're being told that
the people that are going to,
the way that they're going to get saved
is by someone else coming behind them to
help them going through the same
hardships that they barely got there.
So they're there.
Their outlook isn't good on the
situation he had. They're doubtful.
Back to the book,
a large number of the soldiers who
had been in constant exhaustion is
incontinent and exhausting action in the
front line for two years without leave,
without having been home to see their
loved ones. So a lot of these guys,
so they had actually
survived a winter early on.
They had survived a winter as they
pushed into German or as they put it into
push in Russia and now they're
waiting for another one.
But these soldiers had been
fighting for two straight years.
Hard fighting back to the book.
Naturally the troops,
we're not in a position to appreciate
the full extent of the suffering and
deprivation as they were about to face.
They knew nothing of the difficult
problems of the overall supply situation.
So again, this guy is working at the
headquarters, meaning he's, you know,
with the commanders and the leadership,
so he's tracking all the
logistics of the situation.
The frontline soldier doesn't know.
The front line soldier expects that
they're going to bring me bullets,
they're gonna bring me food.
He realizes because he sees
what's actually happening
and that that's going to
be a real problem.
They had no inkling of the countless
worries that lay so heavily and
depressingly on the higher staffs,
nor at first were they aware that that
at one stroke the encirclement had made
it impossible to complete preparations
for winter positions out there and the
supply depots of the army,
late tens of thousands of fur coats,
warm stockings, protective headgear,
and other items of winter clothing,
which could now no longer reach the
encircled forces. For the most part,
the men remained completely inadequately
supplied with winter gear and exposed
to the murderous frost is that thousands
and thousands of warm weather gear
or I should say cold weather gear
and now they're going to get nothing.
They're caught off back the book.
We calculated that our own army,
whose total strength before the INCIRCL
men had been about 330,000 men now
numbered about 280,000 so they're
already short at 50,000 and killed
we the staff,
the officers in the staff departments
also pinned our hopes on the relief
operation,
which was being prepared.
No one even considered that Hitler would
be ready to abandon the outstandingly
proven six army on the Vulcan, throw it
to the wolves. So these guys are even,
I said that even though I
said they weren't hopeful,
they're also thinking there's no way
that Hitler is going to leave 300,000
soldiers out here. There's no
way. Yeah. Back to the book,
he was bound to find ways and means
to rectify the devil situation.
There were even starry eyed
dreamers, not, however,
among the older and more experienced
who maintained that the fewer would not
only get us out,
but it probably already conceived a
plan to turn our apparent defeat into a
glorious triumph. By and circling all the
enemies armies that are surrounding us.
None of these dreamers and
believers in miracles who kept this,
who kept surfacing here and
there until the very end,
had a clear idea of what was implied
by the fact that German soldiers will
simultaneously fighting on the North Cape
and the Bay of Biscay and the front of
Leningrad and veers on in the
caucus in Crete and in north Africa.
Okay,
so again, this guy's fighting
fronts all over the place
and the and the staff officers,
the leadership knew how thinly
spread the German army was.
The frontline troops in, you know,
they didn't make sense of that.
During the weeks of December,
the fighting strength of the army was
deteriorating at a horrendous pace.
The blame for this lay mainly in the,
in the inadequate air lift here,
a catastrophic picture was slowly emerging
in order to be able to maintain its
ability to live and fight.
Our army had initially requested
750 tons of supplies per day,
okay.
Later reducing this to 500 tons per day.
The J you 52 cargo aircraft
had about a two ton load.
The want the h g one one one fighter
bomber had held about 1.5 tons.
So this is going to require like 2000
aircraft to be able to make this happen.
What do they end up with?
Back to the book,
they only brought in 80 to 120
tons of the required supplies.
In other words,
not more than one fifth of the amount
needed purely and simply this meant a
daily deficit of 10,000 kilograms bread
and a fatal under supply of desperately
needed fuel and ammunition. So we're
getting one fifth of what they need.
Now we have to be careful cause that's
a little statistic that were thrown out
there, right? Like oh we're
getting one fifth of what we need,
but I'll think of a human being. And
what you need is a human being just food.
And you cut that down to
one fifth of what you need.
You know you need 2,500 calories a day,
you're going to get 500 [inaudible].
That's what we're talking about.
Yeah, you need, and by the way,
you're fighting and you're going to,
you're being attacked.
So you need thousand bullets a day.
Okay.
Right. You need a thousand bullets
a day. You're getting 120 bullets.
It's there.
Things are not looking good.
Back to the book, the
sunset, soon after lunch,
and by 1400 and 1500 hours, it
was already dark. So this is,
now we're talking Russian winter by
two or three o'clock in the afternoon,
it's dark.
Hmm.
And every day this to reminded us,
depressingly here in the desolation of
the snow Brep snow bounce step of the
enormous distance that separated us from
home were we not all the living and the
dead long buried in a gigantic mass grave.
Thoughts like this occasionally befell
me when I returned from various sectors
of the front,
where in my role as liaison officer,
I had been sent on specific assignments
to gather urgently needed information.
Okay?
They're on the heights above the,
the infamous row shock a valley.
The men of our divisions
lay in desperate battle,
demanding bloody sacrifice there in
the trenches, in foxholes, in the snow.
The soldiers were dying of exhaustion
and cold because they're steadily
shrinking. Rations of bread and
other food issued. Food issued.
We're no longer sufficient to provide
the physical stamina needed to combat
frost at sickness,
so they're starving to death.
They're starving to death in
the freezing death and they're,
they're being attacked and killed by
the Russians with no with no Emma.
One day in the second week of December,
the staff's first heard the news that
the army group, dawn under field,
Marshall Van Main Stein von Main Stein
had begun the long hope relief for the
long hope for relief operation. Soon the
good news, it also reached the troops.
The words gave new impetus everywhere
in particularly on the hard pressed
western perimeter of the pocket spread
like lightning mainstream man Stein is
coming.
The already dying hopes burst
forth the new new courage,
happy expectations. A new spirit
of initiative began to blossom.
The sufferings and sacrifices to
date had not been in vain. After all,
salvation was now beckoning what the fewer
had promised he was bound to deliver,
so they get word Ben Stein's coming.
This is this,
this is good. If everything
went well, they fought,
the hour of all relief could
just coincide with Christmas.
The motorized groups and strong tank
units being led by Colonel General Hoff
elements of which had been brought in
from France in great haste had begun their
relief,
offensive Hoff spearhead tanks
were only 50 kilometers away.
Hold on.
We're coming.
Said one of the encouraging radio messages
would spread like wildfire amongst
the western edge of the pocket. So they're
in radio communication 50 kilometers
and this well respected leader Hoff.
He's on the way and he tells him,
hold on, we're coming. Do you ever,
isn't that like a jinx right
there? You know what I mean? Like,
do you ever celebrate something
even even inside your head,
you celebrate something a little bit
before? You should don't ever do that.
Am I superstitious?
Because I believe that way.
If you think that that's
how it truly works.
But I think, um, I th I
think it's superstitious,
but I also think there's some psychology
behind that. Yeah, I think so too. Yeah.
Yeah. Especially if you realize,
if you just realize, oh,
I just celebrated early right there.
So it's,
it makes you uneasy or
something like that.
I feel like that guy,
that guy got a certain level
of satisfaction just by
saying like, don't worry,
we're coming. Like he had this
moment of glory. That's glorious.
It's a glorious thing to be able
to say, don't worry, we're coming.
It's a glorious thing to be able to say,
and he took that.
He took the easy money right there
psychologically, instead of being
like, hey, we're not there yet.
We need to be ready to worry about
where we are. Yeah, yeah. The yeah.
Finish strong kind of thing. It's like the
guy who's running the touchdown, right?
He celebrates the 30 yard line, right?
The 25 he puts the hand up. Who was that?
There's like a classic creeps
up behind them. You know what?
This guy wasn't even Leon Lett.
He played for the,
I want to say Dallas cowboys.
He was like a,
like a deep, deep, I want
to say nineties maybe.
How many other Dallas cowboy players
can you remember the name of from the
nineties do you remember?
A lot of them.
Like a handful. Just let the coroner,
Leon, he's infamous for this. I mean,
poor guy, you know, he, he's a
defensive line man or something.
Recovers a fumble, runs it in for
the touchdown and he's, he's doing,
he's not even doing and putting
it in the above his head.
He's putting it on the site,
kind of like celebrating it's,
and I think they stripped
him and recovered it I think
if I'm not mistaken. Yeah,
it was bad.
Psychologically you can't stop.
You gotta Kinda strong zee money
you to finish the sprint to the
finish line or that like
races, like a hundred meter
dash, you know the guys like,
or the 200 meter and he's like,
yeah, I want it. Then the guy,
I'm real hungry guy gets it, you know,
right at the end. So that's Hoff.
Hoff takes the easy money
tank can be doing it off.
Back to the book in the sure knowledge
that before us was the last chance for
our salvation.
We feverously awaited the decisive
hour with a feeling of confidence.
The orders we expected could
not be delayed much longer,
but all too soon. Our hopes were
to be bitterly disappointed.
Alarming messages began to came in
rapidly attacking Russian tank forces were
embroiling,
the relieving army and heavy fighting.
We're slowing the advance and finally
leading in connection with the Russian
offensive group operations west of the
dawn to a serious crisis for the entire
army group.
One of the attacks hit Colonel General
Hoff who is hastening towards us in
fearful tension and delay
mounting an agitation.
We read the messages we were receiving
from the far distant German air
reconnaissance and radio
surveillance you units soon.
These brought news of disaster.
The relief operation had began to run
down Hoff's forces in turn threatened with
being surrounded.
We're finally forced to retreat.
The front fell back hundreds of kilometers
and the encircled Stalin Grad or me
on the Volga was left to its fate.
Yeah.
Only much later was I to learn of tragic
details of the events and circumstances
that had sealed the fate of the
encircled army. At this point,
I did not know then that Hitler was still
in no way prepared to give up stolen
ground on the vulgar that for the second
time and after the dramatic conflicts
and the conflicts that he's talking about,
his between him,
between Hitler and the
people that his advisors,
he had explicitly forbidden the breakout
of the six army against the will of his
chief of staff and an opposition to
the demands of the army group dawn.
So
hit little leaves them,
abandons them back to the book.
Among the circle of our closer comrades,
we no longer entertained any illusions
about the bleakness of our situation.
The German front had withdrawn a great
distance away and for the time being
there would be no new thought or Knuth.
No thought of a new relief operation.
Would the German front be able to
hold out for several more weeks?
It was hardly to be expected.
Hunger, frost and sickness.
We're cutting terribly.
Intuit's waning strength and deaf was
reaping and an uncanny harvest and not
only on the fire spewing
iron ring around the pocket.
Yeah.
And even the conditions for a great saving
breakout operations scarcely existed
any longer.
In such an event,
the army would only be able to remain
mobile for a few kilometers because the
lack of fuel.
Yeah,
and if Stalin Grad will
work to be given up,
what then would happen to
the growing army of wounded,
sick and exhausted men?
Did the o k h intend to
give up the vulgar at all?
The measures ordered so far seem to
point the opposite way. Once again,
I was often forced to recall Hitler's
fanatical wor words about the German
soldier on the vulgar about Stalin Rod,
and each time an icy uneasy
crept through my bones,
maybe yes,
maybe we were supposed to hold on to the
bitter end to stay put and fight to the
last bullet.
Okay.
On the dark horizon,
the outlines of a terrible
disaster began to emerge.
Christmas eve approached all the
visible and the invisible wounds,
which the cruel events had caused,
burned even more painfully on this night.
The atmosphere was depressed.
Memories of former Christmas
celebrations with their blissful Shimmer,
only dimly illuminated are harsh reality.
As from a world bone gone.
Okay.
The well loved Christmas carols
sounded in low melancholy this.
So hope is pretty much vanquished
at this point. Not Completely,
cause he's still in May.
He's still saying maybe,
maybe they're just going to leave
us here and fight to the last man,
which is a crazy thought because
I'm going to say this number again,
250 to 300,000 soldiers.
This isn't like,
Hey, you've got 18 guys fight to last
man. It's the Alamo, right? Yeah.
This isn't that. This is
because that, that might have,
you know that that's not going to have
a strategic impact on the situation.
You lose 300,000 combat veterans,
which,
which, you know, the hard
combat hardened veterans,
this is going to have a
strategic implication. Mm.
I mean of course every
soldier that dies is,
is a epic of event in that soldier's life,
obviously in their family
and everything else.
But when you start talking about leaving
300,000 people to die for nothing,
it's, it's, he still can't quite get
that. He's still not quite there.
He sees it on the horizon.
He's not quite there though.
Back to the book.
The New Year had arrived.
Okay.
Jangling frost layover stolen grot over
the stall and drug pocket and breathe.
It's icy,
deadly breath.
The sharp wind blew through the joints
of doors and windows and in the bunkers
and from the floors,
the cold crept up to one's knees.
The daily casualty reports
from our divisions that
increasingly reported losses
other than by enemy action represented
a shattering balance on the death sheet.
So what he's saying there is like,
yeah, people are dying from combat,
but even more people are dying just
from cold and starvation. Yeah. Again,
the Russians furiously attacked
several sectors of our perimeter.
What did we have left to oppose these
powerful Russian elite troops who were
protected from the frost
and had a full stomach?
Not to mention there numerous tanks,
guns, rocket launchers, and mortars.
The only small numbers of heavy
weapons with insufficient,
strictly rationed ammunition.
It's all we had only emaciated men
exhausted by hunger among whom?
The fighting the cold
and spreading diseases.
We're taking a daily frightening tall.
How much longer could the
perimeter withstand the pressure?
It did not escape our attention that the
Russians appear to be concentrating in
front of our sector in preparation
for a major blow. The last sob,
sad possibility grew even
clearer on the dark horizon.
The fate of our destruction
by a shattering off friends
IV breaking over our
heads.
So again, it's interesting
that this guy's, well, two
things I should point out.
Number one,
it's interesting that this
guy's perspective because
he's in the staff and so he
sees more of what's happening
from the general officers.
But let's also make note that he's not
on the front lines and he's so he has it
relatively good,
meaning these protected by the,
by the rush from the Russians,
by some distance.
I mean he's still getting mortared,
etc. So getting artillery, but he's not,
he's not eye to eye with the Russians
like the guys like the soldiers on the
front lines that are sitting in a
little slit trench in the ground and the
Tundra. Hmm. One of the
things that he sees is a,
is a meeting here we go back to the book.
An important meeting of the general
staff took place. At our core,
which the commander in chief of the army
general policy attended with his chief
of staff,
the serious reserved expression of the
tall figure with the head of a scientist
reflected something of a
burden of responsibility that
press down tormenting Lee
on the shoulders of this man who was
the last time I was to see how our army
commander in the pocket.
As far as I can remember,
he never visited our core again.
I soon learned of the outcome of the
meeting and the grave words of our general
staff officers left no doubt about the
consequences of the orders that have been
issued in the meantime.
Okay.
They dealt with the Mo mobilization of
the last reserves of the six the army,
the encircled forces were to
hold on and fight to the last,
yeah.
For this purpose,
the formation of fortress battalions was
to be prepared and executed as quickly
as possible.
All remaining reserves of able bodied
men were to be collected in uses.
Infantry members of the WAFA ground
personnel and anti aircraft troops gunners
who no longer had guns. Pans are
granted years engineers, truck drivers,
clerical staffs,
rear echelon and supply personnel or
once again to be ruthlessly combed out,
the order of mounted to the
virtual disillusion of the
rear echelon services and
clearly demonstrated that the immobilized
army was doomed to stay put and fight
to the last man and the last bullet.
So there you go.
Everyone's going to fight cooks,
supply people.
You're all going to become an infantry
men now and this clearly indicates to a
weeder that that means they're not
going anywhere and they're going to stay
there. They're going to fight to
the last man back to the book,
we felt that we had already been written
off by the higher ups and all that
remained for us was to perform a heroic,
if futile gesture to ensure the
fulfillment of a the historic mission.
And he's got quotes around that of
the army of Stalin Grad on the vulgar.
The troops were again given
the cheering radio message,
which the fewer and supreme warlord
had sent at the turn of the year.
Six army has my promise that
everything is being done to get it out.
But we now viewed this
not just with doubt,
but as downright deception.
They don't believe Hitler anymore.
They used to just doubt him. Now. Now
they think he's deceiving them. And again,
this is not, this is no
small group people. Yeah.
Back to the book, the bread ration
was reduced to 50 grams per day,
ringing cold,
knowing Hong are creeping illness,
enemy fire combined in an indissoluble
offensive packed dysentery.
Typhoid fever had appeared as uncanny
guests and the plague of lice increased
from day to day.
Death danced as murderers,
Rondo back and forth
throughout the pocket.
His headquarters where the numerous
places of suffering despair,
the dressing stations in field hospitals
that filled to overflowing alarmingly.
But he also felt at home on the lines
day and night. So death is everywhere.
Isn't it weird? You know, you
think like just being sick.
You were telling me you were sick a
couple of days ago. Common cool. Yeah.
And you think about what being sick does
to you and now this is your being sick
and it doesn't matter. Like there's no
mercy, you're, you're, there's no mercy.
Back to the back during back
the book during 50 days,
that pocket battled lasted so far.
He, when he's talking about death,
he had already cleaned out
horribly among the men of the army.
About one third of its manpower was gone.
Of the more than 300,000 men who were
present at the time of the Russian
breakthrough,
about 200,000 we're probably still alive.
And how many of these enduring and hoping,
fighting and suffering
human beings had deaf,
not already marked on his own
news that we could no
longer count on any relief.
Before spring was really shattering.
There was nothing more to be done.
Save to hang on and it door the horror.
Now we get a little opportunity here.
Here we go.
There was a surrender proposal sent to
our encircled army by the Soviet supreme
command.
The document was addressed to Paula who
had been promoted to colonel general and
to all the officers and men of the
German forces fighting. It's stolen rod.
It was signed by Colonel General
of the artillery worn Varone off.
Yeah.
And by the commander in chief
of the forces of the Dawn
Front Lieutenant General
Rokos Wicki,
who had now obviously been put in sole
charge of all the forces surrounding us.
The proposal began with a short factual
and large the correct evaluation of our
situation. In particular, it's stress,
the catastrophic state of supply of our
troops who are suffering from hunger,
cold and sickness,
lack of winter clothing,
and terribly in sanitary conditions.
Realistic possibilities of breaking
the encircling ring no longer existed.
Any further resistance in such a
hopeless situation had to be senseless.
Therefore, in order to avoid further
unnecessary shedding of blood,
the Red Army was proposing
a number of terms.
The document ended with a
reference director to the
commander in chief of Stalin
Grad Army,
pointing out that in the event of refusal,
the forces of the Red Army and air force
would be obliged to destroy the pocket
for which he, Colonel General Paulus
would bear the responsibility.
You still got 200,000 people
and
you get an offer,
you get 24 hours to
respond. You basically
surrender everybody. Yeah,
everybody's going to surrender.
Yeah.
And and they weren't sure how
they were going to get treated.
I mean they were fairly confident,
wasn't be treated good. Uh,
hold on the whole though man.
It's all the dysentery treated very
good either that's not treating you very
good at all.
Back to the book,
we soon received various
orders, directives and
messages. Who's burden was that?
The surrender was out of the question.
The commander in chief had passed
the Russian ultimatum onto the fewer
headquarters and ask for freedom
of action for all eventualities.
It immediate reply hit the red personally
forbidden surrender and Paula said
rejected in writing the proposal,
the Soviet,
the troops were not informed
not to be informed in detail,
but from now on they were ordered to
fire without warning on flags of truth of
truce appearing near the front lines.
This instruction from army,
which we received by radio was especially
revealing as to the intentions of
leadership in our staff.
It was received with rejection at
objection because it was a clear breach of
international law so they don't get
told like, Hey, we're not spreading.
What they get told is if you
see anyone with flags, a truce,
shoot them immediately,
which is basically saying we're not
surrendering the back to the book.
I was reminded again of Hitler's high
sounding words about the invincibility of
the German soldier for whom nothing
must be seen to be impossible.
The very thought of capitulation
must be an irreconcilable,
must be irreconcilable with the
prestige of the supreme warlord.
He puts that in quotes every time I, I
don't call it out every time, but he does.
He's sorta mocking Hitler with that.
In his speech in Munich,
shortly before our encirclement,
he had had he not solidly sworn.
You may rest assured,
I repeat this with full responsibility
before God in history that we shall never
again leave Stalin Grad.
Never again for life or death.
We were committed to the cheerless.
Dawn's step here,
our fate must come full turn
the most terrible weeks.
We're still before us and
during those ICDs in January,
the fearful premonition of what was to
come descended upon us like a lead weight
on the morning of 10 January,
1943 exactly 24 hours after
the ultimatum had expired,
the Russian began the destruction of
the pocket with a hellish artillery
barrage.
It was the answer to the rejection of
the surrender proposal up upfront among
the staff's on the line. I again entered
the atmosphere of tension, excitement,
nervousness,
and despair.
The situation was partially
unclear and it confused the cat.
The catastrophe did indeed
appear to be unavoidable.
Okay.
Into this helpless situation. Orders
from army came in time and time again,
defend, hold, clear up the situation.
Fight to the last bullet,
okay.
From their desks,
2000 kilometers away and he puts in
parentheses and exclamation point,
the o k h together with the
constantly interfering fear,
her fear or headquarters
forbade any independent
withdrawal from endangered from
endangered sectors of
the perimeter and army,
which had to meticulously justify itself
for any change in the front line caused
by the pressure of circumstances. Obeyed
so does classic. It's micromanagement,
not decentralized command. They're
even saying, look, if your, if your,
if your is going to collapse,
don't fall back, just die.
Which is ridiculous because it doesn't
help the situation because now there's a
hole and now more,
more enemy.
You're going to come through the hole
and we're going to have people behind us.
Yeah. It's like full on kind of what
you were talking about last week.
Maybe it would be for last week. It's like
do it because I said so kind of thing.
Yeah like there's no really he is going
to die if there's no reason to do it.
No strategic reason.
They'll tactical reason.
Obviously it's do it cause I
said so. Yeah. Whatever. Yeah.
The army core divisions and regimens
obeyed often with bitter criticism,
criticism with open or hidden reservations
flaring up or knuckling under,
but they obeyed and the suffering and
dying of troops in the trenches and fox
holes in the IC step obeyed,
giving their all in the natural
fulfillment of their duty or an apathy and
silent despair.
Okay.
The higher leadership did not
stint with recognition, promotions,
decorations and metals rain
down on mass on the fighting,
suffering doomed men.
But what purpose did this huge,
monstrous commitment and dedication of
human being serve in the face of the
increasingly help military helplessness
and the daily worsening human plight?
I was becoming more and more depressed
by the torturing question of the why of
this sacrifice of most precious blood.
This Pinellas dining
was it not only for the sake of,
of a prestige that a military supreme
command thousands of kilometers removed,
mercilessly wished to maintain then
for whom the price in many thousands of
human lives did not appear to be too high.
Okay.
This question haunted me and would
not leave me until the final sorrowful
ending.
So he's asking why
they start to collapse from the perimeter
of the pocket in towards the city of
Stalin Grad you. Cause they were
kind of pushed out around it,
surrounding it and now they're starting
to fall back to it where they at least
have some coverage back to the book.
The withdrawal of the troops finally
turned into a full fledged flight into
which further formations and combat
groups of various divisions were drawn.
Whole units cease to exist in this
confusion in the sector of our neighbor to
our left.
This fate also put an end to a whole
division that had long been under our
command and in the end had
burned out like a slag heap.
I saw it's distraught general
now a commander without
troops wandering around in
a bunker,
desperately seeking a new assignment,
so he just lost 20,000 men.
He's walking around and saying,
what am I supposed to do now?
Back to the book and this desperate
withdraw was being carried out in icy cold
weather and piddle a snow storms at
30 degrees centigrade below zero.
That's negative 22
at 30 degrees below zero.
The remnant of the regiments that had
shrunk to combat groups and the suffering
hordes of their shadow of other shattered
units moved over the empty white step.
Staggering crowds, dragging,
dragging crowds of lost ha,
lightly wounded and
frostbitten soldiers with them.
How many of those that's
so far had been spared?
Enemy fire succumbed there to exhaustion
and overexertion to the strains of
hunger and to the cold.
Innumerable men fell by the wayside and
we're soon mercifully cupboard over by
the snow
and this was no longer
an authorized withdrawal.
The recoil of the front was now taking
place despite standing orders to hold and
maintain position at all costs and despite
the line of resistance laid down by
the okay. So they finally did
break and they finally said,
you know what?
Survival.
This is about survival and
we're not staying here anymore.
We're going to try and get
back, fall back. The cycle,
the psychological ability of the troops
to resist it now also been eroded.
There could no longer be any doubt about
our fate after the enemy had begun,
has decisive attack,
bent on destruction and our
disillusion was in full pro progress.
It was too late for alas. Departure
attempt to break out to the west,
help from outside could no longer be
considered more devastating even than the
enemy's weapons were
hunger, exhaustion, cold,
an illness of all kinds among the soldiers
who had not been adequately fed for
so many long weeks.
With the advent of the incredible
indescribable strains of daily retreats.
The situation had deteriorated.
Catastrophic Lee,
we were lacking in food
weapons, rest, warmth, hope.
In short, we were lacking in all
the vital conditions for fighting.
Since the long rejection
of the surrender proposal,
the troops had again survived a long,
terrible week of tenacious defensive
fighting, retreat and flight,
thereby tying down superior and
our enemy forces in their area.
Now,
after the loss of our life support base
Patomic Nick airfield on January 16th
the time really seemed to
have come to stop fighting.
The airlift temporarily ceased together.
Okay?
No more food and ammunition and game in
the wounded and sick could no longer be
flown out. And so that's where they're
getting their supplies into Pitt, Tom,
nick air field.
And that's actually where this guy
was for a large chunk of this battle.
It's now gone. So now they even,
you know, before they were,
they were only getting one
fifth of what they needed.
Well now they're getting zero two
by now.
Every day that the fighting was prolonged
was costing thousands of human lives.
There was no more time to be lost and we
waited for something to happen like me,
a numerable,
comrades and brothers and fate probably
clung to this same secret hope,
but nothing happened.
Okay.
And tragedy took its course.
The Russians,
by using their storm troops during
the initial days of the offensive,
it would probably have been very easy
for them to make a further effort and
liquidate the pocket relatively quickly,
but they no longer needed to make such a
highly costly attempt time was on their
side by bearing down on our tenacious
defense with a crushing attack,
our enemy had won its
penetration into the pocket.
Now he was no longer in a hurry and no
longer appeared to consider his victim to
be very dangerous.
The battle that had begun in the meantime
was merely a question of finishing off
wounded game already marked for death.
Okay.
For some time already, the Russians
had dictated the course of events.
Okay.
The date of our final end
depended on there. We'll alone
the stations of the cross of
an army of 200,000 soldiers,
particularly because of the slow,
helpless death of such a vast number of
human beings made anything seen before
with the exception of
Verdun Pale by comparison.
Yeah.
A part of the entire German nation was
sentenced to death here and buy this.
It's vital substance was
dangerously under attack.
The moral effect of these
events touched the whole nation.
Okay.
In the midst of the general
destruction of the army,
there were thousands of individual
tragedies whose localities of horror where
the numerous collection points
for the sick and wounded.
Okay.
Whole convoys of mostly open trucks,
overloaded with their pittable
freight of freezing wounded, groaning,
sick and dying,
move deeper into the pocket,
okay?
From the second half of
January until the bitter end,
the harsh suffering of the fighting
soldiers continued by day and night,
okay.
After eight evil weeks of
indescribable torture in deprivations,
they were now plunged into a veritable
hell of hopelessness and destruction.
Okay.
Time and again it was fight, resist,
hold to the end than disengage.
Withdrawal turned back and
dig in again for defense.
In the snow and stone only hard
frozen earth time. And again,
there were heavy losses, panic and flight
and the never ending useless struggle,
struggle against hunger.
In cold among the staffs,
there was an unending tension perplexity
and despair and feverish activity.
Leadership was still to be seen
from the higher ha commands came,
continue orders, directives,
questions, admonitions, threats,
criticism, opposition and misgivings
were not lacking at the lower levels,
but for the time being,
the mechanisms of command still function.
So despite all this,
and even though they're having this,
this hasty withdraw that's
going against orders,
there's still art direction coming out.
There's still people being disciplined
in the midst of the general
suffering and dying.
We helplessly watch the catastrophe of
destruction approaching us mercilessly.
Inexorably.
Yeah.
The terrible human tragedy that was
nearing its climax was finally commented,
commented upon by the war news broadcast
at home in the pretty and spirited
words,
quote in Stalin Grad,
sixth army is attaching a mortal honor
to it's banners by it's heroic and self
sacrificing battle against crushing odds.
Yeah.
Many of my comrades had mentally written
themselves off intentions to commit
suicide were voiced with
increasing frequency.
Others had given their valuables and
wedding rings to be to the wounded being
flown out.
Okay.
I myself had been,
had so far been at pains to prepare my
relatives for the catastrophe by means of
sparse hints.
Yeah.
Now I felt the need descend home
open word of farewell and gratitude.
Okay.
The letter was hard to write in my ears.
Once more rang,
rang the last goodbye.
My wife had imploringly in besieging,
the called down the telephone line to
Kiev on a spring evening of last year
before the seemingly endless
space of Russian planes.
It's swallowed me up.
Yeah.
Now all would soon be over.
When I see all the letter,
I was gripped by a specially deep despair.
I felt as though I were suddenly
looking into an abyss of suffering and
hopelessness towards which
our whole nation was reeling.
As if the events and Stalin Grad,
we're a preview of an immeasurable
disaster that was to break upon Germany.
Okay.
The general of this division
division had a nervous breakdown.
It was no longer fit for command.
His hopes of being flown out,
the badly wounded and sick had
not been for four fulfilled.
He now had to share the fate of
his soldiers to the bitter end.
This general who is short time before was
a commander of a division head carried
the responsibility for many thousands
of men was once more a mere human being
trembling for his life.
Then did his questions not reveal the
same fear that secretly tormented all of
us.
We made one another realize that the
impending military catastrophe was also a
political catastrophe.
The result of presumptuous
beliefs and actions.
The had long shaking. The healthy
foundations of our intellectual,
cultural,
and national life
had the power that we served as citizens
and soldiers bent it's knee before the
law that was rooted in the code of
ethics or rather had not a new gospel of
violence been proclaimed and introduce
that in a fatal reversal of all values
had ceased to differentiate
between right and wrong.
So these guys are realizing
what's coming around,
what's coming around.
He's realizing that the path that
they went down as a country was wrong.
Back to the book by means of
destructive battle against the universal
educational and cultural
powers of classic antiquity,
humanism and Christianity and
anti intellectual political
religion of power had
successively extracted the German people
from the best of the commonly held
European body of human fought and
thereby also out of any commitment to the
objective concepts of truth,
compassion and justice.
Is that, is that his
conclusion, like during this,
these events or, yes, during
these events, he's realizing what,
what's happening is that they were
wrong and they went immediately.
The thing that's crazy about Nazi
Germany is how fast that transition took
place. It's like we're talking
10 years. What the rise of the,
not to rise the Nazis or they're
their, they're influencing that. Yeah.
The rise of the Nazis just straight up
1933 they started now 1943 so we're 10
years and you have a completely
different viewpoint of the world. Yeah,
that's great. I mean, they're
going against the see what?
Like they're going against the traditional
values. They're going against, hey,
you know, they're going
against the Christian values.
They're going against the cultural values.
They're going against the national values.
Yeah. They're going against them. Yeah.
It's, I wonder how much of is that,
you know, like the soldiers in the,
even the people in the, in the Nazi party.
I wonder how much of it is like denial,
you know,
you know where it's at.
You know how like you're signed
onto like some leader during the,
during the time being, yeah. Or you're
saying right now how much of this denial,
no, no, no, no, no, no. During, during
the ride, remember rape and Dan,
can you remember that there
was one of the nicest guys,
one of the guys who made the
biggest sacrifice was this
was a straight up actual
Nazi and he made massive sacrifice and
took huge risks to save as many people as
he could. By the way, not white
people, not Ariens but, but Chinese.
So, so there's a guy that, you know,
was more related to the traditional
Christian intellectual values.
Right. And yet the, okay. The people that
are in charge of the country is Nazi.
So I guess that makes me an oxy.
Yeah. And here we go. And so,
and these guys war situation,
because there are soldiers,
so now they're fighting for that
evil force. And like you said,
there's some denial.
You also get caught up and clearly the
Germans got caught up in the nationalism.
They got caught up with the Hitler was
a great orator and a very moving speaker
and they got caught up in that and they
weren't in a very depressed economy.
So those things all kind of came to head.
They'd been in their mind screwed
over in World War One and you know,
defeated and then treated badly.
And you know,
there's this whole thing about
Hitler's mustache, you know,
Hitler has got the funny mustache.
Sure. And there's some debate on,
on how much of this is actually true,
but whether it's true or not as a
little bit, it doesn't really matter.
But because of what it represents.
So the deal was that Hitler's mustache,
if you wanted to have a mustache during
World War One because of wearing a gas
mask,
you had to cut your mustache like that.
Hitler still wars mustache like that.
It was like a constant c
symbol that he remembered.
He remembered because he was in world
war one and he was wounded in World War
One and through even despite
all that insane sacrifice,
they didn't win and they didn't like the
way they got treated by the treaty of
Versailles. And so they have that
anx they had the economic angst,
they had all those,
an angst built up and Hitler came along
and was ready to let them focus on
something else.
And and now what,
what weeder is realizing here is like
yeah he had us focus on something else.
All right. And what he held had us
focus on wasn't good. It was evil.
This is crude
analogy
you to training day.
I have watched training day.
That's kind of the same thing when
you watch cause cause the new youth,
the trainee, by the
way, when I see a movie,
I see it like one time in an
airplane and I know I'm not,
I'm not going to be
fully familiar with uh,
sort of pairing the rise of Nazi Germany
and the deaths of millions of people to
the movie training day.
And this is total speculation is just
what we're talking about as far as like
you people that are signed on,
Hey I'm German, you know, it's cool and
you know, we're all Jeremy, we weren't,
you know, solidarity where your and then
kind of the Nazi party starts rising,
starts giving these sorta sort of certain
types of influence and they're like,
oh all right, cool. I mean I wasn't
really thinking that but all right,
we're still,
Germans were cool and it starts
escalating and slowly it's like okay,
you can't turn back it. That's what
happening. Training Gay, right? Yeah.
Like he signed on, he signed on
and he's like Dang. He's like,
I don't know about all this but all right.
Hey,
I'm signed onto the
cause and after a while,
which is the same point that this guy got
and got to where it's like, man, okay,
you guys pushed it too much,
man, I cannot sign onto this.
And then you reflect back on all
the violations, you know, like
to slip. You start to slip when you
don't hold the line yesterday. Nothing.
So that's what happens.
And that's what makes leadership hard.
That's what makes life hard is it's really
easy to get tempted to go down these
trails, these paths that are
not what you should be doing.
And you got to kind of amendment,
and it's hard because in the beginning,
like
you know you're, you're going down a
path you're already signed on, right?
And then you see one teeny tiny violation
and I was like, what am I going to do?
Like make this big stink about this
teeny tiny violation. Yeah, for sure.
Then then you keep going and then
you had already made that exception.
Time goes on. And what are you going
to bring that little thing up again?
Psychologically?
What a Denzel Washington.
He's, he's, he doesn't
introduce that he's,
and go straight to level eight violation.
Right.
He just gives little little violations.
Can you down the path, a little bit of
abuse there, but hey, we're fighting back.
It's all good. And then like a
little like Wah, Wah, Wah, you know?
Yeah, exactly. Right. And that's, that's
what, that's what Hitler did. Yeah.
That's what Hillary started
with. Like, Hey, you know,
we don't want to have this happening.
We've got to keep these things in check.
Look, we're going to,
at least we're going to,
we're going to put the Jews
in a neighborhood, right.
We'll put them in a separate neighborhood.
That way they're not amongst us. Right.
Put them over there and didn't
know and it's okay. You know what?
We're actually not going to be
to move moving somewhere else.
Put Him in a work camp. Okay.
And then you just write,
you slowly escalating before you're
murdering two, 6 million people
and then all of a sudden what you're not
signed on all of a sudden you kind of
thing and you're like, Dang. In
your head, you're like, Dang,
I was assigned on to some of the stuff
earlier, but I had let it go. I'm trapped.
You know,
now you're trapped.
And that's where he is right now.
And He's trapped facing his death,
recognizing that,
yeah,
successively extracted the German people
from the best of the commonly held
European body of human thought like
you saying exactly what you just said.
Success successively.
It's just a little bit at a time.
Back to the book,
all of us who wore uniform war
entangled in a fabric of developments,
in circumstances that we certainly
had not sought or desired.
Now let's not make any excuses.
Let's not make any excuses,
but we see how it kinda
happened as you just said. Yeah.
We surely could not believe that our
employment here in Stalin Grad was part of
a noble legitimate battle for
Germany and interests. Painfully.
We felt that the soldierly virtues
of bravery, commitment, loyalty,
and obedience to duty
in the objective sense,
we're being despicably misused this
deep and the tragedy of cruel events in
which we now would have to atone
for much that we had never wanted.
So yeah,
that's um,
you know, I've heard that
argument sometimes if you,
well, you're going to kill,
there's a bad regime and you're going
to go and you're going to attack the
regime. And then some of the people
that are just there by chance, you know,
you hear that argument. Well, they're
allowing that regime to exist.
Now that's a tough argument to have
because you got somebody for them to rebel
could mean death and so they don't
get, they don't rebel. And so then,
and put in a bad situation.
That's a tough one. Yeah, fully.
But somebody asked me the other day,
so yeah,
it's a long those lines,
you know,
some long winded question on Twitter
about what would you do if you are not in
you, you know, in inside of a
state that was Bob all, you know,
repressive and et Cetera, et cetera. No
holds a go. One word answer, rebellion.
Now would I have the mentality that I
have right now if I grown up in one of
those repressive states?
Probably not.
I'd probably just want to survive
and get some more bread. Yeah, right.
I might not just be
thinking, Hey, there's,
there's something more important than
me and that's freedom and it does it.
Maybe I wouldn't think that. Maybe I'd
just be thinking, Hey, I want some,
maybe I can get an extra 20
grams of bread. It Olga. Dang.
All right.
Back to the book in this is good.
In the proximity of death,
things appeared in their
true light and proper order.
In such a situation. The Bible speaks
to us with an insistence and clarity,
the like of which we had never
felt or understood before.
The fear and misery at the edge of
our existence had given us a religious
experience who strength giving
power bound us together.
Okay,
so he's starting to see really
there's no atheists in a foxhole.
Guess what?
According to Weeder,
that's a very accurate statement.
Among my favorite books in the little
private library I'd taken with me to the
eastern front was a copy of Marcus
Aurelius is self observations.
Okay.
I too had often found
support and comfort in it.
It had contributed markedly to completing
my equipment for war by serving me as
a suit of armor that protected me from
all too frequent woundings by events and
giving me an inner equanimity.
Now,
this book too,
like several others
had become meaningless.
The wisdom of the world, the wisdom
of the world with it's merely human,
temporal comfort had failed.
It did not penetrate into the ultimate
and most profound and could no longer
stand firm in the terrible shock and
helplessness whose mercy I felt myself to
be in in extreme distress with the
ground shaking under foot and a menacing
abyss of nothingness
seeming to open before me.
There was only one last support,
the comforting strength
of the Christian belief.
Perhaps we could pass some of this comfort
and support on two other comrades who
bewildered.
We're wheeling toward the abyss in their
desperation faced with the destruction
of a whole world of concepts.
In an a view of the senseless
senselessness of the catastrophe.
Many a soldier on the staffs as well as
within the fighting troops had reached
for his pistol to put an end to his life.
Okay.
There was no way back and no escape other
disguise their secret fear and inner
feelings of emptiness behind a contrived
soldierly stance or even deliberately
assume to the cast of
mind of a language neck,
which is like these guys were these
old school German mercenaries that were
super hardcore. If they themselves
were doomed to go under,
they would at least sell their skin
so dearly to the end and take as many
Russians with them as they
could. That's interesting. He's,
he's projecting on these
soldiers that you know,
that they're disguising their secret fear.
You know what I'm telling you right now,
that some of those Nazi German soldiers,
they were, they were getting
after it, right? They weren't,
they weren't hiding their,
their secret fear by acting tough.
They were ready to die for the fewer.
Hmm.
So let's not just paint with a
broad brush there. In my opinion.
If uh, we agreed that suicide was out of
the question for religious and ethical
reasons.
As normal week human beings
caught up in error and guilt,
there was nothing left to,
to us put to drink the cup of
suffering to the last bidder drags.
Yeah. In the meantime,
something unbelievable. It
happened and made quickly made.
The rounds are quartermaster.
A still young general staff
officer had suddenly disappeared.
His driver who had taken him to the
gum rack air had waited in vain for his
return. The lieutenant colonel was
missing. He had silently left Stalin.
Rod left the Stalin Grad pocket,
the zone of death and destruction
on his own initiative.
Probably it was a mixture of nerves,
fear,
cowardice in the vain hope that in the
general confusion he might be able to fly
out and save his life that
attempted him to dessert.
The commanding general had made inquiries
by radio that earning staff officer
had shown up at army group claiming the
flown out on official assignment from
the core on matters of supply.
Our general was wild with
indignation and rage.
He declared that he would
have the criminal flown back
into the pocket and shot
before our eyes.
We were all deeply depressed and into
with an anticipated with horror the
terrible scene that had been announced
and which we were spared to our relief.
Our quarter master was shot outside the
pocket on the spot where in his fatal
weakness he had hoped to find a
door to freedom in life. So again,
even though I just talked about some of
the Nazis being committed to the end,
there was many of them that were just
trying to get the hell out of there.
Back to the book, our commanding general
spoke openly of the impending collapse,
accusing lean with
bitterness and secret anger.
He pointed out that it was not our fault.
We had gotten into this devil,
this situation of a catastrophe from which
there was no longer a means of escape.
Okay? Here he is, the commanding
general is now saying,
hey look,
this is not our fault.
So he so clearly, he's
obviously not taking any
ownership of this, but w w okay,
so it's only ask you this.
Okay, Jocko, what would it,
how would it help him if he was to
take ownership of it right now? Right.
If he was to say, Hey, this is my fault.
It wouldn't help them. Could, could.
If he was to say, Hey, look, this is
my fault. This is why this happened.
Would that help him right now? No,
you're right. It wouldn't help them.
What did have helped him a month or
two months ago, if he said to himself,
look, we're in this situation, I need to
take ownership of it and get it fixed.
Would it have helped? Then you're
damn right. It would have who said,
you know what?
Hitler might not tell them.
It might be telling us not to break
out. Guess what? Hitler's not here.
We're going to break out. I'll go get
shot for defying his orders. That's fine.
I'll save all of you. That's, that's
where ownership would've come in,
but what he said was, look, we're, we're,
we're, we're assigned to our faith.
I talk about this all the time.
Just because the boss tells you or doesn't
give you the support that you need or
gives you a bad order.
That doesn't give you the excuse.
You can't put the ownership on the
boss and you're the one in charge.
You take ownership of it, you get the
problem solved. He didn't do that. So he,
he's, I don't want to see allowed
to say it's not our fault,
but he okay.
Him saying it's not our fault is
kind of a different circumstance.
Why? Because they're past the point of no
return. If they're doomed already. Yes.
Cause they don't have any, uh, you know,
take responsibility and then take
responsibility for the fixing the mistake.
There is no fixing the mistakes
anymore. That's why if I was him, yeah,
I would've said, hey guys, it's not your
fault that you're here. This is my fault.
I should have made a maneuver. I should
have stood up to the boss. I didn't.
Here's what we're going to do now to
defend ourselves the best of our ability.
Right.
So then that would still give
the guys some breathing room.
Right. Some psychological breathing
room. Yeah, they fought hard.
They did their best. It's my fault.
I should have. I should have.
How'd you guys do something
different and I didn't.
Here's what we're going to do
now. The fact that he, that these,
that he wasn't taking ownership earlier,
the fact that he's able to blame now
means he was able to blame earlier and if
you're, the minute you start
blaming, you're not solving anything.
You're not getting things
done. There you go. Yeah,
back to the book,
but he left no doubt that together
we still had a task to perform,
namely namely to fulfill our soldierly
duty duty til the last moment in
obedience to the orders from above.
We will defend our perimeter fighting
shoulder to shoulder with our carbines to
the last bullet from his words,
we could surmise that he was staunchly
determined to go down like a captain with
his ship and not to survive the
downfall of his troops on equivocally.
He pointed out that the commandments
of the traditional ethical code of the
soldier now demanded our
ultimate sacrifice without Demir.
Okay.
Now at this point he's supposed to go out
and do a do like a Rocana sense of the
lines and see what's going
on and when he's up there.
Here's what he sees in freezing
cold and wild snow fury flurries,
I wrote across the decile at battlefield
on a motorcycle together with a
sergeant of the military police,
we soon reached a road of catastrophic.
We soon reach the road of catastrophe
or rising dark gray against the backdrop
of a snow bounce step marked by
all kinds of abandoned rubbish.
Half covered cadavers of
horses and wrecked vehicles,
scattered pieces of equipment,
crates destroyed weapons,
the dispersed, the starving,
the freezing, the sick,
but all those still fit for fighting.
Had only one objective to which they
were attaching their last glimmerings of
hope.
And this objective was stolen Grad in the
protective walls of the sellers of the
ruins. They might still be able
to find some warmth, food, rest,
sleep and salvation.
And so they streamed by the remains of
the shattered and decimated formation
trains and rear echelon services with
vehicles that were slowly being dragged
and pushed by wounded, sick and
frost bitten men. There were a May,
she did figures among them
muffled and coats rags,
pitiful rex,
painfully dragging themselves forward,
leaning on sticks and hobbling all
along the fruit on frozen feet,
wrapped in wisps of Straw and strips
of blankets drifting along through this
storm.
This was the wreck of the sixth army that
had advanced to the vulgar during the
summer.
So confident of victory,
men from all over Germany doomed
to destruction in a far off land.
Mulian during their suffering.
Tottered in pitiful drove droves
through the murderous eastern winter.
These were the same soldiers
who had formerly marched
through the large parts of
Europe's as proud conquerors.
Now the enemy was at their backs
and deaf looked everywhere.
There's an interesting piece
that I don't go into too much,
but this guy had written a paper and
presented it up the chain of command with,
uh,
talking about what happened to Napoleon.
Hmm.
And he got kind of told like, hey,
that's not going to happen to us.
Back to the book, the events of 1812 seem
to be repeating themselves after all.
Once again,
the uncanny Russian space was swallowing
many tens of thousands of human beings
despite Napoleon's experience.
The basic elements of geography and
meteorology had again been ignored to a
frightening degree.
On top of that,
the modern superstition that with
the help of machines and motors,
the possible could be accomplished and
the dangers of space overcome had also
contributed to our downfall and it a
fatal pack with the overestimation of
mechanized means of bore had stood the
misapprehension of the limits of human
strength and possibilities. Yeah. Repeat
Tizzy. Yeah. That was another
one of those classic lines.
That's not gonna happen to us. Oh
yeah. I mean it feels like, yeah,
that's a classic mistake.
It's called ego called lack of humility.
Don't worry, that won't happen to us. It
happened to Napoleon, one of the greatest,
you know,
military leaders of all time.
But it won't happen to us
because we have some cars. Yeah,
we've got some tanks or whatever,
but by the way, tanks, tank, fuel,
where's that fuel going to come from?
I mean,
at least a horse can eat a piece
of Hay, right? Sure. You know,
there's no Exxon station
out there on the steps
back to the book together
with several wounded,
we dragged ourselves onwards
until exhausted in shattered.
We finally reached the ruins of rubble
of northern Stalin Grad City area,
so now he's actually was retreating
back to Stalin Grad itself.
What travails did fate
still hold in store for us?
Deaf who might face more often and
closely in recent days than ever before,
it was still refusing me,
but his trusted companion for many weeks,
hunger was tormenting
me with tenacious power.
Slowly making me write
for the end and frost.
The third murderer in the trio had
also bitten me by now as the constant
stabbing pains. Some of my limbs
warned me separate from our staff.
Our Group of officers found shelter and
a dark dirty seller while our men went
to ground in a neighboring
pile of rubber rubble.
This was to be the end of our
flight and our last quarters.
The army had once again
addressed itself too. Okay.
H and pointing adamantly to
the catastrophic situation
had asked for immediate
permission to surrender.
Okay.
Which might possibly prevent
still complete disillusion,
disillusion,
and total disaster.
Hitler's answer had been a steely no
for bid surrender. Hitler had radioed
into the pocket on 25 January.
The army will hold its position
to the last man and bullet.
Okay?
Imagine being that freezing hungry,
tortured by the enemy at your back.
And you got some guy in
a nice,
ridiculous,
it's one thing to be like, yeah, we're
going to the last minute, the last bullet,
and it's this big war, but it
lasts. You know, I don't know,
a week not even though
we eat or like that,
that one big last stand and we're gonna
fight to the death. That's one thing.
And I dig it and that's,
you know,
but just weeks and weeks and weeks of to
slowly dying of starvation in sickness
in this way,
different it's way different to try to
fight til the last man in the last bullet
in that sentence scenario.
Yeah.
Especially because they,
they all kind of know that there's no
strategic advantage to what they're doing.
In worse.
Back to the book Colonel General Policy
and his chief of staff who's fanatical
wheel to hold out was well known among
the staff's relentlessly held onto their
fatal decision on their part.
Many generals and their staffs remain
the executioners of the orders of
destruction under the sorry
circumstances for fighting,
suffering and dying continued torturing
Lee and terribly after the splitting of
the pocket. The death agony of the
army continued for a further week
in the general disillusion
and catastrophe.
It was every man for himself more and
more order and discipline broke down here
and there and the sellers.
This still able bodied in combat,
worthy hid among the second wounded cases
of uncommon rod really conduct theft
of provisions, refusal to obey
orders and open mutiny mounted
a little late.
The elementary drive of self preservation
no longer allowed the question of
right or wrong to be raised and in the
same way that the differences between the
front line and rear line ash,
then the rear echelon we're being erased.
So were the differences in rank
and position. In the final days.
Summary Law was imposed and stolen Grad
with drastic punishments for any crime.
Looters were to be shot within 24 hours.
Hundreds of German soldiers who had
become weak in their misery thus became
victims of German bullets.
Okay.
One could no longer generally speak
of courageous and heroic fighting.
Certainly here and there there
were individual deeds of courage,
personal initiative and noble self,
self sacrifice,
but by and large,
only a mute submission to the inescapable
fait remained to the bitter end.
Yeah,
it was rather the silent hero wisdom of
acceptance of suffering and submitting
not the picture that gets painted
very often. Now at this point,
at this point right now in this battle
is when they hear that speech that goring
said,
talking about this great sacrifice and
how they fought so well and how they'll
be remembered forever and compared them
to Leah [inaudible] and the 300 Spartans
at Thermopylae. It's just, and
here's what these guys thought
with overexaggerated feverish PAF us
the see the speaker recalled the heroic
example of the last of the goths,
and in the end, the historical,
so famous sacrifice of the Spartan
heroes at Thermopylae who had not fall
faulted or given ground until
the last fighter had fallen.
And so it was at Stalin Grad,
just like Leah nighties and his
loyal men and the Greek defile.
So with the German heroes lie on the
vulgar as the law of honor and conduct in
war commanded them to do for Germany
during this speech full of empty
phrases and lies that outdated itself in
hysterical glorification and praises the
demeanor of the deeply delusioned and
incensed.
Adios became more and more hostile.
Yeah.
The glances,
gestures and words all around
on mistakenly showed the
rage that was growing in
people's souls.
Whoever might still have trusted in the
promise of help from the outside now had
to recognize with growing horror that
at home where relatives still hope for a
union. The warriors of Stalin
Grad had finally been written off.
Okay.
We felt that we had heard our own
funeral oration before its time.
The disgusting adulation of the torture
is dying of our army and the deceitful
glorification of conditions that were
against all laws of humanity filled me
with indignation and revulsion.
Must not going w goings words if pierce
the hearts of our loved ones at home
like daggers and rob them of all hope
now that they had been thrown into the
most anxious fears of art
for our lives at home,
we had been declared dead.
The hero is Asian and
mythical glorification of
our stolen Gratta army was
supposed to conceal the
sad truth for a long time.
Now the our relic tale of the German
soldier drama vulgar had become an
irresponsible mass dying
ordered from on high.
The pathetic propaganda of glorification
was obviously intended to distract from
the catastrophic consequences of a
criminally amateurish leadership of war.
And to prevent the question
of blame from even a rising.
Okay.
So you pretty much see how
these guys felt at the end.
And now you might think you might think
that there's a disconnect between Hitler
but cape,
we're proud we're fighting to the end
and this is the way the Germans are and
this is the way we are.
We are superior.
Hmm.
And that the guys on the ground
that they're just beat down.
And so maybe they're just,
maybe they're just weak. Right.
And they're just given up. You might
think that you might think that here's,
this will give you a
little indication that,
that that's the wrong
thought on the one February,
the new spread among us,
that Paula's had capitulated with his
staff and the two southern segments of the
pocket and gone into captivity.
So the leader just surrender.
At the last moment he had been
promoted to field marshal.
This promotion in the hour of the
final catastrophe was grotesque.
It was simply a gesture of
thanks from above and a good buy.
So Hitler thought the policy was
going to die. Well, he didn't
Paulus surrendered,
but the unhappy field,
Marshall Marshall did not set the example
of heroism expected of him from the
top. The German papers
broadcasts later broadcast,
Slater tried to spread the impression of
the style of goring speech that in the
face of overwhelming superiority,
the field marshal had burned his secret
papers and that the general line behind
their machine guns had fought to the end.
Okay.
Furthermore,
after the catastrophe,
German magazines lied to the
German people with fake pictures,
so showing such heroic scenes,
okay,
but the truth of the matter
was something quite else.
We calculated that more than 15
generals and their staffs had gone into
captivity from the southern and
central pockets soon mosque.
Soon the Moscow radio gave
details of numbers and names.
I was only to learn later that some of
these generals had gone into captivity
with neatly packed suitcases
and plentiful baggage.
They simply stopped fighting and gave
themselves up to the victor without any
further consideration for the fate
of the remaining battle groups.
The last request of the field marshal
had been that the Russians should treat
him as a private citizen.
With this,
he had resigned at the official role,
either formally played in the military,
political interest of
the supreme commander,
and as a broken man laid
down his martial ship,
he was driven away in a closed car and
no longer needed to see the appalling
misery of his sacrificed army.
Yeah,
so there's no disconnect. The
troops on the ground, we're right.
These leaders were liars week
and they had no problem.
Okay.
Pursuing glory with someone else's ass,
but they weren't ready
to do with their own.
Deep down inside,
I had increasingly begun to oppose
certain military concepts of obedience,
honor and discipline,
like those that had been
manifesting themselves to
the end in the measures taken
by our command. Was this
only the, so this is,
this is a week we went through
all this and he's like the only,
now he's starting to
oppose some of some of his,
his military concepts of obedience.
If this was was an American,
do you Americans are rebellious by
nature like we don't, we don't. You know,
if you, if you're leading us down the
wrong path, we stand up and say like, no,
you're not going to do that. Stop. No,
he's, you know, here going, well,
they've done all this and know now am
I starting to question these things?
And he even questioned his question back
to the book was this only the revolt of
my selfish instinct for self preservation
was an omission on soldierly stance,
fear of cowardice at a time when
things had become bitterly serious.
Precisely at this point,
I again remember the awkward,
deeply penetrating faults and feelings
with which I'd asked myself at the
beginning of the war. Why and for
whom must you make this sacrifice?
The same questions that had never
really taken root roads again before me,
gigantic Leanna and applicable to the
whole army was there really unknowable.
Hi,
holy objective at stake here and
solid Grad our in our battle,
an ethically justified goal which could
be served by ultimate human human test
of giving one's life.
Did soldierly honor and obedience to
orders really justify this demand so
casually made of us that we
hold out for this lost cause,
this excess of suffering and dying.
Was this immeasurables sacrifice really
decisive for the outcome of the war and
could it serve our country and our people?
This is what this is. You want to know
why we talk about the wire all the time?
Yeah, there it is. Yeah.
Now he should have been asking that
question a long time ago and he said he
started to, in the beginning he
started to ask that question,
but he didn't go through with it. You
know why? Because they were winning.
They were winning. Dz Don't really need
to know why, where I could go out there,
you know, beat this country, beat that
country, roll through that country.
It's pretty easy not getting tested.
Yeah.
Back to the book of foreboding, I had
long held, grew into a terrible certainty.
What was happening here in Stalingrad
was a tragic, senseless self sacrifice,
a scarcely credible betrayal of the
final commitment and devotion of brave
soldiers are innocent.
Trust had been misused in the most
despicable manner by those responsible for
the catastrophe. We had been
betrayed, led astray, and condemned.
The men of stolen Grodd were dying in
betrayed belief and in betrayed trust in
my heart,
the bitter feeling of and all for nothing
became ever more torturing in my soul
arose again.
The whole a bismal disaster of the
war itself more clearly than ever.
I appreciated the full measure of misery
and wretchedness of the other countries
in Europe too,
which German soldiers and German arms
had brought boundless misfortunes.
So he's reflecting and he's looking
around and saying, look what we did.
All these other countries.
How do we,
not so far the Victor's been all too
prone to close our eyes and our hearts and
to forget that always an everywhere.
The issues we're living,
human beings, their possessions and
their happiness. So, like you said,
he turned a blind eye.
He rolled through all these countries.
He did all that evil.
Probably only a few among
us had entertained the fault
that the suffering of the
thought that the suffering
and dying being caused by our,
sorry, profession of war would
one day be inflicted upon us.
We had carried our total war into
one region of Europe after another,
and thereby destructively interfered
with the destinies of foreign nations far
too little.
We had asked the reason why,
the necessities and justifications for
what was happening or reflected on the
immeasurability of our
political responsibility,
that these entailed misery and
death had been initiated by us,
and now we were inexhaustibly coming
home to roost day were in exorbitant,
coming home to roost.
The step on the dawn and the vulgar had
drunk streams of precious human blood.
The Russians were certainly also making
cruelly high blood sacrifices in the
murderous battle of Stalingrad,
but they who were defending their
country against a foreign aggressor knew
better than we why they were risking
their lives. So yeah, the Russians,
they're fighting,
they're dying for sure,
but they know that they're
defending their homeland.
It's a lot easier for them to understand.
Many officers and commanders now began
to oppose the insane orders and emanating
from the fewer headquarters and
being passed on by army command.
By this they had,
they began to reject the long eroded
military concepts of honor and discipline
to which the army leadership at clung
until the end in the unconditional
obedience, such, such as was fatally
being upheld here in Stalin Grad,
there was no longer a soldierly stance,
but rather a lack of responsibility.
So I'm gonna say that one more time.
This idea that
unconditional obedience was,
was, was not seeing right
now as a soldierly stance,
but a lack of responsibility because
you are responsible to do something if,
if you're getting bad orders,
you're responsible for not obeying them.
And you know, I get asked this question
all the time, not all the time,
but you know, sometimes
people say, what if you got,
what did you do if you ever got told
something that you didn't believe it?
I was like, well, we
were home the same page.
Like it's not like we were getting
told to do things that were immoral,
unethical. You're, they
weren't saying, Hey,
go burn this village with
women and children. We weren't
getting those orders. He,
you know what I mean?
We weren't getting told to do things that,
yeah,
that weren't,
that I didn't agree with that.
That my guys didn't agree with and
that's the way the mill are there.
Are there pockets where things
happened? Yeah, absolutely. That's what,
that's the horrors of war.
But if we got told to do things that we
didn't think we should do, we just said,
no,
not doing it.
Hmm.
This was open mutiny.
So they've gotten to the point now flying
me since they were no more orders from
the center towards the end.
Many responsible commanders and unit
leaders on the line acted on their own
initiative and in an endeavor to
stop the senseless shedding of blood.
Many desperate Stalin Grad warriors in
the end sought a way out by suicide or by
voluntary,
by a voluntary soldiers death.
We learned of two generals who extremes
who's extreme resolution had been
shattering.
One,
the commander of a division from Dresden
had shot himself after having ordered
his son, a young lieutenant, to
report to him to say farewell.
The other,
the commander of a division from Lower
Saxony who's tactical emblem was a four
leaf clover and was known therefore as
the lucky division who did not want to
survive.
The downfall of his men had been killed
on the frontline while standing erect
and firing his weapon.
The last pockets of resistance,
what was left of about six shattered
divisions and the remnant of other
formations that had meanwhile been left
to their fate by the resignation of the
army command now had to bear the whole
burden of the concentrated air attacks,
artillery and mortar fire.
It was not only the
fear of the coming end,
the hunger clawing at my intestines
and the pain from my frozen limbs that
turned the last seemingly endless hours
and the Stalin Grad pocket into the
tortures of Hell for me.
The proximity of death toward the last
obscuring veils from my eyes and brought
fruits of long years of individual
experiences, observations,
tormenting feelings and thoughts
into an instant maturity.
Yeah.
Now on the very edge of
being war in it's for us,
okay,
most terrible form became the
inexhaustible revealer of all things,
but he's going through like spiritual
awakening as he faces death in my mind's
eye,
the horrible experiences and pictures of
destruction that would not leave me in
peace.
By Day or night.
We're strung together in a bloody
chain experiences and impressions,
stretching foreign to the past. That's
suddenly a woke in my sharp and memory.
I discovered to be logically
connected links of this fatal chain.
What had formally always caused me to
have nasty premonitions and apprehensions.
What it always disquieted me,
I now suddenly had a recognized as
having been the warning of a fatal
fundamental evil.
The dimensions of which I had fought,
not fought possible
now faced with the eminently
impending catastrophe.
The question about the sense of what was
happening had played me so often during
the war,
seized me again with cruel force.
Hundreds of thousands of flowering human
lives were suddenly being senselessly
snuffed out here in Stalin Grad.
What an immeasurable wealth of
human happiness. Human plans,
hopes,
talents for tile.
Possibilities for the future were
there by being destroyed forever.
Okay.
The criminal insanity of an irresponsible
war management with it's superstitious
belief in technology and it's
utter lack of feeling for the life,
value and dignity of man
and here prepared for us.
Oh Hell on earth.
How could the
long eroded concepts of honor,
duty,
obedient soldierly hair wisdom
figure any longer into our feelings,
thoughts and actions to stay alive,
to be reunited once again
with our loved ones at home.
This burning desire was now the drive
behind all thoughts and actions.
Gradually we had accustomed
ourselves to the,
to the idea of surrendering at the
first opportunity and going into Russian
captivity.
In the end,
I basically had only one wish to stay
alive and healthy and go into captivity on
wounded.
So that's it goes into captivity.
Um, you know, after going through a, uh,
I don't know if you want to call it a
spiritual awakening of recognizing that
his whole life had been
doing something evil.
Yeah.
In the end it's,
it's pretty anticlimactic how it happens,
how they get,
how they end up in captivity.
Back to the book in the
early minutes of captivity,
I felt an easing tension and relief.
In the end,
the insecurity of our situation between
life and death had weighed down on all
of us,
like led
what first attracted my attention.
So now they're captured in what
first attracted my attention.
Imagine this was the fresh
healthy appearance of the victors.
They're simple enviable winter
clothing in good weapons, son,
sub machine guns everywhere.
And the uniform picture of sheep skins.
Padded jackets felt boots and for caps
with broad earmuffs swinging up and down
the warmly bundled up,
well nourished and splendidly equipped
men of the Red Army with their chunky,
mostly red cheeked faces formed
a stark contrast to our death.
We Pale,
filthy bearded and freezing figures of
misery who Hong exhausted and sick and
their makeshift winter clothing
consisting of all kinds of furs, blankets,
scarves, field gray, head gear,
woolens and inadequate foot gear.
This sudden meeting and comparison at
once showed me how low we had sunk and how
little we had been prepared
for this murderous battle
than the Soviets.
The Russians kind of
have their shots at him.
Fritzy Fascist Hitler caput.
They alternated threats
and obviously dreadful.
Kurt curses and contemptuous spit like
raging wolf to vengeful soldiers from the
rear echelons fell on the helpless victims
time and time again to steal personal
baggage and to vent their spleen.
So now they're captured in though the
Russian start to kind of sing and dance
and singing the old folk songs
back to the book.
All the noise and exuberant surrounding
me formed a shrieking contrast to the
inner and outer state,
which I found myself torn from my
circle of comrades left to myself and my
emotions.
In the midst of the joyful dancing and
singing victors with whom no contact
could be established in my inner heart,
I felt abandoned and without hope,
totally depressed, uprooted,
caught off from home,
sunk far away,
subjugated to a foreign will,
pytest sleep piteous Lee thrown to
the mercy of an unknown powers to be
dependent on the whim of the
victor constantly watched
menacingly surrounded by
barbed wire and guns forced to relinquish
to any kind of external freedom
captivity,
men on an unknown form of human
submission and humiliation.
Okay?
It is a bounty for us human beings that
a merciful hand covers the future from
our eyes with an impenetrable veil.
That's a really great line.
Had I known then that I was destined
for more than seven comfortless years
devoid of love and filled with previously
unknown mental and physical tortures
and fearful uncertainties
on the borderline of life.
I never would have found
the strength to say Stan,
the sufferings of the initial
hard months of captivity.
He's saying if he would've known what
the future held seven years he's about to
be in captivity for,
he wouldn't have even made it through.
He would have given up
and he doesn't talk in
this book about what that
imprisonment was like,
but he does give what I
think is a combination of how
we survived it and what he
learned from it.
Going back to the book time and again,
I was soothingly distracted
from my tormenting thoughts
and dark visions by the
wonders of the brightly shining star
filled winter sky that appeared to be so
close to the touch.
It constantly drew my eyes upwards as
if by magical force what its so far
appeared to me as the downfall of a
world come loose at the seams and a
catastrophe without bounds suddenly
took on measurable dimensions.
I regained my equilibrium and found my
way back to myself where I felt earlier
that chaos was swallowing me up.
Now,
calm and peace was flowing
into my disquieted heart.
The reconciling effect came from the vast
order and harmony that the sparkling,
massive bright stars with their eternal
laws of the universe brought back to my
attention.
A new
okay.
The constellation that the stars sank
into my soul was strange and hardly to be
grasped by the intellect.
It seemed to me as if my personal fate
within the framework of events on earth
was secretly included within the vast
all embracing order of the cosmos
for the massive survivors who had
escaped from the hell of Stalin Grad.
The aftermath of the tragedy
lasted only for a short while.
Yeah,
they died in their tens of thousands
during the early months of captivity.
Hunger and deprivation,
frost and sickness had already made them
assure pray for death even before the
fighting stopped
with the columns of prisoners.
Deaf also came to the various camps of
reception where terrible app epidemics
raged everywhere and exact accounting of
the victims of Stalin Grad according to
numbers, dates, and individual
fates will never be made.
The few that were allowed to begin a new
life at home and in freedom after long
years of captivity,
we'll always have to ask themselves
how they can justify the deaths of the
others by their own existence,
how they can uphold and fulfill
the legacy of their dead comrades.
But all Germany must also
loyally remember, it's many,
many sons that lie at rest in the distant
Russian step and try today and in the
future to understand they're
unforgettable. Sacrifice
the new broom ball mounds of soldiers,
graves and stolen Grodd
have long disappeared.
Okay.
The cemeteries were leveled soon after
the battle and partially converted to
soccer fields.
Yeah.
Nothing is left of the army
of simple gray crosses,
but it is as if a great invisible cross.
We're rising there on the Volga
casting its shadow over our nation and
addressing penetrating admonishing words.
Okay.
To all of our hearts.
And that
closes out this book with
with some
penetrating in admonishing words a for
us because there's a lot of warnings
in this book.
Warnings that
we must pay attention to
and if we don't pay attention to them,
then who will?
Yeah,
warnings. The lessons here,
first of all, as a nation,
as a culture, we have to look at
the way things fell apart in Germany
or maybe you look at the way things came
together slowly like we talked about,
the traditional values were we're moved
aside and they were replaced with these
new values,
values that allegedly
protected the German citizens.
Yeah,
they were values that we're going
to make the world a better place
and he uses this term,
this political religion.
That's a powerful thought.
Okay.
Political religion took hold and then
he used that term presumptuous beliefs
that countered the foundation of
their existing cultures and beliefs.
So there's some arrogance involved
that we have people that aren't even
listening to the counter arguments.
I think we have to be
careful not to abandoned
the structures of the past in some kind
of a race to move to the future because
the future,
it hasn't been tested by thousands and
thousands of years of human evolution.
And I understand,
okay
that we,
I'm not saying we don't progress,
but I'm not saying we don't evolve,
but I'm saying you don't bow
down and you don't submit.
You got to think about the direction
that we're heading. And as citizens,
as people,
we have to have the courage to stand up
before we reached the event horizon from
which there's no return.
So now on a smaller level,
the lessons from this book as,
as a,
as a person in business or in the military
or in any team as a subordinate and
we're all subordinate to someone,
we have to question our leaders and,
and I say that all the time.
Yeah.
If we don't agree with that plan
or don't agree with a tactic, you,
you've got a question leadership
when you got out, raise your hand.
But if we know that the intent
of our leadership is malevolent
or it's going to cause suffering,
human suffering on a grand scale,
on a minor scale,
okay,
you have to,
we have to say no and do what is right.
No matter the consequence,
no matter the consequence
and
you don't.
Finally for us as individuals,
okay,
we got to remember that we are
in charge of our own lives.
We are leading our own lives and
where are you leading yourself?
What are you doing that you
know you shouldn't be doing?
Why are you doing that?
What attached roughy
are you heading toward?
You don't have to be heading
towards that catastrophe.
You have the opportunity to prevent
catastrophe in your own life.
But in order to do that, once
again, you have to stand up.
You have to do the right thing,
you have to be comfortable.
You have to impose the discipline on
your own life so you don't have something
else imposed,
something bad in posts so you don't have
a catastrophe imposed on your own life.
Because when we avoid the discomfort and
when we avoid the discipline and when
we avoid doing what we know
is the right thing to do,
that's when you end up in a personal
catastrophe, in your own personal hell,
in your own personal stolen Grotte
you have to do.
Yeah.
The hard thing,
the thing you know is right.
And do you know what is right and
you know what you are supposed to do.
So do it
and avoid
going down a path
that leads
yeah.
To your own personal health
and instead,
yeah.
Get on the path that leads
to freedom.
I think
that's all I've got for tonight's.
So Echo.
Speaking of doing the right thing.
Sure.
Maybe you could give us some ideas,
um,
on how we can,
you know,
continue down the right path doing what
we know we're supposed to do. Sure, sure.
The part where you said,
you know,
you're less likely to raise any questions
or you're more likely to turn a blind
eye when you're winning.
You remember when you said that,
that like on them we use boiler room.
Am I wrong? No, no, no, you're right.
Yeah.
So the guys,
there's a part where he's in there
waiting to go to a party or something,
you know, they're, they're selling
stocks, right? And they're,
they're like garbage stocks or whatever.
Inflating them. Yeah. They're like, yeah,
all this pump and dump.
Yeah.
And so they're in the car going to
some party and he's like, hey, it was,
who was it, Giovanni, whatever
the actors' names. Are they
a, he's like, Hey, he goes,
do you ever wonder how, how we get these
big commissions on these? You know?
And he's like, that's the wrong question
to ask. You know? He's like, wait,
what do you mean? He's like,
he's like, just, just don't
ask that question. Basics.
He said, don't ask that question. He goes,
don't you like the way things are going?
He's like, yeah, but I do. I do, but
don't you ever wonder? He's like, no,
I like being a millionaire. Same
exact thing. When you're winning,
it's easy to turn the blind eye,
you know? Good point. Yeah, man.
So, I mean, I guess
that can apply to, well,
it's interesting that you point
that out and I think that, um,
like on a personal level, right? Let's
say you're doing really good. Yeah.
It's then it can be tricky for
people to do the right thing to,
cause that's why we see like these a
celebrity like movie stars or celebrities,
athletes or whatever. Man,
they do some dumb stuff, right?
They do some dumb stuff because they're
winning. They're thinking they're good.
They can do whatever they want.
They make the wrong choice. Yeah.
You dinner on the evening news doing
dumb stuff that ruins them. Yeah.
And I mean their own personal stone,
God puts him in hell. Yeah. Even, yeah.
With money too, you know, you know,
like in celebrity types and you know,
athletes who you are and just people,
people who get a good job with
their business blows up or whatever.
Yeah.
Any,
any type of winning we could look at it
doesn't mean you're necessarily doing
the right thing. It's harder. My point is,
and I think you're saying the same thing.
Yes.
It can be harder to do the right thing
when you're winning because you just
think you're good to go. You get
arrogant. Yeah, yeah, let's not,
let's not put brakes on this training
here. Just let it all fly kind of thing.
And then when the train kind of
loses momentum, meanwhile, all those,
those things that you've been ignoring,
they're still there. You know?
Look at your empty bank account.
You spent all that money
you're supposed to keep.
It would be for you made money or
money. You were budgeting, right?
You're budgeting, you're surviving,
you're budget and you're doing,
you started making all this.
When he started spending all this money,
all the money stopped coming in and your
budget is God just saying that's what
happens. Sometimes. You can't happen.
Also pay now or pay later. I remember that
one. That was a good one that you said.
Yeah. Did I say that? Yeah.
Pay Now or pay later. We're,
I think we're talking about like
working out or something. Just like,
I didn't say it today though. No, no,
no, no. Pay Now or pay later for sure.
Stuck with nonetheless
support. Yeah. For sure.
Hundred percent good way to
avoid going down your personal,
I don't know. Maybe it does.
Maybe it doesn't. It nonetheless,
if you're in the mood to support and
listen your own personal style and rob.
Yeah, right. But I dunno why supporting
would like prevent that, you know,
you're not. No, we go deep for,
but nonetheless you don't remember,
you don't have any aversions to reaching,
you're reaching deep today.
Solid grog training day.
No, those are conceptually, there
were the same thing. They were,
I know the comparing it's,
you know, most of these world,
most of these like lessons I think, I feel
like they're kind of everywhere. Yeah,
of course.
And you know,
you're talking about these heavy wars
and heavy like events and then you know,
in my mind I'm thinking training,
you know what the, you know, the idea
is still hates the same. There's,
I think there's people out there in
various states of mind share and I think
that,
you know,
your perspective helps them maybe
get maybe see some what I'm saying,
cause maybe I'm,
I'm hitting them from the wrong angle.
So you're coming in from
trading day movies. Hey Man.
Yeah. Actually in the end,
come to think about it.
These concepts right here today when
you're saying, you know, uh, you know,
when it's going well, for
example, when it's going good,
it's easy to turn a blind eye. Isn't
that kind of a lot of movies, how it is,
it's like the guy does real good
and he's just kinda going in it. He,
he messes up in one way or another.
Like pretty much,
I think there's this talk by Kurt
Vonnegut and I've seen it on Youtube,
I think it's Kurt Vonnegut,
and he's like teaching a class
and you'll grab on to get his,
he's teaching some class, like he
just guest teaching and some classes,
which is pretty awesome.
But he's talking about like,
there's four plot lines and they're
all pretty much the same. Yeah,
it's pretty cool. But that's
what happened. You're, you,
you have nothing and then
you get everything. Yeah.
And then you kind of abuse it kind
of. Then there's, then there's,
you have nothing.
You get everything,
you lose everything and then you get
everything back. He's just got these,
it's like I forget them all, but
it makes sense. They're common. Um,
common storyline.
They must be kind of,
I mean they must be right based
on real life. Like, like term,
like scenarios that
you go through in life.
I think it's why there's things come back.
Story, Cinderella story, Comeback Kid.
I mean those things really under
dog story triumphant. Yeah.
That's how nonetheless of
ear in the mood to support
and you know between your movie
watching escapades that the correct word
escapades. Yeah. Yeah.
I don't recommend it.
I recommend you read whatever you'd
train day. Maybe we'll get you there.
That was a good one I thought.
Anyway. Nonetheless, origin means,
isn't it weird that like training
day is this movie that call,
how much does it cost to make
training day, I don't know,
$50 million and like you can go
to the library and get stolen,
grabbed the book for nothing,
literally nothing. Or you can buy it,
you can buy it on Amazon for I think
this book cost like a dollar cause it's
used. But it's just kind of
a strange dichotomy there.
It's interesting for sure. And uh, you
know, obviously we can go into why,
which one is better for you?
I'm going to go ahead and say that stolen
grads better for you than training day.
Oh, well, depends on what
you get out of it. You know,
you know how like asking the
actually people would ask me,
how do you read to get the most out of it?
How do you well,
I read it while I'm reading it
highlighted. Oh yeah. Jordan B. Peterson.
I was watching something. The other
said, don't highlight anything. Yeah,
this is the f this. I have a major
disagreement with Jordan B. Peterson.
I'm not highlighting,
highlighting fool. But uh,
anyway,
so I go through,
I highlight what hits me and
then I go back and reread it.
And then I have the red pen
to circle the important,
really important on the kindle.
It, you can choose your, um,
your color of highlighter.
So the yellow is general
highlighting and then the orange
nonetheless. All right,
well how about this,
we'll talk about some Jujitsu
gies cause people ask me, yeah,
what, Gee, should I get?
You get origin geese.
That's it made in America from the threats
from the cotton. That's what we say.
As we all know, being an American
to the shirt, dirt to the shirt.
Have you said that field to
finish? No, I just was up there.
I was just up at the factory with Pete.
I caught the Facebook live on it,
on my head and my mind to this show.
Is that to shame?
I think it might be just like,
yeah,
two shirt might be field to
finish hands in daylight,
hands and daylight, but
yeah, make some good stuff.
Especially geese in America.
Like I said,
I'm good in Jujitsu,
you know I ha I have a few
geese. Ah, a few these,
I don't use any of them except the
origin ones go to or do you mean.com.
That's where you can get your Ge Ford.
You did too. They also have rash cards,
compression gear.
Right,
and that's for Jujitsu I think primarily.
But you can use it for other
stuff. Of course. Yeah, indeed.
Big Time.
Also Jocko is some supplements,
good supplements.
Krill oil.
I was talking to [inaudible] name is
Josh from Virginia Tech Training Team a
couple of times there. And I
think he was here for, you know,
a few weeks ago whenever chain. And uh,
you know, so we talk about somebody,
he's young, he's 21, and he's like, oh
yeah, I take fish oil. I was like, Dang,
that's good. And krill oil is better
than fish oil. I know this because my,
I told you, I already, my
dad told me all the benefits,
blah, blah, blah. Nonetheless,
but he's taking joint
supplements at 21. He said, no,
I don't have problems with my joints,
but I just want to maintain this
joint situation as I get older.
I was like, Oh, you're way ahead of me.
So, um, so I give them some, uh, your,
uh, joint warfare. Yeah, that's good. Uh,
Pete Pete from origin. He, he's,
he needs joint warfare.
He can feel it dissipate in a day.
And Mike, when I was with was
with him, he'd be, you know,
at five o'clock Nafisa Macra,
hold on, I'll be right back.
Irritation, germ warfare.
So he said he's at the threshold.
He needs it.
Yeah. And that's actually, it's
interesting cause you know,
you can see what's selling and what's
cool is you can see joint warfare,
Krill oil.
Like what's awesome about us,
it's the repeat customers
of people that order it.
Then they ordered again and
then they ordered again.
Because you don't want her to, if you're
not feeling it. Yeah, that's what I'm,
that's how I am with the Krill oil.
100% like if you like I'll
forget and I'll be like,
you know like Oh I'll take it later. I
don't forget. And that, yeah, I know.
Don't you have a morning routine
and whatever. And that's the thing.
That's the thing doesn't include
just wake up, boom, boom,
boom from your medicine cabinet open my,
all my stuff is right there.
Not to go too deep, too deep
into my routine. But during
the week it's, you know,
wake up and then there's
like my daughter's four
and a half, she has school.
So there's that situation going on.
This is nice.
This does not interfere with you getting
up and taking some pills for before you
brush your teeth.
Kind of not see that's the thing.
The routine doesn't allow for me to take
them before I've actually, it's part of,
it's the routine is the routine,
the routine. Because for me,
if you gotta you gotta you gotta take
the pills before you brush your teeth.
Cause when you brush your teeth you got
the strong men in there and it makes the
water like too cold in your
teeth. Yes. He and I liked that.
I think it's more refreshing.
I need to harden up a little bit.
Maybe Jack, probably nonetheless.
Sometimes I forget three,
four and if you forget for like four
days and you're still working out or
whatever, you'll feel it. I will feel
it. So same thing Crilly I need it.
Yup. I had Lafe actually, actually Jenna,
Jenna brought me Krill oil.
I know that Bro. That's okay.
And I don't want to ask for seventh panic.
My crew oil bring me some,
I don't want to do that, but probably the
most important level seven panic mode.
Yup. Nonetheless, Krill oil vector, Krill
oil, Krill oil supercrew has a super,
super krill. It's not normal crowd
super. And there's many reasons for that.
You can find out on the website or do
you mean.com if you want to know those
exact reasons. Also joint
warfare, that's for your joints.
Maintain your body structure
while you're working out.
Good call cause it does
dissipate.
I didn't want to use the word dissipate,
but what do you call it? Degenerate.
Degenerate. Sure. After time when you've,
when you go hard in the paint it does.
Unless like I said, they got compression
gear, gies rash guards, most stuff,
hoodies, which may or may
not be the most comfortable.
Hoodies and pants by the way.
The sweatpants. Joggers, joggers,
yes.
So the the other day I'm like okay,
I'm exporting some special effect
that I did. So I'm like, shoot,
when you export it's like
you can't really use that program.
You know you can exit by me. It's
a long story. But so I'm like okay,
I'm off of my computer for, you know,
it's going to take like 10 minutes.
A big effect. So like I lay on the
couch and have the whole origin
on for whatever reason just
kind of happened to, I lay
on the couch and I'm like,
Dang, I don't think I felt this
comfortable in a long time, but it was,
everything was calm.
That's,
that's pretty bold statement because
you are the experience level of comfort.
I mean comfort seeker hundred percent
and I evaluate you evaluate various
comfort level level.
It
could have very well been one of the
highest. I get it. It was everything.
It was a couch.
It was a time of day.
It was the fact that they usually don't
play around with one of my seal buddies
for many years we were kind of just,
just young,
dumb frog man.
We had this yellow couch that
was like 14 feet long. You get,
it was just kind of deal. It was
like maybe five feet deep. Dang.
It was like a bed.
Realistically it was like five feet deep.
Which ones you through
the back cushions off.
It was from my feet deep and
it was probably 1212 feet long.
And where was this in our
part in your apartment.
Who was gold felt beat.
We got it from some shop.
Yeah,
that's the kind you have like a
lounge and something dollars for,
we had one like that at Uah in the,
in the football lounge. They was like,
it wasn't most graspable that couch you
were looking at tonight in my house.
And you're like, oh that's a nice
couch. That couch out there all nice.
Doesn't even come close to the comfort
of the old gold couch was the deal. Yeah.
It's weird how like ugly like couches
will be the most functionally comfortable.
We had this one my wife forced us to
give away and cause it was outside,
he got phased out slowly. You know how
you get a new couch and you're like, okay,
where do we do that where I'm not
going to give it away because it's too
comfortable and we've had it for so
long and it's like in good shape. Oh.
And then we get another couch for
the, for the side. They're all,
we know we do with this so and
so. It ends up outside, you know,
and he wants to get of a cow, not a couch
outside. It's like it's of, you know,
it doesn't, does, doesn't look good,
blah, blah, blah. Give it away.
But it was the most comfortable culture.
I think we actually know the
new ones more comfortable.
I don't know what I'm talking
about. Nonetheless. Back origin,
go to origin main.com.
That's it.
That's where you get it and
you can get the discipline
there too. Yeah, yeah, yeah.
The discipline, big time. The preworkout,
the pre mission remission. That
remission. Yeah. She didn't say it to me.
I take it before a workout. See, I
don't, I take it before I do Jitsu.
I take it before I have to do a podcast
or I take it before I have to do like
an, like a speaking event, go where I need
to my brain. It has to be firing. Yeah.
Yeah. Could you just
keep before bid? I mean,
I know it has a little bit of caffeine
but like I have and I think you can't,
I don't think I'd strongly recommend it.
Especially if you're caffeine sensitive
like I am, I'm caffeine sensitive.
But you drink your nine
monster energy drinks a day.
You can drink whatever you want from
you talk a white tea cause there's a lot
less caffeine. The you figure the
discipline. She saw a lot of people,
you know a lot of people hit me of used
Jocko white tea to ween off of full
strength coffee cause they don't want
to be on that coffee but there's enough
need caffeine.
They lit a little something to wean off.
It's like Methadone getting off heroin.
So you might want to try that.
You don't the Jocko white tea,
you want to have coffee breath anymore
because no one likes that. Yeah,
it's brilliant. It's really not
like Methadone. But since the uh,
the pre workout,
pre mission has a cognitive enhancers,
you figure, you know, when you sleep,
that's like the best part
of your brain or cupboard.
Best time for your brain to recover.
Maybe that's a little something I
don't recommend it cause like I said,
but you never know. Could
be, could be something.
I wouldn't drink it before I go to
bed. Maybe when you wake up. Yeah.
But I don't drink when I wake up I'll
drink cause I don't drink it for,
I don't drink any kind of pre
workout for it before I work out,
before I lift weights, before I do a
metcon I don't, yeah, maybe I should,
I don't know.
Maybe I should try and one of the reasons
cause I don't like have anything in my
stomach when I'm working out. Yeah. But
those pre workouts is like, yeah, I know.
It's not really anything, right. It's
just like water. Like water. Yeah.
I'll maybe I'll try it. Yeah,
tell me. Report back please.
Okay. We'll do. Yes sir.
Also speaking of working out,
I get my kettle kettle bells from on
it on.com/chocolates we can get them
kettlebells, the designer whey you
don't have to get the designer ones.
I know all we say the designer ones get
to designer ones and I'm still saying it
big time. Let's see. You don't have to
like, let me get to know him a little.
Get to know ones, but nonetheless on
it, they have other cool workout stuff.
You want your work out to be creative
telling me like, you know the, you know
the mace rate one of those? I have. I do.
Yeah. You ever done like a workout with
a mace? Yeah. Yeah. I incorporate them.
My name for, I've got to mace exercises,
but one of them is called like,
can I have notes in my notebook on what?
My workout and I have like
barbarian smash. That's the word.
No, no, no. That's the
movement of the movement. Okay.
I think made up and then one's like a
battle ax swing. Sure. So, yeah. Yeah.
It's like you can do those with the
mace. Yeah. And it amazes heavy though.
Like my race is 20 pounds.
Yeah. That's heavy for
Tevye. 20 pounds. That's how much
the baseball bat way. Oh, I dunno.
I Dunno. A couple pounds.
You can put your sauce,
16 ounce weight the other
day for the end of your bat.
When you're getting warmed
up. A Macy's 20 pounds. Yes.
It's really heavy and the, to me, you
gotta be careful actually. Yeah, big time.
Yeah,
because be careful.
You don't expect that much weight on
a mount of Mace with that weird cause.
The 20 pound Dumbbell, you think, oh,
that's a 20 but that's not
even part of the workout.
I don't need to warm up with
20 pounds in any exercise.
The kind of attitude and then you're
like swooped winter blues so late.
Then you pick up that
mace and you're like,
this is like the heaviest stick I've
ever be held for sure in stick form.
Nonetheless, the three, give them a lot
of this stuff too. It's really cool.
So go on a dotcom slash Jocko
and check it out. Get something.
Also subscribe to the podcasts,
iTunes, Google, play, stitcher,
anywhere there where they broadcasts.
Podcasts, podcasts, podcasts.
Yeah, Spotify to confirmed. Boom. Do it.
Also Youtube, if you want the
video version of this podcast,
she wouldn't see what Jocko looks like.
You know, you're into that kind of stuff.
Look on Youtube.
Also have excerpts on there.
Actually someone emailed me and
said just for the excerpts at, Hey,
thanks for putting excerpts on there.
That's pretty cool.
That is pretty cool to be like,
yeah, just hey, this is cool.
So obviously it's a good thing.
There are excerpts on there.
That's a good thing cause sometimes
the podcast goes a little long,
especially this section.
No,
I think your two hours of reading
the book,
not in the less youtube, some value
there. I think if you, you know,
you watch with so certain people they put
it in there each year. Live some point.
Yeah.
On our,
on the youtube channel we'll pull
even more value. Send you an alert,
right? I think so. Yeah. Yeah.
If you're subscribed, yeah.
If you allow the alert and you're
subscribing you can. Yeah. That's good.
You do good way to support.
Also Jocko is a store.
It's called Jocko store Jocko store.com
that's where you can get all the cool
shirts. They're cool. I think they're all
the shirts. Discipline equals freedom.
Get after it.
There's even the shirt that Jocko
where's every single day in his life,
the victim. I make sure it's available.
You can get it. You can get it.
I'm also rash guards on, there's some cool
stuff. Women's stuff on their hoodies,
patches, hats. You know what? I'm going
to make this commitment right now.
I'm going to put something new.
Every single,
I don't know what you're not.
I'm like closet committed.
I don't know.
Every month I'll put something new and
people have a dial you to tell you what
they want. No, actually,
yes, actually I like that.
Or even she'll be on
social media. Email. Yeah.
Email through the store or
Twitter or whatever the PR we do.
Everyone does for sure.
They see all this stuff.
Is suggestions actually alive
there. Yeah, exactly right.
Heavier duty sweatshirts, hats,
beanies beneath, you know,
they're on the way. Yeah. So yeah,
they're in the pipe for sure.
100% that's a suggestion.
Yeah.
This is all people
suggestions from the field.
Say that. Yeah. So yeah, it takes
suggestions. Big Time. I kind of,
I pulled the trigger on the ones
that have the most suggestions.
So sometimes I understand that,
you know, if you're like, Hey,
I made a suggestion and I still
haven't seen the, you know,
you're in the field too and I dig it,
but if you're the only one siren, sorry,
I got no pull over here. Yeah, you
get a little, not that much though,
unless anyway, Jaclyn [inaudible]
dot com that's the place. Also,
psychological warfare. If you didn't
know what that is, here's what it is.
It's an album that you can buy an iTunes,
Amazon music,
Google play, anywhere where
you can buy MP three downloads.
It's an album that you can buy
with tracks, chocolate tracks,
and this is what it's for.
It's not music.
It's not Jocko singing or playing guitar.
What else do you play?
Ukulele now? Yeah. You can lay it
up. Yeah, that you can't. So Jackson,
I'm playing that and he's, he's
speaking to you. Pragmatic.
He's given us us pragmatic advice on
why or how I would say how to overcome
certain points of weakness in
our campaigns against weakness.
That's what it is.
So you know you want to skip the workout,
you want to cheat on the diet or it isn't.
You're compelled to one day cause you're,
you're feeling tired.
If you run into little speed bumps
and your campaign, listen to this,
to the track where everything,
trust me, just look at it.
What if instead of somebody
wanting to watch training day,
they want to read one of these books,
where could they get them in?
What's the best way to shop for them while
supporting this podcast? Glad you ask.
I got the solution right now. This is
what I did. If you didn't know already,
here's what I did. Go to
Jocko, podcast.com Jocko
podcast.com not the store.
It's the podcast website.
Oregonized all the books by episode in
a section called books from the podcast.
Click through there. Actually that's a
good way to support two takes it Amazon,
Amazon prime to get the
book in like two days. Boom.
And it supports the podcast to big time.
Good way to support things
whenever you like. Man. Long
Mow, lawn mowers, duct tape.
What else? Rubber.
Duckies if you have kids,
you know what else you can get on
amazon.com as you can get Jocko white tea.
It's true.
When you get it.
Also order yourself some new weight
because upon drinking Jocko white tea,
you will be able to dead lift
8,000 pounds certified you.
Oh,
you got some
new weights? Did he? Yeah, I
did. All right. We'll leave
it at that. It's all good.
It's all good.
It happens.
Uh, you can also get some
books, some books, uh,
from, you know that, that
I've kind of put together.
The one of them is called
way of the warrior kid.
That book teaches kids to do
the right things in their lives.
Study, read, workout, eat clean,
help others work hard, uh,
get tons of feedback on that
book because it helps kids.
They relate to it.
Speaking of related to it,
there's a little warrior get out there.
12 years old and name is Aiden.
He reached out to me and wanted,
he makes soap from goat milk.
Do you hear this story?
Makes me hear the whole story.
Okay. He makes so from goat milk.
You know why he makes soap from goat milk.
You can't do anything with
goat milk in California.
You can't sell it to someone
because it's not edible or whatever.
They have laws reglaze
write the regs in place.
What do you do with goat milk then?
He didn't know what to do with it.
Did he figure it out? I'll make soap
and then he wanted to make good soap
and so he said, hey, can I make some
Jocko soap? And I was like, Yeah Dude,
you're 12 years old.
Get after it.
And he did Irish oaks
ranch.com you can order yours.
Oh,
it was on a link on the website.
Front page so you can support a young or
your kid. 12 years old business owner.
So legit way I hit him.
Discipline equals freedom field manual.
That's also about getting stronger,
smarter, faster, healthier and better.
The audio version of that is not on
audible. It's on iTunes, Amazon music,
Google play. It's an album
with tracks by the way. Sure.
Actually it's two albums with tracks.
On top of that,
we've got extreme ownership.
The book written by myself
and my brother Leif Babin.
It's about combat leadership.
That's what it's about.
And if you want to learn how to lead,
you can check out that book.
Also, if your business team or your
organization needs a little extra help,
you can utilize our leadership
consulting company called Echelon Front.
You're, you're in a lot of talk
tonight about the rear echelon.
That's why we named national
and international on front
the rear echelon of the
people in the rear echelon.
The front echelon is the people in the
front lines and that's why we named the
organization Ashkelon Front because
there's a lot of people that talk about
leadership, but they're talking about
it from the rear echelon, from the back.
We're talking about it from the front,
our experiences on the front lines.
We solve problems,
whatever problems through leadership.
So that's our company national in
front. Me, Leif, Babin, JP Denelle,
Dave Burke. You can
email@echelonfront.com or the website.
You can check it out if you want to.
And finally if you haven't heard yet,
the muster.
Yeah,
Washington DC May 17th
and 18th San Francisco,
October 17th and 18th we've had four of
them in the past two years actually like
the last year and a
half they all sold out.
This one's going to sell out to it is a
leadership conference where we drilled
down on how to lead. We give
leadership tools, tactics,
strategies
that will allow you to lead
and when echelon front,
that's our event.
You can register for it
extreme ownership.com and
if you want to continue to
talking with us or you have
questions or if you have answers,
if you want to tell me a mistake
that I made in the podcast tonight,
which I'm sure I did
or you have comments you want
to make as to what we do here,
you can find us on the interwebs,
on Twitter,
on Instagram and on the face she ball
hot echo is echo Charles and I m at Jocko
Willink.
And finally thank you for
listening to the show.
Thank you for supporting the show.
Thank you for spreading the word.
Thanks to those of you that
make this podcast possible,
the men and women of our
armed services that protect
our freedom and especially in this case,
our right to free speech to the
police, firefighters, paramedics,
and other first responders that are
out there every day, keeping us safe.
Thank you.
And everyone else that is listening.
Thank you for standing
up and leading yourself,
leading yourself away from
weakness and toward strength,
away from laziness and toward action.
Away from comfort and
towards the discipline,
away from catastrophe,
been toward victory.
Keep leading
and keep getting after it.
Okay.
And until next time,
this is echo and Jocko out.