This is Jocko podcast number
one 28 with Echo Charles and me,
Jocko Willink. Good
Evening Echo. Good evening.
It's been a little bit
since we've done a Q and a.
So we're going to roll into some Q
and a and gonna to try and answer more
questions than normal
with some shorter answers.
Got a lot of Twitter questions which
necessitates shorter questions and thereby
in some cases, shorter
answers. I've got to,
I've got some more detailed answers or
detailed questions stacked up for another
Q and a. But for today we're just going
to try and get through some of these,
um,
no guarantee on that.
But with rock and roll. Cool. Taco,
do you believe in overtraining,
keep believing overtraining, or
is that an excuse people, youth,
you have the CT, Fletcher's
triathletes, yourself, et Cetera,
who get after it daily.
You also find other elite athletes who
believe in rest days who are by no means
slackers. What's your take? You
know, what can you overtrain? Yes,
you can. Yeah, you can definitely
overtrain. I will say this,
most people don't overtrain cause you got
to work pretty hard to overtrain. Yeah.
And if you overtrain you'll know it
if you're paying attention to your
performance because your
performance will start to go down.
That that's what's happening.
And I've said this before,
I've seen it with fighters that were
preparing for a fight and they'd be
overtraining and you'd watch
their performance. Someone
that's normally crushing,
let's say the fighters normally crushing
training partner a and all of a sudden
training a partner, a starts getting
the better of the fighter and you know,
you know, it's, it's obvious the guy's
overtrained so take a couple of days off,
get some steak and get back,
get reset cause you're overtrained
so yeah, you can overtrain for sure.
Now what I don't believe in,
well it's hard to overtrain.
I mean these guys are working to
hard when they're overtraining,
but a lot of people just, they, they do.
You can use overtraining as an excuse.
What I do is I'm going to
do something every day.
I try and do something every
day regardless. Like even if,
even if I feel like I'm completely,
like last night I got kind of beat
up on the mat. I know I'm pretty,
I'm pretty overtrained right now, but
I'm also getting ready to go on a trip.
So I'm like, okay, well I just to still,
I squatted today and I'm still
going to train hard tonight.
And then I got a couple of
days where I'll be on the road.
I might take one of those days and just
like do more of a stretch mobility type
scenario work.
I'll still get the blood flowing cause I
got to get the blood flow. But you know,
maybe just like a hundred burpees
and then a bunch of stretching.
So I'll do a little recovery on the road.
But yes you can overtrain it's hard to
do it if your performance is going down,
you're overtraining, eat some steak, take
a break, take a break, eat some steak.
Well hundred burpees kind of a lot.
I think a hundred burpees. Yeah.
That's like less
than 10 minutes. Put it this
way. I did. Oh then again,
all the times it did a hundred burpees
with after a workout so that it feels a
little different. Yeah, you just
go do a hundred burpees. Burpees,
yeah. The, well, the Gilkey.
So overtraining though is like there's
two or maybe even more different kinds of
quote unquote overtraining. So there's
like this like a for real like, I dunno,
I'm going to misuse a clinical
version of overtraining,
which is like official, like your blood,
you can recognize it in your blood,
it likes certain things and sure,
whatever. And there's all these symptoms.
They're not as probably it's a thing,
it's an actual thing like you don't sleep
and it's like your body be essentially
goes into this like negative kind of
feedback or positive feedback loop where
it's like,
but it just,
you're overtraining and it takes
like a while to get out of it.
Like a while you gotta
go through this process.
And then there's also like a condition
like rhabdo something that's a serious
situation that's essentially overtraining.
Yes.
That's a cute or training quickly.
Yeah,
usually to get hit with the rabbit and
then there's like this kind of gray area
and you can get Rhabdo I
guess you can get, I think,
I think you get robbed when like
certain muscle groups offer.
But anyways Rhabdo yeah, that'll take
you out. I remember cake nuts was we're,
we're rolling kicked.
He's the kind of guy who's like
just kind of down for anything. Not,
there's kind of like fireplug
type guy cause he's super mellow,
but he's just down for anything.
Like the kind where if you're going to go
do something kind of weird or whatever,
he'll always concerned to just be there.
You know, he always kind of says yes.
So anyway, we're training
and he, you know,
when someone asks you to roll and
you're done, you're like, oh, not done.
Maybe next time, you know, not
cake, nuts. He was like, okay,
does and you could tell he was like tired.
It's like okay.
And then we're all done or 80 and then
you know how certain guys come in late or
whatever. It may be one, two
guys. And another guy asked
him, number one, we're like,
Dang, cake dot still rolling. And I
think even enrolled before us too,
and he was just rolling and rolling.
He might've did some other PT
or whatever and he's like, man,
I'm really tired right now. And then
another guy asked them, well, let's roll.
And he's like, okay. And we're just
laughing. Like it was kind of, yeah,
tile these, which means all these
roles are not like relaxed scenarios.
Their actual level nine deaf battles.
He's going forward.
He's a perfect dog down by the way.
Oh, that's cool. Yeah. Um, but yeah,
at the time I think he was a white belt
and yeah. So he goes and you're like, man,
I'm tired. I'm messed up. And
I was like, yeah man, I dig it.
And then you rolled a lot and then come
to find out he had rhabdo. But anyway,
and then there's a grey area over
training where you're training a lot.
Maybe your testosterone will be down
from training a lot. And me, you know,
your nutrition may or may not
be all that kind of thing.
So your performance does go down.
You feel a little bit more tired
going into training, you know,
if you're lifting or whatever,
you can't lift this heavy and all this
stuff that's like a great or you're not
overtrained no, he just, how you say
just your, just steak. And a day,
two days later, boom, you're
kind of back in the game,
you know,
kind of thing.
But I don't think that's a clinical
technically overtrained maybe you're not
recovering day to day as much as
something like this, but none the less,
but all true things. All real things. Hey,
your bodies, this machine man. If you,
you know, with all these different
systems that the system's ain't work,
all ain't working right, you may not get,
you know, the performance that you, uh,
do you want?
Next question.
What would you pack for lunch if
you had a typical nine to five job?
Chicken, steak, beef Jerky, the
nuts. I don't know. A salad. No.
Big shocker there. Yeah, just
don't eat the doughnuts in
the office. Next question.
Know Tuna Sandwich? No. Tuna
Sandwich. Whole wheat bread,
tomato, lettuce, sprouts.
That's your go to now.
That's what my mom would probably pack
for me if she was packing my lunch
for lunch. When you were
younger. That wasn't a question.
It kind of sounds like my mom would
have happened to me when I was young.
Pb and J. All right. Oh, there it
is. That's good bag of potato chips.
Oh that's not good. Well how's PB and
j good but, but potato chips are not,
I just manages the same. It tastes good
actually. But peanut butter is good.
And of course what I would do is take
the attendance was put them on the
like a second. All good. But yeah, so
there you go. You guys know what to eat.
Come on, knock it off. But I,
I'm sure they're asking because
that is kind of a thing.
Like do you have a nine to
five job? Right. And especially
if kind of the culture,
he was like, okay, I go to work and
then boom, we got, well got a lunch,
me and my boys from work, we did a
lunch, maybe a bar maybe, you know,
kind of thing. But they want to break the
cycle. So it's like, you know, it's not,
it's kinda common LG like okay, break the
cycle of bring your own lunch. You, yeah,
we'll definitely bring you a much,
normally you will, you eat better,
but you also won't spend $19 for lunch.
Yeah.
You'll spend like $6 for lunch and it'll
be better for you. So that's just, yeah.
Yeah. Okay. So maybe I
should've made that more clear.
Don't go out to the little
corner store and or whatever,
the corner restaurant and spend $28 for
crappy food that's going to make you fat
and lazy. Yeah. Just pack your own food
that cost $6. That's gonna make you lean,
strong and smarter. Yeah. But, and then
their incomes, this question, I, I think,
I don't know, but I think so because
let's say you've never done that before.
Yeah. Sounds crazy. But here's the
thing. So, so Greg chain, right?
You always eat tough and I don't think
he ever like cooked at home or whatever.
Right. And me and Kinda, well, I'd kind of
do both, whatever, but I cook it at home.
I go make it, have my goto
little things right. And home.
So we were talking and I was
explained to him, Oh yeah, oh yeah,
I'll just do this when I'm on the
program, I'll do this, I'll make this.
And he's like, Dang you,
you actually do that.
And I'm like cook and make stuff at home.
I'll surprise like it was like
this foreign thing for it. Okay.
I'll give you a goto right now. You want
to talk to co two. So you said tuna.
I have a
tin chicken. Like I don't even know
what my wife calls it. Tin Chicken.
It comes to can cause I
don't really like fish. Sure.
And so I have chicken in a can open it
up, put some mandates in there. You're,
you're good food. I'll do that too. And
you can get big big cans of chicken.
Go to Costco. Total. Goto.
Yeah. Yeah, that's a good one.
Let us sodium a lot of times
in those ones, you know,
if you care about this kinds of things.
But yeah,
there's a lot of chicken in there too.
You know what he can do with that too
if you have just a little bit more time.
The ticket, the one in the Kansas wheat
is good cause it's so fast. Boom, boom,
boom. One speed. But if you, uh,
you can like kinda halfway
boil some chicken, chop it up,
saute it, and then chop
it up even more. Boom.
Add the minis is kind of the same
deal and you can do it that way.
You don't need like the canned chicken.
Some people do not prefer canned chicken.
That's cool. That's the thing. I can
do other things. Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Then that's the other thing I'm talking
about anyway, so, well, you know,
if your mom made chicken,
I know,
you know how Greg, it was foreign
to Greg to actually cook at home.
It's foreign for people to actually
make a lunch. They're like, man,
where do I start with this thing? What
do I do? And then usually in fact,
from what I understand anyway,
usually it's kind of like, oh, all,
all kind of sort of buy a lunch
while I'm not at work. You know,
maybe go to the store,
buy one of these box lunches or
something and then bring it in.
It's defeating the purpose. Yeah, it's a
thing, but it's a defeating the purpose.
You make the lunch like a
sandwich or something like
that. I'm telling you. Cool.
It works. That's the direction
you want to go. That's my opinion.
Next question. You've mentioned
being involved in real estate.
Are you still involved? How'd you get
started? Whether flipping or renting,
flipping,
buying,
fixing up and selling houses
or renting or whatever.
Did you start with a lot of money or no?
Is it something you are
or were very hands on with
or contract workout? I've been real lucky
with re the whole real estate thing.
Part of it's,
cause I was in the military and
while the crash happened I did,
I didn't even barely knew there was an
economic crash going on. And so we're,
so we're talking 2007 2008 timeframe
when the market crashed and I was in the
military,
so I just kept doing what I was doing
and bought some houses then and I would
say yeah. And then I've continued
to do that. So it's a good,
it's a good investment.
Longterm, short term,
you can get screwed if you think you're
going to buy something right now. Like,
for instance, flipping a house, that's
cool, you can make a lot of money.
But also you could buy right now,
buy a house for $200,000 and think
you're going to fix it up and sell it for
$300,000 and then you buy
it and the market crashes.
And now your house that you bought for
$200,000 is only worth hundred and 50 so
now you're, you're out of luck. So you,
the way I look at it, you know, just as,
as a normal person. Yeah,
just try and buy a house.
That's number one by trying my house to
live in and then try and pay it off as
fast as you can.
And then when you get it to a good point
and you fix it up and you think you can
run it out,
that's cool dude.
It rented out and buy another one and keep
doing that one thing, one, I, you know,
I'm no real estate expert. I'm
not running around, you know,
explain, explaining. I'm
not going to put out a,
I'm not going to put on a seminar on the
proper real estate investing, but hey,
if you're going to buy, buy a
house, this is, this is something,
a little bit of advice.
If you're going to buy a house,
buy a house in the place
where you want to live,
where you want to live in it
by the worst crappiest house,
but where you want it, cause the location
you cannot change. Once you buy it,
you're stuck in that location
and so he said if you can,
but you can always rebuild it and fix
it up and make it nice. So buy a house.
I made that mistake one
time I bought a house.
I bought a bigger house in a place where
I didn't really like it, but I thought,
well the house is so
nice and big and about,
it was like two weeks after I bought it.
This is actually the
first house I ever bought.
Two weeks after I bought it I was saying,
man,
I should have bought the
other house I was looking at.
That was in the location I wanted.
Then it was a little bit smaller
and not as Nice. So anyways,
by where you want it and then fix it
up as you go along. As far as the work,
doing the work,
all the work that I did on my houses,
I did myself.
And
now I don't do it as much anymore
more because I don't have time.
But when I was in the navy,
well you either have time
where you have money, right?
So when I was in the navy,
I had more time,
if you can believe that when I was
in the navy and I had no money,
so like all my houses, when I
bought them, I couldn't afford them.
I could barely afford them.
So you gotta be,
that's now not advising that because
if you gotta be able to suck it up,
if things go sideways, you're going to
be living on Lee. No money live in leap.
It's going to be lean Christmas doesn't,
my parents used to say to me,
and that's what I said to my kids,
is going to be lean Christmas.
So you gotta be ready for the link. Some
people aren't ready for Lean Christmas.
Yes.
Some people cannot live,
some people cannot control
their expenses if things go bad.
And you know,
when I bought all my,
just about every house I bought when I
got into my house, it was like, okay,
we made it. Now we're going to
starve for two years or whatever.
Trying to get everything
squared away again. So anyways,
you got to be smart. Um,
but it definitely makes more sense to buy.
I shouldn't say this cause there's
some people that argue again,
I think if you're going to
live somewhere for a while,
buy a house instead of paying
someone else's mortgage,
pay your own and try and pay it
down as quick as you can. That's it.
That's my advice. Cool.
Okay. I guess I dunno,
I'm really less of an expert in that.
Yeah. Like, like here's an idea.
When you joined military as save up all
your money, don't spend it on booze,
which you're going to,
you're going to want to cause everyone's
gonna be going out. Don't do that by,
by whatever.
You can buy by the little Condo,
buy something and then rent out the
rooms that are in it and you sleep on the
couch and you rent out the rooms
and you're paying the mortgage.
As soon as you get that
thing kind of stable, boom,
go and buy another one and that's,
that's how you can start doing it.
You said that it was easier for you in
the cause you were in the military. Why?
Why is it easy?
Paycheck was coming no matter what.
He hasn't like I was going
to get laid off. I mean,
so many people got laid off during the,
during the economic downturn,
they couldn't buy, they couldn't afford
their mortgage payments anymore and that,
that was made the bad
situation even worse.
So for me it was like I was just sitting
there collecting my paycheck as normal.
Didn't even really realize that the
market was getting destroyed on all fronts
because I was in the military and I
wasn't sitting around staring at the,
at the stock market everyday trying to
figure out where it was going to go and
do, do you get, I mean you do, right? You
get like benefits or he'd loans easier,
whatever. Yeah. There's something
called the VA loan, which,
which is a good loan. It's a good
loan and you can only get one though.
So I mean I use that you can reset
it and you use it on other houses,
but which I've done a couple of times,
but that's a cool little jumping off
point or jumping off, jumping off point.
It's a really good jumping off point for
sure. But the thing to be careful of is,
is speculating and thinking that the
prices of houses is always going to go up,
which is what everyone fought in
2006 2007 2008 hey, don't worry.
The prices are just going to
keep going up. They're not.
They're going to come down sometimes.
Yeah. And so you can't bank on that.
You can't bank on that. What you bank
on is like, okay, I liked this house.
It's in a good location.
I'm gonna live here for a long time.
If I get stuck in it for a long time,
I don't Matt my mind,
I won't be mad and I can suffer.
Okay. I can make my family suffer. Okay.
Like, you know when you can't take your,
your family out for dinner for
months on end like, oh no, sorry,
we're not going out for
dinner. Oh No, we're not doing
that. We're not buying that.
Buying your kids used stuff for Christmas,
which I did when I was in the
military. The, okay. You know,
I'd love to get you something new,
but guess what?
Sometimes Santa Claus bring some
stuff from recycled, recycled goods.
Some other kids didn't want
it. That's fine. If you,
if you don't have that in you to
suck it up and, and live lean,
then you, you don't, then you
need to make different decisions.
Cause cause a lot of times I know
it was like this and like oh seven,
six maybe, um, where guys,
like I remember seeing people,
they'd like a lot of people were just
becoming loan officers. Oh yeah for sure.
Like flipping houses, you know,
kind of thing. And it's kind of all,
they look at it as like
this get rich quick kind of
thing. And then they're like,
yeah, let me just do it. It's either
you have no experience necessary,
all this stuff and then
they'll do it all educated.
All like with none of the way
you just said none of that.
And I got a buddy that he,
he was telling me the story cause he
was in the seal teams and during that
market boom, during the housing market,
boom, he bought like five houses. Yeah.
And he is so funny to hear him.
He's a humble guy and he's telling him,
telling me the story is 10 years ago,
he's telling me the story, but he's like,
he's like,
yeah,
when I was doing this I thought
everyone else was so stupid.
I thought it was just the smartest guy
in the world because of what he was doing
was getting these loans that he couldn't
afford. But at that time, the, the,
the mortgage people were giving loans
to anybody and he did it and he did it
over and over. And so we ended
up with five houses and he said,
he remembered asking you another
real estate guy, like, Hey, what if,
what if the housing prices go down?
And the guy's like,
that's not going to happen. And
if it does, even if it did happen,
you'd have six months to a year to
offload all your properties and it'd be no
problem.
Within a month of that,
the market turned and
he said 30 days later,
every one of his
properties was upside down,
meaning he owed more than
they were worth in 30 days.
And he ended up foreclosing on it.
All those houses, except for one,
he was lucky enough to keep the one that
he lived in anyways. So, yeah. Don't,
you know, be measured. It's balanced.
Don't just get crazy. Yeah. Yeah.
It's not like this.
Get rich like the risks.
I would take was the risk of,
okay,
if things don't go well,
it's going to be a lean
Christmas and I'm okay with that.
If you're not okay with Alene Christmas
and Eileen and not going out for dinner
and buying your kids, use presence for
Christmas. If you're not okay with that,
but you know, what do you want for
your birthday? Oh, you want to,
you want something for your birthday?
Cool.
I'll get you something that resembles
that, but it might not be the act.
If you're not okay with that,
then then don't do it.
I never would gamble the fact
that, okay, if this goes wrong,
we won't have anywhere to live.
That's a different,
that's a different level gambled. I didn't
gamble that. I didn't gamble like, okay,
if I, if the market goes sideways,
I'm not going to have a place to live.
I didn't gamble that. If the
market goes sideways, Hey,
it's going to be a lean Christmas and
even you like by your own admission,
you said, I, you know, I do it
where I'd live. Lean kind of thing.
Like you don't have to do it that way.
Like you can be set way more.
You could give yourself your yourself
pattern but no risk, no reward,
but don't risk everything. The
smart be calculated. So yeah,
buy something. Buy something
when you're young, hang onto it.
Rented out by something else. Hang on
to it. Rented out. That's a good plan.
A good longterm plan.
Gotcha.
Talk a long term plan. Long term as
the market goes up and down. Yeah.
This is probably good. At least
most of the time anyway. Long term.
Think long term. Think long term. Yes.
Downtime. Do you ever watch mindless
TV? I asked you this question before.
Do you ever watch mindless TV or youtube
videos to decompress at the end of the
day or is that laziness justifying
wasted time? You know, quite frankly,
I don't have a lot of
free time to do that.
Even if I was all fired up to watch a
mindless video on youtube. Yeah. Uh,
so I guess,
I guess not really.
If I'm going to decompress sometimes.
I mean,
sometimes my kids will want to watch
something and I'll sit there and watch all
soon, whatever. Go Watch an episode
of the office or something like that.
It was going be good. Kind of mindless.
Kind of funny. Yeah. Yeah, that's,
that makes sense. Same, same
deal. I think I used to, you know,
of course I watched my whole life. Five.
Oh, that's a good one. Kind of mindless.
They can tell you this. I've watched zero
w if if they put it on screen or not,
I wouldn't even know what it
was. Les From we, we went,
we were in the hotel gym the other day.
It's like,
check it out and replace the
TV. I'm like, what? He said,
that's Hawaii five o I even
know what he's talking about.
He took a picture of it. He took a picture
of it. He said he felt your presence.
Yeah. It's good. Yeah. That
would have fired me up.
Best workout in the world right there.
[inaudible] we're a gut check.
Next question.
I'm a high school football coach.
When you were in charge of training,
at what point did you use mass punishment,
mass punishment? This basically when
the team's not working together. Gotcha.
Right. When the team's not
working together, and that
can take all kinds of forms,
right? But if they're, if
they're not working together,
they're going to get punished together.
If they're blaming each other,
If they're not supporting each other,
they're going to get punished together.
One thing that I think with a gray areas
is if you have an individual that's
making mistakes, having problems not
performing correctly, and then the team,
whose responsibility is it to
get that person up to speed?
It's the team's responsibility, so if
that person continually has a problem,
it's like, Hey, if the team
doesn't take care of that problem,
then the team has to, has to pay.
Yeah, sure. That makes sense.
Next question.
Instilling and maintaining discipline
in subjective career fields such as
becoming a musician, artists, et cetera.
How do you face the obstacles thrown at
you when you're subjected to people's
opinions to make a living
and not the standard?
Do your job type type of lifestyles?
This, this, this question,
I'm not sure if I have an answer that
people are going to want to hear on this
one.
I think first of all I originally thought
like okay this is about discipline and
you need discipline to get gooder
craft cause that's for sure, right?
If you want to get good at music
or r or whatever, you got to,
you got to have the
discipline to practice it.
But that's not really
what the questions about.
The questions about how do you survive and
how do you deal with it when people
are might not like what you make. Yeah.
And from my perspective,
I think you should do things like art
and music because you really love doing
them and not to make money.
And I think,
I think if you do those things
truthfully from the heart,
then it will strike a chord
with other people in many,
many cases because human beings have
whatever human nature is all kind of the
same.
And so if you do something,
then people will like it and then you
will end up with people that like your
work,
if you're doing art or music
or whatever to make money.
If that's your goal,
well then it's going to be subjective and
that's going to be problematic because
people might, might not like what
you're doing. And so then what you do,
you change it a little bit and then you
change it a little bit and you change a
little bit.
So I dunno,
to me it's like I would rather have
another job that makes me money
so I can get by so that I can do what I
want artistically, if that makes sense.
Uh,
I actually had a guy the other day
that was like saying you get up early,
but different people that are artistic,
they have to have a different
path because they, you know,
if someone's gonna gonna make
music or they're going to,
they're going to draw or paint
or they're going to write,
they need to have freedom.
And I was like, well,
I've kind of written some books
and I play music in a band.
And we make rock and roll.
You know what I mean? Yes.
I didn't get all crazy with the guy
was to be like, no, I'm an artist too.
I just was like, hey man, you know,
if you want to do what you
want man here to help you out.
But that's kind of like the too on the
podcast, like a podcast isn't like,
oh well we need to do this so that we
can get more people to listen so that we
can get more money. It's no actually,
if you don't want to listen to this,
don't listen and we don't,
we're beholden to no one,
no one advertiser is going to pull their
advertising from us cause we don't have
any.
Yes.
So we can do what we want and not be
worried about what other people think.
And I think when you do that,
here's the, here's the, here's the,
the weird,
the thread ties back in.
I think if you're doing what you want and
you're creating what you want from the
heart, truthfully, when it gets out
there, people, people will get into it.
Next question.
How can I introduce my female boss to
the extreme ownership way without being
offensive? Just sell it as
improvement given the stance before,
give the book to her and tell her that
you read this book and you really like it
and you want to become a better leader
and if she could read it and keep you in
check.
If she sees you get not aligned,
she you'd appreciate it and then
just let her read it. Then let the,
let the book work. It was funny, you guys
are talking about this at the muster,
I think late. Maybe you said
it. Maybe they said, I don't
know, but you were like,
I'll tell you how you don't do it.
Throw the book at her and say you need
to square yourself away. Read this book.
And of course that was fun. Not Good. No.
Next question, do you experience
loneliness while at the top?
It's lonely at the top. You ever
heard that expression? If so,
how did you handle it? You
know, actually not really.
And I guess from my perspective,
I look at the top being when I was in
leadership position and I was a platoon
commander or a task unit
commander or the commander of the,
the training detachment, was it
lonely at the top? Not Really, man.
I had friends and people that are hung
out with and people that I would trust to
talk and have conversations with
and so that wasn't really a factor.
And then on top of that,
I actually don't really mind being alone.
It's not a big deal to me.
I don't feel lonely when I'm
by myself. I'm fine, I'm fine.
Somebody asked me the other day,
are you an introvert or an extrovert?
And I was like, mom, probably
both. And they're like, no, no,
but you have to be one of course,
cause right, right. They said,
so the test or whatever, and I said,
um, I said, well, I don't care.
I literally don't care. Well, like if I'm
in a room with a bunch of people, okay,
if I'm in a room with by myself, don't
care, whatever, bring it. No big deal.
Yeah. I think that extrovert,
if I'm not mistaken, like,
like has the need, you know, like they're,
they're attracted to other people being
there. Yes. So I guess that's what I said.
I'm like, yeah, that's fine. Whatever.
Don't care alone. So, so yeah,
I, you know, and I always, like
I said, I had friends that do,
I trusted it and weren't,
weren't like we're good enough friends
that they weren't going to be trying to
get their own gain out of being my friend,
you know,
people that were friends with me before
I was in a leadership position and
people that remain friends after, so not,
not that big of a deal to me. You know,
luckily I guess I'm lucky cause I mean,
it must be a thing if everyone says it.
Yeah. And I guess maybe like I'll tell
you what you do, you do, you work,
I'll tell you this, this is you, when
you, when you're, when you're at the top,
when you're an owner or you're the leader,
there's times where you have
to do things by herself. Yeah.
There's no doubt about that.
And if you have a problem with that,
you're going to have a problem being in
a leadership position because there's
things that you have to do as leader.
You have to lead from the front, right?
You have to work harder.
You have to do extra you.
You should be working
harder than everyone else.
When you're in a leadership position
of an organization, no doubt about it.
And if you're not working harder,
that's not good. And if you're,
if you're working harder,
there's gonna be times when
you're not with anyone else,
and you have to be okay with that. And
I'm perfectly okay with that. Don't care.
And that's actually what,
that's what that expression means.
It's lonely at the top,
meaning like you're at the top because
you're willing to be in a general way of
putting it, behave or be a certain way
that other people either can't write.
So you're not going to be able
to relate from that perspective.
But you're definitely lonely at the top.
There's no one that's going to sit there
and do what I'm willing to do to be
there. Yeah. Like where are you at
pawn? Don't know, haven't seen you,
but I'm up here by myself, but I'm
gonna keep getting after it. Right.
That's kind of the way. Yeah. That's
how people end up in those positions.
You don't end up in those positions.
You don't get gifted positions.
You don't just get end up. I shouldn't
say never, but I didn't. Yeah, sure.
Yeah. Had to grind it out, keep grinding
it out. I think. Yeah. You know what,
thinking about this question,
I think what you said doesn't surprise
me at all because as a human being,
I think we all kind of,
maybe sometimes we do,
sometimes we don't admit that it is
good and nice to have like someone there
kind of supporting you in
this way. Where, where,
where you kind of feel like, oh your
feelings matter kind of thing. Yeah.
It sounds super soft,
but it's like kind of deep down
inside where like let's say,
you know how like you know the no listen,
so you know the idea that like
people just don't understand.
You know that concept.
People just don't get it.
They don't understand or whatever.
So when you go to the top,
that feeling is everyone everywhere
that people just don't understand.
This is the difference.
I don't look at it.
People in a negative light because they
don't get it. I'm fine with it. Yeah.
Like I recognize that.
What I'm,
I recognize that I'm not 100%
normal and I'm, I'm not, it's not,
I don't look down. Right. I actually, I
said this word, I just get interviewed.
Oh,
I got interviewed on business
insider by [inaudible] and he's like,
well, do you always keep your
discipline? I was like, no.
People get out of the seal teams and
they get fat and they don't care anymore.
And it's like, I don't, I don't care
about that. I'm stoked. You know,
that means they're stoked and eating
breakfast in bed and they're hanging out
with your kids. It's all good. I don't,
I don't have a negative opinion of them.
She's like,
I don't have a negative opinion of someone
that prioritizes things differently
than me. It's fine. It's
perfectly fine. Yeah. I get it.
That that's what point and I'm okay.
I'm okay with that and I'm
not looking around going, wow,
I wish I had more people to hang out with.
It's lonely up here.
That's exactly what lonely at the top is.
Yeah. Yeah. And there was a, there was a,
when I was in my first seal platoon I,
we went to Guam.
When we got there there was a guy,
and I don't even know who did it.
I don't know where this,
I don't know who this was,
but there was a seal that left like
a, a surf ski. You know what that is?
It's basically like a kayak that you
sit on top of anyways and there's just a
little, a little, a little note
to himself. It said the higher,
the fewer meaning like hey when you,
cause he was training hard for it.
I didn't know who he lost to set.
The higher, the higher, the fewer.
So that's the same thing.
Yeah. I'm going to shoot with
him. Yeah. Okay. Makes Sense.
Yeah man. So like, you know when
you're in the office working,
you know that you tell kids too, cause
that's a whole bullying thing is people,
kids, kids get the feeling
that being alone is bad.
Like being alone is not a bad thing. You
should be comfortable being alone. Yeah.
Yeah. And as a normal human, it's key.
I think for the most part,
okay. Being alone is one thing,
but being alone with no choices and
other, so like if, if you, you know,
you're at the office cause you just
grind all day, you're at the top,
slowly at the top, whatever you're
in the office, you're working,
everyone else is out at uh, you
know, thanksgiving, whatever.
But you're working because you
got to work, you're at the top,
you're still the man, but you're working,
you know, kind of thing. Some people,
not you, some people will
be like, man, you know,
like I'm in this top position
but I give up. Like all of these,
you definitely give things, you know,
and yeah, exactly right. But again,
you say you're okay with it.
I get it. Of course. Yeah.
And if it gets to a point where I'm not
okay with it, then I adjust the balance.
There you go. Okay.
That's how you deal with,
they're just about what you're going
to be playing. The longterm Dame. Yeah.
Not the short term gratification
check.
Swish.
Would you ever consider being
in the reboot of the office?
All, you mentioned the office, that's why
events, I'd read the questions earlier,
but kind of in my head layers.
Do you like Dwight Schrute the best
Shrute to Dennis aright. Shrek.
Dwight Schrute. What's wrong with
your shoe? True farms. Yeah. Uh,
the officer's a great show and my kids
are obsessed with the office for some
reason, so I watched the
office sometimes with them.
There's a British version of the office
and I actually prefer the British
version of the office,
I guess because it's just my personality.
But the British version, the is
kind of depressing. No, it's funny,
but it's Kinda depressing because
the American one goes over the top.
The characters are over the top. They
are an extreme. So they're funny. Yeah.
You Go, oh, that's funny. For, for
the boss to have that attitude.
It's a caricature.
The British one is toned back just
enough that it's more realistic and it's,
it's a little bit depressing and
that's what my kid, I told my kids,
you got to watch the British one.
The British one is much better.
And my kids watching them, like, I don't
want to watch that. It's depressing.
So yeah, that's great. And Dwight
Schrute is an awesome character. Yes.
Because it kind of, because everyone
knows a Dwight Schrute who's Dwight truth.
He's a character in the office.
I mean, I've seen it and stuff,
but I don't know the names of the guys.
He's a guy with glasses like this,
self defense and Dorky.
Sorry,
check. So you would be in it if they're
like reboot of the office. Hey Jocko,
we want you to be Dwight Schrute
or whoever I could be. Yeah,
let's the main guy's name.
Michael. Right? The character,
I mean, yeah, the boss. Yeah.
Michael. Actually, what's funny
is when you watch that show,
you can see leadership
issues. Yeah. There go there.
Do you see the glaring leadership issues?
It's a good little good little lessons
learned for leadership in there. Yeah,
sure. So who do you be? Who's
your choice? Hey Jocko. Oh,
I'd have to be one of the people that are
in there. Yeah, this is a we'll reboot.
It would be cool as be a super
hardcore version of Dwight Schrute.
Like a Yes for our core version of
Dwight shirts. That'd be pretty funny.
Well isn't the whole co like comic genius
behind the character of Dwight Schrute
is that he's so Dorky, like a
Napoleon dynamite type guy, right?
Like he's like so dorky but use
like this bar hardcore droid shirt.
So you could be some hard core,
but it'd be inverse. You'd be,
you'd be dis Dorky like your dog.
You know,
how do I treat it as trying to sell the,
his hardcore in this,
but he's just defeat any character
to the extreme can be funny. Yeah.
So in your case, actually if you,
if you like when I'm on Twitter,
I take my character, you know,
where someone says, what's,
what's a good dessert steak?
Just having fun.
You're like text message too, by the
way. Just so everyone knows. So yeah.
So your character is hardcore, underlying
hardcore. That's like the known thing,
but then you're trying to be all out of
like smart or something like, you know,
like a, like a studious. This
is for the [inaudible]. Yeah.
I'm not worried about it. I
don't know man. That's how it is.
Looking at the classic well
Huh. All right. Next question.
Has seen kids in hellholes ever made
parenting harder for you leaving or not
leaving kids? Not really. Uh, when, uh,
when I was overseas and you'd
see kids in horrible situations,
it just makes you appreciate
the opportunity that you
have to provide for your
kids and to try and help
those kids as much as you can.
So I don't think it made
parenting harder for me. Yeah.
Yeah. It makes you appreciative of the
opportunities that we have. For sure.
Yeah. I feel like I know that
question where, yeah, when,
if I see like kids in hellholes it,
it doesn't make it harder,
but it makes it like you're
more sensitive, you know,
like stuff just affects you more with
your kids. I Dunno. In my experience.
That's what happened.
Cause you kind of can't be that way.
Like it messes you up when you see like,
like my wife will read like a trafficking,
like human trafficking or
and stuff and you see people,
whether it be pictures or video,
whatever.
And so it kind of leaves a mark
in your brain. So I don't know,
maybe you're just playing everyday kind
of stuff and you see your kid and you're
like,
Dang,
you can't help but remember those pictures
and do a comparison that'll make you
paranoid. Do in a good way. Yeah.
Yeah. Be careful with your kids.
There's evil people out there for sure.
Next question.
How do you reduce your bosses?
Anxiety levels do a really good job.
You know what I mean?
Stay ahead of the power curve.
Do a really good job.
Keep them informed and kick ass.
And that's how you relieve your bosses.
Anxiety. Step Up. Yeah.
That's good advice for your wife too,
by the way.
We're leaving your wife's anxiety
levels. Yeah, for sure. Take lead, right?
Not Lead like, oh you know, call all
the shots necessarily. But you know,
if, if, if you guys are trying to figure
out where to go for dinner, boom, call it,
call it man. Don't be like, oh,
whatever you want, don't do that.
Don't create the leadership
void. Don't do that. Check.
I learned that from you by the way.
Next question.
Trying to keep in shape while
traveling long term and not use,
not having gym access as an excuse
for letting my standard slip.
Best pieces of kit training styles from
maintaining conditioning and adding mass
while living out of the backpack.
Get rings. It rings good.
Gymnastics would,
gymnastic rings.
Why would plastic or metal will
make you get sweaty and slept?
And you have to bring a ton of chalk
and you need a little bit of chocolate.
The Wood rings,
it's a little one resorb and there's
the best thing to grab onto get would
gymnastic rings.
You can carry them anywhere and then
just do a bunch of calisthenics. I mean,
come on man.
Just on a knows what adding mass,
how has ed mess can slit? Oh,
you gotta get creative. Yeah,
you've got to get creative.
But it's do you know,
instead of doing squats,
you know,
air squats do jump squats
or doing some dynamic.
Do you ever wonder why our metrics?
Yeah. Do one legged pistols. Yeah.
All that stuff. Yeah. Yeah.
That's the key. I got to do
that right now. Like I can't,
you can't build a hole in my,
this is called the Ulna boom.
So they drilled a hole in the attached
to the 10 and nut in the hole. They go,
they push the 10 in through the hole.
They put an anchor at the
end of the boom anyway.
A lot of swelling in the forearm.
You can't grab nothing,
you can't grab anything and have weight.
So Calisthenics,
you've got to kind of make your position,
your wrists in a position,
in a comfortable position and
you can do calisthenics. Anyway.
Point there is,
I'm in that boat where lifting weights
is not an option at this very moment for
me. So you got to kind of get
creative. So like a push up.
You can make the pushups harder.
If you put your feet up in the
higher you put your feet, you know,
the harder it becomes.
Or you do like a one arm pushups situation
and then you can do like a decline,
like um, you know, you go on
a counter first, right? Okay.
How many of these one arm pushups?
You can do more than 20. Okay.
Maybe you go for like a chair or
something like this. Something, something,
a shorter boom. You can do more than 20 of
those. Okay. Now I can go to the ground,
see what I'm saying? And then you can go
raise your feet up as time goes on. Boom.
There you go.
Good for.
And actually bodyweight through space
is the best way to build size in your
muscles there. As far as like
exercises go, it's good information.
It is better than dead
lifting and squatting. Well,
okay, so that dead lifting,
squatting, that's going to be d
is going to depend on the weight.
But think about this.
Dead lifting and
squatting is moving
your body through space.
So do an air squat.
You're moving your body through space
as opposed to men squatting with weight,
right? Back Squat. Right, right,
right. But when I'm squat, yeah,
duty heavy with squats yet,
but again, like I said,
moving your body through space is the,
are the best exercises for mass.
What is what is not moving your body
through a squat compared to a leg press.
So if people haven't,
even though those aren't even in my,
those aren't even in my mind I know about,
but this guy asking the question,
it might be, I'm trying to help him
out. I don't want to help you out.
You got the whole exercise
thing figured out. I get it.
You know you're an expert
in your boring workups.
Talk about that later.
Nonetheless,
the body weight or body moving your
body through space is the best exercise.
The problem is or tends to be that your
body has a fixed amount of weight more
or less.
So you can't adjust the weight and usually
you can move your body through space
a bunch of times. If you do air squats,
you can do a bunch of air squats.
So it doesn't provide the quote unquote
tension that you need to build mass.
That's what you go one at a time.
Create more tension on your muscles while
still moving your body through space,
which could wind up to be a better
exercise for you. That's what I'm saying.
That's good advice man. Whatever. Brad,
don't act like it's crazy
that I'm saying this stuff.
That's the question really the question
with this whole moving your body through
space thing. Yeah, that's the
information. I have no idea what that,
I kind of get it now.
But you were saying it as
if it was some unknown.
It is unknown.
If your body through space,
you know what a hammer strength machine
is. Okay, so it's, you know, it's like a,
it's like a, I dunno like a lever kind of
thing. Technically it's like, you know,
you put some plates on it, you push
it, there's no pull or nothing,
but you know you're never moving your
body through space and I'm moving in your
body through space.
So I'm kind of creating the spectrum
here so could just consider that.
Then it's kind of far down this other
movement or things that are further down
the spectrum, but that's fixed
movement. There's no balance required.
There's no whatever.
It's just like you're just pushing late.
It's isolation movements, right?
Plane, the plane is isolated.
All this to the plane of movement,
right?
So that we'll have less neuro
muscular activity when you push it.
Even if you're pushing heavy weights,
then something like graduate too,
like a barbell bench press,
right? For example. But even that,
even though you do have to balance,
so that's a big step up,
but even that you don't have
to balance in certain planes,
certain planes of movement,
you don't have to balance like the,
what do you call this one lateral,
whatever,
the lateral movement and a barbell
bench press, which is the bar.
You don't have to balance.
It's fixed,
but front and back or forward for new
back, whatever. You do have to balance.
So you know it's still good.
Now go to dumbbells,
now you have 360
degree plane of movement that you have
to balance more neuro muscular activity.
So dumbbells are better
than barbells in that way.
There were muscular activity
and you can adjust the weight.
So you can do things where you can
only do three reps. You can do things,
you can do 20 reps if you
want. So boom, great exercise.
Can't really do it in a hotel room,
but just saying, generally speaking,
good exercise.
But now you go the tip top.
The best exercise for neuro muscular
activity would be pushups because same
thing, you're moving your body
through space. You're not balancing,
weighing and balancing your rings.
Boom. Then I'll get even better.
Now you're going like creative, which is
good. That's like beyond the spectrum,
which is good. Totally good. But
so yeah, keep these things in mind.
I think when you, when you do a thing,
wait, so if you can add or window workout.
So when you, if you can add
weight, that's the challenge.
If you can add weight to these,
moving your body through space exercises,
that's when you need it. Again, I'm just
going to take this one step further.
Do it because you don't necessarily have
to add weight as you stated earlier.
Yes,
you can adjust how you're moving your
body through space and then you can get
the,
you can get additional,
and I'll tell you what really makes
us obvious as if you do any gymnastics
training. If you do a
pull up, that's hard.
If you do a talk, pull up where your
knees are pulled up, that's even harder.
If you do a l sit,
pull up where your knees are up,
put your feet are pointed straight
forward. That's even harder.
Each one of those things is a little
bit harder. And same thing with a dip,
like just a regular dip.
Your feet hanging,
it's easier if you bring it up
to a talk is a little harder.
If you bring it up to an l,
it's even harder.
So you can keep doing these things
and there's squats that you can do.
I mean just doing pistols alone,
that's a lot harder.
Some people can't even do pistols.
Yeah.
And so you might have to do an assisted
pistol. We'll start off. Yeah. So yeah,
you can make it happen.
Pistols, got a hard men,
especially if you've never done it before
because it's hard because the balance
back and side to side balance
360 degree plane of balancing,
that's what this whole thing's about
moving your body through space is
where'd you read that? Uh, old
school. A Bulgarian Phil Philosophy,
philosophy workout program called there's
the old school never deviated from it
much. The core really good too,
by the way. Um, it's called,
he called, I remember serious growth
is what is called weird. Right.
Like that's such a lame name. But man,
I was in high school and I was like,
all right, you know, you read all
these things right. And you know,
in the back of the, uh, you know,
Muscle magazine or whatever
and the little article,
I remember all the Bulgari
and it was Kinda like, uh,
that was a big thing.
No kidding. Well Gary,
well yeah cause the Bulgarians were
doing really good at weightlifting. Yeah.
Quiet. No one knew. It
was weird. And these guys
were like, yeah, five weeks or four
weeks, my bench went up to this.
And you know when you're in
high school band heck yet,
but I'll get that or whatever.
So you get the prominences book and it's
just got serious growth and it explains
everything really in detail too. I
was like, Dang, this is pretty good.
Real plain English to not alders
rural science or whatever.
And maybe they're still, and they
were doing kido too, by the way.
That's where I learned about
ketones is 90 that's crazy.
It's been around for a long time.
For name.
The Atkins book came out in
the sixties or seventies yeah.
That's way different though. It's not,
it's not a way different way. Different.
Yeah. This was, this guy is been
around for a long time. Yeah. Maher,
Dr Mario or Morro de Pasqual.
That's who was the Quito Gut. And
again, back in 94 he's still around.
Yeah, no kidding. So yeah,
so we did this thing,
we get this book and it's like
laying it out and you know,
I'm down 1516 years old.
I'm down to lift five days a week.
Let's do this and brow. We
did it. And you eat good.
Not like crazy. I didn't do the
ketone never did. Um, but you know,
they have it as an option and
so we did or whatever. And we,
it was weird since I gained
like 20 pounds and I just,
we just kept doing it. So, you know, you
played football, you can't really gain,
there's also this whole thing that you're
15 and your body's just filled with
testosterone.
You were going to gain 16 pounds anyways,
I'm telling you,
I'll tell you this right now.
I was talking to Jody Mitic about this
briefly too. I'll tell you this right now.
If even at 40 you go on this thing,
it depends on the train going,
this, this type of work.
And I'm not even like selling this
work on it or nothing like that.
I'm saying this'll, people will
think you know what though? Okay.
People will think you're on steroids if
you do this workout for like six weeks,
that's it. Six weeks, they'll think
you're on steroids. Straight up.
Like my whole life when I'd like go on a,
on a like a six week thing, they're all,
he's on steroids. Obviously.
He's on Sir. No Sir.
You don't even have to take supplements.
That's the weird thing. But here,
let me say this though,
now that I'm thinking of it as or
about it when I'm a grown adult,
most programs,
if you actually do the whole
program exactly what works.
It works really good. That's the thing.
People just don't do the workout. Oh,
what do you need to do? Lift heavy
weights a lot. Eat good interest. Good.
Yes. Yeah. You'll get, and
let's, and let's face it,
it's not eat. Like if someone says,
Oh yeah, it's easy. Cause the thing,
it's not easy. This is why it's not
easy. It's not just the workout.
That's why you have to do the workout.
Then you have to eat enough of
the right things too, by the way.
And then you have to arrest enough.
That's basically,
you have to change your whole life.
So if you're like, hey, it's easy,
just change your whole life.
It's not easy. And not that,
I'm not saying that that's a
good excuse or to anything,
but I'm just saying it's not quote unquote
easy, but yet there it is. Do Diet,
exercise, eat good workup,
good and rest good.
You'd be good hotel or Jim,
actually, here's what you can do.
Here's what I do when I
go to the muster or wherever. If I'm there
for like a week, like the last muster,
all like go on Google maps and find like
all the gyms and be like, all right,
I'm going to get, that's kind
of the commitment. Obviously,
you know that's an interest.
That's your commitment.
Like you want to stay in shape, add mass
as you say, conditioning, adding mass,
whatever. Look for the gym near Your
House. Commit to pay that Jim feed.
She's like, what, 10 bucks
or something like that. And
boom. That's the commitment,
right? Do that. That's what I do. Same
thing. Would you just sit, by the way,
next question.
Forgive or wait to settle the score.
Uh,
you know what?
This is kind of a question
that, okay, so forgive.
If you can forgive people for them,
that's cool. Now here's the thing.
You got that little thing in the back of
your mind because you want to settle a
score. I know. I don't forget. God, I
love to tell you like, Hey, just forgiven.
Forget. Right? But it's
hard to do that sometimes,
especially if all certain situations
merit, you know, a little bit, a little.
It's hard to make that happen. A little,
a little something extra special.
But this is what's interesting.
Forgiving someone is actually
a form of settling the score.
If you can think about this.
So for me,
the best revenge you can take
on someone is success, right?
Is ignoring them and the best revenge
is not even letting them know that you
even think about them anymore. Yeah.
That's the best revenge in my mind.
So you forgive them and you just move on.
I think that's the best thing to do.
Forgive them,
move on and go kick ass in the world and
the little part of your brain that will
really wants to take revenge. You'll be
taking the best possible revenge you can.
You'll be doing it in the best possible
way and it'll be the best for you as a
human being. Yeah. So that's
what you do. Yeah. Yeah.
I forgive you and then you go kick ass.
Yeah.
Forgiving someone for real, like
for real, for real. Forgiving them.
It's really hard. Even if you do take
the highroad behavior wise on the inside,
it's like you kind of don't,
there's this guide to high school and
actually wasn't even in high school was
you're still holding high school grudges?
No. Uh, well I guess technically, yeah,
it's still there. Like if there was
like, if he were to see, I don't know,
something good that I did like now
and be like, aw man, he's doing good.
That would give me satisfaction
right now technically yet.
Still that little something. Yeah. But um,
if it's to forgive someone fully
to be too to a point where,
Oh yeah, if you saw that I was doing
great now, or something like that, um,
and that wouldn't move me either way.
To get to that point is we're super hard.
So I think just like how you said,
like the behavior that you want to
kind of do you want to enact yeah.
Is,
um, is, yeah. Don't let it bother
you. And here's the thing with,
don't not letting it, not
letting it bother you. Don't
let it affect you at all.
Like no factor. Like you almost like you
didn't even notice kind of thing. Yeah.
Okay. So that's hard to
do. But if you can do that,
if you can pull that off bread, that's
the worst for the other person I'm saying.
So like you ever,
you ever had like uh,
exactly what I'm saying Bro. I'll get
this. Where did I say he's, you know,
you think to yourself tank.
Did I say something to Piss that guy off?
Whoever it is, whatever. I
don't know. Somebody or that
girl or whatever. Oh shoot.
Did I say something? Or they offended or
whatever and you just don't quite know.
But it's not big enough to bring up
so you can't bring it up and get that
satisfaction of knowing, you know.
But if they don't just don't say any.
Let's say they were offended say don't
even like you, but they just don't,
don't like talk to you rather than if
they ignore you or don't acknowledge that
you said something or something like that.
That's way more.
That bothers you way more than them,
like cussing you out or
something or yelling at you
or like Super Mad at you and
them telling you they're mad at you
is way more like satisfying. Yeah,
and them not. If you just go stem,
forgive them and move on. Yeah.
But if you go stem,
you can't overly ghost like you can't
overly ignore. Just be like, hey. Yeah,
like literally like, yeah, all
good. Oh yeah, it's good to see you.
And I haven't said that's
why if something's going
good for you, if that's what,
if you're mad at someone and they
text you like, Hey, you know, oh,
and if you give them like one word
answers or you don't text him back,
that messes with them way it
worse than you saying, yes,
I'm mad at you and you hurt me
and you piss me off or whatever.
Playing all these games. No
Bruh. I learned it from me, Bro.
Check. Nonetheless. Good advice right
there. Good advice. Next question.
When you've crushed your daily to do list,
do you then take the time to relax
or do you attack the next day's list?
Is that against prioritize and execute
since the mission is done for the day,
you know, just do more. Just keep
going. Even if it's on the next day,
keep going, do more. If you
have extra time, do whatever
you can do to stay ahead.
And I do that pretty much
until I'm brain dead. And I,
I w I can definitely work myself
into until I'm brain dead.
Like I can get to a point where I'm
reading and I'm writing and it's just,
it's just, uh, it's just done. I'm done.
And so I just have to stop and take
a break and then I'll go do something
mindless for awhile, you know? So,
you know, if you forgot stuff to do,
keep hammering until you can't hammer
anymore and then say, oh, okay,
you know what?
I need a little breather and then take a
little breather and they get back to it.
Right now I could work 24 hours a day,
24 hours a day,
seven days a week, 365 days a year, and,
and I wouldn't be able to get done
the things I'm trying to get done.
So it's not like I'm sitting there
going, oh cool. I got a break. No,
I can see it's all he's got is more stuff
to do. Gotcha. You got things to do.
So not a bunch of,
uh,
Boise call, it breaks and
it relaxing. This is not a,
not a lot of that happening right now.
Now you go surfing. Is that a break?
Kind of. It's like a big break. Well,
it's kind of hard of the process.
It's like if you're doing
five sets of 10 on the bench,
what are you going to do? One set of 50
no, you do five sets of 10 so first at 10,
what do you do? You get a rescue
to recover. That's what surfing is.
That's it's the rest between sets.
That's all that is right there you go.
Was part of the process check.
But what would you,
would you recommend for someone who's
like a normal person? Do what? You can.
Knock it out. Build up extra free time
if you need a break. Take a break.
Gotcha. That's pretty crazy, right.
Know what I'm saying is I get to bring
what you can. If you need a break,
take a break. If you knew a little
relaxation takes some relaxation. Yeah.
Don't waste your time though. See,
people, people do relaxing, but they do.
They don't even do it. Good alien
feel relaxed when they get done.
It's not productive. Relaxing.
Yeah, they're, they just,
what they did is they did
something stupid for an hour.
They watched youtube videos for an hour,
but I did that help, you know, go outside,
go for a run, do some burpees, go
surfing, go do some Jujitsu. Uh,
play with your kids, whatever. Do
something that actually has some value,
the real value. Uh, but
till what about, you know,
Pahata and we're going to, uh, the bar.
Yeah,
that's not great,
but sometimes don't get too hammered
because you're hung over the next day.
You can't account, you know,
you can't function as good,
boom. Can't, uh, your output,
your productivity comes down next day.
Better tell everyone what pal Honda means.
Cause not everyone knows like old Hannah.
I guess technically it means done with
what you're doing. Power means done.
Honda means like do. Yeah. Uh, but yeah,
Paul Hanna Po Finish what you're doing.
Tip.
It's referred to when you're
finished with work. Yeah.
That's the way I would use it. Yeah.
When you finish work, Pau Hana goes good.
You know,
whenever it's like Miller time and
for Kinda the same thing a little bit.
Next question,
would you recommend you get too far?
55 year old female with no
former martial arts background.
Is the risk for injury to high? Answered
this one a bunch of times. Hey, yes,
you should do Jujitsu.
Pick good training partners.
Get your ego out of the picture and go
very slow and learn the techniques and
you'll get something out of it.
Watch out for sparring. Rolling live.
You need to be really careful and you
need to really select good training
partners that are very much
more experienced than you are.
Don't roll with white belts. If you're
a 55, don't even roll with blue belts.
If you can help it as a 55 year old,
unless they're small and smart,
just be careful. But yeah, it's a great
trade. It's a great thing. What about, um,
cause I actually got asked this
online and I was actually through dms,
like going through his, a girl, her last
name is Taylor, if I'm not mistaken,
we got a first name anyway, she's
a black belt and she, uh, you know,
when it comes to girls rolling, just even
just regular girls or whatever, let's
face it.
I mean in training,
they do have a bigger kind of kind of
obstacle in that way where they're at,
they are at a higher risk of injury
more times because everyone, if,
if the rolling with the guys,
I mean everyone,
chances are everyone's bigger than them
and they might be going hard and they'd,
you know, some guys especially early
on and they don't realize that Dang,
they're putting a lot of
strength and you know,
all this stuff into these
moves and you can live in
Morocco and hard. Yeah. They don't even
realize it. Exactly. You're exhausted,
relaxed,
knew
exactly where they do have this obstacle.
Even 55 year old a lady or even
just an older person in general.
Um, they do have that added obstacle
where yet you do have to kind of, yeah.
So what's the question? Yeah. The
question is like what do those people do?
Same deal. Yeah. No, they do. They
have to be more extreme cautious.
They have to take more caution.
Okay. You're 100% right.
What you're saying is right.
You do what I just said.
You don't want to go
with a psycho white belt,
you don't even want to go with any
white belt, right. Cause they're there.
They don't know what they're doing.
So go with someone that's a purple belt.
Someone that's relaxed, they're a 55
year old woman is gonna be on a different
pace down the path. We're going to be on
the path, which is at a different pace.
And the stress is too,
I would focus on the,
the learning of the technique a lot more.
You know,
it's been a lot more time drilling
and learning the technique and then
occasionally with your
black belt instructor, with
your Brown belt instructor,
with some of the high level
purple belt smart people,
you do a nice little roll with them,
you have some fun, you see what works,
what doesn't work. You learn a
little bit more. Take that path,
take that pace down
the path. Right? Right.
Don't go in there with a big ego
and know what happens every time.
Like if you introduce Jujitsu to people,
they think that they have the
solution to something that you teach.
And it's like, no, you don't
actually have the solution.
You are don't know anything.
So just just don't do that.
Is that the monster?
And you know,
we teach Jiu Jitsu for the first time to
a bunch of people and we were teaching
the MPAA, right? The escape,
the show escape where you roll
the person over from the mouth.
And this one guy, you know, he's like,
I'm teaching what screen? This one guy,
he's like, I look, this doesn't work.
And he's got his weight all the way and
the other side and he's got his leg up.
I remember that. Yeah. Yeah. And I'm like,
um, I'm like, yeah, there's another move.
You just do this popup and now
you're in the guard. And then,
but like in his mind, like Jujitsu, just
us, wasn't it? What does and doesn't work.
I don't know what this crap
is that Jocko was all into,
but obviously it doesn't work.
It's like, no, actually it works.
So you don't,
you don't uncover the magic of
Jujitsu in one moment, you know?
Yeah.
Oh, actually, you know what?
I do remember the question.
So you know how it lit can fit five
year old women a role with you know,
high level people, people that you
trust, people who have a lot of control
over the, over the situation. What
about like, let's say I, you know,
I'm a 55 year old woman.
I have a twin sister,
she's 55 we're in the
same shape kind of thing.
Just normal people and can we roll?
You better be careful.
You better calm down. You better knock
it, competitive. You better relax.
Now one thing that's good is I
would say yes actually. Yeah,
I would say you know why?
Because you're around equivalent strength.
You're around equivalent knowledge.
You still got to be careful that you
would prefer you go a couple of six months
before,
before you jump in and do a death match
with your twin sister at age 55 I know
you, you've been competing each other.
So just, just try and relax. You know,
I used to say jade trying to
kill you. Like dude, come on.
When jade used to train, no sorry.
Sure he could check. No, I know,
that's what I'm saying. He tried.
It's funny to g even from birth,
jade was a little bit bigger
than me. Not Anymore. No, no, no.
And I think it's literally a direct
result of it. Of always been little bits,
Molly and complex. Yeah. Like
a little small mini micro.
A bit bigger than this dude.
And you know when that happened,
he was bigger than me through high school,
through even through college who had
bigger than me until we were done kind of
with college,
just come on lift.
And I ballooned up to like almost
to 50 to 50 and then he was like,
were you athletic when you were
to 50? Yeah, surprisingly. Yeah.
Not what you got to go back up there
again and wasn't as athletic, you know,
a grown adult. It doesn't make
sense for me. I'm not tall. I Dunno.
This is my opinion. And plus in Hawaii,
lean to 50 not as lean as I am now.
No,
I wouldn't call myself lead or cut,
but I wasn't fat though.
That's the thing.
I even have this old picture of me and
my friend Scott Lewis, he's a cop now,
by the way. He, uh, we're, we're
like, cause he would lift it.
He was my listing partner.
Oh yeah. Big Time. And um,
we were like,
this is what I was like two 45 he was
like maybe two 30 or something like that.
And yeah, it was big. But I
was like, dude, I was like
surprisingly defined though.
I got 51 time
and then I went and ran a four mile
run and I did not feel good. Yeah.
And I was like, okay,
I'm done with this. Yes.
I was pumped to be to
50 just cause you know,
that time I did a four mile run and I
was like, good God, this is horrible.
I can't do my job. And that's
the answer. That's the answer.
Why you don't want to be
two 50 and even being like,
that's a huge amount of weight even
health wise, especially as you get older,
whatever, like to be just rolling
around two 50 you know? Yeah.
Yeah. And if you can't do a
four mile run, if you can't do,
I probably thinking back like even a one
mile run would have been kind of kind
of more difficult that would've
liked at two 55 was not a good sign.
Yeah. That's uh, that's
how it went. Well, so yeah,
that's the point there being a,
I got bigger then jade boom.
And with that little micro Napoleon
complex it crew like I was more like
aggressive or am even still not like
more like I'll take up more aggressive.
Like I started, he didn't even consider
Jesus as I started. You just go Charles
more aggressive. That's funny cause I
don't figure it that way. You think Jason?
I think Jade's more aggressive.
Maybe like to get in like a
debate or something like yeah,
he's definitely addressing
a hundred percent. But uh,
but yeah, physical activity.
I probably started to Dj. I was
like, before jade started, I was up,
I was like well into purple belt before
Gevins started and that's such a big
gap. So yeah, Jake and tried to kill me.
He will not kill me. Just simply won't.
It's almost impossible. It's pretty much
impossible. Technically in impossible.
There's uh, so if you
go a percentage, right?
Chance of him ever beating me,
the percent of the percent chance of him
beating me is closer to zero than it is
1% true.
That's how it is right now.
Unless you went on a complete warpath.
Oh,
what do you mean if he trained training
boy, yeah, that goes for every,
but currently that's how it is.
So He's 0%.
He's off the path,
doesn't he met her?
He can get on the path still 0% chance.
Next question.
I'd like to hear your thoughts on people
entering the military in their thirties
I'm sure you saw it. How did
they fare? I don't remember.
Military at an older age is fine. You
got maturity, you've got experience,
you've got intelligence,
and so that's good.
You're going to bring a lot to the
table. However, you also have maturity,
experience and intelligence.
So the only downfall of it is you got
to do some dumb stuff when you're in the
military and,
and,
and if you're older and you see how dumb
some of the stuff that you're doing is,
you're,
it's going to be harder for you to do it.
You're going to have a little bit of
a negative attitude on if you allow
yourself, it'd be easy to do. I
should say that if you allow yourself,
it'd be easy to develop a negative
attitude about that stuff.
I joined when I was 18 years old.
I didn't care.
You want me to do whatever
you want me to do? I'll do it.
I didn't see the stupidity
and a lot of this stuff.
And so I think that's the only drawback
because you'll just be looking at some
of the stuff that you do in
the military thinking, oh,
this is a much more efficient way to do
this. And if you let that get to you,
it's going to be problematic. So going
there with an open mind, do the crap,
the tedious and kind of mindless stuff
that you got to do and push through that
and then you'll get to a position of
leadership and you can do your best to
mitigate that and take care
of other soldiers, sailors,
airmen and Marines while you're out
there serving the country. So yeah,
it's awesome. It's great.
You'll, you'll be a big benefit.
Do you think that that even that,
um, how you were saying like,
okay, you'll, you'll,
you kind of look at things in more of an
adult way kind of thing where it's like,
well, there's a more
efficient way to do something.
What do you think that that mindset would
kind of keep you from, uh, you know,
being more cohesive to with if you allow
it to. It definitely will. If you, if you,
that's why I said, do you have to
allow, if you just go look, this is,
this is the way it is right now.
I'm a, I'm a, yeah.
[inaudible] in the military.
They're telling me to do this thing.
It doesn't make any sense right now.
I'm going to do it to the best of my
ability and move forward. If you say, Oh,
this is stupid and you spread the
negativity of the other guys who go,
why are we doing this? Students,
yeah, it's going to be problematic.
And some go in there,
have a good attitude.
You can promote really quickly if
you're squared away like that, you know?
So you got a good opportunity.
How do you, I mean it's,
I think it's totally good to go. What
about even like socially, you know,
like kind of like, oh these kids
are 18 you've been out in the world,
you've had a job, you probably
have a house, you might
have kids. These kids are,
I was out of high school. Like, you know
what I mean? It's, you're not there yet.
You're,
and you think about what,
you know when you're that age
compared to what, when you're,
when you're 30 you know, my big thing is
I tell my kids all the time, you know,
or like my oldest daughter who's in
college and whatnot, and I'm always like,
when I was your age, I was and
my first seal platoon, you know,
like you just can't even compete with
what I was doing with the responsibility
that I had when I was 18 years
old. You know, all that stuff.
But the truth is when you're 18 you're
not as mature as you are when you're 30
so yeah, there'll be a social disconnect.
Like I went to college when I was,
I think I was 28 or 29 or 30 and so yeah,
I was around kids that
were 1819 years old.
And I realized very quickly that, you
know, you'd meet some mature kids,
but a lot of kids were just, they
were just young, you know? I mean,
there's not a big difference between 18
and 15 for some people. Right. But yeah,
it's true. You think about what you were
doing your f 15 years old, 16 years old.
Like I joined the military.
So luckily I had some kind of
structure imposed upon me. Yeah.
But you think about the kind of stuff
that you can do when you're 18 years old,
people do dumb, dumb, dumb
stuff. Yeah. You, you, you,
you look back and you're
happy that you made it.
Cause you do dumb dumb stuff.
We were talking about wasting
your time on youtube videos.
Go waste your time on Youtube.
Like just put in penal teenagers
doing dumb stuff and you'll,
you'll say wow. And, and 50%
of the stuff that you see,
you'll recognize like, oh yeah I remember
that. So yeah, don't do dumb stuff.
And as a 30 year old in the military you
can help give some of that guidance to
people. So I think it's cool. Go for
it man. And kind of vice versa. Right?
Cause like if you're the 18 year old 19
year old guy, there's like, you know,
a hundred will however many other 1819
year old guys, you guys are cruising.
Then here comes to this 30 year
old, you know, all levelheaded, Bro,
I can't relate to this day.
This gets kind of weird.
The other thing is when you're 18 you
don't even know how much those 30 year
olds just think.
You actually think you know more than
looking at them like they're idiots.
Why would you not,
you know,
swing off this rope and see if you can
get through the window on the third floor.
Why would you not give you that
old and what exactly. Yeah,
so that's something I would be out.
Brace yourself for that too.
Remember the perspective of an 18 year
old and they're not looking at you going,
gosh,
I'd like to learn about how
they're looking at you. Like, I can't
believe you joined the military.
What's wrong with you? Yeah,
hold man. There was, there
were guys who actually can,
they came from the military
and still eligible, right?
For F four foot point in college and
when I was 26 when I was 27 and let's
think, let's face it, 26 27 that's a
Yo, that's a, you're physically like,
you're solid still. And we looked at
them, I was like, man, these are like,
these are old school guys, these are
like old careful with them and practice.
Literally it was like I felt like
that for one of the guys anyway.
And then you go to class, right. And you
get these people who, you know, they,
they don't go to college right after high
school. They go, you know, later on when,
in my opinion when most of us should go,
when you know why you're going.
And so this one lady was in my class,
she was maybe 35 maybe 36 whatever
and discussed all day long.
No, she didn't look at me at all. She
freaking donor on program. Yeah. Yeah.
Like I was no factor in her
life. She was doing, yeah.
Literally the correct way to do
it. She sat up front, you know,
and she's asking questions.
Protocol. Literally.
That's really the way to
go when you think about it.
You don't even have to think about it.
That's the way to go. But nonetheless,
she like this,
but she's obviously 30 something years
old and it just didn't compute to me.
You know, like I was like,
well, what's important thing?
But that's a really key part of this
conversation is when you're eight,
imagine as a 30 year old
when you're looking at that
18 year old, they don't see,
I understand anything,
sir. Don't check. No Sir.
We don't want 18.
Next question.
You've said everyone will know if you're
the one taking own ship and leading the
team in spite of having a poor leader
or someone who does everything for their
own glory,
but what do you do if your boss's boss
doesn't make the connection between your
work and the team's success?
Good.
Good. You know what? I do? Keep
working hard. That's awesome.
Make keep making your boss look good.
I recommend that you put your ego in check
would be good to get that credit for.
For what? For what's happening.
You're looking for that glory. The,
and they're the boss is doing
it for glory. Well guess what?
That's making you mad cause you want
some of that glory. You know what?
It'll come the two things about
this. Number one, let them have it.
Make them look great. You're worried
that the boss's boss doesn't get it.
It will come in due course.
Be patient, work hard.
Give your boss the credit.
Don't worry about it and in
due course it will come you.
You can't fool the boss or the
boss's boss won't get fooled forever.
They won't get fooled forever.
And you know what?
Worst case scenario you get your bosses,
you get your boss promoted. Cool.
Now he trusts you. You worked hard for
him. You did good. He can take his role.
It's okay. It's okay. This is very common.
This is no strange question.
Yeah,
no question.
What do you do for fun when
you're not getting after it? I,
this is kind of a weird question, right?
Why? Because you're always getting enough.
Well because his surfing getting after it.
Yeah,
it is actually edges are
getting after it and yeah,
it is getting after it is
playing guitar getting after it.
Yes it is rock and roll band
getting after it. Yes it is. Okay.
I guess if I'm hanging with my kids,
is that getting after it?
Sometimes I kind of, it turns what we're
doing because we were doing Jiu Jitsu.
I don't know, um, what I do for
fun where I'm not getting after it.
Just stuff that I enjoy doing.
Like you said earlier,
like it doesn't take discipline
to go and do Jujitsu.
If did you just use really fun for you
and did you choose definitely fun for me
too.
I would say 70% of the time I'm,
I'm like super stoked to be going and
roll 30% of the time I don't feel like it.
I go anyways, our sets
say 28% of the time. Sure.
There's like 2% of the
time where I recognize,
oh I'm going to get hurt today cause
I'm beat up or I'm tired or whatever.
It's like, okay, you know what,
maybe I won't train today. Or,
and even on those days,
sometimes I'll come in and I'll just
do a light role just to make sure,
put myself a little discipline
check. So yeah, I don't know.
That's the kind of the thing where I
guess from other people's perspective,
if they're thinking Jujitsu's not fun
and working out, it's not fun and, and,
and practicing an instrument's not fun,
well then I'm not ever having any fun,
but actually the opposite is true.
All those things are fun for me, so I'm
having fun all the time. There you go.
Yeah. It kind of kind of goes in line with
that other question. Enlightened lists.
Like, do you ever do mindless stuff? So
maybe that's kind of the work yard work,
cleaning the garage, stuff like
that. But you know, actually,
you know what it is now that I think
of it, it's the, the question could be,
could be, do you, what do you
do fund? Meaning what do you do?
Like mindless stuff that's um,
that's not technically productive.
So you say turf surfing. Oh, perfect.
Is Not technically per productive.
I don't know though. So it's one of
those things where like, you know what,
you feel good when you get out of the
water. I mean you get a little workout.
It is because you get better at
surfing. Yeah. So it is kind of product,
but there's no, there's no
productivity to surfing. There's no,
there's no ultimate goal other than the
doing it itself. Same thing with guitar,
but you're getting better at guitar.
So like even like yard work for example,
it's like sure, that's fine. Yeah.
That's productive. You're improved,
it's productive.
It's like what you're asking me is what
do I do that's completely unproductive.
Productive.
Yeah.
I Dunno right now there's not a lot,
hardest question in the world.
There's not a lot of things right now
that I'm doing that aren't somehow
productive I think.
But anyways,
because the technique I'll phone though
because that was the actual question.
You're just trying to yeah.
I'm all assuming
that you, you know,
cause watching youtube,
back to the other question, watching
youtube videos of like he ever, uh,
like Trey go on youtube actually don't
do it. But if you do do it, do this.
Go in the search in youtube,
go drunk, girl fails.
Okay. That's what it's called.
Trump girl fails. Okay.
So there's probably maybe 500,000 to
10 million of these videos potentially.
That's my estimate. So what that
means is once you're done with one,
the other one's coming. And here's
the thing, it never gets old.
So that is, I do think it gets
old. All right. Well, I mean, yeah,
that was more of like a, what you call the
exaggeration. But it takes a long time.
I would argue for certain, for most of
us, for it to quote unquote get old.
So the point there is that is something
that is straight up, not productive.
Sure.
You can learn a lesson.
The lessons to be learned from those
videos get learned literally the first
video who literally, and then they
don't get learned in the first video.
Because the first one just seems
like it could be an anomaly.
It's like when you tap them for
someone that's never done it before,
it takes like three or four before
I go get it. You're right. The,
you know something.
I don't know.
So you gotta watch three to five
drunk girl fail videos with your,
you know,
16 year old daughter and say like,
this is why you don't get drunk.
This is why. Yeah, actually
you don't believe me. Okay,
we'll watch two more and we'll see if
there's any of these things that you would
want to see yourself
behaving gas. Yeah, but,
and you could argue that maybe
if you watch five, six, seven,
10 20 you start to see another pattern
get revealed within the pattern of drunk
girl fails. So one of them is, you know,
a girl riding a scooter down
this path so you're not,
not like not just don't get drunk but
don't ride scooters. Exactly. Right.
Exactly right. We see dance on the
bar when drunk. Yes, exactly. Right.
So if you see, let's say within the
span of 15 drunk girl fail videos,
you see,
you know,
30 of those is girls dancing on the bar
versus only two of them were girls on a
scooter.
You can kind of discern that
dancing on the bar statistically,
right today is a little bit more
dangerous. I'm just saying, hey,
we're digging for lessons that will
all that. So that's a bad thing.
This in digging for lessons as a bad
thing. That's what you're saying.
That wasn't a lesson, Bro. Sorry,
digging for lessons. Next question.
Virtuosity requires your favorite subject.
Discipline.
Creativity is important as well.
Does a single focus on
discipline inhibit creativity?
No.
Jimmy page.
Next question. Seriously.
Jimmy page. What? Okay.
All right.
Well you're a bitch led Zepplin Guitar
Virtuoso practiced with discipline.
I just answered this on the
kids who were podcast. Okay.
Because Jimmy Page played guitar so much
when he was in school that they had to
take his guitar from him during like
study halls during lunch. Like, no,
you can't just sit there and play guitar.
You need to do other things.
That's how much he practiced.
Yeah. He practiced so much.
He became such a such a skilled player
through that much discipline that he was
able to get more creative than
almost anyone else on the guitar.
So there you go. It doesn't
give you freedom. It,
it expands your creativity.
Yeah,
and Jimmy page is one example of a
multitude. So let me ask you this.
I guess we kind of talked
about but not really.
I've never actually asked you
that. I can remember. So if you,
and let's assume that Jimmy page,
he didn't do it because he
felt like this is, you know,
what I should be doing right now,
whatever he did just cause I'm addicted.
Tick Guitar,
I love it.
And there's nothing I'd rather be
doing and all this stuff. So if you,
the question is,
if you just love doing it and
that's why you're doing it so much.
I Love Guitar. I don't want to eat
dinner. It now I'm busy on my guitar,
you know, enjoy myself and learning and
just loving it every single moment of it.
I don't want to go surf. I'm on
my guitar. Boom every single day.
Is that discipline
okay?
Yes.
Yeah,
because let's say, okay.
Actually, I don't know.
I guess not technically.
Yeah, it is. It is,
it is.
But I,
I'd be hard pressed to find somebody
that loves doing something so much that
they do it all the time with no
discipline whatsoever. Yeah. TheN in, uh,
I think I agree with you there.
But technically is that discipline though
cause you know, take Michael Jordan,
right? For example. It's not a good
example for what I'm about to say.
I think the guitar examples good cause
if you really love doing it and that's
what you're doing, I'll tell you what,
it takes discipline even if you enjoy it.
Yeah. I'm going to stick
with that answer for now.
So let's say you don't want to
and even more important answers.
I don't think it matters. I don't think
it matters either. So I don't want really,
because it's like it's because it
kind of alter at the end of the game.
It did you put in the hours of practice
and did you get good at it? Okay.
Did you get good at it?
That's what the question is.
Did you get good at this thing? Usually
I'll take him all the time. Pretty much.
With very few exceptions. The way you get
good at something is practice. And then,
you know,
usually since you can't do one thing
all day every single day for you know,
30 40 50 it's going to take discipline.
Meaning you're going to have to do it
even though you don't want to do it kind
of thing,
which is part of what discipline is.
But what if that part of it doesn't,
isn't there,
cause even like Michael Jordan and
he's so good and he's probably loved
basketball,
whatever,
but they're ha there was of course days
where he's like okay I'd rather maybe be
hanging out, I'm going to take
display. Right, right, right.
But that was a real person cause cause
to get a person that loves something so
much that it took them zero discipline,
I don't think that's a realistic person.
I think that anyone that does anything,
it gets to a point where the only
thing that drives him to do that extra
percentage is disciplined. So I
guess I will stick with it. Yeah.
So I guess the question, if you want to
kind of relate it to like a real person,
so you don't,
a person who again just like loves it,
he just loves what they do.
Of course they're going to have thumb
discipline because they're going to have
some days that they don't love
it or whatever. Like are they,
would you consider them a discipline
person in their, in their field? Yeah,
but we've also talked about this before,
just people that are very disciplined in
one field and completely on discipline
and other fields. Yeah. So,
so it's kind of an indicator that
that might not really be technically
discipline.
Technically they got the practice hours,
you work, if you like it, that's
great. If you don't like it,
well here's appears on indicator.
If you,
if you don't like doing it or what are
you doing it for if you don't even enjoy
it.
I mean the end right to the,
to the end or whatever it means to an end.
But if you're going to dedicate level 12
to something that you don't even enjoy,
I think I did, that's kind of
problematic. I think you're right too.
Next question. When you realize that
nothing will change in the leadership,
do you tap out and move on or continue
trying to be a good leader to your crew
who deserves it?
That's definitely a question of that.
It requires a little bit more information
to give a good answer too. You know,
because what's the situation?
Can you be,
is there an opportunity that you could
become the leader longterm because that
totally changes the outlook,
right? If if you could,
if you could do a good job and step up
and move them to a more senior leadership
position where you could take even more
turd turns or take even more care of the
crew will, then that's a positive thing
and it might be worth hanging out for.
Also,
is it a complete dead end?
Like is there no possibility it's a
family owned business and all the senior
leadership has related to the family
and you're not part of the family and
you're never have a chance
that that changes the prospect.
I mean obviously then it's like,
okay,
well maybe it's not worth sticking
around there. If you leave,
can you leave where you can give open
the opportunity for other people to go
where you're going? Right? Which is
not a good thing in terms of, you know,
you're not being very loyal,
you're being anti loyal,
you're being unloyal
disloyal if you do that.
But if the leadership that you're working
for isn't taking care of the people,
then you have to have some loyalty to the
people you work with. So there's that.
Um, I think that you, you,
you have to assess everything that's
going on in this situation, which,
which is not evident in this one
quick question. I would say this too,
like don't blind side your boss,
right?
That's something that if you're
going to leave, leave on good terms,
explained to him what's going on.
Also,
that can be an opportunity to start a
conversation about how the leadership
could include proof.
A lot of times people don't want to
change anything until it really smacks him
in the face. And one of the things
that smacks him in the face is,
is when one of their good people
comes in and says, Hey, look, I, I,
I'm going to leave because
of these reasons. And again,
you don't on the exit interview
or on those conversations,
you don't just drop dime and make
everyone make out to be this horrible
situation and say,
here's some things that I've noticed.
Here's some things that
I would want to change.
Here's the direction that I see the
company going and this is the direction I
think it should be going. And for these
reasons I've decided I'm going to go try,
you know, try my hand somewhere else.
I think if you'd be open like that,
it can start some good conversations and
possibly you could make some progress
or possibly you could
confirm your suspicions,
which are no one wants to change.
No one wants to do anything different.
And if that's the case and you
realize it's a dead end for you, yeah,
you've got to take that option.
You can't beat your head against
the wall on the 40, you know,
you can beat your head against the wall
47 times on the 48th time. It's like,
okay, I need to do something
different. So pay attention to that.
Next question.
What can we all learn from tenacious
d that most people overlook?
The critical question
question, but there's actually a real,
a real legitimate answer to that.
And that is that tenacious
d who's, uh, a very, uh,
funny group of individuals.
Jack Black is one of them who's a musician
and a comedian and an actor and Kyle
gas as the other member. What, what's,
what's great about them is they
don't take themselves too seriously.
And I think that's the lesson to learn
is don't take yourself too seriously.
Have some fun and
don't take yourself too seriously.
There it is.
Yeah.
And I would say there's a
difference between taking
yourself seriously and being
serious.
So you know how like
being serious is like, okay, you're
not necessarily joking all the time,
but taking yourself too seriously is like,
you know,
if like a joke is made about you or you
can't laugh at yourself or is that kind
of stuff? Yeah, yeah. It's different.
So you can be serious all the time.
You can be a serious person and not
take yourself to see that. That's true.
And that's a good,
that's fine. That's fine.
The person who don't want to be as
the person that takes themselves too
seriously all the time, that's
a problem. So inversely,
I guess could you to like, could
you be a very nuts, serious person,
but take yourself too seriously?
Could you be a very serious,
could you be a very like, jokey,
not serious person? Yeah, for sure.
This the person that you can dish it
out but you can't take it thin skin type
guys. Yeah. Kind of like you
write a little bit. Yeah. Yeah.
I see. I see what you did
there. I got a next question.
Unless there's anything more
from tenacious D no. You know,
maybe some good songs we can
inspirado right.
That's from tonight.
That's where he got that.
I've got to give him a warning of
language is not appropriate for kids with
tenacious d. Ignore some of the subject
matter. So be careful with that.
The warning.
Next question.
You mentioned you rarely
pay play closed guard.
Rarely is this just a personal preference?
I would say that it is somewhat
a personal preference, right?
Because there's definitely some people
that intentionally played closed guard.
That's their game. Um,
but at the same time,
in order to attack even
from the closed guard,
most of the time you have to open your
guard. So therefore your guard is open.
So open guard and that's
kind of what I do.
Skip the step of opening my guard.
But you've been in people's guard that
have really good close guards. Yes. Yeah.
It's not fun. No. And that's why I try
not to let people close her guard. Yeah.
Cause you can prevent that from happening.
Yeah. There's people that have really,
really solid psycho closed guard.
So I'm not anti closed guard and
some people are great at it. Uh,
my personal preferences to
play more open guard. Yeah.
Yeah. It's one of those
things were closed guard.
If you're not a person who always
plays closed guard or whatever,
it can be just something that you kind
of use for specific situations. You know,
like if you're trying to maybe breed
regained some energy or something like
that, you want to rest a little bit.
Or even in like a self defense,
like a striking scenario,
like a closed garden. Mike, Mike
know the close guard, isn't it?
There's no doubt that closed guard has
viable purpose and is good and I do use
it. I just don't use it a lot. Yeah. Yeah.
And if you're a taller lanky guy,
closed gardens might be a little
bit short fat legs that you know,
up. My closed guard is like my toes are
touching depending on the size of the
person.
And actually where it stems from,
if you went to the root of it
is it stems from foot locks.
So if you close your guard, when your
guard opens, you're vulnerable in that.
There's a moment where
you're both vulnerable and
if you're training with guys
that have really good for locks,
that's not a good situation.
So that's where I started not closing
my guard because there was always that
transition period where my feet were
vulnerable so I just stopped closing my
garden, kept it open and move my fit feet
towards me to keep it little bit safer.
Yeah. Next question. We've
got time for one more.
Yes. Yo Jocko. What's
the best way to increase
Yo Jocko? What's the best way
to increase one's confidence?
You want to increase
your confidence?
I'll,
I'll tell you what I think what you do,
if you want to increase your
confidence is you do Jujitsu,
you work out,
you get stronger,
you read and you study and
you learn and you get smarter
and,
and then you practice speaking and you
practice speaking so that you can become
more articulate and then
you practice some more
and then you,
then you do hard things.
Things that are challenging,
things that are tough and then
you get tougher. You don't quit.
That's what you do.
And then you stand up straight with your,
with your head high and your
chin up and your chest out.
And at the same time you also stay humble
cause you don't know everything.
And there are people that are
better than you are at some things.
People that are smarter than you and
they're stronger than you and faster and
more athletic than you and they have
more money and they got better looks and
they're funnier.
But all that is okay.
It's actually okay because there
are things that are more important,
more important than being
strong and smart and athletic.
More important than all of those things.
Things like loyalty,
honor
will,
things like courage,
the courage to stand and
the will to keep going
and to do the right things
for the right reasons.
Yeah. And if you know, if
you know you won't give up
and you know you won't give in and
if you test yourself and you fail,
but you know you're going to get
back up again. If you know that,
if you know that,
then you know that your character
is strong and that's what matters.
And that right there.
Okay.
Is all the confidence you need.
And I think that's
all I've got for tonight.
So Echo. Yes. Speaking of
being stronger and faster.
Yes. And doing Jujitsu. Sure.
And learning and just
being on the path overall.
Maybe you could give us some
information on how we can effectively,
efficiently move down that path.
Yeah.
Support and support ourselves,
support ourselves and support others.
That's really ultimately really what it
is. Makes it intellectually supporting.
Yes.
So I will talk about our company,
little company in Maine
called origin origin main.com.
This is where you can get Jocko
Super Krill oil is for your joints.
Omega Three's making three's have a
lotta benefits, valuable benefits,
but the ones that I personally
have reaped,
can you reap benefits? Benefits,
right? Just can't reap the foot.
And Terry DGF. Yeah, yeah.
So watch out for that.
But if you are in the reaping mood,
reap some benefits of Jocko Super Krill
oil by way of your joints being healthy.
It's a big deal when you're super young,
like young 18 1920 all are to,
I'd say like maybe 27
maybe. I Dunno, maybe older.
This is less of a factor but at the
end of the day your joints are healthy.
You're going to be in a way better spot.
Way better spot then you would be if
they're not also another co a supplement
called joint warfare.
This one,
I mean they all have antioxidant stuff
in them but joint warfare has glucosamine
and conjoin.
This is for what?
Like cartilage tendon type
stuff and curcumin. Curcumin,
yeah, so you put those together. Boom. The
ultimate joint supplements, the big deal.
Huge deal.
Like you can be super strong
and be lifting and but you
got to warm up like for
20 sets just because your joints
are all like stiff and whatever.
Sade say bye to that problem.
You take these, there it is.
Boom.
Joint supplements get on it.
Go to or do you mean.com also
another supplement called discipline.
This is for your brain,
makes your brain work better.
It's nutrients for your brain.
That's what it is and also
nutrients for your body.
So a pre workout,
it's a pre study. It's a pre mission
supplement called discipline.
Get Down? Same, same place or do you
mean.com tastes good too, by the way.
Is other flavor out?
When does the other flavor out?
We're making it right now so soon.
[inaudible] a little further than
soon. Soon to me is like, yeah,
like a little more distant than soon.
But we're working on shipping. Yeah,
that's soon to me. And is Pina
Colada by the way? Oh, sorry.
I got a different name for
it. Yeah. Uh, coconut. No,
I got a better name for it. I bought
it later. Oh, later. Okay. Secret name.
Cause I'm not sure if it's legal or not
the name. Okay, Gotcha. You have in mind.
All right, cool. Well,
so we're all very excited about the name
and the tastes and you know, whatnot.
Pineapple, coconut is the
working title, working title.
There you go. Uh, cognitive and
physical force multiplier. Good one.
Also milk. Okay, so milk,
I'm going to say the word protein powder,
but I'm not saying Malki
is protein powder. Oh yeah.
If you want some additional protein,
what's a good way to get it?
That happens to taste really,
really good.
Like a mint chocolate milkshake,
not a diet and milkshake. I like
a mint chocolate milkshake. Right.
And you want protein, take milk,
take it every day if you want to.
My buddy sent me a text, he goes, yeah,
I saw that mark had probiotics
in it. Dang. Even better. Yes.
And he said, I, he said, so I just ordered
it because I need some. Yeah. And He,
and he's like, Whoa, this stuff is
good. I said, yeah, I know. I said,
I know. And he's like, yeah, it's awesome.
So you can anyways making
the supersize milk shake.
Yeah. Hey man, I can relate because
that's literally what I do. Yeah, no,
I could tell when you
got on the mark train,
cause your attitude changed. You
know you went from like, Oh yeah,
we've got more cause it's good and blah
blah, blah. To when you were like, hey,
it's kind be a game changer.
You know, it's, it's so failing.
What does it makes it so feeling,
feeling like, like when you eat it,
you just feel complete.
When you drink it, you feel,
say she'd completely say sheath.
That's why you know,
you know the term meal replacement like
oh we kind of meal replacement sir.
This isn't supposed to be a meal
replacement. It's not supposed to be.
The intent wasn't okay. Replace.
But what happens is if you have it,
like yesterday I had one in the,
in the afternoon I had a light launch,
which was crap. I ate a crap lunch.
Like not not, not healthy.
Gotcha. Little off the path. Cool.
So I was feeling like, ah,
okay. And then so in the,
a little later than that I said,
you know what,
I'm going to have some bulk right
now to try to reset the path. Yeah.
And then I got home from Jiu
Jitsu last night, six hours later,
didn't even barely eat anything for dinner
because I was still full. Why is that?
Amen. It's, I'm feeling satiated.
Satisfied, satisfies you on multiple
fronts. Plus it's psychologically come,
come on. And you kind of knew that it
was the mall can, you were like solid.
We felt good about that.
You were satisfied about that.
That's probably a big factor. So it's
not supposed to be a meal replacement,
but that's not what it was engineered.
That's what it was an engineered for.
But it turns out that if you have it,
you won't be that hungry
because you'd be so full. Yeah.
Yes. True for milk. No
big deal. So it's so,
it's so different.
We had to create a different word for it.
That's going to be in the Oxford English
dictionary soon. I'm sure it will.
It'll be, oh, it'll be, they'll
have to define it in the OED.
You know what the OED is? Oxford
English dictionary. Yeah. Yeah.
That's the real deal right there.
There you go. That's the big one. Yeah,
that's the big one. That's the mother of
all dictionaries. Must Be. It must be.
It is. There's no must be. Dang. And
milk is going to be in there. You said
we'll petition.
I won't even have to petition for
cause people are just going to start.
That's how I was just going to be here.
It's just going to be how and it really,
that's how words get in the dictionary.
Just keep using it. And here's the,
here's the good thing about that word.
Not to go off on too much of a tangent,
but a will and I don't mind
doing it with this situation.
Mark is the actual legitimate
situation. Mark. It's more mark,
but it's not like the word regardless
and misusing the word because they're not
educated on that specific word.
And they use your regardless.
Their friend uses their neighbor
use it there. Who knows?
Maybe we'll get in there too.
[inaudible] he's a Hawaiian word. I know,
but maybe we'll get it into
the English dictionary,
but it's not English cause
that's the thing done.
The English dictionary is not filled
with words that are only English.
The whole English language is
made up of other words. Gotcha.
Consult kind of pile on in there.
Right. And milk. We'll petition.
We can't petition.
You don't petition to get them in there.
You actually just use the words.
So like the word forte.
I wonder if that's my forte. People
started trying to rip off milk. Yeah.
It'll be like, hey, we use xerox me a copy
of that. Right, right. It'll just be the,
it'll just be the way. Yeah. Yeah. Instead
of be a new thing, like I'm going to,
you know, first I'm going to work out
and then like I'm just going to, um,
I'm going to, yeah. Oh, you picked
me up some milk from the store. Oh.
And then people say, well what
kind of milk do you, right,
right, right, right. Yeah.
And then won't we just be talking about
flight cause it'd be nine different
brands of milk. Okay. You're from the, uh,
kind of the easy way is New England east
coats at technically for sure as it can
see. Okay. So d d did you grow up
in a place where they say cokes?
No more pop. We called her soda. Call
it soda. Yeah, we call it the soda too.
So I've, cause they'll soda. Okay.
That's normal to me in, you know,
as far as my experience goes.
And then there's pop, you've heard
pop pop. That's like the Midwest,
Ohio. And then there's
coke, like coke, coke,
sprite.
I had to do this. Uh, when I
was going to college, I had to,
they wanted us to get the words for what?
Okay,
what do you call if you get an ice cream
cone and you get little flavored tiny
bits all over it, what do you call
those little flavored bits? Sprinkles.
Sprinkles. That's, that's one
of the standards. There's a,
there's some people that call
them jimmies. Okay. Okay.
My wife's from England and I,
and so I did this to her.
So we had that.
We had a bunch of words that were broken
out that people call different things
like soda pop, what it like, what do
you call this? What do you call that?
Where you from? What do you call
this? What do you call that?
I did this with my wife and I actually
luckily recorded it because I knew it
would be interesting. How'd you record
it? Like on a tape recorder. No kidding.
Tape recorder. Old School. Yeah. And then
I go and I, so I asked my wife, you know,
what do you call the things that you put
on an ice cream cone that are a little
different colors and they're
little tiny bits of sugary candy,
what would you call those? And
she, without missing a beat,
she goes hundreds and thousands.
Hundreds of thousands.
I started laughing kind of a mouthful.
Hundreds and thousands.
Yeah, yeah, there's no, and
then I said, because, okay,
what do you call
ham?
Manet's lettuce on a long bun.
That's,
what do you call that in the
sandwiches at me? There is no specific,
but I get it, I hoagie. Okay.
But I dunno like a sub
sandwich or something.
We used to call the grinder. Yeah, this
is like a new England grind to get it.
I want to get a grinder,
but my,
my wife calls it a bap bap,
bap bap. And this is like, I said, what
do you call that thing? And she's like,
oh, it's a bap bap cheese back. Anyways.
And was that just a long thin,
which like long look at subway sandwich,
sub club.
So at some point people are just going
to say moke and that's going to have a
meaning beyond just what
we have right now. Yeah.
Because people will be
making it. Everyone's gonna
be trying to make it. Sure.
It's going to be just so calm and you
know it's going to be, it's like, oh,
you'll have is going to replace, let's
say it replaces lunch, like, oh yeah,
I eat three meals a day. Breakfast,
Moelleken dinner. Right. Oh,
what are you going to have? Oh yeah. Hey,
they're gonna come over from
Olc later on. Yeah, right here.
Guys coming over tonight.
Do you have some Mulkin watch the game.
I have some milk's. Yeah, right. Yeah.
You're going to look on kids'
elementary school schedule.
It'd be like boom, you know,
recess and then you know,
1130 mark and then, you know,
boom. History, you know I got
you, man. That's where it's going.
The Horn is going to sound
mock break, right? Yeah.
Let's go get some milk for soffits.
Pau Hana. That's what I said.
A lot of times on that.
My part of the island,
we called it a little bit different.
Right, right, right. Got You. Man.
I have the New England, Hawaii. All right,
so that's Moke milk. Okay, boom. Yeah.
Mark does it go and get and get your,
you get your hands on some of that.
You're good. Yeah. Pau and I didn't
analyze it means finish work.
It means when you're done work your
pile Ho. I know exactly what it come on.
This is for the people maybe
explain that to me yet,
but if you say pau pau sounds like peel,
pow like pop pow. That
means finished. Literal.
Yup. Directress you pile. Yep. Right.
You finished a I pal. Yup,
I'm finished. Definitely.
Yup. Did you do like, no,
you're doing,
it means doing like if you say Hannah
hope that means let's do it again.
You know, whatever it is. Or like
if someone, usually they say, well,
a commonplace they say it is like if a
band is playing and it's like a dope song
and they killed it, they say,
Hon, I hope means like do it
again. Play it again, man.
I remember yelling that when
I was a kid or if you go,
you go do something fun
and you guys are done.
You say your goodbyes to your friends
and you say what tomorrow Honohan means
you wouldn't do that thing tomorrow.
It's good again,
unless back to origin, our company
origin made in America. By the way,
this stuff,
good stuff including gs four
digit to starting Jujitsu.
You ask, ask me as Jocko whatever. If you,
if you asked me or Jocko
what gt get here it is,
I'll end compromised.
Not uncompromised.
No exception,
no exception that I can think of anyway.
You get an origin geek for many,
many reasons.
I'm not going to go into all of them,
but they are made in America and they're
made for Jujitsu. Sounds Weird, right?
Like a 40 minutes.
Did you do to get gifts made for Jujitsu?
Not as much as the origin Geek.
That's the thing.
You have a Jujitsu guy who is an expert
in textiles manufacturing some fashion.
I know. I know, but it's part of
it. And he's like, you know what,
I'm going to make a geek for Jujitsu,
for doing Jujitsu in,
you know,
not just hey AGI,
which is cool and you can use a Virginia
to let's make a bunch of blanks and
whatever brands can buy
them from us and you know,
just kind of this thing and we'll
ship into them in the u s no,
it's not that Pete made Jujitsu gies
four digit to shape for Jujitsu woven for
Jujitsu. That's important part. Yeah.
So when you put it on, you do that.
You did too. Yeah. And when you put it
in the dryer, it actually dries. Yeah.
Which is even so this is totally geeky.
These keys,
all of them perform when you do and you
do too. And when you're not junior. Yeah.
Boom. There it is. And all made in
America. Did I mention that everything,
even the threads are made in America.
Even the cotton is grown in America. Nope.
Yeah.
Most of us already know that,
but I'm going to say it again because
some of us don't necessarily know that.
Now we do.
It's pretty cool when you're putting
on a g and you know the people that
actually made it. Yeah.
That's what made it. Yeah.
And when you're,
when you know you're supporting the
economic growth of this country.
Yes.
And at the same time you're getting the
best possible ghee you can get. Yeah.
I'd say that's 100% positive.
That's a win win.
Yeah. When came across the board and
everyone's kind of in the game together,
you have that additional like
additional feeling situation.
That's my opinion. That's my
experience anyway. Also, rash guards,
these are good rash guards by the
way. Um, well inventing in good,
good rash guards. Is that just
a matter of opinion? Okay.
Or you.com look at the rash guards.
You'll like one,
get one of those.
Boom.
Also the immersion camp you
did through immersion camp.
One of the best ways to learn anything
including but not limited to Jujitsu is
day Merce yourself in it.
Immerse yourself in Jujitsu.
You can't on August 26
two sessions, you can go from
the (262) 072-0820 nine now.
And then the second session,
the 30th through the second September
2nd or he can do it all either way.
More stuff. And you just do, Dean
is going is deemed going. Yes.
So Dean lister is going Jockos going,
I'm going
layoffs going race. Can Leif
Babin is going. Dave Burke's
going. Good deal. Dave.
And Jp is going,
so maybe Mike in Flynn as
far as the echelon front,
maybe. Maybe not. No. I'm
telling they're not. So maybe
not. No, not, not going. Okay.
Got You. I understand now. Okay. Either
way, we're all going to be there.
And if the question it is,
I don't have any Jujitsu at all,
I don't have any need to do to it.
I'll do I go to a Jujitsu camp?
Yes. The answer's yes. Andy's
going to, it looks like, okay.
Andy Barr training hardcore
for a ADCC and oh yeah.
Somebody asked if,
if there's an,
is there a chance to go see the
factory where everything's made? Yes.
And the answer is affirmative.
Uh, middle of the week,
Wednesday in between Jujitsu
sessions, go to the factory, you know,
get to see everything, get to meet the
people that make everything. It's awesome.
Yes, very much so. That's a
good little hangout spot too.
Last time we were there were kind of
hanging out there for a little bit. Yeah,
for sure.
It was kind of,
but yeah, it's a good one. That's going
to be a good one. Eat some lobster too.
If you like lobster. I don't know. Some
people don't like lobster so and whatever.
Maybe that's not the draw. Yeah, eat some
steak. Boom. All good. Good camp camp,
Echo Lake layers. You
mean? I'll see you there.
Also for fitness gear on it.com/jocko.
Good kettle bells on there. The
Best Kettlebells, matter of opinion,
my opinion. Yes, 100%. The
only kettle bells I have on it,
kettle bells and I think I have more or
less all of them. All of them except the,
this teeny tiny small ones
in one series or all of them?
All of them. All of them. All of them.
The Zombie one. Zombie ones. Well,
some of them were sold out. So
aside from the sold out ones? Yes.
Oh actually I don't have the star
wars ones yet. You're getting them.
But here's the same way they ask these.
So that's the team is in
the game a little bit.
So different inspired for Boba Fett.
Depends on the workout. But here's the,
here's the thing, I'm gonna be honest.
Like if I do have the same weight,
maybe I'll get one in one. You know,
cause I have double of everything here.
But wait, double meaning for
total customers. Talk to each one.
Free Chan. You know, you'd
do the double hand. It's
situations. Yeah, those are dope.
Good thing too about on it.com that
website is the information on there.
Health,
various uh,
philosophies in pursuits of
exercises and workout programs.
Like depending on what you want to do,
stuff like that.
Good information about the
products to also socks.
I know. Seems like a small deal. I know,
but I just got some in their
dope and they're kind of like,
you know how like when you're
going through the airport, right?
You've got to take off your shoes.
Some of us, some of us, you know,
I know I get it. Some people they
don't get to take off the shoes,
but when you got to take off your shoes
and you kind of have your socks and one
time, so I was going through,
I had the on it socks on.
It felt kind of some because it
felt dope cause they're kinda dope.
They looked dope. You know what
I'm saying? Whole situation. Brag,
get some socks and go travel
report back anyway. [inaudible]
dot com slash [inaudible] let
a real good stuff on there.
Improve yourself also when
you are shopping or chew or
when you're going to shop
for any of the books that Jocko recommends
including Jacola's books by the way,
extreme ownership, the updated one
way, the worry kid, both of them.
Discipline equals freedom
field manual best kind of feel.
Men are best kind of manual by the way.
Field manual and you can read in the
field anyway when you're shopping for any
of these books.
I kind of organized on Jocko podcast.com
jock was books are on the front page
right there, kind of in plain view.
Murray designed the website by the way,
but this is going to stay the same.
I have a page though,
Jocko podcasts books or books
from the episodes, what it's
called. Anyway, top man,
you click on there,
they're all organized by episode.
Authors listed there with the title.
Boom, click through there. Boom.
Good way to support by the get your books.
Get your other stuff from Amazon.
Whenever you're getting
good way to support
people, don't think that's
a big deal. It's a big deal.
Just that small little action
has a big reaction.
Kind of like remember dropping
a piece of sodium in water.
I remember people had been reminding
me of that analogy on recently.
No, we haven't talked about it in allow
you drop piece of sodium and water had
explodes to huge small action by dropping
a small little thing. Big Reaction,
sodium. Fair enough. There
you go. Revisit down. Anyway,
also subscribe to the podcast.
If you haven't already on iTunes and
stitcher and Google play or wherever else
you listen to podcasts, a lot of podcasts,
apps, so subscribe, good way to support.
Also subscribe on Youtube for the
video version of this podcast.
It's something in but what I call
it important the video version.
Sure.
If you want to know Daca looks like,
if you don't know where you
want to know what I look like.
If you want to know what the guests
look like cause that I think is going to
Pique your curiosity more.
So that's my opinion anyway.
Playing there is video version of
the podcast also excerpts on there.
We'll put on there. Uh,
you know for, you know,
you want to share some lessons that Jocko
talks about with your friends online,
email it to him, whatever,
Facebook, whatever and uh, you know,
they're more likely to
listen to a little excerpt.
Then maybe a three hour podcasts on
something and sift through that one lesson
you wanted them to learn. You see
what I'm saying? Anyway, Youtube,
subscribe if you want. Good way to
support. Also, Jack was his door.
It's called Jocko store.
This is where you can get the shirts,
the very short that Jack was wearing
right now. You can have that exact shirt,
exact shirt if you want,
if that even means anything to you,
but I think the shirts are cool.
Discipline equals freedom. Get after it.
You know you want to represent in
your part of the world, in the field,
in the wild.
That's the weekend.
Get a chocolate store.com this women's
stuff on there as well and patches.
Hats to kind of hats, truckers
and flex fit. They're good.
They came out good I think so. Go on
there. Let me know what you think.
You think they're good? Get something.
If you don't think they're good,
let me know how I can improve,
how we can improve collectively the
hat situations. People were very vocal.
We invite them to be vocal.
If they think of a a product
or a shirt design or something,
and I encourage that. Also, rash guards
on there. Good, cool. Rash guards,
19% increase in performance. What
we used to preach. You know what?
I'm going to go ahead and
continue preaching that.
Also psychological warfare.
I'll tell you what this is.
If you don't know,
it's an album with tracks of Jocko
on there. Each track not singing.
He's saying stuff and this is what
he's saying. If you're having, okay,
if you're having moments of
weakness on your kind of pursuit,
your campaign against weakness is what
we're calling it. Having trouble wake up,
waking up in the morning every
once in a while or you're,
you're feeling you don't feel like
working out. I know. We know that.
If you don't feel like working out,
you still work out.
That's the deal.
You still work out if you don't,
but every once in a while you really
don't feel like doing it or you're so
caught up in this other thing and you
kind of play games with your mind,
you're like, you know what? I could
skip the workout in. It's justified,
literally justified because I would get
this other work done then I'm working on
right now. That's another one,
but you listened to this doc.
Jocko will tell you this track, when we
leave one of the tracks on the album,
he listened to it. Jack will tell you
why you shouldn't skip the workout.
And guess what,
you won't skip to work out 100% effective
psychological warfare is what it's
called Jocko Willink. It's on iTunes
or Amazon and whenever you can buy it,
wherever you buy mp3s,
that's where you can get it. Good way
to support check. Also you can get
Jocko white tea,
you can get it dry in little
tea bags and that's cool.
And now you can also get it in
a pan cans of Jocko white tea
tastes really good and more important
gives you an 8,000 pound dead lift,
which is, you know,
not a big deal. So, uh,
no more of the sugar filled,
chemical laced, crappy energy drinks.
Those are gone no more.
Those days are over and said it's
time for Jocko white tea in a can.
Uh, books. You mentioned them
the way the war, your kid series.
Okay.
Getting kids on the path now.
Discipline hard work,
respect the path to getting stronger,
smarter,
faster and better. And if you don't
believe me, if you don't believe me,
check out my,
uh,
my social mutech on my
Twitter and you'll see kids,
kids working out,
cleaning their rooms voluntarily studying,
voluntarily doing book reports
voluntarily. Check it out.
It's awesome.
You can
see it there.
Get your kids on the path and get your
neighbors kids on the path and get your,
your nieces and nephews on the path.
Also a path of a warrior kid
that's all about hard work.
You can go to Irish oaks ranch.com and
get some soap made by warrior kid Aiden.
He just started his own business.
I got stuff still. It's good to go.
He gets it from goat milk.
Yeah.
Let me ask his farm that again.
I said this before.
It's important to understand too with,
you know how you get like the,
your neighbor, whatever they
make their little designer soap.
Maybe they looked it up youtube or how
to make it or whatever.
They put their perfumes in and they wrap
it up in a nice little net rapping with
a little ribbon on. It's cool. I dig it,
I dig it. But you don't really use that.
So you know, it's like, all right, I'm
not going to use it all. Thanks. You know,
and I got a soap decorative piece,
whatever. It's not that kind of,
so it's legit.
So you use this.
So I didn't even think to say that
because I thought everyone knew,
I guess know people get suspect
because he's a young kid maybe.
Or you just hear like, Ooh,
special. So I don't know.
Then depending on your experience,
I'm sure people don't give
you decorative soap items. No,
they don't regularly. No.
Okay. Do the good thing about
this soap from my opinion,
it's all about function. And this
soap will help you stay clean. Yes.
Uh, the discipline equals
freedom field manual.
You can give the gift of
discipline and you know,
if you know someone that's like sort
of maybe got a foot off the path,
that's a person that's right for the
discipline equals freedom field manual.
Yeah. That's a person that you go, hey
man, it's got this book, man. Give it up.
Just take a look at it. Yeah, let's take a
look at it. Yeah. It doesn't look normal.
Nope. It looks actually pretty dope. Yeah,
and then they read something and
then they say, Oh, you know what?
I don't know for quite a long term,
gets them back on the path.
If you want the audio version of that,
it's discipline equals freedom field
manual. It's, it's not on audible.
It's on iTunes, Amazon music,
Google play, other MP3 platforms.
That's where it's at.
Also for leadership,
extreme ownership is the leadership
book for the battlefield,
for business and for life.
Now,
the audible version of that is available
on audible and it is me reading it and
it's Leif Babin reading it,
otherwise known as Texas
Batman because he talks to me,
so if you want to hear us read it,
not just reading it,
but there's also sound effects, some
sound effects. We didn't go overboard,
even though we were attempted.
We had to pull the reigns a little bit,
but I don't know why it didn't very
talk about this very much, but yeah,
check it out.
The audible version of that book also
do September 25th the follow on book two
extreme ownership.
It's called the dichotomy of leadership.
It's available for preorder right now,
Amazon,
Barnes and noble local bookstore.
If you want that first edition version,
which you do
in order it now,
that way the
the publishing company who's lagging
doesn't get it living in the stone ages.
They won't print it enough
and then you won't get a copy.
It'll take an extra week.
They've got to print more like
happened with the warrior kid.
Books like to happen with the first
extreme ownership like what happened with
discipline equals freedom field manual.
They ran out. If you preorder it,
they won't run out so preordered and
if you need support at your business or
your team, we have Ashkelon Front.
It's me, Leif, Babin, JP Denelle,
Dave Burke,
our website,
Ashkelon front.com and we solve problems
through leadership. That's what we do.
All the problems you have in your business
and your team and your organization,
the problems that you have, all of them
are leadership problems, all of them.
That's a bold statement to make,
isn't it? Yes, and it's factual.
You're not going to solve those
problems through spreadsheets.
You're going to solve those
problems through leadership,
so let us know if you need some help
and of course there's the muster.
We've done five musters so far.
All of them sold out.
The last one we did in DC was nuts.
It was awesome.
Lot of knowledge that's getting put out.
A lot of intensity.
There's one more monster in 2018 it's
muster zero zero six in San Francisco,
October 17th and 18th it is
going to sell out as well.
Don't get mad when you can't
go because it's sold out.
Go and register extreme ownership.com
and also for current military law
enforcement, firefighters, paramedics,
border patrol, other first responders.
We got roll call zero zero one
September 21st in Dallas, Texas.
It's a focused one day leadership training
seminar and it's aimed at people in
uniform.
Then you can also register
for that@extremeownership.com
and until the muster in
San Francisco or the roll call
or the immersion camp in Maine.
If you want to maintain contact with us,
you can find us on the interwebs.
Echo is at echocharles
and I am at Jocko Willink.
And to those of you that are wearing
the uniform out there on the front lines
right now,
thank you for keeping evil at bay and
the vets that have already served.
Thank you for doing your share
and to the
first responders, police, law
enforcement, firefighters, paramedics,
border patrol.
Thanks to all of you for staying ready,
staying alert,
staying strong,
and keeping us safe here at home and
to the families of all that serve.
Thank you for your sacrifice as your
loved ones serve us and to the rest of you
out there.
Thanks for listening.
Thanks for supporting you actually make
this podcast possible. So thank you. But,
but nevermind all of that.
Thanks for doing what you do every day.
Thanks for waking up
early and staying up late.
Thanks for putting in the hours,
the long hours
grinding,
working,
making things happen,
standing up when the hard times come
and they come,
you're not alone.
The hard times come to all of
us and when they do stand up,
grit your teeth
and get after it.
Until next time.
This is echo and Jocko out.