This is Jocko podcast number
one 32 with Echo Charles and me,
Jocko Willink. Good
Evening Echo. Good evening.
Okay.
The warriors are all dead.
They lie on the more field.
Yeah,
they struggled but shall not enter.
They went but shall not return.
Okay.
The planes are flat and wide.
The way home,
as long
their swords lie beside them,
they're black bows in their hand.
Though their limbs were torn,
their hearts could not be repressed.
They were more than brave.
They were inspired with the spirit of woo,
steadfast to the end.
They could not be daunted.
Their bodies were stricken down,
but their souls have taken a mortality
captains among the ghosts
heroes among the dead
and that is an excerpt from an ancient
Chinese poem written by Q one and there's
not many details of his life.
He was a patriotic poet that lived
around 300 BC and the poem refers to the
spirit of woo,
which I like
cause woo means Marshall
as in martial arts,
as in things that are related to war
and things that are related to fighting.
Well that's a Wu means of war.
Three is talking about the spirit of war.
And of course China has an incredibly
rich history of art and culture and fought
for thousands of years.
Many dynasties that I've
carried on that rich culture.
But we also of course know that
China has a long history of war.
The Knowledge About Warren,
we've already looked at one
of the fundamental books
about Warren strategy from
Sun Tzu,
the art of war.
And today we're going to take a look at
another important document that comes
from China.
It's called the 36 stratagems.
And this document has been
around for a long time
and it's actual origin is
debated where it came from.
There's some people that say Sun Tzu
wrote it. Actually, there's a, uh,
another military
strategist named Zeus Dang.
And some people think he wrote it,
but the current prevailing view
is that it's a compilation of information
that was compiled by different people,
different authors over the year,
over the years.
And the actual version that I'm using
was compiled by a guy named Peter Taylor.
And if you remember, so 36 stratagems,
that's what it's called,
the 36 stratagems.
And if you remember from a
recent podcast that we did,
stratagem doesn't mean strategy.
It doesn't mean that it's a trick.
That's what it means. It's a subterfuge,
it's a, it's a sneaky
maneuver to get what you want.
That sort of strategy is now this
book is divided up into six sections.
The first three are
for when you're winning
and the second three are
for when you're losing.
The winning stratagems are advantageous,
opportunistic and attacking.
And the other like losing type strategies
when you're losing our confusion,
deception and desperation.
And you don't want some of
these we've heard before summer,
a new take on an old idea or an old take
that we think is a new idea in all of
them.
Reinforce kind of what we know and allow
us to think about these things a little
bit different way and see them from
a different angle. So here we go.
The 36 stratagems
number one sneak across the
ocean in broad day light.
And so after they give that,
that's the actual, that's the,
that's the stratagem right there.
And so you've got to give a little
explanation around some of them.
And Peter Taylor does it in this book.
He,
he lines them out and I've
actually seen there's a,
there's another copy of this same book
where they all have the sort of general
uh,
explanation.
A lot of them have the same general
explanation own almost as if it's part of
the same book,
but to hit that part.
So it says number one sneaker
across the ocean in broad day light.
What does that mean?
What you often,
what you see often you do not doubt and
what is familiar becomes uninteresting
and a perfect cloak for
the unusual and unexpected.
This strategy means that you can mask
your real purpose by using the ruse or a
fake target that everyone
takes for granted. Tactically,
this is known as the open
faint in front of everyone.
You Point West when your goal is
actually in the east. For example,
a goalkeeper when facing a penalty shot
will often stand to one side or the
other,
effectively inviting the opposing player
to aim towards the open space when in
fact the goalkeeper reacts
and moves to this exact space,
the moment when the shot is taken.
Thus saving the goal.
No,
pretty clear.
Next one to besiege way to rescue Zau
besiege way to rescues out when the enemy
is too strong to be attacked directly
than attack something they hold
close to them or value dearly.
So this is a little bit different
than just a flank, right?
A flank means I'm going to
hit your weak point. This is,
I'm going to attack something
that you care about.
Take the indirect approach
and find their Achilles heel.
So that is the weak point.
But the first,
the first explanation is
not just the weak point,
it's I'm going to attack something
that you are, you care about.
Thinking about how do,
how you do this in a relationship like
a well in a business relationship or
something and insults. Oh yeah.
There you go. All kinds of things.
Back to the book of the origin of this
proverb is apparently from the Warring
States period when the state of way
attacked Zau and laid siege to its capital
hand,
Dom Zau term to key for help.
But the key general son been determined.
It would be unwise to meet
the army of way head on.
So instead he attacked their
capital on hearing the news,
the army of way retreated in haste and
the tired troops were then ambushed and
defeated.
The idea here is to avoid a head on
battle with a strong enemy and instead
striking his weakness elsewhere so
that that part we've heard before.
We know that part,
but I liked the idea of attacking
something that they care about more.
I mean that's a classic. That's
a classic like classic is, Oh,
I can't get to you but I'm going to get to
your kids. Yeah, yeah, yeah, I'll, I'll,
I'll kill your kids. That's
always the worst. Right.
And you know all your movies that you
watched. Yeah, they always do that.
What? So that as far as comparing
it to a flank flank is like,
I mean comparatively speaking,
what just,
I mean obviously to go
to the side of the side,
is this somewhere the metal shielded
or bunk, right bunker, right number.
Yeah.
Number three,
kill with a borrowed knife attack using
the strength of another in a situation
where using one's own strength is not
favorable trick and ally into attacking
him or bribe an official to turn trader
in your favor or use the enemy's own
strength against him.
Borrowing a knife to kill
may seem rather to devious,
but fundamentally it's making use of
others' resources for your own gain and
sometimes without your
opponent's knowing it.
There's some underhanded
stuff with this for sure.
The idea here is it caused damage to your
enemy by letting a third party bricked
by getting a third party to do the deed.
In fact,
it can be said that your enemy's enemy
is your front, which we've heard before.
Kill with a borrowed knife.
That's a good one. The,
I keep thinking about when I read these,
I think about people interacting with
other people and how someone will get
someone all spun up like, Oh,
can you believe echo did this?
You shouldn't say something about that.
You're right and like, like do that way
number four wait to at leisure
while the enemy labors,
it is an advantage to choose the time
and place for battle in this way.
You will know when and where
the battle will take place.
While your enemy does not encourage your
enemy to expend his energy in feudal
quests to while you conserve
your strength, when he is
exhausted and confused,
you attack with energy and purpose.
What part of Jujitsu did you
not understand right there?
So he asked me that the other day is it
isn't a tactic to let someone get tired
and 100% yeah. It's like one
of the foundational principles.
Yeah. I mean if you look at the
early UFC, if you look at hoists,
Gracie in the early UFC,
that was,
I would say he used that term, that
tactic a majority of the time. Yeah.
That's like what essentially did you
through is like when they started it like
caleal grief. He was a little guy,
whatever, and that's the, yeah,
that's what he would say.
The whole time you cook up and they
call it cooking and look at all,
it's part of the deal. No cookie
dough. That's good. I like that.
I haven't heard that one in a while.
Number five,
loot a burning house.
When a country is beset by
internal conflicts or when
disease and famine ravages
the population or when
corruption and crime are rampant,
then it will be unable to
deal with an outside threat.
This then is the best time to attack.
These are devious,
aren't that when you read
them, they're devious. Amen.
Marshall with the Marshall Way. Yeah.
You know what? I've seen some companies,
some businesses that do that right
there and they do it well. Yeah.
When they're really,
when they're really hostile,
they sew the seeds of all that,
all the chaos,
all the ravages and all the famines
and all the corruption and crime.
When a company's really devious,
they sow those seeds with the other
company and then they watch them fall part
of them. Then they go in
and take them down. Yeah.
Luda burning house means taking personal
gain from bad situations that your
enemies are facing. While a house is
ablaze or during major disturbance,
there'll be enough confusion to make
it easy and accessible to steal or take
advantage of the situation.
When your enemy is in a
state of confusion and chaos,
it prevents the perfect
opportunity to wipe them out.
Number six, make a sound in the
east then strike in the West.
In any battle,
the element of surprise can provide an
overwhelming advantage even when face to
face with an enemy.
Surprise can still be employed by
attacking where he least expects it.
The idea here is to get the enemy to
focus on his on one location and then
attack a weekly defendant spot in boxing.
Fainting is a body movement
or an incomplete attack
used primarily to create a
certain reaction from the opponent.
The idea is to create an opening or draw
the opening into responding or draw the
opponent into responding so that you may
anticipate and counter with a prepared
attack.
In order for faints to be successful,
they must make the opponent believe
that a punch is a real thing coming.
So we've talked about that before.
You can't,
you can't do the weak attempt
at a submission as well.
With Andy, last night we've been having,
we've been having some wars
lately and last night he,
and it's funny and this is,
there's a whole,
there's a whole thing going on because
psychologically,
right,
if there's a timer on paying attention
to it psychologically and like I know how
much time I can survive
in certain situations,
so I might take a risk that
I know, hey, if I end up,
I'll take this risk right now there's,
there's,
there's a minute and 18 seconds left.
I'm going to take a risk.
The risk is going to take me 18 seconds.
If I make it great,
if I, if, if the risk pays off great,
we're going to be in a good spot.
If the risk doesn't pay off,
well then I've got,
it's going to take him 10 seconds to get.
Now I've got 50 seconds.
I know how long it's going to take.
The set some things at the time it was
good to go. You're going to be okay.
Last night it was close, close, close.
I'd play the game of risk. Took a risk.
They didn't pay, you know, going off.
Yeah we were going, they took
the risk, didn't pay off,
ended up in a bad situation and,
and he was straightening out my arm
and,
and I got out of the arm lock and he
slapped a triangle on me and I'm hard to
triangle too cause I'm just like large.
Right? He slapped a triangle on me.
If you do get the triangle on me, it's
going to be pretty deep. Now it's,
and I was like, it was literally
that was thinking of myself. He's,
he doesn't have time to finish this.
He does not even like,
I don't even have to defend this right
now because he doesn't have time to
finish it. So he slapped it on there. I
didn't even defend. And then I was like,
oh no,
this thing is tight, tight,
and then the bell rang.
I laughed because it's not,
it happens all the time. Yeah.
That timer thing is like,
that's a real thing.
You can almost physically feel the time,
but here's,
here's the thing is if there's no timer,
if we don't have a clock running,
my game is different yet I won't
take that risk. I'll super patient.
Super. You know, sarge
used to joke about it.
Sergeant be like,
oh,
Jocko was going to hang onto your arm and
work that arm with not moving for like
seven minutes. He's going to say he's
hanging out. This is all good with me.
I'm over here just, I'm just,
I'm just cruising. I got your,
I'm not letting go of it. That's not
happening. I'm going to sit here.
I didn't know that. You have a little
bit, you're using some strength.
You're using a little bit
to just maintain. Yup. I'm
going to let that happen.
I'm going to let you cook. I'm going
to cook me a little bit, but you see,
you could cook stuff in five
minutes. Right? You know,
it's hard to cook something
in five minutes. It's true.
Well yeah, that is true.
Generally speaking, that tie
like, you know, it's a different,
the difference between,
you know how like some roles you'll go
against the wall or something, you know,
you just, and you go against a wall
and then sometimes you're like, hey,
we're by the wall in the corner or
whatever. So let's go to the middle.
Or sometimes you know, depending on
who your role with what the tempo,
what the mood is. He just
no walls fair. All good.
So that's what the timer kind of is to,
you know, or that's what it feels like.
You can almost feel it where it's like,
okay, the tenant, when the time goes off,
the time is game. This is all part of
the game now. But if there's no time,
it's kind of like, it doesn't
have that. So you kind of have,
I have more fun role and with Andy
when we do, when we have the timer,
because that means every three minutes
I'm taking a risk and I'm trying to make
something happen. Or, or if he's in a
dominant position, which he, you know,
he gets him really dominant positions
and he's really good at maintaining them
and he tries to get it done in that time.
Otherwise he'd be cooking me for a longer
time, I guess. Which would not be fun.
No. So I should say that could
be all right. Next section.
Stratagems for opportunistic situations,
create something from nothing.
Make somebody believe there was something
when there was in fact nothing or
simply put lie.
One method of using this strategy,
Mr. Creating an illusion
of something's existence,
when in fact it does not exist.
Another is to create an illusion that
something does not exist when it in fact
us pretty obvious. You know, it's
a good thing to think about it.
Like even if you're of the attitude
that you don't want to lie,
it's good to know these stratagems that
other people can use them on you. Yeah,
fully. And the lie, I mean that seems
like a conceptual life. Like, you know,
you know the guy who gets
fired up and puts the,
puts on this huge display isn't
that sort of ally, you know,
ferocious and crazy.
And then it's kind of usually
just to cover up something
else. Yeah, that's true.
Or if you get, like, if you're going
to spend just a moment in time,
Sam Harrison,
Jordan Peterson just dropped in here and
started having a discussion about what
was the line,
what was,
I'm sure that would just take this
whole thing to a different place.
Well,
I'm sure the first thing they would do
is determine what is considered a lie.
Conceptually, it's like any, any
deception really. Yeah, yeah, that's true.
So like look, if me and
you are in a, I dunno,
MMA fight or something and my
ankle is straight up sprained,
I'm not going to show it.
You know,
like my natural inclination
is to limp on that thing.
But I'm going to go out of my way
to just show that I'm not, you know,
it's no factor. Is that a lot? Yeah. Yeah,
it is right here. Yeah. I'm
in fact injured. I met there.
I bet we're going to get people that
are like, no, I lie is technically no.
There's probably some technical
definition that's puts it beyond just a
deception. Yeah. That's my guess.
Intentional deception.
It's weird cause here's the deal.
We know what Elias.
Yeah, we know what Elias,
we know what it is. We know what is
the line? What is it? I Dunno man.
There's that gray area. I'm telling you
there's that gray area. Check small,
but yeah.
All right.
We will not have a discussion about that
next.
Openly repair the gallery roads but
sneak through the passage of Chin gang
deceive the enemy.
We've been obvious approach that we'll
take a very long time while surprising
and by taking a shortcut and
sneaking upon him the clock.
Just classic fundamental strategy.
Next,
I like this one.
Watch the fires burning across the river.
Delay the delay entering the field of
battle until all the players have become
exhausted,
fighting amongst themselves at that point.
Go in at full strength and
pick up the pieces. When was,
this is exactly remember that the person
that just asked on the last podcast
about how to stop getting interrupted.
This is what we're talking about dude,
that right there and let other people
like to have their conversation and fire
their ammunition and then when they're
done fighting amongst themselves and
they're exhausted going at full
strength and pick up the pieces.
When a serious conflict breaks
out within the enemy alliance,
all you have to do is be patient and
wait quietly for the chaos to build up
because of once this internal conflict
intensifies than self destruction will be
the outcome besides the patient,
besides being patient,
make preparations for any advantage
that might come out of the chaos.
So sometimes you just got to sit across
the river and watch the fires burn for a
little while. And it's interesting
because that's exactly what that is
cause you're compelled to
interrupt back then all this stuff.
But it's good to sit back and
remember that the fires burn light,
the fires burn number 10
yeah,
hide a knife behind a smile
charm and ingratiate
yourself with your enemy.
And then when you have gained his trust
to move against him and secrets sons,
who's it most often quoted advice,
was to keep your friends
close and your enemies closer.
But here the stratagem
is far more duplicitous.
Okay.
In that it advises that the sole purpose
of keeping your enemy close is not just
to understand them and be prepared
for any aggression from them,
but is to deceive them with a treasonable
act that would see their downfall,
hide behind a knife for the smart.
So I was having a conversation with a
guy the other day and the question is,
if you've run something up the chain
of command to the absolute top,
you can't bring it up anymore.
And actually this was a person
in the fire services. If you've
brought something so far, departments,
if you brought something up the chain
of command to the absolute top and you
still haven't gotten what you wanted,
what would you do?
Then they were asking me and I was like,
well,
there's some a lot of things you
could do that in that situation,
you know you've got less because the,
the,
the topic was basically if
training should be harder, right?
If people aren't training harder and I'm
bringing it up the chain of command and
people say, no, it's fine.
No, it's fine. No, it's fine,
and you believe that the strong,
that people should be training hard
so we're more prepared to do our job.
What would you do? Then Jocko, and I was
like, well, you know, you, while you cook,
you know what you could do. You could
say, okay, you know what you don't want.
Listen to me. Fine. I'm going public.
I'm going to write an article in the
newspaper about how our department is not
prepared to handle emergencies.
That's what I'm going to do. Okay?
And then they're going to listen.
Okay,
now let's think about that. Let's
think about that outcome, right?
The outcome is there's a
decent chance you get fired.
You definitely aren't getting promoted,
you.
And so whether you get fired
or you don't get promoted,
you get stuck in this position where
you have no influence on. By the way,
did you get any check training change,
know now could there,
is there a possibility that
the public takes note and goes,
Oh wow,
this is wrong and we're going to,
we're going to have another election and
we're going to replace this fire chief
or whatever. Is there a chance that
could happen? There's a chance,
how'd that fire chief end up in
that position? He's a political guy.
He knows how to make things happen.
He knows how to take care of himself.
And if you think he's gonna let some
little article out in the newspaper,
get him deposed from his position,
you're wrong.
You're under Matt estimating your,
your enemy at this point. Yeah,
so don't do that. So I said,
what if instead of doing that,
you wrote let's say same idea you a
positive article about the fire department
and it made everyone look good and
the chief looked at you like you were
spreading the good word. And he
says, oh, well, you know what?
I appreciate you putting up that article.
That was really good.
It made us look good. He mastered that
part music. I liked your article. Well,
you know,
chief,
I just want to let people know what
we're doing over here and now you're
building trust. You're building trust with
him and now he says, Oh, you know what?
Yeah, you, you know what? You
should run this thing over here.
Once you run that little thing and you
take that thing and you run it and you
keep it in the box that you know he
would like it in and then he goes, hey,
you know you did a good job with that.
I'm going to get you
up a little bit higher.
And eventually you get to a position of
influence where you actually can make
the change that you want to make.
Now again,
the thing is when I say things like this,
people are always,
they don't want to hear it.
Like when, when when someone,
they think they know me and
they're like, oh, you know what?
And I was saying this the other day at
a different company that everybody wants
me to say, you know what you're going
to do when a situation like that,
you come in with a battle ax and you
start swinging and you take out everyone
that's in your way.
That's how you win,
and I wished that that was true, but
it's actually not true. It's not true.
You don't win. You don't win when
you do that. Yeah. You have to think.
You have to play the game. What you have
to do is hide a knife. Gone to smile.
Now that's, that's very true.
Treasonous. He calls it,
but if your goal, if your goal,
let's take the fire department.
If your goal is to actually do a better
job and save more people's lives because
you've trained more and that's the knife
that you're trying to get out in the
end. Is that a bad thing? No,
it's actually a good thing.
You're not hiding the knife
behind a smile. You're hiding.
Save lives behind a smile.
That's what you're doing.
This takes tactical patients.
Yeah. Tactical patients.
That's a word people used to throw around
because they thought it sounded cool.
It does. It does. It's
a real thing though.
And if you don't have tactical patience
to play the, to win the long war,
it's a long war. Years.
They can take years.
This situation that they're talking to,
this fire guy the other day,
that situation could take
years to unfold years,
but,
and we've talked with,
if you just make a stink and cause
problems and run up the run your mouth and
cause all this, all this focus and
bring the spotlight to the bad areas,
guess what?
You're not even going to get,
you're not going to get moved up into
putting in a better position. Yeah.
So don't do that. Yeah. So crazy.
That's like a lot of times the advice
you'd give is literally the exact opposite
of what it feels like we should do.
And it's like you feel like, Hey,
I need to do this. I just need
to know how can you tell me how?
And you don't tell how you say,
hey wait, you need to do this. No,
you don't need to do that. You need to do
the exact opposite of that. You're like,
aw man,
it's not what you think you me up.
But um,
I will say through experience that your
answers tend to be right 100% the time.
Yeah. People a lot of times
you don't hear anyone.
When I was younger I didn't want to hear
them either. Yes, that part is true. Yeah,
for sure. When when I was younger
I was like screw that guy. Yeah.
What am I do cultivate a relationship
with this, this guy? Yeah. He's,
we know on sat,
you know there's a,
there's a military term onset tried.
I used to,
that used to be my staff used to be.
That used to be as bad as that was the
worst adjective I could use. I'd be like,
that guy's unsat
or you know,
whatever it was to gear people like well
how's that gear unsat cause you'd get
marked like on an inspection UNSAT,
which meant on satisfactory.
I need to bring that back man.
It's been awhile. But yeah,
Jeremy Cake not too used to always say
that sat on set cause you could have
sense to that was if you
were to say to me like,
oh how was that dinner last
night? Sat meaning it was, it was,
it was good. It was fine. I said
that they knew was that sat unset.
You have to put sat and on onset kind
of together for sat to make any sense
whatsoever. Naturally check. All right,
number 11 preserve the plum tree or sorry,
sacrifice the plum tree to
preserve the peach tree.
There are circumstances in
which you must sacrifice shirt,
short term objectives in order to
gain the desired longterm goal.
This is the scapegoat stratagem whereby
someone else suffers the consequences
and the so the rest do not pretty,
pretty straightforward. That one.
I think some of these strategies
that are straightforward,
what's good about hearing them is that
you recognize them because it might seem
obvious, but then you, when you're
doing it, you do it. You're like,
well I don't know. We
could and you say, oh wait,
you know what we're actually
doing? We're, we're,
we're sacrificing the plum
tree to spare the peach tree.
That's what we're gonna do right now.
Once you commit to that or
you understand it fully,
then you can execute it with
more authority. Yes. Was
she in the in the wild too?
Cause like if you have that, that
framework to stick to, you know like,
oh this is what we're going to do kind
of thing and all these other variables
happen on equity, you know, unplanned
stuff. But you have that to stick to it.
It makes it way more clear
to the commander's intent.
The commander's intent
is very clear and so on.
And we know what we're going to do.
That's what's going to happen. Number 12
okay.
Take the opportunity to pill for a goat,
a while carrying out your plans.
You need to be flexible enough to
take advantage of any opportunity that
presents itself however small
and avail yourself of any profit,
however slight. That's a
good one. I think it's,
I think it's important
to keep in mind though,
that you don't want to get
pulled off track, right?
You want to keep focused on your mission
and all of a sudden you can be running
around gathering up goats
while your real target escapes.
So let's not get too crazy with that
one. But again, let's keep it in mind.
Next section.
Strategy for attacking situations.
Number 13
stomp the grass to scare the snake.
Do something unnamed but spectacular to
provoke a response of the enemy there by
giving away his plans or position or
just taunt him. Do something unusual,
strange and unexpected as this will
arouse the enemy suspicion and disrupt us
thinking.
This is recon by fire.
Just fire some rounds and maybe the
enemy shoots back or you're not,
and now you know where they are.
Next,
borrow a corpse to resurrect the soul.
Take an institution,
a method or even an ideology that
has been forgotten or discarded and
appropriate it for your own purpose.
Revive something from the past by giving
it a new purpose or bring to life old
ideas,
customs or traditions and reinterpret
them for your to fit your purposes.
Here's,
here's an example is like Hitler,
he brought back,
he would bring back like old viking
symbols and route that route.
The Viking tradition like,
hey,
you're a viking where vikings and
they have like little symbols. That's,
that's exactly what it is and just
use that so then people have a deeper
connection with with this thing.
Yeah,
makes sense.
Next 15 entice the tiger to
leave it's mountain layer.
Never directly attack an opponent who's
advantages derived from its position.
Instead,
Laura him away from his position,
thus separating him from
his source of strength.
The strategy is based on the idea that
the tigers powerful only when it's in its
natural environment,
but if removed from that environment
becomes weaker and more vulnerable.
I don't know if a tiger is weak,
a not a good environment.
I think a tiger could still kill me
pretty quickly. Even in a city street,
maybe in the water he
couldn't. No, that's not true.
No personnel in Sri Lanka.
The Tigers would swim like
they would swim and pull fish,
get into boats and pull
fishermen to their death. Yeah.
How's that for a nightmare and
that's rough. That's again,
pretty clear. You know what? This isn't
Jujitsu. You get someone to play that,
not their game. Yeah. Oh, you got a good
guard. Cool. On the pole. Garland room,
or really well, why did you do to founded
yet again? It's you take a guy who's,
you know, what's the traditional
method of fighting? I'm a standup.
Throw punches and kicks. Adam.
Yeah, so Jujitsu, it's like, oh,
you take them out of the punching
and kicking situation to the ground.
No punches, no kicks and effective
boom. That's as you who shits. Yup.
You're not in your special place anymore.
This is,
this is an interesting one.
Number 16 in order to capture one minute,
let one must let loose cornered.
Pray will often mount a final
desperate attack to prevent this.
You let the enemy believe he
still has a chance for freedom,
his will to fight thus dampened
by his desire to escape.
When in the end the freedom is proven,
a false owed and the enemy's
morale will be defeated.
You surrender without a fight.
So we've, we've heard that one.
That's the golden bridge.
We just heard it from Frederick the great,
I think we also heard it from the Getty's.
They're saying,
give the people a little out. They see
that. They see that chance to escape.
I remember,
I think it was for Getty,
it's was saying did they would just leave
their weapons because they want to get
away so bad.
They just leave their weapons and,
and then you're just waiting for him.
Slaughter.
If an enemy has no way to retreat than
desperation will increase their bravery
and ferocity of their fight.
So you always offer them room for
retreat and in such a retreat there,
their morale will be low.
Next,
tossing out a brick to get a jade gem
bait someone by making him believe he
gained something or just make them react
to it and obtain something valuable
from him in return.
Pretty straight forward.
The real meaning is to attempt this to
tempt through the offering of something
useless in order to
gain something valuable.
It is a tactic that
utilizes baiting the enemy.
The point of this tack is to throw out
bait that does not seem like bait on the
other hand is important to have a keen
sense of judgment to ensure you do not
take the enemy's bait in return.
The ability to look past the immediate
gain and see the longterm cost is a
valuable skill.
So if you're in a leadership situation,
sometimes you hold the line,
you appear to hold the line on something,
and then you, then you let you let
it go. Right. You know, like like,
do you want to do something a certain way?
And I'm like, well [inaudible] I don't,
and it's something I don't care
about. Yeah. I hold the line.
I was going to give you a
nice victory at the end of it.
I didn't already know that, but yeah,
yeah. You feel like, oh yeah, I see.
I was right. You're happy. I made
it happen. Yeah. Make it happen.
I was able to convince [inaudible] to do.
I didn't care.
I'm not going to tell you that.
I was like, no, you know what?
That seems like a good design
for that t shirt that go with it.
Next,
defeat the enemy by capturing their chief.
If the enemy's army is strong but it's
but is allied to the commander only by
money, superstition or threats,
then take aim at the leader.
The commander falls,
the rest of the army will disperse
or come over to your side.
If however they are allied to the leader
through loyalty than beware the army
can continue to fight on after
his death out of vengeance.
That one's straight
forward,
but that is something that's very
important to recognize is is what kind of
loyalty the people that
you're going against. What
kind of loyalty do they have?
I work with businesses all the time.
There's businesses that established a
massively loyal employee base and the
people are their way. They are loyal.
They're not there for the money.
The money is like part of it, but they're
there because they want to be there.
Those companies and somebody,
somebody comes in and starts trying to
mess with those companies. Blood bath,
it is a blood bath.
Okay.
Now that's the, now we're getting
into stratagems when you are losing,
so things change a little bit.
Now we're on the losing side.
Number one is stratagem tragic
for confused situations.
This is a good one.
Remove the firewood from under the
pot if something must be destroyed,
destroyed the source.
The strength of the fire
determines whether the water
will boil and the strength
of the fire comes from the burning wood.
It may not be wise to confront
the boiling water directly,
but by taking the wood
from under cooking pot,
the boiling water will soon be cool.
In other words,
do not confront your
opponents strong points,
but instead remove the source
of his strength. Yeah, that's,
I don't know that I necessarily agree
with the last part there that not
attacking the strong points.
I think it's huge.
I would say watch out for
the volatile points and you,
you don't attack the things that can
do you damage like boiling water,
you attack something that's a little bit
detached and you go after the source.
I think what he's talking
about is like they call it,
it's a problem solving method.
If I'm not mistaken.
This to this direct in the systemic, oh
yeah, for sure. Yes you are correct. Yes.
Yeah. Attacked at the source.
Right. You know of these problems.
It's like you know the plant at home,
right?
You got a tree growing in the yard.
The leaves are turning Brown.
That's upon us not even fall. The
leaves turning Brown. You know what?
Paint those leaves green.
That's the worst. Yeah, exactly.
That's attacking the boy
and that's a direct, yeah,
that's a direct problem solving
approach or or I always say water.
The leaves don't want her to leave.
You don't want it to leave your water,
the roots and then over time. That's a
systemic approach. That's the one. Yeah.
Kind. You roll deep. Sure.
Next Dis.
Number 20 disturb the
water and catch a fish.
Create confusion and use this
confusion to further your own goals.
Originally it means to stir the water,
the sediments in order to cloud the Ver
the vision of the fish and therefore
catch the fish here.
It means to create confusion so that
the enemy does not know what is real and
what is not. A confused enemy is
more vulnerable to any attack. I was,
I was rolling with Taylor the
other day. Sure. And we were doing,
we were standing up,
you know when we are getting after it
and tailors flows you that don't know.
Taylor is a beast.
He's and he's like barely human.
He's a beast and he wrestled and he does
Jujitsu and he's just sick grappler and
fighter by the way. No one will
fight him, which really makes me mad.
He's like he will fight anyone
and no one will fight him.
He just keeps destroying people.
No one wants to fight him cause you
get nothing out of it. Cause he's not,
he doesn't, his record is new. I
think he's three and oh right now.
So you wouldn't, if you beat a three
no fighter, that means nothing.
If you lose two or three in o fighter
you that that's not good for you.
No one smart is going to
take a fight with him.
I'm probably not helping by
saying this right now. Yeah,
not anybody that's hearing this is like,
okay well that's one person
I'm not going to fight.
My point in this was we were,
we were doing take downs or we had
gotten to a point where we're doing take
downs and he must've thrown 87 fakes it
me in like three seconds where I was,
I had no idea what was
happening cause I puff.
So he definitely disturbed the water,
caught the fish
that used to happen with Sarge Sarge,
who's an awesome restaurant
and Jujitsu and if,
if he hadn't been doing much
wrestling he would, he would,
I could read that he's going to come
because he's just got a sick blast.
Double like sergeants, blast
doubles, just sick and,
and he just comes in full power
and it's just hard to stop. But
if he hasn't been wrestling, he
really, he knows he can just,
he just goes into like, okay,
I'm gonna hit up last double.
Like I'm tired of
playing around and stuff.
And so he gets that look on
his face and I could read it,
cause I know him for 25 years and he'd
get the blast, double look on his face.
I remember one time,
you know,
I must've sprawled on him like
two or three times in a day. And,
and it was,
it was kind of,
I could see he was a little bit
surprised that he wasn't dead.
He didn't take me down. And
I was like, yeah. So I told
him, I said, hey, you know,
when you haven't wrestled for awhile,
you don't set it up, you just do it.
And then we wrestled again
and he'd set up again,
just 47 little touches my
face to pull my arbitrary,
donate to this here pushed me there,
drag this good slap here, boom.
And all of a sudden here comes the blast
off of which I didn't know was coming.
That makes a big difference.
Yeah. Get them waters blurred up.
Yup.
Alright.
Hmm.
Sluff off the CICADAS.
Golden Shell.
Cicadas like a cricket or
like a grasshopper. Mm.
This stratagem is mainly used to
escape from an enemy of superior force.
Mask yourself by either leaving
you're flamboyant traits behind,
thus going incognito or just masquerade
yourself and create an illusion to fit
your goals of distract others.
So the grasshoppers,
crickets at some point in their,
what's it called, the lifecycle,
like spam lifecycle. Sure.
Yeah. They, they basically,
their skin, whatever it is,
they're shell. Yeah. They have
to, they get rid of it. They molt.
Yeah. They get rid of it.
Yeah. Well you can do that too.
Yeah. You can leave some stuff behind them
if people think that's still going on,
but really you're escaping. Yeah. When
a cricket has grown to a certain stage,
it's sheds its outer shell and leaves the
empty shell behind this empty shell is
often mistaken for our wheel cricket.
Yeah. It's kind of like on total recall,
remember total recall the movie Arnold
Schwarzenegger? I don't remember what,
I don't fully remember it.
Yeah. So, oh yeah, yeah, yeah.
He comes in as that woman? Yeah. Well,
yes. Okay. Oh yeah, there's that part too.
Yeah, they the lady. Yeah, two
weeks. Right. Then it malfunctions,
throws the head and it's an explosion.
I was thinking more like the Hologram.
They always, they had this hologram
thing where it's like, oh, you know,
it's him, but it's just the
Hologram. Meanwhile, he's,
I think escaping for something like this.
I went and saw when I was in college,
I had to go see a Shakespeare play,
which was cool. I'm down with that.
I would bring my Shakespeare
book to the place.
I had my notes when I was there and it
was funny because after the play was
over, they went, they like
brought out the cast and was,
you know,
kind of introducing them with some details
about their career and the woman that
played that woman,
that head came apart and Arnold
Schwarzenegger was inside her.
She was in the Shakespeare play and
here she was just getting off stage from
crushing some Shakespeare and I think it
was Richard the third and the highlight
that they pointed out of her whole career.
It was that she was like the woman in the
Arnold Schwarzenegger movie whose head
came apart and total recall. That was
actually, and then then it was in,
in the pamphlet that they give
you when you go to the play.
It was telling this guy
did this and this guy was,
it has been in this and this guy
was in the royal listen, you know,
and then it's got her and it says
she played the woman in total recall.
Yeah, but here's the thing
about that, like on paper,
literally on paper that
doesn't, that sounds like, oh,
this little thing, but bro,
that was a huge part of the
movie. Let's face it, two weeks,
how long are you going to be on Mars?
Two weeks. And it's like, whatever.
Do you have any vegetables or something
like that. And then she goes two weeks.
Oh Dang. Thing starts malfunctioning.
Boom, boom. They identify them.
Emmett's big part of the movie. Bigger
than Shakespeare. Arguably. Yeah, no.
All right. This is one is a little bit
of a contradiction. Listen to this one.
Number 20 to shut the door to catch
the thief, to capture the enemy.
You must plan prudently
if you want to succeed,
do not rush into action before you move
in for the kill first caught off your
enemy's escape routes and caught off any
routes through which outside help can
reach them.
So that is the opposite
of having a golden bridge,
having an escape route that your people
can get out of. So you've got to,
if you've got a note, does that
mean now they're both in valid? No,
actually to me it means they're both
valid. But you need to recognize,
because for instance,
let's say you're in a situation where you
surround the enemy and all of a sudden
they start fighting really
hard cause you're like, Hey,
I'm going to fall 22 I'm going to,
I'm going to surround,
everyone are going to
keep them locked in there.
You do that and they start fighting really
hard and you're losing a lot of guys
that you know, hey, open up a
little spot for him to escape. Yeah.
And let him run away and we'll be
waiting for him over here. Yeah.
So just because things
are opposites do not,
does not mean they negate each other.
Yeah. It's one of those deals where,
you know, it's circumstantial, right?
Like in Jujitsu it's like, Oh yeah,
does this scenario, you know,
going against this guy, does this,
uh,
should I use strength and power
and should I hustle a lot?
We'll that strategy work with
this guy or is it like, okay,
I should play more passive or
something like that. No, that's true.
And actually to get even more
tactical and Jujitsu, you could,
you could,
let's say you mount someone
and they started just getting
crazy cause they don't
want to take a good getting completely
nuts and you're trying to choke him,
try to choke because you've got every day
and they're getting nuts and you can't
do it if you open a little spot for them
where they think they can sneak out.
But you're waiting for him there with
the arm lock. Yeah. Yeah. Get the W.
Yeah, actually, yeah. That is really
how it kind of works. Where, yeah,
when you get mountain you
want to hold position.
I mean as far as traditional to do
through, for lack of better term,
you get mount, you want to
hold the position right?
Don't want to lose position.
You can get flipped over, but if you can
hold them out, good. But if he's big,
strong, the starts, you know that
last desperation attempt, boom,
you got to kind of let them
hopefully turns over. Really,
that's usually what they do. If they don't
have the experience and then boom, you,
you, so you essentially give
up the mountain, but, but
you get it. Even he was like,
if you talk about a big strong guy,
that's your more experienced,
even just you could prevent them
from pushing you up in a way,
right?
You could block that door down when
there's no escape or you could let them do
it a little bit. You can have that little
thing and then boom. Yeah, arm locked.
Just whatever's better for the
peds situation. Sure. Next,
befriend a distant state
while attacking a neighbor.
It is known that nations that border
each other become enemies while nation
separated by distance.
Next number 23 be friend,
a distant state.
While attacking a neighbor,
it is known that nations that
border each other become enemies.
While nation separated by distance
and obstacles make better allies.
When you are the strongest in one field,
your greatest threat is from the
second strongest in your field,
not the strongest from another field.
That's a, that's a good
thing to think about. Hmm.
That's a good thing to think about.
When you were the strongest in one field,
your greatest threat threat is from the
straw second strongest in your field.
That makes sense. See that business
all the time, right? The, the, the,
the company that makes pizzas isn't
worried about the company that makes cars.
Yeah, that's true. Right?
They're more about the other
companies that make pizzas.
Nope.
Next 24
okay.
Obtain safe passage to
conquer the state of Gill.
Gail is a state.
Borrow the resources of an
ally to attack a common enemy.
Once the enemy is defeated,
use those resources to turn on the allied
that lent you them in the first place.
That's under handed situation right there.
It's underhanded situation right
there, isn't it? Yeah, it's bad. Yeah.
Careful with that one.
But you can see it now.
It's something you gotta watch out for.
Well, if that's your enemy to begin with,
I'm assuming, yeah, that fits
your enemies to begin with,
but if how much of your
enemy is going to help you,
they help you and then you
just turn this down the track.
Got To be careful of that. I think that's
the definition of backstabbing. Yeah.
Okay.
Yeah, that might be the day. That is the
actual definition. All right. Next one.
Stratagems for deception situations.
Number 25 replaced the
beams with rotten timbers.
Disrupt the enemies formations, interfere
with their methods of operations,
changed the rules which they are used
to following and go contrary to their
standard training. That's all
really good stuff. In this way,
you remove the supporting pillar,
the common link that makes a group
of men and effective fighting force.
This goes back to what you just said.
I mean,
it's clearly go away from what they're
used to, right? That's what we do.
That's what Jujitsu was supposed to
be. Everyone's going to, like you said,
they're going to stand and try and
punch you. We're not going to do that.
We want to take them down to the ground.
Next 26 point at the mulberry tree while
cursing the locust tree to discipline,
control or warn others who status,
position or status or position excludes
them from direct conversation or
confrontation.
Use analogy and Innuendo.
When names are not used directly,
those accused cannot retaliate without
revealing their complicity. Oh,
well that's sneaky.
You know,
that's like when you're in the meeting
and there's the person up the chain of
command they haven't been showing up
on and you start saying, you know,
we got people,
you'll bill hasn't been on time and
you're really talking about them.
I have to use this sometimes
have to use it sometime because we will
work with companies and the company,
let's say, let's say the CEO
brings us into the company.
Sometimes we figured out that the CEO is
the one that's the root of the problem
and one of the reasons that they're,
the root of the problem is because they
don't think they need to change anything.
And so they bring us in to change
everyone else. Guess who needs change?
The big man,
the big man,
the reason that they don't want to
change is because they got the ego that
prevents them from listening.
So to go in and directly confront them
on what they need to change is not going
to be effective. So to go
in and give, I've given,
I've given a whole presentation,
I did this one time where I gave a whole
presentation and maybe I've done it
more times, but there's one time
that I specifically remember,
I gave a whole presentation to,
you know,
the 15 people, the senior
executive leadership of a company.
The entire presentation was
directed at one person, the CEO,
and I was going, it was about
ego. It was about, you know,
keeping that in check and how you don't
know everything and how you got to let
your listen to your subordinates
and all those things.
He wasn't doing any of those things.
So isn't there like a basic tactic that
I think people do all the time instead
of, you know, like I'm the boss and I'm
holding the company meeting and whatever.
And, and you know, let's say there's one
guy who always shows up late to work,
I dunno. And in the meeting
he'll be like, hey guys, we've,
we've got to show up on time.
It's very important,
but just the very use of the word
wheat rather than pointing at one guy,
you know, we got to show up
at the time we got to do this.
It's kind of like the person
who is who he's talking about,
Kinda like he feels it. Yeah.
That's a good way to start.
There's some people that even
when they're not part of that we,
and so sometimes you have to
escalate that to you. Yeah.
But that defeats the purpose of that.
And it's defeated. You can, if you,
if the strategy doesn't work,
you might have to escalate into something
a little bit more direct, you know,
break out the battleax.
Yeah.
That's always the last option is just
to make sure everyone wants to break out
the battle ax. That's what
everybody wants to do next.
27 feign madness.
But keep your balance,
hide behind the mask of a fool,
a drunk or a madman,
to create confusion about your
intentions and motivations.
Lor Your opponent into under estimating
your ability until overcompensate
overconfident. He drops his
guard, then you may attack. Yeah,
that like the movie white men can't jump.
You ever see that?
So he did it woody. Oh, and he
made it like he couldn't play ball.
Like he was just this Dork Geek,
what do you call a chump, whatever.
That's what they'd call him chump.
Like he's Super Dorky.
He goes and everyone else
is just so cool and boom,
flashy and all this stuff. He comes in,
he's a super nerdy and you know, boom.
Of course they pay a cam, you know,
kind of thing. And then he beats him.
Would he beat them with flashiness or
would he beat them with, with traditional,
let's call it just who's your
style? Hardworking. Yeah.
Well no, he had legitimate
skill. He was like this. So yeah,
he'd come in, he'd be
Super Dorky. And then, um,
at first he tricked them.
So he came in the introduction to him.
He was like the acting all Dorky. And
then the guys, the Wesley snipes in them,
they're all playing basketball
and they're, you know,
get into little arguments or whatever
won't guy gets hurt or is Bunyan on it or
something. And they're like, hey, we need
another guy. And then the guy who's like,
you know, let's, you know, get
him or whatever. So they're
like, Hahaha. You know?
Yeah, you got him. Whatever they
play, he ends up to be pretty good,
doesn't show a lot, but he's like pretty
solid. And then they're like, hey,
you guys lucked out. You had this
Dorky guy, you guys kind of lucked out.
And he's like, Oh yeah, you
know, maybe you did look up,
or maybe I'm just better than you,
but they're already convinced he's the
stork you got in there and I cough.
I'm better than you. He was like, all
right, well, it's been kind of thing.
They're already convinced.
Bull Shark consist scenario.
Yeah, yeah, exactly right.
Same exact thing. Yeah. Yeah.
That's pretty obvious one.
And I think,
I think one thing that,
again to take away from this
is if you know these things,
you're less likely to be suckered
in by them. Yeah, that's,
that's the most important thing. Yeah.
That you see the pool shark thing,
I saw a guy who really
clumsily tried to do that.
He'd worked in night club,
we had a pool table in there and this
guy came in and he like acts like he's
like, he comes in and just a normal
guy, he comes in with his own key.
Oh by the way, his own pool
stick, which is an indicator.
Yeah. Like total giveaway. And he didn't,
comes in and then immediately when like
he kind of enters the little scene,
you know,
the little area where the pool,
he acts like he's just kind of drunk
and just real oblivious, you know,
he just total just switches to a
different guy. And here's the thing, we,
you can't let drunk people walking
around in the bar. So you know,
when waitresses or other, or the manager
would come by and they'd be like, Hey,
is that guy that guy's to junk? Like, why
are you kind of like keep an eye on him?
And I'm like [inaudible], he's
not drunk. He's like acting drunk.
So I go talk to them just
to sort of make sure.
And he was just like all normal talking
to me. I'm like, no man. But yeah,
he tried no one. I mean it wasn't
like no one to get my phone.
He wouldn't get money from anyone.
Well, here's the thing. No,
because it was like a nightclub.
It wasn't a competitive pool hall.
No one cares. No one's going
to take is, no one's even
gonna bet. They're like, Bro,
we're just cruising. I'm like, why are
you, you know, wanting to bet kind of.
I'm not saying that happened,
but I'm saying that's the,
I guess in this day and age you'd have
to be pretty dumb to fall for this.
Anyone who will haul
scenario to beat this guy,
you got to really think you
can beat them. Right. Otherwise
you'd just be dumb. Alright, next,
remove the ladder.
When the enemy has ascended to the roof.
This is another one that kind of is a
little bit contradictory with Bates and
deceptions. Laura, your
enemy into treasures.
Treacherous terrain then caught off his
lines of communication and avenue of
escape to save himself.
He must fight both your own forces
and the elements of nature. Okay,
I see what makes a little bit different.
It's the elements of nature partner.
Yeah,
because otherwise we're
just doing something that
we talked about wasn't good,
which is don't give them any escape.
Then they're going to fight really hard,
but if you put them in a situation
where they've got to fight to both the
elements of nature and you,
that makes sense.
Okay.
29 deck the tree with false blossoms.
Tying silk blossoms on a dead tree gives
the illusion that the tree is healthy
through the use of artifice and disguise.
Make something of no value,
appear valuable of no threat.
Appear dangerous of no use a peer useful.
Pretty straightforward.
Yeah.
No. Who does a lot of that
stilts and your role with stilts?
He like Bates, he puts his
arms, he's super flexible. Yes.
And he'll put his arm way over there
and it'll be all obvious. I've,
I've tried to tell him
stilts when you hear this,
if you backed off your,
your exposure a little bit, it'd
be more believable. Yeah. Right.
Cause it smell real.
It doesn't smell real easily.
He liked taps the ground with his
arm but he sticks it all out there.
Like any bends it enough.
So it's almost an a perfect camera like
we're going to do is go for this but
he's so flexible. If you go for
it, he's going to off balance.
He's going to put his hooks in cause
he's six foot something like six foot six
year and super flexible.
You ever think with him,
I don't know if this is the case or not.
We ever think cause I think there's every
once in a while where he's overdoing
it because he's trying, you know it's
like a like a charades. You're right.
That might be part of it. Yeah. You know,
he's over doing that so
much that you don't do it.
Cause I'd actually actually you're right,
we've had that conversation.
He's told me before that sometimes he
would stick something out cause he knew I
had it so good that if you just tried to
make it look so obviously I wouldn't go
for it. He was right.
He's actually correct.
There's a lot of times when I see him
do something like I am suspect with
everything he does, everything
he does, I'm suspect. Yup.
Any 200% like you think you're going
to pass the guard. He's going to,
he's got some little scam
going. Yeah. He's trying to
trick you. Yep. So be careful.
Number 30 some scam scam.
It's going to stab you in the door.
Make the host and the
guest exchange roles.
You serp leadership in a situation
where you are normally subordinate.
Infiltrate your target initially.
Pretend to be a guest to be accepted
but develop from inside and become the
owner later. Tell it's
the same, same, same
hair already talked about with
the fire department scenario
because that method is a lot better than
the method of battleaxe cause you won't
even make it through the front door
if you're holding an ax. Right.
Then I'm gonna let you in.
They're actually,
the more I kind of listened
to you kind of is the,
the battle ax approach.
Really. Most of the time,
all that does is create another war.
He just basically took one war
and made another war in there.
Now you got two major wars, by the
way, that's, it seems to be the result,
you know, just to give
everyone a little bit of relief
where the battle ax is appropriate,
a hundred percent appropriate is
with yourself and your own life.
You know what I mean?
That's the difference. That
doesn't give anybody relief.
Yeah, it does. Because you can use that.
You want to use it, you want to use it,
but you gotta use it on yourself,
not on herself. I want, Oh,
you're saying people don't
want you to at yourself.
How do you going to fix yourself? You
fix it. All right, well listen, I mean,
we'll get that weakness
and no real. Let's see.
That's the exact thing I'm
talking about with you,
because the strange thing is that the
other methodology doesn't work with
yourself. If you're like negotiating
with Chris [inaudible]. You know what,
I'm not really that way. He can. I'm
going to play the long game with myself.
I'm just one donut. Not that big of a
deal. I mean really, I don't know. Nope,
don't do that. Battleaxe
yeah, see, so that yet again,
it goes along with your whole thing where
I don't want to hear that when I say I
want to bring up the battle
ax fright jungle. Right.
You want it to be for everyone
else causing the problems.
But that's not the way it works.
Only can use the battleax on yourself.
That's where you use it.
And when you do that,
what you do is you do solve the problem.
It's the actual, so what's interesting,
there's a dichotomy here I tell
people with, with everyone else,
don't use the battle ax. That's
where they want to use the battle ax.
They don't want to use the
battleax on themselves.
But that's where I tell him
to use the battleax. Yeah,
it's a strange world fair that rights
are out. Life gets a lot easier.
It's harder at first, but he
ends up easier. But yeah, it's,
it's so 1000 million percent can something
be a thousand million percent? Surely,
but if it could be one of the one
of those things and it's yet again,
one of your things where it's like,
Hey Jocko, I'm trying to do this.
I need to do this. Tell me the
best way to do it, and your,
and your answer isn't okay. This is
how you do this better. It's, hey,
you don't want to do that. You
want to do this. Oh, by the way,
that's the exact opposite of
what you think you need to do.
That's your whole thing. Same exact thing
with your battle ax analogy. I'm like,
Hey, I need to take a battle ax to
my boss, man. He just doesn't get it.
All this stuff and you're like,
Oh yeah, oh no, you don't.
You actually have to take the battleax
yourself. That's your whole thing.
Yes it is. Yeah, because if you
take the battle ax your boss,
so you're going to get hit,
you create another war to
yourself and you cut off the
the hostility.
You smash the d,
The hostility that you
have towards your boss.
If you use the battleax on that hostility
and you start treating them with
respect and trying to
build a relationship, guess
what? You're going to win.
If you use the battle ox on him,
he's going to break out a
bigger battle ax and guess what?
He has one because he's the boss.
He's got a much bigger battle ax.
Yes, he does, and technically isn't
that the whole watering the roots thing?
You know
the systemic problem solving. Start
with yourself. You know, that's,
that's definitely part of it.
That's part of it. In their
next stratagems for desperate situations,
number 31 the beauty trap.
Send your enemy beautiful women
to cause discord within his camp.
This strategy can work on three levels.
First,
the ruler becomes so enamored with the
beauty that he neglects his duties and
allows his vigilance to Wayne.
Second other males at court will begin
to display aggressive behavior that
inflames minor differences, hindering
cooperation and destroying morale.
Third other females at court motivated
by jealousy and envy begin to plot
intrigues further
exacerbating the situation.
This is also known as the honey trap.
The honey trap. They do that
on Rambo. First blood part too.
He had that. Remember that cohort, you
have them check him and he had a girl,
a Vietnamese girl, if I'm not mistaken,
and he meets her, her name is Ko.
Yeah.
So they go and they got to take down,
you know they got to say the Po adobes
and the girl disguises herself as I think
a Vietnamese prostitute if I'm not
mistaken on a moped. Honey trap. Yeah.
So they're like, oh, neglecting
their duties, all this
stuff. Boom. They come in.
But to add to the whole scenario,
she's like actual warrior either.
So it's like double layers and
you know she's getting after it,
getting totally getting after it.
Check number 32
the empty Fort Strategy when the enemy
is superior numbers in your situation is
such that you expect to be overrun that
any moment than drop all pretense of
military preparedness and act calmly so
that the enemy will think you're setting
an ambush.
The strategy is to be used sparingly
and only after one has first developed a
reputation for military prowess.
This also depends on having a clever
opponent who in proceeding the trap may
overthink his reaction.
Don't takes guts, but I guess
the the, it normally takes guts,
but you might not have any other choice.
Right?
Like you're choking your chances like,
okay,
we're just going to act
like this is no big deal.
Just going to act like
this is no big deal.
Who was telling me a story about that?
Maybe it was you or it was jade
about being an Australia where you're
telling me about that was that jade?
Possibly. What was the
store like? Oh yeah,
I was telling you going into the alley.
Yeah, I was telling you about jade story.
Okay. Yeah. Was that on the podcast
that you did that? I don't think so,
but the point is, jade had
a choice act like, okay,
so he sees a situation could be
hostile, and his choice was like, okay,
I don't really have a choice here.
I can either act scared,
in which case I'm going to
become a victim that's, that's,
or I can act nonchalant and there's
a possibility I don't become a victim
because they see that I'm like, whatever.
Right? And so that's what he did.
And guess what? The guy was like,
good. Hey Man. Oh good. Yeah.
Luckily we said Australia.
Next
33 let the enemy's own spy.
So discord in the enemy camp undermine
your enemy's ability to fight by secretly
causing discord between him and his
friends, allies, advisers, families,
commander soldiers in population.
While he is preoccupied in
settling internal disputes,
his ability to attack or
defend is compromised.
For some reason.
I have the word truth written here,
and I think the reason,
oh, this is what I have,
that this is why I have that there. I was
thinking to myself, how do you do this?
And the,
one of the best ways to sow discord
amongst people is to tell them the truth
about what's happening. How so? Well,
you've got some enemy camp and you
start, you start saying, hey look,
you should say, look how look
how the bosses living. God.
It's just pay attention to how the boss
of it, I'm just telling you the truth.
The truth is the boss eaten crab
legs every night. You guess what?
You're eating chicken patties. No, no, no.
So I was on the ship, I think it was the,
I think it was a u s as Cleveland,
and there was an underground
newspaper on the ship,
but there was basically leakers
that we're telling the troops,
the sailors on the ship,
what they were eating in the
wardroom where the officers were.
That word started getting
around to chicken patties.
Dryton chicken patties for 48 days
straight. You know what? No. Hey,
that's a lot of chicken patties.
You're not, you're not gonna,
you're not gonna want any
more chicken patties. No,
but then you get word that they're
eating crab legs. That was the big one.
I don't even like crab legs,
but everyone else seemed like crab legs.
They were mad when they found
out that's what the wardrobe.
So what they did was just
the just telling the truth.
Cause discord. Just tell him
the truth. Yeah, makes sense.
Now of course you could
weave in some lies, right?
But just I'm saying is oftentimes the
truth is the most powerful weapon.
Yeah.
To cause discord.
Now I'll always tell you that
truth is the most powerful weapon.
Definitely truth is the most
powerful weapon that you
have. Like just in general.
Just in general.
The truth is the most powerful
weapon you have for yourself.
Be truthful with yourself. If you can
be truthful with people around you.
Now does. Does this mean you
tell the truth every single time?
No,
because you,
sometimes the chicken is dry and you
just need to do that to yourself. Right?
That's a legit, why don't we talk
about that before, but truth,
truth is definitely the most powerful
tool that you have and even when it comes
to creating discord, the best, let me
put it to you this way. Let me just,
I don't want to go through this
whole tangent, but the best,
if you're going to create discord,
it's more powerful to create discord using
the truth than it is trying to create
discord because the lie can be unwound,
figured out the truth when they go,
well, no, that's not true,
and then you go, oh wait, that
is true as a real problem.
34 inflict injury on oneself to when the
enemy's trust pretending to be injured
has two possible
applications in the first.
The enemy's lulled into relaxing his
guard since he no longer considers you an
immediate threat.
The second is a way of ingratiating
yourself to your enemy by pretending the
energy the injury was
caused by a mutual enemy.
Build that little bit of trust.
Remember when I talked about,
remember when I talked about when you,
if you come to me and you're emotional,
you're all mad about something and I
have to to tamper down the emotion,
but I can't. I have to show you some
of the same emotion. I reflect it,
but I diminish it a little bit. Yeah.
That's a way of building trust between us.
Right? Well, it's the same
thing. If I'm, I called liquid,
you come and look what
they did to me and I go,
look what they did to me to say thing.
They wounded me to look at this.
I'm also mad at them. We're a team now.
I do that with my daughter, by the way.
What's a, when she, she
had a hangnail last night,
even hangnail and she didn't
know what a hang nail is.
I think it's her first hangnail
just five sad. It's sad.
All those hanging on.
What hangnails coming your way.
All those hangnail future for
a, so I'm like, yeah, I see.
Just little things. Yeah. That used to
happen to me when I was a little too,
so it's kind of like, oh, we both kind
of have that same scenario. Same thing,
dude. Mutual. Hey, mail, hatred. You know,
let's bring the team together
and uniting against hang nails.
I'm telling you it's real.
It's real name, ma'am.
I'm a hundred percent onboard.
Hanging rails are real.
I didn't know you had hangnails
man, when I have them too tight,
a little bit of bond.
35 chain stratagems in important matters,
one should use several stratagems applied
simultaneously after another as an a
chain of stratagems. Keep different
plans operating in an overall scheme.
However, in this manner,
if any one stratagem fails,
then the chain breaks and
the whole scheme fails.
Now I completely agree with the
first part of this, which is, yeah,
you should train these things together,
which is obviously what we do in Jujitsu.
You use one move in that
setting up another move,
which is setting up another move,
moving the defense. That one's,
that's another move, but I don't agree
with the fact that if one of them breaks,
they all the whole thing falls apart,
but that shouldn't be necessarily true.
You should set up your strategy gyms,
you're stratagems that you
expect that some of them are not,
are going to fail a little bit and
that's okay because that's why he got the
backup ones right. Am I wrong?
I don't think you're wrong. No.
And chaining things together.
That's you have to do that.
You have to hit from multiple angles
and you have to have, that's how,
that's the Ooda loop, right? That's okay,
I'm going to do this and then you're
going to react. I'm going to do this,
I'm gonna be there.
And when the next one there,
where the next one in there with the
next one having a heads up on things make
such a big difference.
In other words,
just so much of winning in Jujitsu is
that I know what you're gonna do before
you do it.
So much of winning in combat is I know
what you're going to do before you do it.
Setting these things up properly,
chaining them together so that the
enemy doesn't know the opponent,
doesn't know the next thing in
the chain, but you do. Yeah.
Yeah. I think he, that's powerful. Yeah,
I agree that it seems like you're
looking at it like the, the,
the chain of stratagems is like a totem
pole where it should be like a tree or
like a web or something where you can
kind of go and this can break off and,
but yeah,
his one is like,
like a straight up like actual chain
know one link breaks. It's like yes,
but true.
Last one,
number 36
if all else fails,
retreat,
important one.
If it becomes obvious that your current
course of action will lead to defeat,
then retreat and regroup
when you're aside is losing.
There are only three choices.
Remaining. Surrender,
compromise or escape.
Surrender is complete defeat.
We don't want that.
Compromise is half. Defeat
might be an okay outcome, especially
when compared to the alternative,
which is just surrender,
which is total defeat.
But escape is not defeat.
Hmm.
As long as you are not defeated,
you will still have a chance.
And I think that's a fitting end to this.
And again,
this is something that people
get wrapped around all the time.
They don't want to give up,
they don't want to give up.
They don't want to give up.
In skydiving,
you have a malfunction. If
you have a malfunction, you,
you try and fix it for a little while at
2000 feet. I think it was what
I learned in the military.
Free Fall
at 2000 feet, you make the decision, I'm
not going to get that parachute open.
I'm going to cut that one away.
I'm going to bring out my secondary.
But guys would, you know,
in the parachute world,
and right now the parachutes are getting
so good that it's, it's a lot more rare.
But guys would get target fixation on
trying to fix the bad parachute that was
up there and they'd look at it and look
at it and try and fix it and try and fix
it and try and fix it and try and fix
it. And then they, they did hit. So
sometimes you got to retreat.
It's okay.
Yeah,
it's okay. Surrender is complete.
Defeat. Compromise is half the feet,
but escape is not defeat it.
As long as you are not defeated,
you still have a chance. So retreating
is smart. Sometimes it's okay.
And I think that's a good lesson.
It's okay to retreat but never,
never surrender.
And that's that book,
which definitely some good lessons
in there running some new ones,
reinforced some other ones,
hoping that everyone out there listening
learned something from that too.
And if you did any want to
give the podcasts some support
Baja
and here's how you can do it and support
yourself by the way actually could be
the more important thing. I think so. Yes.
I think it's the more important thing.
Yeah man. Cause he yet
like on the plane, right?
You know the oxygen masks
since coming down real. Right.
You can't just start putting the mask on
your kid. No. What if you suffered Kate?
Yup. Can't help. Nobody knows
where it just help yourself first.
You can't support what we're doing here
if you're not on the path. Exactly right.
Yeah. That's the primary thing.
Yeah. That's what we're about
to begin.
Good way.
Let's start with the origin feeding name
for the way to begin the support and
get it. Origin layers in the industry,
we call it those layers. Anyway, origin.
This is what origins is
a American made company
that delivers American made
products starting with geese,
Jujitsu gies for Jujitsu,
not just generic gies name on it.
Yeah. Not that, no, not generic.
I'm telling you that that's aren't the
kind of geese where you'd be like, Hey,
you know what, I think I'm going to
go down to the market right now. Yeah.
I'm going to put on my g you don't,
you maybe if you're doing that you'd
maybe don't need an origin gay.
You get whatever you who
go down to the market.
But if you're doing Jujitsu with your g
yeah. We recommend you go with uh, the,
the origin g which is made in America,
which is awesome.
The cotton is grown. Yeah. It's
grown here. American hands.
People are working, people are working
in Maine. We're bringing that back.
So yeah. Get those and rash
guards as well. Yeah. Woven,
woven material here. Yeah, they kind
of got everything. They got, uh,
you know, regular clothes as well.
Joggers, sweat suits. [inaudible].
I was having a discussion,
which I'm not going to go into,
but I will go into this
part of the discussion.
I was in discussion with someone that
was like basically telling me like, well,
you know this, this business,
this business is hard.
What we do is hard in this business.
You're trying to tell me that what they
were doing in this business was hard.
I was like, Hey, it's not that hard
what you're doing and trust me, what
they're doing is not that hard. Trust me.
There's some businesses I work
with a lot of different businesses.
I'm complex businesses out there
in the world. Really Complex.
The business particularly that I was
talking to that was having this discussion
with, that was telling me how
hard their business was, which,
what does that sound like to you
when someone's like, Oh, you know,
it's really hard. That's an excuse.
Of course. Hey, if it was easy,
everyone would be doing it, right?
Yeah. You know, it's really hard.
This business is really hard and I
was like, you want to talk about hard?
I'm like tried getting an ancient loom
up and running and weaving material that
hasn't been done in 40 years.
Here in America we've,
there's 8 million little
threads going into this thing.
Try sorting that out. Telling me your
business is hard. Yeah, that seems hard.
That's hard. But it's being done
right here in America at origin.
Really good stuff on there.
Also supplements,
Jocko supplements,
joint warfare,
Krill oil and discipline and milk.
So consider these four.
They all kind of play into each other.
Joint Warfare,
obviously warfare against degeneration
of joints, not against your joints.
It's for the joints. It's your joint
sweet Jean War on degeneration anyway,
however you want to spin it. And then
the lessons for your joints. Krill oil,
same thing. Omega threes really
good for general health as well.
If you like protein supplements.
Moke see what I did there.
I didn't call it protein powder.
That's good. That's good.
It's a very understated too, which I'm
down with. You can not understate it.
Yeah cause the bottom line is if you
like delicious things in the world,
you're going to like milk.
So milk is peanut or not peanut butter.
It's good to be. It's about the
chocolate butter. Yeah, those are,
those are inbound.
Yeah.
Someone sent me a picture tweet,
I think it was on Twitter.
One had chocolate milk, jug
other hand milk. He said,
I'm going to take it for
the team to the experiment.
Remember I said mix the milk with
chocolate milk. Might be too chocolaty.
Might be he just said he's going to do it.
He didn't report that verdict.
That's kind of just indicated
he was commencing with the
experiment that's Kinda jacked up.
We will have mark at the immersion camp,
Jujitsu immersion camp,
August 26 through September 2nd
up in Maine on Echo Lake layers.
So come up and hang out with me with Lafe,
with echo,
with Dave Burke. Still
not 100% on JP, but yeah,
we're going to be up there in Maine
doing Jujitsu and hanging out.
Oh and D Dean lister. Oh yeah. No big
deal. The muster and Andy's going to,
it looks like Andy's going Burke.
Andy Burke's gonna be going.
So we will be all just training and
getting after it. And hanging out.
Here's the thing, it doesn't sound as
dealt when we were they hanging out.
But here's the thing.
It is ultimately cause you can learn.
You can only do Jujitsu. How many hours
a day can you do Jiu Jitsu? You know,
it depends on who you are. Obviously
call it eight. We'll call it eight.
So eight and eight. So eight hours.
Then you sleep for eight hours.
What does that leave you
ate more so more hours.
You got to fill those eight hours
I hanging out. That's eight hours.
Eight hours a crew. Could we cruising?
Cruising. Sorry. I'll be cooking big time.
If I'm not doing this.
You should actually,
so I'll be halfway in halfway out
because you've got the injury limited,
limited, limited, but we'll, we'll
just say limit anyway. Yes, yes.
August 26th to September 2nd.
Is it
also good way to support his go
to Jocko store.com that's right.
Chocolate is a store. It's
called Jocko store. Anyway,
it's where you can get tee shirts,
rash guards, hoodies, hats, you know,
all these stuff.
A products,
we'll say that we put out
discipline equals freedom shirts.
What's the new one? What did
I put on there that's new. Oh,
is there a new discipline equals
freedom shirt. Is that up yet? Yes,
it's not up yet. It will be up in a couple
of weeks. It'll be up in a couple of,
maybe even one week.
So it could be up technically by the time.
So it's so it's up. It's up, right?
It's cool. The new shirt is up. Yeah,
just one equals three new one. Um,
but yeah, if you want to represent,
go there Jocko. store.com. Use
the word represent. I like that.
There it is.
I think it's the new one is uh,
take the high ground or the high
ground. I'll take you. That's a fact.
Something like that. Shit. Unless if you,
um, actually where we email list, right.
And I don't really talk about this,
offer it and didn't want
it to be an annoying thing.
You know how sometimes
you go to a website,
it'll pop up in your face
and you can't like move,
you know,
I try not to because people want to,
they actually used the word they
want to capture. Capture. Yeah.
Capture your email.
Yeah. Technically, yeah.
I don't want to capture
when we're so out in you and
what is not in the game. Like
you, you just said like how,
I mean even your tone indicated how
you feel when a pop up with a form,
you know, comes in. It's
kind of like when you um,
like let's say you go on a first date
with someone and they give you like a
contract or something.
It's Kinda like, hey,
sign this before we can take any steps
forward with what we already plan.
We were doing, by the way anyway.
I know we do have an email list.
Like you can put your email and sign
up for the email list if you want.
And it's there.
It's accessible,
but I think it's on the bottom from
Nancy on the other website on the side
anyway.
It's there.
It will not be a pop up in
here and forever. No ever,
ever, ever. And furthermore,
if you sign up for that,
you won't get the daily,
Oh you know,
this and that and this and that and this
everyday because let's face it, Kay,
I signed up for,
I think it was bud k it's called,
it's like knives and stuff.
They're just cool. Nice.
So I signed up for that one and every
single day man, I'm getting the thing.
I'm like, cool. The first day
I'm like, cool, that's cool.
Second day I'm like, cool.
That's kind of the same thing as you sent
me yesterday, whatever. Daily man, daily.
So that feeling I got,
I don't want other people to have that
feeling about Jocko store. So anyway,
you can sign up for the
email list if you want.
And what I will send
you every four months,
if ever, I'll send you an
email that says like, okay,
if there's a new shirt
that everyone was required,
you know how like take the high road or
the high road of take you like people.
So many people were emailing me saying,
hey, we should do this one, do this,
should do. So it's kind of that, you
know, it's like everyone's input. Okay,
new shirt, boom on email and
everybody, okay, there's a new show.
It's like that kind of stuff and it's
very rare check. I don't want it.
You've got an input through it before too.
I remember one time you're asked for
color, right? Right. Yes. So yeah,
that kind of stuff. It won't
be annoying stuff like, hey,
three things that you don't
care about clicks, you know,
I won't do that stuff ever,
ever, ever check nonetheless.
That's what's going on Jocko. store.com
if you want to represent, get some stuff,
get some stuff, good way to support. We're
also subscribe to the podcast, this
podcast, iTunes, wherever, Google play,
stitcher,
leave reviews and all that stuff.
And also if you didn't know we
got the warrior kid podcast,
which yeah,
you might not think that you would
listen to it, but if you've got kids,
definitely they'll dig it and
good podcast to listen to.
Lately.
I've been,
lately I've been telling the stories from
uncle Jake from when uncle Jake was a
kid.
Uncle Jake is sharing stories
of his childhood that have
little lessons in them.
Big lesson, even big lessons and,
but, but they're not they're stories.
Yep.
And that's been kind of the direction the
last couple of podcasts have had a uh,
a story from uncle Jake story from
Uncle Jake that we can all learn from.
So that is the warrior kid podcast.
I answer some questions from for more
of your kids and then they're short too.
They're 20 minutes
because kids should not be sitting
around listening to a four hour podcasts.
We only do that cause we got to like
work to do commute and all that stuff.
Yard work. Yeah, it's good. It's
kind of good for the parent actually.
Really good for the parents
and teachers by the way. No,
I've gotten great feedback from parents
and teachers. Absolutely. You're awesome.
These quiz questions, the Q
and a questions, you know,
they send in and you
answer them eloquently.
I might add uncle Jack's pretty eloquent.
Yeah, I like to think so for sure.
Uh, but you know, in real life these,
these kids ask their parents these
questions or the teacher, you know,
and sometimes, you know,
maybe the teacher on the spot,
maybe he's busy or maybe they don't
know or something like that. So like,
you know, I, I see it, I
know that I do it for myself.
When I listened to him
I'm like, okay, boom.
Cause I've heard that question before and
these answers a little bit better than
mine. You know, Jack, uh,
also the youtube channel. Yeah.
We've got a youtube channel,
it's called Jocko podcast and that's
where echo puts the videos and the video
excerpts and enhanced video excerpts.
So you can check that out too, which
is cool. And Yeah, yeah, do that.
It's good. A good way to
support for sure. Subscribe to,
you already said iTunes and stuff,
Google play.
So that's a good way to start that
seemingly an easy obvious thing,
but it is a good way to
support legitimately check also
on it.com/jocko by the
way. Okay. What is on it?
We all know it on and it is,
but if you don't know,
it's where you can get
the best fitness gear.
It's where you get all mine.
Oh,
it's going to get a bag or
like the sandbag things. Yeah,
I got one. Okay. Yeah, they're
good. They're good. Yeah.
Like so it was,
I forget it was good for the
big functional strategy. Yeah.
Like you know how, um, do you know
what I've got to figure out though.
Remember that bag that they had
up in Maine, the 200 pound bag,
I got to figure out what the deal is
with that so I can rehearse. Actually,
it's pretty simple.
If you've got to make a game 10 10
adjustment to do it, you'd be like, okay,
this is mark. Depress it. No, just clean
it. Yeah. Put it over your shoulder.
You have to shoulder. Yeah.
Okay. So the thing is,
and I tell me if this is cheating.
Okay. So to lay out the scenario,
there's a 200 pound bag of gravel.
Not that's what it is. Yeah.
200 pounds, which is him.
No handles, no handles.
It's a sack of gravel,
not a canvas like made out of the either.
It's like nylon. Yeah. So it's real flowy.
200 pounds dead. You'd see dead
weight. It's extra dead weight anyway.
So then you got to just put it on
your shoulder. That's it. Pick it up,
pick it up off the ground, putting your
show. So tell me if this is cheating.
So I did it in a,
I succeeded but I try not the first time
I tried it once and I was like whoa.
And you know it falls down and
I'm like man. But uh, Mike,
one of the guys there, he said, hey,
when you lift it up first you got to keep
the weight on the forward part because
even when you lift it up,
it kind of divides the bag kind of
India because it flows, you know,
all the gravel kind of flows to the,
to the ends or whatever.
You got to divide it up.
But when you divide it up,
you got to keep more of the weight.
More on the, on the, on the front part,
not on the,
the part closer to you because it'll
just flow down and it just doesn't work.
His, his explanation way more short
than that. But um, so is that cheating?
So I was like, all right, I did it
and then I, and then it was easy. No,
it's not easy. Okay. So it's, yeah, it's
hard. Like if you practice or something,
it'll be easy course. I mean, you're
strong enough to do it for sure.
But the technique or some techniques
to get it up there. Yeah, it's, it's,
it's hard. But nonetheless, um,
the, my point was with the bag is,
you know how,
you know,
you lift a bunch of weights and
this guy and or me or whatever,
we can bench a lot, squat
a lot. But then, you know,
when you're doing like yard
work and you gotta I dunno,
shovel a bunch of dirty wheelbarrow and
you're picking it up and you're trying
to lift it up this little
hill and you're like,
well, the second your role with guys
that work construction, they have,
they have legit strength
that comes to the other side.
Exactly right. So I'm like, man,
I'll buy one of these bags and just sort
of like have it part of the workout,
you know,
do some hills or something with it.
But anyway, on it.com/ [inaudible] and
there's a lot of cool stuff on there.
Then he says,
and kettle bells and whatnot,
all kinds of good stuff. Uh, psychological
warfare album being get on iTunes,
Google play and be through.
We're working on the second one.
If you got something you want to
meet to address psychologically,
let me know now and I'll start putting
together a little list and we'll get it
into your brain psychologically.
Yep.
And speaking of which,
speaking of psychological,
how's this for a psychological right
here. Hold on. Here we go. This,
you know that is that right there?
That's Jocko white tea in a can.
You can get it.
You can get it at Amazon right now.
It's available in Canada
too and it tastes delicious,
which is fine. You want things, it tastes
good. That's good. It's good for you.
Replaced the crap that you drink,
the energy drinks that you drink.
Get rid of him. Get this instead.
You will absolutely feel better.
You'll be more healthy and bonus.
You'll be able to deadlift hundred
percent guaranteed. 8,000 pounds,
so that's right there. I was good
enough. While you're on Amazon as well,
you can get some books.
We got the way of the warrior kid books.
Just check them out. Just check them
out. That's my statement. Check them out.
Warrior kid books, feedbacks.
Unbelievable kids getting after it.
Once they read those books, the
discipline equals freedom field manual.
How to get after it.
Demand you on how to get after it and
kind of stay after it and stay because if
you get after it for a couple hours and
then that's all the getting after you're
doing.
If you crack that book open though,
you'll see this crack it open.
If you want to listen to it,
you can get it as an album with
tracks, iTunes, Google play, all that.
It's not on audible,
extreme ownerships.
The other book been out for awhile.
It's still people still buying
it and it's about leadership.
It's about combat leadership in how to
use combat leadership principles in your
business and your life and obviously in
combat as well. And then on top of that
life and I have a new book that we are,
I keep saying that we just finished it.
I think it was Tim
Ferriss I heard say like,
oh he was writing a book and he
goes yeah I'm done with my book.
And one of his friends that was a writer
was like okay cool you're 50% there and
that's the truth.
When you get done writing it,
you're 50% there cause there's a ton
of work that you still have to do.
I finished around of edits yesterday
and what's cool is reading the book,
I'm super stoked on the book and people
are going to get a lot out of it.
It's called the dichotomy of leadership.
It comes out September 25th my publisher
who listens to this podcast who hears
me say these things doesn't get it
or not going to order enough books.
They're like,
well you know,
you never know when we don't
want to take too much risk.
Order the book now so that you get a
book when it comes out first the dish,
you don't want second a dish,
third a and that's lifetime evidence
that you weren't in the game.
Don't let it happen. And then when
you meet me and you're like, Hey,
can you sign in? You're signing
my book. And I was like, cool,
y'all sign your second edition sadness.
The first edition I'll be like,
hey we go back, we go back.
So like the second edition you'll just
sort of sign your name and then with a
line or something.
But the first edition of the Games that
you went to supports that whole one,
and we are here together. Oh, second
edition. How you doing? Poser.
Poser. If you get the
second dish. Well, anyways,
all kidding aside.
That's coming out September 25th if you
want to get that dichotomy of leadership,
how to balance all those little things,
you got to balance as a leader.
That's what you gotta do.
Speaking of leadership,
if you need leadership training
inside your organization,
Ashkelon Front Echelon, front.com we solve
problems through leadership. It's me,
it's Lafe. Jp. Dave got
Mike's a rally on board,
got Flynn Cochran onboard.
We're expanding, we're growing.
We're getting after it
and we got the muster.
The monster's up in October,
San Francisco, 17th and 18th all
the other musters have sold out.
I think we're dropping a video probably
already this. The video will be dropped.
Yeah, I know, but it hasn't
been circulated, so we're
going to circulate little,
what do you call that?
Advertisement video. Yeah.
Technically informational video.
Informational. Informational.
It's more kind of like, as if to say is
I'm put it as accurately as possible.
It's to say, hey look, the countdown for
this thing, because we're all news coming.
It's number six, five before then
over, hey, we knew it was coming.
Hey the countdown to this event,
it's official, it's official.
We're counting the days down right now.
Cool. It's months, but San Francisco,
October 17th and 18th all
the other ones who sold out.
If you want to come better get registered
extreme ownership.com and also we've
got the the roll call,
September 21st in Dallas, Texas.
That is for uniform personnel,
police, firefighters,
law enforcement, military
border patrol, paramedics,
first responders,
all them.
We put that together so that
you can get out there one day.
Real quick leadership seminar for you all.
So same thing,
registered extreme
ownership.com come and get some
and if you want to continue
this conversation with us
virtually until you see us
live at the muster or you see us live
at the roll call or you see us live in
August at the immersion camp up in Maine.
Then during the time where do you
waiting to see us live? Guess what?
We can still kind of carry on this
conversation virtually via the Inter webs
Twitter,
Instagram,
and the Facebook echos at Echo
Charles and I am at jockowillink.
And speaking of those in the military,
for those of you in the military that
hold the line against evil and also to
those that are in police and law
enforcement, firefighters, paramedics,
border patrol, first
responders. Thanks to all of you
for being ready to respond anytime,
any place.
Thanks to your families as well for
supporting you while you support us and
everyone else out there. Thanks for
listening. Thanks for supporting.
Thanks for fighting,
fighting to be smarter and
stronger and faster and better.
Thanks for putting forth the effort
every second of every day and thanks for
remembering
what the ancient spirit of Woo taught us.
As long as you are not defeated,
you still have a chance.
So keep getting up and
keep getting after it.
Until next time,
this is echo and Jocko
out.