Yeah. Just remind me to never
complain about anything ever again.
You know what I mean? Yeah. Don't, don't,
don't let me complain about
anything ever again. I mean,
I don't consider myself a big
complainer, but come on, this is just,
we have no reason to complain
about anything. Yeah, yeah man.
What's crazy too is one of the heavier
parts there where I felt it was when he
talked about the claustrophobia heart.
Yeah. I know you have an issue with,
Dang it, it's there, but
he's not saying it's not,
I'm not super sensitive to it, but it's
something I know. I feel that, that,
that's like a tough one to
get over, you know? Yeah.
And especially going through
all that stuff first and Dayton,
you got to deal with the cla. I Dunno,
man. This might be too heavy for me.
Well, it was too heavy for a lot of people
and yeah, I mean it's almost like you,
you, we almost don't need to have a
discussion about this book. You know,
magnus just stopped talking about it.
Everyone go read it. I get it. You know,
and just, let's move on. You know,
because like I said, it
just makes you realize
just what kind of suffering there
can be and how good you've got it.
How good you've got it.
I'm going to go to bed tonight in
my bed and it's going to feel good.
You feel good to appreciate that
I'm appreciated every night. Yup.
Yeah,
so cause you think about like some
little things you don't even think about,
but they're like a real luxury.
It's just things that you really enjoy
but you don't even think about it.
They're just, they're just
like a whatever. Like for me,
I really like a nice cold, you know,
big a bottle of water. You know,
I have a big, just a big bottle of
water. I completely take it for granted.
When I go to work out in the morning,
I dropped a couple of ice
cubes in there and fill it up.
It's all nice and filtered and whatnot.
Oh I don't think anything about that.
You know, that would be like
Heaven, heaven. And then you get D,
You know, you go to bed at night,
you just crawl into the, to the,
the 500 thread sheets or I
don't know, there's some,
there's some kind of
sheets that are in this,
but whatever they are kind of cotton
sheets that are all nice. Yeah.
Declining to those. You
don't think about that.
You're not thankful for that every
night. Yeah. Pit pretty much everything.
Like I said, pretty much
everything. Even like, Oh yeah,
you know how you're
breathing right now. Look at,
consider that compared to that.
What you just read there? Just,
we'll just breathing. Listen,
let's just start with that.
Let's just break it down with air. Yeah.
That's the beginning. And I remember,
um, the cable guy was coming [inaudible],
which already sounds silly. I know.
And um, and he was late. He was supposed
to come this to was the cutoff, right?
Where he was going to cut
it. It was like, you know,
before the struggle is real. The
cable guy was late. Yeah. So he can't,
I don't know, two 15 or
something, and I had to go,
I want to see it go to
workout or something.
This is getting worse and worse
than no. This the [inaudible]. Yeah.
For my 15 minutes later, he's,
you know, he's, he's fixing,
not fixing for an unannounced. Yeah.
And yeah,
and that's one of the things I
thought of primarily when you said,
think of all the little luxuries. So
not only, I'm not only am I complaining
about something I don't need,
I'm complaining about
something that I'm kidding.
Like a supreme luxury. I'm
complaining about that,
you know, because it didn't come
out 15 minutes of all things, um,
before the time that it did.
Yeah.
I'm going to check myself to good
idea. I'm going to check myself too.