This is Jocko podcast number
14 with Echo Charles and me,
Jocko Willink. Good
Evening Echo. Good evening.
Now
I want you to imagine yourself
in the moment,
the moment,
just prior to the battle.
Now,
I don't want you to think
that because you're a soldier,
that this training has made you into some
kind of a superhuman or maybe you and
to a different kind of
being because it hasn't,
the training that you've
been through hasn't changed.
The fact that you're a human being.
All warriors are human beings.
So this is you I'm talking to
and I want you to think about that time
before you are going into the battle
because that's the time
when you can actually think.
Yeah.
When you're waiting,
when you're waiting to go,
okay.
And if you're going to feel fear,
this is where you feel
it because you have time,
the preparation is done, the planning
is done, the briefing is done,
the gear is prepared and you are
dressed and you are ready to go.
And now you're just waiting,
waiting for the call or for
the signal or for the command
to execute.
And so you have time to think.
And in fact,
all you can do at that moment,
it's thick.
And if you're in Iraq,
maybe you're waiting to go
into the [inaudible] district
or Ramadi where there's
been vicious IED and casualties
happening every day for months on end.
Or if you're in Vietnam,
maybe you're in a helicopter and you're
about to take part in an air assault on
a known enemy stronghold.
Yeah.
Or if you're in the Korean War,
maybe you're hearing the whistles,
the whistles signaling a coordinated
attack by the Red Army and you're just
waiting,
waiting for the shooting to start.
And if it's world war two,
maybe you're just off shore and you're
in a landing craft and the sound of
explosions and gunfire in the distance
on the beach where you're headed,
the beach you're waiting to hit.
And if it's world war one,
perhaps you're waiting in Europe
10 and Burger Verdun or the psalm,
but you're waiting to go over
the top out of that trench
and into almost certain death.
And in that moment,
what do you think about,
do you think about family,
friends? You think about your
life, do you think about death?
You think about that girl you, you wished
that you would have asked to marry.
Maybe you're thinking, how
did I get myself into this?
Or maybe you're thinking,
how do I get myself out of this?
Or maybe you're just sitting
there rethinking the plan
and the sequence and the
orders you were given.
Maybe you're thinking about your friends
getting killed or wounded.
Maybe you're thinking about
yourself getting killed or wounded.
You could be thinking about
so many different things,
but one thing is certain,
whatever you are thinking about,
whatever those thoughts are,
those thoughts are clear.
Those thoughts or an insight
into your true nature,
into your being,
into your soul.
And maybe that's the thing.
Maybe that's the thing we miss
about combat. And you know,
we always hear about the adrenaline rush
and the excitement and the challenge of
combat,
but what about
the cleansing of the mind
against a backdrop of death?
It seems like there's,
there's some purity that can only be
revealed by the horror and the blood and
the violence of impending combat.
Eh,
and as you think these thoughts,
and there's this moment when you
realize that who's killing us
is us. It's other people.
It's other humans.
And, and, and what are they
thinking? Who are they?
Why are they,
what are they
and what am I doing
here? Why, why am I here?
And despite all those Fox and all
those ideas and all those questions,
there's only one answer.
And the politics,
they disappear and the thoughts disappear.
And the fears and the reservations
and the concern and the ego,
it all disappears
because at that moment,
that moment of truth,
there's only one answer
forward,
forward into the battle,
into the fray,
toward the smoke and the fire and the
bullets and the bombs and towards death
to face it or head on.
And maybe maybe that is what
the real addiction of combat is.
Maybe that's what we yearn for.
Maybe those.
Okay.
Those are the thoughts
that feel our dreams
and are nightmares to be
there again in the breach.
Yeah.
To have button one clear and resoundingly
purpose for everything in our lives.
Everything in our world,
everything in past and present in future.
All of it wrapped up
into that one instant
to have that one singular purpose
for being alive at that moment
to attack,
attack with everything you have
with every ounce of commitment,
with every bit of clarity and focus
that you as a human being can possibly
muster.
I tack with your weapons and your mind
and your body and attack with your very
soul
and maybe that purity.
He's a what we miss.
He's what I miss
about combat
and so let's go back there once again,
once again to the battlefield
to World War One. Again,
in my mind,
the most brutal of all wars,
war tactics and intelligence
and strategy did not matter.
It was attrition and death and horror
rendered possible only because of
the purest and almost insane level of
selflessness and bravery,
and this starts off in that very
situation waiting for combat.
Okay?
I sat up for a long time that night in
the foreboding eve of battle mood of
which all soldiers at all times have
left report on a tree stump clustered
around with blue anemones.
Before I crept over the ranks
of my comrades to the tent.
I had tangled dreams in which a
principal role was played by a skull
in the morning.
The tender green of young leaves
shimmered in the flat light.
We followed hidden twisting paths toward
a narrow gorge behind the front line.
On the dot of noon,
our artillery launched into a furious
bombardment that echoed and react code
through the hall though the
wooded hollows for the first time,
we heard what was meant by
the expression drum fire.
We sat perched on her habit,
have her Sachs idle and excited.
A runner plunged through the
company to the company commander.
Brisk exchange.
The three nearest trenches have fallen
to us and six field guns had been
captured.
Loud cheers rang out of
feeling of up and Adam
at last at last,
the long for order in a long line,
we move forward toward the
pattern of heavy rifle fire.
It was getting serious to
the side of the forest path.
Goal thumps came down in a clump of furs,
bringing down a rain of branches and soil,
one nervous soldier through
themselves to the ground.
Then deaths call slip through the ranks.
Ambulance men to the front.
Okay.
A little later we passed
the spot that had been hit.
The casualties had already been removed.
Bloody scraps of cloth and flesh had been
left on the bushes around the crater.
A strange and dreadful site that put me
in mind of the butcher bird that spikes
it's prey on thorn bushes.
We entered the battle trampled
realm of the infantry men.
The area around the jumping off position
had been deforested by the shells and
the ripped up no man's land
lay the victims of the attack
still facing the enemy.
They're great tunics.
Barely stood out from the ground.
A giant form with red blood.
Spattered beard stared fixedly at the sky.
His fingers clutching this spongey ground.
A young man tossed in a shell crater is
features already yellow with impending
death.
He seemed not to want to be looked at.
He gave us a cross shrug and pulled
his coat over his head and lay still
in a curious failure of comprehension.
I looked alertly about me for possible
targets for all this artillery fire,
not apparently realizing that
it was actually ourselves,
that the enemy enemy gunners were
trying for all they were worth to hit.
Ambulancemen.
We had our first fatality or shrapnel
ball had rip through riflemen stone.
Stallers caught carotid artery.
Three packets of lint were sodden with
blood and no time in a matter of seconds.
He bled to death
in the rising mist.
I leapt out of the trench and found
a shrunk in French corpse flesh like
moldering fish cleaned greenlit greenish
Lee through slits in the shredded
uniform turning around.
I took a step back in horror next to me.
It was a figure crouched against a tree.
It still had gleaming French leather
harness and on its back was a fully packed
haversack topped by a round mess tin.
Okay.
Empty eye sockets and a few strands of
hair on fire on the bluish black skull
indicated that the man
was not among the living.
Okay.
There was another sitting down slumped
forward towards his feet as though we had
just collapsed all around
were dozens more rotted,
dried, stiffened to mummy's
frozen in Erie, dance of death.
The French must've spent months in the
proximity of their phone comrades without
bearing them.
A headless torso was jammed
in some shot up beams,
head and neck were gone. White cartilage
cleaned out of a reddish black flesh.
Okay.
I found it difficult to fathom
next to this very young man,
lay on his back with glassy eyes and
fist still aiming a peculiar feeling
looking into dead questioning eyes.
A shutter that I'd never quite
lost in the course of the war.
Has pockets had been turned inside out
and his empty wallet lay beside him.
Okay,
so that right there is a portion of the
opening chapters of a book called storm
of steel.
Going into the introduction of the book.
It's a storm of steel is one of
the great books of World War One,
if not the greatest. Ernst, younger.
That's the author Earth youngers book on
the 1914 war storm of steel is without
question the finest book on war
that I know, utterly honest,
truthful in good faith
in contrast with most
of the others is stark.
It has no pacifist design.
It makes no personal appeal.
It is notably unconstructed book.
It does not set its author and his
experience in any sort of context.
It offers nothing in the way of how's and
why's it is pure where and when and of
course above all what
there is nothing in it
about the politics of war,
nothing even on its outcome
and very little on the wider
strategy of its conduct.
War is all fighting is all.
Everything else is cropped away
and from first to last in the affirmative,
it is the work of a man whom the war made.
Yeah.
So it's a little bit of a different kind
of book that was someone explaining the
boot, someone explaining
the book and just how it is.
It's just about the fighting. Yeah.
So just throw just about the right.
Yeah.
And
that's one of the things
that makes it so powerful.
And it's also one of the
things that reflects very
well what it feels like to be
on the front lines. Yeah.
When politics don't matter,
when the outcome doesn't even matter,
the outcome of the broader war doesn't
matter anymore to what are we doing right
now? This trench? Mm
hmm.
Talking about being in these
trenches, which he, you know,
obviously all these soldiers
spent an immense amount of time.
They lived in these trenches.
Back to the book,
the desolation and the profound silence
sporadically broken by the crump of
shells were heightened by the,
sorry impression of devastation,
ripped have or Saks broken rifles,
scraps of cloth counter pointed
grotesquely with children's toys.
Shell fuses deep craters from explosions,
bottles,
harvest implements, shredded
books, battered household gear,
holes, who's gaping? Darkness,
betrayed the presence of basements where
the bodies of unlucky inhabitants of
the houses were nod by the,
particularly a city of swarms of rats
in the cattle buyers and stables and
Barnes, the bones of livestock
still dangling from their chains.
Trenches dug through ravaged gardens
in amongst sprouting bulbs of onions,
warm board,
Rhubarb Narcissus buried under
weeds on the neighboring fields,
grain Barnes through whose roofs grain.
The grain was already sprouting.
All that with half buried communication,
trench running through it,
and all suffused with the
smell of burning and decay.
Sad thoughts are apt to sneak up on the
warrior in such a low cow when he thinks
of those who only recently led
their lives and tranquility.
So he's actually providing a little
caution to people. A little caution,
the warriors that when you see,
you know these babies toys and there's
normal village that's been ripped and
Alice trenches running through it and
you can't let that sneak up on you.
He says that he motion,
you've got to detach yourself from that.
And speaking of the rats
here,
he says they are repellent creatures.
And I'm always thinking of the secret
desecrations they perform on the bodies
and the village basements.
Once as I was striding through the
ruins of Monaco monkey on a warm night,
they came oozing out of their hiding
places in such undescribable numbers that
the ground was like a long carpet of
them pattern with the occasional white of
an albino,
so so many rats,
first of all,
so many rats that it looks like a carpet
in so many rats that there's actually a
regular occurrence of albino rats.
That's a lot of rats
and talking about life in the trench,
we're real renaissance. Back to the book,
we were real renaissance men who can turn
our hands to anything and the trenches
make their thousand fold
demands on us every day.
We sink deep shafts,
construct dug outs and concrete pillboxes,
RigUp wire entanglements,
divine drainage systems,
revet support level raise and
smooth fill in latrines in a word.
We do all possible tasks ourselves.
So these guys are in the business
of constructing their house,
constructing the trenches that they
live in. They live in these dug outs,
which is like a lower part of
the trench where they dig in,
they build all this stuff themselves
and that's what they do and then in the
middle of that, back to the
book, a century collapses,
streaming blood shot in the head,
his comrades rip the bandage roll out
of his tunic and get him bandaged up.
There's no point bill, come on.
He's still breathing, isn't he?
Than the stretchers bearers come along
to carry him to the dressing station.
The stretcher poles collide with
the corners of the fire base.
No sooner has the man disappeared.
Then everything is back to the way
it was before someone's spreads.
If you shovel fulls of earth over the
red puddle and everyone goes back to
whatever he was doing,
only a new recruit maybe leans against
the revetment looking a little green
about the gills.
He's endeavoring to put it all together,
such an incredibly brutal assault so
sudden with no warning given it can't be
possible. It can't be real poor fellow.
If only you knew what
was in store for you.
Okay.
Seven October,
1915 standing at dawn on the fire.
Step opposite our dug out next to the
century when a rifle bullet ripped through
his forage cap without harming a
hair on his head. At the same time,
two pioneers were wounded on the wires.
One had a ricochet thought
shot through both legs,
the other a ball through
his ear in the morning.
The century out on our flank was shot
through both cheekbones the blood spurted
out of him in thick gouts and to capitol.
When Lieutenant von [inaudible]
Wald visiting our sector
to take pictures of SAP
and barely 50 yards away turn
to climb down from the outlook,
a bullet shattered the back of
his skull and he died on the spot.
Large fragments of skull were left
littering the century platform.
Also, a man was hitting
the shoulder but not badly.
The middle, the platoon section of
trench was attack with six inch shells.
One man was hurled against
a post by the blast so hard.
He sustained serious internal injuries
and a splinter of wood punctured the
artery in his arm that night.
Two men were wounded.
Qualin sport unschooling wire
boot Schmidt was shot in both hands and
one five and Schaefer took a bullet in
the knee following a torrential
downpour in the night.
All the traverses came down and formed
a gray sludge, porridge with the rain.
Turning the trench into a deep swamp are
only consolation was that the British
were just as badly off as we were because
we could see them bailing out for all
they were worth. Since our position has
a little more elevation than theirs,
we even managed to pump our
excess there way. So here it is,
they're almost face to
face with the British.
They're getting rid downpour of rain
and they take a little satisfaction.
The fact that they can actually funnel
some of the water into the British trench,
that's how close they are.
Okay.
The crumbled trench walls explode,
expose a line of bodies left there
from the previous autumn's fighting.
I was standing next to territorial
Wiegmann in front of the Outenberg readout
when a long shot pass through his bayonet,
which he was carrying over his shoulder
and gave him a bad wound in the groin.
So this is kind of the daily life that
he talks about being stuck in these
trenches
and it's just brutal.
It's brutal.
And you can kind of get the,
the matter of factness that he
delivers so much of this with take, oh,
this guy was shot,
this guy who had his leg blown off
each just like boom, boom, boom,
boom.
You know when he mentioned how he noticed
someone else reacting to that when
meanwhile it's just a real
matter of fact to him, but right.
Just the other guy reacting to it stands
out, you know, that's all matter of fact.
It is.
And the book,
which I kind of got in the beginning,
talked about some of this first combat
that he's exposed to when he goes on to
go through, I mean just
the battle, the song,
which is 60,000 casualties
in the first day,
60,000 casualties in the first day.
You know,
there was 58,000 killed in Vietnam.
I mean 58,000 Americans killed in Vietnam.
We're talking 60,000
casualties the first day.
And in three months there was a million,
a million.
It's, that's the whole state of,
by the way, it's, it's, it's,
it's unbelievable what this war was.
It really was.
And it's really unfathomable as I think
about what these guys were ordered to do.
And the fact that they did it
over and over and over again.
We,
we have,
we have more respect for human
life now than we did then,
period.
I don't care what anybody says.
We have more respect for human
life now than they did then.
Maybe that means were weaker.
Maybe it means we're more cowardly,
but
just to send millions of men to their
death for our river that didn't really
have any strategic impact
that that was true.
It's it, it's, it's, it's horrible.
It's horrible to think about.
And so now we're getting,
well, I leave that to,
for people to read,
you know,
the bulk of the middle of the book
where he goes into these details,
but then I kind of moving forward
here more towards the end of the book
and now we're getting into these
really pretty fierce battles.
And also what's interesting is this
is when he starts seeing the enemy,
like they can hear him
in the other trenches,
but now he start to
meeting them face to face
and indeed we heard on 29 November
from captain von Brixton that we were,
that we were to take part in a sweeping
counter offensive against the bulge that
the tank battle at Cambray
had made in our front.
Even though we are pleased to play a part
of the hammer having so long been the
anvil,
we wondered whether the troops still
exhausted from Flanders would be up to the
job. That said, I had every
confidence in my company.
They had never let anyone down.
Yet on the night of 30
November to one December,
we were put on Laurie's.
It's a truck and the process,
we took our first losses as a
soldier dropped a hand grenade,
which for some reason exploded
gravely injuring him and another man.
Someone else feigned insanity in
attempt to get out of the battle
after a lot of tooling and froing a buffet
in the ribs from an NCO seem to sort
him out and we were able to go.
It showed me that that sort of play
acting is difficult to keep up.
Now,
I've talked about this before and if you
didn't go the last time I talked about
it and look at this shellshocked
videos of world war one on Youtube,
there are [inaudible] to watch and you
realize what this war did to people.
And I pulled this section
out because he was a guy
who probably had gone completely
insane and he's like saying,
this guy feigned insanity. He just
said, you know what? This guy is faking.
You know, even though he probably was,
he probably was. He says, you know what?
Beat this guy up.
Tell them to suck it up and now we can go.
And that's exactly what happened.
That was kind of the attitude, right?
Remember you're saying that was
kind of the attitude back then?
It would absolutely was the attitude. It
was the attitude innate. They talk about,
I mean I've, I've paid more attention
to it on the British side, but Yo,
if you came back from the war
with all your limbs and you
went into a medical ward,
meaning you were in there because
you had psychological problems, they,
it was because you were a coward and
their minds. Yeah. Which is sick.
It's sickening. Yeah. Yeah.
I think how you were saying life met less
than or where it means more like human
life. I think it's just the, it was
just the lack of knowledge, you know,
like they've looked into it over the
years and stuff and they kind of Co as far
as the, as far as the PTSD and the shell
shock, everything. Yeah. Everything.
We've learned all kinds of about that.
But it is really horrible when you
see those videos of what they have,
what this war did to people.
And that's what war does do to people.
You know, we got to remember
that, that it impacts people in,
in a horrible way.
And this war to me,
especially more so than near the war,
primarily because of the
conditions and from the,
the indirect fire, the mortars
and the shelling. And again,
it's something that you
have no control over.
And also you could see these guys had
no control over their, their fate.
They're going to get told to do
something and they were going to do it.
And if you weren't going to do
it, you are a coward. You know,
if you were to protest and say,
hey,
this doesn't seem like a good plan
to me it wouldn't be well, okay,
what's your strategic opinion?
What your tactical loop,
which your tactical brain tell
you knows? No, you're a coward.
And that's why it's so important
really in any endeavor,
especially in war, but
in war, in business too,
to have an open mind from a leadership
position to listen to what people are
saying because they might be right.
And here,
I guarantee you there were thousands and
thousands if not hundreds of thousands
of soldiers that would've said, hey, you
know what? This doesn't make any sense.
And part of it is incumbent upon
them to say, you know what? No,
I mean it's like we talked about
with the Polian Maxim, right?
Napoleon's maximum was if you are aware
of a problem with an order and you carry
it and you get your guys killed,
you're culpable. Nope, it's on you.
So these guys obviously hadn't read
that and head you don't get it.
Hadn't taken that on board. Will you
listen to your subordinates and you say,
okay, what do you think of this plan?
We've tried it 12 times in the past,
you know, a month and a half and
we're going to try it again tomorrow.
We're going to get up at the sound of
the whistle and we're going to charge
towards these other enemy machine guns.
It hasn't worked yet,
but we think it might work tomorrow.
No one figured that out.
Listen to your people and
listen to your brain. You know,
listened to your common sense.
Don't get stuck.
Don't get stuck in a
mental Rut with anything.
And it's so easy to look if you could
send millions of humans to their death
because you can't think your
way out of the strategy.
You can't identify a
strategy as being wrong.
You can't come up with a
new way to execute something
that shows you how trapped in a box your
brain can get and not only you but your
buddies that are all thinking the same
way and you're all feeding off each other
with incestual ideas that are the
same ideas being fed to one another
and it leads to this.
Back to the book.
Suddenly there was some commotion at
the British Barricade, hand grenades,
flu rifles, banged machine
guns. Clattered they're coming.
They're coming.
We leaped behind sandbags and started
shooting in the heat of the battle.
One of my men,
corporal kingpin house jumped onto the
parapet and fire down into the trench
until he was brought down by
two bad wounds in his arms.
I took note of this hero of the hour and
was proud to congratulate him two weeks
later on a ward of the Iron Cross.
First Class.
Okay.
No sooner had we got back from this
interruption to our lunch that there was
more pandemonium.
It was one of those curious incidents
that can suddenly and unpredictably
transform an entire situation.
The noise was coming from a Saab Altar
in the regimen on our left who wanted to
line up with us and seemed
inflamed by a buzzard.
Fury drink seemed to have tipped as
innate bravery into towering rage.
Where are the Tommys? Let me Adam,
come on boys. Who's coming with me?
Okay.
It is in snit fury.
He knocked over our fine
barricade and plunged forward,
clearing a path for
himself with hand grenades.
So this guy is, you know, going after it.
He's the, you know, he's described
as being like almost drunk.
Maybe he is drunk,
but he's just standing up and charging,
charging forward,
clearing a path for himself with
hand grenades back to the book.
His orderly slipped ahead
of them along the trench,
shooting down anyone who survived
the explosion. Explosions,
braverly bravery,
fearless risking of one's
own life is always inspiring.
We too found ourself,
ourselves,
picked up by his wild fury and scrabbling
around to grab a few hand grenades.
Rush to form part of this buzzer.
Ruckers project progress sooner.
I was up alongside him,
tearing along the line and the other
officers to followed by riflemen from my
company.
Okay.
Even captain von Brixton,
the battalion commander was up
there in the van rifle in hand,
bringing down enemy hand grenade throwers.
Okay.
The British resisted manfully.
Every traverse had to be fought for four.
Okay.
The black balls of mill's bombs.
Those are British grenades crossed
in the air with our own long handled
grenades.
Behind every traverse we captured,
we found corpses or
bodies still twitching.
We killed each other sight unseen.
We too suffered losses.
A piece of iron crashed into
the ground next to the orderly,
which the fellow was unable to avoid
and he collapsed to the ground while his
blood issued onto the
clay from as many wounds.
Okay?
We hurt, we hurled, we hurdled
over his body and charged forwards.
Thunderous crashes pointed us to weigh.
Hundreds of pairs of eyes were lying in
wait behind rifles and machine guns in
dead man's land.
We were already a long way
from our own front lines,
from all sides.
Bullets whistled round.
Our steel helmets are struck the
trench parapet with a hard crack.
Each time a black iron
oval broke the horizon.
One's eyes sized it up.
With that instantaneous clarity of which
a man is only capable in moments of
life and death.
During those instances of waiting,
you had to try and get to a place where
you could see as much of the sky as
possible because it was only against it's
Pale backdrop that it was possible to
see the black Jaguar iron of those
deadly balls with sufficient clarity.
Then you hurled your own
bomb and leaped forward.
One barely glanced at the
crumpled body of one's opponents.
He was finished and a new
dual was commencing in the
exchange of hand grenades.
It reminded me of fencing with foils.
You needed a jump and stretch
almost as in a ballet.
It is the deadliest of duels
as it invariably ends with
one of the participants
or the other being blown to smithereens
or both
hand grenade fights.
And just to kind of explain that a
little bit, it's one thing that you,
that we definitely learned in the seal
teams when you're patrolling at night,
and this is especially before night vision
when you wanted to see the person in
front of you and especially like to see
their hand signals, cause we, you know,
we use all hand signals at night,
so if you want to see them,
you kind of get down on a knee
and you put the, you put the back,
the back light behind him so you
can see what handsome or passing.
And what he's doing here is they're
trying to get as low as they can and back
light the sky as much as they can so
they can see the grenades that are being
thrown at him.
And then when they do get thrown at them,
they try and get up to a spot where they
don't think it's gonna blow up and then
their Hac, their own grades. Back
in these moments,
I was capable of seeing the dead.
I jumped over them with
every stride without horror.
They lay there in they're relaxed and
softly spilled attitude that characterizes
those moments in which
life takes its leave.
Now they get the,
now they get the British kind of trapped
the trench. They were trying to escape
down, doubled back on itself towards ours,
like a curved frame of a lear and at the
narrowest point they were only 10 paces
apart, so they had to pass us
again from our elevated position.
We were able to look down on the British
helmets as they stumbled in their haste
and excitement. I tossed a hand
grenade in front of the first lot,
bringing them up short and
after them all the others.
Then they were stuck in a frightful jam.
Hand-Grenades flew through the air like
snowballs covering everything in milk.
White smoke, fresh bombs were
handed up to us from below.
Lightenings flashed between the huddle,
the British huddling up rags of
flesh and uniforms and helmets.
There were mingled cries of rage and fear
with fire in our eyes.
We jumped onto the very lip of the trench.
The rifles of the whole
area were pointed at us.
Suddenly in my delirium,
I was knocked to the ground
as by a hammer blow sober.
I pulled off my helmet and saw to my
terror that there were two large holes in
it.
Cadet Mormon leaping up to
assist me assured me that
I had a bleeding scratch at
the back of my head.
Nothing more.
A bullet shot from some distance had
punched through my helmet and it only
brushed my skull.
Okay,
half unconscious.
I reeled back with a Hurley
applied bandage to remove
myself from the eye of the
storm.
Okay?
No sooner had I passed the
nearest traverse that a man
ran up behind me and told
me that tab had just been killed in
the same place by a shot in the head.
The news floored me,
a friend of mine with noble
qualities with whom I shared joy,
sorrow and danger for years.
Now who only a few moments ago had
called out some pleasant treated me,
taken from life by a tiny piece of leg.
I could not grasp the fact.
Unfortunately it was all too true
in this murder.
A sector of trench.
All my ncrs and a third of my
company were bleeding to death.
Shots in the head,
rain down lieutenant hop than another
one was another one of the fallen and
older man I teacher by profession,
a German school master in the best sense
of the word my two ensigns and many
others besides were wounded and yet the
seventh company held onto the conquered
line under the command of
Lieutenant Hop and Raf,
the only able bodied officer
remaining until we relieved
of all the stimulating moments in a war.
There is none to compare
with the encounter of two
storm troop commanders in the
narrow clay walls of align.
There is no going back and no pity
and everyone knows who is
seen of them in their kingdom.
The aristocrat of the trench with hard
determine visage brave to the point of
folly leaping agily forward and
back with keen bloodthirsty eyes.
Men who answered the demands of the hour
and whose names go down in no chronicle.
And I think as we read these books,
write these books, these are
chronicles. Somebody wrote,
this guy lived in wrote,
but he's making a specific point here.
He, he uses the term, the
aristocrat of the trench.
And it's not the turning of the term
aristocrat that isn't, it's not the,
you know, the, the snobby
aristocrat. That's not what
he's talking about. You know,
you look up the definition of Aristocrat
and one of the meanings of it is like
the, the best of, so that's
what he's talking about.
These guys that were the best guys in
the trench that had the heart look that
would get after it.
And yet their names go down and no
chronicle. And I'll tell you, I know
many,
many brave men in the seal
teams in the Marine Corps,
in the army,
brave souls that were
all risk Kratz of war
and their name will go
down and no chronicle.
Hmm.
Uh,
later battle,
two men who had just ahead of us
tried to make it back over the top.
One toppled back into the
trench with a shot in the head.
The other shot in the belly
could only crawl into it.
We hunkered down on the floor to wait and
smoked English cigarettes from time to
time. Well aimed rifle
grenades came flying over.
We were able to see them
and take a vase of action.
The man with the wound in the belly,
a very young lad lay in amongst us,
stretched out like a cat in the
warm rays of the setting sun.
He slipped into death with an
almost childlike smile on his face.
It was a site that didn't depress me,
but left me with a fraternal
feeling for the dying man.
Even the groaning of his
comrade gradually fell silent.
He died in our midst shuttering.
It's that, that line,
they're really caught me.
Maybe he died in our midst shuttering.
And it's,
I think what catches you about,
it's because the other,
it's contracted with the other one who
died with an almost childlike smile on
his face.
And you know,
as I was thinking, when you see
this much deaf, it's like, you know,
when they say the Eskimos have
thousand words for snow because they,
they're so familiar with snow and these
men were faced with so much death that
they saw this,
the,
the varied faces of death and
how different they are. Yeah.
And you know,
one thing that I remember from some of
the older Vietnam seals talking to me
about guys that had been wounded, and
this is, you know, uh, in the 90s.
So I had no idea anything about combat.
And I remember like they were telling me,
hey, you know, sometimes guys get
wounded, big it shot in. It does,
it doesn't phase them. And it's
part of, it's the physiology.
Like if you get shot in a certain place,
each doesn't,
it just doesn't do
anything. You know, you can,
you can drive off and then you'll have
someone else get shot in a different
place. Yeah. And it just, it,
there's nothing you can do about it.
Like it blows their femur a part or it
hits their hip in such a way that they
cannot.
And they were just down in agonizing
pain where someone else may get shit shot
on a through and through.
Meaning it just goes in one side and
out the other and it's almost like they
don't even notice it. Yeah.
Cause it, it happens so fast,
happened so fast and it doesn't
cause any traumatic damage.
And then you have the psychological
aspect where some people psychologically
they get hit and they're freaking
out. Oh my God, I'm going to die.
And some other people or are, you
know, I got hit. Just leave me alone.
Hey I got this. Don't worry about me.
I ain't got time to bleed. Yeah. So,
so those are some situations that
you are just different.
And then it's the same thing obviously,
when this guy sees death after death,
after death,
he sees the variables and
the various faces of death.
Okay.
So now we're getting towards the end
and ease.
I mean,
this is at a point now where
they're starting to recognize
that they're going to
lose the war.
And what's crazy about that is net
now, okay, if you, if you tell me, hey,
we're fighting for our
country, okay, I get it.
We're going to drive on and maybe
we're gonna make some sacrifices.
And these guys now recognize that
they're probably not going to win.
Hmm.
And he's kind of given his guys a brief
before they go into another assault.
I paraded my company in battle order in
a small apple orchard standing under an
apple tree.
I addressed a few words to the men who
were drawn up in front of me in a horse
shoe arrangement.
They looked serious and manly.
There wasn't much to say in the
course of the last few days.
And with a kind of sweeping this,
that is only to be explained by the
fact that an army is not only men under
arms,
but also men fused with a
sense of common purpose.
Probably every one of them had come to
understand that we were on our uppers.
And on our uppers is an
expression that means
it's like when you're in poverty or
when you don't have the means anymore.
So they knew.
He knew that they were on their last legs.
They knew that they
were on their last legs.
He goes on with every attack.
The enemy came forward
with more powerful means.
His blows were swifter
and more devastating.
Everyone knew we could no longer win,
but we would stand firm.
Okay.
But we would stand firm.
Now they're in his final battle.
I had a very impartial feeling as if I
were able to view myself through by not
colors. You can see ease
now becoming detached. Yeah.
For the first time in the entire war,
I heard the hissing of individual bullets
as if they were whistling past some
target.
We were coming downhill.
Indistinct figures moved against
a background of red, brown clay,
a machine gun spat out.
It's gouts of bullets.
The feeling of hopelessness
increased even.
So we broke into a run while the
gunners found we're finding their range.
We jumped over several snipers ness and
Hurley excavated trenches in mid jump
over a slightly better made trench.
I felt a piercing jolt in the chest as
though I'd been hit like a game bird with
a sharp cry that seemed to
cost me all the air I had.
I spun on my access and
crashed to the ground.
It had got me at last at the same
time as feeling I had been hit.
I felt the bullet taking away my life.
I had felt deaths hand once
before on the road at Maury,
but this time his grip was
firmer and more determined.
As I came down heavily on
the bottom of the trench,
I was convinced it was all over.
Strangely,
that moment is one of the very few in
my life of which I am able to say they
were utterly happy.
I understood as in a flash of lightning,
the true inner purpose
and form of my life.
I felt surprise and disbelief
that it was to end there and then,
but this surprise had something
untroubled and almost Mary about it.
Then I heard the firing grow less as if
I were a stone sinking under the surface
of some turbulent water
where I was going.
There was neither war
nor
enmity.
Okay.
Well
obviously he did survive that wounding
because he was able to write this book
and he wrote many other books.
The book is called storm of steel
by Ernst.
Sticky younger.
Okay.
Yeah. And as I wrap up these books, again,
sometimes I feel like, you know, hey,
where do I compare this?
How do I tie it in?
Okay,
enemy.
Now obviously there's lessons in
leadership and stir trategy and you know,
I talked a little bit about listening
to your troops and keeping an open mind.
Okay.
And even though,
yeah,
you know, they started off
in the description of this
book is saying, you know,
there's no pacifist leaning in this book,
but something that I often remind people
okay
about, well, the guys
that have fought in wars
is that if there's anybody,
okay
that looks at war and says,
let's try to avoid it if we can.
It's the guys that have been there,
the guys that have fought,
we don't want to send our friends to war,
we don't want to send kids to war.
And I think this book is a reminder.
Okay.
Of just how bad it can be
and just how horrible,
well a thing that war is.
Now,
of course that always comes with the
caveat of the fact that there are things
that are more evil than war
and there are things
that can only be stopped.
There is evil that can only be
stopped through the waging of war.
But when you do have to
go to war because the evil
must be stopped,
then go to award a win and win decisively.
So you don't put men
through horrors
for nothing.
Going back to that, the part
where you're talking about, um,
guys getting hit and they deal with in
different people just have different
reactions
when it's that kind of blow
like a bullet happened so fast.
I don't think your nerves really register
of it depends on where you hit because
you're,
the bullet could go through your arm.
You don't notice it or go through
your arm and hit your, your bone.
Graze the bone. Yeah, I could
hit the bone. It could shout
to the bone. Yeah, I know.
I saw guys that got hit in
the bone and it's devastating.
Yeah. And you see guys that got through
and through and your, and they're fine.
Literally fine. Yeah. And so
that's, you know, war is a, uh,
there's a, there's a, there's a
huge element of chance in it. Yeah.
And you know,
I actually got,
there was an internet question that I
got asked and I didn't, I don't think we,
we brought it up,
but it was basically somebody saying,
how do you deal with the randomness of
war? Like you could just, how do you do,
how do you deal with
the randomness of war?
And for me it's the way I dealt
with the random acts of war is,
is the really simple thought of I'm
going to control what I can control.
And if I can't control it, I'm
not going to worry about it. Yeah.
You can't worry about the
random sniper shot. I mean,
you can do everything you
can to mitigate it. You know,
when you're out there in the field,
you know, you keep moving, moving,
you stay behind,
cover as much as you can.
You don't came up in the same
spot over and over again.
You do the the things
to mitigate the risk,
but you can't just be dwelling on it.
Right, because you can't control it.
Yeah.
The same thing of getting hit with a
random IED or a random of indirect fire
from a mortar.
You cannot mitigate all that risk.
So what do you do?
You do everything you can to
mitigate it and then you know,
you worry about the
things you can control.
And I used to tell that to MMA fighters
too, and I'm, I've told that story before.
You know,
listen,
guys are getting worried they're going
to get knocked out or they're going to
get caught a submission. It's a, Hey,
you've done everything you can
to mitigate that. You've trained,
you've conditioned yourself,
you've sparred, you've done Mitch,
you've done everything that you can do.
If that happens, you can't control it.
If it happens, you can't control
it. So don't even worry about it.
Worry about the things you can control.
The pace of the fight,
putting the fight where you want it to
be. Winning the rounds, being a tactician,
worry about those things. Don't worry
about getting knocked out. You know what,
keep your hands up. Keep your head
movement, keep the distance incorrect.
Those are the things that are going to
keep you it from getting knocked out,
but you can't mitigate all
that risk. You're in a fist
fight and in a fist fight.
Some people,
sometimes people get what knocked out
and in a war sometimes people get wounded
and sometimes people get killed and
you cannot mitigate that risk away.
It's a war and you got to deal with it.
I remember, this is gonna sound kind of
funny comparatively speaking, but um,
I shot my own hand one time was what? A
BB gun. You know the kind with the CLT.
You don't have to tell this
story to the public. You know
there's a lesson in there though. It's not
even a lesson. It's like less than one.
It's don't shoot your hand with a gun.
It was done.
It was one of those ones where
you know that you put the Cot.
So it just changed the seal two
cartridge and I was like, Hey,
there's no Bibi's in here,
so I'm going to see just how strong
does this air feel, you know,
with the brand new CEO too
and there a BB in there.
And so I shot it and I
didn't feel anything.
That's the weird thing is why I say so
when I shot it and went the BB went and
it went deep in there and went in.
I didn't see it and I saw this little
kind of like our little ring, you know,
like a little tab, a skin just appeared.
And I was like, what? You know,
like I felt the air. I was like, that's
some pretty strong air. And then kind of,
you know, a few seconds went by
and um, I feel just this pressure,
like someone's like kind of squeezing
my hand a little bit with their fingers.
And I was like kind of confused because I,
of course I didn't,
there was no BB in there. I knew that
from the beginning and I don't know that.
Right. Yeah. I'm saying that's what I'm
thinking at the time. And then maybe,
you know,
maybe 10 seconds or so it just starts
gushing blood and it comes to [inaudible]
but no pain, no pain. And you know,
and I kind of like you start kind of
blacking out. I think he was, I was,
I was like 12 years old. Um, I start
kind of blacking out. It's, and what,
what happened was the B,
the BB went through and got
lodged in my tendons under there.
So it took like three surgeries to
get it out. You know, the first one,
he just reached in there second when he
cut a little bit and then the third one,
um,
they'd just cut my head open.
They had to like move the tendons to
the side and like grab it. It was bad.
But the point is there was no pain. Yeah.
Cause it just happens so fast, you know?
Actually that's one point.
The other point is always treat
weapons as if they're loaded. Oh yeah.
Never point a weapon or anything
you don't intend to destroy.
Oh well we know that now.
I'm just making sure
everybody knows that for sure.
Had some young listeners out there don't
point guns at your hands and pulled the
trigger.
Yeah.
That's actually always treat weapons as
if they're loaded and never aim a weapon
or anything you don't intend to destroy
period. Those are like the official,
like when you, if you go through like
a gun courses, something like that.
Those are, that's the first
thing. Yeah. Interesting.
Well you know you went through seal
training so it's a little bit more heavy
than a gun course. The basic principles,
gun safety do not change. Yeah,
and they should not change.
I wish I would've known that
when I was 12 thank you.
I think it's a time for some,
some questions from the interwebs.
Yes.
Questions from the interwebs.
Speaking of the inner webs,
we are in fact supported by on it.com
and if you don't know what
on it.com is or what it is,
it's where we get our supplements and
bunch of other supplements that that work.
Not extensive information on there too.
If you want to know
mark, you can also get stuff. Yeah.
You can also get like
kettlebells and collect bells,
which I have and which I
utilize. Yeah, tentatively
and not just normal kettle bells
either. Yeah, let's just say that.
Yeah,
it's true.
O n n I t.com backslash backslash Jocko.
Okay. Yeah. Get yourself a
discount. Yeah, yeah, yeah.
10% off free shipping on
everything except for the heavy,
heavy items, which are the weights
and kettlebells, whatnot. Anyway.
Yeah. Do it. First question,
can you talk about your
training schedules, roles,
which is Jujitsu training sessions
we call them. Was that for me or you?
Explain to me what roles is for
everyone. All right. All right.
In the event of them not knowing,
we'd be rolling.
So can you talk about your
training schedules, your roles,
and what is a typical week?
What does that look like?
Well, for me, you know, I work
out everyday, so what that means,
every morning I wake up early
and I get it on. I lift weights,
I do calisthenics, I do some kind of
sprinting evolution seven days a week,
seven days a week.
And,
and as I've explained to many
people on the Twitter, they say,
don't you ever take a day off? And I
do, but I don't plan to take days off.
Days off.
Life brings days off.
You got the broken water heater,
you got the sick kids, you got sick,
you got the, the car broke down,
you got the event at school,
whatever it is.
Some,
there's some reason there's some
travel plans that don't allow it.
So there's life will give you days off.
So don't take off days voluntarily.
Don't do that.
Let the days off,
calm through life and then then you
don't have to freak out about it.
And you just go,
oh cool,
I've got a day off day to Roscoe
and the travel or on an a,
you don't want to miss a workout today,
just going to take it as a day arrest. So,
but I do,
I work out every day.
And part of that is going off instinct
of what I feel like of what type of
workout I'm going to do.
And, and by that sometimes,
I mean I don't feel like doing
a certain kind of workout,
therefore I'm going to do it because
it's punishment for being weak.
And then there's times where I'm like,
you know what?
I do not want to do that kind of workout
today because I feel an impending
injury. You're like, Hey, I'm going to
lift real heavy today. No, not today.
I'm tight. I'm sore. I'm going to
not do that type of workout today.
So it's a little combination
of in instinct and
disciplined versus freedom of,
you know what?
This is going to be too much for me today.
I don't want to lift heavy today,
or I don't feel it.
Sometimes I feel like lifting heavy.
Right? You know, in other words,
I'm maybe drained,
I'm drained to do some kind
of an endurance type work
workout or a Mac concert.
It's going to go in there and
just just do some singles and the,
but then some days you
feel, you know, I'm man,
I don't feel like putting any heavy
way up to them to go in there and do
something lighter, but maybe higher
repetitions. And that type of things.
So I'm doing that every day,
you know,
calisthenics sometimes and doing
a combination of all three.
Sometimes I'm doing one. So that's just
just how I'm getting after it. And again,
I think at some point I'm
going to write an ebook
because the publishing process and the
publishing world is a real pain and,
and the ebooks not, and just book an Ebook
is easier. It's easier to do. You do it,
you produce it, you just put it through
Amazon. And Amazon just says, Oh cool,
you sell them.
We sell.
I could sell them for like three
bucks and then anyone could want,
some could just get it. And it doesn't
have to be, I don't feel bad if I don't,
you'll, if it's not the, it's something
that I could do the way I wanted to do.
I don't have to, I don't have to like I
don't have to make it a certain length.
Oh No, it man, it's three
bucks. You know, it's 28 pages.
That's the information I have is not,
you know, if someone said, Hey Jocko,
we want you to write a fitness book,
then I've got to be 127 pages and it's
got to have a bunch of things in it that
I don't want to talk about because
it's not that complicated. Right?
So 27 pages ebook,
download it,
print it out, everybody can have it
cost. Three bucks. People are stoked.
We're all good.
People can stop asking me what my workouts
are like because everybody wants to
know that. I don't know why I'm not, you
know, some incredible athlete, you know,
so here's my workouts. And so that's
what I'm thinking of doing. Um,
then again,
that's debts I had been thinking about
actually getting someone and saying, hey,
you seem like a capable human
helped me write a little ebook.
I'm going to tell you what to
put in it and you do it. Why?
So it like sounds dope or whatever you
want to know. Just so it gets done.
Because right now I'm just busy too busy
for their fitness ebook right now. Yeah.
So I got to move that up.
I got to move that up on my chart cause
I know people want to get out that. Okay.
So then on top of the working out,
there's this surfing,
which if there's waves I'm surfing.
Right, right. That's just the way it goes.
If there's good ways I'm surfing,
there's not always good waves,
but if there's ways of surfing,
one thing I need to do more of is just
go out and paddle. I need to do that.
We'll just go out. So you're
constantly in shape cause paddling,
paddling a surfboard is different kinds
of conditioning. Anything else? Yeah,
just to be in shape for battling,
Kinda like I've been saying, hey,
if you want to get good
at humping a ruck sack,
then just hump a rucksack that if you
want to get good at doing post two bovis
well if you want to be good at paddling
a surf board, you got a paddle,
a surfboard.
So you always feel weak when the big waves
come and you haven't surfed in awhile
and you feel weak because you haven't
been paddling. Lack the discipline.
So I should be paddling more.
Uh, and then we get to the,
the Jujitsu, the role that
Jujitsu. So our role, if I'm home,
I'm going to the gym and
I'm training, uh, you know,
we usually do some technique.
I usually get a little
something from Jeff or from Dean
and you know, Dean and Jeff, the,
what's crazy is you can always learn
something and it still freaks me out
because it's not like when
I say learn something,
I'm not like saying that they're teaching
me some new variation to the Gogo plot
yet, right? No, they're teaching,
like dean will say, Hey,
when you put the guillotine on over here,
make this adjustment.
Or when you're passing the guard, do
this here. Like some simple thing.
Or Jeff, remember Jeff
Glover was, I said, Hey Jeff,
teach my son though the Darce choke.
And I just watched him give my son,
you know, like a seven minute class
on the Darce choke. Now, my son,
you know,
can you imagine you're getting,
you're nine years old and you're getting
a personal class on the dark joke from
Jeff Glover, but my son, you know,
he just thinks that's normal,
but I'm watching it.
And I remember Jeff was just going
over a little details and all
stuff that I did not know
to go relearn in the dark,
really learning the Darce choke.
And so there's always these little
things and I always am surprised at the
obviousness of those things and actually
does happen occasionally in the other
direction.
You know,
dean was going through a slump where
he's really having a hard time passing my
guard and I just said, hey
man, you've been doing,
why just do x?
And he could see,
I saw on his face because he has a,
a mutant grappling mind,
like I saw on his face as soon as
I told him that it was a thing,
it was a connection made and he instantly
started passing my guard again. Nelson.
Yeah. Damn. But um, but yeah,
you get these little obvious things,
you get the,
the learning.
So you're always trying to learn a
little something and then, you know,
there's the situational drills
of going in and then there's,
then there's the reality. Here's the
reality, man. I like to roll. Yeah.
I like to roll. That's the
reality of it. I enjoy training,
not starting, not starting in one position
and going into, no, I like to train.
That's what I like to do.
That's what I love about Jujitsu.
So I like to roll and I
roll and whenever I go in,
my goal is to role and
the same way that I will,
some nights I go in, like there was
some days I go in or nights and,
and you know, normal night, I just feel
like we're all on slack going in rural.
Some days I'm like, you know what
man, I'm not feeling it today
and because I'm not feeling it today,
I'm going to get it on and
I'll force myself. That Kinda,
that's Kinda like when
you're a kid and um,
you start crying or something
and you dead tells you a,
I'll give you something to
cry about. Yeah. Like it's
like that. I feel like it, oh,
you don't feel like it.
I'll give you something to not feel
good at or whatever it is that it. And,
and like a couple weeks
ago I said to Mike,
I got there and I did not feel
like rolling. And I said to myself,
I'm not going to stop until
everybody stops. And so, you
know, the last, you know,
so we start with 20 guys on the mat
and then after three rounds, there's,
you know,
15 guys or 16 guys in the mat and then
a down day 10 and then eight and then
four. And then it's me and one other
guy. I'm like, it looks like it's,
you got the last round of my friend.
But I just did that to myself.
It's a little form of, it's a little
form of exercising a little discipline.
But that being said,
there's days where I go in and,
and I don't feel it and I don't feel
it as a different sense that I have,
which is today's not going
to be a good day today.
I'm going to tweak something today.
I'm too, I'm too worn down or whatever.
And so I'll go, I'll do, I'll do
some roles and then I'll just,
I'll just leave it at
that. You know, I won't,
I won't force myself to stay on
the map forever. So I do again,
I used that instinct of,
of what I am feeling to make a
decision on how it's going to go down.
That's fine. One day,
um, Greg, he randomly,
I came in, he was like, yeah,
I feel like I just feel like I'm
going to break my toe today. Yeah.
It sounds weird, right? He said, yeah,
I feel like it. And I was like, Oh yeah,
you just feel that. He was
like, yeah, I just feel like it
that day I broke my toe.
I didn't really break it.
It was like kind of dislocated or
something like that. But it's weird.
That's weird, right? I know way
different point, but still. Um,
so my workouts, I'll go through it
real fast. Different than yours.
I work out average five days a week,
but
they're not everything all in one.
So I'll, if I roll three days,
I'll lift. And do metcons and cardio
and that kind of stuff. Two days.
Really? Yeah. So, so I don't do like what
do you do with all your free time man?
Make videos. That's right. Hang
with them. I am. So you really,
how many times a week do you
train? Three. Three, sometimes two.
Unless I'm like super busy
then one dang. Yeah. But yeah,
back when I was competing I was
doing six and now it's like two days,
not two days train. But
I'll do running, lifting,
conditioning and then a different
session I do Jujitsu and whatever that
entails. Um, same thing as you, you know,
do some technique, but I'll typically,
hey, how many rounds do you
feel like on a typical day,
you know how you'll do some technique,
little book class or training session
even you'll do some technique,
maybe some drills, six and then rounds,
right? So you'd do six rounds that solid,
what, five minutes? Six, six
or six, six minute rounds.
You know, it's kind of like,
it's, yeah, it's strange because
that's one time we did like a,
we had the gym was closed but
we had, you know, an open mat,
but it wasn't an open mat.
It was like, hey, we're going
to train. And we did wait,
we who just won a bunch of handful.
You guys, you were probably there.
I don't know. I don't
remember. But we did six,
six minute rounds,
no gooey and then six,
six minute rounds where you there
that day? I usually don't get tired.
I got tired that day. Well, I got tired
that day. Yeah. The, how's it? Okay. So I,
I'd go to, I haven't been taught
to us in a few months now, but um,
I'd go there like when they
are trained for ADCC and um,
I go there once a week,
once every two weeks just for one.
And so they do stuff like in
every single time I've been there,
it's been one of these things tend to
six tens six rounds of 10 minutes each,
30 seconds in between one and then
one minute between the next one,
you know it goes through
or five 10 minute rounds.
Oh No.
For 10 minute minute rounds
and then one 20 minute route.
Those you get tired. Yeah, sure.
I have a conditioning because
when we do 20 like when I'm,
when Dean's getting ready for an ECC or
whoever we got that's doing the longer
or the no time limit matches and
I'm doing 20 his 20 minute rounds,
I'm just good to go in.
Yeah. I surprisingly handled
what I was in. Good shape,
man did it.
But I think it has to do with what we
talked about the other day where I'm not a
really fast sprinter. Right, right.
I'm not a really fast runner,
but if you put a ruck sack on me,
I can go for a long time. Right.
And I think it's one of those like I can
grapple for a long time not get tired.
Yeah. I think mine's psychological
where if I know it's 20 minutes,
then I'm not, I don't feel
like, I dunno, confined or,
I don't know. I feel like the
hardest thing that we do is early.
It was like when we shark tank, each
other, you know, is when you're putting,
you know, I'll be in the or one
of our guys that's competing.
We'll go in the middle and you're
getting a fresh guy every two minutes,
one minute, three minutes, five
minutes, whatever the case may be.
You're getting somebody fresh
on you and that's where you get,
that's where you get tested.
Yeah. I would say a typical class,
so it's like anywhere from a five
minute round, six minute round,
either five or six minutes,
three, four or four routes.
I'd say that's a typical, you know, not
a training for a competition. Just to,
you know, this is what we're doing. If you
go four, five, six rounds, that's like,
that's kind of a lot around compared
to just the average I think in my
experience. Yeah. I let I start. I feel
like I got, I got good training yet.
Like six, six veterans. That's where
I feel good. Yeah, that's 36,000.
It's almost 40, 40 something minutes and
training. That makes me feel good. Yeah,
man. Yeah, that's a lot.
That's a lot though. You know,
you'll see guys dropping off after
three rounds out, say not everybody,
obviously it has to do with
who you're training. Like Yay.
I can train with somebody that's
not that good all day long,
but you can start getting the grinders on.
You gotta be ready.
We did. I just, Oh,
and I've trained with Andy won round
one and it's like literally like three
rounds with, within like an average
normal person on your level.
Pace in the string.
What's cool about Andy was Andy is,
he's probably my main training partner
now. I treat them all the time.
Uh, but for a while he didn't work out at
all. He didn't like lift her knee, right?
Yeah. Back in the day. And then I said,
hey man, you got to get to the next level.
I hate to say it,
you got to do some working out.
And he's an athletic guy
anyways. And I just said, hey,
go do a bunch of pull ups and then the
next day do bunch of pushups and dips and
the next day do some squats.
And he's okay.
He started doing it and in a month,
man,
he was a different dude and now we
started powerlifting. So he's even,
he's even morphing a little bit more,
but he's won some big,
he's won some big tournaments. He's
got some game for sure. He did good.
And the in the Challenges League minimum
is challenging like second or something
like that. Yeah. Good. He's great training
partner. Yeah. It's funny. He was, um,
I noticed that where he was
always athletic and stuff
and then one time I ain't
seen him for that long, but like we
don't take him off and say, Hey, what,
you know, what did you do? Cause you look
way different right now. And he was like,
oh, I just changed my eating.
I don't eat like a whole, uh,
containers of Nutella anymore.
Okay. Gotcha. But yeah,
I don't know. But yeah, that's
it. Next question. Let's do it.
Can you please share on your podcasts
what the difference between lazy
delegation and decentralization is?
Okay,
so decentralized command is obviously the,
uh,
one of the principals combat where
you have in the book that we wrote,
and I have a very simple definition
that I've been explaining to people.
Decentralized command, it's
everybody leads. That's what
decentralized command is.
Uh, and, and obviously
that means you want
everybody else to lead.
And so this question is what's different
gene being lazy and just delegating
everything and what's
good decentralization.
So Leesie delegation number
one is delegating things
that are actually your job,
right? Cause there's, there's some roles
and responsibilities that people have.
And if you take something that is supposed
to be your job right and you delegate
it to somebody else because you don't
feel like doing it, then that's lazy. If,
as a matter of fact,
if you're delegating something that
it's something that you're delegating
because you don't want to do it,
then,
then that's being lazy,
right?
If you're actually delegating something
because it's something you don't want to
do, right, then you're being lazy. And,
and I'll tell you,
it's actually a mindset to take on the
tasks of the things that you don't want
to do or that your team
doesn't want to do.
So this is like literally do elders.
There's something that is hard to do or
that no one wants to do, do that thing.
And I'll give you an example.
We had to,
we had to stand watch in Iraq
on my first deployment to Iraq,
we had to stand watch on the prisoners
that we would capture. It's, we come back,
we have to stand watch on him.
So I made myself and my
assistant platoon commander,
I was a platoon commander
at the time I gave us.
I assigned us the worst
watch of the night,
like the zero 300 in the morning
until zero 500 in the morning.
The watch that nobody wants because it's
in the middle of your sleep pattern.
No one wanted that watch. I put us on
that watch. We took the worst watch.
So I didn't delegate the hard watch.
I took the hard watch.
So there's an example of
the opposite of being lazy.
You're taking on board the hard tasks,
you know,
another one is when we would go
shooting and we'd get done shooting.
And believe it or not, even the seal
teams, you got to go pick up brass.
You got to go pick up brass off
the ground, all over the desert,
all over the field, all over,
wherever you did a bunch of shooting.
And it's pretty easy for the guy that's
in charge to have a meeting to attend to
when it's time to pick up brass. But I
would always pick up brass, you know,
I wouldn't delegate Shell, the shell, the
shell casings, but it's a pain. You know,
it literally,
yet when you're at,
at land warfare it takes a
couple days to pick up brass.
And instead of like I said, instead
of having to go back for a meeting,
I'd go out there and you know,
jump in there and have the crap job.
Like everybody else, I'm picking up brass.
So I wouldn't delegate these things.
That's being lazy when you
delegate that. Uh, and,
and another thing I'll find is if
somebody's complaining of some,
if one of my subordinates is complaining
to me about having to do something,
okay,
I automatically take it and I say, Oh,
oh, echo, it's a pain for you to do this.
Cool.
What I'll do it.
And it has a good psychological
effect on, right? I mean it's, it's,
it's each showing them that like,
look man,
I'm here for you and if it's
too much for you, I'll take it.
And I've had people literally
going under, no, I got,
cause that's the instinct that people
have. They go, look man, I got it.
And that's what I would do if I complained
about something. And then I said,
and then my boss said to me, you
know what, if it's too much for you,
I'll take care of it. You're
like, no, no, no, no. So,
and that's awesome.
I'll tell you,
there was also a little
form of discipline in there,
a little form of discipline of taking
on board tasks and doing things that you
know you don't want to do.
That's a way of exercising some
discipline in your life and making things
happen. So that's the kind of thing. All
those things, that's like lazy delegation.
If you're doing those kinds of things
where you're getting rid of jobs you don't
want,
you're getting rid of jobs that you should
be doing and getting rid of jobs that
are a pain or are monotonous,
or you think they're below you.
So the opposite of that is
decentralized command, right?
This is where you're letting other
people do what they're supposed to do.
It's when you're letting people do
things that will help them grow. Hmm.
Does it help a person
grow by picking up brass?
I suppose there's a little
character building and there,
but it's not going to
literally help them grow.
So you don't need to delegate that task.
Does it help someone grow as a leader
to do the zero 300 zero 500 watch on
prisoners know it's pain. It's
just, it's just unmitigated pain.
So it doesn't help people
grow so that that then,
then you don't have to decentralize that.
But if you've got something that's gonna
let somebody grow, you, let them do it.
If there's something that allows you to
stand back and be the tactical genius,
and we wrote about this in
the book, you know, then,
and thereby allowing me to have a
different perspective on something,
then I should absolutely decentralized
and delegated. So if, if,
if there was a mission came up and
we need to come up with a plan,
I would tell you to plan it.
I'd be like Echo,
you come up with a plan on this and then
you'd go and plant it and you'd be all
involved in it and you would lose
the elevation that I would have.
So when I come back to look at your plan,
you say, here's the plan. I go, hey,
it looks good except for these two
points. And you'd be like, man,
how did he see those points?
I'd say it's because I had the altitude.
So that's another time
that decentralized command,
it's a very helpful decentralized
command means letting people make little
mistakes and not punishing
them because of those mistakes.
That's decentralized command.
If I
just hammer people and punish them when
they make a mistake because they're not
going to wanting to take any,
chances are they're not going to want to
take any risk and they're not going to
want to lead because I've been punitive
with my actions towards them. Now,
that doesn't mean,
and I've seen this happen.
That doesn't mean if I'm going to let
you go play on a mission and I see you're
screwing it up, I'm just going to let you
have a catastrophic failure, right? No,
I'm going to be like, Hey, echo,
think about this over here. Hey, echo,
think about that over there.
We're going to get you dialed in.
I'm going to let give you some rope, but
I'm not going to let you hang yourself.
I'm actually going to give you enough
rope to get the job done and think on your
own. But if you start looking like
you're going to hang yourself,
I'm going to stop you.
The other thing about decentralized
command that's positive,
that's not just lazy delegation is when
you let your subordinate lead so that
you can focus upward,
outward and forward.
So if,
if you have a mission,
if we have a mission to accomplish
and I tell you to lead it,
that means you can take care of
that mission. I can look upward,
meaning up the chain of command,
find out what's going on on outward,
meaning what's the enemy
doing and forward meeting.
What's going to happen in the future.
And if I'm wrapped up in the,
in the accomplishing of the task
at hand from a leadership position,
I can't do any of those things. I can't
look out for it. I can't look out.
We're like, can't look forward. Hmm.
You gotta let people lead so
that they can become leaders.
And your actual goal, and this is
where people get intimidated, is too,
to set them up so they can take your job.
That's what you want.
You want them to be able to take your
job right. And people get scared of that,
but you can't be scared of
that. Yeah. What was that?
There was a quote where where one guy was
asking the other guy or something like,
Hey, what happens if we develop, you know,
our workers and then they
leave us and he's like,
it's better than not developing on
and having them stay. Yeah, yeah,
yeah. That's a good point. I
mean that's me doing a quote.
Okay. You know what I'm saying?
No, that's, that's good.
And you definitely want
to set your people up.
Do you want to work yourself out of a job?
And then you've got your
other opportunities will
come because people will see
that you develop a team,
people to see that you develop good
leaders and they're going to say, hey,
I want you to come and do that at this
higher position and you're going to get
benefit from that as well. Well, Echo,
can you ask Jocko to talk more
about the writing process?
Any ups and downs,
obstacles,
daily rituals and or future plans.
Uh,
so I know I've asked answered
this question before. Mm hmm.
It's very all answered again. I'm
going to do it quickly. What were my,
what did I do when writing? I wrote a
thousand words a day no matter what.
If I had some obstacles as
the question had said here,
I would write if I had ups and downs,
I would write, if I had a daily ritual,
it was to write every day.
That's what I did.
I wrote a thousand words a day and when
you're writing a 50,000 or 60,000 word
manuscript,
that means in two months you've got your,
you got your manuscript done.
The thing about writing every day,
and I've said this before,
is if you write every day,
you don't need to rehash what you
wrote before because you remember it.
So you can just open the book
or you can open your page.
You can open the document that you
can just start writing. And even,
I used to like kind of lead my,
leave myself a lead sentence
that I knew would just,
I could sit down the next day and start
flowing right into it. So do that.
And also I had the outline, I mean for
extreme ownership that Leif and I wrote,
I had the outline,
we had the chapters,
so I broadly knew what I was writing
about and then it's just a matter of
sitting down and making it happen.
And when I went to college,
I was an English major in college, and
guess what? I sat down and wrote when it,
when I had to write papers,
when I had to write scripts,
when I had to write whatever
I had to write, I just sat
down and started writing.
And then it's the same thing when
I was in the navy. The navy, right.
All kinds of stuff. You write evaluations,
you right, operational summaries.
You write a wards,
you write all kinds of things in the navy,
and I used to just sit down and it's
right. That's what you got to do.
You just got to get on it.
And one thing about me
is my rough draft might,
when I'm sitting down I just start
writing. It's, I know it's going to be
rough. It's going to be a rough, rough
draft. That's what I'm going to write.
You just go, just go. And I don't care.
And an misspelling stuff
and a punctuations bad, but
I don't care about that.
I'm going to get a stop it because it's
so easy to clean that stuff up later.
The hard part is getting the,
the f the foundational information down
on the paper. That's the hard part.
Um,
and it's easy for me to
edit it or hone it later.
Now as far as future plans,
future books, uh, yeah,
I mean Lafe and I are
definitely doing a follow up,
a book about leadership and
we're working on that right now.
So that's a common,
I noticed that your text
messages are always grammatically
correct. Yeah. I was a,
I was an English major and I took classes,
I took classes like advanced
grammar and syntax. Yeah.
And uh, yeah, so I, it actually,
I find language and linguistics
to be very interesting.
Yeah. And I know that, uh,
Mike stro strikes some people
as weird, but I really do.
I find linguistics and language and
the written word and the way words are
combined together to make
thoughts in people's brains.
It's a very interesting
process to me and so I was, uh,
I was very interested in it and
that's another reason why I,
why I studied English when
I was in college. It's the,
it's the written word, the
written word, which is a very,
very powerful, very, very powerful tool.
I also noticed your over youth of
capital letters in your text messages.
Oh,
maybe that's just how you're feeling.
Sometimes that's only when I'm
texting you certain things.
Next question,
like I'll see you on the map.
Next question.
Is Detachment something you do in real
time or is it before or after any event?
I think I've heard you describe both.
Is it both?
No, it is not. Both. It is not both.
Actually, if you think about it. Okay.
The detachment that we're talking
about is when you get involved in these
situations,
you got to detach yourself from it so
that you can make good decisions so that
you can see things clearly so that
you can assess things clearly.
That's why you detach
from these situations.
So technically if before
or after an event,
you are detached from them, right? Because
they're not happening at that time.
Now I guess you could be so emotional
about an event that even after it happens,
you could still not see it clearly
because you can't detach from it.
So I guess I could give it to you that,
okay. Yeah, yeah, yeah, that's true.
And real for it.
You could be so amped up about it and so
nervous about it and so emotional about
it that I guess beforehand you could.
So I guess, I guess I am wrong,
I am talking about detaching
throughout the process, right?
But even if you're,
if you have to detach beforehand,
you're not detaching on
the incoming situation.
You'd have to detach from your current
yes. Being nervous about the uncovered.
Right. And that may help you prep it
all. I'll talk about that a little bit,
but the skill itself is being
able to detach during the event.
And I'll tell you, once you do detach
from it, it's actually pretty easy.
But to punch through that gravity that
your brain makes with emotion and chaos
and mayhem.
That's the hard part.
The hard part is to notice that you're
stuck in the gravitational pull of all
that emotion.
So you got to pay attention to that end.
What you really want to try and do is try,
and it's what you just said,
try and detach yourself
before the gravity and the uh,
the gravity of the emotions
and the chaos builds up.
If you can detach before that,
then you'd have to break through it.
You're already outside that
realm and so then it's, it's,
it's much easier.
So it's like there's quick sand in front
of you and it's much easier to just see
the quick stand and just say,
I'm not going to step in there
than it is to walk in there,
go up into your waist and start feeling
getting sucked down and then decide, oh,
I'm going to pull myself out of
that. It's a lot harder. Yeah. So
you got to look for those signs.
You got to look for that moment.
When you start feeling emotional or you
know that it's going to be something
emotionally,
you got to step back from those and get,
get yourself in the
habit of asking yourself,
what do I look like right now?
What does Jocko look like right now?
What does Jocko sound like right now?
Listen to yourself talk.
Listen to the words that are coming out
of your mouth and see if you're being a
reasonable human or not.
And I'll tell you one thing that I,
I do,
I kind of see is, you know,
when I'm in the movie,
the Terminator, when he sees like the,
the various responses he could give. Well,
when I'm feeling,
when I'm really good in a very detached
mode and I'm having a conversation with
someone, I like see the options in my
head of what I could say to him and I,
Oh yeah, that'll make them mad. Oh
yeah, that's too authentic. Okay,
that lots of good one. Hey
Buddy, blah blah, blah, blah.
So I think that that mindset
kind of works pretty good.
But again,
look for the signs.
Look for the quick sand look for the
emotional quicksand and don't step in it.
The emotion of the anger,
the frustration.
There's little physical signs too. When
you start feeling the sweat beading up,
when you start feeling hot,
like you literally start feeling hot.
That should be a big red flag. Yeah. That
warmth that flushes through your face,
that's not good. Yeah. The breathing,
when you start getting,
when you're breathing starts increasing,
your pulse was going. That's the stuff.
You got a notice to say yourself. Oh,
there it is.
There it is.
That's the quicksand of emotion
and confusion and chaos.
You don't want to step into it. You want
to pull yourself back. We'll take away.
There is like be like the terminator. No,
I'm not saying be like the terminator.
That was a,
that was a comparison of thinking of
being able to visualize the options that
you have and if you're emotional,
you don't think like that when
you're emotional, you're just,
you're just blurting out whenever
he's going to come out of your mouth,
but when you're detached a little
bit, you okay. I could say this.
I could say that, oh, this is
answered three and we say it.
It's like a problem solving tactic.
It's interesting because on the
terminator he blurted out analytically,
he blurted out an emotional response
because he was acting like a person.
You remember that?
You remember what he said?
I don't to profanity when he's
in the thing he's looking at,
he's all shot up and the superintendent
or whatever the whatever it's knocking
on the motel door. Okay. Hey Buddy,
you got a dead cat in there or what?
Cause all these flashes riding off.
So he looked through his responses and
they're pretty funny. If you read them,
I forget exactly what they are, but he
goes the like, the one he chose was,
fuck you asshole. That was it.
Instead of, well, you know. Yeah,
I do remember that. Yeah. That was pretty
dope. The fake emotions, which sometimes,
which I've talked about before, sometimes
you got to use the fake emotions.
This switcheroo. Yeah. Or is that what's
good for the goose is good for the no,
it's like when your kid is not getting,
you're not listening
to what you're saying.
You're not having the impact
that you want to house.
You got to show a little bit of anger,
turned up the heat.
That's kind of good too. And
don't get crazy with it. Right.
As far as with the kids
where if you show anger,
not only is it like a powerful thing and
they're like, oh shoot, this is powerful.
It demonstrates to them that you care
about what what we're talking about right
now. I care about it rather than, you
know, rather than I'm just a machine.
A robot. Yeah. Yeah. I don't care.
But I know I'm supposed to
tell you this kind of feeling.
Next question,
how do you deal with being evaluated
specifically by different people with
different, a PD since and motive. Oh,
how do you deal with being evaluated?
Well,
I can tell you right now,
nobody likes being
evaluated, right? Nobody. Mm.
Now you might get somebody that
says, oh, I love being coached and,
and there are some people that
are pretty positive about that.
And as a matter of fact, I have clients
where they want to be coached. Right.
But most people, especially in a normal
environment, like if you go out new hires,
someone to coach you.
Okay,
okay.
But most people in a normal environment,
they don't like being evaluated.
They don't like being judged,
always judging.
So the first thing you have to do when
it comes to being evaluated is get that
in your head that you like.
Everybody else has defense mechanisms
and they're going to flare up.
As soon as somebody says
something critical of you have,
soon as somebody goes to evaluate you,
your defense mechanisms are going to
go up. And then once that happens,
once you feel those defense mechanisms
go up, you got to put your ego in check.
Hm Hm.
You got to put your ego in check.
And then once you do that,
you got to listen, Liz.
I know it sounds crazy. Listen to
what they're saying. Don't even,
don't even think of a response.
Say to yourself, you know what?
I'm not even going to respond. I'm only
going to listen to what they're saying.
Yeah. But, and, and to kind of, you
already can't even take it. No, no,
I can't take it. Oh, I'm saying,
but I think because people will
will quote unquote do that,
but they won't really do it. As
far as, I'm not gonna say anything.
I'm just going to listen. Yeah,
that's actually, that's actually,
that's actually how they set it up to
look. I'm not going to say anything.
I'm just going to listen. Yes, exactly.
What I'm talking about is like you don't,
or they'll all body language,
you know the kind where they're like,
you know, they'll do that kind of
stuff. Don't do that. We'll not do that.
So you're right. You got to, and
not just listen, but truly listen,
not listen just with your ears,
but listening with your mind and
your brain and with an open mind,
an open mind,
and then think about what people are
saying and then see it is important.
See it from their perspective. Because
if you just see it from your perspective,
you're not even seeing what
the criticism really is.
You're only seeing the
defense of the criticism.
So actually get in their mind and say,
wow,
what does this look like
from their perspective?
Why would they be taking the effort?
And the risk and the challenge of trying
to present this problem to me if it
wasn't important or are they just
doing it just to make me mad? No,
they're trying to help you. And you
know what just like, just like a joke,
you know they say like every
joke has some little truth to it.
Every little criticism.
Even if the person is your arch rival,
their criticism is built on something.
Yeah.
So what is that reality that you can take
away from it even though you've got to
take it with a grain of salt, especially
if the person, like it says here,
if the person has different
opinions and mode as well.
Of course they have different opinions.
You want people with different opinions.
Maybe they have different motives.
So maybe you think they're trying to usurp
your authority or something like that.
So you maybe you got to take
it with a grain of salt,
but find the grain of truth in there
too and find what it is from their
perspective,
what the problem is and learn from it.
And one of the most beautiful things
about this is you take the criticism and
you make adjustments. You know, how
do I deal with about being evaluated?
I try and accept the evaluation and
make adjustments to improve myself as a
human.
That's how I deal with being evaluated.
And I'm not saying I deal with it
anybody better than anybody else because
everybody gets defensive,
myself included.
You know, we had a little conversation
when we started tonight, right? Sure.
You said I repeated some stuff on the
last podcast allegedly and you know,
and then we talked through
it and then I said, you know,
and you know, I noticed that your camera
work was a little bit off and you know,
it was just the point. My point was
just approved. How defensive we all get.
We all get, and you know what I did? I
said, you know what? I noticed that too,
you know?
But as far as me repeating,
there was a couple little sections
and it was because we pull,
I pulled from multiple different books
and they had a little bit of overlap and
looking back on it probably shouldn't
have. But at the time I thought,
you know what? This is emphasizing
really important points. Yeah.
But still people don't want to hear
the same thing over and over again.
So I probably shouldn't have done that.
So guess what criticism accepted on.
I will adapt,
adjust and I will make improvements to
my game based on your criticism of my
technique, my skill, and my life.
I didn't accept your criticism about the
camera work. No, you don't. You know,
you don't know anything about my there
it is him up framing it is who are you to
tell me? Yeah, tell echo anything.
Can't tell Leco anything.
Take their criticisms. Fix the
problem. That's what it's all about.
Your use them to get better.
Next question, Jocko. Echo.
What are your guilty
pleasures other than donuts?
And by the way, I don't even like donuts.
That's pure echo right there. Yeah.
You were talking about yet
a donut delivery it, sorry,
let me finish the question.
What are your guilty pleasures
other than donuts, Jocko?
What do you do when you momentarily give
in to a vice or something that you know
is bad for you meant?
I liked it.
I liked the fact that the people that
are asking this is actually two questions
in one. I appreciate the fact
that this person says, Jocko,
what do you do when you
momentarily give into a vice?
I appreciate that as if I'm this person
that could only for a fraction of a
moment given to any form of
advice because I am not a human,
so I appreciate that.
I appreciate about this two part question.
The first part asks both of us,
specifically Jocko and Echo,
what are your guilty pleasures?
The second part asks other or the second
part asks Jocko overtly excluding my
name. Jocko, what do you do when
you momentarily give into a vice?
It's something that you,
and the way I see this is that
you do something about it.
If you momentarily given me,
if I'm momentarily given like no,
no one want to hear my advice
cause it probably doesn't work.
Oh I thought you were to because
it's just game over at that point.
It is getting over this one.
Uh,
or you could take it that the fact that
they don't even think you ever break.
Yeah. Yeah. But then again,
you're talking about eating just leaves
Oreo cookies on here. So that's an issue.
Uh, but to get down to it,
what are your guilty pleasures?
I guilty pleasures
number one,
first and foremost, mint
chocolate chip ice cream, uh,
and especially mint chocolate
chip ice cream milkshakes.
And I do some twisted things in my brain
to kind of convince myself that those
are actually good for me and that they
contain you just enough carbs and there's
approaching in there and there's some fat.
It's actually like a full good meal,
which is just a big lie cause it's a
big sugar bomb, like a supplement. So,
but I do, I do, uh, you know,
I love mint chocolate chip ice cream.
I really love chocolate milk too.
And,
and there's been these articles floating
around the Internet best posts you can
get. And it's another
thing, it's like, okay, but
the reality is it sugar
in milk and they had it.
So again,
I'll,
I'll twist that one in my
head and sometimes for 10
minutes I'll convince myself
that really that is the
right thing to do. Right. Uh,
obviously we've discussed on here before
those little damn a principal wrapped
hot dogs that they serve in the airport
that have some kind of butter or
something on them that just, damn, I
don't know who invented those things,
but God bless him. And then, you
know, you know, the normal crap foods,
the potato chips, the French fries,
the whatever, the junk. Okay.
So am I,
he immune to the genetic evolutions that
human beings have been to through that
make us desire sugary foods and the
endorphins going off and firing your head?
No, I'm not immune to those things when I,
and I'll tell you when I do, first of
all, I like to earn those things, right?
I either earned them on the front end or
the backend, like one way or the other.
Like I either busted my ass and it did
a couple of days of hard working out and
all of a sudden, um, you know,
I'm out with my good and we're swinging
by and all of a sudden I see there's a
little ice cream shop in the
corner. You know what? Hey,
let's get a little ice cream.
There's a little little go time. And,
and one thing that I,
when I do it,
I don't like have guilt when I'm sitting
there. I don't know. I'm not going,
oh my God, I can't believe I'm doing
this. No. I say, man, this is awesome.
This does ice cream. Milkshake
taste great. That's great.
But later on the,
either that night or the next day,
I earn that thing,
put a little punishment in place.
Little punitive reprimand
for slack behavior. And,
and I'll tell you the thing you gotta
be careful of is that it is a slippery
slope. And as you mentioned,
like one potato chip
can lead to 20 and it does lead to 20.
And even that is like,
okay, understand we had a,
we had a derailment,
right,
but don't let one day of bad food lead
to another day of bad food and no working
out [inaudible].
That's what happens.
That's what makes you sign off
the rails and it, and actually,
I mean there's like Tim Ferriss,
he's got that thing where he does,
it's something like six days in a row
of eating super clean and then on the
seventh day you actually,
it's not just GPA,
you have to like just get after it
because your body has to get the shock of
carbs and all this stuff. There's
another big lie. Like you can tell you,
you can twist your day all of a sudden
be like, well, you know first dude,
but you do have to be careful
of the slippery slope.
That for me, that's what,
that's what I happens. I think.
I don't believe in this
stuff that you know you,
you use up your willpower throughout
the day and you use up your discipline.
I believe that your discipline decisions
create more discipline decisions.
Now if I do just have a
disaster of a day or if I have,
let's say for whatever reason,
I have a two day just
gluttonous train wreck binge
where I'm just, where I just for
whatever, I lose the bubble, you know?
And there's could be anything, any number
of things that could cause that maybe,
you know, it's like
multiple, I don't know,
bad situation with travel than
with an event than with something.
They'll come home and it's a birthday
party and they there the only thing that
eats pizza and I'm like, you know
what it is and it's just done. Right.
Is it better to hold the line yet is, um,
but if I do, everyone knows situations,
then I'll usually react to that.
You know,
I'll earn it later. I'll, if I go
on a just a terrible food thing,
I'll do some kind of a fast, I'll do like
a 24 hour fast, maybe in a 48 hour fast.
I haven't done a 72 hour,
but I'm gearing up to do a 72 hour.
What do you just drink? Water? Yeah,
just drink water. Just drink water.
I did the 48 hour and it's at, it was
actually nothing. It was like, no problem,
no factor. I did everything normal
squatted, went surfing, did Jujitsu,
there's some guys on the mat and I said,
I was talking to big Eric, you know,
big Eric and as, hey, I got to tell you
something, when we get done training,
this is after,
this is on the second day of doing it.
And so we trained a bunch and you
know, it was no factor. And he's like,
what were you going to tell me? And I
said, I haven't eaten for for 48 hours.
And I said, you know, I'm just trying
this out and I feel completely normal.
So, uh, so that's, that's one of
the things I'll do a government,
I'll just do some kind of, you know,
psycho kind of hardcore workout. Um,
you know,
we,
a body in motion tends to stay in motion
and a body at rest tends to stay in
rest. Don't let the momentum start going
the wrong way, you know what I mean?
Get that body back in motion,
get back on track,
snap yourself back into the discipline,
you know,
crush some workouts,
get after it and get on that path,
the path of discipline and
strength and stay there.
You mentioned the,
the giving into the brain that you
are evolved to have or whatever,
you know, and that's like seeking
out sugar and fat and you know,
fat's not bad, right? But that's what your
evolved to want. And it's for a reason.
So, you know, put simply back
when you're a cave caveman,
you didn't know when the next
meal was coming from. So you know,
you get that honey or
sugar that that means much.
Eat as much as you can. So your brain's
still like that. Um, so a good tactic,
and I use this crazy crazily, it
worked. It worked for drinking.
Know I mentioned this too before,
where you just understand that your
brain is in a way playing a trick on you.
And if you give in
literally by this model,
you just felt for a trick. And so
now you know that, right? So you're,
you're falling for a trick that is played
on you by your own brain because it
thinks it's,
you're still a caveman.
So you see these donuts
or cake or I dunno, pizza,
something delicious and fatty.
You mean what you had for dinner tonight?
He's seen my dinner.
And your brain is, hey,
is this is one of those situations though.
It's your daughter's birthday party,
right? You got the family
over, what are you going to do?
Put them all on a Paleo Diet for the
evening will tell you you're can get him
some pizza and ice
cream and it's all good.
And it's a little bit
a cake for Echo Gerald.
Basically that was lunch and then I had
a salad for dinner. Okay, good, good.
Good job. So you disciplined, you're
here to back on the track. But so if you,
you understand that you're, you just
fell for a trick right there. Um,
so now going forward, you know, we're
okay if I have these cravings or you know,
that donut looks delicious,
whatever way, um, you're gonna,
you're about to actively and consciously
fall for a chick right now. There.
There's no scarcity of food
right now. There's an abundance
of food. And you know,
it's a perfect
phrase for this.
Don't be a sucker. Yeah, exactly.
Like, like how often is he like, yeah,
that's like the one of the worst
thing someone can tell you that hey,
you are a soccer and that's why it worked
for you. Yeah. Don't be a sock. Yeah.
So don't be a soccer to that piece of
your brain that's trying to trick you into
wanting stuff that's actually
bad for you. Yeah. So yeah.
And so how the trick works is your brain
is saying, hey, those donuts, those are,
those are beneficial.
And look at all these benefits.
You'll get your calories, you know,
who knows when they're going to come.
That's what your brain is.
That's how it feels.
They're going to come when you
ordered Domino's. Yeah. Yeah. That's,
that's the reality.
But your brain brain's not telling you
that it's given you a crate because you
need all those calories.
You don't know what it's going to
come and look at all these benefits.
It's going to taste good. And
they said, this is what you need.
That's what your brain is telling you.
This is what you need.
But the reality is you don't live in
that world anymore where you can get as
many donuts as you want.
No.
So it's tricking you into thinking that
the short term benefits are the benefits
when in reality, since the world
we live in now is different.
The longterm benefits of the benefits.
Yes.
And they don't involve donuts or drinking.
Don't be a sucker. Don't be a sucker.
Yeah, it helps me. It helps if you
care about being a sucker though.
That's the thing.
If you're like,
I don't care about being stuck and
there's no way to be like in another way
though. That's what I think too.
That's what I think too. All right,
next question
Jocko.
Is Buds the right filter for the kind
of people you want in the seal teams?
Does it filter out good
people and letting the bat
so buds is the basic underwater
demolition seal training and
it does a decent job and I'm not going
to say that everybody that makes it
through buds is a guy that you want to
work with or even a guy that you want on
your team because
one thing that happens in buds
is that punishment is dealt out,
right? I mean it's just suffering.
It's just hard work. It's, you know,
putting a boat on your head and being
cold and wet and all this stuff and you
either embrace that and crush it.
That's one way to get through.
That's the way you should get through.
But there are guys that they,
they find a way to get buy in,
to sneak by and to work the system.
Right?
It does happen and those guys
definitely exist in the teams.
Then the real team guys know who those
guys are. But the one thing that's hard,
it's hard for a civilian to know the
difference because two is really going to
seals the seal seal.
If you have your tried and you're a seal,
you must be a bad ass. So what is it like
kind of like when your coaches saying,
okay,
everybody push ups for you know,
60 seconds and he's looking around and
when you see he's not looking at you,
you just kind of cruise, there's
sacrifice, there's all kinds of guys,
there's all kinds of little
corners that you can cut.
There's things you can get away with.
And the weird thing about buds is,
and I think Lafe talked about this
when he was on the podcast is,
or maybe he didn't,
maybe we just had it in conversations.
But you have a mentality when you're
going through buds is that you're,
you're a team and you're trying
to help everyone get through.
And so you don't like rat those guys out
when you see him cutting corners, you,
it very seldom do you wrap one of
those guys out. Unless it's just a,
an atrocious case. Most of the time
guys are, you know, like, hey man,
are you okay? Like, Oh,
in instructors coming,
like they'll help people skate
through, right? So it's, it's,
it's pretty negative when you get through
buds and you're in the seal teams then,
then you know, everyone
says to a man will say, oh,
I wish I wouldn't help anyone get through
because now they're in the teams and
now we can't count on them and now
we've got to carry their weight. So,
so, so it is definitely a
test of making it through.
But there's two ways to make it through.
You can crush it and survive it or you
can sneak through it and skate through it
and it does happen.
Now it's also mainly a physical test
and people talk about, no, it's mental,
it's physical, right? Yeah, there's a
mental aspect to it. No doubt. And if,
and if you're not mentally
committed to making it through,
then it's going to be hard for you.
But it's primarily a physical test and
physicality is actually a small part of
being a seal.
Now of course it's like a baseline factor.
I mean it is a factor as a CEO, you
gotta be able to do the job physically,
but that's the baseline, right?
And being a good athlete is definitely
does definitely not automatically make
someone a great seal because there's
guys that go through buds that are studs
physically and we get the seal teams.
They're not good,
they're not good seals. They,
they might be a bad leader,
they might be unsafe or they can't shoot
or they can't handle the pressure or
they can't handle the grind because you
get a guy that's an elite level acts
athlete and guess what?
He's used to elite level of food.
He's used to elite level of,
of treatments.
He's used to an elite level of rest and
you get to the seal teams and there's no
elite food. There's no elite
treatment, there's no elite rest.
There's just grind and you're out the
desert and you're just going on in the
operation after operation after operation.
In some of these high level athletes,
there's such a fine tuned machine.
It's like we talked about before,
they're like a Porsche or a race car and
what you want to be as a four by four.
Like you can put diesel or biofuel or
whatever into that engine is going to keep
running. You have to put the high
acting clean stuff into the sports car.
And some of those guys break down on that.
And, and, and the reason is, like I said,
it's because the seal
teams is not buds training.
Mm.
And I've said this before, no one in
the seal teams cares about buds turning.
Once you've,
once you've gotten through buds,
it's like as normal as brushing
your teeth, like everyone's
done it. No one says,
Hey, did you brush your teeth?
No, we all want to her teeth.
We all went through buds. It's
not that big of a deal. Um,
one thing that buds does do good though
is it does do a good job of finding
people's weaknesses and
whether it's swimming or
whether it's running or whether
it's the obstacle course or whether it's,
whether it's lack of sleep or being in
the water and the water work that they
make you do. If you have a weakness
of any of those areas, it's going to,
it's going to show,
it's going to show.
But again,
some guys do find a way to make it through
and they end up in the teams and they
end up doing a couple of seal platoons.
But
okay.
Again, being just being a seal
doesn't make you a bad ass.
That's just the truth.
It doesn't make you a great leader.
It doesn't make you a tactical expert.
It just doesn't,
it means that you made it through the
training and you survived a couple seal
platoons.
That's what it means.
Now there are plenty of seals that are
bad ass and great leaders and definitely
some tactical experts,
but it certainly isn't every seal cause
there's a bell curve in the seal teams.
A bell curve. Just like any other group
of people or any other organization.
And at the top of the bell curve,
you got a bunch of relentless on stoppable
warriors that carry more than their
share of the weight in the teams.
And these are the guys that have built
or are building the reputation that the
seal teams have.
And then in the middle of the curve,
that's where you got the bulk of the guys.
And these are great guys.
They're great seals,
they do the job and they do it well and
they're outstanding professional combat
troopers who get the job
done and they get a job,
they get the job done
on time and on target.
And those are awesome solid guys that
maintain the reputation of the seal teams.
They maintain it.
Okay.
And then you got the crew at the bottom
and these are the guys that slipped
through the cracks.
They work the system and while they're
technically classified as seals,
these aren't guys that are like respected
by other guys in the seal teams.
And quite honestly,
these are usually the guys that talk
the most and brag or boast about being a
seal.
And these are the guys that they don't
build the reputation or maintain the
reputation to seal teams.
These are the guys that live off
the reputation of the seal teams.
Hmm.
When in all likelihood they probably
haven't contributed anything themselves to
that reputation. Hmm. Leeches.
But
that is what it is.
And,
and as I always say, the teams
gave me everything, the good,
the bad and the ugly.
And I wouldn't,
I wouldn't change a thing. I love
the seal teams, the frog man,
the Awu gunner in a seal platoon,
the point man, the corpsman,
the radio man,
the rear security,
the platoon chief and the
LPO and the OIC and the Aoi.
See
those guys,
those guys in a seal platoon,
the ones that carry the
weight and carry the torch,
those guys are in my blood.
I love those guys that
are always well, okay. Uh,
last question
Jocko.
What does discipline really mean?
You know,
besides waking up early and how do I
employ it to all aspects of my life?
What does it really
mean? Yes, discipline it.
It does start with waking up early.
It really does.
Okay,
but that is just the beginning in,
I always say that discipline is
the root of all good qualities,
but you have to absolutely apply it to
things outside of just waking up early.
It's, it's everything.
It's working out every day,
making yourself stronger and faster
and more flexible and healthier.
Discipline is eating the right
foods to a few. Your system,
it,
it's about disciplining your emotions
so you can make good decisions.
It's about having the
discipline to control your ego
so your ego doesn't get out
of hand and control you.
It's about treating people the way you
would want to be treated and and doing
the tasks that you don't
necessarily want to do,
but that you know will
help you or help your team.
It's about facing your fears.
Takes discipline to face your
fears so you can conquer them.
And that's what discipline is.
Discipline means taking the hard road,
the uphill road to do.
What's right for yourself
and for other people.
It's so often the easy path,
the easy path that calls to
us to be weak for that moment,
to break down for that moment
to give in to the desire and
the short term gratification.
But the discipline will not allow that.
The discipline calls for
strength and fortitude and we'll,
it won't accept weakness,
it won't tolerate another breakdown.
The discipline CANSIM
like it's your worst enemy,
but the reality is
discipline is your best friend.
It will take care of you like nothing
else can and it'll put you on that path,
the path to strength and health
and intelligence and happiness.
Most importantly,
it'll put you on that path,
okay
to freedom
and I think that's all
we've got for tonight.
So
thanks to everybody out
there for putting on those,
those headphones and
listening to this podcast.
Thanks for the feedback you give us.
It's definitely good to know that people
are listening and getting something out
of it.
Also,
thanks for subscribing and reviewing and
spreading the word and thanks to on it
for the support for the great
products that they make.
We appreciate that and please
support them for supporting us.
Okay.
And speaking of support,
another big way you can support us
and the podcast is if you want to buy
something, anything, especially
the books that we talk about,
go through our website to
get to amazon.com echo.
How do they do that?
Just like how you said,
just instead of going straight
to amazon.com go to Jocko,
podcast.com or Jocko podcast,
[inaudible] dot com or Jocko store.
Oh. And they just click on
that and it'll go to Amazon.
So Jocko podcast.com and that's if they're
going to buy anything. Yeah. Anything.
Um, yeah, the books or
even, yeah, anything. If you
want to buy some duct tape,
get that duct tape through Jocko,
podcast.com. Yeah, that's awesome. Yeah.
Do that.
And when you go to Onnit,
o n n I t.com/jocko okay.
And get some Alpha brain,
you know,
improve the cognitive start thinking.
We'll start bringing them, bringing
the thought up. Yeah. Proof the mind.
And if you're going to get after it, I'm
a hard workout. Get some shroom tech.
Highly recommended you like,
you'll be glad you did. Yeah.
You'd be glad you did for
sure. The shroom tech. Yeah.
You know, uh, awesome.
We really appreciate that
support. Again, that's how,
that's how Echo Charles his host in all
this stuff and paying for all this stuff
and all that.
So it's much appreciated.
If you want to talk to us or
engage with us or ask us questions,
you can find us on the
interwebs on Twitter.
I'm at Jockowillink and of
course Echo Charles is at echo.
Charles.
Thanks for leaving reviews
of the podcast on iTunes.
That helps us with the rank and gets us
pushed up and gets us more listeners.
Also,
if you,
if you bought the book extreme ownership
that Leif and I jump on Amazon throw
review up there,
that helps us out as well,
man. We're asking a lot
of the people. Yeah, I,
I feel like, I feel like everyone
was kind of doing that anyway though.
You know, it's, I think, who's
everyone? The people, man.
The people, the people. Well, the
biggest thing is spread the word.
Spread the word if you want,
if you feel like, yeah,
if it's been worth your while,
spread the word and you know,
really most importantly to you,
you,
you, that's listening to this.
It's trying to get better,
trying to be better,
trying to do better.
Thank you
for getting out there and getting
after it because when you make yourself
better,
you make the world better.
And so, until next time,
this is Jocko and echo. Oh
out.