This is Jocko podcast number
one 63 that Echo Charles and me,
Jocko Willink. Good
Evening Echo. Good evening.
I am bleeding out.
Okay.
I can feel my life ebbing away as blood
seeps from my body into the Iraqi soil.
A few brown weeds splashed.
Crimson now are crushed around me as I
lay sprawled on my back in the middle of
this ambush.
The weeds offer no concealment.
I'm in the open alone and wounded
sizzles of pain hit me in waves
like pulses of electricity.
A bullet has torn off my left arm.
Okay.
After I get hit,
I reach over to grab my left hand.
Okay.
It isn't there.
Yeah.
I hunt around feeling only the gear
on the far left side of my body.
No arm. I tried to move the
fingers on my left hand,
but my mind sends signals to
a station that doesn't exist.
Now I can't feel anything but pain.
Yeah.
Bullets kicked dirt in my face
through my night vision goggles.
I see green blooms of light
strobing the darkness.
Muzzle flashes from automatic weapons 10
meters away and enemy machine gun opens
fire again.
It is a belt fed,
Russian made crew served weapon,
probably a PKM.
They sound like giant zippers tearing
open when the gunners go cyclic,
like now
the air around me or rubs
with sharp cracks. The
miniature sonic booms of seven,
six, two millimeter bullets speeding
past me a 2,500 feet per second.
The terrorist gunner lowers his aim.
Yeah,
a spurt of dust blows across my face.
Again,
several bullets pass so close to my head
that I feel shockwaves as they go by
to the left and AK 47 assault
rifle opens up. Then another,
I'm pinned in a crossfire
without cover or concealment.
A crippled sitting duck in a kill zone
at least a hundred meters long and 75
deep.
Okay.
With my right hand, I key the radio
handset I have mounted on my chest,
troops in contact troops in contact,
I called him my command.
We have three severely wounded,
including me.
Okay.
Static greets my words.
I can't duck.
I can't crawl away.
There's no place to hide. All I can do
is ignore the incoming fire and stay
the PK. I'm a gunner. PKM
gunner finds the range,
bullets crack around me,
dirt flies.
The terrorist eases up on the tripper
trigger, but only for a second
I hear him on leash, another burst, then
I hear nothing at all.
Okay.
And those right there are some excerpts
from the opening chapter of a book
called the Trident,
which is written by a retired seal
officer by the name of Jason Jay Redmond.
And this book does an incredible job
not only of bringing the reader to the
front lines in some pretty
chaotic combat situations,
but equally important,
it brings the reader into the challenges
of leadership and the challenges of
life, especially the challenges
of facing significant adversity.
And Jay's book humbly splays those
challenges wide open for all to see.
And that humility from Jay is what
makes this book so beneficial.
He tells us plainly and bluntly of
his personal triumphs and tragedies is
victories and his defeats and how he
eventually found success and overcame by
travelling the path of humility.
And since I have the honor
of actually knowing Jay,
he is been kind enough to come by this
evening and talk about his experiences
with us. So with that, Mr j Redmond,
thanks for stopping by brother
Jocko rather echo. Thank you. Good.
Thank you both for having me on. Awesome.
Awesome to have you sitting here, man.
Hey Man, honor to still be here.
Blessed, that's for sure. You know,
like I tell so many people I'm
living on a second chance, you know,
you and I got too many
brothers who are not,
I don't know why the big man decided
to give me a chance, but, uh,
I'm making the most of it.
Okay. Outstanding. So, uh,
I wanna try and start a little bit at
the beginning so people get a little bit
familiar with where you are. Everyone
always wants to know where people, where
people came from, how they grew up.
I'm going to the book right here.
I came from a family with a rich
tradition of service. So in retrospect,
this made sense.
My Dad was a US army airborne rigor at
Fort Campbell during the Vietnam War.
My paternal grandfather
earned a distinguished flying
cross while piloting a B
24 liberator bomber over the flack
filled skies of Hitler's Europe.
I also had a great uncle who flew fighter
aircraft and the southwest Pacific
during World War II.
He made the ultimate sacrifice
in battle against the Japanese.
I dreamed of adding to that legacy,
a life of combat metals and service.
I was young and naive and had a
long road to travel before I could
truly understand what my grandfather and
great uncle gave for the country.
But that idealism became
a very big part of me.
I wanted to carry a rifle for a living.
My Dad watched this desire grow
in me and decided to focus it.
My freshman year in high school. He sat
me down in our tiny living room and said,
you know, Jay, we had these guys
come through airborne school.
They were us navy called seals.
They jumped out of airplanes,
swam. They bluets blew stuff up.
Given how you love the water,
maybe you ought to look into them.
So your dad planted the seed, Huh? It did?
Yeah. A young age. And you know, this was
90, probably, uh, or I'm sorry, um,
probably 89 show, 88, 89.
So back then you really couldn't find
hardly anything about the seal teams.
And uh,
this was at a point in time
where Gi Joe was big. I mean,
I'm a, you know, 13, 12,
13 year old kid into that.
And then I was probably about 14 when
my dad told me about the seal teams and
uh, started researching
it, found almost nothing.
And by sheer happenstance,
one of the guys in our church was
a huge special operations buff.
Uh, he was a guy that was
unable to go in the military.
He had had polio actually
when he was a kid,
but he was just infatuated by it.
And he had done tons of research and he
actually had collected some things about
the seal teams.
He had an old soldier of
Fortune Magazine Day. Yeah.
Awesome. It's so different nowadays
know nowadays you just Google it.
I exactly back in the day,
you had to be lucky enough to know some
dude in church who happened to have a
copy of the issue of soldier of Fortune
magazine. Is that still a thing?
And it would a fortune still out
there dude. It actually is. Uh,
as a matter of fact,
somehow in some weird twist of fate,
I ended up being on the cover of soldier
of fortune and after the book came out
and it was the most bizarre
thing because now you know,
you're in the military and
you look at this stage,
you kind of laugh at soldier of fortune.
It's a little bit,
uh,
you
know,
really focuses on probably the,
the Gung Ho aspect of sof as
opposed to you came full circle,
full circle, that's for sure.
Field of soldier fortune.
It was, it was pretty funny.
But um,
but that magazine and that journey of
coming to understand who these guys were
that you really couldn't find much about
them. It just drew me in even more.
And the only thing,
the core thread that I found over and
over again was toughest training in the
military. And, you
know, I was a young kid,
I was a small kid and I just had this
inner fire that if you told me I couldn't
do something, it just drove
me even more to want to do it.
And everyone, you know, at
that point in my life, uh,
that's probably four foot
11 and about 95 pounds.
So when I told people I
was going to become a seal,
they laughed me out of the room. And
that just fueled me even harder. And,
uh, I set my sights on that dream
and that's where I was going.
And you use some of the things you
did or you started playing football,
you started getting involved in sports
to make sure you were physically fit and
all that.
So that was part of the driving factor.
It's part of any good way
to sort of prepare at least
in a minimum way for buds.
Yeah, absolutely. I mean, I wanted to
build a mindset. I knew that fitness,
I knew that being part of a team, I knew
that pushing myself in different areas.
So I started wrestling and I started
playing football and I was smallest guy on
our team. But man, I just, I love
football. I've always loved football.
My Dad had always told me, no,
you're too small. You're too small,
you're going to get hurt.
And uh, so probably my 10th
grade year I said, you know,
I don't care what you're telling me,
I'm going out for the team. And uh,
thankfully we lived in a
really small town and uh,
I think they would take anyone and they
looked at me and they say, well, you know,
we can at least use you as a tackling
dummy. And a, and I said, Roger, that,
I'll do it, man. Awesome.
You know, I will, you know,
I'll hit somebody as hard
as my 95 pounds cam and uh,
got out there and just, I love the
sport. You know, I was, you know,
not a starter in any way, but, uh,
I was out there every day just grinding
and I'd try and lay the hardest hits
that I could on people.
And I played receiver and
cornerback and Nice. Yeah. Now.
I was also a little bit as a,
as I read through the book,
kind of piecing together what you
were like when you were a kid.
I got to this point here.
I know that she's kind of a little
bit of a different direction.
Going back to the book at the same time,
I fell in with the wrong crowd.
I got a job my junior year and
my work friends were drinkers.
I started sneaking out of the house by
sliding down the intent to pull outside
my window. I'd meet with
friends, we'd go drink.
I'd stagger home drunk at odd hours of
the night, scaling the side of the House.
With the help of that Pole, my family
tried to nudge me into course correction,
but I had a chip on my shoulder and
refuse to listen, especially to my dad.
Things got worse.
My relationship with my father and step
mom spiraled out of control into the
ground. Months of this war us
all down. As that slide continued
that that happens, right? I mean
that's straight up happens to kids,
especially boys. And I think it has to
do with, I'm going to prove myself. I,
that's what I think, hey,
I'm going to prove myself.
And one of the ways that
you prove yourself is by
proving that you're willing to
sacrifice in a way.
And what better way when you're
16 years old to prove is like, oh,
watch what I'll do. I'll drink,
I'll drink this whole bottle.
And I think that leads to young
males doing a lot of dumb stuff.
And it sounds like you were right on
board. Absolutely. You know, the, the,
the thing that shaped me though,
there's where I got really lucky as I
was smart enough and, and disciplined.
I have to understand that,
uh,
if I got myself in any
kind of major trouble,
I wouldn't be able to go in
the seal teams. So like I said,
we lived in a real small town in
rural North Carolina and you know,
drugs were prevalent. Um, and a lot of my
friends were starting to get into that.
And I just said, man, if I get, you know,
that'll stop me from going in the navy.
So at least there was kind of a line I
wasn't willing to cross. Uh, and I'm,
I'm fortunate there were a couple of
times we got ourselves in trouble where,
you know, we were right on the edge of
the law being involved and you know,
we managed to dodge that
bullet, but, uh, yeah,
I wanted to get out there,
I wanted to fit in.
So I think it's a combination of both
peer pressure as a young man, you know,
I want to fit in with this group.
Uh, but I have my hopes and dreams,
so this is the direction I'm going.
And I think that's where a lot
of young men get off track.
They want to fit in so much that they
give up on their hopes and dreams and that
gets sucked down this path. Uh, for me,
I had such a laser focus on
what I wanted to do that, uh,
it at least kept me in check.
Yeah. I will say this, just
to kind of add to that point,
from my perspective,
if you,
if you've got someone that's
aspiring to do something, you know,
hire the people that don't have those
aspirations are more than happy to try and
crush that dream for him and more
than happy to pull them down.
And so I've found that throughout life,
if you have some high aspiration
that you're trying to achieve,
where you see someone that's
got high aspirations that
they're trying to achieve,
you can watch the people around them.
If they're not good,
people will try to rip those things and
pull them down and pull them off that
track. Scary. I, and it's funny
equivocally true. I mean it's
one of the tenants, you know,
I now speak on something I call
the Pentagon at peak performance.
And the fifth level is, or I'm sorry,
the fourth level is social leadership.
So how we lead ourselves, how we build
our ring of friends and influencers and,
and your unequivocally right,
a great influence or an entrepreneur
I've been recently working with,
he gives an amazing analogy of,
he was up in Alaska on a vacation.
He was walking the beach and there was
a fisherman that was fishing with a net
and catching crabs and he was putting
the crabs in a bucket and you know,
it's early morning and the guys name
Bedros Keuilian and Pedro's was watching
this happen,
you know,
early in the morning and looked in the
bucket and there was about 10 crabs and
probably about five gallon bucket and
probably about eight inches of water.
And he kept watching his one crab would
climb up and grab on to the edge of the
bucket and try and pull itself out. And
he like tells the fishermen, hey man,
I want to let you know you're
going to lose one of your crops.
And the fishermen doesn't even
turn around and look at it,
keeps throwing his neck and he goes,
watch what happens.
And Vedros kind of steps back and he
looks down into the bucket and he watches
his all the other crabs grab onto that
other crab and pull him back down.
And he had this epiphany moment of the
circles of influence he had in his life
and he was like, oh my God, I
have crabs in my life. He's like,
I have people that I want to climb up and
be better and they're pulling me down.
And it is unequivocally true.
I mean it's something I brought up to
the bud students yesterday. I said,
if you want to be the best seal,
you need to surround yourself with
the guys who are driven discipline and
they're pushing themselves to the edge.
If you want to go to the next level,
you need to surround yourself with the
guys who were either already there or
they aspire to get there.
Because if you're going to
surround yourself with people
who are content to just
drink and not move forward at all,
they're going to try and pull you into
that circle because they're going to feel
threatened that you don't
want to do what they're doing.
And they want you to assimilate with them.
Verse driving forward and being
successful. It's unfortunate.
It's just kind of a way of
life. It's a, it's a horrible,
it's a horrible situation. So watch
out for it because it's everywhere.
So you end up, so you graduated
high school and go to a
recruiter and boom. Right.
I mean any, any other particular things
around the recruitment process? Yeah,
the recruitment process was actually,
I actually kind of got off track a little.
So I went to the recruiting station. I
as soon as I decided I want to be a seal,
I went to the recruiting station.
So I was 15 years old,
this 95 pound weakling and walk into
the recruiting station and unlike, Hey,
I want to be a seal.
And there was an old crusty,
I mean he was like an old
school probably 25 years,
e six and just crusty as all get out,
you know,
boatswain's mate. And that dude basically
laughed me out of the office was like,
get Outta here. Stop
wasting our time. You know,
you couldn't even carry the paddle.
Much less the boat, you know,
get out of my office.
And it didn't phase me in the least.
I came back like next week and was
like, I want to be a seal. And uh,
they,
this guy chased me out of the office.
I came back about four or five times and
he just continued to not even give me
the time of day.
So finally I was kinda tired of that.
I try the way things are real rough when
the recruiter won't give a kid the time
of day. Yeah. Try to make that
quota. This is hardcore. Oh Man.
Yeah. Well, I mean, you think about
a 25 year, he's six. He, yeah,
he was at a point he didn't
really care. So, uh, you know,
when I got to the point,
uh,
I came back again probably about eight
months later and at this point I had
really started to train. I was focused
on it. I didn't let him determine me.
And I came back and he had left just
by sheer happenstance. He was gone.
And there was a new recruiter in there, a
guy by the name of Henry Horn. Um, Henry,
if you're out there
and you listen to this,
I've never been able to
track him down and thank him.
But Henry took me in and was like,
yeah man, absolutely sit down.
And they had this video,
you may remember this be someone special.
And it was the cheesiest,
it was like 1980s video at uh,
at its best. And uh, and it
was this high speed, you know,
the seals come in on a helicopter and
they'd get out and they take down this
target and take out these
terrorists and you know, the,
the tagline is be someone special.
And I just ate it up man.
And uh,
came back on a regular basis and a,
and Henry was fantastic. He told me, these
are the things you need to do, you know,
AskPat fitness, this is what's
going to happen. So went to, uh,
went to go sign up, you know,
right. As I was turning 17,
I was going to do the delayed entry
program and I went to go sign up and went,
mmm. Um, well I've got
a backup for a second.
There was a glitch. I'm sorry.
I've got my facts backwards here.
I actually,
because of the deal with the crusty e six,
I was, uh, and him being a block to me,
I changed my mind inside to go army.
At first, Henry happened after this,
I'm sorry, I got that backwards. Henry
happened after this and when I went back,
I decided to join the army. I
said, well, fine. My Dad, you know,
he was army the Rangers,
I'll go the green baret route.
So I went to meps to pro or
to do my intake screening
for the army delayed entry
program. And I failed the
physical because when I was a kid,
I had ruptured my eardrum and I had a
lot of scar tissue on my eardrum and the
army said, oh, well, you're not
going to be able to equalize.
So they tried to convince me
to still go in. They were like,
oh well you don't have to be
an airborne ranger. You know,
you can do this or you can do that. You
can drive trucks. And I was like, no man,
that's not what I want to do.
So I left and I didn't sign up and
probably a couple months went by and then
that's when I came back and the crusties
six was gone and Henry Horn was there
and really helped pave that path. So
kind of an interesting road. And uh,
I think the lesson is this is there's
always going to be roadblocks that are
going to deter you from your dreams.
You know, don't let it stop you.
Keep driving forward,
uh, cause by, you know,
if I just listened to that guy
right from the beginning, you know,
I never would have been a seal. So
you go in, you show up at Bud's.
I like this as a good,
going back
to the book, your, your intro to Bud's,
one night I was as ordered to escort a
member of class one 99 back to his room.
Building in six oh two he'd
quit the program and the
navy required an escort for
anyone who rang the bell.
During hell week,
I went off to find him in the darkness.
He was waiting for me.
A smaller guy like me wrapped in a
blanket. He was shivering so badly.
He seemed ready to fly apart. He'd put
the blanket over his head like a hood,
giving him a monastic look.
He said little.
So we made our way to the barracks and
silence. I walked alongside him, fit,
fit to burst, wanting to get any details
on what I'd soon experience. Finally,
I couldn't stand it anymore.
As you reached his door and opened it,
I blurted out. So come
on, man. What was it like?
He turned to me and looked me in the eyes.
His rooms,
night light cast an orange
glow across his face.
His skin was waxen and he
looked hollowed out at length.
He answered in a slow earnest
tone. Dude, it was so cold.
I would have poured gasoline all over
myself and little match just so I could
have been warm for a few seconds
before I burned to death.
He stepped back without another word
and slammed his door for the first time.
I wondered what I'd gotten myself into.
That's legit right there.
Intro to buds.
So there's a, so not only did
that blow my mind, uh, you know,
there's a funny little side story.
We actually had to edit that.
So the fire thing,
uh,
we actually created because
what he actually, he told
me that exact thing, the,
so the,
the dialogue is the same,
but what he told me was about
as vulgar as all get out.
It would have made the
book rated triple x and a,
and it was so mind blowing because
I mean, you know, the fire thing,
we tried to come up with what
is as impactful as possible,
but it does not convey,
I'll let your imaginations run wild.
But what he told me and he
slammed the door in my face,
left me so stunned that I was like,
what the hell did I get myself into?
I mean it was, but we could not put it in
the boat. I mean it was so bad. I mean,
I was like,
my kids can never read that
chuck check. So, uh, anyways,
I mean then you get there,
but you go through buds
and buds is cool and you,
you write about buds a little bit in here,
but you don't spend a bunch of
time on it because as we know,
buds is not a huge part of
our careers in the seal teams.
And I'm going to jump right right ahead to
the book here.
Seven years in,
three South American deployments
into my career as a seal.
I found myself in Fort Knox,
Kentucky working as a basic warfare
instructor with a small group of fellow
operators. We worked 18 hour days,
but being 20 something and single,
once the gear was stowed,
all we wanted to do was get out on the
town and blow off some steam. Work hard,
play hard.
That was our pre nine 11 mantra.
The nineties teams
work hard,
play hard.
Uh,
I always have to explain to people how
cool it is being in the teams being an e
five and the teams or what were you
any fibernet sex at this point? Uh,
I was in new five e five and the teams,
and I was telling the story the other day,
this,
when I got to seal team one that
there was, I was a new guy in,
was quietly walking through the locker
room trying to keep my eyes averted from
looking at anyone. And
I hear this guy go, ah,
yes. And I was like, oh my God.
And it was this like barbaric yell
from this human being a who is one.
And then I looked at him and he
was this monster guy, probably six,
seven,
six,
six 280 pounds of tattooed flesh.
And someone's like, what
happened? And he goes,
I just made e five master
chief is far as I'm concerned.
So yeah, you know, you get to be an e five
in a seal platoon, you know, you've got,
if you, if you're not looking for
a lost a lot of responsibility,
you won't find it. But
you won't, you know,
you're a little bit above some of the
crap work. So it's not a bad place to be.
And that's where you were doing
during deployment, after deployment,
three deployments to uh,
South America and doing
the training gig where you,
were you at training cell at the team at
this time or was it already consolidate
data? No, each team had a Joan
individual training still. Yup.
I did that too.
And this is also the time during one of
these trips where you met your future
wife. That's right. So you know, you know,
the seal teams are an interesting place
because being an all male unit, you know,
the only time you have an opportunity to
meet people ladies is typically in the
bars. And because we did such a good
job, you know, I tell people, uh,
the mindset of the early teams
really was, you know, uh,
you know, Marcinko captured that
mindset and his book the road warrior.
But it's interesting to see post nine 11,
how guys are so laser focused
on combat, you know, but for us,
you know, literally we trained
hard and then you know,
you were actually looked down on if you
didn't go out and party and burn it down
to like four in the morning and then get
an hour of sleep and get up and start
training again the next day,
which was just stupid, you know,
you weren't operating at
optimal efficiency, but that
was just the way it was.
That was life and a accepted
it and drove through. So yeah,
I was fortunate enough one
night we went into a, a crazy,
huge bar that somebody had
scouted out and said, hey man,
this is a target rich environment. And
uh, the Phoenix Hill tavern. And uh,
went in there and yeah,
beautiful blonde
walked in and I was like,
I need to get to know this young lady.
You did. All right, man. Uh, along
along the course of this, um,
you apply for the CME to animal program,
which is the same program I did.
I think you were a couple of years
behind me and we're going to the book.
I had applied to the semen,
to admiral program something.
The navy started to encourage top
performing enlisted to become officers.
Only 50 candidates a year were accepted
back then to the competition was fierce.
I gained a slot in the navy,
sent me to college just in time
to miss the outbreak of the war.
I watched the towers fall.
I recognize the magnitude of the moment
and left school and a days fully aware
that our country was heading to war.
With three years of college ahead of me,
I feared I'd miss my chance to be
a part of it. A few days later,
I drove back to my old seal team to see
my former CEO and mentor commander Vince
Peterson.
He had stuck his neck out for me more
than once and had been instrumental in
getting me a shot,
a slot in the semen admiral program.
I told them I wanted to drop out of school
so I could get back to a platoon and
help with the war effort. Commander
Peterson sat listening quietly as he,
as I explained my desire to come back.
He was a legend in the seal teams.
He had been a former marine before joining
the navy and headed to seal training
at the age of 36 he was highly respected
both up and down the chain of command.
In my leadership fence analogy,
most men fell on one side
of the fence or the other.
While there were those small few who had
the unique ability to stand on top and
move back and forth for Vince Peterson,
there was no fence.
As I sat down with him and asked
him to put me back in the platoon,
he looked me dead in the eye and said,
read. This will not be a short war.
It's going to go on for years and
we're going to need strong warriors and
leaders for upcoming battles.
You need to stay in school.
Then come back and lead
check
I,
when I read that,
of course I thought about,
guess what I was doing
when nine 11 happened,
I was in college as well
all in the same program.
That's probably a year or two
ahead of you. And guess what I did,
same thing.
I called the detailer who was a friend
of mine who I'd worked for and I said,
hey, I don't care about
college. I'll do online.
I don't care about any of this. Sent me
back to a seal team right now please.
And you know this individual to is
as well. And I know who this guy is.
And the,
he told me the exact same thing.
He said this war is going to last
a long time. Yeah, of course.
I didn't believe it. And it, you know,
and this is what's interesting. I
recently saw the guy that called and I saw
him and his wife who I know his wife and
she's a great person and I was telling
her this, telling you this and you know,
she said it was so awesome to hear.
She goes, do you know how
many calls he got that day?
So there was zero unique
about Jocko calling the,
the CLD Taylor insane, sir. Get
me back to a team right now.
Every single guy that wasn't an a
seal team. And the teams or if we,
everyone that a B billet of any
kind was calling the detail insane.
Kippy back to a t you put me in coach.
Yeah.
And it goes to that meant telling
you were talking about we, we were,
we were just training and training and
training and it'd be like training for a
game and training for the
Superbowl and never get to play.
So you,
you,
so you actually did a great job in
college and you, you, you are an ROTC too,
right? Oh, it was, yeah.
See I got the real scam deal where I just
went to college and it wasn't wearing
a uniform. I was like far enough
ahead of you that I got the deal.
You were in the original program,
so you got commissioned and went to school
is an officer say you're getting paid
officer pay check. I go to school.
I got the most ridiculous deal.
I apologize to the taxpayers, I think.
And the navy quickly realized, okay, yeah,
we screwed this one up. So I think it
took them two iterations. Yeah. I was in,
because I think I was in the third
iteration, third or fourth, but, uh, no,
we actually were required to be
a part of ROTC. So, you know,
every day we were,
we were up early and we,
and the Hampton roads in ROTC at that
time was the largest ROTC consortium on
the east coast.
So you had a Hampton University,
you had Odu Old Dominion University
and you had Norfolk state.
And they had at that time probably about,
I think we were at about 330,
a Midshipman,
an officer candidates,
and we had a huge contingent
of x enlisted. Uh,
so there was actually,
it was probably six or seven seals and
the program there at that time. Um,
so it was good. I had teammates to
go through with, but uh, yeah man,
we played all the games and real quickly
I realized, I said, okay, you know,
they want it, you've got
to step up, you know,
they're going to put you into
these different positions.
And a lot of the guys who had come there
before me were kind of like, no dude,
we don't want to do anything. We don't
want to be involved. We just want to,
you know, a lot of
times, typical team guys,
we want to create our
own little circle of,
of trust and we don't want to let anybody
else in the circle. And I was like,
Nah man, we got to change
that mindset. You know,
there's young kids here that we could
influence to become future frogmen I shed.
And uh, cause there was no, they had all
these communities at the school. They had,
uh, they had, you know, surface warfare
community. They had the aviation club,
they had the sub Mariner club,
but there was no special operations club.
And there were young kids were interested
in. I said, Whoa, we need to create this,
you know, we have the experience,
we can help these kids.
And then the other thing I said is I
said, well, you know,
I'm going to try and step
up into leadership positions
and I think all the rest
of us to do the same. And, uh, and
thankfully, you know, it worked.
We all jumped on board. And
you know, I was fortunate,
I did excel in school and I
ended up leaving the school
as the student battalion,
commanding officer. Uh, prior
to being commissioned to am,
I was the regimental commander at
officer candidate school and that was,
you know, the number one
position. And I was a man. Yeah.
I was talking to my mom
and I mentioned to him,
which I shouldn't have done because my
mom just doesn't understand. I was like,
well yeah, I'm, I'm, you know,
I'm the registries because at the last
couple of weeks of ocs and she's like,
listen,
what's going on now?
Cause then I could call cause you
weren't allowed to call. So I said, well,
we're doing this and I'm in
charge of the thing here.
It's called the regimental commander.
And she goes, oh, what he you,
you're the commander? And I said,
yeah, I'm the regimental commander.
And she goes on, are you
in charge of? And I said,
I am overseeing the cleaning of every
toilet at officer candidate school and
it's going quite well. So
yeah. Spotless, spotless,
uh,
you.
So you do a great job in college and now
you go back to the teams after college.
Going back to the book,
instead of having an advantage,
I found myself left behind.
Everything had changed and as our
platoon went through its training cycle,
I always felt like I was playing catch up.
I made mistakes and exercises that I've
never made in the 90s they made me edgy
and tense,
feeling the pressure of trying to be a
leader and drinking from that training
fire hose. At the same time, I
got tight and held on even harder,
which only made things
worse in our time off.
I drowned my frustrations
and booze and routinely,
routinely made an ass of myself.
None of this was helping my credibility
with the men I was supposed to be
leading,
but I didn't see that at the moment.
It also didn't help that senior chief,
Pete,
Carrie and I despised each other
almost from our introduction.
He was a good skilled seal and I
respected as tactical abilities,
but I felt his people skills were
lacking rough and abrasive at times.
His leadership style clashed with mine,
which set us on a collision course.
While I privately railed against Kerry,
I was too blinded by
arrogance to see my own flaws.
I wasn't making a good
transition to being an officer.
I'd been enlisted for so long.
I identified with my enlisted teammates
more as one of them rather than as one
of their leaders.
It put me too far away from the fence.
The senior chief and the Aoi see are
supposed to work closely together to make
sure the team functions effectively.
The AIC and that's assistant officer in
charge is also supposed to learn from
the chiefs tactical experience that
never happened in our platoon. Instead,
I refuse to humble myself and listened
to the senior chief as the pre deployment
workup wore on.
I wouldn't con we w we couldn't
conceal our dislike for each other.
The feud spilled out into the open and
culminated with a public screaming match
in Europe after a tactical
exercise with some NATO allies
in the weeks that followed
my arrival within the team,
our relationship became the
cancer in our locker room.
By the time we got to Afghanistan,
we refused to be civil to each other.
I had lost touch entirely with what it
meant to be a leader during the daily
briefs.
We would openly take shots at each other.
I talked about this dynamic
many times with my superior,
the platoons officer in charge one
day the OIC finally said, look,
you do have to work this out.
I'm tired of it.
We never could or did work things out.
Different platoons structure things
in different ways. In Our platoon,
senior enlisted members acted as fire
team leaders with chiefs and some more
experienced officers acting as
the assault force commanders.
I had been assigned as neither.
If I'd taken a step back,
I might have realized that I hadn't
given my Bosch as much confidence in my
leadership, but I didn't see that. I
only felt slighted. And in bittered
rough tour. Yeah, but
all brought on by myself.
I mean, you know, the dynamics
obviously created some interesting,
uh, you know, problems. But
you know, as often happens,
I wasn't taking ownership of
my own actions and instead
was just kind of trying
to point fingers
externally. Well, you know,
it's peak carries fault that these
things are happening when the reality was
80% of it was me, you know, 80% of it.
So it's one of the things that I
talked to a lot of individuals about.
I think you see it in special operations.
I know you and I both have spoken
to professional sports teams. Uh,
I see it there were young men Xcelerate
quickly and achieve this elite status
and then you get a little bit of a namerd
with who they are and their abilities
and lose sight of the end state,
which is to be an effective part of the
team to do their jobs. So ruthlessly,
well, it, it plays this huge part in
the team and at the end of the day,
whether you're in professional sports,
whether you're in the seal teams or even
whether you're in some elite business,
you know,
that's what has to happen.
And I lost sight of that and I'm more
focused externally instead of internally.
And really now I speak a lot on what
my three rules of leadership is.
And the foundational,
the first rule is lead yourself
and how you lead yourself.
80% of leadership is leading yourself.
You know,
you talk so much about discipline, it's
how you discipline yourself. Tell you,
structured yourself, it's how you,
yourself. It's how you set the example.
And in doing so,
it automatically leads to rule number two,
lead others.
It almost makes it easy to lead others
because you've already done all the work.
They want to follow you because
you're setting the example.
I kind of had it backwards.
I was trying to lead others,
but I wasn't leading myself and
it's almost impossible to do.
And I meet all these people,
you know,
that I've gone out in business and
talk to them. They say, Jay, man,
how do I be a better leader? And you know,
my first question I always ask them is,
how well do you lead yourself?
Uh, because that's where I really,
really failed. We talk, you know,
and the several times you've mentioned
a principle I talk about called the
leadership fence and leadership fence
was just kind of a concept I came up with
after watching a lot of really
good leaders and bad leaders,
including myself in that
category. Um, you know,
years later I looked back
and the idea was this,
that imagine a chain link fence and,
and that fence represents where
you are in your leadership journey.
And on one side of the fence
are all those you lead.
And on the other side are those
you report to your superiors.
Everybody has a natural tendency to kind
of fall on one side of the fence or the
other depending on how they grew up or
how they came into the organization. Um,
for me,
obviously when you start out as an e one,
I connected a lot more with the guys on
the side of the fence and I was leading,
uh, as a matter of fact,
the teams back then, uh,
typically wanted to switch coasts
with guys. If you're an enlisted guy,
they want to send you out to
the opposite coast. And, uh,
that didn't happen for me.
And I tell you what,
I look back on that now and I think
that was a mistake. Uh, I, you know,
I created a lot of my own problems
and the seal teams were right in their
thinking on how to do that because now
the hardest leadership often is pure
leadership, you know, to break
through those bonds of, Hey,
you and I were both friends,
but now I'm in charge of you.
So how do we navigate that waters?
And if you're close with those people,
it makes it a lot more difficult.
You know,
you have to be the one that really asked
to break those bonds. And sometimes,
you know, it can damage friendships
if you're not careful with that.
And I think I was more
focused on retaining that.
So that was on one side of the fence,
the other side of the fence.
A lot of times you see individuals that
come into an organization later at a
higher leadership position.
So they get brought in as an officer.
They get brought in as a
leader to a company and
they're mo more focused on that
leadership position that they don't
take the time to get to know the people.
They're leading a,
so they're too far away from the fence.
It's a chain link fence so that you
can talk through it so that you can
communicate through it.
And the best leaders have the ability
to be right up against that fence.
So whether they're on either side,
they're able to turn around and
gained guidance from the individuals,
whether it's their leadership and
communicated through to those they lead or
whether they're on the
side of communicating and
interacting with those they
lead and communicating through and
getting guidance from who they follow. Um,
okay.
Problems arise when you're too far away
from the fence. You know, the, the,
the leaders who are so far on the
other side of the fence at all they're
thinking about is how do I make the next
rank? You know, we know who they are.
I mean we've seen those guys who
literally, you know, you think, man,
you would like kill your mother to make
the next rank to be this or be that. Uh,
and then we also know those guys who,
you know,
they have no aspirations to try and get
better on the other side of the fence.
And we, you know, we joke
about the Cori fives, you know,
they're perfectly content,
you know, the magic position in
the seal teams where, you know,
you're at that level where,
um, you're high enough above
to not do the grunt work,
but you don't really have tremendous
responsibilities. I was way too far away.
That was the bottom line and this is
where I was tremendously failing and not
setting the example I wasn't
communicating with, uh,
with the leadership I was,
they were trying to provide me guidance
and basically saying, hey dude,
you're screwing things up.
And even even Pete carry
himself was trying to convey
to me in his very abrasive
way, hey dude, you know, this is
not the way you do things. Uh,
but I was blinded both by
having an excelled, uh,
at this point in my career, really
rocketing up, uh, and thinking, oh,
I know these things. You
know, I'm, I'm the man. Uh,
so humility is such a critical component
of leadership to take that step back.
And if anybody's given you advice,
always take a second to think through
it and, and, you know, evaluate, hey,
even if maybe you don't think it applies,
there's probably pieces of it that dude,
that's the reality.
Yeah. Always when someone's giving me
critique points, you know, and of course,
and it's every single,
I say,
every single person on earth doesn't
like receiving critique. Like,
and I always joke about the fact that
even when someone asks for criticism,
when they get it, they still get
mad. Even when I say, Hey, Jay,
would you read this thing that I just
wrote and tell me what you think of it?
And then you read it. You say, you
know, I thought it was a little,
you could do this a little bit
better. I'm going to be mad. Right.
Everyone gets mad. And so that's,
so what I do is the same thing.
I take a step back when somebody
gives me a critique point,
even though I'm completely offended
and I don't agree with them.
And I think I'm right because
I'm an egotistical maniac.
I put all that aside and I say,
wait a second,
there's a reason that they're telling me
this. There's gotta be some truth to it.
I liked,
I'm one of my favorite things about
this book is the fact that it,
it reveals the,
the,
the difficulties that we
have in the seal teams,
which are the same difficulties that I
see all the time. So people think, oh,
and you're in the seal teams,
everyone's just perfect. And
you know, this, this, uh,
Pete Carrie would be the perfect mentor
and he'd just be able to come along and,
and then you'd be the perfect recipient,
the perfect mentee, ready to learn.
And everything's just perfect and it,
and it's actually completely untrue.
And what you have in the seal
teams actually in the, in the,
like in the civilian sector and
companies and organizations,
they have these personality,
you know, different
personalities. In the seal teams.
And so you think, oh, in the seal
teams you don't have that. No,
you actually have it worse because
you've got these guys that have,
that have really built, their ego's been
built up and we all think we're great.
We all think we're a tactical genius.
We all think we don't have
anything to learn. And so,
so we have a lot of issues
around this exact kind of thing.
And it does completely derail not just
leaders, but it derails platoons and I,
I mean we would disband platoons
and when we would dismantle tune,
that means the platoon is
no longer going to exist.
We'd have a platoon coming through
training. The platoon would get disbanded.
It doesn't happen very often, but
it happens. And when it happens,
it has,
it has zero to do with the [inaudible]
e fives and usually the Esx is,
and it has 100% to do with the senior
aesics is the chiefs and the officer's
inside the platoon that just are
disasters. And it does happen.
And I think the fact that you,
the,
the fact that you talk through some of
these issues are, I mean that's what,
that's where it's very revealing about
the seal teams in this book is like, Hey,
we got,
you know,
we got the same issues that they
have an other or any other team,
any other organization
and that, that, you know,
that thing that you talk about this,
this fence, you know, that's, to me,
that's the dichotomy of leadership,
right?
That's like you can go too far in one
direction or the other and if you go too
far in one direction or the other, you're
going to, you're going to fall apart.
Yeah. So check. All right,
now you're on deployment in Afghanistan
and I always, I always mentioned this,
I haven't mentioned it yet,
but I'll mention it right now because
I'm only reading small portions of this
book and there so much more great detail
in the book and you'll have a better
understanding of these lessons when you,
when you read the whole thing.
So if it seems a little bit,
you know,
if it seems it's jumping
around a little bit,
it's just because I'm
only reading chunks of,
cause I'm not gonna read the whole damn
book. You can read it yourself. All right,
so now speaking of jumping around,
you're in Afghanistan,
you had a mission go down where it sounded
like you guys got some bad intel and
it caused a little bit of a problem.
You hit the target pretty hard and you
guys got put on an operational pause mean
and hey you guys aren't
going to do anything and,
and that's a great story and how that
unfolds is great and people should read so
they can learn lessons from that.
But then I'm going to go skip a lesson.
Here you are in the Chow Hall and you're
sitting with some of your boys and I'm
specifically losing using that term
because at this point you definitely are.
We're boys with the boys
and I'm going to the book.
I'd been searching for a way to prove
myself ever since I'd come aboard now the
opportunity to do so had
just fallen in my lap.
I had to take it in time.
I learned there was nothing more dangerous
on the battlefield than an immature
and arrogant officer who feels
he needs to prove himself.
It can lead men to their death and what
you're looking at is you happen to be
sitting in the Chow Hall with the
commanding general and these guys kind of
your, your boys kind of egg you
on to go talk to them about, hey,
why are we, why are we standing out
in a year, an ensign at this point?
Okay, so here we go. I walked
over and stood beside the
generals table, excuse me,
general,
and it's in Redmond naval special warfare.
Do you have a couple of minutes?
His aides glowered up at me.
Stamped on their faces is like,
who the hell are you? Look,
that made me momentarily waiver.
The general invited me to sit down.
His aides looked frosted and grew
more so after I began to talk, sorry,
I just wanted to talk to you
about this operational pause.
We still seem to be in.
I began the general's face registering
nothing but interest. I continued.
I know there was a miscommunication
with our first mission,
but we know the enemies out there and
we'd really like to take the opportunity
to go after them. The general heard me
out then replied diplomatically. Well,
Anson, I've got to look at all
the strategic factors here.
We must always weigh the strategic
impact with the impact on the civilian
populace and there are implications
to going out and operating at night.
I understand that sir,
right now where at a crazy time in the
war and we have to balance what we're
doing. Well, general, I said I can
hardly read that with a straight face.
Well, generally I said we really feel like
we can contribute in a positive way by
going after the men who pose a clear and
present threat to coalition forces in
general was noncommittal
but remained polite.
I don't think as aids took their eyes
off me through the entire conversation,
I could feel them boring holes through me.
I thanked them for their time,
got up and headed back to my table.
The other two operators were gone.
Why hadn't they stuck around?
Get some,
yeah. Be aware of a peer pressure
and be where, you know, once again,
it comes back to that, that
lead yourself, lead yourself,
that founding principle because you know,
this was a dangerous thing. And, and, and,
and I did this several times during
that deployment. You know, this,
this misunderstanding or this idea that
somehow there's this shortcut to be an
effective leader, that there's this
push button, easy button, that beep,
look at me now. I'm a great leader and
this really was this moment. And I mean,
people understand this was an
interesting time. So this was,
um, this was July of 2005. So,
um,
June 28th of 2005 operation red wings
had just happened and that was our troop.
So we had, um, you know, we
had lost five of our guys,
including our troop commander. Uh,
we had lost my air Christianson.
We had lost my good friend and the
OIC of that platoon, Mike Mcgreevey,
I originally was in echo platoon.
Um,
we had trained alongside
those guys. So, uh,
we were all grieving and
we all wanted revenge.
We all wanted to go after the enemy.
So the very first mission
we did was to mission.
You talked about that got us
in a little bit of trouble.
So now take the dynamics of everybody
grieving because of the loss of our
teammates and,
and then doing our first mission and
being put in hack because of really some
outstanding issues that you
can read about in the book.
We had actually done everything right
but it kind of got placed back on us.
So I just, you know, it's these
moments that as a young leader,
whether you're in a business, whether
you're in the military, law enforcement,
whatever you do,
that you see this shortcut,
oh look what I can do. And
it got fueled when, you know,
my teammates and I sat there and
started talking and you know,
teammates where the biggest,
you know,
shit talkers on the planet and uh,
they uh,
they definitely were egging
me on and I ate it up, hook,
line and sinker and I was like,
you are absolutely right.
Here is a great opportunity for me
to, you know, shed some, you know,
amazing wisdom and insight to this general
where he now is going to be like, oh,
young ensign.
You're so right.
We should absolutely allow you guys to
go out and conduct all these operations
because I'm, you know, I'm not smart
enough to allow this to happen. I mean,
the air,
the arrogance that I had and really
sad that I didn't think through,
you know, what are the implications of
this, you know, for you to go do that.
I mean, it was just a stupid decision. Uh,
and I realized it as soon as those
guys were gone, like all of a sudden,
I'm like,
Huh,
what did you just do more on? And, uh,
as I walked back from the Chow Hall
to, uh, to our, you know, our camp,
I was like,
this isn't going to go.
He went and told your boss
that you did it right. I did.
I went straight back to my CEO and I said,
Hey,
I want to let you know what just happened.
I said, I thought it was good idea.
Um, and, uh, I don't think it was,
and you know, it was funny, he kind
of looked at me and he said, why, why,
why did you think that
was a good idea? And, uh,
and I said, well, I was, you know, I
didn't, I was doing it for the boys.
It was about the boys and you know,
so it really was,
and at the end of the day it was
about me. And that's where, you know,
really understanding that,
you know, in leadership,
you are the last point in the equation.
And
don't get me wrong,
you know,
there's an overlap of everything
that happens that we do.
So oftentimes you're focused on the
mission. You're focused on the man.
And of course by doing that, well,
there is a positive impact for you.
And there's nothing wrong with that.
But that thought process, it should be,
it should be by sequence, if you will, not
because you're focused on it, you know,
100% and you're right,
the biproduct of focusing on your
people and focusing on your mission,
the byproduct of that is you will
be successful. And the contrary,
the contrary in situation is literally
if you focus on yourself instead of your
people and your mission,
you will fail you, will you.
And you know what fails a strong word
because there's people in you and I know
him who have focused on
themselves and they, they, they,
they can win this battle and they
can win this tactical bound. They,
when this tactical battle and
they can get to a certain point,
but eventually it will come back on them.
And you won't be truly
successful as if you would,
as you would have been had
you focused on the men,
the mission and not focused on yourself.
I call those people leadership
wrecking balls too. They're good at,
they're good at what they do. Um,
you know, in some ways peak carriers,
one of those people, he was very good at
what he did and he got things done. Uh,
but he had a tendency to leave.
And a lot of organizations have these
individuals and they keep them around
because they do get things done,
but they leave a path of
destruction behind them.
And over time people don't want
to work with them and you know,
that's why I call him the leadership
wrecking ball. So you know,
I tell people you need to evaluate
yourself. Are you one of those people?
Do you turn around? You know, forward.
You look at the successes that you have,
but you turn around and look and there's
a path of destruction in a way there.
No doubt about it.
All right,
so you've guys eventually do get
back in the game. You, you the,
the pause,
operational pause gets lifted and you
guys are operating again and here you are
out on an operation. You're in an
Overwatch position on a hilltop.
Going back to the book
between burst of gunfire,
I heard him report troops in
contact troops in contact.
We're facing at least 20 enemy fighters,
a wash of static followed.
Then I heard joker add.
One of our Afghan soldiers is wounded.
We need reinforcements.
Jay, here's your chance.
Your teammates are in trouble.
I looked down into the valley.
Thousand feet below the slope was steep,
perhaps 60 degrees in places getting down.
There would be a serious
climb once at the bottom.
We'd have to maneuver to the sound of
the guns through broken terrain and
vegetation that would
complicate approaching our
guys without getting shot by
accident.
I called the Fred and asked if the
western Overwatch team was still in place.
Gunfire erupted over the radio as he
keyed. Is Mike and answered? I think so.
Okay, good. That gave us eyes above and
control of the high ground over there.
This is the moment Jay,
go prove yourself.
As we dropped off the lip,
senior chief Carey called to me over
the radio and wanted to know what I was
doing. We're going down. I
told him he went ballistic.
Absolutely not. We need to
link back up, fall back.
The boys needed help and we were closest.
If it had been anybody else,
I might have thought twice about his call,
but my own personal quest to prove myself
coupled with my intense hatred for him
clouded my judgment.
I ignored him and we pressed on.
As we dropped further into the valley,
we lost all communication
with the headquarters team.
I began to realize what a hairy situation
I had just placed the two of us in.
We had given up the high ground to move
down a thousand feet of vertical terrain
to try and link up with an element under
fire with an enemy force almost one
kilometer away. I pushed this thought to
the back of my mind. The boys need help.
Focus on that,
but where was the fight?
The sounds of battle echoed all across
the valley making it difficult to
calculate distance and direction.
A broken transmission filled my earpiece.
I couldn't tell what it was,
but I recognize Jay ds voice.
I tried to establish contact a moment
later through washes of static jds voice
came back. Where the hell
are you, Jay d demanded.
I told him we were at the t
intersection on the valley floor.
Get your ass out of the valley.
Now he said with so much anger I could
almost feel a blast of fire shoot out of
the earpiece. I was about to
explain my intent when he added.
Those guys are in a major fight and we
can't call and close air support because
we don't know where you are.
That shook me.
There were aircraft overhead waiting to
join the battle with rockets and bombs,
yet they could not make their runs because
of my decision to go into the valley.
I should have thought about our air
assets, but I was too blinded by a,
my own ambition with my Kombat
IX inexperience on full display.
It started to dawn on me at
last had I made a mistake.
What if somebody got hit
during the delay I'd caused,
I keyed my radio and reported that we
would be pulling out of the valley and
climbing up the north face of the t
intersection to link up with our element
there.
Once we were consolidated on the North
Ridge and our security was set for what
was surely be a long night ahead,
JD came looking for me as he approached.
I could see he was livid.
What the hell were you doing and dignity.
I told him I was trying to
go to the aid of my brothers.
He looked at me like I
just spit on his wife.
That was a stupid thing you did read.
You could have gotten people killed.
His words made me even more righteously
indignant. I fired back at him.
The boys were in trouble
and I went to their aid.
I did what I needed to
be done in the moment.
Jay d refuse to accept that I tossed
out a similar situation that occurred in
Afghanistan a few years
before as if establish,
establishing precedents
would help my case.
Jay Dee knew the mission too and he cut
me off with not the same at all. Red.
They didn't have air support available.
I didn't know. I know we ditch.
I shouted back.
You delayed it with what you did.
Jd roared at last what?
It was clear to j d that his
words were not sinking in.
He ended the argument currently said,
we'll deal this when we,
after when we get back to Kandahar,
you turned in, stalked off.
I watched him leave and
struggled with my own thoughts.
Had I really made that big of a
mistake. No, no way. I went to help.
When is that ever wrong
bro?
That's a rough,
you know,
a lot of people read that section who
don't have a tactical background and they
don't fully understand. They're
like, Oh man, no, you did
the heroic thing. You know,
you went down into the
battle and you know,
you tried to take the fight to the enemy.
But you know,
I tried to explain to them, you know,
you don't have a tactical understanding.
You know, there are so many things
that were done wrong there. Um,
okay.
That it literally,
and this story would be so different if
something had actually happen and the
potential for something to have gone
wrong is through the roof. I mean,
you've been in Afghanistan,
I mean, you know,
the fighting positions and basically I
took myself off a very advantageous high
ground position that we owned down into
the valley a thousand feet below. I mean,
there could have been hundreds of fighting
positions in caves above me that any
one single fighter could
have just decimated us.
And it would have been one
thing if I got myself killed,
but I pulled a young team guy,
machine gunner down with me.
So I placed this guy's life
in jeopardy. And you know, I,
the funny thing is,
you know,
I tried to paint it in that moment
arguing with JD that I was doing the right
thing.
I'm taking the fight to the enemy.
I'm supporting my brothers
and all this bs. You know,
the reality was I wanted to get
in the fight at that point, uh,
I had been on the edge of a lot
of firefights and, and you know,
and even inviting them and
until you get in there,
you haven't proved yourself.
And I wanted to prove myself.
I wanted to prove myself both as a seal,
as a fighter and as a leader.
And this was another moment,
just like the general where I thought,
here's my opportunity.
And um,
and I was so unwilling to listen.
Um, you know, that I had made a mistake.
And the reality is if I had
owned it in that moment,
it probably would not have
been as bad as it was.
But the mere fact that I just planted
my flag on that spot and was like,
screw you, you're wrong. I'm
right. And I did the right thing,
I think just turned what was
a fire into a raging inferno.
Yeah, yeah. No, that's,
that's rough. And I think also
from a, from a tactical perspective,
people make mistakes like this.
Like it can happen and it can
happen. And, and you know,
I talk about being able to detach and
that's something that I definitely learned
in the seal teams.
And it was,
I think one of the most
advantageous skills for a leader,
especially a combat leader to have,
is to be able to,
to step back from the
situation as it's unfolding.
Because if you fully knew,
hey,
we've got air overhead and they're in
a firefight and if I go down there,
we won't be able to use air support.
You wouldn't have done this.
Even even, uh, 60 gunner, you know,
even a pig gunner would say, oh, okay,
no, I need to, I need to let
that unfold. But you know,
your excitement to get down there and,
and get in the fight is definitely,
that's something that,
that can grab a hold of, of anyone
if they're not careful. And,
and again, it's what we just talked
about with you at that moment.
Put yourself ahead of the
mission ahead of the team and,
and then, yeah, I mean this idea of
ownership and, and you know, when I,
when I kick off, uh, the book that I
wrote with lay for extreme ownership,
you know, it kicks off with a blue
on blue and you know, it was a,
it was a lot of bad things happening.
There was a lot of moving parts going on.
It was a horrible situation to
an Iraqi soldier got killed,
several more got wounded.
One of my guys got wounded.
And I can tell you right now,
like I think if I would have
said, hey, this wasn't my fault,
blame it on someone else. I, I,
I think I would've gotten fired
about in about three seconds. Um,
because it's just a,
it's a bad situation to unfold and yeah,
you planting the flag on
that is, is rough. And,
and I mean,
your humility and putting this out there
is awesome and people can learn so much
from that because if you
recognize how easily you and
you know, okay, let's, let's,
let's, let's paint you in a bad light
that you were young and you were,
but let's paint you in a good light.
Even with,
you had those qualities of being hyper
aggressive and you wanted to get in the
fight and you would a little bit arrogant.
You're still a team guy that's
trying to do a good job.
It wasn't like we were trying to do
a bad job, so to recognize like, hey,
even if you're well intentioned, if you
don't pay attention to these things,
they can grab a hold of you and they can
pull you in the wrong direction. And,
and you look up and, and you're,
you're, you're planting your flag and,
and putting up your defenses
around an indefensible position,
which is where you ended up here. And
you nailed it with the idea, you know,
it's something I know you talk to people
about a business and I talk about it.
I think it's no different
probably in fighting. You know,
you've got to let the
battlefield developed.
Sometimes we have this natural instinct
that when something bad happens,
when a crisis happens, we feel
this, you know, oh my God,
I got to react immediately
before we actually take time.
And even in a gunfight you typically
have a few seconds and it's amazing how
much information we can process in a
few seconds before we react and move.
And so that was one problem.
And the other problem and you know,
was I was driven by this relationship,
um, issue. And it's funny,
you know, the individual, uh,
the retire mass chief that you
were with on Thursday who was, uh,
I served under him twice later.
We had talked about that exact situation
and he had given me advice later and he
said, never let your personal feelings
get in the way of your professional
relationships. And I had, I had absolutely
let my personal feelings drive that.
And that was probably the biggest f
you moment, you know, like I said,
if it had been anybody else,
but my hatred for him had grown to
the point that I was just like, yell,
let me show you buddy. You know? And so
all these things, you know, dangerous,
you know, that not only did you know all
these things you have to be careful of.
I mean, this is what
falls under, you know,
a lot of people call these different
things. And my pen Ogana peak performance,
I call it emotional leadership.
So your ability to detach yourself
for a second and say, okay,
I'm not going to let my
own personal feelings drive
this because what's going on
around me,
my ability to lead and make the right
decisions is more critical than what I
feel. And, uh, obviously, you know,
I have not learned those lessons yet.
I was on that, uh, on that glide path.
And at this point I was on the glide path
down. I was crashing and burning ruff,
ruff. Uh, going back to
the book back at Kandahar,
I heard the first whiskey whispers
about me floating around the team.
The men had nicknamed me Rambo read.
Though some may think being
compared to Stallone's,
Lone Wolf silver screen icon was
a compliment within our community.
It was a supreme insult in the seal teams.
There's no room for individualism.
The foundations of our success rest on
mutual cooperation and communication.
A lone wolf like Rambo could destroy a
team with catastrophic effects on the
battlefield.
After we debrief the mission,
JD Richardson took me into
his makeshift office and said,
read your operational abilities
had been called into question.
We're sending you back to [inaudible]
to meet with the CEO and we'll discuss
this further when the rest of the
team gets back. I was stunned.
At worst, I was starting to expect
something more than a wrist slap,
but nothing like that.
I was being sent back to
the rear out of combat.
Nothing can ever be more
humiliating for a warrior.
I trained my entire adult life for this
and now I had been told I didn't measure
up.
I felt like a mule kick to the gut.
I heard rumblings that senior chief
Kerry wanted to see my trident taken away
behind the scenes.
He was pushing for a Trident
Review Board to determine my fate.
The months of infighting between us had
been bad enough now he was trying to
destroy my career.
I was sick at the thought of losing my
tried and over a single bad moment in a
valley whose name nobody back home would
ever know and whose vocation would not
matter to anyone,
but a handful of men who had fought in
it and it's in Redmond had demonstrated a
consistent pattern of bad decision making.
I thought again about my screaming match
with senior chief Kerry during the NATO
exercise.
When it ended,
what did I see in the eyes of what
did I see in the eyes of my teammates?
Embarrassment. This wasn't really
about one moment in the valley,
was it Jay?
I had to face that fact.
I rubbed my anchoring temples.
I felt like my head was going to explode
from the pressure building inside of it.
My life was being destroyed and I had
made myself vulnerable to these attacks
with my own actions if I was allowed
to continue to operate stories of this
deployment,
which circulate through the teams.
If I go to my next platoon
with my reputation in tatters,
who would follow my lead
sitting neatly on the wooden
crossbar on the floor beside my bed,
my holstered Sig Sauer p two two
six sat well oiled and cleaned.
I leaned over and pulled it out.
I knew around was already in the chamber,
but I drew back the slide and took a
look to make sure we called a suppress
check and it confirmed what I
already knew my gun was ready to go.
As I held the pistol, I thought
of the Great Samurai warriors who,
if disgraced,
would commit ritual suicide.
Part of me willed my hand to raise the
SIG to press it firmly to my temple.
Yeah,
my life is over. There's nothing
left but an honorable exit.
I glanced over at the desk and saw a
picture of my beautiful wife, Erica.
The image of her face riveted my
attention. Her easy going smile, her eyes,
a light and lively, always quick to
laugh or offer love and compassion.
What would this do to her? After
all, she'd sacrificed for me.
Would my death snuff out the life of her
gorgeous eyes with a bullet I put in my
temple,
I'd leave her the burden of my failed
career and a ticket to a lifetime of
grief. The kids would live
under that cloud as well.
You know, it's interesting,
a lot of people, um,
who have not read my book or maybe they
have read it and they gloss over this,
but they will
wrongly assume that my injuries and that
ambush and the aftermath of that ambush
where the hardest thing I've
ever been through and a,
and I tell them absolutely
not. Um, by far that,
that moment right there in that
period of time in my life about a, uh,
that was about a four month
period, maybe five months, that,
that journey to the bottom and I was
almost at rock bottom at that point.
And this is where
the psychology of humans is an
interesting thing because, um,
all of us have that little voice
that lives inside of us. A,
I call mine my demon and
my demon has been, uh,
my greatest pusher because
he tells me what I can't do.
And he also at times can be,
uh,
the most dangerous thing out there because
they will push you to do things that
are wrong. They will push you to do
things and tell you you can't do things.
And it was in that moment that I
literally was listening to that,
that you know, you will never recover
and you, you know, your career is over.
There's no way you're going
to come back from this, uh,
the guys who are never going to
follow you again. All these lies,
these are lies that we tell ourselves.
And I think it's really important.
You know, if there's anything
about me, I tell people that I am,
I am an expert on overcoming adversity,
failure and crisis.
And it doesn't matter how bad things
have been, you always can recover.
It goes back to those
three rules of leadership.
You just once again go
back to leading yourself.
And in that moment though,
I was so
crushed,
uh,
so crushed because I had convinced myself
that I had done the right thing. And,
and unfortunately I still believe that
and I just saw myself as a victim,
a victim who had no way that I could
recover. And, you know, it's sad and,
and you know,
God moment that I glanced over,
cause I don't think if, if I had
made the mistake or wherever I was,
him not having pictures of
my wife and kids right there,
I probably would have done it.
Uh, cause I just felt so hopeless.
And then I was ashamed,
um,
honestly for thinking that and thinking
about the impact I would leave on them.
So I'd love to say that was the catalyst
of starting to climb out of that hole.
But I actually continued to spiral down
over the next couple of months, uh,
until finally, you know, my, you know,
that moment occurred right after,
you know,
my judgment had been set upon me,
which really I was very fortunate because
I should have been grateful because
really what they could have done is
said, you're outta here. You know,
we're sending you out of the teams,
you're going to go before try to review
board. And they didn't, you know,
the CEO believed in me. He said, you
know, you've done a lot of great things.
You've had some amazing moments.
You've just, you've got some flaws,
you've got some arrogant
flaws and you definitely,
we need to work on your decision making,
um,
leadership abilities. So that's
what they did. It's, it's a,
you know, when, when I was
reading this part, it's,
it's gonna be, it's, it's, I don't
know, I don't think you could have,
I don't think a human being,
I don't think you could explain.
I don't think we'll Shakespeare could
explain to someone that's not in the teams
what it feels like to be in the teams and
to feel like maybe that's not going to
be your life anymore.
That's rough man.
And I don't think he,
I mean you did your best and like I said,
I don't think it's just too to explain
and I mean I guess you do it because you
explain,
listen,
you were at a point where if you couldn't
be in the teams you didn't want to be
alive. That's where you were at right
there. And I guess that does explain it.
I think it might be hard
for people to relate to,
but like for people like you and me,
that grew up literally whole
adult life in the seal teams.
I can't even imagine if
at the, in the, in the,
in the highlight of that moment
of being deployed in combat,
you just lost your,
your comrades in arms from your
task unit and to be told, okay,
you can't do this job anymore. I
mean, like you said, and again,
I think it's going to be hard for people
to understand that it seems like you,
you would never want to,
you wouldn't want to live at all.
And then just to add this onto
what you're saying, and I,
and I say this every time that I talk
about these kinds of personal, uh,
storms that people get into,
and I've just got to say this in case
someone hasn't heard me say it before.
When you're in that storm,
it seems like it's goes
forever in every direction.
Anyone on the outside would anyone 10
feet away from you would look at you and
say, Oh yeah, you're, you, you
made some mistakes. You need to,
you need to get back on the horse
and need to get back out there.
Here's what's going to help you get fixed.
Here's what gets you back on.
But when we're it,
we,
every direction you look is black
and you think you're not getting out.
And team guys don't play around either
at all. Going back to the book. I,
so you decide, okay, I'm going
to, I'm going to stick it out.
You're on your way back.
I made my way my way back to my hooch.
When I entered our living quarters,
I walked by our message board and
saw notes scrawled next to my name.
Why don't you go ahead and kill yourself?
Yeah.
I stared at the words for, I don't
know how long the hallway was empty.
Nobody had been standing around
waiting to see my reaction.
Okay,
that's team guys.
There's no mercy in a seal platoon,
not, you know, I've often thought
about that and, and you know the deal,
we have incredibly dark humor.
So I often wonder with somebody just
trying to lighten the mood and kind of
shock me into, hey dude, come out
of it. You know, go fix yourself.
Uh, I've always, I've often wondered that
or were they serious? And just like, dude,
you're a disgrace. Yeah, we
don't. And, and I know for a fact,
I mean there was a point, uh, right
before we left on that deployment, um,
a couple of weeks later where guys were
being divvied up into where they were
going next. So next platoon and its next
leadership and they were asked, you know,
who, who do you want to work with? You
know, who do you want to work under? And,
and uh, they unequivocally wrote,
we don't want to work with bread.
Uh, so this was an additional blow that
really kind of reinforced, hey man, you,
you, you, you got some, uh,
you got some work to do.
Except I'll be honest, I wasn't at
that point yet. You weren't there yet.
I was still at rock bottom. You
know, you talk about the storms.
I talk about life and bushes and
this was a major life ambush,
one of the first major life
ambushes I'd ever encountered.
And I literally was on the x taking,
withering fire and uh,
I couldn't figure out
how to get out of it.
And you were doing your best and return
fire with your pistol? Yes. In this case,
I was going to return in one round
thinking that was going to fix things.
I'm going to, I'm going to, I'm right,
I'm going to maintain this position
right here and I'm going to win. No,
actually you're not. You need to, you
need to look around. You need to maneuver.
So you do end up keeping your tried it
because obviously there were some guys
that believed in,
like you said,
believed in you and saw
that you had the potential.
And actually sometimes people ask me what
makes a guy get fired or not get fired.
And for me it's like almost a hundred
percent if the guy lacks humility,
they're going to get fired. Or
if they, if they, if no one,
if I would see a guy that had no humility
whatsoever and I didn't see a crack,
it'd be like,
okay this guy's a lost cost.
Cause he's never going
to listen to anyone.
You can't coach someone that
lacks humility completely so,
or you can't help them.
They,
they're going to sit in on
the acts and just get shot up.
That's the way it's going to be.
A, so somebody saw that, hey,
we can get through to this guy.
You know, he's a good team guy.
And more importantly to that point,
and this is a great leadership
point in organizational point,
not only are they going to sit there and
take those hits because there are too
arrogant to be willing to move.
They're going to pull
everybody else down with them.
And that's where it gets really dangerous.
I mean,
especially in our community where
lives are on the line. I mean,
if they're unwilling to learn
or humble themselves enough,
they're going to get somebody else killed.
And that was the big concern
at that point. And Man,
I've got to give Kudos to my commanding
officer who is a friend to this day.
He saved my career because I wasn't
exhibiting humility. I was fighting back.
I was, I did the right thing.
I'm the victim here, you know,
I'm just being thrown under the bus.
And thankfully he had enough
faith in me. I guess he had seen enough
good that he said, I think we can fix him.
Yup. Good man. Uh,
and one of the things that they do to
fix you in the seal teams is send you to
ranger school. I wonderful. Very
curious from Fort Benning, Georgia.
And I would say there's a small,
there's,
there's some people that go to ranger
school cause they want to go to ranger
school right on. But oftentimes
in the seal teams, ranger school,
and I wouldn't even call it punishment,
but it's,
it's like a reeducation and that's
definitely something that has always been,
and that's what they do with
you. Okay. They're going to,
they're going to send you to a really
tough training school where it's not just
a tough training school where you get
weeded out, you learned some tactics,
you learn to, you learn leadership. And
I did not go to ranger school, but uh,
you know,
it's a great school.
Everyone that I know that the
rangers that I know are awesome guys,
so great school, but oftentimes
we use it in the seal teams.
Maybe punishment is the wrong word.
In some cases I know it's been punishment.
Occasionally a guy will want to go there.
But generally guys,
I mean generally guys are working so
they're not going to go to ranger school.
You end up getting the ranger
school and here we go. Sick, hungry,
burning with resentment
because as you said,
you're not at this point you're still
like all this is this, this is crap.
I don't deserve this.
Yeah.
I W I was to say I was bitter
is an understatement. She uh,
uh,
burning with resentment I went into the
first few days with without my heart or
mind engaged. The first week of ranger
school is nothing but a gut check.
Long days with minimal sleep exposure to
the elements and constant physical and
mental evolutions to get those who
don't want to be there to quit teamwork
leadership within a circle of peers
and decision making under stressful
conditions where the objective
of this first phase as a seal,
I should have represented my community
in the best possible manner while by
displaying leadership,
a commitment to teamwork and a willingness
to overcome obstacles. Instead,
my action showed me to be arrogant,
ill tempered,
and unwilling to work with others.
Many soldiers falsely believe that
seals are like that in my actions.
Re simply reinforced it.
I failed to represent my community
as anything but that stereotype.
So you have this bad attitude.
You go out on a compass course,
you're pretty good at land nab.
You think you're going to kick ass.
You don't kick ass. You do
a bad job. The black hats.
Who were the ranger instructors?
Here we go.
The black hats chuckled with laughter.
Damn squid got lost.
We should have given you a boat.
Swaby another growled. Not Surprising.
Seals don't know how to navigate any ways.
I failed at something.
I once took great pride in not
so good without your Gucci gear.
Are you another sneered I lost it all
my pent up fury frothed out of me.
Screw this course and screw you.
Kiss my ass.
I walked up to my company instructor
and told them, I'm out of here. I quit.
Are you sure you want to do that
without thinking? I said yes.
All. I was reading this
book and I was like, Dang.
I was thinking, damn, I been wholly
shit. Yeah. Talk about a total
breakdown of emotional leadership.
I mean that's the reality. I had died and
the, and here's the problem with that.
I allowed this to happen
by not managing myself.
I had allowed this,
I was like a pressure cooker waiting to
pop off and instead of managing it and
recognize it and come to
grips with it, I did. And it,
it just manifested itself in that moment
where I failed the Land Nav course,
uh, because of my own
arrogance. And then, you know,
I allowed those ranger instructors to
get under my skin in that failure instead
of immediately saying,
well, hey, no big deal.
I could have gone back and done it again
like three days later because I wasn't
the only guy in that failed. There were
other guys that feel, but instead of that,
I instantly just,
it was one additional
blow that I had sustained.
And being at this tipping point,
you know,
I allowed them to get under my skin and
snapped and it is the only thing I have
ever quit in my life that I
have verbally quit. I mean,
for all intents and purposes,
I rang the bell in that moment and so
angry and frustrated and listened to that
demon that said, your career is over. You
will never recover from this. You know,
this is the final Straw. You know, you
had an opportunity and you missed it, man.
So you know,
nobody's ever going to follow you again
and everyone's screwed you over and put
you in this point. Absolutely.
That's why, you know, victim,
victim, victim mentality.
Now this is a miracle.
This is the miracle.
Big As god moment that
people don't understand this.
This is a miracle.
The colonel in charge of ranger
school happens to be friends with,
uh, Vince Peterson, who we talked about
earlier, and that's not his real name,
but he's a legendary seal officer and a
prior Vietnam Marine battle away city,
by the way,
just to just an awesome guy.
And for whatever reason,
miracle,
the colonel that's in charge of
ranger school is friends with,
uh, with Captain Peterson. And here we go.
Going back to the book, you're
sitting there talking to the colonel.
Vince Peterson was the greatest
natural leader I'd ever known.
He had a knack of expressing where the
team needed to go with just a few words.
He'd plant seeds like his men
taking ownership of the plan.
Then watched as everything went
forward with the plants when the plants
succeeded and it almost always did.
He never took the credit.
He gave it to everyone else.
In retrospect,
I'm not proud that all I
could manage was the fable.
And this goes back to something
you talk about earlier in the book,
but at this point I was still
unable to face the truth myself,
let alone admitted to the leader
I respected above all others.
Yeah,
and so here you go. Your conversation
with captain Vince Peterson red.
Do you really think ranger school
is punishment? It is sir. Read.
Have you ever thought that maybe
there is an opportunity here, sir?
You have a chance to learn something
of value if you're willing to take it.
I didn't know what to say to that.
I had not been trying to learn
anything since Afghanistan.
I had been trying to defend and justify.
You're getting ready to
throw your career away. Red,
I'm not sure I have a career
left, sir. Red. He said firmly,
what are you going to do if you get out?
If you come back,
you'll be out of the navy in a month.
How are you going to support your family?
He let that sink in. I had no
answer and stayed silent. Besides,
do you really want to go through your
life having ended your career this way?
You can recover.
You control your destiny and your future.
You can earn back the respect of the guys
if you give them something to respect.
If your actions demand respect.
I hadn't looked at it,
my situation from that angle red,
get back in that course.
Finish it,
then come back with your head held high
and show that you have the ability to
lead.
Okay.
That'll leave a mark. Yeah. Well, and
you know, for people to understand,
I,
I didn't sleep a wink that night after I,
after I quit and I was so ashamed of what
I had done and I was so convinced that
there was no way I
could undo it. That, uh,
I literally was just resigned to
the fact that my career was over.
And, uh, when I went into that office, um,
I first spoke to the sergeant major and
the sergeant major asked if I wanted to
speak to anybody in the seal teams. Hell
no, man, I don't want to talk to anybody.
You know, I am a failure.
I am broken. And, uh,
and then it was the colonel who
asked me and I said the same thing.
So the mere fact, and this
is, he didn't even offer,
he just started dialing. Mm. So the,
and the mere fact he talked
about this bait moment that, uh,
that Vince Peterson will happen to be
at his phone and answer right then and,
and, and saying be on the
phone and him to hand it to me.
And there was no way in hell. I mean,
I had such respect for this, this man,
there was no way I could say no. And
you know that conversation, you know,
this is,
this is the highest levels of leadership
to be able to quickly analyze the
situation, especially when you're working
with people to understand, you know,
okay, this is where we're at, this
is the battlefield I'm looking at.
This is what I have to work with and
this is what I need to do to move this
person to where we're going to
motivate and inspire them. And I mean,
he did it flawlessly.
He know exactly what to tell me.
He told me both the good and the bad.
He gave me hope and he told
me what happens if you don't,
which would be hopeless,
you know,
I will have you out of the military and
less than a month. And then, you know,
I tell people that is the most succinct
and powerful leadership advice I've ever
been given. You know, people will
follow you if you give them a reason to,
if you give them something to respect.
And that really is the foundation of,
you know, the three rules of
leadership. I talk about lead yourself,
that's 80% of it,
you know,
leading others comes naturally
and he was right because
I left that office. And uh, the, the
funny thing about it though, as a,
I got off the phone and I
asked the colonel, I said
serve,
which put me back in class and uh,
he didn't even miss a beat. No,
he said instead,
uh,
you will go to the holding company and
we will class you up with a new class
month later,
which is just what you needed.
You get rolled back for 30 days.
Going back to the book,
I bent down and picked up the cigarette
butts lying in the grass at my feet with
a flick.
The butts spun into the garbage bag.
I'd been dragging her across post with me.
So here you are,
a combat seal officer
picking up cigarette butts.
13 years in, 13 years in, as
I filled my bag with litter,
the bit bitterness flared. Again, I've
put 13 I'm putting in 13 and a half years.
I was a member of one of the most elite
special operations units in modern
history. Millions of dollars were
spent preparing me, training me,
outfitting me to handle the toughest
battlefield tasks our nation can face and
my own brothers have reduced me to this.
I stopped and thought
about that statement.
Where was the personal
responsibility in it?
Vince Peterson's word came back to me.
You have an opportunity to learn
here if you're willing to take it.
I served with good men whom I respected.
They turned their back on me
or did they?
What did all this say about me?
A door suddenly opened in my mind.
The place it led to was a dark room
that I had never entered inside.
I could see the truth about myself
through the facade of lies I had built.
I stood at its threshold not
really wanting to walk through.
Sensu once said, if you know your
enemies and you know yourself,
you will never be defeated.
I didn't know myself.
I was running blindly through
life, refusing to even
acknowledge my weaknesses.
I have been an arrogant
ass most of my career.
Clearly I needed to come down to earth.
Maybe trash detailed did serve a purpose.
After all,
I guess I needed to mentally flatline
before I could reconstruct my self for
leadership. I found another cigarette
button, flicked it into my bag.
The bitterness over being forced into
this sort of work evaporated far from a
humiliating burden.
It was giving me clarity
I surely needed for years.
My attitude had hobbled relationships
and endangered my career.
I suddenly recalled a moment years before
I'd worked my tail off for months on a
special project.
When I finished it,
I knew I was going to receive a
significant award for the effort.
For whatever reason,
it got downgraded to a lesser award.
What did you do after you found out?
I thrown a temper tantrum.
I went off on one of our admin guys who
had congratulated me after I received it.
Instead of being grateful, receiving any
sort of acknowledgement, I'd thrown the,
awarded him. I might as well have thrown
it in the face of Captain Peterson,
who was my CEO at the time.
That incident stuck with
my peers who witnessed it.
And for years after when I ran into
one of them, they'd remind me of it.
Jason Redmond, navy
achievement, medal thrower,
Van Guard of leadership.
I can't say I look forward to
picking up trash the next morning,
but I didn't start the day
despising what would come next.
I was ashamed that I'd have thought so
highly of myself that I saw myself as
above picking up trash.
I realized that as a seal leader,
it was my responsibility to accept the
example with everything I undertook.
There you go.
There you go. It was a, you know, so
this is probably the point. And uh,
I talked to a lot of people about this.
Like,
I wish I could say that after I hung
up the phone with Captain Peterson,
uh, that I went back and was
like, you know, yeah, let's go,
let's do this. You know, let's crush this.
And instead I still was kind of finishing.
I was on that slope down to crash that
plane and I finally crashed that plane
and hit really the, the
bottom of the barrel. Uh, and,
and it was at that point that I
really started to analyze myself.
And this is something I talked to
a lot of people about. You know,
you truly have to know yourself.
You cannot because our
weaknesses manifested
themselves in the hardest times.
Uh, they don't come out in the
good times and the good times,
there's no issues with it. And the only
way you could manage that, uh, you know,
is true in mental leadership and
emotional leadership at the highest level
because in the hardest times,
and usually those are the times you've
got to be managing the most is when it
comes up.
And it was by really starting
to rip myself apart and look at,
you know, all these things that I
had done and understanding, oh yeah,
when I get into these situations,
I feel that, you know,
that that meltdown with
the ranger instructors, you
know, I felt that coming on,
I could have stopped it, but I
didn't, I let it go. You know,
they lit the fuse and instead of tamping
it, you know, out, I let it burn
and blow up. So it was, you know,
really it was these moments,
and this is probably the biggest thing
that I can tell anybody out there.
It is never too late. You
can always come back. Um,
so for,
for months I had convinced myself that I
was a victim for months I had convinced
myself there was no way to do this.
And for the first time when I
finally looked at, you know,
these are your weaknesses,
but oh by the way, man,
you got some amazing
strengths and you know,
you need to figure out how
to amplify these strengths,
minimize these weaknesses and,
and what an opportunity you have.
You are a seal that's in ranger school
that couldn't crush this course.
Set the example and come back
every day is another opportunity.
You're going to screw up again.
And that's okay. But you know,
so for the first time I saw hope standing
at the rock bottom and looking up
through this tunnel, I saw a glimmer
of light. Well, what's, what's,
when you say that,
what I think about is what
people get themselves into.
They boxed themselves into this scenario
and needs to exactly where you had
boxed yourself into, which was,
hey, look, this guy doesn't like me.
This guy's blaming me for
that. This, these people have
a bad attitude and you're,
and, and guess what other
people you can't control.
And so you end up in a hopeless situation
because I can't change this guy's
attitude. He's an asshole.
He doesn't like me.
He whatever we had to run in this person,
they don't trust me and
I can't change that.
And so when you're in a situation where
you can't change the situation at all
because you don't have control over
any of it, well then guess what?
You're hopeless.
But the minute you look at yourself
and you say, wait a second,
I actually control everything
that's going on right now.
Everything people's perception
of me is based on my behavior,
not theirs. And that's what,
that's what I liked. What, uh,
what Peterson said you,
you control your destiny and your
future. That's the, that to me,
I highlighted that 98 times.
You control your destiny and your future.
And at this point in the book is where
you saw and it took you for picking up
cigarette butts in. It took you to that
point where you say, wait a second,
all these things that have happened to me,
I can get control with them and I can
turn them in a better direction and yeah.
That's awesome. And the
journey began. Yeah. Um,
that you kind of expand a little
bit more here. I could not,
I could not change my decision,
but I should.
You're talking about this is
when you're talking about,
you're reflecting now on what happened
on your decision to go into the valley
and Afghanistan. That whole scenario
that you got in trouble for.
Here's what you said about it.
I could not change my decision,
but I should have owned
it in its aftermath.
I should have listened to those with
more experience taking my lumps and moved
forward.
That is how leaders grow.
I was so desperate to justify
and defend my actions.
I lost sight of what to do
of what I was there to do.
I was there to lead when necessary
and to follow when called upon,
but above all else to accomplish
the mission as part of the team.
Instead in the aftermath,
I made it all about me
and the defense of my ego.
Again, when you come into the office
and you say, this wasn't my fault,
I was doing the right thing. Everyone
that's looking at you is thinking he's,
he doesn't even see what he did
wrong and that's where you know,
you talk about in this book, you talk
about the fact that one of the most,
one of the most horrible things on the
battlefield is an arrogant young person
that thinks there's, there's not
going to listen to anyone. And you,
when you sit there and
put up your defenses,
you're showing everyone that back to the
book. Yes. And your chief Kerry hated me.
We loved each other, but the truth, he
was a damn good operator in a firefight.
I would've wanted him there as a
tactical leader in his own abrasive way.
He'd attempted to mentor me.
If I had put down my pride,
I would've seen it and I would've learned
a lot from him. That never happened.
I failed to manage our relationship
and it poisoned the entire platoon.
It also hurt my reputation
with my teammates. My self
deceit finally collapsed.
Keri had not done this to me.
I done this all to myself.
I was being punished less for the
decision I'd made and more for the way I'd
fiercely refuse to take
responsibility for it.
The more I railed against
those aligned against me,
the more I deserve to be punished.
I wasn't betrayed by my teammates.
I betrayed them with my selfishness.
It was time to grow up.
Damn.
Yeah.
It was exciting because it suddenly,
ranger school suddenly became
a new opportunity and a really,
I shut my sights on. Um, you know,
kind of interestingly enough,
I think all of us are
super goal driven people.
And for the first time I
saw an opportunity and a,
and shut a goal, you know? Yeah. Which is
what I think all of us do show well at,
you know, we, we have a target to move
to and now I have a path to go after it.
Um,
and that that path became,
I want to graduate the honor man
of this course and a PSAT sat the,
you know, woke up the next morning firing
up the guys around me and a, hey man,
we're getting ready to start
up again. It's going to be
awesome. Let's go do this.
So yeah,
again,
I'm harping on this a little bit,
but just the fact that this book
is so powerful because to, to,
to walk through that transition,
and I'll tell you,
anybody that's read extreme ownership or
anyone that listens to this podcast is
going to be especially, um, they're,
they're going to be having an even
deeper understanding. Cause they,
I talk about this all the time
and to see you go down that path,
see where it leads and then be
able to come back. I'll be no,
I'll come back out is awesome.
But,
but it's so powerful to actually hear
from your perspective from someone that
was in that exact position and doing
those things to hear you saying it and be
able to witness the turnaround.
It's a powerful, powerful stuff.
Next morning I hit the ground
running and never look back.
The company I joined was
full of strangers, no matter
I did everything full boar.
Made sure I help, but made sure I help
everyone in my squad whenever I could.
I was going to be the dis.
I wasn't not going to be the
disconnected selfish jerk.
I had been this go around,
my heart was fully invested
and you kick ass and ranger school,
you're not honor man,
because you find out that,
yeah, I only find out at the very
end that uh, if you're rolled back,
you're not eligible.
But I did really well.
I was ranked at the top of
my period vowels. I mean,
all the instructors gave me a lot of,
hey man, you're, you're just crushing it.
And uh,
so no matter if it was a goal,
you know that another great guy
earned it and well deserved.
You end up back at the back of the teams,
you go back into a task unit and
you're an assistant platoon commander.
Now this again,
is this a reroll as a,
is it a re a riff reload as an assistant
platoon commander or were you still
just super junior cause you
were seeing an animal guy?
No, uh, I had just made JG at this point.
So back then we still,
you know,
now they're kind of doing it differently
than a lot of us Shah Sema Dad,
we're old guys did have the
ability to do two pumps. Yeah,
they made me do two poems.
Yeah. Yeah. They wanted me
to do two pumps and this is,
I mean, for those who are not
aware, there was a little bit of a
impetus on me because they basically,
so as officers,
if you ever get a letter of reprimand
in your record at effectively ends your
career. I mean, if that official letter
goes into your record, you're done,
you'll remember you won't make the
next rank. You're going to be out.
And they basically wrote this letter,
uh,
my outgoing CEO who was in Afghanistan
to my incoming CEO who was taken over the
team and they basically said,
you made some mistakes and we questioned
your tactical decision making and
leadership abilities, but we're going to
give you a second chance. So this letter,
and I was, you know, I was in the office
with the CEO and he put it into uh,
his safe and basically said,
this will be burned or shredded
at the end of the deployment.
If you show us you have the ability,
then if you don't,
it will go into your print.
And they had my officer record
right there and they were like,
it will go right here into your record.
So,
and I think they knew the power of that
also. And it gave me additional momentum.
And I think this is important in, you
know, I mean, same way we raise our kids,
there's got to be accountability.
You can't just tell somebody, hey,
this is what I want you to go out and do.
We have to let it lay out the right and
left limits and tell them this is where
you're going to go. And you have to have
those things that hold you accountable.
So I don't know if I necessarily
needed that. I was pretty fired up on,
on wanting to get back and set
the example and redeem myself.
But I will say on the back of my
mind, I knew a man, you, you got to,
you got to crush it. That's uh, that's uh,
I dunno if that's happens
in all the military,
but in the seal teams there's,
there's a lot of letters that get shredded
and part of it is like a cover your
ass.
Like when I was a commander,
a part of it's cover your ass
because hey look, you screwed up.
And if you screw up again and everyone
knows that this has happened multiple
times and you haven't been counseled
about it, I look like an idiot.
And not only do I look like an idiot,
I am an idiot if I'm not documented
that you screwed something up.
So I'm going to document this
and make sure that, you know,
I've got a documented but by the way,
I'm not trying to kill your career.
If you can turn around and you
can get back on the path, cool,
this thing is going in the
shredder but here it is. Got It.
You got some ways to go before this
thing goes in that trigger to it's pretty
common thing in the seal teams, not too
common. But um, so you're in a task unit,
your assistant platoon commander
and things are going good and you,
you were a lot more self aware and again
you have to read the whole book to get
all these details about that transition.
You were a lot more self aware and you
started off as mobility commander and
then eventually you start
working with the assault team.
And here we go back to the book
after that first successful mission.
Now on the assault team,
I had earned a spot in the
mix and harmonized with the
task units, battle rhythm.
Our platoons rotated back and forth
between running mobility or running the
assault force.
The pace was intense.
And the mission started to blend
together in a groundhog day sort of way.
I may have lost my way years ago,
but through God and a willingness to
work hard and learn my strengths and
weaknesses,
I had earned my way back into the
brotherhood and you detail some,
some good missions,
uh,
some pretty hot missions.
You know,
you guys gotten some pretty good gunfights
and you're getting towards the end of
deployment and your tea,
you commander, he's, he,
you have a little conversation
with him and he says,
we're going to have you run as ground
force commander on the next one for a
second.
What this really meant failed to register
really JP and the date that this point
in the book, Jp is a guy, he's your
task unit commander. JP nodded.
Yeah, I spoke to Eric and Paul and
we all agree you're ready for it.
Besides this will help get you up to
speed to be a platoon commander at length.
I finally answered. That's awesome. Thanks
for the opportunity. You earned it bro.
He turned to leave. I had done it.
My career was back on track at last.
I knew so many in our community
would always hate me for my mistakes,
but I had earned back the trust of
the men I served and fought with.
Since 2004 I had been an
officer within our community.
Ranked does not automatically
make you a leader.
Your character makes you a leader.
Your actions make you a leader.
Rank is almost irrelevant.
After years of selfish focus on myself,
I'd finally understood
what it meant to lean men,
lead men of this caliber and what was
required of a man in order to be part of
this.
Most elite of all fraternities.
The letter in the safe would
be destroyed for an instant.
The horizon ahead held no boundaries.
And again,
I skipped. This was not
like an easy process, man.
You worked your way right back up.
You started with small jobs,
you made some mistakes that you, you
know, you, you talk about the uh, you lay,
you lazed the marine, a
Marine colonel and, and uh,
he was not happy about that.
Not Happy. So quick story,
you're doing deconfliction and you
can't identify and so you escalate the
deconfliction to a visible laser and then,
you know,
they realize that that both
sides were friendlies and you,
it was a marine corps colonel that you
would lasing and he wasn't too happy
about that. And when you win, when you're
commander brought you in and said, Hey,
what the hell happened? You took
ownership of it and said, hey,
here's the mistakes I made
instead of blaming everyone else.
So big, big turning point. And,
and I, and I think this is an important
point. You know, you, you know, I mean,
within our community,
it's pretty hard to turn around when
you've made a major mistake like that.
I mean, obviously guys get
out, uh, we've had guys shed,
it had been sent to the fleet,
uh,
as some never come back and then
some come back and redeem themselves,
but in a command,
some just get put into a ostracized
position of low importance inside the seal
teams. Right? And it's like,
oh, cool. Yup. You, Oh yeah,
you're stationed over there yet.
We know where you're doing.
And we know all about you and,
and we get that you still
have your trident and you're
still considered a seal,
but you're not a team guy.
And we all know that, yeah.
That you would not be invited to go
back to an operational billet. You know,
you're relegated to training and
all the other things. So, I mean,
it really is for people to understand.
I mean,
our community is driven by
amazingly talented warriors.
And at the end of the
day, you know, the leader,
they rely on the guys next to them
and their leaders to make those good
decisions.
So if you've made bad decisions,
I mean to be able to come back
and them say, okay, you know,
you've shown us that we can
trust you once again, uh,
to lead and make the right
decision. So, um, it really,
I tell people there's a hardest
road I've ever walked. I mean,
when I got wounded I was
like, I got this. Yeah. The,
uh,
the trust when broken is
extremely hard to rebuild.
And I get asked a lot, how do you
build trust with people? Either,
whether it's been broken or whether you
don't know him and it's very clear in
the book,
and again this is why people should get
the book the way that your task unit
commander, and I'm trying to think of
the alias because I know him to a JP,
the way that you're tasking the commanders
very common to what a guy does. He,
he gives you a little bit
of responsibility and let
you let you earn a little
bit of trust and then once you've earned
a little bit of trust to gives you a
little bit more responsibility once
you've earned a little bit more trust.
And that continued going,
this is,
this is now a six month deployment
plus a year long workup or whatever.
So He's been giving you a little bit of
trust in you've been earning and earning
and earning and earning back your trust
and you are digging out of a deficit,
right?
That's a lot harder.
So that is a lot harder when
if you show up as a new guy,
you're like a zero,
right?
Cause p and then you're going to get a
little trust and maybe get to a 0.2 and
then you get a little bit more
responsibility and you get to a point for,
you were at like a negative nine.
And so you had to just, you know,
earn your way back to get to zero.
And then once you're at zero,
then you had to build up. And at this
point in the book, and you did some,
again, I'm sorry I'm not
going to go into everything,
but you knew you had a pretty dynamic,
uh,
potentially horrible situation on
folding big gun fight going on.
Some head counts not accounted for people
and you took charge of the situation
and that probably is what,
you know,
jumped you up a bunch of levels in
people going, okay, you know what,
we can trust this guy. And, and,
and then you continued these to build
that trust and up to the point where I
need to explain this,
cause I didn't up to the point where
the task unit commander said, okay,
one of these next coming missions,
we're going to make you
the ground force commander.
And what that means for civilians is that
means you're in charge of everything.
You're going to go out, you're gonna
be the, this, the, the main leader,
the senior leader, not even the main,
they're going to be the senior leader,
the guy in charge of everything
that's happening on the battlefield.
That's what the ground force commander is.
And you're now being,
it's enda deployment. You're
being told, look, you've, hey,
we want you to be the ground
force commander in one of
these upcoming operations.
And that is the ultimate trust for
someone to give to a subordinate is,
hey, I want you to go out and take my job
that I would normally do you go do it.
So, pretty amazing, uh,
come back. Uh, humbling.
I mean,
yeah.
So you're almost at the
end of deployment and uh,
like uh, uh, an op comes up,
we were one week away. Yep.
[inaudible] to get ready to go home.
Um,
no to self those last operations,
be careful for first and last man,
the first mission is,
and the last one's a Gotcha.
You and it's
the mission comes down.
It's one of those missions
where you guys are kind of like,
this probably isn't going to go down.
It's sketchy intel,
the high visibility if it
goes in your thinking because we get a
lot of those, Oh this is going to happen.
And you get used to getting all amped up
and then eventually you don't even get
amped up anymore. You continue with your
daily routine, go to the gym, workout,
whatever. And this particular case, you
guys, you, you literally went to the gym,
you're working out like normal.
And I didn't think there was a chance
in hell this mission was going to happen
and some of the guys
who were looking at it,
but I just didn't think it was going
to happen. It was already late. Uh,
so we were outside really
the window, um, you know,
to really try and execute in a,
in a good manner in my opinion.
And then there were external things,
you know,
there's some classified factors to it
that I don't talk about in the book where,
which were others.
Some of the really big reasons why I did
not think there was any chance this was
going to happen.
But,
but it does and you guys roll out on a,
you know,
al-Qaida target and definitely you
guys had the intel that bad guys,
expected security team expect
enemy security team expected.
And, and again, like we would
hear that a lot. I mean,
it's not like,
oh this Intel's 100% and you're
not gonna do anything different.
They tell you there's a security team,
enemy security team. You're like, okay,
check.
We've heard that 27 times.
They've only been there however many
times. And so you always, always expect it
that they had,
there was a little more
detailed information about
this security detail that
made it a little bit hairier than
some of our regular missions.
I mean there were things
that we knew. Um, uh,
yeah,
I can't get into the day.
I can't get into the details but
basic more solid into absolutely.
So it made it a little bit different
and kind of raised our hackles a little
more than normal. But you know, the
process of the mission is the same.
I mean I know probably you, I've talked
to other people, you know, the guy said,
did the bin Laden raid the mechanics
of that mission where the same,
it was just a level,
you know,
how we take down a target is pretty much
the same regardless of where you go.
And it was the same for this case. There
were just some things that made us go,
maybe we should prepare a little more.
You guys roll on to target
and things get pretty,
pretty intense pretty quick. Once
you've, once you've hit the target,
you've got it secured.
Now we got some squirters meeting some
folks that we think of runaway from the
target building. Again, I'm not going to
go into the full detail of the mission,
which you did a beautiful
job of explaining what this
was like in the book and
that's why he was get the books.
They can read it,
but as we mentioned earlier,
this ends up in a firefight and
you're in it. Going back to the book,
I keep my radio and called JP
troops in contact troops in contact.
I have three wounded,
including me.
The machine guns were still blazing away
at us and they walk their barrels right
and left criss crossing positions with
hundreds of 7.62 millimeter bullets.
I recognize that if I didn't
get a tourniquet on what
I fought was the stump of
my left arm,
I was going to bleed out.
I looked back at owl and the
rest of my team behind the tire.
Right then owl saw me get to my
feet and try and run to join them.
Al told me this later,
but I have no recollection,
recollection of standing up after I
was hit the first time the PKM Gunnar
spotted me moving and laid on his trigger.
According to Al,
I'd only taken a step or two in my head.
Whipsawed forward and my body
spun around to the left. I fell,
limped to the ground.
The team thought I'd been killed.
Al Recognize the dire situation we ran
and called it an immediate fire mission.
The [inaudible] crew turned it down
the first time two times before finally
making. Al acknowledged that if anything
happened to us, it was Al's fault,
not the gun ships.
The first 25 millimeter shells
hit the thicket behind the enemy.
I lay less than 50 feet from the
enemy machine gun that engaged me.
I drifted in and out of
consciousness the entire time.
Awake in a fog of confusion.
One minute out cold.
The next al risked his life to
save me during a lull and fire.
He rose from behind the tire and charged
over to me. Shawn laid down cover fire.
As Al ran into the teeth of that PKM
bullets cracked and we wind around him,
but he reached me and dragged me back
behind the tire where he put a tourniquet
on my mangled arm.
I remember nothing of this and I didn't
know al had even moved me to the tire
until months after the fire fight.
The Medevac bird arrived a few minutes
later and the guys helped us aboard.
Once we were airborne and out of harm's
way, the remainder of the task you'd,
it fell back to the original target
compound to wait for extract,
but the fight was over.
The gunshot.
Gunship detected more movement in
the thicket. Enough was enough.
Al called in one o five millimeter
howitzer from the AC one 30 and turned the
thicket into a smoking crater.
Months later when JP visited me at home,
I learned that the al Qaeda commander had
fled the house when he heard our birds
coming at the start of the mission,
he left part of his personal security
detail behind a fight, a battle.
He had no stomach for himself
and they died to the last man.
After inflicting three casualties on us,
months later,
another seal team ran the al Qaeda
commander to the ground and killed him.
Okay.
Justice served.
So
that firefight, and again, people should,
should read the book to get the
details of that firefight. But, uh,
just reading about you wounded,
which I've covered that part and now
you're up and running and get shot in the
face and down.
Every BYO guys think you're dead.
And,
and you know,
I
should have covered this with a little
bit more detailed, but you know,
you're trying to make calls, you're
trying to let people know what's going on.
You're trying to decipher the situation
cause it was a rough situation that you
guys were in and you end up,
you know,
okay,
getting extracted.
Your boys took care of you.
That did I owe my life to those guys.
I mean they fought back that
gunship overhead. Um, you know,
force Special Operations Squadron.
I owe my life to those guys.
That was the closest fire mission ever
in the Iraq war. Um, we were, well,
well they wouldn't bring in
that mission because we were,
we were literally within
any danger close parameter.
There were the machine guns that had me
pinned down. Uh, we're about 45 feet,
50 feet away. So, um,
owl did an amazing job.
I mean,
this was his third combat deployment, you
know, experience Jay, attack experience,
team leader, and you know, really,
I mean, he hung it all out there,
exposed himself to get me saved my life
with my tourniquet and the rest of the
guys,
you know,
fought amazingly [inaudible] to get us
out of there and get off the accident
survive. And um, yeah,
I wanted Al to get a navy cross.
Um,
they downgraded it to a silver
star to this day, you know,
I'll tell anyone he deserved a navy cross,
but all those guys did an amazing job.
I owe my life,
my life to them and the gun ship it.
Um, and obviously, you know, in the
beginning of the book, you know,
the thought that I had lost my arm and
what tent, what happened is actually,
I guess my arm was pinned under me. So
when I reached for it, I couldn't feel it.
And you know, it just stunned
all my nerves damage too,
right? Yeah, yeah. Yeah.
So when, when, uh,
and this is kind of an interesting
point that I talked to people about and
something I'm speaking on all the
time now, this idea of surviving.
So having trained in a career where we,
where we learn how to execute ruthless
and devastating violence of action in an
ambush to crush the enemy and destroy
the enemy in that kill zone on the x and
to now be on the flip side of that coin
and be in a very well executed ambush.
I mean, they had us, it was an la ambush.
They had us caught a very good crossfire,
um, you know, and just sheer
will for us to fight. And,
and at least in that, uh, push back
enough that it gave us a window and,
and by the end cheer,
we were shooting a lock that
there happened to be that
tractor tire back there,
at least one point of cover.
Because beyond that there was nothing
but thousands of yards of open Iraqi
desert. But to be in that ambush, uh,
in that devastating and
withering crossfire,
I stepped out of that
ambush into another ambush.
And the next day ambush was what I
call a life. Suddenly here I was,
I'd been on this amazing
journey of failure, uh,
growth,
understanding,
gaining experience and wisdom
and redemption and, you know,
career back on track,
getting ready to, um,
screen and go over to the next level.
Seal team was my goal.
When I came back from that deployment,
I was doing that.
And suddenly to find myself
laying in a hospital bed,
I'm so weak. I needed nurses
to help me go to the bathroom.
From the amount of blood loss I had a,
the very first thing I woke to
was the doctor's telling me,
most likely they were going to have to
amputate my arm. I had no use of my hand.
Uh, I had not seen myself in the
mirror. My face was totally blown apart.
Um, I had lost my nose, a
cheekbone, my eye, my bay,
the bullet traveled, the bullet
hit me right in front of the ear,
travel through my face,
and exited the right side of my nose.
So it took off most of my nose.
Uh, took out most of my cheekbone.
It vaporized my orbital floor.
So my,
I actually dropped down into
the newfound hole in my face,
so it damaged my eye muscles, uh,
broke all the bones above my eye.
It shattered my jaw, broke
my jaw in my chin. Um,
so I had not seen myself laying in the
hospital bed and I'll be honest, I was,
I wasn't ready to look at myself. Um, I
knew I had tubes coming out of everywhere.
I was tricked, I was wired
shut, I had a stomach tube.
That's how they were feeding me.
So I stepped into this next ambush.
Um, I was, you know, with this
thought of where do I go from here?
And
I'll be honest,
for the first couple of days I kind of
struggled and I think this is natural.
So we talk about this idea of being
pinned down on the x and how we have to
survive in,
whether it's a real world ambush or
it's a life ambush for anyone that's out
there that's encountered some
sort of devastating event.
And I classify life ambushes and event
that'll forever leave physical, mental,
or emotional scars on you.
Um, you have to get off the x.
So I'm laying there in this hospital bed
and I'm like kicking myself. I'm like,
God,
man,
what if I had you do the things that
humans do when bad things happen?
We start to think, well, what if I had
done this or what if I had done that? Or,
you know, what if I could go
back and change this fact? And,
uh, I did that for probably, I don't
know, 36 hours after I got to Bethesda,
you know, just kind of lost
in my mind thinking about it.
And at one point I just said,
stop.
You can't go back and change the past
and the hand. What's happens happened.
The only thing you can
do is shape the future.
And I thought back to that journey
that I had been on from ground zero,
from that broken man in Afghanistan,
ready to kill myself to where
I had come. And I said, dude,
the only thing you can do from
here is shaped the future.
So get off the and go.
And I never looked back from that
point. Um, and I tell people that,
you know,
you have to push yourself into those zones
and discomfort so that you can handle
these hard situations when they come.
Because if you've never forged yourself,
if you've never been put into
these areas of discomfort,
you're going to be crushed when they come
because you're not going to be ready.
I was so ready for that moment
when it came. I mean, you know,
it took me about 36 hours after I
got home to figure it out, but still,
that's pretty quick for a devastating
injury like that. And I never looked back.
You're, you're in Bethesda. And just to,
just to kind of give a little
bit of detail around that,
you've got some doctor,
a name female doctor named Dr Maillard,
and here we go back to the book,
kind of like she's about
to list your kind of,
your situation that you're
in with energetic bluntness.
She laid out the extent of my wounds.
The machine gun bullet entered
just in front of my right ear.
It shattered my job, vaporized my right
orbital floor, destroyed my cheek,
and exited through my nose.
I'd suffered nerve damage as well.
Virtually nothing was left in my cheek
bone or ocular floor bones on the right
side of my face. She and her team was
amazed. I didn't suffer greater I damage,
so that was a blessing.
My nose was almost completely destroyed
and we need a full reconstruction.
They would need to repair
my shattered jaw implant,
a titanium plate to replace the ocular
floor and we'd have to repair the damage
to the rest of my facial
bones on the right side.
I was still under the impression they
could fix me right up and get me back into
the teams. Not, not
now. I was not so sure.
And you were at this point,
your jaw jaws wired shut and
your traits so you can't talk.
So you write out a note. How many weeks
are we looking at here, doc weeks?
She said surprised. No,
Jay. We're talking years.
A few years.
At least years.
It didn't even sink in at first
there would be progressive surgeries.
Each one will need to be fully healed
before we can move on to the next one.
She went on to explain that there was
no roadmap for the extent of the, Eh,
because of the extent
and nature of my wounds.
My case was highly complex and I would
recall require extensive bone and skin
grafts in the years ahead.
After she left,
I struggled to keep my spirits up.
This was news I did not want to hear.
Yeah.
You know, and this should an
interesting, uh, fact I, you know,
I talked to a lot of other team guys
about this. I think a lot of us,
we do a really good job
in the seal teams and I,
I would like to assume other
military units do the same.
We do a really good job of preparing
guys if they get killed. Uh, you know,
page two, we make sure
they're all taken care of. Um,
I don't think any of us ever
give much thought. I sure didn't.
If I was severely wounded.
Uh,
I think most of us think one
side of the coin is, you know,
it'll be merely a merely a flesh wound,
you know,
and we'll walk away and we'll
get back. Uh, and then the other
side of the coin is I'll be killed
and I was good with either of those.
I just kind of resigned
myself to that fact.
So it was a whole nother thing to be
severely wounded and be faced with this
fact that, hey, you may
be forever disabled,
uh,
and it was tough for you and
here's you run into this situation.
Going back to the book, one afternoon
to family members came to visit us.
Erica took the opportunity to step
out and grab some lunch for herself.
I talked with them for a bit, which
left, which quickly fatigued me.
I started to drift off before I
even realized it while I was dozing.
I heard them whispering to each other and
only got fragments of the conversation,
but it was enough.
They were full of PD for me.
When Erica returned and
my relatives departed,
I wrote down all that had happened,
recounting it sent me into a fury again.
I tore off the sheet of
paper and handed it to her.
Then I thought for a minute
and added never again.
Never again would someone
seal feel sorry for me.
I fought for my country and I'll fight
to regain my health so I will ultimately
be able to return to our nation's
battlefields. I was not here for sympathy.
I was here to recover, to be a leader,
to set an example of mental fortitude.
It would be all too easy to give
up into despair, but I refused.
There were men and women in this complex
who were far more badly wounded than I
was. Missing limbs burned, suffering,
brain trauma or eyesight loss.
I would be grateful for
what I had determined to
succeed in the days ahead and
when you use these principles I learned
over the last two years to guide me
forward.
I wrote a note to all my visitors and
ask Erica to hang it up on the door and
here's what the note said.
Attention to all who enter here.
If you are coming into this room with
sorrow or to feel sorry for my wounds,
go elsewhere. The wounds I
received, I gotten a job.
I love doing it for people.
I love supporting the freedom
of a country I deeply love.
I am incredibly tough and we'll make a
full recovery what is full that is the
absolute utmost physically my
body has the ability to recover.
Then I will push that about 20%
further through sheer mental tenacity.
This room you are about to enter his
room of fun optimism and intense rapid
regrowth. If you are not
prepared for that, go elsewhere
from
the management.
And uh,
awesome.
I mean in that picture got sent to me
by someone and eventually it got sent to
everyone by everyone. So it was a, uh,
a viral picture of that sign on your
door that you eventually put in bigger
writing to make sure everyone saw it.
That's right.
MMM.
You, yeah. You eventually you
do get home and, and again,
you know what always
I Chuck,
Oh,
I want to make a really important
point about this cause that,
that that was really a
learning point for me.
Or it was a jump point.
And it,
and it comes back to what we've two we
talked about earlier in the beginning,
a little bit of this social leadership
idea, who you surround yourself with.
And in that moment I had
individuals to want to express pity.
And I realized how dangerous that was
because if I listened too long to people
express that it would be easy to accept
that to accept this victim mentality.
And I've walked that road
before and I was like,
no way am I going to allow that to happen.
It is a choice.
And that's what people need to understand.
You know,
having a positive attitude on how you
handle the situations you're in is a
choice. And the more you accept
positivity and drive it forward,
the more you actually start to believe
it and it will create momentum.
And that's really what happened
with that sign. I said,
I will not allow that to happen again.
No one will come in here and
be sad because I refused.
I will not allow it. And, uh, and you,
you never know the impact of the
decision that you're going to make. You,
you never know how, even though deep
down inside you're like, Holy Shit,
how do I get out of this situation?
But you project that positivity who you
can bring with you and bring up and how
much you can leave a,
an impact that lasts a lifetime.
That sign has gone on to help
hundreds of thousands of people.
I've had people write me that have
had cancer. I've had people that have,
that have written me, that have
had major, horrific accidents.
I didn't keep the sign. I had it framed
and it hangs in the wound who ward,
uh, Walter Reed. And the bottom of
the sign is like, rub clean now.
And uh, I'm told that all of
these wounded warriors, whatever,
they go to a surgery,
they go by and they rub it and it just,
it continues to have this impact.
Um,
secretary gates wrote about
the sign in his book. Uh,
Michelle Obama's book just came out.
She wrote about the sign
and what the impact is.
So one moment of saying,
I'm not going to allow someone else
to drive my thinking makes all the
difference. And I tell so many people
that it is a choice. It is a choice.
You can choose to be a victim and to
feel sorry for yourself or you can choose
to be a victor and drive forward even
if you don't believe it in the moment.
It doesn't matter, you know, say it,
live it and start driving forward.
And that belief will catch fire within
you and everybody else around you.
No doubt about it, man. And, and the,
the unfortunate opposite that is when you
start allowing yourself to be negative
and you start listening to people that
want to be negative and be in drag you
down, you can easily had had
yourself in that direction as well.
So when you make the choice and make
a decision on which one of those two
directions you want to move
in, up or down, we recommend you move up,
move forward. Yeah, absolutely.
Uh, later that spring,
Eric and I went out to eat at a local
outback steak house to celebrate the on
wiring of my jaw.
They'd been almost seven months
since I've been able to chew food.
I was still underweight and confined
to wheelchair because the grass,
but we both needed a night out. I just,
you know, I, when I was reading this book,
um, I was like eating
something, whatever, you know,
and it's just one of those things that
we all take for granted every single day.
And you know,
I've had multiple prisoners of
war on this podcast and you know,
they're eating a bowl of rice once a day
or ball of rice walked twice a day that
has chips of wood in it for three years,
for six years.
And here you are. You know,
you're not in a prisoner of war,
but something as simple as eating a steak.
And that really like hit me
hard because as you know,
I take stakes very seriously and, and to,
to think that like verse seven months,
no steak and the daily things.
And that always gets me thinking about
the daily things that when I talked to my
friends that have been wounded,
it's like it's the daily,
every day things. And
as matter of fact, uh,
when we had Jim Webb on and he was
talking about one of his friends that had
been wounded in Vietnam and he's like,
that's the daily current.
Like that guy was courageous in Vietnam,
but he's courageous every single day,
takes him x amount of
time to get up out of bed,
takes them x amount of time
to get his prosthetics.
It takes them x amount of time to do
normal functions that people can normally
do easily.
He's got a struggle with them all and
he does it every single day without
complaining.
Daily courage.
And so just thinking about
you and that situation, man.
Awesome.
I flew to Chicago almost once a month
to preparation for my first surgery with
Dr. Walton,
which had scheduled for July.
The airports and their crowds
continued to be a tournament.
Little kids pointed at me and called
to their mothers to look at me too.
People refuse to talk to me.
They'd act ashamed or embarrassed
or they'd set expressions,
have pity on their faces internally.
I raged at them.
Are these the people I sacrificed for
coming back from a ship of coming back
from Chicago on one trip,
I just broke everyone who stared at me.
I treated with a sudden boom.
By the end of the trip though,
I realized I needed to do something
different or the bitterness would eat me
alive. It gave me a thought.
I came up with an idea.
I went online and designed a couple t
shirts. The first one said, stop staring.
I got shot by a machine gun.
It would have killed you.
I put an American flag on the back
and called the wounded were so
are you still making
the wounded wear shirts?
So what do wears on pause for right
now, but it will be coming back. So we,
we've got some work, we're getting
things online in 2019 but a yeah.
A lot of people have asked me when
it will come back. It will be back,
I assure you. Yeah. So
this podcast is eternal.
So most likely when people are listening
to this, it is live. Do you get it?
You can get your wounded wear t
shirt. That's right. Uh, yeah. The,
you were talking about that,
that sign and that sign got
so much attention and was so,
uh,
so impactful to so many people.
You ended up going to the Oval Office.
You ended up meeting President
Bush with your family. Um,
and then you ended up coming
back to the White House again.
And we're going back to the book.
I went to Mike [inaudible] stores,
metal of honor ceremony in the White House
that April Mike was a fellow seal who
had jumped on her hand grenade,
thrown onto a rooftop. He had
okay.
And saved two of his teammates
in a firefight in Ramadi.
He shielded his brother's with his own
body and paid the ultimate price for that
devotion.
Okay.
It was deeply moving to be there to see
Mike's Family receive his posthumous
metal of honor.
But while I was there,
I met another seal named Ryan job.
He'd been part of the team three and
had served with legendary sniper,
Chris Kyle in Iraq.
During the 2006 campaign,
Ryan had been a mark 48 machine gunner
for the team and during a firefight that
spring of bullet had struck his weapon,
then hit him in the face,
destroying his right eye.
He survived and reached Bethesda
much as I would a year later,
but nerve damage cost him
his vision in his left die.
The prospect of spending the rest of his
life blind had to have been terrifying
though he never showed it. Instead, he
announced that if he had to be blind,
he would be the best
damn blind man there was.
So that's where I met
you for the first time.
Obviously a Mikey and Ryan and Chris
were all with me and task you to bruiser
and you came out for the,
for the medal of honor ceremony for Mikey.
And I actually remember
looking at you guys, you know,
looking at you guys talking to each other
and I actually thought I had pictures
of it but I didn't,
I thought I had pictures of Youtube
talking but I didn't have any pictures.
But it was,
it was a crazy to sit there and look at
both you guys that have been, you know,
both men shot. Unfortunately Ryan,
you know, he lost vision in both eyes,
which obviously could have happened
to you very easily and thank God,
you know, it didn't, um, and
you guys kind of, you know,
I guess when you have getting shot in
the head and calm and you guys be Kinda
became Bros and uh,
continue on here.
Ryan and I bumped each other on multiple
occasions over the next several months.
On one of the occasions Ryan had come
out to the east coast seal teams for
wounded warrior,
a Benevolent Organization conference.
As we made small talk
and met different people.
I Ryan and another CEO who
had been shot in the eye,
we're joking around and came up with the
idea for a club for seals who had been
shot in the head.
It was a very small club.
We decided to call the club
Shit seals hit in the head.
We unanimously voted on our motto.
This club sucks.
So yeah.
Um,
just to pretty awesome. And
that's pretty much the, you know,
that's definitely Ryan biggles job's
attitude was he was just going to have a,
an awesome time all the time,
regardless of what situation he was in.
He was gonna, he was gonna
get after it and um, yeah,
it was cool to see you guys meet. Yeah.
Hey, Ryan was awesome and you know,
he was ahead of it.
It was interesting because
the reconstruction process
that they were doing with
me,
it was the same they were doing with Ryan.
And obviously I was
blessed to keep my vision,
although they were fixing
things with this. Right.
I so often I'd call him and
I'd be like, Hey, you know,
you had this done. How'd it
go? You know, what did you do?
Do you have any recommendations?
Like anything, you know,
you go to the people who have experienced,
so Ryan and I got close through that.
Yeah. Just kind of learning
from him. One of the, this,
this was another bit of a,
of a surprise to me. Again,
this is the kind of thing that I never
had to think about, but he, here you go,
going back to book.
In the months that followed,
I knew that I was in for the long game,
the slog through surgeries and
setbacks and tenured. And again,
you got to read this book to
realize the absolute just medical,
uh,
medical trauma that you're
going through day in, day out.
And this really drove it home to me. I
called it medical budge. There you go.
That's really what it will.
Medical Buds. And here's,
here's one thing that just
hit me like a ton of bricks.
By the summer of 2009,
I was starting to run low on the
available patches of skin for grafting.
My body was roping the scars from
surgical sites and over a dozen,
a dozen graphs. That to
me, I'm thinking of myself,
I mean you're running out
of skin to graph to, to,
to do damn two,
do a damage repair to your face.
What is that process like?
So a lot of times they harvest
the skin from, you know,
your thighs and areas and,
and it,
and it wasn't that I was
just running out of skin,
they were running out of skin cause I've
got quite a few tattoos so my back is
totally tattooed, you know,
uh, you know, top of my arms.
So that's what the problem was becoming,
putting tattooed skin on other
parts of your bodies. No big deal.
They could have cut that in a second,
but obviously they were
like, you know, we did the,
I did not want to put
tattooed skin on my face. Um,
so that's where we were
starting to run into issues.
And this really is something that a
lot of people don't understand with,
with battlefield injuries is they're
super dirty bombs or dirty bullets are
dirty and you fall in the soil.
And you bleed into the soil
overseas and that's nerdy.
So the vast majority of
wounded warriors come home,
especially from this war,
uh, with infection problems.
And there's so many guys,
myself included,
that it's not your initial injuries
that are as devastating. I mean,
obviously there's levels of devastation,
but for so many of us,
it's the infection problems.
So many guys come back with their limbs
and ended up losing their limbs because
of the infection. I had major infection
problems, which caused us to continue,
have to do more and more graphs.
They would have to cut out what they had
done because it was infected and failed.
Um, they rebuilt my nose three
times. Uh, so the first two,
they had a totally cut out and start over.
So that's why we were starting to
run into issues. Hey, where do we,
where do we get more cartilage?
Where do we get more skin? Um,
they can use cadaver, but it does not.
It does not last. It doesn't always take.
So they always want to use your own body.
And that's where we
started to run into issues.
September 24th,
Ryan job is dead.
I hadn't known Ryan incredibly well.
I wouldn't call him a close friend.
We talked on the phone occasionally.
We shared a common experience
and discussed our notes
on recovery and we shared
a twisted sense of humor,
but above all,
I respected his spirit
and relentless energy,
recapture all he could out of life.
He made the most of every
moment and achieved things.
Most people with their
eyesight intact never would.
In 2008 he climbed Mount Rainier.
When I heard about that,
I was blown away in
the climbing community.
That 14,000 foot volcanic mountain in
Washington state is considered one of the
most difficult to summit in all North
America. It has deadly crevices,
narrow ledges,
and glacial ice.
It is as technical climb as you can find.
Mount Rainier claims on
average three lives a year of
those who aspire to summit,
and Ryan made it to the top
two years after that bullet
robbed him of his vision.
He and Kelly,
who he had married,
he and Kelly were getting ready
to have a daughter together.
Ryan had started a new life,
found a fresh path to blaze and
had built something from the ruins.
He really was being the best
damn blind man out there.
Then with the snap cosmic fingers,
it was all stolen from him.
Okay.
And if you don't know the story,
there was what he went through one of
his many surgeries cause he was still
going through surgeries and after the
surgery there was complications and
he,
he died as well.
They killed him. I mean they matched up.
Yeah. There was, there was overdose Tam.
That was a total mistake.
And that slayed me. Um,
Ryan's death rocked me.
Um,
because I know how hard it is to stay
positive and to drive forward despite
these really hard
injuries. And, uh, and it,
it just, it killed me
to know that, you know,
it was a medical mistake that
killed him. You know, I mean,
it's hard enough to go through all this
and you survived battle and you know,
all these things. Yeah. So that, that,
um,
that really shook me when Ryan had died
and you're still looking at
unknown numbers of surgeries ahead.
And it at the time, yeah,
I was halfway through.
So this was 2009.
I ended up having surgeries all
the way up until 2011. Yeah. And,
and the other thing that was
crazy about Ryan was, um,
I'm not going to say he was
out of the woods. I mean,
but he was pretty damn far out of
the woods and that's why, you know,
to lose him like that was just
a fucking nightmare. Yeah.
You at this point you still want to get
back to the teams and you're trying to
get your arm fixed to the point where
you can have enough mobility in it too
to change magazines to
operate your weapon.
So you're going to a bunch of
different people trying to see who is,
who can make this happen. You
finally find a guy that's, you know,
you think you have a good lead on
somebody that can make this happen and he,
you go to see him and he says,
going back to the book, Jay,
I'm going to be frank with you. If you
were my son, I wouldn't let you do this.
What you have now is the
best possible outcome.
If you proceed and have another surgery,
you'll probably lose some of the
range of motion you have now. Worse,
you'll set yourself up for
a lifetime of chronic pain.
Okay.
The drive home was a quiet one for me
as I deliberated whether or not to roll
the dice one last time.
By the time I turned off the
freeway in for Virginia Beach,
I knew it was not worth the risk.
My days as an operator, we're over.
Part of me always suspected this
might happen. This might happen now.
It was confirmed.
I had no epiphany's during the drive home
about what to do now as the that dream
to kick doors again slipped away.
What would I do?
How would I support my family?
I didn't have any answers,
but I knew one thing I'd lived as Ryan
job had honor his memory and never take
another day for granted.
Ryan's death reminded me that
nothing is guaranteed in life.
They can be taken away in a heartbeat.
The life you've built with everything
you've got can come apart in an instant
from circumstances far
beyond your control.
You either adapt and overcome or you
become a casualty of those twists of fate.
I refused to be a casualty.
So you get this news that,
hey, you're not either, we can't do
this. This is what you got. What?
You got this where you're at.
And the idea of getting back
operational again is gone.
And it's funny, you and I were
just talking about, you know,
you were a over talking to some students
at Bud's and you had a guy that was,
was, but what have you
been injured? Older guy,
you said it wasn't real to come back
and yeah, he's medically dropped,
medically dropped,
not going to be able to come back.
And so dream is gone and it's interesting
you're talking to him and you'd been
through it,
been through it,
and your attitude was
okay when we can do now.
Okay.
And, and like I told him,
I mean, so you know, this,
this idea of life ambushes, uh, I told
him, I said, you just stepped into one.
And uh, there, there are
small ones and big ones. Um,
a lot of times they're totally unexpected,
but the reality is most ambushes
aren't totally unexpected.
There are indicators that we
see before we ever get into it,
whether we're aware of seeing them or not.
Sometimes it's after the fact that we
look back nine 11 is a good example of
there were indicators that
we missed before nine 11
happened. Uh, for us as seals,
when we move into areas
we know that's a bad area.
We are in an area where we're getting
channelized there's high ground above us.
This would be a good area
to execute an um, you know,
for me,
I had seen those indicators coming
so I kind of knew one was coming.
I had met so many doctors who said,
um,
literally the doctor from Johns Hopkins
who put my arm back together, um,
they actually wrote a medical journal
about what he did with my elbow. Um,
I mean he successfully reconstructed and
elbow that had been totally destroyed
and it was always funny to me. There's
an arrogance and I think there has to be,
there has to be a little bit level of
Aaron and arrogance and confidence and
high level orthopedic surgeon.
So every time I'd go meet one of
these guys they'd be like, Oh yeah,
I can fix your arm.
And then they slap that
ray up and I'd watch,
it was like the air got sucked out of
the room as they looked at it and then
they would look at me and they'd say,
yeah man, I'm sorry. I, they're like,
I don't even know how your
arms work in the way it is.
So when I met the guy from Duke who
was one of the premier, you know,
hand and arm guys,
literally the guy that put my arm together
was probably the premier hand and arm
guy. And I tried to get him to go back
and do more and he said no. He said,
there's no way in hell.
He said your arm. He said,
going into your arm and you're getting
what we got is a miracle. He's like,
I am not going back in. And I recommended
against anybody else doing it. Well,
I still tried to find other doctors and
it was his guy from Duke who finally
convinced me. So when that
moment came, I kind of knew.
Um,
so as opposed to this young man from buds,
it was less unexpected than
what I stepped, you know,
for me it was just unexpected.
So, um, it just became,
where do I go from here? Um, and,
and interestingly enough, I had laid out
some different things for myself. One,
I wanted to do a 20 year career,
so that kind of became my first thing.
Can I still stay in and finish my career?
Maybe I can't be operational.
Um,
at this point I was at dam neck and I
think I was at 18 years at this point.
So it had been four years,
almost four years from
my injury and a silver.
A couple of days I talked to, I was
working in operations and I just said,
hey, what are our options? What can we do?
And they actually allowed me
to go work some new things, um,
different projects and different things.
So it was great.
They allow me to finish
what I set out to do,
but it also gave me a decent
amount of time at this point.
It was another year before we started
the medical retirement process,
which actually took two years.
So it carried me to 21 years and it
gave me a lot of time to really look at,
you know,
where does my future go from here?
And to kind of lay out
what are my new passions,
what is my purpose and where do I go
from this life after the military?
What can I do with all these lessons
that I've learned and you know,
how do I pay it forward? How do
I honor Ryan? How do I honor?
And all these guys that every day I walked
by this granite wall and they didn't
get a choice. They didn't get
a choice to come home. So, um,
okay.
Thankfully, you know, I had that
time, it still within the community,
but also coming to grips
with the fact that, you know,
like I talked to those young men about
so many people are so strongly tied to
what they do for a living,
uh,
that they cannot function if suddenly
it's taken away from them. Uh,
there's a lot of meat,
a lot of police officers and firefighters
or professional athletes that if
suddenly their career is over, they
don't know how to function without that.
They've, they've tied their identities
so much around what they've done.
And,
um,
I realized that the lessons
that I learned in that the,
the seal teams and this journey that I
had been on was incredibly relatable. Um,
and it wasn't, had nothing to do
with tactical lessons. You know,
I didn't need to be the guy that got
out and taught you how to shoot or do
anything on that.
Like that.
What I realized it realized is there
were amazing life lessons, the lessons,
human lessons, lessons in leadership
and teamwork and overcoming a bursty.
And this idea of helping people,
you know,
not only survive but thrive
from crisis at ambushes.
So that really started to become the
path that I was walking and to help other
wounded warriors.
Well,
I just want to wrap this last little
section of the book because we're talking
about the identity and what you
invested your life into. And
you say this,
I held the try to in my hand,
this golden emblem had driven my life.
I focused on it. I called the did it,
I became enamored by it.
I almost lost it,
and then I earned it back before
I sacrificed my body for it.
Okay?
Only then did I finally understand
what it truly represented.
It carried the spirit of warrior
poets like Mike Murphy, Mike Monsoor,
and Chris Kyle. It carried the
spirit of my friends Ryan Job,
Adam Brown, Mike Mcgreevey, Kevin Houston,
and the 79 other men who have made the
ultimate sacrifice for freedom and the
Brotherhood since nine 11
okay.
I didn't know why God spared me,
but I did know I would find a way into
the future where I would use each and
every day to honor my brothers.
Yeah.
Who had not made it home.
And
I think obviously you've done a lot to uh,
honor our brothers
and
I think you continue to do that obviously
every day with what you're doing and
how you're doing it and how you're
taking the lessons that you learned and
bringing them to two more people
spreading the word broadly.
Um,
what did that translation transition
look like? Like the, you know,
from the time you got out into
where you are now because you know,
I mean obviously everyone that's
in the military right now, one day,
I hate to break the news to y'all.
One day you're going to be not in the
military anymore. Bring us from, you know,
the end of your career into where you are
now and where your focus right now and
what you're doing. Yeah, absolutely.
I think that transition is
a lot harder than people.
I realize, I think a lot of things,
I'm sure you experienced this,
we take for granted the level of
structure that exists in the military and
suddenly you get out in this
feeling world and that's not there.
I was a little bit fortunate
enough that I had launched, uh,
the nonprofit when you were a later to
become the combat wounded coalition while
I was still on active duty.
But, uh, so when I got out,
that kind of became my focus.
Got It.
I will say that I made the mistake that
a lot of military members and especially
special operations members make when
they get out. I tried to do everything.
Everything I saw was an opportunity
that I didn't want to lose out on and I
falsely can convince myself, yeah,
I have the ability to do that.
So running the nonprofit, we did
a lot of amazing things, you know,
two and a half million dollars. We
help thousands of wounded warriors, um,
even created a,
a program specifically to help
them to employers build structure,
find their new passion.
But what I started to realize,
and I was doing all this while I was
still trying to speak and develop content
and work on things, uh, and take care of
a family and kids and all these things,
and I kind of had an epiphany in
2018 I'd been doing this, you know,
I had retired in 2013 so five years
I had been doing this. And uh,
I suddenly realized,
you've got to find that one thing that
you truly are going to make a difference
at.
And I took a step back in 2018 and said,
where can I have the most impact
and what really is my new mission?
What drives my passion? Where
is my destination? Where am I,
where am I going to set that course to
go? And I realized, I look back, you know,
we were doing a lot of great
things with the nonprofit,
but there's 43,000 veteran
nonprofits out there.
We are losing more guys
to suicide right now. Uh,
then we lost to the
enemy. And I said, okay,
so one option is you go create
a whole nother nonprofit.
But there's a lot of good ones out there.
And I think that's part of the problem.
It's diluting some of the
message. So I said, maybe
I'm better off focusing on,
uh,
helping a whole bunch of people with this
message and lending my support suit to
another organization.
So myself and the board made the decision
that we were going to phase down our
organization in 2000 and 2019.
Made that shift that I'm totally focusing
on delivering this content to help
people overcome adversity,
to,
to launch themselves out of
failure and to not only survive,
which some people just survive from
these life ambushes from these massive
catastrophic events,
but to thrive from them,
to use them as a launch point
to get better. Uh, and to
understand how to do that.
Cause I realized, man, you know, this,
you've written all this amazing content
on it and all that is coming into the
second book that'll come out in
December called overcome. So,
uh,
I have online courses that are getting
ready to come on board here in the next
couple of months.
And I just want to get out there and help
as many people as I can and then lend
myself to some of the organizations
that are out there that are helping. Uh,
R W we're specifically with posttraumatic
stress and traumatic brain injuries.
One of the things I've started doing a
lot of research and what we're beginning
to understand is,
um,
I used to think that if we could help guys
find a new purpose after they got out,
it would help solve their problems.
Wounded Warriors.
But what we're beginning to
understand is that we have never,
the way we train now and the way we
have fought wars is exposing guys,
especially on frontline
combat units and special ops,
special operation units to level
of blasts that we've never in,
in,
in up until this point.
And the way we trained in the military
we haven't done before. So, I mean,
you look at our breachers and how
many blasts we exposed them to just in
training. Yep. Um, and what
we're starting to see, I mean,
I've had multiple friends now that have
killed themselves, who I said, no way,
no way.
And I've watched these downward slides
and what we're starting to find out is we
are creating physiological impacts on
the brain from these continued exposures
to these blasts. So we need more
research. We need, you know,
we need more non pharmacological
solutions to these problems.
And there's a lot of things that are
out there that are on the forefront.
So one of the things with research,
I started doing some stuff with
the concussion legacy foundation,
which is the same group working
with the NFL or you know,
highlighting the impact
of CTE on NFL players.
And we're beginning to realize that some
of our special operations guys like Rob
Guso who took his life severe CTE,
but what they figured out
is it's different. Uh,
some of the premier premier neurologists
that are out there and figuring out,
it's different.
It's a,
it's blast and the blast goes all the
way through the brain as opposed to a
concussion that creates an impact.
And there's a centralized location.
Now for guys or even gals out there
that I've had multiple concussions that
creates more. But the bottom
line is we need this research.
So I donated my brain to the concussion
legacy foundation and I'm encouraging
all the veterans that are out there.
If you have been in combat,
donate your brain. You need it. I get it.
You don't need it when you're gone and
they're not going to come early and
collect, you know. But, uh,
the bottom line is it is an amazing way
to be able to give back to the veterans
that are coming up behind you because
they don't have enough veteran brains in
the brain banks that are out there to
understand the kind of trauma we're
putting on our brains.
And until they, and, and,
and obviously they can't study the
brains while we're still alive. So if,
if you want a way to give back,
look up the concussion legacy foundation
and donate your brain, I did it.
We need the research 2030 years from now,
we can make a difference to save some
young warrior that's out there that got
exposed to blast and now can't figure
out why his world is falling apart around
him. So those are my passions.
That's my purpose. And A,
I want to help as many people out there.
I want to make you better,
help you thrive from adversity,
help you thrive from failure and crisis.
And for our wounded warriors,
I want to help try and solve this epidemic
we're seeing in the suicides and the
brain trauma.
Yeah,
that's,
I mean that's just awesome.
It's awesome to see you
moving forward with that.
And I know we've been going for a while
here and that's probably a pretty good
place to wrap. Where do,
where can people find you?
Where should people locate
you and when they want to,
when they want to hear from you?
Yeah, absolutely. Best Place.
Go to Jason redmond.com.
That's my website and you
can see what I'm doing.
You can contact me through there. I'm on
all the major social media platforms, uh,
Jason Redman on Facebook.
And Jason Redmond,
ww on Instagram
and Twitter.
Awesome.
Echo speaking to people
and making people better.
You have any quick recommendations on
how you know we could improve ourselves?
Sure. This is x Charles, by the way.
I have one question in ranger school
when they told you to like, all right,
when they asked you,
do you need your Gucci,
was that the thing that kind of sent you
over the head when they said the Gucci
thing?
No, I don't think it was that. I really,
it was a, it was the land Nav comments.
I mean, I had taught land math. So, um,
the funny thing about
that Gucci Jacket is,
so the army guys were only allowed
to wear the army jacket liner. Well,
we didn't have those. Yeah.
And I Gucci, Patagonia,
I had the member of the green from these
that came. Yeah. That's what I had.
So every day I put that on the ranger
instructors would lose their minds.
And uh,
and in the beginning I had such a bad
attitude that I just took it in a negative
way. But the second time I
went through it became the,
how often can I put this
on and spend these guys.
So I still have it. This, I still have it.
Every time I pull it out of my closet,
it puts a smile on my face. Yeah. Nice.
What else? No, that's it for
questions. Yeah. Yeah. We
can talk about getting better
though. Yeah. And Jay's about to
start training in Jujitsu. Boom.
So he's going to need a to g two G
so we need to get that hooked up.
Where are we going to hook
them up with a g from origin?
Hundred percent even 99% a hundred
percent 104 g and all made in America.
Okay. All right. That's all we need to
continue to grow this country. Yes sir.
So yeah.
Origene if you're into Jujitsu,
getting into Jujitsu or already in Judith,
you want to g a new G or another geek
origin method are going to say used g I
can get a used as a market for used gies.
No,
they're shit that I was going to say.
It probably depends on who wore it.
I guarantee there's people out
there that would love a choco gay,
but that gets a little weird.
Yeah. That doesn't smell good.
Well, yeah, maybe some, some people, maybe
if someone like lost weight or something,
you know,
I don't use this anymore.
Eventually you were out of GE or although
the new ones talking to Pete the other
day,
the amount of Geek pants or Giza
period that had been returned is like,
so he said, yeah, we get like
three geese back a year with some,
it's actually had worn something out.
They just don't wear out out orange
and he's just do not wear out. Yeah.
Get some of that. Yeah.
You got to like, um, yeah,
like if you lose weight or something
and then you don't use it anymore,
or if you're like,
you get the new one and you know how
like you turn you back to the old one
because the new one that's
the new hotness, you know,
you don't really wear it anymore,
so he'd give it to your
friend or something like this.
There's that rash guards, tee shirts, uh,
other stuff. Yeah. Supplements,
supplements, joint warfare.
Joint warfare and Krill oil turned out
to be the most important supplements
there are. In my opinion, to hang.
He thought it was the protein
powder and the creative team.
That's what we thought in the
beginning. Not Anymore. Joint joint.
The worker hundred percent we thought
that. Yeah. Well yes, I agree.
We do have drone warfare coil and if you
do want protein you might as well enjoy
it. Yes sir. Get yourself some milk.
It's still good for you. We need protein,
we need the protein. That's why we
have milk. Which have you tried milk?
I have it. Okay. We're gonna get
you some milk and especially,
well it depends on what flavors you like.
I like mint chocolate chip.
I am a fan of nut milk but
apparently doc Luke hates meant,
well apparently he was going Berserker
the other day saying why would you drink
something that tastes like toothpaste?
Yeah. But so as it turns out some,
you know, to back to
another fence analogy, some,
it's like you either love it or you
really don't like it. As it turns out,
that's the situation with them. Where
we got meant peanut butter chocolate,
the vanilla gorilla. I'm a huge fan of
peanut butter chocolate. Okay. Okay.
Well I do like mint chocolate.
I got hostile with my whole family the
other day. Well not with my whole family,
with my wife and my youngest
because there was no,
I wanted some yogurt and there was no
blueberry, there was no strawberry,
there was no coconut, there was a
leaf vanilla. And so I started saying,
why would a human being
in 2019 by Vanilla Yogurt,
like choose,
choose of all the I get if it comes in
the variety pack and you end up with it,
you understood.
But straight up selected no wrong answer.
So I had to get hostile,
super hostile and I was telling my wife
and my youngest daughter that they are
crazy for just liking that vanilla. They
are for sure. But at the end of the day,
you know, he had an understanding of
other people. They have other opinions.
My seems my youngest daughter,
nine years old, she makes,
so what she does is she takes
strawberries, cuts them up,
and then she puts a whipped cream on
it and then she takes or your kid milk
strawberry and sprinkles it.
Nice
little protein protein from.
Cool. Yeah. That's good. Oh yeah.
Where your kid milk does for the kids?
Right?
Little more formally than our adults.
I know that possibly do drink it like me.
They sneak it to, yes sir. They do. Also,
if you want to represent while you're
on this path you did to working out,
waking up or you wake up early.
I do, however I get up at five.
Okay, so the up early crew,
if you're on that. Oh,
and you want to represent
aesthetically Jocko was a store.
It was called Jocko store,
so we go to the chocolate store.com
that's where you can get shirts,
discipline equals freedom.
A shirt that has jackals face on it.
It says good backwards. It's for
you. It's a message for you anyway.
You want to reframe very fitting
for today's story, right? Love it.
Looking at yourself. Yes,
adversity. That's got a
branding problem with hold on.
Good, good opportunity. Look forward.
Actually I liked that like for, you know,
cause there's a lot of different
approaches, you know, like you say,
get off the exit and like
look forward. Absolutely. Men,
you have to show the people look back,
they look back at what they've lost and
I don't know what's going on right now
kind of thing, which is natural by the
way. Oh It is course. But man, yeah,
that's good.
Just long enough to assess what you
did wrong and then you move forward,
learn some lessons and then
move forward. But yeah. So yeah,
if you want to represent
and go to Jacklyn, store.com
lot of cool stuff on there.
If you like something, get something new.
Hoodies up there. By the way, by the way,
are they thick, rather thick?
Okay. That's, you know,
that's not what I'm looking for.
Well, you know, we're making,
I'm going to think I'm gonna call him when
I finally get the hoodies that I want.
Mccoll Michigan hoodies or
Minnesota hoodies for that
people main Eskimo hoodies
off up north,
north polar for tax.
You think they wanted that lightweight
hoodie during the polar vortex, Bro? No.
So I'm just saying there's like different
regions of the world so he can get
that align with Ferg
guarantee for 20 below
region that we're talking about is
coal. Yes sir. Okay. I dig it in.
That is a good name for it for
sure. Cool. So anyway. Yes.
When it gets cold you can
have hot Jocko white tea. Yes.
As opposed to cold Jocko
white tea company on Amazon.
Ever subscribed to the
podcast if you want to.
Don't forget about the
warrior kid podcasts. Yeah,
that's good on a lot of people say
that's the best podcasts for kids ever.
You're not a lot from kids and
here's why you feel that way.
You won't be wrong by the way you
feel this way because it's so simple.
So you're like thinking of it in terms
of Leon, when my kid listens to this,
oh they're going to get it fully and
then you listen to it, you're like, Dang,
I'm kind of get into me. You
know, like it's kind of for me.
So that's a problem with adults,
man. We complicate every, yeah, I do.
Yes. Yeah, that's the uh, that's
why I love the for your kid books.
This is a message for a 10 year old.
And guess what I've had,
I have many adults that say thank you
for writing that Warrior King Book Echoes
One of them. Another one.
Yes. Yeah. So there's that.
Don't forget that warrior
kid soap from young Aden,
13 year old warrior kid has his own
business. He's getting after it.
He's got goats up in central California.
He milks them.
You can't sell goat milk or whatever
in California cause they got all these
rules. So what can you do
with it? You can make soap.
He started making soap and his,
his motto is stay clean,
which I paid up. Don't worry,
don't worry. And I gave it to you.
I'm so arrogant and egotistical,
I want to take the credit for the,
for the name or whatever the mantra of,
of Aiden's soap store.
That's messed up. That's
sows. That's weakness, right?
It's a collaborative thing.
Youtube channel echoes makes you a
bunch of videos. Speaking of arrogant,
he thinks his videos are great and
he posts them on there. There you go.
Never demonstrated that. But yeah.
Thank you. Okay. You sure about that?
Yeah, I think so. Yeah.
Yeah, yeah. Okay. Yes. Yes sir. Yeah.
Youtube does a good on the video version
of this podcast too, by the way. Check.
You know,
you can see what everybody looks like if
you care about that sort of thing. Uh,
people watch people watch the ones with
guests because they want to see what the,
cause they know what I look like.
They know what echo looks like.
They want to see what j red.
And it looks like,
what does a man look like that
took a round through that phase.
At that point they stopped the
podcast and press play on Youtube.
See what's going on.
It is $2 million and sexiness.
So if you've ever wondered where
your American tax dollars went to,
it went to a good cause. This time
you're not quite the $6 million man.
You're the two magnets,
your million dollars
hundred per psychological warfare.
You can get that too. It'll,
it's a little something to help you out.
Look it up on iTunes.
That's all we're going to say
about it. Period. Period. Period.
They to go, man, Jay's got
to go. All right. What?
Maybe Jay doesn't know what psychological
warfare is. Good is what it is.
It's an album with tracks Jocko tracks
telling you how to get through moments of
weakness that you might
come across and about.
Instilling that discipline to get up.
I've actually listened to cycle.
I thought I got flanks for a second but
it actually wasn't. I stand corrected.
What else we got? We got on it. If we're,
when you add to your home gym situation,
your home fitness situation going on
at.com/jack a lot of good stuff on there.
Get a jump rope if you
don't like get rings.
Actually rings are 100% in my opinion
and I'm signing on 100% the best thing
that you can get, I need some
rinks. I know where to go for a,
I'm thinking about that from
my home gym or you definitely,
you definitely got to have rings it.
That's the first thing you need.
I used to say the first thing
you need was a pull up bar,
but you can do more with rings and you
can do poems so you might as well just
get rigs kettlebells too,
by the way.
We got some books.
Okay. First of all book.
I again read a bunch of excerpts
today but not even close to putting,
giving justice to this book to
try to end by Jason Redmond.
We will have it up on the site,
right? Yes sir. On the top.
Oh, that's you have menus on the podcast
or something from episodes to be,
have you ever looked at our
website and thought, oh,
that looks like a cool website for 1996
yeah. I wonder if I was the only guy.
I was wondering if I was the
only guy and I was like, yeah,
well that's 96 but that's cool.
Maybe echoes just doesn't like me.
Retro Retro is in eight more
years it's going to look cool.
That's what's happening with the,
with the website. So you know,
you're ahead of your time. Taco store
website looks all cool. Why is that?
Well, you know, various reasons.
Okay, cool. That sounds great. Uh,
we also got some books.
Mike Cain,
the dragons kids book for kids
between the ages of four and 100.
So get Mike in the dragons way,
the warrior kid and Mark's mission,
those are out and we have booked three,
which I completed is being drawn by
the artist right now. John Bozak. Uh,
we're going to put that up so
you can preorder it so you,
so I don't sell out of books like we
did Mikey and the dragons immediately.
So I will fix that this
time. I apologize. Last time.
Discipline equals freedom field
manual. Get that, how to get after it.
Audio is on iTunes, Amazon music,
Google play, extreme ownership.
First Book that I wrote with my brother
Leif Babin and the follow on to that,
that dichotomy of leadership talking
about don't go too far in one direction or
the other as a leader or you will
blow it echelon front of my leadership
consultancy and what we do is
solve problems through leadership.
Whatever problems you
have in your organization,
I 100% guarantee they
are leadership problems.
That's what they are and that's what
we do. Me Leif Babin, J P and l,
Dave Burke, Flynn Cochran, Mike's
Raleigh, Mike [inaudible], go to Ashkelon,
front.com if you need help with
leadership in your team or organization,
the muster,
speaking of leadership,
this is our leadership conference 2019
this is when it's going down May 23rd and
24th in shy town,
shy town town Chicago.
We can get steaks.
We're going to,
we're going to talk about leadership
September 19th and 20th in Denver,
Colorado.
We're going to steaks there too and
then December 4th and fifth in Sydney,
Australia.
We're going to go there and yes,
we're going to get steaks there as well.
Look at all these events.
Have sold out completely and all
these are going to sell out too.
So if you want to come,
go to extreme ownership.com to register,
haven't even worse.
It's selling a lot right now and I
haven't even posted anything about it,
so I'm scared of the post
so I don't want people to,
I don't want non podcast listeners
to get a crack at it early,
but I'm going to have to post soons so
let people know what's up. E F online.
So this is online interactive
leadership training.
It is interact. I know, I know. It
sounds like one of those words like, uh,
like a Buzzword, right? Interactive,
but you straight up interacts.
Okay. Remember those video
games back in the day.
We're all about the same age were
on the old school computers, right.
Where you can, you're like, oh,
I'm traveling through the woods and I
can go down this and choose your own
adventure. Yeah. You know, and you can
choose one and it'll, they'll do it.
It's kind of like that.
Yes.
You have to make leadership decisions
in the online training he did.
Once you learn the principles,
you have to try and apply them to
combat and business situations.
So that's e f online.com.
Check it out.
You can get it as an individual or you
can get an enterprise version for your
whole company.
So that's that and ETF Overwatch where
we're connecting combat proven leaders
from the SPEC ops community and from
the combat aviation community with
companies in the civilian
sector that need leadership,
proven leadership to align and
move their company forward.
Go to F,
overwatch.com for that.
And if you want to continue this
conversation, ask questions,
give us answers.
Tell me what I mispronounced.
Tell me what historical fact I got wrong.
Hit us up.
We're on the social media,
on Twitter, Instagram,
and on the face.
The Facebook,
Jason Redmond is at Jason
Redman at ww echo is adequate.
Charles, I'm at Jockowillink
Echo. Anything else? No,
thank you so much for coming.
Jay rendered any closing thoughts
to shout out to everybody out
there? Um, you know, most
importantly obviously, uh, my,
my beautiful wife who our
journey is included in this book.
So if you are one of the lovely females
that are out there that would say maybe
this book isn't for me. Uh, it absolutely
is once again in is not a combat book.
It is a journey of leadership
and at its heart and soul.
It is a love story and my
wife never batted an eye on
this journey and this book
is dedicated to her and my kids'
shoes love brought me home.
So big shout out to them and a
big shout out to both of you guys.
Thank you for having me on and a for
getting out there and we need more
leadership out there and you guys are
putting it out there so it's awesome.
Oh no brother,
thanks for coming on and obviously
thanks for your service to our country.
Thanks for what you did for the teams
and thanks for what you're continuing to
do right now.
You've sacrificed a lot and you're still
out there every day grinding and making
things happen.
Thanks for doing that and man overcome.
And of course thanks to all our military
personnel that are standing watch
around the world to protect our freedoms.
And utmost appreciation for
those wounded warriors like Jay,
who continue to sacrifice bravely every
day for the freedoms that we all enjoy.
Okay.
And also thank you to our police, law
enforcement, firefighters, paramedics,
EMT is correctional
officer's border patrols.
All the first responders out there who
stand watch on the home front to keep us
all safe.
Okay.
And to everyone else out
there that's listening,
okay.
There really are no excuses.
There are none men like Jay Redmond
proof that men like Ryan job prove that
without question.
So don't allow yourself to fall short.
Don't allow yourself to give anything
less than everything you've got.
Yeah.
To take the fight to the enemy who
ever in whatever that enemy might be.
Yeah.
Do what you're supposed to do.
Be who you're supposed to be
by going out there every day
and getting after it.
Then until next time,
this is Jason Redmond and Becko and Jocko
out.