To everybody listening.
People in uniform, people in
business suits, people in coveralls,
people,
everyone.
We talked today about Mikey Monsoor
and don't want to leave you with this.
Mikey monster was named
after Saint Michael.
Saint Michael is the war your archangel
that led to heaven's army against Satan.
Yeah.
Saint Michael was known as the
principal of the angelic warriors
and was seen
as a protector against the darkness
and in the Christian religion,
specifically in the Anglican and the
Catholic and the Lutheran churches.
September 29th September 29th
is known as Michael Mass.
Yeah.
Or Saint Michael's Day.
And that day,
September 29th,
was the day that our Saint Michael,
Mikey Monsoor
was killed in Iraq.
The city of Ramadi sacrificing his life,
okay.
To save the lives of
three of his teammates,
three of his brothers,
three of his friends.
And I would ask you this,
when September 29th comes around,
okay.
Remember
I would ask that while you honor the hero
and you honor the warrior that Michael
[inaudible] was,
please
also remember
that Mikey was a person,
keywords,
a smiling kid.
He was a jokester.
He was a determined man,
a brother, a son, or an uncle,
or a friend,
or Michael Monster.
War was a young man
with hopes and plans and
aspirations and dreams,
dreams for his future
and dreams for his life.
And in that moment of truth,
he gave them all,
all those hopes and all
those dreams he gave them all
to us.
Remember that.