This is Jocko podcast number
82 with Echo Charles and me,
Jocko Willink. Good
Evening Echo. Good evening.
I was walking down the street okay.
And I was pretty sure I would die
and I did not mind.
In fact,
a large part of me looked forward to it,
to that release to go to heaven,
to meet Christ for it all to be over
accorded death like a sailor courts,
a twirling Spanish barmaid.
I was not afraid,
even as we try to grasp broken streets
with asphalt and make shift concrete pile
like sloppy cake icing,
hiding the surprises below
large iads and screams and blood and
burning flesh and burning vehicle tires.
Okay.
All superficially hidden,
all obviously present.
All a joke.
Death had been at the forefront of my
mind and part of my decision to become a
soldier at all
and that's what I considered
myself, a soldier, a grunt,
an infantry man,
a ground pounder,
a soldier.
What else is there?
Yeah,
we all turned into soldiers on patrol.
We competed with each other and the men
and other units and other services to
see who could patrol in
the most disciplined way.
We would see who we could catch staring
at his feet or not watching his field of
fire or not scanning for threats or not
keeping his shooting hand on his gun.
Yeah,
and when the shooting did start,
we would watch to see who would panic
and who would cower.
These were seemingly fun games
and recesses breaking up the fear,
which was so overpowering.
It put a deep ache in our
stomachs and in our bowels.
There was chaos that
brought me to this point.
Wild music as a young boy slayer,
Metallica in their prime venom Motorhead,
heavy alcohol use by age 10
drug use by age 11 late
night punk concerts and mosh
pits where I nearly lost my
front tooth at age 12 as it dug
deeply into a punks shaved head,
I was tall for my age and
people treated me like an adult.
They tried to bring me into their filth.
Junkies,
perverts,
degenerates
and evil world
burning
so much. So that war, who
was a dream come true.
It seemed as if now I could fight back
against the depravity and evil that tried
to engulf me
and I held that quiet hope,
that unspoken hope that maybe I could
die in war doing something heroic like
they trained us to do.
Maybe this God forsaken and
worthless life could be over.
Yeah,
this gauntlet
and so the IED laden roads attempting
to scare me and us or a joke
and I did not care about it,
about the setup,
about the punch line.
I just wanted enemy contact and I
wanted to smell the blood of particles
floating through the afternoon air
and the screams of the dying.
That is what I wanted.
It seems so beautiful.
My mind had romanticized at all,
but what we got wasn't so romantic.
Isn't wasn't so beautiful.
Most of the screens I heard with the
screams of my countrymen as they bled
or the screams of innocence who were
in the wrong place at the wrong time.
I watched the funerals of men.
We shot going right past us.
The children crying,
the wives glaring as they damn us with
ancient Babylonian curses that would try
to follow me back to my home in St Tannic
nightmares where I could not escape
them.
Yeah.
All those things made def
so true and so beautiful
and so acceptable.
Okay.
No,
those words were written by
someone that I served with
in Ramadi in 2006 and he sent them to
me the other day after we talked and I
asked him to write down what he thought
about and he was walking down the street
in Ramadi and
obviously what he wrote about
get revealed so much of the,
the incredible spectrum
of emotions and thoughts
that run through our heads.
And obviously war
magnifies those.
Okay.
But these are thoughts of a human being.
And these are the kinds of
thoughts that people have,
not just in war but in life,
the struggles.
And as I was sitting thinking about,
you know,
that word and that the fact that struggle,
it absolutely shapes us.
And I was talking about this when I was
with Joe Rogan and Chris Cornell from
Soundgarden had just killed himself.
And we were talking about the struggles
and Joe was saying that destroy you.
You got to kind of like struggle and
you need struggle. People need struggle.
And some of the feedback that
I saw on social media was,
you know,
there's a difference between struggle and
challenge and that a challenge is good,
but struggle is bad. And,
and you know, I don't know,
and I'm not wishing struggles upon anyone.
I'm no guru.
But I do know that struggle
and strife shapes us.
Okay.
It shapes us. There's no
doubt. And I was always
thinking about this,
I started thinking about a bunch of
different books that I've read in the past
and one of them is a book called,
and we'd go on
and it was written by a guy named will,
our bird,
who's from Nova Scotia,
Canada.
And he was a soldier in the
Canadian army in World War One.
And He'd enlisted in the
army to replace brother.
So his brother had been killed in
battle and he said, okay, I need to,
I need to enlist now. And at first he
couldn't enlist because he had bad teeth.
And then as more and more guys got killed,
they loosened the standards and they
allowed him in even with his bad teeth.
And the book is very different.
Yeah.
And we're not going to go
through the whole book today,
but what makes the book different is he,
he talks about
like the supernatural
and he wrote another
book as a matter of fact,
which is called ghosts have warm hands.
And so this kind of supernatural
world is something that he,
he spends some pretty
decent amount of time on.
Yeah.
And in the beginning of the book,
one of the things that he says is the
trench at zero hour was a crucible that
dissolved all insincerity
and the superficial,
and you can clearly imagine that these
guys getting ready to go over the top,
I mean,
what else matters at that point?
Everything that's not true is everything
that is not sincere just means nothing
at that point.
And I'm going to go to the book here for,
for a minute.
Okay.
In, here's one of the things he
said about sort of, again, I'm,
I've just started thinking
about the psychological side.
Yeah.
Of what people are going through.
So here we go to the book.
This story is an effort to reveal a
side of war that has not been given much
attention. The psychic effect
it had on its participants
there existed before all battles and even
in the columns of the trench routine,
a condition before which all
natural explanations failed,
that no supernatural
explanations were established.
Every human emotion ran its full gamut
in that land of topsy turvy and prolonged
intensity of feeling rot,
feeling rot,
strange psychological changes
which warped the soul itself,
never on earth.
Was there a place where a man's support
often as sole support was his faith in
some mighty power?
Yeah,
all intervening thoughts were
swept aside unconsciously.
There were born faiths that men carried
through critical moments and tortured
minds grasp fantasies that served
in place of more solid creeds.
Okay.
I think it's interesting that
he says warped the soul and,
and I don't actually thinking,
and again, I'm no literary expert,
but I don't think he means that with
the the negative connotation of warped
being negative and bad.
But I think he means like a
departure from the normal,
a departure from the straight line moving
away from the natural direction and so
it leaves,
it leaves men changed
and like I said, I'm not going
to cover this, this whole book.
We'll probably do it at
some point in the future,
but I think when he gets to the end of
the book and he makes some statements
that are pretty powerful and of course
this is now after he's gone through the
war and he's on a ship
sailing back to Canada
and I'm going to read this section here.
We go back to the book
darkness,
the rush of the ship.
I felt my way again into a stifling
dug out into an atmosphere,
rancid with stale sweat and breathing
earth mold and the hot grease of candles I
saw faces,
cheeks resting on tunics,
mud streaked on shave and dirty faces
with some with teeth clenched and sudden
hate.
Some livid with pulse stopping fear.
I saw men turning on their wire bunks
quivering as if some red hot grill.
I heard them gasp and sob and cry out in
agony and mutter as they tossed again.
Then a machine guns note louder,
higher, Sharper crack. Crack.
Crack has its sweeped over you in a
shell hole where you hug the earth.
Okay.
The growl of guttural voices,
heavy steps in an unseen trench,
just the other side of the black mass of
tangled Barb barricade beside which you
cower.
The long drawn wine of a shell.
It's heart gripping explosion, the
terrible, oppressive silence that follows.
Okay.
Then the first low wail of the man who
is down with a gaping blood spurting
wound.
I moved about,
shook myself,
sniff the salt air and tried
to rid myself of my dreams.
Then as I stood there,
there came a sudden chill.
I grew cold as if I had
entered a clammy cavern
I could not understand,
but went and got my great coat,
a dim figure past me. As I returned
to the deck and the voice said,
we're getting near home,
I can feel the change.
Ah,
I knew we had left the warm current and
we're into the icy waters near her home.
We had left behind the comradeship of
long hours on the trench post and patrols,
long days under blazing suns and
cruel marches on, cobbled roads,
the brotherhood of the line,
and we were entering a
cold. See, facing the dark,
the unknown.
We could not escape.
Dark figures came and stood beside me.
I had not thought that anyone saved
myself would come on deck and here they
were, 10 a dozen, still more,
all hunched in, great coats,
silent staring.
I looked at my watch.
There was three o'clock in the morning.
These men could not sleep.
They were come to see the
first lights of Halifax.
I moved quietly among them,
scanning each blurred face.
It was as I thought
they were all old timers,
the men of the trenches.
We went on and on and on
and no one spoke though.
We touched shoulders.
I tried to think of a comparison.
Ah,
we were like prisoners.
I had seen them standing like
that without speaking, staring,
thinking
prisoners.
We were prisoners,
prisoners who could never escape.
I had been trying to imagine how I would
express my feelings when I got home
and now I knew I never could.
None of us could.
We could know more,
make ourselves articulate,
then could those who would not return.
We were in a world apart,
prisoners in chains that would
never loosen till death freed us
and I knew those at home
would never understand.
They would be inpatient.
Wondering why we were so dumb on able
to put our experiences into words,
and there would be many of the
boys who would be surly taciturn,
moody resenting good intentions,
perhaps taking the hard
liquor and aimless drifting.
We have the Brotherhood,
could understand the soldier,
but never explained him.
All of us would remain a separate,
definite people as if branded
by some monstrous despotism.
Yeah,
but I warmed, as I thought
of all that, the Brotherhood,
it meant the sharing of blankets
and bread and hardships.
The binding of each other's wounds.
The talks we had had of intimate things
of the dog had simple faith that men had
showed flashes of their inner selves.
That strengthened to one's own soul.
Yeah.
Perhaps when my bitterness past,
when I had got back to normal
self to loved ones tried hard.
By years of waiting,
I would find that despite that horror,
which I could never forget,
I had equalizing treasure in memories.
I could use like Jacob's ladder to get
high enough to see that even war itself
could never be the whole of life.
The watchers stirred,
I tingled my throat tightened.
Okay.
Waves of emotion seized me,
held me.
I grew hot and cold at queer sensations.
Every man had tensed craned forward,
yet no one spoke.
There was the moment for which we had
live, which we had dreamed visioned,
pictured a thousand times.
It held us now so enthralled,
so full of feeling that we
could not find utterance.
1 million thrills ran through me
far ahead, faint, but growing brighter.
We had glimpsed the first lights of home.
That line.
Okay.
When he says,
perhaps when my bitterness is passed and
I could use my memories and he's saying
he could use his memory's like Jacob's
ladder to get high enough to see that
even war itself could
never be the whole of life.
Okay.
And most of the struggles
he's talking about,
those are the hardships.
Yeah.
And this,
this change in his mindset to
not let those drag him down,
but,
but to use those to climb up.
And I think, I think we, you,
we lose track of that sometimes
in all we see is the trench
and we get stuck in the trench.
And I think it's
interesting that these men
literally,
and metaphorically speaking,
these men were in trenches,
but they were able to rise
out of these trenches,
these trenches of unimaginable suffering.
And I,
I think to myself,
if they are able to rise out
of those hellish trenches,
then that means we can too.
We can't do. And again, this,
this thing that my,
this thing that my buddy had sent me,
they just got me thinking about
that psychological turmoil of war.
And that sent me into thoughts
of another book. Again,
another book that
I read a while back and reading
and remember when I read it,
but I just started thinking about it.
And this one was about Vietnam.
And it's, it's a classic,
it's, it's called a rumor
of war. And, and again,
we'll will absolutely cover this book
on the podcast in detail at some point,
but I'm kind of just was
on this literary tour mode
and the psyche I think is just a good
view of the psyche that people have in
war,
which again reflects
life.
And there's a section in this book
where Phil Kaputo is assigned to a rear
echelon unit using the rear and you know,
he's a lieutenant in the Marine Corps.
He's in the rear and I think he's in a
regimental command post or something,
but he's not fighting.
And here's what he thinks
of that go into the book.
In the middle of November
at my own request,
I was transferred to a line
company and first battalion,
my convictions about the war had eroded
almost to nothing. I had no illusions,
but I had volunteered for a line company.
Anyway,
there were a number of reasons of
which the paramount was boredom.
There was nothing for me to do,
but count casualties.
I felt useless and a little guilty about
living in relative safety while other
men risked their lives.
I cannot deny that the front
still held fascination for me.
The rights or wrongs of the war aside.
There was a magnetism about combat.
You seem to live more intensely
under fire. Every sense were sharper,
the mind work clearer and faster.
Perhaps it was the tension of opposites
that made it so and attraction balanced
by revulsion.
Hope that ward with dread,
you found yourself on a precarious
emotional edge experience experiencing a
headiness that no drink
or drug could match.
The fear of madness was another motive.
The hallucination I had had and that
that day and the mass of seeing Maura in
Harrison prefigured in deaf had
become a constant waking nightmare.
Okay.
I'd begun to see almost everyone as they
would look in death, including myself,
shaving in the mirror in the morning,
I could see myself dead.
Okay.
And there were moments when
I not only saw my own corpse,
but other people looking at it.
Okay,
I saw life going on without me.
The sensation of not being anymore came
over me at night just before falling
asleep.
Sometimes it made me laugh inside.
I could not take myself seriously
when I could already see my own death,
nor seeing their deaths as well.
Could I take other seriously?
We were all the victims of a
great practical joke played
on us by God or nature.
Maybe that was why
corpse is always grinned.
They saw the joke at the last moment.
Sometimes it made me laugh,
but most of the time it was not at all
humorous and I was sure that another few
months of identifying bodies would
land me in a psychiatric ward.
Okay.
On staff, there was too much
time to brood over those corpses.
There would be very little time to think
and align company that is the secret to
emotional survival in war,
not thinking.
Finally there was hatred,
uh,
hatred buried so deep that I could
not then admit its existence.
I can now though it is still painful.
I burned with a hatred for the Viet
Cong and with an emotion that dwells and
most of us, one closer to the
surface than we care to admit,
a desire for retribution.
Okay?
I did not hate the enemy for their
politics, but for murdering Simpson,
for executing that boy whose body had
been found in the river for blasting the
life out of Walt Levy
revenge was one of the reasons I
volunteered for a line company.
I wanted a chance to kill somebody
and you could see even in that the,
you know,
comparing that with the first piece of
of things being a joke and how you just
hard, you just get to this point
where things just become a joke.
How can you take anything seriously
would you don't even know what's going
to happen and if you're going to live,
how much meaning does life have?
If you're not going to live it,
it gets back out to a line
company and now he's on patrol
talking about
not only what that's like externally
but what it's like mentally.
Psychologically.
Going back to the book,
I tightened the shoulder straps of my
pack heavily loaded with signal flares,
smoke grenades,
dry socks,
a Poncho and three days
rations and entrenching tool
and machete were lashed to
its side.
Yeah.
In my pockets, I carried a map.
Compass, hand grenades, more flares,
Hallo zone tablets, malaria pills,
and a spare magazine for my car.
Being a pistol to clips of ammunition,
knife first aid kit and two
full canteens hung from my belt.
My steel helmet and flak jacket
added 20 pounds to the load.
Okay.
The gear probably weighed
over 40 pounds all together,
but I felt a wonderful
soaring lightness in my limbs.
I felt good all over,
better than I'd felt in months.
Even Neil who is not inclined to hand
out compliments had praised my gung ho
enthusiasm before the platoon left.
Base camp
as sudden and mysterious recovery from
the virus of fear had caused the change
in mood.
I don't know why.
I only knew I had ceased
to be afraid of dying.
It was not a feeling of invincibility.
Indifference rather high.
It ceased to fear death because
I had ceased to care about it.
Certainly I had no illusions
that my death, if it came,
would be a sacrifice.
It would merely be a deaf.
They're not a good one either.
A good death involved a certain
amount of choice, ritual and style.
There were no good deaths in the war,
but the manner of dying
no longer mattered.
I didn't care how death came so long
as it came quickly and painlessly.
I would die as casually as a beetle
is crushed under a boot heel.
And perhaps it was this recognition of
my insect like pettiness that it made me
stop caring.
I was a beetle.
We were all Beatles scratching
for survival in the wilderness.
Those who had lost the struggle
had not changed anything. By dying.
The deaths of Levi Simpson,
Sullivan and the others had
not made any difference.
Thousands of people died
each week in the war,
and the sum of all their deaths
did not make any difference.
The war went on without them
and as it went on without them,
so would it go on without me?
My death would not alter a thing.
Walking down the trail,
I could not remember having
felt an emotion more sublime
or liberating than that
indifference toward my own death.
Again,
a
a common fought pattern is this,
this feeling of, Hey, I'm in hell.
And one thing that trying to set me
free is death. And once I overcome that,
that, that, that just allows me to
go and do what I'm supposed to do.
And I'm just going to fast forward
once again, kind of like a,
with the wheel bird going to the end
where we're Kaputo kind of wraps up his
what he's going to bring home from the
war. And at this point he's, you know,
he's obviously survived the enemy.
He survived actually at this point.
He'd survived a court martial
cause he'd gotten in some trouble.
There were some bad things that
happened while he was in charge.
There was,
you know,
cases against him and he kind of got out
of that situation and now he is heading
home.
Going back to the book,
we stood waiting in the
sun at the edge of the,
there were about 150 of us and we watched
his replacement draft filed off the
big transport plane.
They fell into formation and tried to
ignore the dusty tanned ragged looking men
who jeered them.
The replacements looked strangely young
for our younger than we and Awkward and
bewildered by this scorched land to
which and indifferent government had sent
them.
I did not join in the mockery.
I felt sorry for those children knowing
that they would all grow old in this
land of endless dying.
I pitied them knowing
that out of every 10,
one would die,
two more would be maimed for life on
other two would be less seriously wounded
and sent out to fight again.
And all the rest would be wounded
in other more hidden ways.
The replacements were marched off toward
the convoy that awaited to carry them
to their assigned units
and they're assigned fates.
None of them looked at us.
They marched away
shouldering our sea bags.
We climbed up the ramp into the plane,
the plane we had all dreamed about.
The grand mythological freedom bird.
Uh,
Julia shout went up as the
transport lurched off the
runway and climbed into the
placid sky
blow lay the rice patties and the green
folded hills where we had all lost our
friends and our youth.
The plane banked and headed out over
the China Sea towards Okinawa toward
freedom from death's embrace.
None of us was a hero.
We would not return to cheering crowds,
parades,
and the peeling of great cathedral bells.
We had done nothing more than endure.
We had survived and that
what was our only victory.
Okay.
And I think that is important for us to
remember that in some cases some of the
things that we go through,
some of the things,
some of the challenges and tribulations
and trials that people get put through,
sometimes survival,
his victory.
And all you can do is survive and make
it through a situation that you're in.
And I think sometimes
when people survived something horrible,
instead of being happy or elated
that they made it through,
instead they focus on the fact
that they got put through it. Yeah.
And again, I don't, I'm no
professional at all. And there was no,
there was, there was, you know, even
when I was on Joe Rogan's podcast and,
and we were talking about Chris
Cornell committing suicide,
you know, someone said, you know,
cause we kind of devolved into
a conversation of hey, you know,
get outside and Tim Ferriss, when Tim
Ferriss was on this podcast, you know,
he was saying, you know, get move
and get physical. And so, you know,
Joe and I were just kind of
talking about that and, and,
and someone came on and said, you know,
you don't know what you're talking about.
It's, it's, it's, you're lucky to survive
something like this. It's horrible. And,
and you know, I kind of said, man, I,
I know I am. I'm not saying that. And,
and literally,
I re listened to Joe and I talking in
both of us of what we were saying was over
and over again. I don't understand this.
I don't comprehend it. You, you know,
so I don't think that was the
intention. We're saying, oh,
all you have to do is go get it out of
kettle bell and you'll be good to go.
That's not the intention at all.
And that's not what either one of us,
not only was it not what we were trying
to say. We didn't actually say that.
We were saying, Hey, I don't
understand it. I haven't
been in that position before.
That's why we brought,
that's why I brought Tim on here
because Tim had lived through that and,
and knew how bad it was and planned to
kill himself and so that to me is someone
that can give their opinion.
Joe and I were literally saying,
I don't comprehend.
Yeah,
but I think when you get a guy like the
author of this book or rumor of war,
who's,
who's talking about their,
their victory or his victory and the
people want to play with their victory in
Vietnam will survival was
just getting through it
and I know that's nothing
you're going to be joyous about,
but I think at least recognizing,
okay, I made it through,
now let me move on. Yeah. Is important.
Now again,
I,
I went on this kind of literary tour
that I was launched into after reading
what,
what my buddy wrote because it reminded
me of so many other things that I've
heard and so many other
things that I've read.
And so another great,
you know,
viewpoint comes from Eugene Sledge and
he wrote the book with the old breed,
which is a classic and we covered it,
podcast number 10.
If you want to stop now,
go back and listen to podcast 10
with Eugene sled with Eugene sledge,
with the old breed.
It's just
account of what he went through
in World War II, in the,
in the Pacific theater
with the Marine Corps.
But he wrote another book after that.
And the next book that he
wrote was called China Marine.
And it's talks about what
they did when the war ended.
You know,
and he,
the time he spent sort of pacifying and
any country spent some time in China and
then it talks about what it was like when
he got back to America, back to mobile,
Alabama.
And
it's definitely impactful,
definitely impactful.
So here's what he came to came home too
and then I'm going to pick up where his
dad,
he's talking to his dad and his dad was
a physician during World War One and
that's one of the reasons his dad was,
if you remember Eugene Sledge couldn't
get in the Marine Corps at first because
he had, I think he had a heart
murmur or something like that.
And so they didn't let him in and
his dad was kind of okay with that.
And the reason he was okay with that was
because he had seen what the boys from
World War One had come home like not
only physically but also psychologically.
Guys had
guys had the shell shock,
which is horrible when you see in
her, again, I've said this before,
go on youtube and look at videos
of world war one shell shock. It's,
it's horrifying to look at.
And that's what Eugene
Sledge's father had seen.
And so when his son couldn't go in the
marine corps, he was kind of like, okay,
you know, you, you can
serve in other ways.
And Eugene Sledge wanted to
surf and so Eugene Sledge Guy,
he actually got a waiver and the,
and I guess the heart murmur had faded
enough or they didn't notice it until we
got the Marine Corps. When
he comes back, his dad,
his dad is talking to them and I
think it's a good place to pick up.
His Dad called him Fritz. That was, that
was Eugene Sledge's nickname at home.
So here we go.
Eugene Sledge's dad talking to him Fritz,
he said,
okay,
I know you've been through
an awful experience.
I know that nobody had it worse than
the First Marine Division except maybe
those on Bataan and those
others who were imprisoned.
I'm tremendously proud
of both you and Edward.
You did your duty under terrifying
conditions, but you survived in one piece.
Granted with some terrible memories
you'll have to learn to live with.
Okay,
but take my advice first.
Never become embittered because
many other men had safe,
comfortable war assignments all too often
obtained through political influence.
That's the way of cowards in this world,
okay?
To never feel sorry for yourself
because of what you endured.
On the contrary.
Feel fiercely proud that you served
with the finest and fought against the
fiercest enemy and live to tell the tale
three.
If you ever drink alcohol,
do it in moderation.
Alcohol can be a wonderful escape from
bad memories, but it is addictive,
will make you act the fool
and ultimately ruin you.
To the last remark, I
replied, I know father,
I've seen that happen to
good buddies recalling some
of the worst cases in China.
He replied,
yes,
and I've treated some of the nicest
people who were ruined by the stuff,
but I can't cure them.
They must have willpower.
Okay,
so really straightforward
warning about alcohol.
Check about not feeling bitter towards
people that didn't maybe do more.
Go through what he went through
and be proud of what you did.
Now this is
again just another piece that that
they actually in in the HBO miniseries,
the Pacific, they vague kind of portray
this part of Eugene sledge coming home,
but it's worth reading his
account of it back to the book.
As my life settled down somewhat,
I began to think of my
future rather hastily.
I decided to go to Auburn then called
Alabama Polytechnic Institute and major in
business.
I'll never forget my first day at Auburn,
I was in the registrar's
office in Sanford Hall.
The big room was crowded with long lines.
If entering students standing in front
of tables behind which clerks were
noticing or noting each student's
college credits from service schools
determining which might transfer to
Auburn, there was allowed hub hub,
a voices with about a hundred
people in the room. Some men,
mostly air corps veterans had been to
various technical schools and Auburn gave
them two years credit.
All veterans were excused from
ROTC and physical education.
When I stepped up to the table that the
head of the line pretty Brunette about
my age,
probably a student's wife asked pleasantly
what schools I had attended in the
Marine Corps. I recited all the weapons
and tactics schools we had in training.
She became more and more disconcerted as
she looked in vain on her checklist for
anything remotely resembling
what I was saying. Finally,
in desperation, she slammed her
pencil on the table and said it aloud.
Exasperated voice. Didn't the
Marine Corps teach you anything.
Okay.
A gasp ran through the crowd and
you could've heard a pin drop.
I didn't lose my temper,
but I realized that like
most civilians ward,
this lady meant John Wayne or
the sweet musical South Pacific.
Slowly placing my hands on the table
aware that all eyes were upon us.
I said in a loud,
calm voice lady,
there was a killing war.
The Marine Corps taught me how
to kill jabs and try to survive.
Now, if that don't fit into
any academic course, I'm sorry,
but some of us had to do the killing
and most of my buddies got killed or
wounded.
She was speechless.
There were many red faces among
the obvious noncombatants present.
I doubt if there were half a dozen
interim Friedman or tankers present.
She recovered her composure, looked
me in the eye and said, I'm so sorry.
I apologize.
I didn't understand.
I told her she was very kind and I
did not mean to upset her. You didn't.
She said, you made me think so.
I got credit for ROTC and PE
and the room returned to normal.
Young lady wished me
a long and happy life.
I thanked her and left.
I felt like some sort of an alien and I
realized that this sort of thing would
confront me.
The rest of my days.
The war had been so momentous to me.
I couldn't imagine anyone not sharing
that view or pre or appreciating the hell
I had suffered.
In fact,
I was totally unprepared for how rapidly
most Americans who did not experience
combat would forget about the war,
the evils we faced and how incredibly
tough and had been for us to defeat the
Japanese and the Nazis.
I didn't realize how swiftly
most Americans would once
again take their freedom
for granted.
Okay.
Clearly that applies to
veterans and people that have
been overseas fighting and
you come back and it's like no
one even knows that you were gone.
Yeah. It's like another thing, you know,
you get that passage of time when you go
away for two or three months and you go
back to where you're from and it seems
like, oh, how long have you been gone for?
All three months.
Oh,
it seems like people think you were
gone for a couple of days or a couple of
weeks. Yeah. It happens at the gym. Like
I'll go into the gym and someone who,
Oh, where you been, you know, I think I
haven't seen him in a week. And he says,
oh I, I tore my ACL. I been
gone for eight months. You know,
it's one of those moments. And that
happens with war. Two guys go away,
they come back every time,
just went by.
And that can be frustrating in those
eight months or six months or 14 months at
someone's deployed overseas fighting for
their lives and they come home and that
other person didn't even notice
they were gone. Yeah. I mean,
I feel bad when somebody had an ACL
tear and I didn't know it. You know,
I feel kind of bad and I haven't
seen you for eight months, you know,
if you feel like I feel bad about it.
Okay.
And I'm sure that person is
saying, you know, Jocko gees,
we used to train all the time and you
didn't even realize that I was gone.
You thought I was gone for a week.
Yeah. Right. Yeah, exactly. Well,
imagine how that fuels to a,
a veteran that's coming back
from war and that is, this isn't,
this isn't like some odd case. This is
the norm. That's actually the norm. Yeah.
I mean,
it's different for the direct family
that's waiting for the individual to come
home. Then those six month deployments
or 14 months deployment seemed like an
eternity.
Yeah.
But for that casual person
or that acquaintance that
you don't know that well,
they're thinking, oh, did you?
Where are you? Bend? Yeah. Oh yeah.
I was overseas fighting.
Yeah.
And he's got,
the way he kind of wraps up this book
in his epilogue, and again, you know,
this is another book that we'll probably
explore at some point in detail, but
going to the way that the topics that
he brings up as it closes it out and
reflections on how the war
impacted him psychologically.
Here we go back to the book,
looking back over the momentous events
of 50 years ago when I was a marine,
evoke strong emotions.
The years immediately after
the war were the hardest.
Okay.
As Paul Fussell remarked,
the combat veteran not only
has to survive his experience,
he has to learn to live with
it the rest of his life.
Yeah,
he was so right for the first 20 odd
years after my return nightmares occurred
frequently waking me either crying
or yelling, always sweating,
and with a pounding heart.
Some nights I delayed going to bed
dreading the inevitable nightmares.
Old Comrades wrote me that
similar troubles drove many
of them to drink and to
the ensuing misery of alcoholism,
which they beat with
sheer self discipline.
Okay.
Eventually
the war left me with a deep appreciation
for the simple things in life.
Putting on a clean pair of dry socks
is one of the greatest luxuries.
I know.
A shave,
a warm shower, and sleeping
in a, she did bed or two.
When it is raining,
especially on an autumn,
I look out the window at the falling drops
and my faults sometimes drift back to
those awful days on Okinawa.
Snafu and die bailing out a muddy fox
hole with an old helmet shivering in a
torrential cold grain and both of us
cringing as each Japanese shell came
screaming into the Corp Strewn area
to explode with a deafening crash.
That quickly bring my mind,
the focus of my mind back to the present
and thank God I didn't have to suffer
hardship and misery again
and oh,
what a blessing to be
relieved of constant terror.
My love of the outdoors was
strangely affected by the war.
The way I looked at my
surroundings was altered.
My view of the outdoors and taking a more
analytical perspective of its features
as military terrain, likely areas for
the placement of various foxholes.
The company, 60 millimeter
mortars to cover the full aids,
the light machine guns so as to
achieve crossfires along the company,
front fields of fire and possible
avenues of enemy attack or ambush.
This change in outlook was
intense in the early years home,
but I cleared my mind of it
by concentrating on plant
and animal species present
or probable,
but the old combat view
of things still creeps in.
Sometimes after more than 50 years.
And that's something
that definitely sticks.
Every guy I know that's been overseas,
every guy, every thing we look at,
we see it as some kind of military
terrain in a city. For me,
especially it's in the city, cause I
did most of my combat was urban combat.
And that's what I'm looking at all
the time. Not only on the highway,
on the buildings,
when you're sitting around,
when you're sitting in a hotel
room looking out in the street,
everything that you look at,
you look at from a combat perspective.
Okay,
now he, he, he,
he was a outdoorsman and he goes back,
he gets back from the war
and he's going hunting.
And this is the first time that he's
gone deer hunting after the war.
And he's out hunting
with a group of people,
but he gets dropped off in one spot
by himself. They have a boat by river,
they take a boat, they
drop him off alone. And
here we go. Back to the book to beautiful.
Doe's appeared walking briskly through
the water as they exited the woods and
stopped at the far edge of
the pond about 30 yards away.
They kept looking toward the area of the
drive and moving their ears to capture
every sound possible,
more loud sloshing of water and two doughs
and a large buck came up to the first
dose and stopped.
They finally looked in my direction.
I remain still and since the
wind was blowing toward me,
the deer could not pick up my scent.
They stood motion motionless staring
at me and standing up in that clump of
cane.
They seem more concerned with the
bang of the hounds than with me though
because the way I held my rifle,
I could see my wrist watch,
so I timed the action
or inaction of the deer.
One of the dose picked up an acorn
at the edge of the pond and ate it.
The buck was large and it
had a fine set of antlers.
The eight points gleaming in the light.
Slowly I raised my rifle
and cited in on his chest.
No,
he was to find a creature to kill.
I had murdered one of his kind that
morning, so I did not need the venison.
Slowly,
I lowered my rifle.
Okay.
The buck remained motionless,
motionless.
His instincts probably told him no shape
such as he saw in the cane was natural
dear,
like most mammals have very poor sight
except for detecting motion and are
primarily colorblind.
For 15 minutes,
we stared at each other,
a shot in the air,
which send them springing away into the
woods, but a shot would frighten them,
which I had no desire to do.
The deer seemed more curious than afraid.
They kept sniffing the air,
which apparently bore no sense of danger.
I had on waterproof boots,
but was beginning to get cold.
Finally, I needed to move a little. I knew
that as soon as I did, they would bolt,
so I whistled softly every big year.
Turned quickly in my direction.
I whistled softly again.
All the deer slowly lowered their ears,
turned,
went sloshing onto higher GRE
ground and ambled into the woods.
Looking back at me once or twice.
Okay.
The whole episode is one of
my most cherished memories.
When Jim picked me up in the boat,
he asked if I had seen a deer.
I said, no, not wanting to
tell him I had seen five.
When we returned to camp,
several people asked me what I had seen
and I reported a few squirrels and some
wood ducks.
If I had told those eager at
hunters what had really happened,
they would have elected
to throw me in the river.
Okay.
Gus didn't allow any drinking
during hunting hours.
So after the guns were all unloaded
it and putting their cases,
the bottled spirits were brought
forth and the partiers all had a ball.
Each of the Wari hounds
went to the fenced yard,
jumped up on the raised platforms
and went into the barrel for a nap.
The platform was raised as protection
against high water as well as alligators,
which have a special
appetite for dog flesh.
We crossed the river after a
while and scattered to our homes.
So when did my last year on put the memory
of that beautiful buck and his harem
down the river.
I have wondered how long he survived.
I am not anti hunting as long as
it is managed by wildlife experts.
Most game animals out produce their
food supply and since civilization has
destroyed most of the natural predators,
starvation results,
unless populations are controlled by
game management overseeing proper hunting
practices,
but the terrified eyes of that spike
buck I shot are something I'd like to
forget.
Okay.
I have felt the same terror when being
shot at, so hunting is not for me.
World War Two gave me a convenient
measuring stick for duty,
courage, terror, friendship
patients, horror,
endurance, compassion, discomfort,
grief and pain.
Yeah.
That has remained with me daily.
The English poet Robert Graves said World
War One affected him in much the same
way.
Anyone who has not suffered the
prolonged fear and limitless fatigue,
that was combat.
That was the combat infantry man's lot
might find this difficult to comprehend.
Over 50 years later,
I look back on the war has no what were
some giant killing machine into which we
were thrown to endure fear
to the brink of insanity.
Some fell over the break
and physical fatigue to near collapse.
Those who survived on hurt.
We'll never forget and cannot forget.
The many friends lost in their prime and
the many articles of civilization they
ruthlessly destroyed.
As I look back,
some facts are quite clear.
Japan's sneak bombing of Pearl
Harbor destroyed many American lives,
ships and planes.
We had no choice but to
destroy imperial Japan.
The a bomb ended that war.
It saved millions of American lives by
preventing a murderous invasion of Japan
and the probable of a
suicidal Japanese population.
The Japanese soldier was a bloodthirsty
foe imbued with the code of Bushido.
If we had not defeated an army
that fought, it was unbeatable.
Who knows how many American
cities might've shared the
horrid rape of Nan King.
In looking back, I'm still amazed
I escaped the killing machine.
Why I never fell,
killed or wounded in that storm of
steel thrown at us countless times,
still astonishes me.
I am proud of the number of the enemy I
fired on and hit with my mortar rifle or
Tommy gun and regret the ones I missed.
There is no mellowing for me.
That would be to forgive all the
atrocities that Japanese committed against
millions of Asians and
thousands of Americans
to mellow is to forget
each man who survived.
I am certain was plucked from the
mire of death by the Almighty.
And in this I feel humble and grateful.
Socrates said,
know thyself.
I do.
The war taught me.
Okay,
okay.
The war
is how he closes out
that book.
And
the war taught me as well.
And the war
still
teaches me.
And that's why I read about war
and why I talk about war.
And that's why so much of this
podcast is about war because war
can teach us,
but
it's not only war that teaches us life.
Life
teaches us,
but that's,
that's only if we are humble and open
minded enough and a tentative on enough to
watch,
then listen and learn from it.
Not only from our own paths
and the things we go through,
but from what we see other people do.
It's a teacher.
Life is a teacher and yet,
and you see this all the time,
there are people that
do not learn from life
and they make the same mistakes
over and over and over again.
Just completely unaware
of the lessons that are,
that are smacking them in the face,
smacking them in the face.
And I think that's where you have
to flip the switch in your brain,
that that hardship
that you're facing,
that trial,
that tribulation in bedded in,
that misery
is a lesson
to teacher.
And it's only a lesson if you're willing
to learn from it.
A hand life is a hard teacher,
but
do your best
to listen
and to learn from it.
And I know, speaking of learning,
I last
Facebook live,
got some,
some good questions and I know
it's a little, a rough transition,
but good. Um, you know, just kind of
going through all those different,
different people's books and you can see
what war did to him and you can see the
similarities with all of them that
human beings put in really stressful
situations, human beings putting in
life the have similar outcomes, right?
I mean there's,
there's commonalities in it.
And I think the more we look for those
commonalities in the more individual you,
me,
the more I look for these commonalities
and in different people's experiences,
the better off I'm going to be.
Right?
The more I'm going to be
able to understand what's
happening to the world around
me or to the people around me.
Yeah.
And that's the one thing that I think is
really important as is seeing, you know,
when you start talking about the,
the life lessons hitting you in the face,
it's always hard if you're the person
that's getting hit, that's the, you're,
even though you're the person
that stands to gain the most from,
from understanding what's
going on around you, you're
also love the person that has
the hardest time recognizing it.
It's just like when you're sitting outside
of an MMA match or an Nmf MMA fight,
and you as the coach has the corner men,
you can see what's happening and the
guy that's getting punched in the face a
lot of times they don't
see what's hitting them.
And they don't think of it as a lesson.
They don't,
they're not taking anything
positive away from it.
They're getting punched in the face.
And it's not until someone says, Hey,
the guy's hitting you with a left
hook. You're, you know, you're,
or you're dropping your hands or
whatever so that the person can make a
correction. They're not learning
from it. They're getting hit.
And that's what happens to a lot of us
in life is we're getting punched in the
face, punched in the face, punched
in the face, and we don't recognize,
we can't step back.
We can't detach from being
in that situation where we
can actually assess what's
going on and say, oh, okay, I see
what's going on here. I see what I see,
what changes I've got to make.
That's why the,
and then what happens is this is what
happens. What happens is you say, oh,
Echo, I see you're going through some hard
times. So I go up to you and say, Hey,
echo, this is what you're doing. This is
what you should change. And what happens?
Big Ego flare up from Echo.
You don't know how I feel.
You don't know what's going on.
You don't know what it's like.
You don't know what it feels like
getting punched in the face, bro.
I'm just trying to help you.
You don't get it.
So what we do our in our instinct is to
put up defenses even when somebody is
trying to help us out,
right?
So that means you got to get good
at trying to help people out too,
because we already know that everyone
gets defensive and that everyone's ego
flares up and that when you talk to your
friend that's either a vet coming home
and he's facing problems, or someone
that's having a hard time at work,
or someone who's having a
hard time relationship or
someone that's having a hard
time with whatever addiction has gotten
a hold of them, all of those things,
you got to learn how to,
how to talk to those people in a way
that you're not being offensive to them,
which is hard to do.
Cause we all take offense
whenever somebody tells us
that we're doing something
wrong, we're all offended by
it. We're all offended by it.
Even the most positive, helpful
person. Your own your mom,
right? Your mom comes to tell you
something, you get offended, right?
You're your best friend comes and
says, Hey, you know you, you, you,
you're doing this.
You're going down the wrong path here.
You don't know nothing about my path.
So having that detachment so you can
see it yourself and then having an open
mind when somebody tries to help you
and then when you are trying to help
someone, trying to do it in a way
that you don't attack their ego,
those are some good things to think
about as you're going through life.
Trying to take lessons away from it.
So crazy hood,
apologize again, applies
to everything you know.
It's like when will you ever hear
people say, if I knew then what?
I know now that of course,
right?
The jacked up thing is there's all kinds
of people that know now that tried to
tell you then there's so much,
there's so many places to get
this information. You're saying,
if I knew then what I knew now,
well then guess what? All kinds of
people we're trying to help you.
We're trying to help me.
We're trying to tell me what to do.
I wasn't listening to any of them. My
Ego's too big. I know what I'm doing.
I'm the smartest person in the world.
You don't understand the situation.
It's going to be different for me. My
life has special, my life is different.
You don't get all those things.
All those things that we say.
If we just had an open mind to listen to
what people were trying to tell us or,
or at a minimum have an open mind to
listen to what life was trying to tell us.
It's hard. It's funny because
it's so true. Like how you,
when you're,
when you say,
if I knew then what I
know now and you say it,
we'll back then there was
people yelling at you. Yeah.
Screaming and metaphor thing yet,
right.
They're giving you that knowledge so you
could have known then what you know now
kind of thing. Then you got to
go one step deeper and go, Dang,
well I should've known then to
listen to you guys. You know?
I know to listen to you guys now
kind of thing, man. It's like,
it's almost like this borderline
impossible scenario. It's hard scenario.
There's some things in life,
and this is so unfortunate that
you have to learn only from life.
There's all these stupid things that
people go through and you just, you just,
you watching them go through
it. Yeah. And, and again,
I talk about this story
where you, you, you get,
you get someone that's going
down a downward spiral.
You pick the downward
spiral that they're on,
whether it's their relationship
that they're in is a disaster.
Whether they're getting addicted to
whatever you want to get addicted to,
you know, whether that's
work, whether that's alcohol,
whether that's drugs,
whether that's gambling,
whatever thing you want to be addicted to,
you pick the downward spiral
that you want to jump on.
The person that's on that downward spiral.
It,
they don't see it in everybody that's
outside of the spiral can absolutely
identify it and tell them, and they don't
want to get off. I mean, I know, hey,
addictions are horrible. Right? And
that's why they're called addictions.
And that's why people ride that
downward spiral until it destroys him.
Like Eugene Sledge's dad talked about.
It's like, Hey, it'll ruin you. Yeah.
The only way out is willpower.
The only way out.
And then Eugene says you got to defeat
it with pure self discipline, you know?
Yeah, you can, you can have fun
little games with your mind.
And when they're little
like chess matches,
which with your mind with alcohol,
I know that from experience and um,
I'm winning.
When we first started doing the podcast,
I didn't realize that you drank as
much as you drank at that time. Yeah,
I was like, cause we
were recording. Yeah, we
poured one out. I was like,
what are you doing bro?
I'm like in here to get after it.
And you're,
you're going to have a drink during this.
Yeah.
Well in my slight defense that one
drink wouldn't really affect anything.
And I know this because other people told
me this and I feel this where even if
I'll get hammered, this was back
then you couldn't really tell.
People would be like, oh,
you don't even seem at all.
Meanwhile on the inside I'm like,
but yeah.
And here's another thing, and this
can apply to a lot of people. I think,
not everybody,
but maybe some people where you know
how I was the kind of where I would only
drink at home when I did work. Here's
the thing though, I works bizarre thing.
Yeah.
To The textbook definition of an alcoholic
drinking at home alone while you're
working.
I'm sure it's one of the potential
symptoms but straight but on potential,
when I went to like the bar
or something like hang out,
I didn't really go to the cloud.
I mean after I stopped working
in the club I heard do it, but
you know to go hang out and stuff,
I drink way less.
I wouldn't even really want to drink that
much but at homework and that's when I
would drink.
But like I said,
I work every single night
and for a long time too.
So he was like every night for
like years and years and years.
But the only problem that it would kind
of create where these kind of covert
problems like the next day I wasn't,
is driven to do much.
I'd work out a go train, I do
all the stuff that, you know,
I've been doing for whatever years.
But you know,
like how you learn something new to bring,
you know,
Xyz element of your life to
the next level kind of thing.
It would really get in the way of that.
So, so you're kind of stay in that level,
like three. Yeah. But
here's the thing though,
in certain ways I was learning a lot
because you learn a lot when when I work
and stuff, when I do, you know all
these programs and do video stuff,
you learn a lot while
you do it. So man, I was,
I was learning and getting better and
my stuff. So in a way the problems,
like I said, weren't real obvious. And
then after awhile, like after time goes,
you know what it was what really
brought the problems to late was fucking
hanging with you because you'd
be like, okay, we're here now.
We're going here to this week.
We're on like a whole different thing.
And I'm like, man, I can hardly keep
up with Jocko. So at night I'd be like,
Oh yeah,
I'm keeping up with Jakob and the next
day I'm thinking when you're doing stuff
early in the morning doing stuff during
the day, you're letting me know, okay,
now we've got this. And I'm like, Dang,
I just basically been recovering at
all day because I don't feel that good.
I did a workout as we used to record
the podcast at night, later at night.
And so we'd get done at one
o'clock in the morning and yeah,
I'd have to get after it in the morning
and not have to. Yeah, exactly right.
So it's weird when you do that routine,
you get this weird second.
I think your body just gets
ready to do work and stuff.
You know how you do
something over and over.
Your body just kind of just accommodates
the schedule. So I was like,
at night I'd do fine, but during the
day I wouldn't want to do nothing.
And meanwhile you're, you know, doing
all this stuff. And I was like, man.
And not to mention all the things that
we talked about that I was like, oh,
I got tricked by my brain. [inaudible]
meanwhile at the expense of my whole life.
Aside from those, you
know, for the next for you,
is that because you were kind of the
cause of the problems were covert?
There wasn't any,
I'm assuming that there wasn't any
external people trying to help you and be
like, Hey Echo, you're,
you shouldn't drink at night because you
were still maintaining an unacceptable
standard of humanity. So, and you,
you're taking care of your wife,
you're taking care of your young
daughter and so you're doing what you're
responsible to do, your what your
responsibilities are. We're being handled.
They're just being handled at level
three and level three was okay.
Maybe people thought that was where
you were at. You know, actually,
and this may sound better,
but this is worse.
They were being held at level
essentially level 10 everything.
Like everything I cared
about was being handled.
Everything like to the really high level,
like hanging with the kids,
talking with them. So my wife
would go to bed earlier than me.
So then you'd say of late working,
working, drinking, I could still wake up.
I'd be messy, you know, not,
not that like happy to be awake, but
I wouldn't, that wouldn't, never,
that would never show
dealing with other people.
And then there'd be times where I feel
if I was just too, and really it just,
I just felt tired. That's what it was.
I didn't feel hung over. You know,
this is actually brings up a good point
is that I think a lot of times people
spend,
because they're,
because they're achieving a minimum
standard, or maybe even a medium standard
or a solid standard. In your
case, from your perspective
to me was I was working.
Yeah, you're working, you're
getting your job done. Yeah.
Making, making good care of your
family and doing workouts like hard,
good workouts during the day. But
everything else, I was like, oh my God,
I can't do this.
But I bet there's always,
so basically if you're not looking
at yourself with a critical eye,
you can get by with a lot as a person,
as a human being you.
If you're not looking, if you're not
looking at yourself with a critical eye,
you are going to get you.
You're not going to reach your potential
because you're not going to push
yourself as hard as you possibly
can, which is, you know,
the MMA fighters, when I was trained, a
lot of MMA fighters, I would tell them,
listen, you can train without
a coach and you can train to,
let's say,
let's say you're super disciplined.
You can get to like 84% this
is an interesting dichotomy.
You can get to 84% of your max
output of you're pushing yourself.
A coach is then going to take you to the
next level and he's going to get you to
98% but this is what's interesting.
The last 2% goes back on the individual.
So let's say I'm training
you for Jujitsu tournament.
If you just yourself with
a Jujitsu tournament,
you get to 80 82% of your potential. If
I, cause that means cause you're, you're,
you know, you get to the last round and
you look at your to be a, you know what,
I'm probably, I might get hurt this
round so I'm gonna take it off.
Like you know you're going
to make all those excuses.
You're not going to old
hold the line right now.
If I'm training you now I'm
going, okay. Okay. Okay. You've
got to be here. Get back.
Are you going to do in two more
rounds? Hey, you're done with your,
you can do some burpees and you know I'm
gonna, I'm gonna make you do that stuff.
So that's what a coach does,
but then you take that last,
that's going to get you to 98% but the
last 2% is back to you because I can't
make you do the burpees
as hard as you can.
I can make you do them, but I can't make
you do them as hard as you can. I can,
I can make you do
another round on the mat,
but I can't make you do
it as hard as you can.
I can't make you try moves that I,
that you don't feel like trying.
Yeah.
So it takes a little teamwork
in those situations, you know?
And that's something
I definitely saw with,
with MMA fighters is yeah.
Without a coach,
they're not going to push
themselves hard with a coach.
They'll push themselves harder.
But if you're going to be a champion,
you got to get that last 2% of yourself.
Yeah. And what's crazy is you can,
you can kind of make someone your coach,
even if they don't know it, you know,
how like, um, where, I mean,
I think you'd kind of know that
you're kind of the coach, you know,
as far as cause your coaching,
probably anyone who interacts
with you and in a regular basis,
they're going to kind of at the very least
look at you and know that you wake up
early and get a lot done for, for a
reason, by the way. So they know that.
So it's kind of like, okay,
I can follow suit. You know,
I can take cues from Jocko in
this way and I can approve it.
It doesn't have to be in the
exact things that you're doing,
but just stuff that they do.
So I think if you actively do that,
where, I mean, I'm speaking from a
place of supreme luxury by the way,
in regards to this where,
you know, I'm like,
you're talking about it directly to me
every single week. And I'm like, yes sir.
And I go back and try it, you know,
try my best to apply it to my stuff.
So of course,
but you can do that.
Even if you watch someone on,
I don't know,
online or something or you read it,
you know how people do like blogs
and stuff like that. You know,
if you're like a subscriber to a specific
blog and you really like, you know,
to the way they do things or whatever,
you can,
you can get that same effect
in a smaller way, I think. Um,
but you can get that same content
can definitely, but you just,
you gotta be conscious of it
though and how you say it.
Like you have to have your own self. Like
it's self discipline for sure. But um,
what did you say?
You just said it's self awareness.
Look at yourself with a critical
eye that you got to do that.
And here's the opposite of that.
In my opinion and from what I seen,
the enemy of looking at yourself with a
critical eye is being good at justifying
stuff. Yeah. Especially,
you know how they say smart people are
dangerous in that way because they're
really good at,
because yeah,
rationalizing something in justifying
something is exactly what it is,
is exactly what that says.
It's justifying it.
Are you justified in x, Y,
z? And if you are, you are.
So if you can justify something to
yourself and you're good at it, yes. Okay.
In your mind is literally okay.
It's not a good situation. It's,
it's very dangerous. Yes. He's
a very dangerous critical,
I've got just the critical, let
me write, call yourself out.
Yeah.
If you want to reach your maximum
potential and move from level three to at
least level eight man.
So what I was saying is that got some
pretty good little rapid fire questions.
You know,
I didn't want to take a bunch of time
on them but I just want to at least
address some of the questions that
came on the Facebook he live. Sure.
I've got a stack of questions that have
been coming in on Facebook and Twitter
and those two primarily is worth the
big questions come into and I've got a
stack of those that we'll get around
to in a Q and a at some point.
And also a lot of questions that get
asked right now heard them before.
So if you have a question,
if you haven't listened to the podcast
at this point you might want us to just
go back and listen to the other contrast
because the question that you have
about how many hours I sleep at night
and what time I go to bed and you know
those kinds of things, they're
there in the podcast and you don't,
I'm not going to talk about
them too much anymore.
You can have like you're
watching jeopardy.
There would have been something cool about
stopping the podcast at number 25 and
said that's it.
That's all you get.
And just cause we addressed a bunch of
stuff and then just let it marinate for a
while. That would be season one. You know
how they do that and been a good idea.
Yeah.
We should have done that.
We should have done season one and
then paused and let people really have
marinated that first season and
then season two comes and see.
I like that. You wouldn't,
you wouldn't never let that
happen. That's what I think.
Well it depends cause it
strategically it's a good idea.
It's a strategically good idea.
Yeah,
I think it is because also you're going
to let that stuff marinate and then
you're going to get good feedback on a
bulk of work that people can then say,
hey, this was a good area of
topics that you discussed.
Please readdress and hit the
following concerns. Right, right.
And so we could attack those, those
concerns in such a manner. Yeah.
I guess that's one way here,
limit, I think this is,
I'm speaking selfishly here,
but I think this is a big deal
where even if you repeat yourself,
even if you answer the same question,
literally the same questions over
and over again, it's like, you know,
when you go to school or college or
whatever and you get a review every week.
I think that, yeah, it is. And you just
choose. The best example for me is,
do I ever, I never absorb a
move in the first try. Yeah.
You gotta give you gotta
teach 12 different times.
I learn one 12th of it each
time and then 12 times later,
I know the whole move. Perfect analogy. If
you Jacqueline's telling echo, yeah. Hey,
don't complain, like don't
complain, problem-solve, don't,
who cares about how you feel care
about the objective kind of thing.
And you told me that one time,
even two times I'd be like, cool,
that sounds dope man. I need to do
that. And then next week, next month,
six months later. Do you
think that sticking with me,
maybe it resonated with me,
maybe not, but no. Yeah,
if you're saying it every week to the
point where it's like I don't even hear
your words. I just know it as
the concept is just in there.
That's when like when I hear
people complaining that's
a big red flag violation
just sticks out like a sore thumb
will receive someone blaming someone.
That's the reason it sticks out because,
so back to this idea of
having different seasons.
If it was season one, people would,
the recommendation was there,
go back and listen to them all again.
So you'd get reiterated on the
exact points. It's good in theory,
but it doesn't work I think. I
don't know. That's a toughie.
I don't know where to get a hundred
and then we do that season one.
Season one is two straight
years of podcasts. Yeah,
that could work because you know how cause
this is the concepts then we take one
week off. No, we start season two week.
I Dunno. Anyway, I have to, I like the
way you've been doing it to be honest.
It's my input one guy.
This is my input.
Well you do have 50% of the
vote here apparently. Oh,
all right. Well let's get these
questions. Yeah. Like I said,
these are quick questions. Yeah.
These are like, yeah, I like them. No.
Okay. First question,
I'm going to read these,
just how they're listed and then we'll
go swimming and or running for Bjj
conditioning. Question Mark. Yes. Swimming
and running are good for conditioning.
I would recommend that you use sprints
slash interval training for both and I
think that's going to get you
where you want to be. Also.
It's good to have that good base cardio,
so that's good too.
Uh, but yeah, they're both good.
The best conditioning for Jujitsu,
Jujitsu. Mm. The, the, the,
the shortfall of that is that
you can sometimes push you,
you've never mind.
Sometimes you can push yourself harder
in with burpees or with some kind of
metcon or, or swimming or running,
you know, he could do sprints,
you should be breathing, you should
be able to make, breathe harder
doing sprints.
Then you can doing the rounds
of Jujitsu for conditioning.
Yeah. Now the rounds of conditioning
in Jiu Jitsu are more important,
but if you want to push herself extra
hard, you got to do something else.
So swimming and running for
digits or conditioning guests,
they're good use sprints.
Yeah. And I agree. I've seen
as far as did you do that?
I just learned this and I watched it. It
was on a Marcello Garcia video randomly.
I don't know where he was like,
okay,
I don't do any other external exercise
for conditioning, whatever. For Jujitsu.
I used you do.
So that's conditioning,
but I don't just do
regular did you to this is,
I do in any demonstrated it and he was
going against a, he's obviously a high,
high,
the highest level black belt.
So he grabs the guy and the guy is a
blue belt I think, and he's like, okay,
this is how you do it for conditioning
is the goal. We're going to fight.
We're going to roll for whatever, however
many, however many minutes they go.
And he's like, boom, boom, boom. He's got
one move next. Boom. He's just going all,
he's not even finishing moves. He's
going to the next one. Then he'll finish.
Then they start again and he's going,
you could tell he's going hard.
He's essentially going as hard as
he would if he had only 30 seconds,
45 seconds left on a high
level competence. That's how
hard and fast he's going.
And um, he was like, okay. And he
explains, you just, you're just,
your focus is going from move to move as
fast and as hard as you can and you're
breathing and all this stuff.
And he goes,
that's how you get conditioned with
Jujitsu. And I was like, Dang man, that's,
that's good. Because think about it,
just like how you said when you hit,
let's say you have six rounds to
go into regular Jujitsu training.
Six it's so easy.
You're just focusing on doing your
Jujitsu and with Jujitsu is energy
conservation, like all of these things
that are anti conditioning release.
They are so you can, you
know, get into good spots.
Let me show you one step even more
granularly. If you take six rounds,
the last 30 seconds of each round it's,
and I talked to Taylor and to Andy
about this and I said, hey guys,
when we get to the last 30 seconds, there
should be no cruising allowed at all.
You should be going for the finish and
you should be going for the finish.
Like if you've got 30 seconds left,
go for the finish.
If you've got 30 seconds after you're
in a bad position, go for the escape.
As hard as you can burn yourself out.
Yeah,
that's a huge difference between
how you can just go into, I'm,
I'm guilty as charged
because like you said,
part of Jujitsu is energy conservation.
So for me,
I'm really good at conserving energy.
Yeah.
You can be cross side mounted on me
and you're, you're not going to make,
and I know, I know. Yeah.
I'll be arrogant right now.
If you mounted me or you've
got across the side on me and,
and we had one minute left, you cannot
submit me. You know what I mean?
Like you cannot submit me. I'm really
good. I've had dean lister, you know,
mounted an onside control
for the last 22 years.
Yeah. Right. So I
can defend myself. Well, so
if you have one minute now,
if I give you five minutes that that story
might be double. You have one minute.
That's how much time is left.
So I can completely go into cruise
mode and that's the wrong answer.
If you're going to try and get Neef,
you're,
if you're trying to survive for some
reason, okay, well then yeah, utilize the,
the conservation skills.
But if you're trying to get some
conditioning work and prepare yourself for
aggressive tournament style situations,
you best put out and that's
why it kind of, in a way,
going back to what you said about having
a coach is where the coach will be like,
Hey,
shark tank,
you don't know something like this where
they kind of avoid your capability or
they they,
yeah,
they avoid your capability to treat
Jujitsu as just regular Jujitsu and the
energy conservation,
efficiency, all this stuff.
You know that that's when
a lot of people ask me,
what should I do for my first tournament
is in three days, what should I do?
What should, what should I look out for?
And what I tell people is that, okay,
the person that you would go against
an a Jujitsu tournament is going to go
harder against you than anyone has
gone against you in the gym period.
And the story,
it is a whole nother
level of competition that,
you know,
white belt versus white belt.
The first time you go in a
tournament as a white belt,
the person you're going on against is
going harder than anyone has gone against
you in the gym period. Yeah. You can't,
even when we would have MMA
fighters fighting in the UFC,
it's near impossible to get,
get to get the training partners
to go as hard against that guy as,
as their opponent is going to
go. Yeah. It just, it does not,
there's no legitimate fire.
Now occasionally, you know,
you get guys that are really good
training partners and they'll push you.
But that's why we do shark tank. Yeah.
Because it's hard for me to get, you know,
four guys lined up to roll with you and
everybody's going to go as hard as they
possibly can. Yeah. Everyone's going
to match what you match a little bit.
They're going to use what they have
to use and that's so true, man.
I watch out for, there's a bunch
of those elements in there when,
when you're in a training scenario,
cause you don't have the,
you don't have that background hum of
this means everything like a competition,
you know? So, yeah,
I actually know who does go super hard
is people that have never trained Jujitsu
for first time in the gym.
It's not a competition,
but that's the person feels
like a competition to them.
So true. So true. I mean,
I've been on the weird how crazy it is
that you just take a guy that completely
believes that they can kick everyone's
ass if you bring them the Jujitsu gym and
they'd just get destroyed. Yeah.
Isn't that crazy? It's crazy.
You just use a crazy thing.
It's an ego checker.
That's kind of what else thinking.
And the same thing with kind of MMA.
I think Jujitsu and MMA, you know, kind
of the same deal where it's kind of real,
you know, um, where, you know,
you're talking about, you know,
veterans come home and they come to
everyday life and you people have no idea
really what extreme stuff is,
you know, and these
people aren't, you know,
they're walking around just not knowing.
Meanwhile what they've been,
what they've been through
is just so extreme.
And they come back and they know
they have that basis for comparison.
And you know, you get the steacher
who's like [inaudible], you know,
mouthy and off to the guy I
remember and he goes, did it,
didn't war teach you anything? All
kind of thing. And they don't know.
They don't know nothing.
You know, give them one day,
give that teacher one day with, you
know, it's just a big eyeopener.
So that's Kinda how I feel with
like Jujitsu and MMA and stuff.
And when you go out and when you hear
people talking, you know, like, oh,
I just thought I kicked that guy's ass,
you know, kind of thing. And you're like,
oh my Gosh, God give you go
to the gym one day with two,
two rounds on a normal day,
three rounds because one round
people think you got lucky.
And I know that's the three rounds I
go, well that might've been locked, but,
and then after you submit someone
three times, they're like, okay,
that there's something I don't understand
here and I want to learn it and keep
them one 10 minute round, Oh
God. And watch them just be like,
this die can't do this. I
can't, like it's to the point,
especially early on you get a
10 minute round and you know,
cause when you're going
against someone there's,
that you're locked into a
normal person isn't going to,
they're going to be destroyed after cause
they're going to be in a competition,
white belt mode going as hard as they can.
Again,
someone that's not using any strength or
energy at all who's destroying them and
submitting them every 30
seconds. Man. Jujitsu. All right.
But yeah, the run it what I looked did
like about running like, you know, three,
four miles. Um, it, what I found
that that provided was um, you know,
when you don't want,
we'll do take,
take down battles and no
one's getting each other.
I felt that it really kept me going,
like just being on your feet,
doing low intensity pushing
and I really felt that,
that it helped that agree.
Check. Next question.
What advice can you give on pushups
and bench press for shoulder and peck
injuries. Slash. Recovery. Okay.
Real quick for for all,
for all injuries.
What I say is do what you can and do
what you can without hurting yourself.
So for instance, if you can't do a full
pushup cause it hurts your shoulder,
guess what?
The whole do a quarter pushup and do a
bunch of them and just get that range of
motion. You're not going to get a full
workout, but to get that range of motion,
get it working,
and then maybe in a week you can do half
pushup and then you do half pushups and
then another three weeks you can do a
three quarter pushup and then eventually
you can do a full pushup and then you
started doing your deep pushups in between
rings or whatever and you you get it back.
That's what I do.
I do that with every body part that I
have that might be injured for whatever
reason. I do what I can.
Yeah, I do what I can.
And specifically I'll
tell you what bench press.
I would use dumbbells and not barbell
because barbell locks your arm into
position and this is very similar
to an Americana or a camera eat.
Both of those submission
moves in Jujitsu are based on the same
kind of general range of motion as a
bench press there.
There's definitely something
different about it and obviously it's,
you can do bench press. I mean
people bench press, you know,
hundreds and hundreds of pounds
on a barbell. So it can be done.
But essentially it is,
is a similar motion if you're
like with an Americana,
which is a submission hold in Jujitsu.
If you can move where your wrist is, you
can, it doesn't hurt at all. You know,
if you put your wrist up by your head,
it doesn't hurt.
All that can person can do in
America on all you all day.
Once you bring it down
and now it's submits you.
And that's the way I look at a barbell
and that's why I haven't done barbell
bench press and I don't even know how
long, especially like, uh, going for Max.
I haven't done that. I don't even
remember the last time I did it. But yeah,
for any of these injuries that you
might have, do what you can use minimum,
you use the, use the range
of motion as you can. Don't
reinjure yourself, you know,
don't be, don't be stupid,
but if it hurts your knee,
when you get to a half a squad, do
a quarter squat or little, you know,
do a, uh, a three eighths squad. Yeah.
So that's what I recommend to
get through those. Yeah. And it,
it's, um, that's kind of the
thing. And I know this from,
and I had knee surgery and I had a
quick recovery, quick recovery. And
the reason that was was because
a, you gotta be smart, just like,
are you saying good to be smart
about your, don't I had knee surgery,
I'm not going to go max squat,
you know, four weeks later,
then it'll kind of thing. So yeah, you
take it slow, but at the same time you go,
you treat it like a workout.
Yeah, exactly. Right.
So Pete at some people was, I forget when
I saw, I don't know if I said on here,
but, um, where people would get
a shoulder injury for example,
and part of the Rehab is like the
stabilization for your core and they'll be
like, oh, I'm not gonna,
I'm gonna skip that day because I
don't feel anything that's ab muscles.
Why would I do that? I have a shoulder
injury, so I'm gonna skip that.
And you know, the next day I'll
do my little shoulder exercises,
I'll go through the motions in.
That's it.
But if you treat it like a for real
workout, like where you stretch it,
you kind of push yourself not in weight,
but you know,
you do do them all range of motion,
all that stuff.
Every element of your rehab has
to be real important to you,
including the consistency.
And if you do it that way,
that'll be how don't to me,
and I don't know,
I don't know that the history of the,
this question or nothing but um,
bench press for shoulder injuries
and recovery. Not that they are, no.
Yeah, they don't, that's not a
hand in hand thing like, so if you,
if you're concerned about whether you
know whether or not to get your bench back
up after you have a shoulder
injury. Okay. But they still,
the bench has nothing to do with
recovery from the shoulder injury,
which you do is all the little
staves stabilization muscles in
there, like these weird
motions and stuff like that.
Because a lot of times that's where
it, you know, and it's another good,
another good compliment to, this is
why I had a shoulder injury and it,
it hurt really bad to do regular pushups,
but I could do ring pushups because it
allows you to move away from those range
immersions that hurt you. So that's
good. But yeah, bench press for shoulder,
not good.
I had a guy,
a new guy officer in Ramadi who had showed
up during deployment and he had a bad
shoulder for something and
he's like, Hey sir, I was,
I was wondering if you can me any good,
you know, exercises I could do for a,
for my shoulder, which I have, you know,
a bad shoulder. And I was like, yeah,
do muscle ups.
And he kind of looked at me a little
strange and then later realized that I was
having fun. It ends in
jail. That's a joke.
He luckily he didn't like heed my
advice at the time. He just thought,
wow this guy is insane
so I can do rotators.
Any rotator stuff like this,
you know like throwing ball
motion just controlled in it.
That's been to get you back so you
can recover, you can recover from it.
And that's the thing.
And again you just treat those rehab cause
there's nothing glamorous about this.
That throwing motion exited like
a rotator cuff exercises helix.
Exactly right.
I'm not doing that.
I'm benching as the,
you know,
I'm doing some press deal but if you
do breast sarge like demonstrating.
So I had a kind of a shoulder like
from the day before and starts,
it was like Dang,
you know,
sarge demonstrates kind of heavy handedly
and he ripped my shoulder and it,
I felt it pop out. So now I can't
lift anything above my head.
So all I did was that rotator cuff.
It's like a program.
It's like this way front
back and then down here,
this one anyway did that and it was only
for like two weeks and it was just bad.
Unfortunately sergeant
moved to Connecticut because
he's one of my favorite
training partners.
Yeah.
So he gives you an
accurate and when he gets,
when he's like his goto cause he
wrestled and he's got a sick double,
he would just get in this double leg
mode and he'd get up or something.
Like we'd be scrambling, he'd get
up and I'd see the look on his face.
Here it comes,
here it comes and he blasts that
double that so hard launch me.
I remember one time I rolled with him and,
and um,
I think you may have like seen part of
it if something and you were like, oh,
how was it rolling? We
started, I was like, yeah,
you know how you kind of explain how the
role went or whatever. And I was like,
yeah man. And then he, he got, he turned
on this Modi, you were like, oh yeah,
he sergeant out on the funniest.
Did you ever see him do that?
A slingshot?
So he used to have this defense from uh,
from getting triangled and he would
just, I, I can't really explain it,
but he would basically launch the
other human being across the mat.
And it was awesome. Whenever I'd see
somebody to lock up and he didn't care,
like they put a triangle
on him and he just, he'd go
into, he'd do the sling shot.
You just laugh at it because he knows
he's getting ready to launch somebody.
So Chet got a school in Connecticut,
by the way,
if you're in Connecticut you can go train
there. What is it? What's it called?
I didn't know that. It's called Jujitsu
life. That's what it's called. Okay,
there you go.
Yeah,
one of my old teammates and one of my
longtime training partners to get some
with next, next question.
Do you prep your own food
daily or eat on the hook
and grab what you can? I
do both. If I, if you know,
I generally don't pack up something
and make a little meal cause I'm my,
my travels all weird and random.
But
yeah.
So when I can I and, and I'm at
home so I make something up. Yeah.
But I eat out a decent amount.
I got my go tos
and I go eat there. Sometimes
they make good food for me. Yeah.
If you're on the program,
like back in the treme. Yeah,
when I was at the seams
I bring lunch for sure.
But it was never a lunch cause I never
ate lunch, never ate lunch, never. Never.
It was like,
okay guys,
I'm going to go leave me alone for the
next hour cause I'm gonna go eat lunch.
No, never ate lunch. Never. You'll
never see me saying, hey guys, okay,
let's call it for now and we'll go eat
lunch and we'll meet you back here in an
hour. No, not have, you know, don't eat
lunch, work through lunch and stay late.
And then so when do you eat then?
Just eat,
eat and be on the phone.
I can eat and be at the computer.
I can eat and you know,
unless we're doing something physical
and even then eat while you're doing
something physical, it's as long as
you're not reading on called met con
you missed this one.
What would you recommend for striking
training as an effective real application
practice?
Boxing. Muay Thai. Okay. That's real easy.
Start with boxing because
it's easier to learn.
You don't have to throw big kicks, but
it's very effective martial art, boxing.
And then once you get decent at
that u s Dow, you can go into Moy,
Tai and learn how to use your legs, your
elbows, your knees, your head. So they're,
yeah, agreed. The boxing
too, and this is strange,
but it's absolutely true is if you,
if you don't have experienced throwing
punches and landing punches, it's,
it's surprisingly hard to punch
someone's face and landed at effectively.
You know how like,
um,
like on the movies, you know, you see him,
he still watching macgyver a lot.
So guys,
I used to punch people and
then he'd always shake his
hand like, oh yeah, like, oh,
I hurt my head every. That was
kind of one of the funniest thing.
It was funny. I'm sure I'm a guy,
we're there trying to make like,
oh MacGyver's such a softie in that way.
Such a those hardcore,
he's hardcore like his brain. Like
he's super smart. He doesn't care.
He had gone, you know he's not that guy
who has a paperclip. He has a brain. Yeah,
exactly. Right. Paperclip, we
Harvard. I mean I have. Nonetheless.
That's kind of what that was indicating,
but I thought it taught kind of a
good lesson where if you, you know,
you watch on TV guys, just punching
guys in the face and the head,
but you can, if especially if you
don't have experience punching,
you can probably will break your hand
or hurt your hand. At the very least.
If you go train boxing, even just once
a week, little some boxing or whatever,
you really get to learn like, okay,
if I'd start throwing these punches,
the difference, crazy. Jujitsu,
like six months of Jujitsu
destroys someone with no Jujitsu,
six months of boxing does pretty damn
good against someone with no boxing for
sure. Yeah. Yeah. The only thing with
boxing and like striking, you can kind of,
not really, I mean people are going
to get mad at even saying this,
but I don't mean this like
straight up literally.
But in the streets you can have
kind of some training, you know,
like if you get an a bunch
of street fights all the
time and punch people in the
face, you learn. Yeah, exactly right.
You learn what you learn actually mostly
from being a legit street fighter is
you learn the mindset. Yeah. As stupid as
that sounds. But here's what you learn. I,
if I punch this guy as fast as I can
before he's expecting it and I'm a soccer
punch, I'm, you'll become a good street
fighter. That's, that's what street is.
Street fighting. A lot is
done on aggression, you know,
and if you get in my face and I
punch you in the face, you know,
if you look at me and say, what's
your prompt? Boom. And I hit you.
That's what I'll re like a good experience
street fighter that kicks a lot of
people's asses. That's what they
do. They are over aggressive.
They don't care about getting in a fight,
they're not thinking about it.
They're fighting. And so when you say,
Hey, what's your Prac? Right, right.
Or the guy says, Hey, what do you look
crack? That's uh, that's what, uh,
that's what a street fighter it is.
They're going to take action very quickly.
That's so you can learn a lot from that.
So when you take that and someone,
you know, when someone shows up at the
MMA gym and they says, well, you know,
I got a lot of street fights and if there,
that's most of the time that's bullshit.
But if it's not,
and they're actually a guy that's been
in a lot of fights and it's only so
helpful because now they've got someone
that they're going to shake hands or
with and then engage in combat.
So they've lost the what and I'm not
saying it's a not a real thing. You know,
some of my friends growing up were really
good street fighters and this is how
I'm saying this with kind of a little
bit of knowledge is my friends that were
really good street fighters,
what was made them good street fighters
wasn't that they studied boxing wasn't
that they studied you did too.
It was because they had a very aggressive
mindset and so someone would say, Hey,
what's your cracked? And they were
going ballistic. Right, right. You know,
or someone's, someone says, what
do you look at Prac and that's it.
And it wasn't actually, it wasn't crack.
It was crack, crack, crack, crack, crack,
crack, crack, crack, crack, crack, crack,
crack, crack, runaway or, or you know,
that's so yes,
that's what a street fighter house.
They have a mindset of the day.
I've been in fights before,
but they know that the aggression
will take them a long way.
It's kind of like a guy in let's
say basketball, who, you know,
he has a home court or something and
need to shoot a lot of shots. You know,
like he knows he knows
how to make those shots.
But then now you put them
on the basketball court.
He has military training with
dribbling or McKeany things.
Yes. Yes. That is true. That is true.
You, you can learn the mechanics. Yeah,
and then your own on your own.
You can learn the mechanics,
but the mechanics and then you could
end the mechanics are going to be almost
less helpful.
Yeah.
That's what I'm going
actually understanding the
mindset of what's going to
happen in a fight. Now the mechanics
will be more helpful in basketball,
but it's not.
Once you get in a real game.
The first basketball game I ever played,
I had,
I knew the mechanics and I got destroyed.
Every past I threw for the
first 10 passes I threw,
got picked off and the guys going down
the other end of the court and scored.
I'm not even kidding. That happened. My
Dad was like a Hoosiers kind kinda guide.
You see the movie Hoosiers exactly eight
you're going to work the mechanics.
We're going to work. Paul handling, you're
going to work, passing, not shooting. No,
no sparring or what is it
called? Scrimmaging. Right.
You just got to learn the mechanics
and then that would have been cool if I
would have had a coach that
had a different mindset,
but the coach had the same.
Who's your mindset is? My Dad, which
is mechanics, mechanics, mechanics.
So I worked on all these mechanics.
I had really good ball handling,
a good passing,
and then I got,
it was the first game I played in
basketball. I had never actually,
it was all maybe I done
a couple live games,
but I had never played against anyone
skilled dribbled down the court May.
I was a point guard dribble down the
court, held up my fingers about, okay,
we're going to run play number three went
over to the side through the ball and
the dude just picked it off and the kid
that I was playing against was a really
good player. Then the other guy that
was guarding me, he just destroyed me.
And the reason was didn't have
the experience of live games.
Now I actually brought that mentality
when I was running training. I always,
you know, you can sit there and
learn mechanics and the kill house.
So you can sit there and learn the
mechanics of doing immediate action drills
out in the field. The mechanics
are good. You have to know him,
but you have to also be live.
And that's why I loved and when they,
when the seal teams,
when we went from just having
live rounds and paper targets,
which everyone was, that was
like the highest form. Hey,
we try and we train with live fire.
That's the best thing.
And that's what I was raised to believe.
As soon as I saw we had simunition
and then once I realized how effective
simunition journals, I was like,
you don't even need simulation.
You can go run around literally
saying Bang, Bang at each other,
but you've got people moving
and it's going to help you.
So that that mindset came from
trying to not be just be Hoosiers.
You know Hoosiers that the movie
Hoosiers the basketball movie.
It's an awesome movie.
But the beginning is all just drilling.
And my dad, cause I didn't
play basketball, I was a
dental and play basketball.
He said, okay, so he's teaching me how
to play basketball. But he was like, Oh,
who's your guy?
You're going to be good defense are
going to be good at ball handling.
And then unfortunately my
coach was the same way.
My first coach was the same way. Seventh
grade or eighth grade, just like,
hey Hoosiers, we'd have good defense.
And I dribbled down the court got,
there'll be careful with that.
But someone that played street ball,
someone that played street
ball. Yeah. And, and,
and didn't no one ever taught in
ballhandling no one ever taught them that
theory behind a zone defense.
Yeah.
That guy would have done infinitely
better than I did in my first basket
ballgame.
Yeah. My Dad must've been hanging
as well. Shame you must have been,
what a loser.
How did I raise this kid?
Well it's the same. Same
kind of thing. Yeah.
Those street fighters, they know
how it feels to like land a punch.
They know they have this kind
of intuitive gauge on, you know,
kind of distance in a way. You know,
just cause they've been there. Yeah.
And so that's why when you train people
for anything, even in the business world,
like don't just train the
people the mechanics of of
a conversation that they're
supposed to have. If they're leader,
just don't train them on the mechanics.
Here's what you say. Read this script. No,
put them live. Fire them in there. Yeah.
What am live firing?
Just role play with them.
Having to sit with you while
you're going through something.
Have him go in there and talk to somebody
that you told them how to act and act
all crazy. You do that. Do that with them.
Yeah. Check, check. Do you take creatine?
I do not tick routine.
I have taken crew team. I believe it
isn't. It isn't effective supplement.
When are you remember Fos Virginia?
When that came out,
that was the first Korean team supplement.
I was drinking so much
that it was vanilla.
It was disgusting and I was on the,
I was on a ship at the time with a seal
platoon and we were all trying to get as
big as possible.
We are all taking creatine.
I was drinking so much fos for gain
that I had to hold my nose and do it,
you know,
hold my name is and do it like a shot
made me wanna throw up a weight gainer
gain. Yeah. Yeah.
Well whichever one I was on foster for
gain and it was only a vanilla flavor,
which I don't even like vanilla flavor
that there, there is a mistake. No,
that was all of the Alfred at the time
when it first came out because we were
all in the game. But yeah,
creatine is, it is effective.
I've never really had
any of those big, uh, uh,
side effects where people say
you get dehydrated or whatever.
Literally had that bloated.
I never really felt much of that,
but I don't take routine right now.
Get it for a long time. Me Neither.
And I don't actually, I never did.
Maybe not.
I took this thing called Beta Gin.
I think there's create teeny in that.
It was like long time ago
and he was too good, I think.
I Dunno. But yeah, I don't
know much about it. Um,
as far as what's true and what's not
and I hear great things and I hear junk
things. Welcome to the Inter webs. Yeah.
Next. Do you ever, it's a,
you ever surf in Europe?
I have not served in Europe.
I would like to start from Europe.
I know that you boys up in
Ireland got some big slabs,
so maybe at some point I'll get up
and surf up there. It looks awesome.
It's very inconsistent though and
very crazy with the title differences.
So at some point it would be cool.
He was surfing in Hawaii.
I have, I have. Yes. You ever been
Nikolai before? No. All right.
December. Think about
it. No question check.
I have a bad back and I need
to lose a hundred pounds.
Any advice on what exercises to
start with to kickstart things?
You know,
you have a bad back and you need to take
care of that and I have no idea what
that means.
That could mean so many different things.
What you need to do is you need
to probably fit you, you know,
started figuring out what you can do.
You probably want to go see your doctor
and say, Hey, what can I can not,
what can I do and what can I not do?
And then doctors sometimes are overly
cautious, so maybe get a second opinion,
see what can get away with.
But the bottom line is if you've
got a hundred pounds to lose,
here's what you need to do.
Start moving some way somehow.
Whether that starts off as walking,
where that starts off as
doing some calisthenics,
whether it starts off as riding an
exercise bike, you need to start moving.
That's what you need to do.
And then you need to fix the Diet because
that's where most of that weight loss
is going to come from. And that's
the best ways to kickstart things.
Agree.
Yes.
And you know how
good the Diet thing real quick
that you don't like certain things.
You go into certain situations and you're
hit with feelings or certain things
that you weren't expecting and
you're like, Dang, I reject feelings.
But you know, then you'll
fall into certain pitfalls
because you're like, Dang,
I didn't really expect it to be like this.
You know?
And maybe if you went in there expecting
certain things or understanding that
certain things are going to come about,
you have more will. So the Diet thing,
when you change your diet,
if your diet,
let's say your typical diet is poor
mean typically that's going to mean it
tastes good in some way.
Whether it be you know,
fast food or just whatever's chief.
Good. Yeah, yeah, exactly right.
So it tastes good and food that tastes
good to have a certain chemical reaction
in your brain and they play,
they go hand in hand, pleasure,
pleasure. So when you, um,
when you refine your diet,
typically that means it's going to be
less sugar. You know, sometimes less fat.
It depends on what kind of diet and
you know, you go on. But if it's,
if it's a better diet compared to
your junk food diet based on taste and
pleasures, tasty, less tasty. Exactly
right. So it's one thing to be like, okay,
it doesn't taste as good and I
can handle that. That's cool.
But the chemical reaction in your brain
is basically going to be telling you
like you need pleasure.
You are being deprived of pleasure
and you're going to be like that.
No, they're telling you, your brain
is telling you it's not just pleasure,
it's sustenance. It's survival
exam, not just you want,
I need that donut.
Yeah.
That was the standard and we got to get
rid of that and people call it cravings.
That's your craving. But it's one
thing to be like, okay, craving.
I can overcome that for a lot of
people. But it's, it's a weird feeling.
It goes beyond just that
you want to know a good
way to kick things off.
Go on a fast man going on a 24 hour
fast because I'll tell you what the best
thing about on a fast in my opinion,
is how it recalibrates your,
your it recalibrates two things.
Your actual feeling of hunger and it
recalibrates your taste buds to yeah,
because when you're eating this
beautiful stuff all the time
and you just, it just need more of
it. Whereas once you go on a fast,
when you have a glass of water,
it tastes good.
Yacama stay so good when you,
and then when you break the fast and
you have whatever you're going to have,
whatever your first meal is,
it takes really good and it's very
satisfying because you haven't eaten
anything. Yeah. Your
needs. Yeah, your needs.
So that's one of the best things I
found about fasting is that recalibrates
those, those two things, hunger and
taste and things start to taste better.
It's like, have you ever, did
you drink coca cola? Right?
So you're used to that sweet, sweet,
sweet thing every once in a while for me,
because I don't drink it.
If I tasted it,
it tastes over the top
sweet over the top and be.
That's because I've fasted from having
Coca-Cola's for so long that it just is a
taste that I don't even like anymore.
But there's a middle ground where, hey,
you can have, and you go, wow,
this tastes incredibly good,
but I don't need a ton of it because
I got the satisfaction of the taste.
So yeah, that's another good way
to kick things off. Go on a fast,
I want a 24 hour fast.
You don't need food.
Like I told him when my daughter was
going through her last wrestling season,
she was telling me, she says, you
know dad, I was, I was thinking,
oh cause he's fasting or not fasting.
She's cutting. Wait, nevermind fast.
And she'd gotten weight and
her thing was like, you know,
if a person can live for 30 days
without food, I can make it til post.
Wayans yeah,
you're not starving.
You're cutting weight as big.
Tony Btf Tony used to say like,
you're not going to die. Oh,
you're going to die. Oh No,
no.
So calm.
I talked to Tony the other day on the
phone. There was all fired up. We were,
we were laughing really hard and die.
I was telling,
I was telling a story and he was laughing
so hysterically that it was hard to
understand. So yeah, Tony. Yeah.
That was his thing. Well,
you're not going to,
you're not going to just die if
you don't have anything right now.
Just stops. He, man, that's, that's so
much about what you feel like eating.
Just picture Tony. Yeah. Just
picture BTF Tony sitting there going,
you're not going to die if you don't have
that sort of the tall mu just this be
tougher, wrong with you. Man.
That's such a good, I mean,
it's real funny when he says it,
you know,
it makes you feel like really the real
posts, but he's, he's kind of right.
You know? It's like you're like, oh
my, I'm just, I've been just gravy,
you know? Oh, what do you mean? How
embarrassing is that? Imagine this.
Imagine if you had to announce your
stupid pathetic for cravings and needs,
wants to the world. Yeah. You know,
I imagine if I had to walk into a room
and do a group of people and say I cannot
live another second
longer without a donut,
like that would be so embarrassing
as a human to say that.
And yet we think that way and we
act that way. We don't say it right,
but our actions basically act that way.
We know that the doughnut is not needed.
Yeah. We know that the doughnut
is not needed. If you were,
if you were starving for for 38 days,
eat a doughnut. If you are on day
37 hold off, you might find a steak.
It's so bad, man. You see?
You mentioned that made me think that
it's so bad that this is an official
effective way to like improve
your diet this way, dear.
Don't keep junk food in your house,
food,
junk food in your house.
You can't control yourself and you can
rationalize to you, well, you know what?
This is no big deal.
I'm not going to start that.
I'm going to fast in three weeks anyways
so I might as well just to eat this
whatever right now. That's how bad
we are. We can't control herself.
I liked that idea.
I just thought of just having to announce
your week thoughts to the whole world
and how stupid they would like.
If you're going to carry
out an action that's weak,
you should have to verbalize it first.
I am about to eat this doughnut because
I could not survive without it announced
your rationalization to the world.
Well,
I'm going to skip this workout because
my left pinky is sore from Jujitsu three
weeks ago. Well, no. Well
that's just, that's the water,
a rationalization. Then a lot of ones
that I've dealt with straight up,
I don't feel like it straight
up. That's not good. Come on.
Next question.
P D p e d or Hgh.
Question Mark. Would that means, do you
take these or are in which one is better?
Yeah. Well, PD is the general term
performance enhancing drugs and HGH is,
oh,
human growth hormones.
I think he's asking or this
person is asking if you take him,
I cannot work or your thoughts on them.
The only performance enhancing
drug that I take is chuck away.
I take Jocko white tea now it's being
run through the Olympic Committee to see,
it looks like it's going to get banned
in the Olympics. Jocko white tea. Yeah.
Yeah. Tony had so many new records are
being broken. No, I don't take anything.
Never have the
HGH and pds perform.
What's the performance performance
enhancing drugs. Steroids, Bro. Yeah,
but so let's say
technically it's caffeine.
A performance. Yeah. I think
it actually, I dunno. I Dunno.
I Dunno it well it is. No, I do know
that it is a performance enhancing drug.
It is. And people take it when they
scientifically measure it is a performance
enhancing drug.
But I think for some reason it's legal.
Even in the Olympics or whatever,
I don't think you,
I think you do have a
maximum that you can take.
I don't think you could just fill
your blood with caffeine and,
and go do you know you're wrestling match,
but kind of off. Yeah. Interesting.
You have this friend
called Kate. Cool. Cool.
Kilcoyne is his name in college. He was
like, I want to say outside linebacker.
Maybe instead.
I don't know.
He's a linebacker slumps and so he'd
have a real good workout. And you know,
when you work out lifting, you'd have,
you'd have a pump, right? You know,
you walk around with him. So He'd take
off his shirt sometimes and he'd be like,
look guys, guys, I think come on steroids.
I always thought that was the funniest
thing. Nonetheless. Uh, yeah. No,
no steroids or ped
Junko next,
please do believe in aliens.
I'm assuming they mean extra
terrestrial aliens do mean that? Uh, I,
my opinion on aliens is that I'm sure
in this vast unknown world and universe
there is likely to be other life forms
that have some level of intelligence.
Interesting. How, sure. I'm going to
scale from one to 10 how sure you are.
Obviously you can't be town very um,
over a five but well I actually,
when you take the entire universe,
which is so massive,
we can barely even comprehend it.
The chances are decent
that there's some other,
some how intelligent life
form out there and you almost,
I mean you kind of have to ask,
wait like at this very time,
but then when you think about it,
there's really no time in a way.
Like that's kind of relative to so in
the whole existence would you say what
nine are you level nine? Sure is the
nicest matter of opinion. Don't know.
I think, I think like 9.0 so you're
a believer? Yeah, I'm a believer.
I would be vast. Like if some
wizard guy was like, okay,
you get to make a bet. Do you think
there is or isn't? I know the answer.
You do think there is or isn't,
you know the wizard be proof of concept
right there as you're talking to an what
if he was the guy from the future. Okay.
And somehow figured it out. I Dunno.
They mapped the whole universe.
I don't know. Whatever.
I would bet, oh, the cost is
your life too, by the way.
Like you got to have to make a bed.
You have to make a choice and you,
if you get it right, you live, you
get it wrong, you die. I would bit,
yeah, I would bet. Yes I would. Yes. Yeah.
That's the thing is is you would also,
it'd be interesting to have a
scientist or talk to a scientist
about the probability of human life.
Like how credibly
tiny, tiny, tiny, tiny, minuscule,
like all the little things that had to
happen for us to end up here and it's
good for them to have them
again. But then again, you, you,
you compare that to the unknown.
One of this universe that is so large,
it's been comprehensible.
Chances are it's happened somewhere else.
And even in just, and that's in a way, a
different point where it's like, you know,
what would it take to,
to make humans and wind up being humans?
If you look at it backwards,
it seems really like,
oh my gosh, this is this
crazy, like, you know,
almost impossible odds. Yeah.
Miracle kind of thing. But you,
you can say that with every day thing.
If you look at it backwards. So like,
let's say I had, um, like
the Legos, right? Okay.
We had this big bucket of Legos. It was,
it was one of those big plastic tubs.
It was just full of years and
years and years of Lego sets.
And there's all in there,
if I were to take that to full legos and
fucking pour it out on the ground on a
marble surface. So they scatter
everywhere and then it'll, you know,
when they all settle, it'll be
a little pattern, right? Lego,
various colors, shapes, sizes, all
kinds of different places, spaces.
And to take that exact pattern
down to the nano meter,
that exact pattern,
and be like,
this is the most special pattern in
the entire world ever in existence.
This one is, there is no
way anyone ever, ever,
ever could recreate this exact pattern
down to the nano meter. It's impossible.
That's why this pattern is so special,
but it's just one of many
potential eventualities, infinite.
You know, and when you end up
at something and then say, okay,
that what we have to
end up as his special,
that's looking at it backwards, like I
said, so it's like the lottery winner.
You know the guy who wins the lottery,
he's like, oh my gosh, I'm so special.
I want to let know fricking.
If I took a ping pong ball and I saw and
I had a mosh pit of 1 million people,
one ping pong ball, I throw it in the
mosh pit and then somebody catches it.
Oh my gosh, I'm so special.
Breast, someone's going to get it.
Someone's going to get the ping
pong ball. That's affirmative. Yeah.
So it doesn't make it necessarily
special unless you look at it backwards.
You know, if that guy's like, I'm
going to go into another lunch,
another during the other alien life form
could be something that we could barely
even imagine of what it's
like and that's that.
That probability wise is what it is. Or
it's going to be something like so small.
But if it's like more a
superior intelligence is
going to be something we don't
recognize the same way.
Like if you have a caterpillar on the
leaf and I see it from 10 yards away,
all I see that little cat
caterpillar rate right there.
Hey Caterpillar yelling at it.
You know the vibration from
my voice are hitting it.
It get up out of the Caterpillar.
The Caterpillar has no
idea that you even exist.
Doesn't even know what a human is,
doesn't know about your problems.
It doesn't know about your
podcast. You know? Meanwhile,
you know a lot about your podcasts.
Listen to the podcast and I can say
with a fair amount of stuff. Then again,
I don't know, maybe he does. I don't know.
He has a big butterfly
plans for his future.
Jocko. Next question. Next question.
How can I encourage bro?
We can talk
more about the aliens,
aliens or Legos.
I'm telling you mego patterns because you
know when people see you at full. Yeah,
they go straight teeth. That's an
alien. Even though it's an unidentified,
can't do that. Remember what I was telling
you? That kid's book idea. Yeah, you did.
Tell me about that.
You don't have to tell me again either.
It goes deeper on that telling you,
telling her it's actually,
it's more about the flaws of how
people consider or regard aliens,
potentially elites.
Jocko,
how can I encourage a sense of urgency?
This is a hard one and
others? Well, yeah, I think,
I'm assuming that this means with others,
but for either yourself or others,
which you have to realize is that is
going by very fast and when you have
projects that are, do you, the minute
you look at them, you got to say,
this is going to take longer
than we think it's going to take.
Let's start moving on it now and then
set yourself a really tight timelines to
make things happen and that what that'll
do is it'll make you realize how far
behind the power curve you are.
That was a,
one of my rules when I was in the seal
teams was I was always saying let's be as
far ahead of the power curve as
power as possible as we possibly can.
So is that a normal
expression power curve?
Like that's the thing that you're trying
to stay ahead of cause it's going to
smash you. So I would
always, you know, just,
we didn't slow down the power curve
if we got, we thought we were ahead,
go ahead further.
But I always had a really good sense that
that PowerCurve was coming to crush us.
So that's what you have to do.
Get as far ahead as of it as you can.
Tell everyone where it is or
set some small goals. Say, Oh,
you don't think this is gonna this
project's going to take long. Okay, cool.
Let's just finish this first 6%
which means this, this, and this,
and let's have that done
by tomorrow afternoon.
Tomorrow afternoon comes in and they're
not even close. Okay. Guess what?
We need to align.
We need to get a sense of urgency
going so we can get this done, done.
That's it.
I know that to encourage a
sense of urgency in yourself.
What you can do kind of works sometimes
is you think about the feeling you're
going to have after it's done and then
consider things that you already did get
done. You're have those, well,
you're different, but sometimes we,
the people have things that man,
we need to do and it's just a small thing,
you know, and you're like, Hey,
I'll do it. I'll do it later.
I'm doing something right now. Do
it. You know, tomorrow. Yeah, sure.
That's pretty intuitive to you.
But you know, sometimes you do.
You'd just be like doing it later.
I'm just going to do it later because
I'm thinking about something right now or
I'm doing something right now and then,
or while you're thinking about doing it,
but just do it.
I know with your kids all the time,
Hey, do the dishes, blah, blah,
blah, blah, blah, blah, blah, blah,
blah. You'd already be done. I know.
That's the thing. That's the whole
point right there. So when you do it,
when you do the thing, let's say
you've got to, I don't know, whatever,
you had to respond to an email,
I don't know.
And after you do it that just that
feeling right when it's done, you're like,
Dang, not that. Hey, that
wasn't, didn't take much a,
that's not gonna be a case every time,
but didn't take much. And B, I'm done.
My Dad and he said this saying, this is
what he'd say, do it and it'll be done.
It's a good thing. And as a kid I was
like, hope you're a drizzle. Smart.
That's like it is what it is. Yeah, I
know. It is what it is. You said that,
you don't have to say that, you know,
but what's Your Dad's first name?
Technically it's William
Charles Jr. Okay. Easy.
Those were BC. We have a new quote from
BC. I see. Oh, for Bill Charles. Charles.
Yeah. So bcs in the house, you
know, do it and it is done.
I like that one through it and then it
will be done, do it and it will be done.
Yeah, I changed it a little bit. Do it
and it's done. Yeah. Same thing to say my,
but his thing was always, yeah, exactly
the same thing or the exact words.
BC do it and it'll be done.
Yeah. At me as a grown adult,
arguably you apparently didn't
impact the way you wanted them.
Now I'm seeing the genius
of it, you know, do an,
it'll be done like you don't
have to. So good. Next question.
If do do too,
it's not locally available.
What would be the next best martial
arts choice or the next best thing?
Or is the one way 70 mile drive worth it.
Thank you.
Meaning it's not locally available.
It's seven
miles away. That's a long haul. So yeah,
there's a lot of other available
martial arts, I would say.
You got judo and wrestling and those
exists in a lot of places that Jujitsu
doesn't exist. So wrestling, judo, sambo,
those are all good options. Great options.
You can find a catch wrestling school.
There's, so there's definitely some
options to find a good grappling,
but a real grappling school,
what you want to watch out for is
a place that says it has karate,
Kung Fu end Jujitsu.
You want to watch out for
that place because that means
the guy just put that up
there because you just is getting popular.
So watch out for that guy.
And that one's pretty like
across the board right there.
I mean I can't really imagine many
exceptions where it's like Gra, you know,
like all the other ones and
Jujitsu and it's a legitimate,
it doesn't happen very often. Now you
might have a place that says boxing,
wrestling or Jujitsu. Yes, yes,
probably legit because you've got
legit boxing, legit wrestling,
legit judo and legit Jujitsu. So you go,
okay, that's cool. That's probably true.
But when it's non things I,
they throw Jujitsu on the end of it.
Watch out.
And whenever I'm talking about Jujitsu,
I'm talking about Brazilian Jujitsu.
I've just got to make that clear.
Talking about Brazilian Jiu Jitsu,
not other forms of Jujitsu.
So be careful of that
in the spirit of fairness there, there
very well could be like, you know,
cause a lot of these guys,
they'll,
they'll have this vast
background in like Kempo karate.
You're got taken care of from other site
and then they get to know for sure he
knew I was at their traditional
lands but they're Jujitsu legit.
That's why I said just be careful,
just be careful with my battery.
And most people,
if 15 years ago they started taking
Brazilian Jujitsu and they got their black
belt there,
their Tai Chi Quan,
uh, whatever, whatever.
Martial art is not at the, on the list
of what they teach at their school.
It's gone. Actually the, if
they're a black belt in Jujitsu,
they're teaching Brazilian Jujitsu and
they don't say Brazilian Jujitsu plus
Baucom Quan or whatever. They don't
say that they're going to do that.
And if they do do it,
I actually am going to question,
there are some questions. There's
questions again, can it be,
can there be a legit person? Yes there
can. There are some legit dudes that are,
you know,
black belts in Brazilian Jujitsu and
there are a black belt in some other
traditional martial art that
they took before that that is,
that does happen most of the time when
they realized that the white belt or blue
belt in Brazilian jujitsu destroyed
them and their martial arts,
they'd studied for 10 years.
They don't put that on the list anymore.
That's why I,
that's what it does to most people.
So that's why there's questions,
questions, there's questions. So yeah,
if the wrestling wrestling what, well
I know I'm missing it. I apologize.
Got Folks out there if I'm
missing. But wrestling, judo,
sambo,
catch wrestling those.
Now if there's no kind of grappling
then you boxing Muay Thai you,
that's your next best option so that
you're still learning how to fight.
You just aren't getting the groundwork
and you definitely want to get the ground
work at some point. So, and then
the question on the 17 mile drive,
I get this a lot to some people,
they have no martial art in
their area and they have a marsh,
they have Jujitsu 70 miles away.
What should I do?
My vote in that situation is it
get some maths at your house,
get two or three of your friends.
I want to learn how to fight,
start watching youtube videos and once
a week on the Saturday go down to that
Jujitsu school. When we were
training back at Fabio's, there was,
there was people like that they lived in,
they lived somewhere in,
in the desert of southern California.
There was no Jujitsu.
They work nine to five and
then on Saturday they'd come
out and train and that's
what they got.
And they go home and work on their drills
with their three guys that they were
driving 80 miles to come and train
on the weekends. So yeah, that's,
that's a method of doing it to you.
You can train on your own with your
buddies on the maths that you get and
watching youtube and or whatever
online mechanism you want to use.
And then once a week you come and you
make the trek and you learn and you get to
train with other people and you see where
you're at. Yeah. Dang. That's good. Yeah.
Very good. Yeah. The next
best thing is the heart.
I guess it's some total matter of opinion,
but I feel like wrestling,
like if you went, um, okay.
Like while wrestling is
like a really good tool.
It depends on what you're doing.
Yeah.
Like why, why you're doing it. Yeah. Yeah.
Like for self to wrestling is awesome.
Yeah.
I know that that's awesome.
Wrestling is,
gives you such a massive advantage,
not only in Jujitsu but in life. Yeah.
It gives you an advantage.
So wrestling is awesome.
That being said,
judo is awesome too,
and if you train, but there's more of
a variation in judo schools, right?
Yeah.
And a high end judo school,
those people are awesome and
that's a great martial art.
And you've learned groundwork. You learned
take downs. It's a great martial art,
don't they?
I would no question about it.
There are some weak judo schools though.
Judo has a little bit of a tendency to,
sometimes judo people can adapt
some of the traditional marts,
traditional martial arts attitude,
including the attitude of,
of we're not actually training.
And so that has happened,
but that's, that's less.
That doesn't happen very often. So
yeah, if you can find a good judo,
the way you find, if it's a good judo
school going put on a g and and say,
let's fight or let, let me train with
you and they're going to put you,
they're gonna, they're gonna take you
down and be able to work you over.
That's what judo is. Judo is very similar
to Jujitsu, very similar to Jujitsu.
So Judah is a great thing to
have. Wrestling is a great
thing to have for sure.
Sambos awesome.
Sambo is actually like judo
and wrestling together,
so sambos great. Same with catch
wrestling. Again, there's catch.
Wrestling is a little less with
catch wrestling, you're, you're,
you're a little bit more apt to find
somebody that doesn't actually know what
they're doing.
And so you have to be careful of that.
There's some phenomenal catch wrestling
schools though, for sure. Yeah. So
that's true.
I think we've got time to look
at one more of these. Yes, Jocko.
How do we get the desire
to have discipline?
How do I
get the desire to have discipline?
I keep
getting asked this type of question.
How do I get disciplined or how do I
want discipline or how do I maintain
discipline? And the answer,
it's, it's a simple answer,
but obviously it's not easy.
And there's all all kinds of little
tricks and methods that people talk about
and you know, they have
some merit, you know,
maybe they do work these,
these things, you know,
do the little things people say and,
and wake up early.
I say that and write things down and
take cold showers and tell everyone what
you're going to do.
So broadcast it and make promises or,
or make bets with, with your friends. Have
something that you don't want to lose.
And those things, those
ideas, they're cool.
I'm sure they're going to have some
impact and if they work for you, that's,
that's awesome.
But,
but the fact of the matter is that the
reason discipline is hard to maintain is
because it is hard to maintain.
That's what makes discipline hard.
It's hard.
And if you hear me claim that
discipline is easy for me,
then straight up,
that's just my ego talking.
That's what that is because
I'm
unfortunately just as human as everyone
else and it is a work to maintain the
discipline. That's what it
is. Work holding the line,
maintaining the standard,
giving no slack, none.
That's the discipline,
that's the discipline and it is hard.
And if there's one thing I would
say that does make it easier,
it's to envision what it
feels like when you're done,
what it feels like after you've worked
out or you've held the line on your food
intake or you've pushed through some
monotonous project that you have to do in
all those things. When they're
doing that, they feel good
and
contrary to that invasion,
what you will feel like later
when you let the discipline slack,
you know the feeling,
feeling weak and deed and you
know that you're falling behind.
So get to know those two different types
of feelings and ask yourself which one
you want to feel in 10 minutes
or in a half an hour
when when the thing is done,
when the discipline has blend implemented,
remember what that feels like and then
remember that those minutes and those
hours they turn into weeks and
months and years and holding villein.
In those critical minutes we'll put you
in an infinitely better place physically
and mentally if you
maintain the discipline.
So work through the weakness,
fight through the temptation,
hold the line,
maintain the discipline.
It is not easy,
but it is worth it
because
yes,
because discipline equals freedom.
And I think that's
all I've got for tonight.
So
Echo is speaking of discipline,
perhaps in a discipline manner.
You could explain to
us how we could support
this podcast if we want it to.
If you want it for sure.
I feel like we should,
like we always do in a disciplined way.
Talk about on it. Despite
discipline, I mean concise by the way
are over to member half
hours or something like that.
That doesn't control, that
doesn't, you're not even,
that doesn't play into your head,
does it? You're in the game.
You're here throughout your job.
Done. You care longer takes correct.
Nonetheless. Last time I mentioned
that I ran out of Krill oil.
You even said you should go
to the store and buy. So yeah.
Did you know the good thing is
when I went home from our session,
it had come in. Oh,
along with the orangutan.
Oh, you got an Kettlebell? Nice to have
them. Or just one. One. What's the weight?
54 pounds. You need another
one? Yeah. So I want,
I want the Zombie one for
whatever the ranking ones. Cool.
But the Zombie one was really cool.
So they're out of them.
I think they're the same late 54 seven
one two 54 is they're out of them.
So I was like, yeah, I'll just get
one of these just, you know, as
a one off. And then when the
Zombie ones come in check,
I'll get the two Zombie ones.
So where's this?
Is this store that you're talking thing,
is that on at.com but I'm
explaining what it is. Just gives,
people don't know or they don't
understand the importance.
I think it's important. Nonetheless.
Krill oil came in. This is what you do.
And I mentioned this before
and this is what I'm gonna do.
I'm gonna try to do, I should just
do it in, it'll be done. Stay on it.
You know what that is, right?
Stay on it. Oh, the automatic,
the re Oh yeah. What do you even
call it? Three automatic automatic.
The ship kind of made a shipment.
Yeah.
You just pay every month and it
automatically comes. Yeah. Yeah.
I think you might even get a deal
on that one. I don't know though,
but that's what I'm doing.
I'm a status called stay on it.
You know what men that's in a lot of
people or companies do that, you know,
like the other stuff. Yeah.
I'm alon like toilet paper.
You know things that you just use all
duct tape duct constantly running out of
that. That's, that's a good deal.
I mean, that's a good thing to
do with basically everything.
At one time when I was drinking,
I don't drink anymore hardly.
Um, who was it? It was Rudy.
He asked me to do something of video or
something, I dunno. And he was like, Hey,
can I pay you in vodka and
I could have a savage. Ivan says that,
no rough crude anyway. And he goes,
can I pay you and vodka? I didn't
tell him to get out of here. I was,
I was considered, I was
like, wait a second.
It kind of is like currency when you
drink every day, every day, you know,
it's kind of like, well, I'm going to
spend that money anyway. So I'm like, Hey,
you know what I could do,
I'm just thinking about,
it lasted for like five seconds,
maybe 10 maybe 20 but I thought to myself,
hmm,
think of how much money
I would've charged him,
like double it or triple it and
get that much worth of vodka. Boom.
I just saved 75 no,
66% you know what I'm saying?
Okay. Move on. Nonetheless,
the point still stands
if it's,
if you don't have to think about it,
it just comes,
you start to run into this thing like me
where I'm at a Krill oil for one week.
Actually it was a little less than a week.
It doesn't matter.
I won't be out of it at all. So yeah,
stay on it. That's the one krill oil.
Strawn bone didn't run out of that,
by the way. And that's good man.
That's stuff is good. It's weird how I
told you right how my shoulder was jack.
Like the Tim didn't party.
He'll weird spot to get healthy
and I didn't even stop lifting.
You know how you get tendinitis?
You're like,
I gotta stop lifting or lifting lighter,
you know,
suckers Stromboli stay strong.
Get rid of the tendinitis and any bone
issues. I think if I'm not mistaken,
I'm not sure I got to go back on the
website. I get addicted to that website.
It's like interesting stuff.
Um,
I think it can delay or stop
the onset of osteoporosis.
I don't want to make that clear.
I'm not making that claim. I'm not,
I'm not making it cause I'm just saying
that's what strontium does. Nonetheless,
a good kettle bells on their workout
stuff, especially if you like,
like you know how if you go in bench,
I don't bench but if you do a, you know,
just repetitious shoulder press, I dunno,
it can get boring,
but if you're into like
interesting type workouts,
you know how like do you have a
mace right. One of those do. Yeah.
And you had clubs.
See Yeah.
See that's why you work out so much in
our early in the morning cause you're all
looking forward to it.
It's all interesting and fun if you're
into those interesting workouts and it's
cool cause you can like look up a bunch
of workouts just for one kettle bell,
you know. So maces and of course they
got the traditional stuff, jump rope,
whatnot. But um, like they
have these metal thanks.
I don't know what they are but it's like,
you know, these are for working out.
So it's like man,
you can't even get bored
working on anymore really
when you go in there anyway.
Websites. Interesting too. Anyway, this
stuff, the supplements are outstanding.
They do have, um, yeah.
I'm going to say it,
this nut butter blend.
Also, I've got some MCT oil,
MCT, MCT stands for. Yes, I do.
Medium chain triglycerides.
It's good for you. Anyway,
I cook with Owen and I put it in.
What didn't you make?
Like a decert with it or
something. All kinds of stuff,
but it was something. Sure.
Mct, heavy whipping cream,
something. Anyway, go on there.
Get 10% off.
If you want 10% off,
go on it.com/jocko it's a good one.
Support Yourself, support your joints,
support your health.
I don't think you should
be in a situation anymore
anymore, given the times we're
in to not support your health.
There's really no room for not
supporting your health right now.
All your needs are met.
You're not going out and like
you're not hunting for food. Yeah.
Nonetheless, do that on a
dotcom slash Jocko. Also,
good way to support your
brain is to read these books.
Eugene sledge,
another one from him trying to marine
also around a four and a rumor of war and
we go on,
I'm reading it upside down and we go on.
Um, those are powerful
books on the website, Jocko,
podcast.com there's a page,
it's called books from the episode
top Menu. Click on it, boom.
All the books from all the episodes
with the link directly to Amazon.
You get those books through there.
That's good way to support Amazon.
Click through. Or if you're
doing any other kind of shopping,
just click through our website and get
whatever you're going to get including,
but not limited to these
books, duct tapes, duct tapes.
Maybe you need multiple roles, duct tapes.
But even if there was multiple rules,
I think it's still duct tape.
Did you got different types
of duct tapes still? No.
Okay.
Or paper clips.
St Dealer or whichever macgyver stuff
that you're into. Getting a bad,
been getting more nice.
I'm going to bring them in for pro.
You ever go on Amazon and
be like, hey, this is cool.
And then you how they show you the little
suggestions and then you buy all the
suggestions. Do you ever done that
before by all the suggestions? No,
cause I've disciplined, I need, uh,
so I went on there and I got a flashlight.
You know how noddies flashlight
technology nowadays, especially nowadays,
back in the day, remember the ones
that you had a had had like a,
it was like a suitcase flashlight, but
they're big. So those were dope as a kid.
Like if you had that one, you're
like the man. Yeah, exactly right.
It's some kind of reliving it. So
I'm like, let me get a flashlight.
And then you look at all
the new flashlights out. Oh
my gosh, these are awesome.
So I'm like, okay, I'm going to buy
this. I don't buy a MAG light back.
Lights are dope.
Cause he can hit people with it in the,
in the event of having
to use it for a weapon.
So I get one and then I click on it and
there's various options on the length of
it. I'm like, Ooh. So I get
the regular one camouflage
for my daughter. She's four.
She likes flashlights, like
all kids do. I get to, for me,
one for Sarah Tooth, it's a long one.
It's like us. It's called like a six cell,
meaning it takes six batteries.
So you can imagine how long that thing,
it's like a straight up Bhutan
with a flashlight on it. So I got,
I wind up getting nine flashlights.
I don't need nine flashlights.
This is an indication of a total lack of
discipline while they're on Amazon. Yes.
I hope you didn't click through though.
Yeah. Yes I did. And I got a book too,
by the way, so yeah, sure.
I lacked Amazon flashlight
shopping discipline,
but I got some cool flashlights. There's
this technique here. I'll show you it.
You might even know this,
but I learned this in bouncer.
It was security training and this was
a technique that you're this illegal to
use. You can't use it as security
or because it's offensive.
It's not insecurities,
minimum force necessary to effect a
whatever to to defuse the situation,
whatever.
So this is what it is.
Let's say this was a flashlight and
the say, this is the light part, right?
Like so usually as a lay person, you
hold the flashlight like this, right?
And you like in law enforcement and
stuff like that, they hold it like this.
It's kind of up above like that. So
this is how you hold it. So you shut,
you grip it right there by the,
the head of it with the light.
You shine it in the guy's face and be
like, calm down, calm down, calm down.
They can't really see you there.
Just blinded by the light kind of.
And they're like, oh ha ha. And they hear
your voice saying calm down, calm down.
And men you can get and you flip it around
and hit him with it and you get those
long mag lights that it,
the six cell full batteries,
boom. They don't see it coming.
They don't flinch, they don't blink,
they don't anything.
It's just a complete,
you see light one moment for a split
second, the light kind of goes down,
then flash, then you see, yeah, you
wake up. That's it man. The video.
I saw a guy doing it to somebody.
I was like, Dang, that guy. It's,
it's like you know those eerie,
you know like when you see a person die,
whether it be on video or whatever,
he gets to like shot and his body just
goes limp. He doesn't know what's coming,
nothing he but it looked like that he
got hit with it so square and so hard and
he didn't even flinch. It's a real
effective thing. Don't do it to people
unless they're in your house or
something like that. Anyway, I digress.
Also,
good way to support is subscribing
to the podcast, iTunes,
Google, Google, play,
Google, play, stitcher,
all these podcasting,
providing platforms.
Also Youtube technically as a podcast
providing platform, so subscribe to it.
Alan, here's the thing about
youtube. If you don't already,
it gives you the added benefit of being
able to see the video version juncos
face talking about these things,
so subscribe to that.
We'll add some other excerpts on there,
some enhanced excerpts
that when we're calling them. Sure they
enhanced one. What's the music on there,
right? Some B roll.
That's what it's called.
Bureau and think that that's
not the actual thing anyway. Um,
and also what did I say I was going to
put on there last time I was going to put
on something on Youtube.
Yeah, some more videos,
more videos or whatever.
It's just a theory at this point, but
nonetheless subscribe and boom, you can,
you know, support that way.
Also, Jack was a store.
It's called chocolate store.
What's the website?
It's an online store,
Jocko store.com so what this has,
if you don't know already is t shirts,
hoodies. I think I'm going to put some
light hoodies on their summertime.
You don't like that? I do. No
heavier. Nothing. Yes. Heavy
heavy Hoodie or no shirt?
Yes. To wear tank tops.
Not really. Oh you do?
Yes.
My wife threw a bunch of minor away
about five or seven years ago because she
doesn't like the wrong,
no,
they were just all old and ratty
and just throw them away randomly,
which was awesome. Just don't throw
really, because that was a longer me.
That's not cool.
It's one of those,
it's like one of the four things that
I still bring up to her. No kidding.
She'd be like, oh, can't
believe how hot it is today.
I'd be comfortable if I had a tank top.
I don't have any because
you threw them away. Yeah,
no, they were nice. She does it
like the way you look in those tops,
it's offensive. Their
sensibility. Cool. Yeah, man.
I'm just saying, you know, stop pointing
the finger. Start playing in left thumb.
Right. That's the expression, right? Yeah,
yeah, yeah. You gotta watch out for that.
Strangely, I don't watch out for your tank
tops are barely in my house, you know,
point there is someone did say,
actually not many people saying tank tops
will be cool. I don't wear tank tops.
You do? Apparently still.
That's obviously a sore subject.
Yeah. Let's make some tank tops off
of, do my whole wardrobe with tag down.
Bring them back in the game.
Thank [inaudible]. Yeah. Ooh, Dang. Yeah.
You know those kind of put them on the,
on the sander or whatever.
Nonetheless, shirts are cool. If you
think they're cool, check checking out.
[inaudible] dot com go in there, check
out the shirts. This rash guards on there.
I think I, I'm saying obviously just
my opinion, the rash guards are cool.
That's like to me actually there's
a lot of good things on there,
my opinion, but nonetheless,
shirts on there. They're cool. Um,
if you want to support,
do it that way cause the website,
see if you like something, get
something. Hats are coming soon,
whatever that means. But
they'll be here soon. Also,
psychological warfare. If you didn't
know what that is, I know you do,
but let's say you didn't know what
that was here. I'm going to tell you,
it is an album with tracks Jocko tracks.
Jack was saying what?
Hey,
these are the pragmatic,
logical reasons why you shouldn't slip
on your diet or your waking up early or
this is why you should not
skip through the workout.
This is why you shouldn't
slack on the workout.
Like all these little things that you'll,
the probability of you slacking on
certain things in life are they fluctuate
really, but in the event of you slacking
on something and you need a spot, verbal,
verbal and psychological,
get this,
check this out.
Search psychological warfare,
Jocko Willink on iTunes or Amazon
music or wherever they sell mp3s.
Get that and get a little spot.
Get a little spot for your points
of weakness in your journey.
I said it and that helps.
Also, you can get Jocko white
tea on Amazon. By the way,
we talked about a little bit today.
The person said that they drank a couple
of Jocko white tea this morning before
I left for muster zero zero two and ended
up at muster zero zero one not saying
that I've proven Jocko white tea allows
you to travel through time and space,
but here we are. So again, this
is a verified purchase review.
So this is the person that
actually experienced this.
So we need to keep that in mind.
Jocko white tea,
you get home to amazon.com
also weigh the warrior kid
book for kids
and possibly adults.
I think we're starting to
see that here is a review.
I wish I had read this book before.
It gives you an excellent path
to a successful, fulfilled
life. It is very easy,
but don't be fooled.
It's incredibly deep too.
I think it is great for a 10 year old or
for an 80 year old as you are never too
old or too young to learn the basics
of an honorable life worth living.
Fantastic. 100 stars,
so that's pretty cool.
Pick up the book.
It's about how to be better,
how to overcome the obstacles that we
all face and it's told through the voice
of a 10 year old boy
named mark and his uncle,
Uncle Jake,
who comes into his life to help them
overcome some of these obstacles.
So there you go.
That's where the warrior
kid also discipline equals
freedom field manual editing
is complete at this time.
So many of these questions I get asked
all about all the time are laid out in
his book, food workouts, martial arts,
and my,
my operating system.
Once you, that I've talked about on
the, on this podcast is in the book,
in a written form.
This book is like the podcast that you
can read and absorb and refer back to.
So
the book is like the podcast,
but you're going to see it's not
a normal book. It's not normal.
My publishers says we've never
published anything like this.
I don't think there's anything
else published like this ever.
So it's a little different.
It's not a regular book,
just like this isn't a regular podcast
discipline equals freedom field manual.
You can preorder it right now.
And of course,
extreme ownership leadership book is
based on what I learned during 20 years in
the seal teams about leadership
and especially from the
battle of Ramadi and how
to take those lessons and
apply them to the battlefield,
to business and to life.
Wrote that with my brother Leif Babin
who was on the battlefield with me in
Ramadi. Also, we have leadership and
management consulting company, me, Leif,
Babin, JP Denelle, Dave Burke,
leadership and management
or alignment for your team.
If you want that email
info@echelonfront.com and
finally the Muster Austin,
Texas July 13th and 14th too late.
Sold out. We're done with that one.
Not done with it.
It's still gonna happen.
But you can't come because it's sold out.
No more seats.
We were able to bump it up a little bit.
I think we've got to like three 20
or three 30 but that's a lot. Um,
we were supposed to only have
300 and then rearrange some
seats or whatever. So we got it to three
20 I think. But that's it. We can't,
we cannot put anyone
else in there sold out.
So the next shot is back in San Diego,
September 14th and 15th back the
Omni hotel on the bay in San Diego.
A lot of people from the first muster
in San Diego are coming back and I think
that will be awesome to hear
from people. Okay. You went,
you went to the first muster,
you were, you learn some things,
then you brought him back to apply them
real world. You hit some obstacles.
What are the obstacles that you hit? Let's
figure it out, how to get around them.
That's musters zero zero for San
Diego, California. After that,
we're not going to go again with
a monster for awhile, you know,
at least until sometime in 2018
probably once again in the springtime,
but later in the spring.
So be aware of that.
If you don't come to September, it's
going to be awhile. And until the muster,
if you do want to communicate
and hang out a little bit,
you can find us getting af.
Well,
you're not really getting
after it on the Internet,
but you can find us typing letters
into a keyboard on the interwebs.
That's right on Twitter,
on Instagram and in the Facebook.
Keep whole-hog echo is that Echo Charles
and I am at Jocko Willink and thanks
for listening and subscribing and
supporting and spreading the word,
but more important.
Thanks for grabbing a hold
of the challenges and the
struggles in your life and
learning from them and then climbing up
those challenges like a Jacob's ladder
and using them to elevate yourself
instead of letting them drag you down.
And when you get to the top,
look around
and give someone else a hand, pull
them up, tell them what you learned.
Try to do it in a tactful way.
Try and teach them and look around and
see who can help you and teach you and
what you can learn from other people
and teach people to overcome
challenges the same way that you did.
The same way we all did by learning from
our problems and our challenges and our
struggles.
And after we learn from them,
we grabbed them by the throat,
get after it.
So until next time,
this is echo and Jocko
out.