This is Jocko podcast number
21 with Echo Charles and me,
Jocko Willink.
And our guest tonight is Mr Tim Kennedy
who is an active duty army
special forces soldier,
ranger sniper MMA fighter.
Little bit of that Jujitsu black belt,
the zits fighter in the UFC
current fighter in the UFC
who everyone's waiting to
watch fight again,
an American patriot,
God bless America and
just all around beast
that miss anything,
uh,
pretty skinny right now and have a kick
ass mustache and he's got that going for
him and really excited
to have Tim on the show.
As you know, there's not been
a lot of guests on the show.
The only other guests that's been on this
show so far has been Mr Leif Babin who
was one of the platoon commanders,
worked for me in Ramadi or last deployment
and wrote the book that I wrote with
him and we had a pretty fired up podcast
and talked about a lot about the things
that we went through and experienced.
And you know, knowing you,
and I know you're a little bit
younger than me, but, uh, you know,
you just been through a lot of the same
kind of life events and mistakes and
mistakes and same kind of stuff.
So it's pretty cool to hang out with you
a little bit today and get to talk to
you.
And for everyone that's waiting to know
the results of the grappling death match
between 10 candidates come and go.
We can't even tell results
because it's still to be decided.
It didn't happen today.
We, uh, we ran out of time.
Tim's got a little dinged up
injury and so we had to forgo that.
And so instead we just went out
and slaughtered some meat. Dude,
it's amazing barbecue coming from
a text and I was like, really?
You're taking me to buy into barbecue?
Yeah. Had to do it. Not disappointed.
So also with us, of
course, is Echo Charles.
Good Evening Echo.
Good evening.
So we're going to get straight
into it. Uh, two questions.
We've got a ton of questions from the
Internet. Everyone's like exploded.
It did explode. Like, what questions
should I ask? And he's like,
my phone's on fire by
the Internet broke and,
but we did get a ton of questions,
so thanks everybody for asking
a bunch of cool questions.
Obviously we can't answer them all and,
but we're going to try,
we're going to take a crack at it.
And the first one,
and I just started this whole thing off
with cause it for anybody that does know
who you are, because I bring in a lot
of fans from, you know, MMA or whatever,
but not really, you know, most of
the people that are listening to me,
I think they might be Jujitsu guys,
but there's a lot of business people and,
and stuff like that.
So I guess to start this off with a
question that would give everyone a little
bit of background about you, other than
what I've just said, is someone said, hey,
I'd like to hear a little bit about Tim
Kennedy upbringing and what led him to
enlist.
Oh man, go Tim. Uh, I grew
up in central California,
uh, Rural California. When I say I'm
from California, people are like, Oh man,
you like, Hollywood is like, no, like
do you surf? And I was like, dude,
I speak Spanish.
I argue with Mexicans.
I ride horses and that's all
there is to do where I'm from. Um,
it's beautiful there,
but uh, it's very rural.
It was like an hour long drive from
my folks place to the gas to them,
the supermarket. Um, so you know,
as I was like the Christian version of
a boy scout or royal ranger and grew up
hunting and shooting,
um,
and I dunno,
pretty normal kind of rural kid.
Like there's a lot of like the Marcus
Luttrell and then Chris Kyle's like,
they're from Texas and it seems like
a pretty natural thing as a a decent
athlete. I wrestled and
always wanted that next thing,
that next challenge. And
uh, so I was in college,
I was fighting, um, I just won the ECC.
It was like I find Jason
Miller, Ryan McKown. Anyways,
just like Dennis Kang was in
the tournament is an eight
man, one 85 tournament.
Chucklito was in my corner.
Matt Hughes was the ref and um,
it was for three fights
in one night and uh,
one that which ranked me in the
top 10 in the world. And uh,
that was like August 30th of 2001
then September 11th happened,
um,
uh,
watching planes find a buildings
piss me off pretty bad.
So at that time I was a pretty bad person.
I had three women pregnant.
And um,
within the next couple of weeks I also
found out that I had possibly contracted
the HIV virus. And, um,
so it's professional fighter and Grad
school working at Dotcom and commerce in
California thought I was pretty awesome.
And like all revelations in life,
um,
when you're not reaching your potential,
it's a stark,
horrible reality.
And that's what it was.
It was this wake up call that I was a
piece of shit I should be probably buried,
would be, um, what I've sir,
it would have served the planet
better had I just knocked,
continued consuming oxygen.
So you're saying that that trigger
moment for you was when September 11th.
Yeah. You saw everything that was
happening and you said to yourself, man,
this is what I've done with my life
so far. Yup. That's pathetic. Yeah.
Time to get in the game.
Yep. All correct there.
But I think a little
bit more, um, negative,
like I am a super nasty piece
of poop beyond the theoretic.
Yeah. I'm looking on, my dad's an
amazing human. My mom's an amazing human.
My sister and my brother, you
know, like even to this day,
I aspire to be what they are. And then
I was like, man, I'm a really bad.
So I go down to the recruiter's office
and I didn't know the difference between
special forces, Navy Seals,
um, marine recon, um,
being a ranger, being a green
Brae. So I went in, I was like,
I obviously want to [inaudible]
they're all in the one at the same.
And I was like, I just want to, you
know, be Chuck Norris. Essentially.
They laughed at me. Um, but it's
when I got to the recruiter's office,
when I thought I was like this awesome
American, again taking my say self like,
aw, I'm so cool that I'm
going to go do this, you know,
like how selfless of me and there's
2000 people in line ahead of me,
you know, not, not like 1000, not
like 100, which would been a lot,
2000 people in s in rural California.
We're like,
Oh man, I got to go do something and
they'll beat me to it. So I'm again,
a complete piece of shit.
So that,
that was kind of like the
genesis and the origin.
That's what brought me to
the recruiter's office.
And then through the course of
trying to figure out, you know,
what they're as vap score and your gt
score, being a college athlete, you know,
like what the right fit was. I wanted
the fastest thing to get me behind a gun,
um, with people that
wanted to kill bad people.
And that's a ended up being the
green berets. Awesome. You know,
one of the things, I was on a, uh,
interview in England and I was talking
about the fact that America's pretty
restrained in the way it handles things.
But I also said that if we
get pushed to a certain point,
and I don't know where that point is
and you can't describe it and no one can
predict it, but that's a
case in point. You know,
something happens like September 11th,
and you've got 2000 men,
military age males in rural California
standing in line to go and make the
ultimate sacrifice if need be.
You can't forget that about American now.
You can't forget that about him.
You go to Pearl Harbor, you
know, Beautiful Hawaii. You
drop some bombs on us for,
you know, because you're pissed off about
the economics of some oil deals. Uh,
we're going to drop nuclear bombs on you.
Yeah.
You come and fly some
planes into our buildings.
We're going to go and try to wipe your
culture off the face of the planet for 15
years. And that's where we are
right now. Yup. Get a freaking clue.
Don't fuck with us. We get pissed
off if you push this too far,
that's pretty much it.
You know,
you got guys like this who are
already in there just like listen man,
bad decision.
Yeah,
it unfortunately you can see that
because it is American because it's an
isolated place and it's a very comfortable
place to live and people are driving
around, you know, while you were, you
know, flying around on a, on a helicopter,
getting ready to get inserted on a target,
there was someone else flying around
the mall and they're Cadillac Escalade,
getting ready to go and buy some new,
you know,
apple software or hardware
and that's their reality.
I mean they have no idea what that's like.
So we do forget in America
that what's happening,
what can happen to us and the
threats that are out there.
We can forget about that very easily.
And a lot of Americans do.
I know a lot of Americans, I know
Americans are listened to this podcast.
They don't forget that. Then they know
what we talk about it all the time.
But there are Americans that have no idea.
They live so isolated from the rest
of the world that it just wait, the,
the thought of going to war for them,
it means going to the mall cause
it doesn't change their life.
It doesn't impact their life at all. I
mean, we're here in California, you know,
like the perceived Utopian know,
like the Shangri la of the United States
and just two hours north of year. Yeah.
Two radicalized fanatics,
bring machine guns,
automatic rifles or raw shot rifles
and start mowing people down.
So I think we're coming to a crossroad
where people are going to either need to
wake up and stop being pandered
entitled Little Bitches.
Um,
or we may not have the same type of life
and culture and opportunity that we've
always claimed America to
have and to be. Yeah. Uh,
the key point of that being
freedom and the freedom to move,
the freedom to go to that ball.
It's the freedom of all those things that
we definitely take for granted because
we've had it for over 200 years.
If people forget what it's like
to live in an oppressive society,
they're gonna learn it here pretty
quick. Yeah. Yeah. And that's,
that's one of the best things that the
military does for you is you get to
travel with these all these other places
in the world and see what the rest of
the world lives like.
I caught a little flack from the Inter
webs because I didn't mention that. Yeah.
I know that there's other countries
that are first world countries in Europe
that are nice places to live
too. I get that. But would that,
they don't send us in the military
to those places. We, you know,
we don't get to go to the first
world countries that are all nice.
We go to horrible places
where there's wars happening.
And so that's our impression
of the world a lot of times.
And it's accurate because that's what
most of the world alive is like. I got it.
Germany's nice. Right. You know, but
you said Belgium was really nice.
We said it like from, you know, from
the fifties until just, I don't know,
about two months ago we were like,
Oh man,
they got great chocolate
and she's and coffee,
when is the last time you were in
Belgium? Right. Pretty Nice. Oh crap.
They're pretty much breeding
terrorists there. Yup.
So shut your face if you're talking to
Jocko about what the world actually is,
and at the same time you,
you talk about like where you don't get
sent to the nice places and the people
complaining they don't get
sent to the bad place. Right.
They don't go on a vacation
to Liberia. Yeah. Yeah. So
it happens. So yeah, they'll,
of course they're all, hey, I,
I've been all over the world to all this,
all this horrors that you claim to
have seen, you know, kind of ad.
Obviously you don't say that, but I had
a pretty good and balanced perspective.
Like you live in San Diego, California,
right. It's freaking gorgeous here.
It's one of most beautiful places
on the planet. It is. Yeah.
You've been to some nasty places. Um, I
think in like, if we're going to be like,
oh, Yin and Yang and you know,
balance of life and crap, um,
with the amount of evil that you've seen,
you've seen the sheer amount of BD,
you know, he married the same woman,
got a beautiful family, you know,
you've been in, had an amazing
career, run a great company. Yeah.
You saw horrible things too.
But like if somebody's going to come
and talk to us about our perspective on
life, you know, and like, oh, you don't
really understand if you, you know,
if you spent time in France,
like bitch, I have, first of all,
second is I'm not talking about France,
even though Paris just got their
ass kicked and then the train,
which would have been like a
complete massacre. Oh, that
would have been, um, yeah,
I understand. And you don't understand
until you've been with me too.
Like Kazakhstan or the packy Afghany
border. Shut your fucking face
Jackie. Uh, okay.
To cuss on here cause
that was that. Sorry. You,
you can, uh, you can swear if you
feel the need to. I'll try not to.
When I said I was running late, as I was
walking out the hotel, uh, to come here,
I got grabbed by some people and like,
man,
I'm getting some great feedback
about your presentation yesterday.
Did you know that you said Fuck 18 times?
And I was like,
I thought it's about 10 thank you.
So is that a positive
or negative feedback?
All in one of the podcasts we talked
about swearing and we talked about it for
like 17 minutes. Yeah, because,
and my basic point was I try
not to swear on the podcast.
The reason I try not to is because this
is going to be out there forever and it,
my kids are going to listen to this and
other humans are going to listen to this.
And so I think,
man,
I'm going to try not to swear and I
do swear sometimes, but I try not to,
but sometimes it's needed and I believe
in you let in the last statement it was
needed.
Okay.
I'm going to also try not to agree,
but sometimes you put the exclamation
mark at the end of a sentence.
Sometimes it's needed, you know,
sometimes it is. All right.
Anything else on that?
We're just kind of get warmed up.
I know. First question, we're just like,
well I hate session begins
at war for 15 years. Yeah. It
was a coming out of the gate strong.
So getting into America a little bit.
Next question.
I love this country.
Thoughts on current
military law enforcement,
self defense techniques and what you
both would incorporate to make better?
Hmm,
that's a super broad question.
You know, I'll narrow it down. Okay.
And I've talked about it a little
bit on the podcast, but you got cops,
police who have a hard job. I'm
miserable. Do you never do it?
I'd be in jail. I could never do
it. Never would want to do it.
Would you say to me?
Yeah dre.
I mean just dealing with dealing
with the dregs of society, you know,
for 14 calls and then the 15th call,
you're going to you some domestic
violence. And I mean just,
it's just a horrible hard job.
And then you have these shootings where
quote unquote innocent people get shot.
And sometimes they are. I mean I've
seen some of these police shootings,
there's no way I can approve it and I am
all about killing bad guys and some of
the shootings you just say man that comp
and I and I always look at it the same
way and I say that cop didn't have
the training they needed and I,
what really hurts is
that I know how to train.
I know what to do to make them better and
get them better at that. I know you do.
I don't have the money. They don't have
the time. You don't have the money.
They don't have the time.
A lot of times they don't even have
the experience within the department of
someone that knows how to train people
mentally cause that's what it is.
It's mental preparation of getting
someone ready to handle these scenarios
because it's just an unknown scenario.
That's what it is.
And one of my worst examples is this
guy pulls up to a seven 11 it's all,
it's all body camera, the guys, the whole
thing's on video. The guy gets a call,
there's a guy with a gun and stuff.
11 pulls up in his cruiser,
the seven 11 gets out of his car, sees a
guy walking away, starts yelling at him.
The guy's wearing a hoodie. The guy's
walking away from him. He's the cops,
yelled at him, freeze, freeze priests.
That guy doesn't freeze
and find these yelling at.
He's standing the cops standing in a
wide open, holding his gun out, you know,
priests, priests, and finding. The
guy turns around and looks at the cop,
reaches his hands in his pockets.
Boom, cops shoots him. Guy Falls down,
falls the curb roles. He's on his
stomach. Cop comes over, rolls over,
starts to search him. He finds,
pulls his head, pulls his hood off.
He's got headphones in,
reaching in his pockets.
He's got an iPhone on and he was just
sitting there listening to music.
Couldn't hear the cop turned around,
reached in his pocket,
turn off the iPhone and you know,
the cop who got the call,
there was a guy with a gun and it takes
you reaching for a gun. Dustin guy died,
bled out, and you can hear the cop.
The cop felt horrible, you know,
once he realized that, he's like,
come on buddy, it's going to be okay.
I'm gonna get you.
You mean just like the classic things that
I've know you've heard before of like,
I want to save this guy's life
and it's not gonna happen.
And what I know is that that guy going
into that situation from the get go,
if you think someone's got a gun, don't
stand out in the open and talk to them.
Get behind cover and stand back and you,
you'll stay behind your car,
get on your cruiser,
get on your loudspeaker and look at him
and watch him and see what he's doing
and see if there's a real threat.
But don't expose yourself to by standing
out in the middle of the open where if
he does have a gun he's going to get yet.
Yeah.
And those are simple things that you know
you could do to improve the training.
What you have to do is you have to put
people in stressful situations during the
training and that's what
we did in the seal teams.
I know that's what you guys do in the
SF is you get put in these horrible
stressful situations where
everything is getting destroyed.
You're getting shot with paint ball and
they're blowing smoke grenades up at all.
Frags hit you. They do that in the
trainings that when you get in combat,
you're not freaked out and
you can handle this situation
train hard so you bleed less. You know,
it's like, it's pretty simple. And uh,
but we,
we do
in Austin,
we do a stress test a week.
Sometimes it's barbell stuff on the range
and kit where we're doing like Olympic
lifts to a sprint and then you
pick up your gun and shoot, um,
or it slung and you do
like a five mile run.
And as soon as you step on the range,
it's like 500 targets.
You're just running down the line.
Um,
that's so,
I know,
and it feels normal for my heart rate
to be pounding so that I can't hear
anything besides my own beating heart
in my ears, sweat dripping into my eyes,
sweat dripping on my optics,
my grip being jacked up because it's
covered with sweat and you know,
a little bit of blood cause I tripped
and fell on my face, you know, like,
and that seems normal.
If I went to a range and shot
in like a vacuum, you know,
like where it's like air condition and
like guys, like, all right, um, no,
you can't shoot faster than one round a
second and know drawing from the holster.
So let's just, you know, have a good
time here. I would know what to do.
I'd be like, this is
really uncomfortable. Um,
can somebody just start screaming at me
and throwing something at me so I could
just at least shoot, you know,
100%. Um, the training for that,
my brother's a police officer.
My Dad's a police officer.
I went to the police academy in
[inaudible] 99. Um, and how was astounded?
I was a kid.
I was 21 years old.
I was astounded at how they
were not prepared for anything.
One was like, all right, how about this,
all 20 of you try to get cuffs on me?
Yeah. Didn't happen. No. Now my
wrists were bloody, you know,
I had a cough on my leg.
I have one cop on my arm but I had like
six or seven of them cuff together and
there's like,
there's like 18 or there's 12 of them
yet left and they didn't know what to do.
You know this is a 21 year old
kid and it's not their fault.
Just like you said, they just don't
have the training. Yeah. With that said,
if a cop tells you to get on the ground,
get on the freaking ground,
talk to them about it later and I get it.
Like you're,
you know the constitution so well and
you're like the greatest lawyer about,
you know, legal criminology, shut up,
lay down and just figure it out later.
Or have your lawyer do it.
If you can't afford a lawyer,
just have talked to sergeant afterwards.
Yeah.
Just give those guys more training.
And you got to do the right kind
of training. You got to do the,
I think you got to do force on force,
man on man training.
And it was the last time that a municipal
police department did a force on force
training. You should be doing
it all the time. All the time.
Cause we even heard of a department doing
it. That's horrible. Sim, Serta, whatever.
I mean, whatever. Whenever you're going
to use, you got to have people, humans,
other humans that are maneuvering on you,
that are reacting to you,
that are drawing on you or they're not,
or they're raising their hands or
they're pulling out their cell phone or
they're running scared. So when you
did force on force in the seals, um,
who do you use as your op for seals?
See other CIS dude.
And is there nothing better than,
I mean, who wants to win?
Everybody. Everybody wants to win.
So like we at Fort Bragg would use like
82nd airborne or would you use another
SF group? Dude. And that's, I mean,
if there are any second guy
like this is their chance,
they're going to do everything that
they can to shoot an SF guy. You know,
if it's a, if it's another SF guy,
then the, the level of competition,
that competitive nature like, oh, I'm
gonna, I'm gonna, we're going to do,
I'm an amble Shum.
We're going to crawl up
into the ventilation and try
to shoot him in the top of
their heads from the, from the
air conditioning. You know,
they're like taking quickie saws
and cutting the ventilation open.
I mean it's gangster gangster
and you know what? That's what's,
what's great about that is
guess what the enemy does.
The same thing with the moves does,
they're just not as good.
They built false walls, they build trap
trap doors. They do all that stuff.
And I was,
had a,
had a group that was going through their
land warfare training in the seal teams
and they actually failed.
And so we were retreading them make and
go make them them go through it again,
go through their FTX is their
field training exercise,
these big giant training exercises.
We've all kinds of chaos and they
were doing their first re retreads.
They're trying to pass
the exercise this time.
And I go out there and I'm listening to
their brief and I'm watching her duty to
rehearsal and they get done with rehearsal
and they all come together and the
senior enlisted guys kind of putting
out some word and he looks at me and he
goes, Eh, Hey Jocko, do you got
anything to say to these guys?
And I wasn't really expecting
it, you know, so I said, no,
this is 40 40 man seal element. And
I said, yeah, I got something to say.
You guys are going to go out
there against six other guys.
There's 40 of you, you guys
got machine guns, grenades,
and there's 40 of you.
I said, go out there.
And when they start shooting at you
hunt those motherfuckers down and murder
them. And they're like, yeah.
And so the troop walks away and
they're all fired up. And then the,
the senior enlisted guy in the senior
officers standing there and they said,
hey man, thanks for, thanks for, you know,
getting her guys fired up. I think that
really helped them out. And I said,
you should hear what I'm
about to go tell my guys,
which was my guys that were to go against
them because I would give my guys all
kinds of rewards. Anybody that they
could kill I, they would capture bodies.
Anybody could get into perimeter. They
would just completely what you're saying,
they were just completely mud.
Suck them,
draw them into the most
chaotic situations.
And the point of all this conversation
is that you're going against other human
beings and other human beings that
are going to do unpredictable things.
And that's what makes
the training challenging.
And that's what makes life challenging.
That's what makes these
situations challenging in a
real scenario is you don't
know what these people are going to do.
How many,
how many times have you been
dealing with some, you know,
enemy or or unknown and you're like,
what in God's name is this person
doing Iraq or Afghanistan? I didn't,
I didn't fight in Afghanistan. But in Iraq
you'd be looking at someone going, Oh,
this person is insane. What are they
doing right now? Why are they doing that?
They're going to die if
they, you know, it's, it's
crazy. Yeah. That's the thing about
humans is there humans, you know,
there's like points of
departure from logic, you know,
and they live in chaos and some
people can't even live without chaos.
And then we're going into a place where
cultures are different languages or
different,
you know,
what is the norm is different and we're
trying to enact what we think is normal.
And they're like, Bro, you're,
you're crazy. I'm like, no,
no, you're crazy. I'm like,
no, it's, yeah, it's
all poor cops. Yeah. So,
and you know what you can do if
you're a cop though and you don't,
you're forced doesn't have the money
for this or they're not doing this.
You can absolutely train. You can actually
absolutely train in Jujitsu, in MMA,
in fighting. So you get more comfortable
and more confident in those situations.
And the other thing I've said to
do in the past, his man, yeah,
I know it sounds lame,
but watch some youtube videos.
Watch some youtube videos of these, of
bike. The thing that I just described,
watch that youtube video and say,
I watched youtube videos in
combat and before combat,
you know what I watched before youtube?
I watch war movies, but documentaries.
Yeah. So I could watch these
guys in action and get,
see what was happening in their faces
because you can watch people on Youtube,
watch these perpetrators and start to
understand human nature better just by
watching what they're doing. Just grow
your mind, grow your brain a little bit.
And if you wanna get better at shooting
dry fire, yeah. I spend 90% of my,
my practice time of shooting,
um, without bullets in my gun,
you know?
And there's like a few grand masters
that are out shooting me right now. Yeah.
So dry fire.
Yeah.
These are good questions.
Yeah. The Internet,
the Internet's going onto number three.
This is not voting welfare time.
Okay. For those of you that don't know,
they recently removed bayonet training,
dammit. Yeah, I know Tim. I'm sorry.
But they removed bayonet training.
What makes the Green Grass Crow?
Do you know what makes the green grass go?
Thought it was banned at Cheyney?
No blood, blood, blood, blood.
If blood blood. That's what it
does. That's the motto. Okay.
And so the question was,
and I,
I guess I put this in here
just for entertainment value.
Would you have kept bay in that
trading in, that's the question.
And it says w does it sell warrior spirit
are not, um, Tim Kennedy your opinion,
please. I don't even want to dignify this
question with a response. I don't. Um,
it's so infuriating. So yeah, I get it.
We're not going to have
bayonets on 80 fours. You know,
we are in an army now that
tactics are dictating that,
that's not how we're going to train.
With that said,
during bayonet training,
it doesn't give you a thirst for blood,
but gives you an understanding
of what war's like.
And war is chaos. War is
hell. War is ugly wars,
disgusting wars, violent. Most of all,
it's violent and bayonet training while
you're running around a fixing your band
net and show what makes the
green grass grow blood but blood.
Nick's green grass grow.
Yeah, that sounds primal.
It is primal wars. Disgusting. And
you have to one, understand it.
And maybe have trained in it so that
you can appreciate what it's going to be
like.
So when you get there the
first time you've seen crazy
and chaos and anarchy and
rage is there is not there.
It's in training nuggets.
That's pussy. Exactly what we've
just talked about. You know,
it's exactly what we just
talked about and the other,
this is what that question
happened made me do
Tim crunched up is coconut water can ah,
within the statement of that question.
And the other piece of
this is Tim said in that,
I'll go ahead and call it
a little bit of a rant.
He said that war is crazy and chaotic
and evil and disgusting and savage and in
a way when you're in war
you have to become that
and you can't just become it from nowhere.
You have to develop that mindset
over time. Like I'm a bad ass.
That's not how it works. It doesn't work
that way. And so this type of training,
which I would call primal, truly, even
with people use that word all the time,
primal,
I'm actually using it in its
in its proper terminology,
usage,
primal training.
I'm taking a tool used to kill
things and attaching it tool,
a tool that's used to kill things.
Um,
so I can practice with a tool stacked
on top of another cool tool about how to
kill things. And then you're going
to take that thing and you're gonna,
you're gonna slam it into a
thing that looks like a person.
Yup.
Upset to get him used to it over and
over in your shoulders going to hurt and
your hands are going to hurt,
you know,
and like you're going to have
blisters and cut your hands up,
up against your gun.
He didn't realize you had to hold it that
way and you're made to make the mental
note that I'm not going to hold up
against my shoulder at that time next time
because I can't feel my shoulder. You
know, like these are good lessons learned.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
So let's keep the Bain at training,
bring it back.
Bring it back.
Next question,
can you instill the will to kill and
the will to die in soldiers without a
corollary? Nihilism. Yes.
And we get a direct answer from Tim
[inaudible] movie.
The next question we had kind of already
talked about it when we said, you know,
in the contrast of things like your life
I think is a personification of how to
do that.
You know,
if you can't have beauty with,
unless you know what ugly looks like.
True.
You know you can't have hot if you
don't know what cold feels like.
You can't have evil without good.
And I don't think that you
can teach people how to,
let's say if we're just teaching everybody
how to be like murderer killers, um,
you know, soldiers that can
just, we're not making robots.
We're showing them how to do something
and the reason that they can do it and
not be complete psychopathic murderers.
Occasionally one slips through.
I'm not saying that, but not very
often. It's because the humanity of us.
Like what, what is the thing that's
stopping us from killing, you know,
Echo Charlie here cause I'm highly
trained. You are, um, you know,
it's our humanity, you know, and
that's an and my appreciation,
my beautiful wife and my kids,
you know, and Loving Austin,
Texas and barbecue and motorcycles,
like that's normal to me.
So when I have to go and deploy and
see disgusting things and you know,
make mistakes like throwing grenades
into a room with women and then having to
live with that the rest of my life,
the reason that I'm still saying is
because I know what right is because of
ethics and morality and humanity. So yeah,
that's, that's how we, and you can do it.
It's because guys,
intelligent guys that,
that end up in units like the ones that
you were in can understand what the
difference is.
Yes. Yes. And I think that,
I think that this is
something new that is, again,
referring back to the culture of America
that a lot of people starts to slip
away.
But,
but you gotta remember those 2000 men
that lined up in rural California?
Sure. So, sure. There was a little
handful of them that were like, oh cool,
I'm going to go kill some people.
But there was a lot of people that saint
hammer to go out and protect freedom.
And so I think it's not only
something that you instill in,
you work on through the training and
like through the training that we just
talked about of stabbing or shooting
man shape targets or even better when
you're using simulation.
I mean you're shooting at other people.
It instills in you that you can do that.
But I think the values,
the American values that we're taught
as people growing up in this country are
they do respect life.
They do respect freedom and the the
right for the pursuit of happiness.
The things that you just talked
about, barbecues, motorcycles, wife,
kids,
those are things that we respect.
And I'm sure you've been in the situation.
I know I've been in it many,
many times of where you're taking the,
the man from the house,
either you killed them or
you're taking them away. Yeah.
And he's not going back
and he's not going back.
That's one of those things
where, you know, as just as a,
as a person you're looking at,
you're looking at the wife
and kids and you know,
you're kind of thinking yourself, well,
you know, you married the wrong guy,
but you do feel bad for them.
Absolutely. I mean, Hey, sorry, you're,
you're one of the most beautiful kids on
the planet. Your Dad's not coming back.
Oh,
your dad did the wrong thing.
But that dad would also hide behind
those kids were in a ball on that.
Absolutely. Strap a bomb
to him himself. Absolutely.
It's not the same type of human note that
it's not, you know, we are, it's not,
it's absolutely not. And that was
one of the most, that was the APP.
That was absolutely one of the
most disturbing things that,
that my guys would have to deal with,
was it surgeons using kids as shields
and thank God I had some really good
snipers that were able to kill guys
that were literally using kids as human
shields.
Yeah.
We had a guy walking towards us wearing
a bomb vest and we were using thermal
imagers and he had his kid in front
of him and he was trying to cover,
because we heat signature.
He was trying to cover himself so we could
get close enough and he's holding his
kid out. Like, take my kid, take my kid.
And the only reason was he was trying to
cover the distance so he could hurt us
with his bomb vest, which had glass
and shrapnel and nails and stuff.
Yeah. So period. His body, who's going to
use the bodies of water? Impulse charge.
Um, so no, it's not naive that I'm
saying they're not the same humans as us.
They're not, they do not fit
for me to see their same human,
you have to have the same value
for human life. Um, when you,
when I watch marines jump on top of Afghan
and Iraqi kids trying to protect them
from a bomb going off, not using
the kid as a bomb jumping on top of,
they're not American kids.
These are marines or navies or army
guys jumping on top of local kids.
Indigenous kids to save them different
understanding of what humanity is.
Yeah. So we get it. Your question.
Great question. You can do it.
Yep.
And you can definitely,
and we have done it as a nation and we
are doing it and we are continuing to do
it. I don't think we've had
a stronger military, um, ever
guys coming out of 15 years of war.
The experience and the training,
um,
while we have been shrinking for the past
five years, money wise, it's given us a,
we've had to fight wars the
war differently and now,
now I don't think there's,
I'm talking like Spartan Samurai or
even the World War Two era America.
Like that's the type of generation
of warriors that it's small.
It's like 0.5%. Um, but they're, they're,
yeah, yeah, no doubt.
Next question.
Number five.
Exactly.
How much better our green
berets then the seals at what
I think we have to the first
just like me at, at, you know,
21 years old. I didn't
understand the difference. Um,
so every special mission unit has a pretty
well defined mission and all of them
are different.
Um,
I would never want to get in a gunfight
with a bunch of navy seals on a boat,
anywhere near the water.
I mean,
within like miles of water, it
would be, it's just a catastrophe.
Um,
I also don't think that there's any been
on the planet besides special forces
that can do a force force multiplier.
Like weekend. You can take 12 of us,
you can drop us in Venezuela,
leave us there for six months.
And we probably overthrew the
government and place the president,
the new president in place and
running the economics, the Wa,
the power plants, the
commerce, um, transportation.
And like each of us, the 12 of us, uh,
have like married at least four or five
Venezuelans. It'd be like, that's, that's,
people don't understand like why
we have to speak other languages,
why we have to go through
economic and, um, you know,
geopolitical classes. It's
because we're different, you know,
like the missions are different. What
we're supposed to do is different. Um,
and
because of a different mission,
we end up with different products and
those products are a groups of dudes that
are the baddest dudes.
The planet on the planet
for what they have to do.
Yeah,
and I mean I left that question
in there for a couple of reasons.
Number one was because it was,
I thought it was kinda funny whoever
wrote whoever wrote that at a sense of
humor and you know the real
question, you know, which is still,
to me it was just about
really defining and I'd,
I'd say the exact same thing that you'd
say, I would add this to it, you know?
Yes. You know, you look at Rangers, you
look at seals, you look at Greenbrae, you,
you look at Mar soc and everyone's
got their own little specialty of what
they're really good at
and as a whole they'll,
there'll be better at that than the
other group. And then within the seals,
within the rangers,
within the,
within SF you got different
levels of guys that are in there.
I know you probably worked with some seals
that you thought, what are these guys?
And you probably work with some
guys that will, you said, damn,
I'd love to love to work with those guys.
And same thing with me.
I've worked with some SF guys that I,
to myself, man, these guys are just,
these guys are unbelievable.
I would do anything for these guys.
And sometimes you look at and you go, oh,
I wonder how these guys make it through.
You get to teams,
I get to teams that'd be like,
did you really pass selection dude,
that's one thing that's really hard for
the American public to understand is
that there is, and I've explained
this a bunch of times on the podcast,
that there's a bell curve.
Just like any other organization.
There's the top guys that are, you
know, bad, totally bad ass guys.
It just made it through.
And then there was a bunch of guys in
the middle that are totally solid guys
that get it done all the time. And
then there's a bunch of guys that just,
they barely got through and
they skate and that's, you know,
that's part of the way it is.
But one thing I can tell you for sure
is the special operations community.
I don't limit my respect for the
special operations community alone.
For me working with the army, the
conventional army guys, the Marine Corps,
marines, I, they're always
good. They're always good.
They're there consistently.
Your rifle company. Awesome.
Can I please work with you? Because you
just wanted like a bunch of pit bulls.
They'd been like locked up in a cage and
they just get prodded every once in a
while and maybe they go into like tear
something apart and they get thrown like
some raw meat and I call this just
good, you know, do I get it? What do I,
where do I get to kill to get
another piece of this meet?
The Marine Corps really is an outstanding
organization and then there's units
within the army that are unbelievably
just squared away professional,
and they have a heritage
behind them of glory,
for lack of a better word.
And so I'm a huge fan of the entire
military of the entire US military.
It'll be like you, are you proud
to be a seal? Yeah, I mean,
yeah. Yeah. I'm proud of proud to be
a green baret when army plays Navy,
like I don't know crap about
football, you know? But I'm like,
go just for crying out loud,
beat navy for once in this
decade or damn near century.
To be honest with you, I literally
don't care. And the biggest,
when we were in Ramadi working with
the army and with the Marine Corps,
those guys,
the sacrifices that they made were so
they were so just impressive date day
what these guys did and you know we had,
of course we do have better training,
we do have better gear and yet those
Marine Corps platoons and companies would
be out there doing, I mean they're,
first of all, they're living in the city.
You know,
we're going back to a little fog.
We got a little bit of video games and
internal walls. Huge walls. Great Gym.
Yeah, protein powder. Exactly.
Those guys don't do any of that.
They don't have any of that.
We airdropped a pallet of porn and
protein to a fire base that a bunch of
marines that like saved our lives when
we were like knocking on their gate at
two o'clock in the
morning where we weren't,
we were like 200 meters away and we
didn't want them all to murder us and they
were going to like,
please let us
in. Um, our air won't come pick
us up. And we got in there like,
you guys haven't eaten t
rats and they're like, Yay,
we've been pretty much a gun fight every
single night. And you're like, yeah,
they were taking you guys, carry
you guys. God bless all of them.
No doubt about that.
Next question,
we'll American Roe,
that's rules of engagement continue to
become more bureaucratic and cumbersome
or will the u s regained the will to win?
Ah, ah. First of all,
the guys there have the the will to win
and they'll, they'll wait to tell people,
shoot at them. Not like,
not like near them like you,
like as the Roe is. Um,
not like it used to be.
If somebody shot and you heard the
gunshot, that's like getting shot at,
but now we have to be able to
actually say that we were shot at,
that's like bullets
snapping past your head.
Like that's hearing the Wiz and
then the crack that's close.
That's what we pretty much
have to have. Um, Roe. So,
so just let me put some context
around that because we don't have,
not everyone that listens.
This is in the military.
Let me put some context
around what Tim just said.
That's freaking ridiculous.
That means you're waiting until you're
about to get killed before you take
action.
If you're waiting for rounds,
because when rounds are snapping over
your head that that means you're,
you're under suppressive fire just about,
you can no longer maneuver.
So this is like waiting
until for a civilian.
This is waiting until the knife is at
your throat before you decide to defend
yourself. That's, that's what
Tim's talking about. Yeah.
It'd be like a salesman being like your
commission based salesman and you see a
potential client come in,
but you're not allowed to engage him.
You're not allowed to. You actually have
to wait, let him pick up the product
and then walk over to you and ask if he
can buy it and almost have the customer
be walking out the door.
Had he already set the product down right
before you're allowed to talk to him,
that's when you're allowed to engage him.
Does that make sense from
a sales perspective? Yes.
That does echo Charlie wisdom thrown down.
I'm so not good. Not Good. Uh, we'll see.
First of all,
the rules of engagement,
there are not going to be the same here.
So I think some places like Afghanistan
and Iraq have been capitalizing on and
now Syria on our rules of engagement.
I know Africa is Africa is like, okay,
we know the Americans are only allowed
to go to the last concealed cover
position and they're not allowed
to directly engage in less.
They have been actively
fired. So they'll be like, oh,
there's the Americans over there.
We're not going to shoot at
them so they can't shoot back.
We'll just kill all the Africans
who they're there to help.
They're like intentionally doing this
and they're pretty clever about it.
The book of Romp.
Um,
but then right now with
the radicalized cells here,
the fanatic Muslims that
think that they're going to
come here and be able to do
that node, Bro, remember Pearl Harbor,
remember the Alamo,
remember nine 11 shit will be different
if you think you're going to come here
and play around
Roe
will not exist. Nope. No, not here.
Don't, don't, don't.
There's a lot of political correctness
that steer stuff from time to time
gets people killed. It
does. It does. You know,
one of the things that's coming
up a lot in the news right now,
and we got asked them questions about it,
is women women coming into
combat roles inside the military,
which, you know, first of all,
credit to the women that have served
in the wars.
And I've seen women,
I've seen women in Ramadi rolling out
on Cassie facts to go out and help my
guys. Yeah. God bless him.
Fearless, fearless, brilliant,
awesome. Totally capable of their
respective jobs. Full credit.
And then there's a limitation in my
opinion as to where you would want to
intentionally assigned women too,
is that women could do that.
We could never do that is true.
I'm in South America.
I want to get some Intel.
I can go into a bar and work it for
a month before I get one informative.
I just spent, you know, $20,000
of taxpayer dollars. Yeah.
You stick girl in there an
hour. Yep. Has, she has 10.
She like, you suck, you suck,
you suck, you suck. You suck.
I'm awesome at this.
I'm
just put a hundred pounds on her back
and throw out of the back of an airplane.
I love women.
Yeah.
Their legs are going
to break. Yeah. It's a,
just a biological factor of
what is it?
Muscular skeleton. Anatomy.
Anatomy. There you go.
Thank you.
And uh,
they're built differently and thank God
they're built differently cause I could
never give birth know, eat their
way. Tell her that I are there.
We are like what? What right
now is like the, you know,
we were talking about at the
pinnacle of exercise. Uh, well,
one really good way to judge
would be the crossfit games.
Very well rounded athletes that have
to have strength, endurance, agility,
et cetera. And are there different
standards for men and women?
There are different standards
for men. Water. Yeah.
So are we going to have different
standards in let's say special forces
selection? I would hope not. Okay.
So if we had the same standard,
um, you had given an example
of the crossfit games.
Yeah, I mean it was, it was interesting.
I was watching the finals of the
crossfit games. It was last year I think.
And the event the made,
the finals men went first,
it was 10 guys or something and they
came out in the first they had to do
multiple physical activities. The first
one was a pegboard link. What you had,
it was her heart. Yeah.
There are the wrestling room.
They had him in the wrestling room.
You had him in school and you
couldn't go home until you did it.
And this one was,
I want to say it was 15 feet tall.
So it's a pretty tall pegboard and
they had to sell. The guys come out,
they have to go up a peg board and
back down. They get done with that.
They have to jump on a,
on a rower and row a certain amount
of calories and they got hers.
Then they moved down the line and
they're picking up and cleaning.
I think they are cleaning or cleaning
and jerking weights that were increasing
in weight as they went towards the end
and there was a 10 minute maximum time to
complete this evolution. So the
guys come out, boom, they go,
they all go hard. It's hard. They climbed
the pegboard, they come down the road,
the road, they lifted weights,
they're done. Everybody finishes.
They give the guy in the
first place. Okay, cool.
Then it's the girl's term and the,
and they have it set up for the girls.
They're doing the same thing. They
make the weights a little bit lighter,
but they have the same basic concept
and the girls come out and these girls,
they look as big and
strong as I do or you do,
and I'm not kidding. These girls
are beasts. They're amazing across.
The athletes are beautiful and they come
out and out of the eight or 10 girls
that goes into the first
thing and hits the pegboard,
only one of them can make it up.
They're tough.
And the other seven or eight or
nine athletes can't even get up it.
And then the girl,
it took her so long to get up the peg
board that when she got to the roller,
she was exhausted.
She got done with the rower and she
didn't complete the rest of the course
because she ran out of the 10
minute time limit. Yeah. And to me,
I'd never really had thought too much
about the physicality. I always figured,
you know what? You get a girl
that's in good enough shape.
Maybe they could make it through some
of the training that is required for
special operations.
But when I saw that,
it really did leave an impact on
me mentally of how different it is.
And I'll tell you another thing.
I was at my gym several years ago
and I hadn't rolled with a girl,
a Jujitsu for a long time.
Right.
Maybe played around and all of a sudden
we had a girl that was coming into town
that was a,
a black belt in Jujitsu and was a multi
time world champion and great technique.
And, and so I said to me
when I was going to run,
so we were on the mat and she's
like, you know, hey, you want a role?
And in my mind I thought to
myself, okay, you know what?
I got to bring my a game right now. Yeah.
I mean this girl's a world champion.
She's not a small girl, you know,
I mean, she's 160 165 pounds.
And you know, if you make a mistake
against 165 pound black belt,
you're going to tap. That's it. So I
say to myself, you know what, I gotta,
I gotta be careful.
I've got to kind of bring my a game here.
And we shook hands.
And as soon as I like grant and was g,
as soon as I touched her
g and she touched mine,
I just realized there's no way that
she could ever submit me. Yeah. I mean,
unless I just was completely,
it just wasn't going to happen
because she just didn't have,
she just doesn't have the strength.
Yeah. Well, I want to talk about that.
Um, you know, how long have you been doing
martial arts school? 20 something years.
I was just talking about
this the other day.
Like we can within a second
of touching somebody,
have an idea about what they
can do. I mean, within seconds,
like this isn't just like you,
you know, in this misogynistic,
sexist way. Um, we're
all in with his girl. Um,
she doesn't have a chance after I touched
her, that's not what it was. This,
this is like one of the best grapplers
on the planet and a navy seal and amazing
black belt and an instructor
that legitimately had the row,
the revelation,
like realized that this isn't possible.
Yes. And Actually Echo, you described a
story last week. The first time he ever,
he was a white belt and the first
time I ever trained with Dean lister,
as he said, as soon as he touched him, as
soon as you locked up with him, he goes,
Oh shit. I can't do anything. It's this
guy. And so I failed to mention that,
that yes,
when you're a grappler,
as soon as you tie up with
someone second you go, Oh, oh,
this is gonna be tough.
This guy doesn't really know anything.
You even know things like, Hey, I've got
to watch out for this guys, you know,
head position or he's really good.
You can feel all that just by a clinch.
Yeah. And so, yeah, that's what
I, so I should've stated that,
but as soon as I made contact with
her, I said to myself, wow, I was, uh,
I was mistaken because this is no factor.
So let's say one in a thousand women could
make it through one of our respective
selections,
um,
which I think might be a
little unrealistic. Honestly,
I'm thinking more of
like one in 5,000 could,
could do it. That still doesn't
mean that they should be there.
I'm not saying they
shouldn't or they should.
We have to see what it can't be
is dictated that we have to do it.
And then second,
we can't change anything.
Otherwise it undermines the
entire idea of being special.
If you have a special unit and there's
a special requirement to be there,
that requirement has to stay the same.
If you're going to then
change that requirement,
you've then changed the unit and then
you've undermined the woman earning her
chance to be there.
It's going to change the chemistry.
It's going to change how the
team is going to function. Um,
not for the worse, not for the better. We
just don't know what that's going to be.
Yeah. And it's not just, first of
all, it's not just special operations.
It's not just military.
I mean it's any job that
requires physical strength.
That's what I'm talking about.
I'm talking about physical strength.
And if you can't maintain,
if you can't do what the job requires,
if you're a firefighter and you can't
pull yourself up a ladder with Karina, uh,
80 pound rope on your back or
80 pound hose on your back,
you shouldn't be able to have that job.
And yeah,
so it's just one of those, it's one of
those really tough things because, hey,
I got, by the way, I got
three daughters, right?
I got one son and three daughters.
Believe me,
I want my daughters to be
successful and I want whatever,
have every opportunity they possibly can.
But I'll tell you what,
something else I do not want.
My daughter's going onto the battlefield.
If they can't pull one of their buddies
out from the street, if they're,
if they've been shot. How
much do you weigh? 230 pounds.
So you way to 65 to 70 with kid
on, oh, more than that. Yeah.
Our kids gotten lighter. Okay.
So like my, my plates, um,
my first deployment or 24 pounds,
now they weigh five pounds.
The whole thing, like the actual
Bot just to place. Yeah. Yeah.
It's like, so you're saving, you're
saving off, torn on tears in there. Okay,
nice. Just stuff's getting
lighter. Nice. Yeah.
But they're not going to pick up
285 pounds and I'm can happen.
It's not going to happen.
I'm normally a 220 pound guy and I love,
I'm a Garan grenade carrying maniac.
So while my kid is normally like 20,
30 pounds, I had didn't have a
backpack with like 20 grenades.
Cause sometimes I'm like I'm
going to Flash Bang this room.
And sometimes I'm like,
I'm going to Frag it cause I
don't want to deal with sin side.
You know,
you get guys like you and I appreciate
when someone like yourself takes a
certain artistic perspective when it
comes to combat and you say to yourself,
you know what? These little
fragmented aids, I liked them.
I like what they do. They're
so little, they're so mean.
They're so little and they're so
brave. And I liked that. I like,
I like people that have that artistic
expression that they utilize it combat to
express themselves. It's a beautiful
thing. So for an opportunity,
but that's,
that's the uh,
that's the political
correctness and bureaucracy,
bureaucracy in the military.
Not a good thing.
Geez. Here's another one.
How do you stay positive?
Having seen the absolute worst
in humanity? No Man. Easy.
I have a beautiful Brunette.
I'm going to do a huge alliteration here.
Beautiful Brunette busty babe
that's banging in the bikini
that will drink bourbon with me.
Boom. Yeah, boom. Yeah. Nice.
Um,
so yeah,
I have heard kids in women's scream
that I threw a grenade into the room.
They're having their dad shoot
from, um, get nightmares from it.
Uh,
yeah.
Yeah. I've seen doc donkeys go down
wells because the village lied to us.
Yeah.
I've watched bombs get dropped on entire
villages where I knew that there are
people like not bad people.
They were good people,
near bad people and watched
the all the buildings crumble.
Um,
I love life.
I love my wife. I love
my kids. I love a sunset.
I appreciate art. I play the piano.
I wish I could appreciate beer.
Don't have a palate for it.
But like everything about life is that
much sweeter because I know how nasty and
ugly it is.
And if at any point,
I forgot why I fight and I forgot
what Wright was and I forgot,
um, what humanity is, I'm done.
The moment where I was like,
I want to go kill something.
I'm good at it, I'm good at war,
there's nothing else I'm good at.
And there's that temptation
because you're good at something.
You want to go do more of it to
go and spend time doing that.
If I ever had that,
well that realization that I'm
actually doing that, I'm done.
I turned my gun in, I'd go be
a salesman, I tried sell Kias,
I don't care. Now that I'm talking
smack about Tia Kias, I'm just,
or a Hyundai whatever.
And this is a subject that comes up that
I think people want to understand in
the civilian world.
And you've definitely nailed a
perspective that I think most guys feel.
And I would say on top of that
is that war wallet does expose
you to the worst part of humanity
in my mind.
For ever.
I W I don't think I will ever see
anything as moving or as beautiful
as
men
rolling out into a horrible
place day after day,
night after night,
risking their lives directly,
indirectly
for their country,
for the civilians that are there
that they're trying to protect
and for each other. Yeah. And to,
to go to memorial service after memorial
service and realize that these are,
and again, you know, I always try and
remind everybody that listens to this,
that when I say memorial service,
I'm not talking about a dog
tag and some body in a uniform.
I'm talking about a kid
talking about person
and a person that
sacrificed everything in,
in everything,
everything they are
and everything they ever will be.
And so yes, war, we'll show
you the worst part of humanity.
But that right there is an
incredible part of humanity.
And I don't care about the politics of it,
I don't care about any of that.
But you're talking about men that will
give their lives for their friends.
Yeah.
And when I have that
in the back of my mind,
then that makes it very easy
for me to stay positive.
Very easy for me to wake
up in the morning and say,
I'm going to do my damn this
today to live a good life.
Yeah.
And do some good things
and trying to honor those guys.
Okay.
So I don't think war makes you worse.
I think war makes you better.
No services. Those memorials.
They're not like just some dude
had a,
a young,
a young guy and his wife was like,
you know, why don't you bring them
back to me? You know, do you want,
it's like to lose him, you know?
Do you know what we had? You know,
you didn't know him. I was
like, bitch, please. I didn't.
I sat there and took it,
you know, like what do you,
what do you think we sit there and talk
about as we're staring at a tree for 12
hours. Yeah. You know, I know
what your farts smell like woman,
you know, I know what his favorite
panties were on you. You know,
I know every single kid name of it all
through your kids when their birthday is,
you know, you don't think, you think
you know him better than I know him.
How much time did you spend with them
in the past five years? You know,
day and night,
60 hours straight taking his blood,
you know,
being covered in it.
Like we know like this isn't
just some memorial, you know,
did the sacrifices that you're
talking about? Yeah, it's,
there's a different level of, you
know, we're talking about intimacy,
the brothers and when we say it's about
the dude standing next to us, it's the,
it's not just subdued, you know, it's
not some cliche line in a movie. Yeah.
Like these are dudes when
we say would die for him,
it's for a reason.
It's because we've no,
it never known somebody that close and
never will forever and they're the best
dudes on the planet.
Yeah,
you're right over there. Echo
Charlie. Yes. Getting heavy for sure.
But kind of used to it though for sure.
Used to do when he starts talking
I'm just like what is the next word?
There's too much space cause
I can't take it anymore. Shit.
Yeah.
All right,
let's bring it back to you a little bit.
I won't say it later question,
but a little bit of a,
of an easier question.
If a non fighter wants to
learn physical self defense,
where and how can they start?
First of all in your head,
stop calling yourself a non fighter,
whatever that is.
Every bore,
every dude that comes out of the vagina
and in my opinion has the capability to
be a fighter if he just so chooses to be.
And I think every dude is a fighter.
So first turn the switch on. Stop being
a pussy. All right. Sorry. Go ahead.
No,
that's actually a factual information.
Or men are predators were predators.
Yeah,
we've got the dates right here. The eyes,
our eyes are in the front of our head.
Right? Thought other than the top or the
side. They're not on the side over here.
We're watching out for the attack or the
Predator. The Predator. Yeah. So you're,
you are correct. I can see wait right
here. I can't even see what's right here.
I turned my head, so yeah, that's okay.
That's good. Start with a mindset.
Where are you going from there? Um, so w
you're asking the question. It's really,
to me, just a choice.
Anything's better than nothing.
And then of the whatever that anything is,
then there's degrees of better.
There's, I don't think there's
like a right or wrong, you know,
you could do Krav Maga, you could do Muay
Thai, you can box, you can do Jujitsu.
Hell,
crossfit has self defense now,
but anything is better than nothing.
But then the degrees of what that is get,
you know,
I think a little bit better for me,
the foundational martial arts are always
the best to start wrestling, boxing,
Muay Thai, Jujitsu. Yep. You know, you,
you step up a against a guy that has a
little bit of knowledge in any one of
those therapy in the ass and let alone
if he has a little bit in all of them or
he's really good at one of them.
In this case you're asking by,
he'd go into sleep. Yup. Yup. Or you've,
you've heard me say the same exact
thing actually. Yeah. Do you do too?
I would say start with Jujitsu.
Uh,
the reason is you already have a natural
defense for someone trying to strike
you. And that is runaway.
You know, if someone said, if
you're coming at me and you,
you got a knife or whatever, I'm going
to run from you. Yeah. It's okay.
It's defense. I'm being defensive.
I'm running away from you. That sucks.
No, no. I'm saying like if somebody came
100% green with you, I was like, hey bro,
give me your wallet. And just like gotta
catch me first. Yeah, exactly. Exactly.
Travels a few [inaudible] have to defend
yourself is if I grab a hold of you and
now you've got to know how to
grapple some kind of grapple, right?
You gotta be able to get out of that.
And so that's why I say start with Jujitsu
and then for me boxing only because I
think it's easier to learn than when
we tie failing and you want to learn a
little bit of basic striking and then moy,
Tai and wrestling, I
mean, you can just get,
start getting into them too.
But there's the,
the beautiful thing is in America right
now, there's all these places to train.
There's a Jujitsu school and
every, every city, every quarter.
I mean I live in San Diego,
so I guess it's actually
completely out of control here.
I could have taken you on a tour of like
74 totally legit to do Jitsu places in
San Diego and now they all have
Moitai. They all have boxing, all that.
I mean everyone's doing everything.
Yeah.
And so what do you think about like
the self defense oriented martial arts?
So would you be talking about like Krav
Maga? I think those are good augments.
So I, I think once you have a base of
Jujitsu, boxing, wrestling and Muay Thai,
then I think cool now learns from Krav
Maga because they're going to start
looking at weapons or start looking
at knives. I think it's good,
but I think from the beginning I
would rather invest my time in the,
the big four. Yep. I understand. Agree
to get the foundational pillars. Right,
right. Then you can build anything
you want on that. Speaking of that,
there's someone that
asked about SD response.
I'd like to hear more about SD response
and if Jocko is going to be involved
at lunch today, he took me to
barbecue and I was like, dude,
you have to come to one of these. She's
like, I do these. And I was like, I know,
but ours are filing in Texas,
you know?
Then when we're done we'll hop
in a helicopter and go play.
You got you lowered me down
to Texas like 47 times today.
It's going to happen as shit. Like
everything. I like food shooting,
working out Jujitsu
machine guns. I mean, yeah.
I said I might not come back
once I get down there and we'll,
we'll take a camera and we'll fill most
of it and you're going to see Chaco,
like we're going to hook him into
the side of a little bird. And um,
so people get mad sometimes when
I talk about hunting, you know,
until you, um, come and
do it. Shut your face.
Um,
the farmers,
their pay us to either exterminate the
animals or I we've used when you're going
to come and stay at my house,
yeah, we're gonna eat elk. Yeah,
we're going to eat bison.
You know,
we're gonna eat some remarkable bear.
Nice. And, um, not a lot of
wild pig because the pig,
their tastes like toilet.
Um,
well I get mad when you talk about hunting
because I want to be doing it instead
of you. Ah, tell you that. Talk about,
talk about,
because the people,
the people that might not know
about the SD response thing,
the sheepdog response
sheepdogs, it's all about, um,
so sheepdog,
it was a phrase coined by,
um,
Colonel Grossman,
and he used it as this metaphor
that, um, you've got the sheep,
which is like the normal people and they
just kind of cruise around eating grass
and living their lives and they're naive
about the predators that are out there.
Then you have the wolfs and those are
the things that want to get the sheep
grass doesn't taste good when he got
canines, the using your hair. And, um,
so the wolves want to eat the sheep and
there's nothing that would stop them.
And this is in the reality of kind of,
I think the millennial generation
is we've got a bunch of sheep. Um,
well I mean if like the
sheep war really tight pants,
flannels had beards and
never carried an axe before.
Didn't know how to change your oil,
didn't know how to break down a gun,
didn't know how to clean an
animal, let alone kill it.
Um, if those were the sheep,
then that's what we have.
The thing that separates them is the
sheep dog and the sheepdog is genetically
more similar to the
wolf than anything else.
It has the same natural instincts.
Um,
the only differences that it likes
sheep not dead or blood in their mouth.
It likes keeping the sheep alive.
Um,
so that's what sheepdog is.
We give people skills to make them be
the hardest person somebody ever tries to
kill.
So if you're going to go and get in a gun
fight with somebody that's come from a
sheepdog course,
you better be damn good.
If you think you're going to go hands
on and start tussling with a guy that,
or a lady that's finished sheepdog better
plan on it being bloody and violent.
Cause when they come and they
way they finish that course,
we have requirements for you
to finish that course. Um,
people are afraid of their own blood,
but not one of our students.
They've seen it, they've seen it on top
of the person that they're training with,
you know, um, and it's not this
frightening thing. It's like cool.
The fight just got started. Uh,
so that's what it is. It's, um,
we are putting confidence and technique
and skills into people about being hard
to kill.
Yeah.
And I took a look at some of the videos
and stuff and it's something that people
have been actually asking me for and
I'm in the process of setting it up.
But I think
that the videos I saw
looked awesome and you know,
anybody that can get to one of those
courses no matter where you are,
cause it's the, it'll cover
anybody on the spectrum. Right.
Like I could go and I'm going to
get something out of it. Yeah. Andy,
someone on the complete other end of the
spectrum like echo could go. Not True.
Can I bring guys like Jake
signs? Alex Acosta. Um,
Tim Bhutto,
Blake Hays.
So just in that group we have a couple
of professional competitive shooters.
Um, so every time I do one, you're
getting better. I'm getting better.
Yeah. Like I'm trained with Alex Acosta.
Right. But my point was you have,
you have women that ever shot a gun before
in that classroom. Is that right? Yeah.
Yeah. And you both are first. We've
only done two civilian classes.
We'd been doing military and
law enforcement for a minute
and we're like, man, we,
we, it's unfair in this
society that we're at now.
It's sad that we have to give, like
we see the things that, you know,
I think it would be a huge disservice
for you not to share the wisdom like you
do, um, to a society that
is now vulnerable. So that,
that was like,
it's selfish for us not to do this.
And it's,
I think inhumane.
So when our first two civilian courses,
both courses had people that
had never shot a gun before.
Now I'm not encouraging you to come to a
sheepdog course if you've not ever shot
a gun before. Cause it ends up being
a huge, um, painted them but for us,
because then don't have to put somebody
with you the whole entire time.
And that instructor could have been
used to help other people get better.
So it's a little bit shallow, selfish. So
if you're gonna come to a shoot course,
I'm not going to say no. You know, you
got to learn this stuff to say alive.
You have people on trains that just
walk out of bathrooms with machine guns.
They w they go do a Christmas party in
San Bernardino and start mowing people
down. Like this is a different era,
right? Like we can't, we can't.
And and the, and the cops
and law enforcement cannot
be everywhere all the time.
And the, what's the average response
time in America for minutes? Six minutes.
And that's if you're in like a night
in a city with a lot of cops in it,
you go out to some rural
area. Yeah, you're talking
days. We're talking like 20.
Yeah. So you are like it
or not. Here's the reality.
You are your first line of defense and
you might be your only line of defense.
So invest in yourself
and learn some skills.
Have you got money and you're going out
there and you're buying a $2,000 gun.
Don't buy a $600 gun and then come
spend 1400 bucks and train with you.
You know, cool and play jockey.
You know like you, you need,
you need a $500 gun and $100 site
until you get to a pretty high level,
you know,
like stop wasting your money,
get the skills,
get the skills.
What I think that thing a sound awesome
and I'm sure I'll be doing something
with it.
Having my good times.
Okay.
Next question for both of you.
I would like to know the most
influential book and why the,
you've got many influential books.
Okay.
Yeah, I mean one book,
I think the idea of always searching
for knowledge is more important than the
actual single book.
I mean I read,
right now I'm reading this
book on the war of electricity.
It was AC versus DC.
Huge Electric Chair.
Yeah. It's a great story. Like it's a
great story. It's almost split the nation.
Yeah. They're like direct, current or
alternate current, but w direct current,
so much more powerful because
I can take a little bit, uh,
12 volts and I can kill an elephant,
but it takes 120 volts to do
the same thing. So, you know,
Edison, you know, he put it,
he backed the wrong thing and
he was too proud to admit it.
Um,
and so I'm learning a ton one about maybe
putting your belief in the wrong thing
and how you had, how
damaging it can be, um,
and how much damage you can do it
if you're that fix gold stubborn,
you know,
or just set in your ways and how
important it is to be able to always be a
fertile soil that searching
for more nutrients. You know,
there's,
there's no doubt about that.
And I think that that's one thing that's
been common out of this podcast is I
got soaked cause I review books on the
podcast and I get all these people now
tell me, read this book, read this book.
I'm reading more right now than I did
when I went to college and I was an
English major in college. I got people
who just sent, I'm getting books,
I'm getting books in the mail.
Oh, somebody want a troopers.
Just sent me a lone wolf. He's
like, Hey, I sent you a book.
This is two volumes,
so 700 pages each.
I said, man, that's going
to be on my list, but that's
going to be a brutal read.
I mean that's going to be heavy, but
yeah, absolutely. Reading all the time,
uh, is what it definitely
happened to me. I know,
we know echo has been on a
reading rampage, big time,
direct result of the podcast.
A nice story.
Anybody adding been asked this question?
I,
there's only one book that I refer to
all the time as the most influential book
I've ever read, which is about
face by Colonel David Hackworth.
And I've read it many times and I always
go back to it because it's a great book
about a war in leadership and
that's why I read it all the time.
But I got it.
Stack of books to read fiction
ever. Barely. So I actually read,
I split my time between fiction
and nonfiction and I get a ton.
I love, especially in the
Times that we're in right now.
I'm reading like French
Revolution era stuff.
I love learning about the
why of the thing. You know,
why countless times the French people
over through the government why they went
and they started beheading the rich class,
um, why they went and hung
or then built the GTA,
or if there's the why of the thing,
not the, how I get that, you know,
and whether it's like Alexander Dumas
or Victor Hugo, you know, it's like, um,
I get a lot out of that. And then I
also get a ton of wisdom, you know,
when I'm reading like the
Count of Monte Cristo,
when that priest was
digging with, um, you know,
who would then in the metamorphosis as
he's crawling through those tunnels and
emerges then as the count, the
amount of wisdom that, that, that,
that priest gave him
about ruling government's.
Um, I look at that for our government
right now, right. And it's profound.
So,
um,
I don't limit myself while I love reading
nonfiction and learning, you know, like,
I like the book I'm reading right now.
Uh,
all based in real fact,
marketing, science,
engineering. Um, I love going back
and it's not, it's not brain candy,
you know, it's not, I'm just sitting
here chewing on, you know, some crap. Uh,
did I get any reading romance novels
I get a lot from, so I split my time
between fiction, nonfiction, 50, 50. Yeah,
I don't. And I sometimes I'll try, look,
somebody will tell me about
a great fiction book. Yeah.
And I might give it a try,
but in my perspective, you
know, you're talking about the,
what was the why I always like to
figure out, like when I read about war,
I like to think about the psychology
of what's happening with the guys,
especially from a leadership and a
follower perspective of what guys were
thinking.
Because that to me it was always the most
fascinating thing about what was going
down was we got to get
all these guys to do this.
Or my boss is trying to get me to do that.
And how does that work in
these most intense scenarios?
So from Tim Kennedy,
get out there and read.
Next one,
love to hear Tim's thoughts on combatives
how grappling changes in full kit with
multiple people,
et cetera.
Hmm hmm.
Hmm.
Uh,
it doesn't change and you know,
like the basic fundamentals of how
to punch somebody's remains the same.
You give, so like the bodies
to me as a chassis, right?
It doesn't matter what you put on me,
you can give me more or
you can take away less. My,
this chassis is still a
killing machine right now.
The only thing that changes
is my lethality. The type
of damage that I can do. Um,
there's like a Honda Civic,
right?
Just it can go fast or it can run down
the road and gets 38 miles to the gallon.
Right.
But you can change out the exhaust or you
can put some nitrile or you can put in
some wheels,
you know,
eventually what was just a vehicle
that could drive down the road,
can drive down the road kind of fast.
So it's just a basic chassis that
you can expand or detract from.
So this chassis, this particular one,
um, so I don't normally head, but people,
if I'm wearing an ops core helmet,
I'm ahead button machine. I was like,
what'd you say to me? Headbutt
you know, and I was like, oh yeah,
we're gloves that have like
carbon fiber across the knuckles,
brings the bitch slapped back,
you know, like, no. Again,
I'm not being a misogynist.
I do not encourage people
to ever bitch slap.
And I realized that's a sexist term.
But if I ask you question
and you lied to me,
know that I want to hurt
you in the first place.
I believe the politically correct
term is the Stockton slap.
This talks to slap the
back of the pimp slap.
Okay. Um, or maybe more. So
really it doesn't change.
The skills remain the same.
You're just adding kind of the damage
that I can do with the more equipment that
you give me. Yup. That's
it. Pretty simple question.
I don't even have anything to add.
Next one.
Cheaters,
PD use in MMA and elsewhere.
And then plan of action.
Defense for homeless person.
Just threw a bunch of questions in there.
His work on range 15. Oh yeah. And we
definitely got to talk about range 15.
I'm naked in it. That's, so originally I
was supposed to be wearing a loincloth,
um, but had been sweating so much
that when I tore my pants off,
so went the loin cloth. It
was like actual real, um,
skin of an animal and it was like
furry, uh, and skin when you get it wet.
Hunters know this, it deteriorates.
And as did my loin cloth,
so when I tore my pants off
to fight Zombie Randy couture,
I'm not giving anything away
because we really do fight. And, um,
so with my loin cloth,
so tell people about the movie naked
range 15 and Tim Kennedy naked,
um,
is going to challenge everybody's
perspective as to what a veteran is. Um,
I think there's,
I don't know what it is where people
look at veterans and they're like,
they're damaged goods,
um,
PTSD or actual physical impairment or,
uh, just the mentality of they've
gone through training that I haven't,
so that person's now a freak.
Uh,
not even dimension the, the climate
that I think is encouraged from
the government to treat us differently.
Um,
this movie is not very gingerly.
Got To cover those topics.
It will absolutely offend what
I think to be about 70% of this,
of this country. From what you
told me about the movie today,
I'm going to go ahead and up that number
to 90% and I'll tell you what, what,
when you were telling me about the
movie today, so what's, who made it?
What's his name? Primary.
So Matt, best at best,
Nick Paul Massano Matt Best owns a company
called an article 15 range or up is
our company. So that's why it's called
range 15, article 15 and ranger out, um,
pretty clever name. Very, very creative
army for us. That's army. Sorry.
Listen,
you fell a sophisticated cosmopolitan
and we all were officers in the military.
Um,
so uh,
Matt and nick or the masterminds behind
that, Matt is our main character.
He's our hero. Numero Uno. Right.
And He's good looking, man. I,
I've seen a couple of things that
he's done. He's obviously a funny guy.
And they put together this movie,
they did it through Indie Gogo,
which is some sort of a crowd funding,
a deal where you get money from people,
you know, and the, it's the public,
the public just gives money.
And you raised how much money?
I've got a few million,
a few million dollars to make this movie.
And then we had like people
from then we had like sponsors,
people that are in the community
that believed in the product,
like Gerber knives, who I'm sponsored
by, um, weapons manufacturers.
We had like people that make,
um,
Hazmat suits a coffee maker.
Awesome. And they're like,
we just want this movie to be made.
And then people in Hollywood wanted,
when they saw that we were like breaking
the mold because Hollywood is stuck.
It's a cesspool of inhumanity
and selfishness and greed.
That's what that industry
is, that it's, it's,
it's damn near eval when everybody that
has been suffered has been suffering by
that.
The Organization of what Hollywood is,
saw that a bunch of veterans that
didn't give anything and we're like,
we're gonna make a movie.
And it's going to be the most offensive
movie and everybody in this whole city,
Hollywood is going to hate it. They
started helping us to like, wait,
it takes a few hundred
thousand to rent a red camera.
We'll give you three for you to use.
The whole time we had guys that
were like $2,000 a day type,
um, directors and directors of photography
that would step up and be like,
I'm just going to volunteer my time
for three weeks. And you're like,
so we can't pay you the 50 grand for a
week that you normally make or the for
the, for the shot. And
they're like, it's cool. Yeah.
So there is something, when you were
telling me about the movie today,
this is what I think about
what you told me.
There is something about special
operations community that is very secret.
It is something that has never been
revealed to the public view. It,
it is something that is outside. It's
even beyond top secret. This is cla.
Highly classified information
in a special operations can.
We might have to kill you.
Echo Charlie and what it is and it's
something that I seriously have never seen
come out.
The public,
you guys talk about missions they've done
but no one has ever talked about this
fact and that is that the
special operations community
has an insane sense of
humor,
insane and it,
the reason it doesn't get released is
because it's in my belief it is not
previously been and any way
remotely acceptable by the human,
by the normal people,
by the populous and what you told me
that some of the scenes you told me about
today,
they are going to shock.
They are going to shock and everybody
from SPEC ops and most guys in the
military going to look at him and they're
going to laugh and they're going to,
they're going to think it's funny.
They're going to be laughing so hard
and just going to seem normal to us.
It's going to be seeing older than
me. I'll be like, oh yeah, classic.
Of course you're doing that,
but I think like you said,
I mean Hollywood is going to
be beside themselves. They are.
They are going to be completely beside
themselves. This may start a revolution.
I hope so. This may start
a revolution and I, I, I,
this may start a revolution with what you
told me about it today and I know that
everybody that's us in this podcast is
going to go seek gonna go see this thing
immediately and I think
it's going to be phenomenal.
So I'm looking forward to it
when it comes out.
The movie is called Range 15 and
it's going to be in general release.
It's gonna be
the nurse. Yeah. Yeah. June,
June 15th so the premiere,
is it the Military Gi film festival.
Memorial Day weekend.
And that's going to be in Washington DC.
And then two weeks later
is the wide release.
Right now we're in eight or 900 theaters.
That's just gonna keep going and growing.
That's awesome.
PDS stop using them.
Yeah,
pretty straight forward.
I hate him.
I get a lot like
you have a big Mesomorph Physique,
right?
And somebody looks at you, they're
like, oh man, look at that big old guy.
You know what, what Roids
does he use? It's like,
it's all hard work. I've been an athlete
since I was six years old. You know,
my dad was an Olympic level athlete.
My brother is like 10 times the athlete
that I am. My sister was, she's, you know,
she was, she started an athlete
even before we were, um,
like throw stones at me.
You sought a tests every week to military
test has all the time still to the
day. Like I just get tested. Um, last
month I got tested like nine times.
I've always been clean.
I will always be clean.
Yeah.
And just for those of you that don't know
that for those of you that aren't MMA
fans, you fall a lot of guys
that weren't clean. Yeah.
And that's used.
You know,
I've since been in the
academic community and,
and sparring a lot of guys
and fighting a lot of guys.
I've gone with guys and,
and just so everybody understands
when someone goes on steroids,
you can feel it 100%. You can
absolutely feel it. They work,
they work, they work, they work,
they make you stronger. They make,
they make a cover. A couple of faster.
And so the fact that you've gone in the,
in the cage on multiple occasions and
Farc guys that had that massive advantage
and you've beaten him,
uh, awesome, awesome work.
And it's a bummer that, that,
that's out there. Yeah. With that
self respect, integrity. Yeah. You have
more of an outspoken opinion about it,
but say then like the next guy.
Yeah. I mean, so I've been,
I've been a professional
athlete for 14 years. Um,
like the pride peak of guys
dripping anabolic steroids.
Like, I mean, not like
I used in fight camp.
I mean like they took hypodermic needles
and shoved them into their eyeballs
right before the fight type fights. You
know, the vendor delay Silva like Jewish,
like he's up on the sh the ring screaming,
and he probably hasn't even remembered
like the last four days because he's been
in a steroid rage leading up to
his fight. That was the, that,
that is the era of MMA that I
came from. Right. And, um, my,
so my entire career has been that, and
I'm not bitter that like, you know, I,
I fought in lost titles.
Um,
and yeah,
maybe they would have gone differently
had I cheated or they weren't cheating,
but that's not what it's about to me.
It's,
I've been a martial artist
since I was since I was a kid.
So a martial artist has to do with ethics
and integrity and hard work and you're
like the pillars of what being a martial
artist is and every one of these guys
spits in the face of what I think
the sport is supposed to personify.
All the beauty that exists in martial
arts is stripped away every time one of
these guys test positive.
That's why. Yeah. That's,
uh, I'll leave it at that.
I'll leave it at that.
Okay.
While we're on it,
the next question is why
not make one UFC run? Mm,
I do it. Yeah. Are there, are
you gonna fight again? What's,
are you on the schedule?
Are they calling you
post to deploy
in mid May and then at
the beginning of June?
So I know I'm gonna leave
in mid to late May and
nope. Again, I got to break some stuff
down for some civilians here, right?
Yeah.
Tim who's doing all this stuff,
we sit in the room with me right now,
who's got done doing a photo shoot today,
who's making movies?
He's going on deployment overseas
to go hunt down and kill bad guys
in a matter of months. I'm retired. Right?
He's still doing it and he's doing all
this other stuff and he's fighting for
the UFC. Now the UFC, I mean,
yeah,
you should be the absolute
poster boy for the UFC,
for the love of God.
Okay.
Sorry for interrupting you. Okay. So
you're going to go on deployment. Yeah.
For your nation.
Um, and so my, one of my management, uh,
told them that I get back on this date
and from this date until this date,
which is when I leave again, I'll be
100% down to fight anybody they say.
So one last UFC run,
I wouldn't even limit it to last.
The I'm ranked whatever,
six in the war, seventh or sixth or
fifth in the world right now. To me,
I'm a fight away from a title and um,
and I think I can
beat everybody above me.
And I think you can too.
Yeah. Uh, so let's hope
that the folks at the UFC
pay attention to this. I mean, you got
a guy that's a veteran that's a hero,
that's a hard worker,
that's never let you guys down.
Pop and positive that's
trained in his ass off.
And you know what,
besides all that,
he's getting ready to deploy again
so that you can have the damn UFC.
How about when he gets back, you tell
him, how much time do you need my brother,
you t you tell us when you want to
fight and, and who you want to fight.
If I was Dana White, I'd be like,
Oh, you know what, this whole,
this whole UFC schedule is
based on Tim Kennedy. I like,
that's who we based the UFC schedule sound
of that not on what some other person
that's not ever served.
So hopefully Dana White, if you're
listening, my name is Jocko.
Give me a shout.
I'll lay this out for you and explain
to you how this needs to at work.
Let's do this. Loan it. Yes, seriously.
All
importance of recovery within
your training program. Cheers.
And this is, by the way, this
is from a sore necks, you know,
the guys that make weight racks.
Yeah.
Well, you know, for, for
recovery be important.
You have to have done
the hard work to need it.
So I think a lot of people focus
on recovery all the time. Um,
when they seriously, uh,
I, I can't do that today.
I'm on recovery day.
I gotta gotta cry cryotherapy or ice
bath or get a massage or acupuncture,
you know, like bitch,
go train hard, you know,
like these callouses, I cut
off, you know, like weekly.
It's from hard work, you know, and,
and I think recovery is
as important as training,
but first the training has to be there
and it has to be hard enough for it to
warrant needing recovery.
Yeah. Now, I would say when, when
I'm, when I was training fighters,
I don't do it a lot anymore,
but when I was trained UFC fighters,
it was so obvious when they
were overtrained like they'd
go from the, you know,
they be giving me a hard time on the
mat or whatever and all of a sudden I'm
just annihilated and I go,
yeah, hey day off mango,
eat two steaks tomorrow and just relax
and easy. But you know, some guys,
oh I needed a couple of days off.
You don't need a day off.
I think it has more to do with
lifestyle than recovery. You know,
like when people are like, I am just not
being able to put that, get the output,
the volume that I need to do for work.
Let's talk about your life. You know,
like we, y'all chasing pussy last
night. Oh you were? You were,
you were at a strip club. Is
that glitter shut? Get Out, get,
what have you eaten this
week? Tell me, show me your
diet. Did you even have a log?
No, you don't have a log. Get
Out. You know? Well, how much
did you sleep last night?
Oh, you don't know cause what
you drank get out. You know,
like when was the last time you had to
drink? Oh, last night. Get Out. You know,
stop talking to me about recovery.
If you don't get it,
a lifestyle that's conducive to training,
you know,
like you want to talk about healthy
lifestyle, get eight hours of sleep.
Well yeah, I know. Yeah. Hey
Jocko. Doesn't sleep a lot.
That's all right. That's all right. Eat
real food. Stop putting crap in your body.
Stop drinking. You don't. You
won't drop your testosterone.
You were talking about these guys
are having huge problems to stop.
One stop using steroids to stop
drinking. You know, for me,
sex day, everyday get eight
hours of sleep. Work my ass off.
I think that a man for a real athlete,
man or woman,
they have to go to bed tired.
I love that feeling like
you are exhausted. You see
that bed and you were like,
fuck you cannot mean to me.
Can I make it? You know,
can I make it from the shower to bed?
Yeah,
that's what you're supposed to feel like.
We've talked about that
on here and that's,
that's one of my favorite
feelings in the world
of I get to the end of the night and
I'm barely hanging on through dinner.
By the time I get done with dinner,
I'll just, Oh God, I can't wait to crow.
Wife starts talking. You're like,
Baby Wah Wah Wah Wah Wah Wah Wah Wah.
You hear the words, but I don't know
what you're saying. Yeah. You know,
so I, yeah, that's,
that's great input. Sleep,
eat right. It's, you can work, man.
Humans can do a lot of
the body is so adaptive.
So you've got people that can run ultra
marathons and he got people that can
deadlift thousands of pounds the,
and we're the same species. Right.
You know,
we have people that can like paint the
Mona Lisa and there's people that can go
and murder villages,
same species,
you know,
like it is an adaptive thing as
long as you train it properly.
Yeah.
Next question. What are the, what
are the best qualities, SLAs, skills?
A person needs to be a great soldier.
Slash. Fighter. And are these the same?
I think that there are some qualities
in each that compliment each other.
Um,
for example,
the regimented schedule of the military
does good things for somebody that wants
to aspire to be a fighter because most
fighters are selfish little pricks that
are super lazy and they don't understand
what it takes.
Dedication wise to little
things like setting your alarm,
being on time to work out, writing
a journal as to what you're eating.
I'm not chasing pussy all night long and
that you should go to bed like those.
That's discipline. That's, that's
what that is. That's that word. Um,
and a lot of military, not all guys, but
a lot of the military teaches discipline.
So that is a characteristic that would
compliment somebody that aspires to be a
fighter. And then fighters, you know, like
yes. Obviously you're learning skills,
technical skills that
could be life saving. Um,
you know, just like you getting
comfortable with sweating,
you're getting used to hard work and you
know, so some of those things are nice,
but um,
yeah.
So there's some things that that do well.
I think being a good soldier can make you
a better fighter and some things about
being a good fighter can
make you a better soldier.
Yeah. I think, uh,
for me the biggest quality that would
transfer both back and forth soldier
fighter,
and I'll go ahead and throw one more on
there and that's been in a leadership
position,
but to me it's humility and I think what
makes a soldier of fighter a leader the
most important quality that they can have,
his humility,
because the minute that you're not humble
is minute that you stop training as
hard as you can. So the
minute you say, you know what,
I don't need to do that
extra workout today.
That's a lack of humility because
you're thinking, oh, I already got this,
I got this in the bag from a
leadership position, same thing.
I don't really do train my guys hard.
I don't need to show up earlier than my
guys because they already respect me. No,
you need to earn that respect every day.
And so for me,
always humility is the most important
characteristic of a person because
you're not also not learning what's,
you're not humble. I don't need, I don't
need to roll today. I'll read the whole,
I didn't need to get on the pads today.
How did you swing that kettle bell today?
I'm already good.
Get humble yet humble or
you're gonna get humbled,
dude. Boom. That's ranger rupture. Sorry.
Let me, let me put this in my phone
real fast. It'll be recorded too.
When you can refer it back to you. I don't
want you to keep it. I want to keep it.
Okay.
We got all kinds of tee shirts,
sayings that come out of the podcast
each time. Be Humble or get humbled.
Take the high road or the high road
of Tq. Yeah, that's another good one.
Saved. Okay. All right.
Humility right there.
Last learning from external
social thievery of his, um,
intellectual property.
I didn't trademark it yet.
I'm sure you'll cut me up.
Giant fat check for the thousands and
thousands of tee shirts that gets sold
with that on it. Uh, okay. Last question.
And I think the reason this question is
in here is because a lot of people that
listen to this podcast,
they're trying to get better,
try to improve themselves,
they're trying to do good and we all,
and we got people of all ages.
This one in particular says if giving
a high school graduation speech,
what would you advise 18 year olds
navigating their first, their next steps?
Would you tell an 18 year old, oh man, um,
be humbler gambled. Damn. I know, dude,
we need to make a t shirt
that says no, I am, um,
you don't have another way that
this question gets phrased.
And from what the story you told tonight,
what would you tell yourself if you
could tell your own 18 year old self,
what would you tell yourself?
Do something that you don't
know if you can accomplish.
If I'm going to climb a mountain,
yeah, I could go up to, you know,
mission St Louis Obispo,
which is like a 2000 foot mountain and
I'm pretty confident I could claim that,
you know,
um,
Mount Whitney without some training.
Honestly, we've kind of challenging.
Um, you know, obviously a k Everest
Dif, different beasts could do it.
Do,
do that,
do that thing that you don't know if you
can do stop being afraid of hard work.
That's the thing that's gonna
really determine success or failure.
One is your desire to actually do it
and then to the commitment that it will
take to achieve it.
Stop being scared.
Go and do it.
That's what I'd say
my statement.
Yeah.
And I put it right on top of that.
I would say that not only do you want
to stop being scared and do that thing
that you don't know if you can do or not,
but you know what you gotta do is you've
got to start taking the steps now.
Because when you're 18 years old,
your life seems like it's going to last
forever. And I will tell you right now,
it's not gonna last forever
in those years go by like a summer's Day.
And the next thing you know,
you look up
and you're 36 years old or you're
44 years old and that time's gone.
You cannot get it back.
You cannot get time back.
So those dreams that you have,
those goals that you have,
don't put them off another second one,
not one second.
Get on them
and go out and make them happen.
Starting right now.
Yeah. Like you got anything else for
the night? Tana? Mike Schur suspended.
She can't drop them. But if you
could, that's what I would've done.
I just be like,
I'm out.
You got anything else?
Dude, this is awesome.
Thanks man. Thanks for coming on.
You're inspiring. Preciate it, you're,
you're inspiring to all nations.
Uh, Echo. You've got anything?
I thought it was interesting how
a lot of the stuff, actually,
most of the stuff that Tim was talking
about was like what we were just kind of
recently talking about in terms
of the reading stuff. Yeah.
The stop drinking stuff. The, um,
obviously the hard work stuff or whatever.
But it was, it was, I
thought that was interesting.
So I subscribed to this idea of like,
I prefer a dangerous
freedom to peaceful slavery.
And the only reason that that you
can have that is from individual
responsibility for you to have freedom.
It's, there's not this construct.
You actually have to take the work and
do the work that's associated with it and
see what I mean?
He's laughing right now because one of
my sort of mantras in life is discipline
equals freedom. And the more discipline
you have, the harder you work,
the more effort you put into it,
the more freedom you're going to have.
And so as you're
describing this philosophy,
it's something that we
literally say on every, it's a,
it's a chapter in the book that I
read what I just said. Like whoa.
Everything you're saying is like locking
in exactly with like, Whoa, whoa.
He's been saying Amen.
Jocko. Amen. You, it,
we actually have a shirt,
one of the two only two shirts we have.
One is discipline equals freedom.
You don't be humble or get humbled
for ranger up to make. Thank
you. What about what else
on it? Oh yeah. On it. Yeah.
You know all about [inaudible] trainer.
I train there two days a week. Utilize,
I utilize their self. What
do you use? Um, shroom tech.
See she room, I swear. Like, um,
so I'm like a pretty sight. I
think I'm a scientific guy. Um,
so when I'm using something
I'll have like measurable,
tangible numbers.
I can do x number of reps,
reps or rose,
like how many calories can I burn and
10 minutes on shroom tech or off shroom
tech, all things being the same, same
day of the week. Same. Pretty much diet,
same similar weight. Um, it's
more what am on trim tech.
I don't know if it's placebo.
I know when I go in and I roll,
there's nights where I'm
like tuckered out. Um,
and then there's nights where I'm
lunchroom tech and I'm just like,
I want another round. Anybody else got
another round? And that's what to say,
the later rounds, you really feel it as
the rounds go on. Any other so on it?
Yeah. If you want to get, um,
shroom tech or Alpha brain,
[inaudible] dot com or Krill oil right
on h.com/jocko. That's the one 10% off.
Boom. Nice. Yeah, I
forgot. That's in Austin.
It is 20 minutes from me.
Click through,
click through amazon.com. Oh yeah, yeah.
If you want to be free shop on Amazon.
If you want to support this podcast,
go to Jocko podcast.com click through
the Amazon link or a chocolate store.
I'll come and then yet do your shopping
and get a little zone all the time. Hey,
go. Go to Jocko upon Joe and Tom First.
So convenient is take my money. Yeah.
It's like, oh, I have to do is click this
button and it ends up on my door. Nope.
Ah, yeah. It's hard not to do Amazon now.
Say I know it too. Yeah,
man. Do that. Right.
I think that's all we've got tonight.
I have one question.
Send it Brian Stann in
you 2016 is it too late?
I realized the delicates or the delegates
are about to be distributed to a bunch
of bitches.
I think it might be too late.
24 2016 for 2020 I'll have to meet with
Brian Stan and we'll see what we can do.
Want like president, vice president, I
want to presidents. I want Brian, Stan,
and Jocko Javier as my two
president. I don't know. After today.
You might have a little
flood in there somewhere too.
Nope. Nope, nope. Awesome.
Wait, seriously though.
Thanks for coming on.
Appreciate sweet sharing with
everybody and most of all,
thank you for your service to this nation
can never thank you enough for what
you've done.
If you want to connect with any of us
on the Inter webs echos at Echo Charles.
Tim is at Tim Kennedy MMA and I am at
Jocko Willink and all the troopers are out
there that are listening to this.
Thanks for listening
to those of you that aren't on the front
lines of the battlefield overseas right
now,
serving in our military.
Thanks for taking the fight to the enemy,
to the police law enforcement
firefighters that are here state side.
Thank you all for
protecting the home front
and for all the other troopers out there
in the world on your job site or in
your office or in your manufacturing
line or sitting in your cubicle out there
grinding away.
I want you to remember that the grind
is how you sharpen the ax
and it's the toil that makes
the man so keep grinding.
They keep living and go to
sleep later and wake up earlier.
Work hard,
and play even harder and have fun while
you're doing both and squeeze every
minute out of every day
and make every second count.
And the best way to do that
is to go out there,
get after it.
So until next time,
this is echo and Tim and Jocko out.