Yeah,
this is Jocko podcast number
34 with Echo Charles and me,
Jocko Willink. Good
evening. Echo did evening
and tonight we have a guest on the
podcast back for a second time.
My brother Leif Babin.
Good evening. Good evening.
Good to be back with you and if
you don't know who Leif Babin is,
real easy thing to do is go back to Jocko
podcast number 11 and listen to that.
I give him a long introduction
and tell you about who he is.
Guy That I served in
the seal teams with and
like I said,
go back to 11
I think he gets rid of book.
Yeah,
we wrote a little book
called extreme ownership.
I'm sure we'll talk about that tonight.
Life was one of the platoon commanders
that that worked for me in the battle of
Ramadi when we deployed in 2006
and just one of my brothers.
So thanks for coming on the
podcast to get extra. Grab me.
What do you say to a man
that by his own admission
has no soul?
Why would you say anything?
I've thought about it a good deal,
but he wasn't nothing compared
to what was coming down the pike.
Okay.
They say the eyes are
the windows to the soul.
I don't know what that,
Mies was windows too and I
guess I'd as soon not know,
but there is another view of the world
out there and all the rise to see it and
that's where this is going.
Yeah.
It is done.
Brought me to a place in my life I
would not have thought out of come to.
Yeah.
Somewhere out there.
Easy,
true and living prophet of destruction
and I don't want to confront him.
I know he's real.
Yeah.
I've seen his work.
I walked in front of those eyes once.
I won't do it again.
I won't push my chips forward and
stand up and go out to meet him.
It ain't just being older.
I wish that it was,
I can't say that it's even
what you are willing to do.
Yeah,
because I always knew that you had to
be willing to die to even do this job.
That was always true.
Not to sound glorious at about or nothing,
but do.
And if you ain't, they'll know
it. They'll see it in a heartbeat.
I think it is more like water
you are willing to become
and I think a man would have
to put his soul at hazard
and I won't do that.
Okay.
I think now that may be, I never would.
Now that's the opening from the book.
No country for old men,
which is written by Cormac Mccarthy.
You also wrote my favorite
nonmilitary memoir book,
the Book Blood Meridian,
which is just an outstanding book and
no country for old men was actually made
into an outstanding movie as well,
which almost follows the book word
for word. It's, it's an awesome movie.
And in the,
in the movie and in the book there's a,
there's a guy and that's
who's talking to that opening,
Sheriff Ed Tom Bell and he's explaining
that he's seen evil in the world,
the living prophet of destruction.
And he seen his work and walked in
front of those eyes. And ultimately,
and that's kind of what the book is about.
Sheriff Bell is explaining that he
doesn't really want to face this evil.
He doesn't want to put his soul at hazard.
So ultimately he doesn't really
want to be a sheriff anymore.
You can't face that kind of evil.
So he leaves the Tube,
put up the police and he retires and
stays in his own little world and that's,
that's the basis of it.
And there's a way more to it than that.
Then you should definitely read the
book, have the book, which is, it's set.
I think it's sent in
about the 1980s early,
early 1980s and the evil
that he's speaking of that
he's having to now deal with
as a, as a sheriff is the drug
cartels common out of Mexico,
the border of Texas. They've
escalated from, you know,
petty little drug dealers back in the
day and now it's a ruthless organized
crime.
Syndicates that murder with no mercy.
And
like I said,
it's just too much for sheriff
bell and he ends up walking away
now meanwhile in 2016
okay.
The evil that we deal with now is
even more pervasive and stronger and
completely without mercy,
and it's everywhere.
And we can try it and ignore it,
and we can try and act
like it doesn't happen.
There's some things that you
cannot ignore,
and in this case, it's something
that we cannot walk away from.
Okay.
In late July of 2016
okay,
Father Jacques Hamel.