Hi Jocko and echo. I recently
read the book marine,
the life of chesty puller and in the book
chesty references and the unnecessary
loads of administrative paperwork that
was required to be prepared for the
military. I also recently member
on it on a recent podcast,
you recalling a situation in Ramadi where
your platoon leaders were not thrilled
to fill out required paperwork.
I'm a squad sergeant in a prominent
American police department and I'm
experiencing the same dilemma.
The micromanaging and
oversight is extreme and I'm,
and it's taken a toll on the
morale of the officer's citywide.
The tedious paperwork and
constant micro-managing is
preventing good cups from
being proactive. I feel
like the job, quote unquote,
has changed beyond recognition.
I'd appreciate your advice on how
to approach the bullshit paperwork
and increase the morale of my
cops. Thank you for your time.
Okay, so what would I do
in this situation? Um,
first of all, I am going to
be awesome at the paperwork.
I'm going to do it so well that,
because if you blow off the paperwork,
then you go to your boss and say the
paperwork sucks. And it's not any good.
The guy looks at you and
says, Oh, you know what?
You don't even know how to do the
paperwork. How do you know if,
how do you know if it's hard or not?
So what I'm gonna do is I'm gonna do,
I'm gonna Start building a case.
That's what I'm going to do.
So I'm going to do the paperwork.
I'm actually going to log down how
many hours I put into the paperwork.
I'm going to follow that paperwork and
see where it goes and see if anyone
actually reads it, right? Cause if
I can go to my boss and say, Hey,
I spent 28 hours a week filing this
paperwork and know not one single person
read it.
And then you take the manpower of everyone
in the department and then what you
do is you actually build a case.
When you go in to talk to the boss,
you should have a full magazine of
ammunition to combat this paperwork that
you're being forced to do.
You have to be able to explain it to
them in a rational, logical manner.
And you can't.
You can't make any headway against your
boss if you are trying to fight from the
low ground.
The low ground is why don't really turn
in the paperwork and I don't really do
the paperwork and I think
the paperwork is crap.
Then they're looking down on
you. What are you talking about?
How are you dare you say
that you don't even do it.
You don't even know what you're doing.
You got to get on the high ground.
How do you get on the high ground?
You get all that stuff done
to the best of your ability.
You logged down the hours it takes.
You get your whole little team doing it
and you tell your whole team, hey look,
I know this is painful right
now. Everyone in this squad,
everyone in this platoon
is gonna do all this.
We're going to log down what it takes
because I am going to bring a solid case
up the chain of command of where
we need to limit this paperwork.
This is a long war situation.
You know how long it took to build
up all that paperwork? It took years.
It took 20 years, 30
years for that to happen.
I used to joke about the marines,
the navy seal teams, the range,
our range procedures are super loose.
We go out there and we shoot like crazy
and do all kinds of really dynamic
things and we'd sometimes
go to a Marine Corps range.
It was like everything was super tight
and I would tell my guys, I'd say,
look, that's because that happened
over years. One mistake happens.
How do you stop that mistake
from happening again?
Put a rule in place that stops
it. Another mistakes happen,
another mistake happens. Put another
rule in place. Another mistake happens.
Put a p a piece of paper to
stop it from happening again.
And eventually you end up with a
range that's barely even usable.
So that's what happened
in this department.
There was little things that happened
over time and they built and they build
upon themselves and the
next thing you know,
you can't even recognize what your
actual job was. So we have to,
it's so that took 20 years to happen.
You're not going to undo it overnight
and you're definitely not gonna undo it
from the low ground. You
have to get the high ground.
You have to be a performer.
If you're not a performer,
you have no say, do your job, do it well,
fight the long war.