This is Jocko podcast number
one 79 with Echo Charles and me,
Jocko Willink. Good
Evening Echo. Good evening.
So
the Spear Danes in days gone by and the
kings who ruled them had courage and
greatness.
Okay,
we have heard of those
princes heroic campaigns.
Okay.
There was shield Sheaf,
sin scourge of many tribes,
a wrecker of mead benches,
rampaging among foes.
This terror of the haul troops had
come far a foundling to start with.
He would flourish later on as his
powers waxed and his worth was proved
in the end.
Each clan on outlying coasts beyond the
whale road had to yield to him and begin
to pay tribute.
Yeah,
that was one good king
boom opening with a little bit of Beowulf.
And that is the opening of Beowulf
translated by Shamus Haney.
Okay.
And what I notice is even back
in the day in the opening of the,
the original old English poem,
the first one written, what
are they talking about?
They're talking about war and
they're talking about leadership.
Yeah.
And you can hear it in the beginning.
He was a little bit of a weak leader.
He was a foundling to start with,
but he would flourish later on.
Became a good king.
No,
and that's what happens.
You learn, you get better.
And that is why we talk about
war and leadership here.
And speaking of war and
leadership back for a third time,
my brother Jason Gardener,
retired master chief who I've known
since I got into the James' in the early
nineties he's been on the podcast before.
So if you haven't listened to one 67
in one 68 go listen to those first.
There's a lot of ground covered in those
podcasts and I told him to listen in
and listen to him again and see which
what we missed so we could go back and
that's, we're going to do
now cover some more ground,
hit some of that stuff that we
missed. So welcome back Jason.
Thank you. Check. There's I,
when I first got that translation,
which was actually when I was in
college and it starts off with,
so I just said, oh my God,
this is totally legit.
So I start things with so a lot now
when I write, I do that. I do that.
So yeah, welcome back. How's
retirement treating you?
Good
to go. I was going to say
awesome, but I'd be awesome.
Absolutely to death in
the last two podcasts.
So I'm going to try and
ban it into your life.
Is your southern California childhood
creep out with some awesome? Yes.
Everything is awesome. Yup. Yeah.
So you got to watch out for that.
So what do we miss? I know we
missed something from your youth.
What were you talking about the
best, the best show you ever saw?
The best punk rock show
you ever saw? Yeah,
there was one that,
and this is before I could
even drive buddy of mine,
Justin Hawkins and Alicia went up to this,
this Gig at Cypress College
and was DUI plain rap,
the Dickies, the vandals,
the circle jerks.
And there might've been one other
band for $7 in presale. Yeah.
So we got presale
tickets. We went up there,
got in there was probably about 500
people outside who weren't able to get in
because it's sold out.
So they just went ahead and knocked
the doors down and all flooded in.
So what that meant was nobody got searched
coming in for security and people had
crazy stuff like firecrackers.
It was way overcrowded for,
you know what the safe, safe
amount for the building was.
So when you went up by where the doors
were, the security guys had just put,
pushed all these tables and chairs and
we're sitting on them up against the
doors to keep anybody else from coming
in. And the, the show is just unreal.
There were three mosh pits and then
when the circle jerks came out,
they opened up with wild on the streets.
The whole floor exploded. One,
the pits started floating,
crashed into another pit.
We're throwing bricks
of firecrackers around.
It was mass pandemonium was so much. And
so you were like 14 or 1515 years old.
Yeah. My mom had dropped me
off, dropped us off there.
Oh that's awesome. Good for your mom. Oh
yeah, she's got the squared away, man,
that's squared away because a lot
of times you pay if your parents,
if parents try and shield their kids
from that or they won't let them go,
then you would have just snuck out.
They would have never
known where you were Yep.
And gotten in trouble and you had
rebelled against it. Right? Yeah.
Cause that's what happens
if you're, if you're,
if your parents trying
to control you too much,
it's kind of like with any person,
right. You try and control them too much,
then they get out of control.
They rebel against you. Right.
When was this discussion? I think I
was having the other day with a um,
your daughter about people just trying
to box people in and it's another example
of just over centralized
command and yes, it is too much,
too much stuff like that. They're
just going to go the other way.
I was actually,
I was talking about this with a leader
in a company and I was explaining because
you like for sure money drives
people, compensation drives people.
But ability to choose your fate or
some influence over your fate is,
is a also very powerful motivator
and incentive for people to follow.
So when you have a look,
like if you have one job where you
make more money but you don't have any
freedom and you don't have any control
over your own fate versus a job where you
get paid less money, but you
have really a lot of autonomy.
Most people will go with the autonomy.
There are rare people that
don't want any autonomy.
They just pretty much want to get
told, hey, give me my paycheck.
I'll do whatever you tell
me to do, and that's fine.
And that they're not into their
job, but, but a lot of people,
the more autonomy you give
them, the more intuit they are,
the more they enjoy what they're doing.
Whereas if you're just micromanaging
them or a centralized command scenario,
they're not intuit and that's a problem
at the first person you gave the
example, I'd probably exercises. No
initiative whatsoever. Exactly. Exactly.
You know, you have to address that.
You have to address that when we're
working with the companies that there are
people that they just want
to get their paycheck,
they're going to punch the clock at four
59 every day. And that's the way it is.
They don't want to get promoted.
They're fine with that.
And so you've got to know, and you know,
my answer to those people always is,
Oh, if you're leading someone
like that, okay, you know what?
You've got to get the most out
of them. Take good care of them,
and they'll do their job well and you
know, you can count on them for that.
So that's fine. There's
nothing wrong with that.
It's just that somebody that does
have higher goals or different goals,
I guess where they want
to break out of that,
then you've got to give them the
opportunity. And those people,
if you box them in, they're going to
rebel against, you've got to look out,
there'll be like Jason
Gardener, age 15 with a Mohawk
check check.
So I know one of the other things that
you wanted to talk about a little bit was
a was Scotty words.
That's right. You know,
and just common after,
right after Memorial Day, it's
really fitting to discuss him.
Scotty was a good friend of mine. Um,
just a fantastic team guy. He did a,
he did six years in the teams and
then separated in 2005 and he did,
what a lot of guys did at the time was
he started contracting overseas because
he wanted to be at that point of friction.
And for Scotty, I don't think
he was ever, ever happier than,
than when he was at that
point of friction. So he
did a bunch of contracting.
He wound up getting hired by the
defense intelligence agency as a,
as a GS position, a full time
position. And then January, uh,
this last January,
he was killed by a suicide bomber
when he was out operating in Syria.
And I remember when I got the text
message, we were all in a group text that,
that he'd passed. And I just, man,
it kind of floored me for a second.
But then, you know,
it's like Scotty died doing what
he loved and he was just such,
he was a maniac in the
best sense of the word.
Like the hardest I've ever laughed
in my life is with him. And,
and most people will tell you that
anytime they've had a good belly laugh or
something, he, you know,
it was with Scotty and he had that kind
of contagious smile where you look at
pictures and Seth is a lot like
this. When I look at sets pictures,
he's got that smile that just has that
special thing about it that automatically
makes you use smile. Then you know,
you are not ever going to be the voice
of reason and you are always going to be
a good time and you're a good friend.
And so while there's, there's
remorse that he's not here anymore,
I'm so fired up that I got to
spend the time with him that I did.
And uh, so anyway,
I mean there you really have it.
He passed, he's from St Louis,
so they had a big funeral form there
and it was at this Catholic Cathedral.
There had to be a thousand people inside
that cathedral and it was raining the
day they had it.
So the funeral procession from the
cathedral to the military sent a cemetery
where they buried him. I had
to be like at least 30 miles
every Stingel overpass on the freeway,
on the drive there had fire trucks
and first responders out on it,
the freeway, they shut the freeway down.
Every exit was stopped by
police officers, which is,
which is pretty pretty Dang
cool. Okay. That's all.
So then when we got off the freeway and
we were driving on the surface streets,
okay.
People,
the people of St Louis just pulled their
cars over and they were standing at
attention out in the rain. And so it's,
it's moving when someone
in uniform does that,
but you almost kind of
expect that out of them.
But when you see like a 30 year old
mother of two and her two like eight year
old kid and seven year old kid
standing at attention with
their hands in the heart,
over their hearts in the rain and
it was a cold rain as as he went by.
It's just,
yeah,
it's an, it's an amazing and
humbling experience to, uh,
to see that kind of love and respect
by the people of this country and the
people at St Louis.
Yeah, that's, that's awesome.
I, well, I was at with,
with Chris Kyle's per session going down
to where he was buried and that was a
long drive. I want to say it was
a few hours in the entire thing.
And again, it was raining. Same thing.
We're in Texas, but it's raining.
And sure enough, I mean there was,
people were aligned the entire way and
I was riding with one other guy and it
was just in, and we were in this massive,
there was a massive procession
of people, but it was just,
I remember sitting there
for a long time and it just,
the windshield wipers
just going back and forth.
We were not talking because
there's nothing to say. You can't,
you can't put words to that, you know,
you can't put words to thousands of
people standing out in the rain with their
hands on their hearts. Just
every bridge, fire trucks,
flags hung up from the ladders
extended. Yeah. This, uh,
the same, same type of feeling that
I had one when I was doing that.
And it definitely makes you
realize that regardless of all the,
what do they say these days,
that America is division all this
division that everyone talks about,
there's plenty of people
that, that understand what,
what it takes to keep this
country free. For sure.
Absolutely.
I feel like it's such a small
and maybe vocal minority
that's out there and I
don't think it's on a whole,
I think we're,
we're on even though a lot of us have our
differences and I think we're figuring
out how to discuss politics just by
looking at how people discuss stuff on
social media and people were dialing
it in and there they're able to have
realistic discussions with each
other without getting too hateful.
And there are some people that
are still figuring that out.
Yeah, for sure. I'll say two
things about that. I was on,
I was on Ben Shapiro's podcast
and you know, Ben was like,
and Ben's a real nice guy. He's,
you know, very nice to me and,
and all that. And he's, you know, he's,
what's pretty cool about him is he's,
he's like got this running list of
everything that he said that's stupid or
wrong or whatever, you know, his
mea culpa list. But anyways, yes,
we were having this conversation.
He was hinting at the fact of this
massive division and you know,
these massive, right against a massive
left and, and you know, I said,
listen man, I traveled our
whole country all the time.
I work with construction
companies, with finance companies,
with now you do to
insurance companies. I mean,
we meet people from every
different industry. I said,
these people aren't on the extreme,
right? They're not on the extreme left.
Their common sense. They're
Americans. And I said, you Ben, your,
you're like here at, at,
at ground zero for political like mayhem.
And so what do you expect to
see? Like you're, you're the,
you're the lightning rod
for a lot of this stuff.
And so that's what you hear normal
America in really liked that. You know,
it's just not, it's just not,
I'm out there all the time.
You're out there all the time
now, you know, you see it,
no one's coming up to you saying,
you know, with some extreme views,
are there small number of people?
Sure. On both sides, yes, absolutely.
But in general people are realizing,
oh well that's not a bad point.
And then I was on Brian Complement's
podcast and we were talking about the same
thing. And what's
interesting is, you know, um,
Ben Shapiro's pretty pretty
far on the right and,
and Brian Complement is
pretty far on the left and me,
I think they're both really nice
guys that are super cool. And,
but what I said to him was, you
know, w w what you're saying,
what I believe is leading to the attitude
kind of shifting is basically this.
If you're not humble and you
think you know everything,
then why should I listen to anything
that you say, you know, why should,
if I'm on the far left, why
should I listen to anything?
I know everything and everyone on the
right is wrong if I'm on the far right.
Why should I listen to anyone that anyone
say anything that anyone is saying on
the other side, I know everything. If
you're humble and you say, you know what,
I've got some ideas, but
I'm probably not 100% right.
You'll maybe I'm only 98% right? No. If
you just look at other people and say,
Oh, you know what, I probably don't
have the full solution for this.
Maybe I should listen to other people's
opinions and try and try and come up
with a a more broad based
idea than just what I think.
So I think people are starting to realize
if you take one extreme view and you
don't listen to anyone
else, then you're wrong.
And so I think people are becoming
a little bit more balanced.
I certainly hope I, yeah,
and, and I know that,
that I've got some really,
really close friends that are
on both ends of the spectrum.
How do I sit down with them and have
a logical conversation with them?
I find out that our values,
yeah.
Are the same. They're the same. Yeah.
And really it's just a
lot of misrepresentation.
And some unfortunate semantic
sometimes that uh, you know,
drawing us to different directions
or put us on different sides
and you know, that's it.
Speaking of the left hand
and the right hand know
this is, you got to tell this
story about, and this is,
this is a good revealing
story about, I've, I,
I allude to oftentimes the dark sense
of humor in the teams and there's a dark
sense of humor in the military and you
kind of have to have a dark sense of
humor. And I think, did
you see the movie range 15?
No. Oh, okay. It's, it's about,
it's just a crazy movie
that Tim Kennedy and, and,
and Matt best and the black rifle coffee
company. Yeah. Like all those guys,
they throw the keys to the
girl. Yeah. Yeah. It's just,
it's just every horrible dark
joke that you can make they make.
And I don't know how well it did
or whatever. It did good enough.
It did good enough. I mean, I'm
sure it offended a lot of people.
I'm sure it offended a lot of people,
but they did it so good for
good on them. But you know,
you talk about that, that
kind of dark sense of humor.
And I think this story which you
like called me, I don't know,
whatever it was six months ago or whatever
you go to, I got to tell you a story,
which whenever you call me and
tell me that I get super excited.
I tell my kids to leave the room and I'd
like to put you on speaker phone and I
put you on speakerphone and then I mute.
So I don't interrupt you by laughing so
hard because whenever you call me and
tell me you got a good story. I'm
thinking, here we go. So yeah,
tell us about the hand. So, and,
and I talked to Aaron Kendall this
morning to make sure I got the details
correct.
So Aaron Kendall's a seal that was working
at the training detachment when I was
the command master chief there and
he is on a hunting trip out in Texas,
like a foundation supported hunting trip.
And he's driving one of
those side-by-sides out to
where he's going to hunt like
side by side ATV, like an ATV tribe.
Like one of those razors. Right.
And it rolls and it's smack. The
rollbar smashes his left arm.
So he makes a tourniquet out of his belt
and walks like a mile back to the range
house and then they call a,
they tried to call lifelight lifelight
can't come out. It's too foggy.
They get an ambulance comes and gets him.
They start driving him up towards
a, to a hospital at San Antonio.
Now he's in the hospital.
They wind up having to amputate his
left hand in the hospital in this first
hospital. Why is that?
Because it was just completely
smell was so smashed that every,
his arm was just smashed. It was done.
He was losing so much blood through
there and they ended up like,
they kind of had to fight to save the
amputation below his elbow cause they were
worried that because later on in
surgeries they're taking more and more.
So there were a couple of other team
guys that were there and other team guys
flew in to help out.
And they're staying at this hotel right
outside the hospital where he's at.
So they take him from where he was,
they take them to this hospital,
this hospital, and at that hospital
they have to amputate his hand.
So he's bedside talking with the
other, with some other seals.
And they're the surgeon who amputate
his hand is in there checking on him and
they asked the surgeon, hey, do
you guys still have his hand?
And the surgeon says, yeah, I
think so. I don't, you know,
we haven't destroyed. And they asked
him, what are you going to do with it?
And he goes, well, you know, I
guess they destroy it or whatever.
And so Aaron asked,
well, can I have my hand?
And the surgeon says, I'll go check.
So he goes and checks with
the administrators, right?
And they come back and they say, yeah,
you have to fill out these forms,
but we'll give you the hand.
So they fill out the forms,
they give the hand to. Um,
one of the other seals actually
receives a hand cause Aaron now has,
has had to move to a different hospital
that's a little bit better to deal with
the amputations and,
and they've got his hand with the
intent to take it to a taxidermist.
So in the meantime, they're keeping
it in the freezer of the hotel
and
they're taking turns
spending time with Aaron.
So guy will be there at
the hospital with Aaron,
Wally's in the other hospital and other
guys at the hotel and they're flipping
back and forth, which is a
little testament to like, well,
the way it is for team guys are just
looking out for [inaudible] take care of
you. Like you're in the hospital,
want someone's gonna stay with you
24 hours a day. It's awesome. Right?
So one of the guys that's back at the
hotel room decides that either he's got to
go somewhere and he wants to put the
hand in the other guy's freezer or he's
gonna play a joke on one of the other
guys and put the hand in his bed.
And so he comes up with these different
Roos to try and get the hotel staff to
let him into the room and they're not
having any of it because he looks kind of
shady or mean. He's a team guy. So
he, so he's telling him, Oh hey,
you know my friend left his phone
in the room, can I get in there?
And they're like, well no. Or Hey,
well no, actually it wasn't his phone.
It was his ID ready to go. Like
all that stuff that, that come,
they're shutting him down cause
he looks like a criminal. Yes.
So then he leaves to go to the
hospital I guess. But they're suspect.
They're suspect the poor may goes in
there and finds a hand in the freezer.
I have a picture of it. It's horrible.
It's all gray and just like
ripped off right there.
So Adam's family style? Yes.
And so they of course call the police.
The police show up and they just
detain every course of course.
And then Aaron's in the hospital and
all the nurses come up and they're like,
hey, all these police are calling
here. They need to talk to you,
something about your hand.
So he's got to get on the phone and
explained to the police why his hand is in
the thing.
I think they probably validated something
with the doctor too and you know,
calm him down that this wasn't
some kind of murder and a
okay.
Then they kind of settled everything.
They threw everybody out of the motel.
Aaron gave his hand to the
taxidermist. He had a nice,
what they call European Mt. Where the
tax and dermis and Texas is awesome.
So they,
they mounted like the skeleton hand is
in this really cool mountain inside glass
all done up for him. And uh,
Aaron just had,
he had the best sense of humor
about the whole thing, you know,
if you're going to get depressed,
I mean losing a limb is,
it is a pretty good
way to do it, you know,
and in a lot of ways he's like some
of the stuff you see out of guys like,
you know, Travis mills where it's just
funny, you're not guys like that. You're,
you're not going to bum them out. Just
going to keep them going. But yeah,
hysterical.
So then that's obviously
one of the many stories.
How does that translate to like
when you're dealing with your,
with your family? Like, so
for instance, my wife, when I,
when I had to go to college,
I had to go to the nurse San Diego and
he says my first time in my adult life
that I wasn't like in a
platoon. And so I was,
I didn't really think about it,
but all of a sudden I didn't have
anyone to like attack verbally all day.
Cause when you're a seal platoon,
it's just constant, you know,
attack and combat, verbal combat,
sometimes physical combat.
And so when I would come home from school,
of course there's my wife and I want
to have some verbal sparring matches.
So I start hacking away at her, you
know, and finally, after three months,
she goes, she goes, she goes, she's
a bright, you know, she, she says,
Hey, I'm not a team guy. You know? And
when she said that to me, I instantly,
I instantly realized exactly
what she was talking about.
And I knew she was 100% right.
I can't treat my wife as if
she's an e five and a seal,
you know? And
especially like the weapons cleaning
table when we're all stuck there cleaning
weapons is when guys would
just, that's when the,
you would look for weaknesses in any spot
in any guy and just start, pick, pick,
picking, waiting for the reaction.
Yeah. You spend so much time with
people and so much time just waiting,
you know, it's a hurry up and wait
thing. So, oh, what do you want to do on,
on a four hour fan ride? We're
going to destroy someone,
get into a fight, spilled
Cheetos everywhere, you know,
just like total chaos and mayhem. But
yeah, it's all about that. But that,
but I guess what I'm asking
is, I know, you know,
Iris obviously had to get a,
what's the word, indoctrinated into
the life of [inaudible] cause you know,
I met my wife when I was pretty
young and you were not that young.
No. And so you, you know, you, how'd
that work out? Like the ideal wife, the,
I don't wanna say ideal on a throw
that on you pour iris, listen to this.
But the squared away,
let's say that just squared away
spouse was that look like it.
So I gotta go back to,
if you look at my career and you know
this because you said this to her,
when did you on the podcast,
like she used the best thing that ever
happened to me because she's completely
squared away and it's because
she's so solid and independent.
And so there was never,
ever any aspect of me having to worry
about the homefront and there is a
constant,
she's like very dialed
in and challenges me.
Like a lot of my,
I had a lot of like pretty
far right political views.
And then when we sit down and
have discussions and stuff,
she's really opened my aperture
up on that. But you know,
you look at her history where she, uh,
she worked on ranches where she was only
female wrangler with a whole bunch of
cowboys. So she, she got it.
She had that aspect of what it's,
what it's like to be around.
And then around guys and then when I'd
be messing with her like that, you know,
she just, same deal as Helen, let me know.
Just put you in check
basically. Yeah. And the,
okay.
You know, this,
this job that we have where we're
constantly going forward in harm's way and
they're there.
I chose my words kind of part a poorly
on the last podcast when I was talking
about her, I said that she put up with a
lot of stuff that other women wouldn't.
It meant that that gives the indication
that she tolerated a lot of shenanigans
negative.
She was the strength that she had to
have to be home while I was on combat
deployments and then deal
with me when I came back.
That strength.
Yeah.
Most, most women just can't deal
with that kind of lifestyle.
Okay.
And don't have that kind of,
what were the words that you used
on the last podcast she put up with?
A lot of times I said, and so that,
that was a really poor choice of words
because it indicates like she was just a
pushover and she is an absolutely
not a pushover. Yeah. It's
more like she had the strength
to contend with the, the,
the hard life that it is exactly like
being married to some guy that's going on
constant deployment
and isn't around a lot.
And then when they're gone
by the way they might die,
they might come back
horribly wounded, whatever.
And you sign up for that as well.
And she's working long hours
and raising two little kids.
Well, I'm going on six month deployments.
Okay.
Yeah. And then she's, she also
like in, in
I pretty much, I stayed in contact
with her pretty often. So we,
we pretty much talked at
least three times a week,
three times a week on
deployment. And uh, um,
and that's the model that worked for us.
I've described it and I
forget who I described,
it tears emotional
independence like my wife had,
has and had enough emotional independence
that she was just going to run the
show. If I'm not there, not freaking
out, you know. And I think that's,
if you're going to look for
a good spouse, they gotta be,
you can't be, they can't
be codependent. Right.
Cota band is actually actually
like a bad thing. Right?
I mean that's an an actual bad thing,
right? Codependency. Yeah. So, yeah. So,
but if you go to the other end of the
spectrum or not, maybe, I don't know,
maybe there's, I guess if you
go too far on that spectrum,
then you get to where, hey, I don't
even, Oh, you're gone. I didn't,
I wasn't aware of that. Sorry, I'm over
here doing my own thing. Is there you,
but you've got to find
a good strong balance.
Probably leaning towards
independent, in my opinion,
you've got to be leaning Independent.
Cause if you're not leaning
towards independent, I mean
when you don't get the,
you know, it sucks being here
by yourself for six months.
It's not a true partnership. If, if,
if they're not equal, right.
If you're kind of not equal footing and
one person really needs the other one,
um,
then then the partnership at ship
aspect of it is it's not there.
Yeah. That's uh, that's
something to pay attention to.
Cause the thing that's kind of weird is
when you're young guys get suckered into
the being, ha, it's,
it feels all empowering to have
someone that's all dependent on you.
You see what I'm saying?
When you're young and you've got the Carl
and she's all dependent on you and the
world revolves around you, and
then when you're not there,
she's falling apart and you feel, oh
yeah, I'm the man. And so it's easy.
I think that I've seen that happen a
lot where guys get suckered into those
situations and that's not
a good situation to get.
It never works out because
then they're like, well,
and then she's in a situation,
if it's that kind of girl,
she's going to find someone else to take
care of her while you're not there to
take care of her. Um, and then
the case with IRS is like,
we're inside the same box as far as,
uh, just the things that we enjoy, where
we want to be in the outdoors. It's,
it's all the same thing. So, you know,
it's like I said in my retirement
ceremony, when I look, look,
I look at the trajectory of my career
and then when IRS and I became together,
I went from platoon chief to master
chief first time up every time and just
hammered it because she was a good partner
and she drove me to be better and is
always driving me to be better.
It helps to have somebody that's
super squared away like that.
You know what that does?
It forces you like you're not dude's
doing it for yourself because it's easy.
It's sometimes easier to
let yourself down, right?
It's easier to let yourself down
than to let down this person that's,
that's looking at you thinking, Hey,
you could do better than that. Come on.
Are you serious right now? And that's
the kind of stuff that you'll say to me.
You know, she's very straight
forward and I'll be cold.
I'll just say check. Got It. And then we,
we've gotten to the point where we can
give each other pretty honest feedback
without there being any resentment
involved. I've been pretty
straightforward with iris on some things.
We're working on some projects together
and it's pretty cool for me to be able
to just be real straightforward with her,
you know? And she's like, no, tell me.
We'll actually know how to, she says it.
She says no, go ahead and tell me. Yup.
Jack. So you know, speaking
of Afghanistan, um,
your, you, you, you, you did
the last time you on, you know,
we breezed through Afghanistan pretty
quick. We did. But that was actually, uh,
a really, um,
pretty big deployment in terms
of what you guys did there. Yup.
And I know there were some details that
you wanted to get into on some of those
operations and some of the things that
you brought home from those operations,
lessons learned, et Cetera. I mean,
you were talking about one earlier
talking about the mall deuce and bringing
them all deuce. That's it. That's it.
That's a good piece of gear
to bring out on an operation.
Yeah. And usually you got it marked
on, mounted on top of a truck.
But uh, um, when we did
that, that operation, uh,
as frag o six and a CJ engine and we
actually went into Marsha and the element
that I was with was in a blocking position
that was looking down a road that ran
east west and we were the furthest east
position so we were locked in position
on, on that direction.
And where we got dropped off was really
close to where we were going to stay for
four days. So we were, you know,
we brought him mortar and we brought the,
the m to HB heavy barrel,
50 cal machine gun with the big
a tripod for it and everything.
How'd you break that up? How
many guys would carry that?
That's a lot of weight to carry, man.
You talked to Tim about the ammunition
and the weapon and the tripod. Well,
they ammunition got pair dropped into us,
but the initially, the initial insert,
we had an eight ATV on the helicopter
and a lot of that stuff was loaded on the
ATV.
Plus we were inserted maybe
200 yards from the position,
so everything was kicked
out of the Hilo got staged.
We went and cleared the building and
then hauled everything over there and set
it up and we'd done all the, you
know, the imagery set up for, okay,
here's what we're going to be, here's
where our firing liens, all that.
All that stuff was pretty
much set up ahead of time.
Once you guys were doing that. We
started the guys and trade at that.
We were putting through training, started
doing it, started carrying them in.
There was some big team guy, oh
he just got back from deployment.
I know exactly who you carry the 50 cow.
Like he looked like he was carrying a
60 he did and it was a legit good to
watch. His nickname was pig nips.
His nickname was picnic and he's
a beast. I know he's listening.
Good on Ya. That's one of the,
one of my favorite nicknames.
You don't want to have some feature
about you that gets noticed in the days
cause everyone's gonna
call you by some weird day.
And the funny thing
about him is he is super,
he's a big guy and he's super intelligent,
just good good guy
everywhere you measure it.
So we set this thing up in a window in,
you know, inside. So just the
barrel was sticking out and uh,
of the compound that we were holding
aiming right down the east West road,
cause our, our biggest fear is a,
a vehicle born IED coming down that road.
And along across that road there was this,
there was like a hedge row and there was
a little irrigation ditch over there.
And so the Taliban kept coming down
that hedge row and firing at us from the
trees and then just put
that 50 on the tree line,
stitch it like at Shin level
because that would be Chester,
a little bit high level for somebody in
the ditch and just send up belt all the
way down and back and then
push them back further.
Well at one point some guys had come up
from a different direction and they were
getting really, really close in
this treeline, bad guys, bad guys,
Taliban guys. And we could not
traverse the gun over far enough.
So we tried to shove it out the
window, it wouldn't go out the window.
So me and a EOD warn
officer who was with us,
and then, uh, one of my
[inaudible] who right now he's a,
a troop SCA over at one in the seal
teams drug lifting out and put it in the
street and just started laying it down.
So he got the 50 cows set up in the
street right out in front of our compound.
And for a second there we
were taking heavy fire,
pretty heavy fire, PKM fired,
but it was all going a little bit high
and we just kept stitching, stitching,
stitching, and then they were
done. They broke contact.
They didn't not like
that big gun. In fact,
the next day it kind of slowed down for
us because they didn't want to come,
you know, they did. They're like,
ah, we'll find a different direction.
Because we were holding, you know,
basically four square blocks.
So they started penetrating in
from, from different directions. Uh,
the later on, two days later,
guys pushed out to another building that
was about a hundred yards in front of
the position and they got
into a little tick up there.
So we started lighting up the area that
we thought they were taking fire from.
And the 50,
cal was so loud that they thought that
they were taking direct fire from the 50
cow when we were shooting.
So the rounds passing by them and the
rounds passing by them are so loud and
knocking dust off the wall.
That's why I was saying I can't even
imagine what it would be like to be in a
building in, you know,
that one situation that Tony was in
where there's so much light and you're
building up with several hundred rounds?
No, the, the brew blue situation,
those guys put a 150 rounds into 150
rounds and 50 cal from Todd or no,
20 meters away. I mean from the corner.
It was a building on the corner and they
stopped in the corner and just shot.
And those guys coming out of that building
after we got the thing under control,
I mean I kicked open the door,
I saw Tony there and and then,
but and Tony looked pretty much
just like normal Tony. Yeah.
Everyone else in that building look like
they just saw death and they actually
just did see death. I mean they're in a
building, they get 150 rounds of 50 cal.
The guy that was on the roof,
he was, he, he was telling me,
he would tell me this like a year ago
like we were just talking about and he
goes, he goes, yeah, I got out my pistol.
I 100% thought that we were going to
get over Ron and I was going to die if I
didn't just take around through the
concrete into my head. Right. Yeah.
So did they know it was blue and blue
or they think that I'm just getting
hammered by, well one of the, one of the,
one of the many little like
components of this. So that guy,
the guy that was on the rooftop that
I was talking to [inaudible] 12 hours
before he was in another position
and he got lit up with a disco,
a 12.7 millimeter, you know, weapon,
which is the Soviet equipment of a 50 cal.
For those of you that don't know, he
got lit up with that and hit with RPGs.
So he said, I remember him as soon as
you know, as soon as this was all over,
we got back to base. He, he,
that's another thing he told me,
but he told me this way back
then. He said, he said to himself,
I can't believe the guy with the
dish guy found me again. He was so,
he was so, and we were only, you know,
a couple of days deployed and that
same guy. So when he got lit up,
he was in, he was in,
he was on Camp Corregidor in an Overwatch
position looking for ID and places.
He's sitting there on his sniper rifle
and all of a sudden he starts taking
machine gunfire and it's a dish cup.
And then he gets hit with a couple RPGs.
Well I'm inside with the company
commander from, from the,
from one of the companies from
the first and five oh six.
And we were planning an operation
that we're doing the next day.
So we start hearing gunfire and
all of a sudden we hear RPGs, boom,
boom. And I said to him,
the machine gun fire starts.
And he goes, oh listen. I was like,
where a contact. And I go, hey,
my snipers are up there. Don't worry
about it. Like just Jocko the bad-ass,
right. And all of a sudden boom,
boom. So we hear the RPG set.
So we go running outside and
um, I'm still just, I say,
hey, don't worry, my
guy's got this end. Right.
As those words are coming out of
the bottom of the sniper tower,
cause we, we were right next to it,
out of the bottom of the
sniper towel out pores.
That guy who I'm sure will
be on the podcast one day
he comes pouring out of the
tower, his, his weapon,
his sniper gun had been blown like
the stock up blown off bro by the RPG.
And He's, he just looks like, oh
my God. You know what I said? Okay,
well maybe not. It was horrible. But
so that's the guy when they're getting,
when they're getting shot up with
50 cal. Yeah. He just thought,
and the rest of the guys do, cause
everyone knew that this had happened.
Know we briefed it. Hey, hey, just
imagine the PLO going out to this.
I'm saying, hey guys, these guys have
disc, a 12.7 millimeter, you know,
anti aircraft gun out there.
So be ready for some significant
heavy weapons. And sure enough,
that's the guy on the
rooftop thinking to himself,
I can't believe this guy with the
disco founding again. Yeah man.
The end.
And that was one of the big lessons
learned when I got to trade at where guys
would put 50 rounds of 50 cow into
a building with blanks, you know,
simulating combat and,
and then we'd have a trade that guy in
there that would get up and shoot someone
and they'd be like,
that's bullshit. You know,
the guy that that would never happen.
And I'm like, Oh yes, it would happen.
You know, you, we had guys survive
25 millimeter chain gun from,
from Bradley's and still stumble out
of, you know, not friendlies. Not, not,
not for me, but, but uh, you know,
there was enemy that made it out
of buildings that had whatever,
however many rounds,
a bunch of 25 millimeter chain gun
rounds coming out of the building.
They were coming and going into
your building and they'd still live.
So you don't know what's gonna
happen with bullets, you know,
you just don't know. It's
hard to tell. And that, yeah,
frustration in the blame casting
that goes on some of that training.
We'll get into that that later. But man,
Gosh that that 50 cal is
such a bad ass weapon.
Yeah. Period. And then, you know,
later on we had those things
mount on our trucks and uh,
the clearance of Mozel guys were Stopping
v bids that are completely armored
with those things. Just hammering on him.
But then it's on a crows remote system
and what does a number,
that's just a beautiful thing.
It's incredible that that gun was made
in the early 19 hundreds. Yeah, yeah.
For sure. John Browning. Yeah.
That's an incredible weapon.
Use the exact same weapon today. That's
amazing. That's a feat of engineering.
Someone was asking me when I posted, uh,
pictures of all the brass all over the
floor of that room on, on Instagram.
They're like, oh, did
you have any jams? Oh,
we know how to set our head space and
timing. Got The gauge right there on it.
Boom. That's it. That's an awesome
weapon. Now another way, you know what,
you were telling me another one
about getting extracted in like a,
like a, like, like a Russian, like hip 17.
So the, um, we went into this
operation in Zari parents way,
which is a really,
really hot area and we didn't like to
drive anywhere because Afghanistan's
limited, you know,
it's limited roads and so
they're IED threat was huge.
Plus there were culverts everywhere,
so they would just pack all the,
a covert full of explosives and it
could blow up like, you know, to me,
uh, amwraps would kill
everybody that, and uh,
so we didn't have helicopter
support for this one operation,
but we were working with the DEA fast
teams and they had their own Hilo support
and they had these [inaudible] which are
these, you know, Russian helicopters,
which are super durable
helicopters and uh,
um, contracted, you know, American pilots
in them obviously. Okay, that's cool.
And so they had this operation
and they're like, hey,
you guys want to go on it
with us? So we're, you know,
we're the main force on that. And it
was during one of our turnover ops.
It was actually the op after
the, the a when Dan lost his leg.
So we did to two and uh,
get dropped off first
thing in the morning,
go in clear to compounds and we found
a whole bunch of a on that there were
fields and fields of marijuana around
here. And then on that operation,
one of the compounds just
had a whole bunch of Hash,
was like huge burlap sacks of,
of Hash. And I think,
I think they said there was 200 pounds
and in the middle they destroyed it.
And so it was the typical thing that
happened. Women and children left.
Fighters came in and then
we were in, you know,
a three 60 firefight and
we're in the firefight and over
the radio we're hearing from,
from our aircraft overhead,
they're saying, hey,
there's a white van
and
it's dropping fighters off
around you. So this white,
this white minivan is driving off,
picking up fighters and then driving a
big circle around us and dropping off
fighters.
So this is like an hour later
firefights that thing I did the story.
So about an hour later
there's, they're like, hey,
the white coming over because I'm a,
I'm on dual calm so I can
hear on the fires net and,
and that's like the other radio frequency
outside of inner squad comms for
those,
if you don't understand that is just this
one where the aircraft are talking and
when we're where we're all talking and
I'm on both of them and I can hear the
aircraft saying that white van is back.
And so all of a sudden I'm
looking straight north at
200 yards and I see a white
van pull into the open and stop
in, you know, in an alleyway.
So get on the radio.
Where's that white van
and is it directly north?
Our position and the aircraft comes
back. Yeah, I had just dropped off.
Two guys in there stop. They're
looking at you right now.
Crack that crack two rounds and then a
60 gunner just moes the thing down and
they're just done through, well,
firefight just kept going.
Now the MRI seventeens
they can't fly after dark.
They didn't have some
kind of certification,
so they had to come in there and do a
hot extract on that LZ to get us off.
So there's, there's bullets
flying all over the place.
We get stacked to set our breakout,
so everyone's kind of broken down from
their position. We slept security,
they're there setting up the LZ.
And then my job as the senior enlisted
guy on my aircraft was I run out,
I'm the first guy to the aircraft and
I count guys getting on and on the last
guy on that aircraft.
So that aircraft isn't going until I
have whatever number of people getting on
it, getting on it, everybody's piling
on there. I got a full head count.
I'm like, I got a full head count
and there's no seats for me.
So I gotta hop on the ramp and hook
an arm through one of the guy's legs.
My feet are dangling off
the ramp as we take off.
And then I'm shooting just half ass from
the hip because it's fun just for John,
the qual, just for the call of the
apocalypse and now qual at at a,
you know, a place we were
taking fire from as we took off.
And then we got out of there.
That was a, it was a lot of fun.
I going to stop short of saying as awesome
cause I'm not going to use that word
anymore, but it was pretty Dang awesome
right there. That's the consequences.
Yeah, it was.
They no one got hurt. No one got
wounded. Not In that one. Nope. Amazing.
Like you said,
all these bullets are flying around and
it's just incredible because just the
laws of chance.
Yeah. Well those aircraft
too, you know, it's like, um,
those old school aircraft, like when
you read about the Vietnam guys,
and I'm reading a book right now, those
aircraft, they were flying these kings,
they were,
they had a Vietnamese pilots in these
king B Aircrafts and those things,
they, the guy came back from one
off, they had 48 holes in it,
been shot 48 times. And,
and this American SF guys looking at
the aircraft and if he's looking at the
pilot he's getting in like you were
and he gets in and he's looking at this
Vietnamese pilot and the
Vietnamese pilot looks cool.
He's just like Roger and I've
got to use a great quote.
The guy says something along
the lines of when I'm flying,
I'm just thinking about flying.
I'm not thinking about bad guys,
I'm not thinking about bullets, I'm
just flying my aircraft. If it's my day,
it's my day period and the story. But
that coming into hot extract like that,
that's catch and those guys, they,
they come in super fast
and super low speeds,
speeds on their side and
it is sketchy. It's a,
I was in a random Russian
aircraft helicopter.
A hip or what are you, am
I 17 I guess the, the, the,
the NATO term is like a hip. But yeah,
I was in Africa working and,
and that's like we needed to get somewhere
and the only thing they could get us
was he contracted contracted
helicopters but there was,
but it was contracted pilots too.
And I was happy to land on that one.
Those are a pretty common side
over there in Afghanistan.
A lot of the other other
agencies using those.
And somebody had told me, and I
don't know if this is true or not,
that they were, they were so inexpensive,
it wasn't worth doing
the maintenance on them.
So when they got to a
maintenance schedule,
they just destroy it and buy
another one. That's crazy. Yeah.
And I don't know if that's true. You know,
that's something I heard from some
guy over at the Chow Hall who yeah,
who was well informed apparently.
But those pilots were so,
so good and they, you know,
they were all probably ex TF,
one 60 guys that were now hired on by
these other guys that do the job over
there. I was incredible. So speaking of
wounded or in that case, not willing to,
but you were telling me a story about, um,
and I cut you off so you
didn't tell it to me.
You were telling me a story about a
Taliban guy getting shot in the leg. Yeah.
So last time I was telling you the story
about the last time I was telling you
the story about the uh,
the operation where we'd set
pop flares out cause guys were,
were able to get so close to
us and during that firefight,
one of our firing positions up on a
roof, they're like, hey there was,
there was someone that had circled
around kind of behind our position and we
weren't taking any fire
form. They were in, in,
in the process of trying to
flank us and they're like,
hey there's a guy back here and
we just shot him. We killed him.
So stuff calmed down and I talked
to the t u commander. I'm like,
Hey I'm going to press out with these
two guys cause it appeared as if it was
like right around the corner around this
wall and we're going to go see if the
guy's got a radio on him
or anything like that.
So we push out of the compound and we
loop around a wall but it's not just one
wall, it's several walls and we
get a little bit farther away.
So we round the corner where the guy's
supposed to be and there's no dead guy at
all,
but there's a guy standing 30 yards
away on a hill and he shooting at me.
So I have got, I'm patrolling
with my scar heavy,
but I folded the buttstock like a dummy.
And because I, you know, I thought that
was a cool way to patrol. And so now
I'm like, oh no, I can't
shoulder my, my scar.
So I just tried to lock it
out on like five ks. Yes.
Lot Punch it out, dude. Just punch
it, squeezed at him, missed him.
And then it had a stove,
pipe and a g a fee jam.
So I just took a knee and
started to reload and then
cleared the jam real quick.
Started shooting again, but
he was gone. And then, uh,
he turned up again when, uh, when we had,
when we went to do our
extract the following day,
we had to clear a couple
buildings near where, uh, uh,
the Hilos were going to land.
And then we found that same guy
with his leg all bandaged up.
They, they didn't kill them.
They just shot him in the leg
and then we just wound up,
you know, leaving him there.
W so like,
so was that the last time you patrolled
with your scar or have you with the
stock folded it and then, you
know, on another op it was, it,
I learned the lesson of never taken off
my body armor and helmet because it was
hot. Yeah. What happened on
that one? Oh my goodness.
So we were, um,
it was a operation Swally caught where
we'd taken high ground above a couple of
compounds that we'd cleared and
the next day the towel, we,
we'd gotten to the point
right where we had,
we'd started to get a little
bit complacent and all
our engagements with the
Taliban, we'd always had the upper hand
against them. We'd a, uh, completely,
we had air power, we had better
weapons, we were trained better. Yup.
And on this operation we had a, uh,
a piece of high ground right
behind the compounds that we took.
Was everyone wearing, was that
when you use an AA cogs on their,
on their scars generally, or what were
they using guys? W variety of a cogs.
The snipers actually took the,
the scopes off their Sr 20
fives and put them on the, uh,
the scar everyone had basically
everyone had scopes and so lots of them.
And we had 300 s winmac sniper
rifles. So we brought along on this,
I'm just thinking mentally from the
viewpoint of where the enemy's at.
Like you're reaching out and
touching them accurately,
way further than they can
get you. Pretty much, which,
which again will leans towards
you thinking to yourself,
we're going to kick these
guys ass every time. Yup.
And then you did kicked
your ass a bunch of times.
And so then these guys start to take on
high ground all around all our positions
and we can see a guy pushing out
with a PKM onto this flat ledge,
a rock.
He's 1100 yards away and we're
shooting at him with a 300 wind magnet.
It's windy and we're missing,
we're missing clothes.
And he'd go back and then come
back out, go back, come back out.
And they were getting set up all around
us and then they just brought it.
They let us go with a salvo of uh, um,
rocket propelled grenade grenades
and then just steady PKM fire.
And we thought there 300 yards out,
they really can't do that much. Oh it's,
you know, 105 degrees out.
So we'll take our body armor and helmets
off and then they just laid the hammer
down. Luckily for me,
I happened to be right on top of my
body, arm and helmet cause I was in,
in the prone position and then I just
was able to snake into my body on my,
get my helmet back on my
head. And you know, in this,
this is a position where this is the
first time we'd been somewhere where we
couldn't feel sand back.
So we just stacked a bunch of rocks as
best we could to a fighting position.
And the bullets were just
steadily hammering the rocks
and hammering the rocks
and hammering the rocks. And
I was thinking, man, alive,
I'm going to get shot. And I
wonder if it's going to hurt,
but it's definitely going to happen.
The odds are odds are there and
somehow I didn't. And then a,
then B, a, B,
one bomber came on station and dropped
a whole bunch of ordinance and laid the
hammer down. But after that,
and I ran out of water,
we all ran out of water up on this
high ground position. It was like 112,
14 degrees at two in the afternoon we
ran under water and there was no getting
any water until uh, that
night when the sun went down.
Did you listen to that podcast with
Ron Sugar on? I'm sure I did. Yeah.
SF Guy. A medal of honor recipient.
But if you go watch the
videos. Oh, that, yeah. Yeah.
The like the castle that
they're attacking. That's
crazy. Just straight up hill.
I was just, I couldn't believe that I,
I, when I, when I, as I was reading,
like I was reading a bunch of articles
about this situation and then they kept
talking about video and I said, okay,
I'll check out youtube. And I saw it back.
I couldn't believe it. I couldn't
believe it in the way he described it.
It was just incredible. He just laid it
out there. He's like, Oh yeah, you know?
Yeah, he's so understated.
He's like, well, you know,
it was a little bit of a hill and there
was a pretty big building [inaudible] it
was a cliff and there was a
castle on top of the cliff. Now
if we get a awesome guy, you don't.
Other things that we were
talking about and you made,
obviously this is good
leaving Afghanistan,
but it's getting back early
in your career when you were,
when you failed the stocking section of
sniper school and then you went back and
you and you, you obviously made
it through, you pass us the,
the stocking section. And you kind of
touched on it when you were on last time,
but I was wondering like a little bit
more granularity on what you changed that
you went from failing the
stocks to alright, here's,
here's me knocking out
whatever. A 10 yeah.
And it comes down to basically doing what
I'd been taught [inaudible] and people
were telling me is that
you start the stock,
you're told to find the oop, which
is, you know, 1200 yards away.
And the first thing you've got to do is
figure out where that o p obser and o p
is an observation point and that's where
the the guys that are grading you on
the stock, who are other sniper
instructors, that's where they're at.
And you take that this model,
and I was just thinking how it applies
to problem solving basically across the
board where,
okay,
I need to find a goal in my future here
somewhere. In this case it's the stock.
And then before start executing
on moving toward that,
that goal, going to find that, oop,
I need to take some time and
study the terrain and see what my,
you know, line of attack
is going to be in hell.
I'm going to move all the way up to
where to where I'm going to go and then I
need to put it into action. And
while I'm putting an action,
I'm constantly reassessing that goal
and adjusting my actions across the way.
And that when I went from that
model, I went from, you know,
failing stocks to being
the first one done,
hardly spending any time on
my belly and doing that. So
then you take that and
you apply it to life.
And do you think about just
goal setting? Where do,
where do I want to be in five
years and identify it and then say,
okay, do a little research,
how do I get there?
And then get on that damn path,
stay disciplined and then just keep the
eye on the target and keep adjusting
your aim as you go.
And I can look back at times in my life
where really I wasn't paying attention.
I'm really just treading water, you
know, living paycheck to paycheck,
doing whatever. And now you know, I take,
take that model and I apply it to
where do I want to be in five years,
where all I want my kids to be,
what kind of parent do I want to
be and how am I going to get there?
And what's the path I'm
going to lay out for you?
And this is from a leadership perspective.
Obviously this applies because from
a leadership perspective, if you're,
and I was just on Peter t as a podcast
and we were talking about a little bit
about that strategic
framework, tactical, right?
And listening to that this morning hand,
and you know what I said to him where it
first started to occur to me that was,
hey, if my guys don't know what it
is that we're trying to accomplish,
they can't make it. They can't, they can't
move in there. Sure, I can tell them,
move eight yards forward and then
they can't hear me anymore. Now what?
They're going to wait for me to
get wherever they are. I can say,
go take that building right there.
Well now they can't hear me any more.
So now what are they gonna do?
They're gonna sit there and wait for me
to come up and tell them to do something
else. No, they need to know what
we're trying to get accomplished.
And then they need to have this,
the standard operating
procedures down well enough.
So they end the parameters that
they're allowed to maneuver within.
And that allows us to actually
accomplish the mission.
And that's something I think I, I mean
I don't even know when I learned that,
but without that strategic objective,
and that's a strong word. Okay, I get it.
I get strategic. I get what it means,
and I'm not talking about you know,
global warfare,
but when you're in a town and you
have a mission objective that,
okay, we're going to get to this building
or we're going to move to this area,
or we're going to take this piece
of terrain and everybody knows that.
And even when those things
change, because as you know,
you get into a contact or you get into
a situation where you change what you're
doing. You have to let know that, hey,
we're breaking contact, we're
getting out of here. Hey,
we're going to strongly in this building
or whatever. Once everybody knows that,
then they can act on it. Then
they can carry it out. Same,
same thing that w of what you're talking
about. They're now on a bigger picture.
Of course it still applies on a bigger
picture of if your troops in the field
don't know what it is you're trying to
achieve, then they make bad decisions.
If they don't know that you're
trying to protect the populace,
if they don't know that
that's a broad strategy,
then they get out there and treat
the populace. They act like idiots.
If they know that's what they're
trying to do, then they make better.
I'm not saying they make perfect
decisions because they don't,
but they'll make better decisions
because they understand what that broad
strategy is and it's certainly the same
thing in business and with business that
goes back and forth too because business
sometimes in business your, you know,
I run into it with businesses
where there, for instance,
trying to go public so they need
to make money every quarter.
They can just show that profitability
increase and so the biggest thing they got
on their mind is trying to show a good
quarter and they'll sacrifice some
strategic things like the sacrifice,
a little bit of taking care of a customer
because they want to scrape a little
more money out of it, out of the
situation. That's a bad strategic play,
but they do it short term at the time
because they know they've got to make more
in the quarter so they can
come back and reinvest more so,
but everybody's got to know that
because if everyone thinks, hey, hey,
the number one thing is we never let
our customers down. Okay, guess what?
We lost money this quarter. Now we,
now we can't go public because we,
and again, this is really a
kindergarten level examples,
but that's the kind of thing
where what you're talking about,
if people don't understand
what that longer term goal is,
then they can't really operate and
function on their own, which is a problem.
No, you're not thinking longterm.
You're just thinking day
to day basically. Yeah.
I kind of went off at the muster
on that one kid that asked me,
how often are you thinking strategically
and how often are you thinking
tactically? And you know, I just kind
of was going off about, look man,
every single thing I do is strategic.
I'm not making any tactical moves.
I'm not, I'm not worried about
the tactical wins and losses. Now,
there's a reason for that.
I'm in a good spot right
now where a little tactical
loss doesn't mean that much
to me right now.
And it's really easy for me to just
focus on the strategic stuff. You know,
when I was younger I had to focus more
on some tactical things. You know,
that's the way it is. But
even as a young person,
you got to keep that straight. You know,
you might have to take some tactical,
you might have to,
you might have to make some adjustments
and wind some short torn battles just
cause that's the way it is. But you
should be thinking tactics all the time.
Or sorry, you should be
thinking strategy all the time.
You should be thinking long
game all the time. All the time.
Thinking about the long game all the time,
thinking about how was this decision
affect where I'm going to be in the long
term because the short term decisions,
those are the ones that beat you down.
Yeah. I've turned on that long game nested
inside that longterm goal, you know,
strategy. Yeah. Yeah. I, I actually kind
of appreciated that he brought that up.
Oh totally. It was a
good question. He was at,
and he was a younger guy and you
could see he's thinking, you know,
he'd probably, he probably
thought to himself, hey,
it seems like Jocko keeps
talking about the long game.
And he thought to himself, how
often is Jocko thinking about that?
And so he asked the question
good on him. So I could explain.
I'm thinking about it all the time.
I'm thinking about all the time.
That's the way you gotta do it. And it
beat routine as well for bringing that,
that the whole framework of the bringing
the whole framework and everything up.
Yeah. Yeah, for sure. Aspect of that.
Listen to that. And this morning I'm like,
yeah, this lase. That's the same thing
that makes you successful on a stock.
Choosing that goal and then working
your way to it. Doing your, you know,
and you gotta watch out for the situation
where you get paralysis by analysis
or, and that's caught up by,
you had a time limit on a stock. Okay,
you got three hours to get this done.
So you got to get it figured out
and you've got to get moving.
Or I think a lot of people will fall
into that trap where they do too much
study, too, too much study,
and then they're, no,
you're turning to actual life in
life in general. Sure. In stocks,
guys will run out of time.
I said something the other day, uh,
most things don't get finished cause
most things don't get started then people
won't even start peeling. Even make
that move. Of course. Hey, guess what?
Big shocker. There's a dichotomy
and that's the bottom line.
There's a dichotomy.
If you rush into it and you start
moving without having a longterm plan,
you're probably going to make a
bad move. If you take too long,
you're going to wait too long. And
the whole, it's gonna pass you by.
So you have to constantly modulate and
figure out where you're at and no one's
gonna be able to give you the answer.
I can't sit here and be like, Oh,
you know what you wanna do right
there. You want to make this? No,
no one's gonna be sitting there telling
you that day by day you've got to figure
that out and you got to
figure out if it's really,
really moving you in the right
direction. Yup. Way It's gotta be.
When you were talking about
coming back to trade at,
and you know, you and I both had the, the,
the luck to be at trade at in the
positions we were in. I was the,
I was the trade at OIC.
You were the trade at CMC.
So basically where the senior dudes,
we weren't together unfortunately,
but what a good job and what a good
opportunity to see how things unfold and
what a good opportunity to take these
standard operating procedures and pressure
test them. Exactly. So
I was hit up the other day in a brief
where I was talking about when I was there
as a troop sea and we did our
first FTX and you had just trained,
changed training to where we bef prior
to that and every time I'd been through
land warfare prior to coming through as
as at the troop senior enlisted advisor
in 2008 our FTX is, we're all live fire,
great live-fire school,
but it's so canned because it has to be
for safety that it really doesn't put
any pressure on the leadership and
there's not really any pressure brought to
bear on any of your slps. Yeah.
To put this simply to everyone,
when you're in a gunfight,
there's two horrible things
that the enemy will do.
They will shoot at you
and they will maneuver.
And when you're using
live fire for training,
your enemy is a bunch of
paper targets. At best.
They're mounted on those little carts
that can move around, but they're very,
very limited. No, not even remotely close
to what a human being is going to do.
So when you're going with live fire,
your enemy neither shoots back
at you nor do they maneuver.
So in the seal teams we would destroy
our paper targets all the time.
We would crush them all
the time relentlessly.
We would out maneuver them
cause they couldn't move.
We would out shoot them
cause they didn't shoot.
So it was pretty easy to dominate
and you sure there was that level of,
of stress of the fact that is live fire.
And when you're out like in the
desert you are and you and you do do,
and we still do this where you have to
shift fire and you're walking and you're,
you know, you're, you're making sure that
you're safe cause you can't, you know,
you can, you can shoot each other.
But that type of stress
compared to the stress of,
okay now the enemy we're using,
we're using laser tag guns or paint ball
and the enemy has a full on maneuvering
their full on shooting back at us.
That's a, that's a big step up. Yeah.
And so we just completely epically
that first operation and we took a hard
look at the four biggest things we did
wrong and identified where our standard
operating procedures were flawed.
And then we sat down with our leadership
and we got input and started a Mont
modify those slps too,
so we could build up standard operating
procedures that were resilient enough to
withstand all the pressures that you
guys were putting on us and training.
And uh,
someone asked me [inaudible] at a, uh,
a keynote I was given the other day.
Like, well, didn't you guys have sop
prior to that when we absolutely did,
but they weren't good good enough because
they couldn't withstand the pressure.
So they had to be modified.
We had to modify the way we were
doing slps for getting headcounts.
We had to modify how we were dealing
with our down men. Like, honestly,
we weren't carrying
litters around. We weren't,
but it's just an absolute abject
disaster. If you get a wounded guy,
sure I can drag him off the x.
But now if I patch him up and I got
to throw him over my shoulder again,
I'm going to blow out every bandage I
just put on him. That's stupid. You know,
um, our radio comms going
with when everything is
confusing, we had to fix that.
So we had to dial those slps in
the standard operating procedures.
And the beauty of,
of trade at is that as stuff is
happening on the battlefield,
we immediately modify
that in the training.
And we're putting that on top of the guys
and training so they can see if their
standard operating procedures are good
to go or if they're flawed and they need
to be modified. So we can constantly
modified if people are honest about them.
Yeah. And that's, that's
the beauty of the,
basically the petri dish or the lab
that we had out there at trade at.
Cause the other thing
is we could see when,
when people were being honest about their
mistakes or one guys where were blame
casting and not taking ownership
of what was going on and uh,
and not being honest with the recipes.
And then you just develop these slps
like they don't just apply to the
battlefield. We came up with
standard operating procedures for uh,
you know, how we did our admin
stuff, how we dealt with,
with anything that you can think of.
We would think of a good way to do it
and then test it and then run through it.
So you know, you might not
like this, this analogy,
but I think that sop is kind of our a
life hack because is one of those things
that you can lay,
there is no work.
I know except for the standard operating
procedure is pretty Dang close to one.
Yeah. You know what's, as you were,
as you were talking about that,
one thing that I
definitely noticed is the,
you could have almost 90% of the time
that you use the word modify our sop.
You could have used the word simplify
because most of the time it was someone
saying, hey, we got this crazy we,
this is what we're going to do.
We're going to do this and you can do
that. And it has all these crazy things.
And they realized that doesn't work. So
you make it simpler and simpler. Now,
where that's counterintuitive is like in
extreme ownership where I talked about
doing SSC, and when we first started
doing SSE, the plan was real simple,
just smash everything and just
take whatever you'd find right.
But that was horrible plan and
it didn't work. So we had to,
we had to put something that was a little
bit more looked on the surface to be a
little bit more complex,
even though when you broke down the
individual human beings and what they were
doing, it was a very straightforward
and very simple, so, so yeah. Yeah, no,
there's no doubt that having that
opportunity to watch slps get tested and
either pass or fail, and it
was so obvious either way,
because it was so cool in the tunes.
And the taskings would start to work
together and they'd start to cover,
move for each other, and they'd
start to use the centralized command.
They would, they would
crush the trade at guys,
or they would absolutely would
at least get the best of them.
They'd at least kill them all.
Whereas when they're not doing it,
it would be comical for Che that guys
would kill 40 guys or whatever it was.
Then you just be thinking,
hmm, and and, and you're right.
This is where you'd have ego problems
would show up because guys would think,
and it was so hard from,
from my perspective,
from your perspective
when you're like, listen,
the Trade Ed cadre is going to do the
same there they did the same thing to last
nine troops or the last five troops.
They did this exact same scenario and
and the other troops used simple standard
operating procedures that cover to move.
They use decentralized command and they
they one, here's what you're doing.
This is from my perspective
and I know it's hard,
but what you're doing is you're trying
to control everyone or what you're doing
is you've got these,
these standard operating procedures
that are too complicated or you're not
prioritizing and executing your just,
you've got to follow these simple rules
and it would be hard to convey to some
guys if the guys wanted to put up their
ego barrier and let it offend them and
think no would never happen or no,
that's just the trade that guys
knew what we were going to do. Yeah.
The trade guys know what you're gonna do.
You know what you're attacking
a target area. Anyone, any,
any military mind in the world is going
to get the high ground and then they're
going to sweep through if they can
from high ground to low ground.
That's what the s what
everyone's going to do.
It's not like the trade hat guys
that anybody could figure that out.
Any military mind is going to look at
a target and do it one of three ways or
one of four ways, and 50% of those
four ways actually is going to overlap.
So you don't have to be a freaking
rocket science or scientist or or, or,
or Napoleon to be able to figure
out, okay, here's the target.
Where do I think the seals are going
to come in from? It's like, oh, okay.
They're probably gonna come in from
here. I'll set up two guys there.
There's also a chance they're
gonna come in from over here. Call.
I'll put two guys over there. There
you go. We knew you knew our plan.
It's like, yeah, Bro. The enemy
is, it's like you talked about,
you had situations where you
went in and you're like, oh,
well we'll go get on the high ground.
Oh, the enemy put ids there. Yeah.
Guess what? It doesn't take a
rocket science to figure out, Oh,
if you're going to assault us here,
you're probably gonna want to get this
piece of this piece of terrain over here.
So that would offend guys. And they'd get
into the, hey, this is, this is wrong.
And instead of saying, okay, what
did I do wrong? Can you just,
can you just tell me what I
did wrong again cause I didn't,
I'm not sure I understand it.
Oh well what you did is this,
you didn't prioritize next to you or
you didn't use decentralized command and
they will just fit if you're not gonna
listen to that, you know, it's a problem.
I had a guy at the muster just asking
me about like how do you handle it when
someone really picks
you apart on a debrief?
And I'm like, Bro, you
know I handled that.
I what I do is I look them right
in the eye and I say thank you.
Thank you for telling me
that. Please thank you and,
and I appreciate it and I'm going to go
look at what you just told me and I'm
going to try and figure out if
I can fix it. Because otherwise,
like you, you just, I could
see it in this guy's eyes.
Like he's asking me that question
because his ego is getting offended. I,
everyone's ego gets
offended. Mine gets it.
I get offended when somebody tells me
that when somebody gives me the nine big
debrief points on what I
did wrong, I'm freaking mad.
I don't want to make mistakes. I
even ego just like everyone else,
if not a freaking larger
ego than anyone else.
And when somebody tells me I did
nine things wrong, I'm pissed.
I'm pissed at myself,
and it's really easy for me to look at
you and get pissed at you for telling me
that I screwed this up.
But instead I've gotten old enough
to realize even if I don't like you,
it's even harder if I don't like you.
It's even harder when I don't like you.
It's even harder, right? That's what
makes it super hard. But when you go,
you know what, Eh, you bite down
and you go, okay, thank you.
Let me assess what you just told me.
If you could make that little
step up in your life, it's epic.
And when guys would, to your point,
when guys wouldn't make that step in that
step up in coming through the trade at
training, it would be a nightmare.
It was a nightmare. And the thing is,
man, like I love all these team
guys. I want them to go kick ass. I,
that's all I wanted was them to like
go do great things on deployment.
And when you get that,
the guy coming through that just
would be offended by it and I,
I'd be so bummed out, I'd, you know,
I'd just, I'd be so bummed out.
I'd be like, Bro, I just
want you to do good.
I'm just telling you like don't focus
on a head count when you're in the
firefight. That's what I'm
saying. Yeah. And then,
then you get to the point where
you're just like, oh man,
you're not going to get it now.
I'm just going to make you suffer. Yeah.
But the cause you get,
you'll get critique points
where guys will say, hey,
we need to get an op so we can go
start to finish where you let us win
basically. And you know,
if you're playing football and your
college team goes against the high school
team,
that's not challenging for anybody and
you're not gonna really learn anything
out of it. And that's the learning thing.
That's why I gave you a walkthrough.
And so after seeing that so many times
and running land warfare and I started
going out at the front day one
and saying, hey guys, listen,
you're going to get a walkthrough.
That's your time to work through your
whole script on how you're going to run a
target assault.
But I'm shortchanging you if I'm not
putting pressure on you when we have these
FTX nights,
cause we only have this place for a
limited period of time and this is where
you're going to find where your
weak points are and get better.
And then knowing about myself when I
have those two voices arguing in my head,
the one that's my ego and it's making
an excuse for everything that you're,
that someone who's debriefing me is
picking apart and the other reasonable
voice, which I'm trying to turn
the volume up on, um, that's going,
oh yeah, that's a fair critique. Yeah.
Well I got a little lazy there.
Shouldn't have taken my body armor off.
Uh, that, that kind of stuff.
Or where the worst was like the OIC that
would come out after you were OIC in
he,
if he came out to training and he would
find some stuff that was screwed up and
he's like, why am I the one
fixing it? And I'm like,
you are exactly right. And
guys who get angry, he's like,
you'd come down here and he calls
us out. He goes, we deserve it.
Let's not do this ever again.
We cannot have our boss coming out
here and looking at how we're running,
training and calling us
out. And a lot of it was
for, I'll give you an example,
go out to an I ads range and a platoon
is decided to have their 60 gunner walk
point because that's going to work
good for an immediate action drill.
But that's not what you're really
going to do. That's patrol to contact.
That's not what we're training in an
immediate action drill when we're training
for a sucker punch and he's like,
what in the wide world of sports
is going on here? And we'd be like,
yeah, but guys wouldn't
want to tell the platoon.
It'd be one of these small things
where, and I failed in this.
And in leadership a lot of
times where it's just like,
oh I'll just let that
slide, I'll just let the,
I'm pretty soon everything's sliding
and you're not really given people any
guidance. But uh, um, yeah,
people comment,
you gotta be honest with the critique
and look at it and then move forward.
And at the end of the day you always kind
of know when you're wrong and to take
ownership of it, you feel better about it.
Cause now you have power over it,
right? And then it's like, Oh,
if I think that the trade ed staff is
cheating now I'm powerless against it and
it's just kind of a stressor that I'm
deal. Exactly are just going to win.
It doesn't matter. Blah
Blah. And then it's,
it's also on on a trade debt. It's,
and it's difficult to to debrief people
and not come off as condescending.
That's a real skill. And that's the,
some guys are really good at that and
that's something I tried to work on and
I'm not perfect at it.
But to give people constructive criticism
in a manner that they'll accept it,
that it doesn't want to like on poker
talked about that and traded is you don't
really have a good relationship with
50% of the guys that are coming through.
So some guys that come through, like
when you're coming through I'm like,
hey bro, like we, I could just like
be pretty straight up with you guys.
I don't really know you and you're from
like a different team and I never worked
with you before. So I have no sort of
sort of relationship and then it's harder,
you know, to say, hey man, that
was a really bad job, you know,
now I don't know. I what I,
what I ended up doing the trade
out was I would just be like, hey,
this is what happened,
you know? And by the way,
I recorded you on my audio thing.
Like I would carry a little voice
recorder and then when people would be
panicking or freaking out, I would record
them and I'd say,
you were kind of freaking out out there
and you'd see them olds and freaking out
and be like, okay, listen to
this. And everybody was like,
does that sound like freaking out
to your, is that your calm voice? So
the, and the other fun thing
about the dead skier was
you could hit them with the near
miss because if they got killed,
they would get now drugged through the
desert by their ankle and guys didn't
want to die. So they still weren't as
honest about fire as they could be,
but they would still like my favorite
thing to do would be put the God gone,
which is just a regular thing I had
as it lane greater on near Miss.
And if guys were screwing around
like they, they would not, you know,
they'd all be standing up in a perimeter
where they shouldn't be standing and I
would just near miss them all
guys would just dive, dive in.
No real else.
It was like legitimate real routes were
covered out of where they'd hear that
near missing cause they didn't want
to get drugged through the desert for
freaking two kilometers
to the extract point.
Have all their gear be beat
up and bruised, gone punished.
All their liver has to carry. You was
just getting completely punished. Okay.
I'm feel buffalo you smell. Yeah.
Well I would them younger guys coming out.
You know everyone talks about the big
millennials and I'm w from what I've seen
when I, when I talk to the teams and when
I've gone out to some training sites,
you guys are awesome. I think across
the board they are. Yeah. I've,
I mean I've looked at all,
all the new guys and the quality of
the new guys now compared to who I was.
Yeah.
I'm not sure I could have made it through
training if I was compared against all
the guys. Now they're smart,
they're motivated and they're hard and
they're only coming in because they want
to go to a war II. I mean,
cause that's a given.
Yeah. Did I want to go to war?
Absolutely. But it wasn't a known thing.
I got to admit that. I kind of
thought it was, I thought like,
oh I'm going to nom.
I thought I was going to Nob
in 1991 when I got to the team.
But yeah, these guys know for a fact.
I mean they, they, they see, they see,
they see, you know,
memorial services on TV.
They know what's what they're
getting into for sure.
And the, the complaints,
the complaints about the millennials
that I hear are that, oh,
they want to know why they're doing
something. Well, Duh. Yeah. You know,
and you just covered that in that,
that document that was written after
rule or two that says, hey, guess what,
you need to tell guys why they're doing
something or they're not going to be the
most effective. And it's generationally,
generationally,
it's just more blame casting where people
are whining about the next generation
goes back forever. This is normal, right?
I think it's one of those normal whiny
things that you got to be the young suck
[inaudible] no they don't. You suck.
When I was at one of the leadership
courses with some regular navy leadership
and one of the master chiefs was
telling the story that she had any five
[inaudible], she worked in, in,
in supply and she's like, Hey,
I need you to go do the
inventory today. And
she's checked back, comes back
like an hour and a half later.
And uh,
the guy had to go inventory this whole
warehouse and he's hanging out in the
coffee lounge and hour and a
half later and she's like, Hey,
what the heck is going
on here? Should freeze.
Like I did the inventory
and she's like, no way.
But it takes all day. Let's spot check it.
Spot just randomly pulls up a couple
items off that inventory list, checks it.
She's like, how did you
do this? And he's like,
well you know I got this app reader on
my phone and I just went and scanned all
the bar codes,
used his phone and completed the
inventory like that with a little bit of
ingenuity and so basically she just told
him the end state and got out of his
way. It was by accident,
but she got out of his way and let him
figure out how something to do it and
then then went with it.
Nothing wrong with that. Nope.
What about for you as you've gotten older,
what kind of mindset changes have you
gone through where like I've just kind of
talked about one from
my perspective, your,
as I got older I see see different
things and I always try and make that
perfectly clear to everyone
that you know, I kind of
okay,
you know, I learned, I learned
and I'm still learning.
And so, you know, would you, what, what,
what like were some things that if you
could have learned or changed your,
your mentality on earlier?
Like what, yeah, I mean for
shutting down the Ego, uh,
you know,
a lot of my growth honestly is being
married to IRS and is 100% responsible for
her and just shuts down
your ego, shuts my ego down,
but then has on honest
conversations about,
well what are you really thinking
here? And then, you know,
actually listening to what someone's
saying cause the trap I used to fall into
was when someone was talking to me,
I wasn't really listening to them.
I was just formulating what
I was going to say back.
Did that formulating your calendar?
Exactly.
And I probably score a high in
trait disagreeableness yeah.
So you know,
it's just my nature to want to
be at that point of friction.
But that also makes me just, you know,
want to go stick my finger in people's
eyes and offend them and stuff that and
so stepping back and opening my
mind up to other points of view,
um,
and then being a little bit more
cognizant of other people and how they're
reacting to me so I can adjust
how I interact with them. Relation
ship wise, I don't know if you remember
this question at the muster guide asked,
hey, what, what do you do when you,
how do you deal with someone who's
super negative and about, you know,
the, the, the team or
whatever. And you know, I said,
here's a really good leadership
technique that you can use.
It's very complicated. It's called
listen how much you listen to them,
but you actually listened
to what people are saying.
Somebody feels really negative about my
team. Guess what? I want to know why.
I want to actually hear their
explanation as to why they're being super
negative. And by the way,
when you allow someone to voice their
opinion and you listened to them
carefully, instead of
formulating our counterparts,
which is what our instinct is to do, if
instead of you go, okay, what's wrong,
Jason wouldn't mean what's,
what's the problem over here?
I actually want to listen to you. I
want to hear what you have to say.
And that is such an advantage as a
leader instead of always feeling like,
Hey, anybody that steps to me
is getting crushed. Like no,
actually anybody that steps to me,
he's going to teach me something and
I'm happy to hear it. Yeah. Boom.
And then just
are you aware of, you know, by my biases,
my biases.
And then I find this a lot of times with
the Dang media presses the heck out of
my buttons. And so
I got to the point where I just,
I don't watch the news anymore
because the news is, is hard.
It's there to get you angry so you'll
pay attention to it and gets them better
ratings. Yeah.
And a lot of times when I'll see some
really extreme things that they're
claiming people said, when I dig into,
when I actually take the time to dig
into it, it's like not quite what it was.
And now that I've become a
lot more introspective and
so I'm paying attention to
how things make me react.
I'm paying attention to when my face
flushes out or I grip. And I'm like, okay,
now it's time to detach and step back.
I've noticed that that just like,
it's not as not a positive
positive, you know,
thing in my life to have my blood pressure
spiked again and again and again and
again because I've got a 24 hour
news feed coming in. And so,
uh, another teen guy pointed
this out to me. He's like, Hey,
I'm just talking about the news and I
was all angry about something and he's
like, you know what? I quit
watching the news and he goes,
I'm a lot happier since I stopped
watching the news. It doesn't matter.
And I'm like, are you kidding
me? Of course it matters.
But he planted a little seed and
watered it. And then I'm like, okay,
I'm going to quit watching the news
and it doesn't, it doesn't matter.
And I was the point where I'll just
check the news like first thing in the
morning and make sure a volcano went
off. Right now I don't even do that.
If there's a volcano going off,
I'll see the smoke or someone will tell
you that you're going to find out about
it.
The 24 hour news cycles filled with a lot
of things that you don't need to know.
You don't need to know at all. And
that's, that's Kinda the way I am. I mean,
I still look at it, but it doesn't,
it, I'm completely, I, I can look at,
I can look at 19 headlines in a row and
none of them have any remote impact on
my mentality at all until
I see one that says, oh,
there was a terror bombing here. And I
go, oh, okay, let's see what's going on.
Or Hey, there was a US servicemen
killed here. And I'm like, oh, okay.
But every other of the 17
headlines that I read that were,
um, I'm trying to think of a good one
right now cause there's just, you know,
everything is going down and you're
like, okay, fine. Yeah I can get no,
everything's not going down.
The world isn't going to end,
but it's clickbait isn't, yeah, it is.
You guys are the first ones I
heard use that word. I'm like, oh,
that's what that is. Oh yeah, yeah,
yeah. Well what? It's going clickbait,
but it's just clickbait on the TV to
get you to dial in and get them higher
ratings. And then you got to
listen to that. Sam Harrison,
I forget the female's name that was on,
but she did this whole research about it.
They're talking about how the Russian,
the Russian bots and
all that stuff and yeah,
you can create headlines that are gonna
make people click and then you can make
fictional random, you can
just make up stories and peep.
They'll catch fit. You know, someone else
will report that story as being true.
It's a crazy world. The onion joke,
newspaper AP is pick their stuff
up like two or three times before.
Totally nuts. So you got to learn.
You should definitely adult mom learn
to detach when you read the news.
Yeah. And then, uh, something
that I found real helpful is,
is putting a filter on my thoughts.
So the, and this is something that
iris is Kinda talked about. She's like,
the first filter is am I whining?
And then the second
filter is, am I resentful?
And then the third
filter is, am I jealous?
And if I can just catch that
stuff, once I identify it,
it doesn't bother me anymore.
But prior to identifying it,
if I'm just like, oh, someone told just
got a promotion, well that's bullshit.
He, you know, and then, then
I realize, oh, wait a minute,
I should be happy for him for
getting that promotion. Uh,
and Jordan Peterson says something about
be careful who you share good news with
and, and, and I just don't, I, that's
not, that's not something I, I,
I'm proud of when I see it come up in
myself. And it's one of the things that,
that as I age on, I'm trying
to fix. The other thing that,
that as I've gotten older is
I used to be very identified
and now I find myself becoming
more of an individual,
if that makes sense. That makes
sense. And understand this, this is,
that's where I'm trying to go and
this is, this is the path that, uh,
that I'm on and it's a
struggle and it all comes down.
And I kind of wished there
was two words for ego, right?
Cause the ego, if I didn't have
an ego driving me to be better,
I would just be sitting at home
eating chocolate chip cookies on the,
on the college. There's not two
words to describe you to go,
but there is the dichotomy of it though.
And so then you're good to go. Yeah.
You know, uh, what am
I a team guy buddies.
A long time ago you could
use this phrase, which I,
which I always remembered cause
I thought it was really good.
Basically someone was whining
about something and you know,
raise their hand and said, well,
you know, why are we doing this?
And then afterwards my buddy
goes, hey, that's cool.
Put yourself on report for being a bitch.
And so like I've been hypersensitive
to that for a real long time.
I do not ever, you know, I don't
care what I'm broke through,
I will not complain about anything.
Like I am hypersensitive about that
at least I've tried to be. I mean,
you know, cold blocking mockups,
anything, uh, you know, hurt.
Like I hurt my knee and I might need
was all swollen up, all jacked up.
And I didn't tell anyone. I told her,
hey, injured my knee. Nope, no factor.
And finally Lafe was like, Hey,
you know, what's up with your knee?
I sent him a picture, like the knee
is just twice as big as the other one.
He's like, oh my God, are you going to
need surgery? I'm like, no, no factor.
But, and I only sent it to
him like six or seven days.
The swelling had gone down,
but out of the gate I wasn't going
to say anything cause I don't,
I don't want to sit there and complain.
Like, Bro, I hurt my knee doing Jujitsu.
Oh No. You know what I
mean? Like, come on Bro,
I'm not going to complain
about that. Uh, but yeah,
those other things about being resentful
and being jealous when ever I feel that
tinge of what I feel that tinge of
jealousy when I feel that tinge of,
when I feel like I feel like mad
at someone for doing something,
I automatically know
it's me. I automatically,
and I've known that for years there
was a stoner. As a matter of fact,
I was going to, he wanted
to go to Princeton and he,
he said to me, he and he,
I wasn't that, we weren't,
we weren't together at team three anymore.
And so he was talking to some people
and finally he comes to me and he says,
hey man, I want to go to Princeton.
I want to put together this package
and go to Princeton. He said, but, uh,
some of the other people I'm talking
to are telling me it'd be bad for my
career. And I'm like, Bro,
those guys are just jealous.
Uh, that's not happening. I go,
you go and you get your freaking degree
from Princeton. Are you kidding me?
How's that going to be bad for? And he
did. He ended up doing it and he had got,
he got in, he got accepted. And,
but that was one of those things
where it was so obvious to me,
like whoever told you that is just telling
you that cause they don't want you to
have, have another punk card to pull
on you. Cause like, hey, you're stoner,
your, you know, you got a
bunch of combat experience,
you got a bunch of combat awards.
You're, you're this big strapping dude.
And by the way, you're
going to go to Princeton.
Like no one wanted that final
punk card to be issued as donor.
It's hard when you see someone else
that's successful and you know that like I
should be getting up off my ass and
getting into Princeton myself or going,
you know, you can't control whether or
not you're deployed to combat there.
A lot of that other stuff is, and I think
that's where it gets painful for guys.
It's like, okay,
well I'm not going to make the efforts
so I don't want anybody else to make the
effort either.
I'm a crab in this bucket and I'm going
to drag that crab that's trying to climb
out back in the bucket and
this is actually in a way
the warrior kid three this
is why I had to address this,
which in a way the where your could three
you'll have you read it yet. Not yet.
That's one way. The where your kid,
there's a new character that comes in,
his name is Danny Reinhart and
he's like good at everything.
He's better at mark than
ever and everything. He's
like a little bit smarter,
does better on the tests in school and
he's a little bit faster and he can do
more pull ups. And then like to take
the cake because he's a new kid,
moves in and and mark still thinks he's
got the ultimate punk card to pull,
which is I do Jujitsu and I
can choke you. Some of the,
most of the stuff matters.
It turns out Danny Reinhardt's been
trading for two more years and that's
exactly what happens is mark, instead of
saying, wow, I can learn from you. Wow,
you can help me. Wow, that's awesome.
I know you worked hard for that.
Instead he just tries to undermine
and he just is jealous and so that's
something that you deal with when you're
starting to be, even as a little kid,
you know you as even a little kid,
you can be jealous. So checking,
check yourself if you're being
resentful, if you're jealous of someone,
those are like the first things I check
when I start getting mad at someone.
Those are the first things I check when
I start getting mad at someone. I go,
am I being jealous right now? Yes I am.
He didn't say filter is not is not good.
And what's worked out really well
for me is when you identify these,
these people that are good at everything,
keep them around you. Oh for sure.
For sure. For sure. And that's the other,
the other clincher in the way the where
you could three is, is Danny Reinhardt.
He's not only like better,
he's also like a really nice kid and
so that makes mark even matter cause
everyone wants to be friends with
them just cause he's nice. So yeah,
you got to watch out for that.
Check yourself. Don't get that.
I wanted to talk about some leadership
mistakes that you've made and I was
thinking to myself while I could talk,
I could call out Jason for leadership
mistakes that he's made that's kind of
jacked up if I don't talk about any
leadership mistakes that I've made.
Now of course I've listed a bunch of
leadership's mistakes that I've made in
that kind of me of leadership and an
extreme ownership. So there's that.
But I've got a couple that I thought of
and I was trying to think of some broad
ones.
One of them is when I was in Ramadi,
I hate to start off like
that when I was in Ramadi,
I did not do a as good
a job as I should have,
you know, go a little bit further
to keeping the rest of our community
informed as to what was happening and why
it was happening. And to be honest with
you, the reason I say I'll go further,
then I just didn't keep them informed.
I wasn't even thinking about it.
I wasn't even thinking about it when I
got home and one of our good friends said
to me, and he was all fired up and
he's like, we will read in your,
he's like, we read your ars at quarters
every day like he every day at trade at,
at the time while we were in
Ramadi, they were reading the ars,
the after action report for
the, Hey, they killed nine guys.
They killed seven guys in I. That's, you
know, I was like, hey, that's awesome.
That's cool. I didn't
really even think of that.
But what I also didn't think of was guys
that were saying, Hey, wait a second.
What are these guys doing over
there? Hey, wait a second. Wait,
why are you conducting operations
during the daytime? Hey, wait a second.
Why are you staying out
after you get contacted?
Why are you staying in
position? Hey, wait a second.
Why are you working alongside
the conventional forces?
Why aren't you doing stuff
with just special operations?
And I did a bad job of explaining these
things to our community as a whole.
And even when we got back, I had
the opportunity to do it and I,
I spread the word to some people
and was able to explain to them.
But by then some people
had already thought, oh,
well these guys were just over there.
Do we these rogue operations by themselves
and they shouldn't have been doing
it. So that's, that's one,
that's one big one that I wish I
would've done a better job. And I just,
I just wasn't even paying attention.
And you know what, it's like, man.
I mean this is my, this
is my excuse is my,
it's my fault because I was over
there and I'm thinking like, Hey,
we got an operation
tomorrow. I got to, I got,
I got two elements going out in the field.
I'm not worried about
what they're thinking.
I just didn't even think
of it and I should have.
So I don't know if that's an excuse.
It's the reason why I didn't think of
a way I should have and I was wrong for
not doing that. Bandwidth could you've
expended on it though in the moment.
You know what?
If I would have been a little bit
smarter and a little bit better,
I could have taken 15 minutes to
send out an email and say, hey,
everyone want to let you know what
this op was really like because they're
reading the OP sums, right? The
optimum is an official document.
If I could have supplemented
that with, hey guys, Jocko here,
I know this one sounds a little
bit crazy. Here's what's going on.
The Iraqi soldiers that we're working
with, they don't have night vision.
They have one flashlight per fire team
to go out at night with these guys is
completely, uh, it doesn't work.
And so we got to go out
in the daytime with them.
And so that's what we're doing.
Here's why we're doing it. You know,
I could have done it,
I could have expended a little bit and
I just didn't have the awareness that I
should have had to explain these things.
Also to explain them in plain English
because it's one thing to read the OPSM
that's an official document
that's written a certain way.
It's another thing to say, hey guys,
Jocko here, here's what's going on.
And cause I mean let's face it
at that time I'd been in for
a long time and I had
friends everywhere. I mean,
and when my friends would reach out to me,
this is probably should
have been my best indicator.
Some of my friends that reached
out to me and said like, hey dude,
what's going on? Like I
heard you just got a go.
I heard one of you guys got shot.
What's going on? How that happening.
And I had one specific friend of mine
who wrote me like a long email and,
and I wrote him back, right. And said,
hey man, this is what's going on.
But that should have been an indicator.
If one of my friends was reaching out
to me and saying, Hey, what's going on?
I should have been more cognizant
of the fact that people beyond,
and people that didn't know me at all,
you know, would be thinking, well,
you know, well this guy's,
this guy's a hyper aggressive.
And they're just out there taking
too many risks. It's like, no. And,
and what was cool was there were
some guys that were in Ramadi,
other seals that were in Ramadi or working
in and around Ramadi at the time who
I knew and they were like,
Oh, you guys are crushing it.
You guys are doing great. This is
awesome. But I didn't do a good job.
So that's, that's one thing. Um,
I dunno what it looked
like from your perspective.
Where were you when I was over there in
Pei calm poolside at Thailand explaining
to my guys why we had to put the missions
first. Yeah, yeah. Check. Check. Yeah.
But at the time I was excited for
you guys because it was like the,
that was like the first
sustained heavy combat
of that war. Yeah. Everything had been,
we were talking about the big news to
stand around and talk about when you were
at the bar was,
was maybe a tick or a firefight that
lasted five minutes and you guys were
troops in contact 100% of the time.
Every time you walked outside the gate.
Yeah. It wasn't quite that, but it
was a lot. Yeah. And that's for sure.
And that's what, that's what I think.
I think I should've explained that better
than I did throughout the community.
And you know, I still talk to guys.
I still have the opportunity when it,
cause you know, some guys that I'll,
I'll still explain this to some guy that
I haven't seen cause you know how it
is, you run into a guy that you
hadn't seen in 15 years, you know,
and they'll be like, dude, what were
you doing over there? I was like, Hey,
let me explain it to you. I've had
people sit through kind of the,
the Ramadi brief and be
like, okay, I get it.
I get it. Yeah, that makes
sense. Hey Roger. But yeah,
should have done a better job of that
from a leadership perspective. Um,
I was trying to think of
a tactical example of,
and this is real easy story.
One time I personally chase down some
dude over like multiple rooftops as a in
Baghdad, you know,
like just got in a one band pursuit
while I had another guy like trailing me.
But basically we're hitting a target.
There's a squirter I'm outside
the building as it's happening.
And all of a sudden, you know that the,
the overhead asset reports that there's
a squirter and he jumped to another
rooftop and I had a radio man.
The radio man was like near me and we
both know the radio man and he's like,
hey. He's like, oh, you went to the
next roof. And I was like, God, him.
And so I climb up a palm tree
of a climb up a palm tree,
like in between a palm tree and like the
garage and I get to the roof and I get
in and he's like, you jumped to
the next one. And so the radio,
the t j tack is in the street with me
following down and telling me what's going
on. And basically I left my, I
shouldn't have done that, you know,
I should've sent a couple guys and
eventually I got someone else with me and
then we got the guy. But you know, I
just was trying to think of, hey, where,
where did I make some mistakes? Where
that were more on a tactical level.
And that's one right
there is, you know, I,
I'm in charge of the assault and if I'm
out there chasing the guy from rooftop
rooftop, I'm not doing my job. I,
but they did have it on video
[inaudible] and I tried
to get ahold of it,
but of course it's classified
so I couldn't have it. But yeah,
it was pretty cool to watch. You
know, you're doing like par core in,
in Kit punk.
It's called the palm tree and then
jump from roof to roof to roof.
And then eventually they're like, he
said that one right there. And uh, yeah,
so that was one. And then
the last thing again,
I was trying to think of like a
variety of different mistakes.
And here's something from a
leadership perspective that I really,
when I look back, I wish I
would have done a better job.
And that's helping guys with their
finances. Young guys, I mean,
how many young guys enlist?
They get $150,000 reenlistment bonus
and they show up at work two days later.
They've got a new FordF three 50
super duty Harley Davidson a version.
And they have, you know,
they're, they have a,
they have a $62,000
truck that is now worth,
they just had it for a day
and they've now worth 48,000.
So they already lost money and guys that
would rent instead of buy, you know,
just all those things were,
and I wasn't like super at it,
but I was ahead and I should have
been telling guys like, Hey man,
let me talk to you like, hey
guys, let's do a little lips.
Was to talk for half an hour
about where you're at right now.
Let's come up with a strategic objective
of where are you going to be and five
years, you know,
do you still want to be
renting an apartment in IB
because that's probably not
great. Or do you want to be buying a
place, get with one of your buddies.
So I never talked about that
kind of stuff. And again,
what it boils down to is my
own, my own, uh, being obsessed.
Like I didn't care about that
stuff. You know what I mean? I guess
I cared about it enough to do
it. And I got lucky. I had a,
I had an officer one time that said I
bought a house every three years and kept
it. He just said that to me and I was
like, that seems like a really good idea.
And that's what I tried to do,
but I didn't pass that word on and I
could have probably helped out more guys.
So kind of a bummer on
that one. Yeah. Because
that aspect,
and I completely dropped the ball on
that early in my career as well. Later,
later on I got a little bit better
at it, but you know, cause I did 30,
but uh, um, I, I could tell a guy
how to be a good shooter. Yeah.
But then I didn't look at the whole rest
of the Dang pie chart and realize that
if I fixed all that other stuff,
they'd be an even better shooter.
Exponentially better. Right.
And Yeah. That, that,
that was something that,
that actually helping guys, and
there were stuff that this is,
this is something I really failed at
is like, I could see guys messing up,
but I didn't want to
have that uncomfortable
conversation with them to like,
Bro, you gotta you to kind of
fix this. Like, Hey, you know,
you've used the analogy before.
If I have a booger hanging out,
I want somebody to tell me. Yeah.
And so I see get mad at them when he
was talking about I wanted that booker
there. No, I definitely wouldn't.
I had some of those conversations for
sure. And I'm sure you did too. Like,
hey bro, this girl, she's not the one
I'm going to tell you that right now.
Uh, this isn't gonna
work out well for you.
The problem is getting somebody to listen
to that conversation is real hard when
it comes to the ladies. Yeah.
And that aspect of just,
most times it blows up in your face and
then sometimes you're just like, hey,
I realize that maybe I'm going to lose
my friendship with you. True. But, uh,
I got to tell you this, and
later on in my career
when I started to, to,
to start like struggling with anger issues
and that were probably a result of my
combat deployments and started to go
sit down with a psych and I would see,
you know, you were super
angry even before I was,
I was like probably pretty predisposed
to it all. And it just, man,
it just turned it up
to 11. Right. And, uh,
and then I would see myself and other
guys and I would tell him, hey man,
here's the deal. Here's the psychs number.
I want you just to give them a call and
you don't have to see him after that,
but do me this favor.
And some guys that would
help and other guys, the guy,
I made the effort and they'll come
to that conclusion at some point,
but it's like some, you
know, we got to look out,
look out for each other and do the best
we can. And that was something that I,
you know, missed out on. Uh,
I think I probably would have made an
awesome platoon chief about the time I
was, uh,
ops master chief two echelons above it
and really realized what that job was.
Because as a platoon chief, one of the
things that I missed out on was, uh,
that the guys are always looking
at me to set the example.
And so it was one thing during
working hours, I could set an example,
but if I'm a buffoon out drinking too
hard, they're like, you're an idiot.
Or they follow your
example. They, and they,
they'll follow my example and think that
this is acceptable behavior. Uh, if,
if I'm going to bad mouth my leadership,
which is, I'm embarrassed to say it,
but it's the stuff that if I didn't,
didn't really have my aperture open on
the big picture and would complain about
the command and then I complain in front
of the guys just screwing them over.
And I did because they're
like, well, he's whining now.
I'm going to go ahead and whine. Uh,
I had issues where like personally I
didn't like the person that I was working
directly for and that,
that tainted my interaction
with that person.
I didn't have any relationship with them.
And then my whole platoon would suffer
because I had a bad relationship with the
next guy up just cause I didn't like him.
Uh, which is complete weeks off. Yeah.
Oh yeah.
I was having a conversation with
Dave Burke. Good. Guilty. Yeah.
And it was, we had, he just quoted me yes.
Yesterday I was hanging out with them
and the quote was like, whatever,
six months ago we were having a
conversation and I said something like,
Hey Dave,
whether I love you or hate you,
you won't know either
way. And, and he was like,
yeah. He's like, well,
it kind of freaks me out cause you're
super nice to me and now I'd say you could
just hate me and don't care. And
you know, we laughed about it,
but that's exactly right.
And that is the truth.
Like the guys that I hated never knew it.
I mean, to this day they
don't know it. And so, I mean,
you and I were having a conversation
about a couple of people that I obviously
don't like at all. They
don't know that so,
so you've gotta be professional at all,
at all times and it's a
very small number of people.
Most people are pretty
cool to me, you know,
and most people support
what I'm trying to get done.
So I'm pretty lucky in
that way. But yeah, if you,
if you let that out as bad,
is there ever really a reason not to
be polite? The a very seldom. Yeah.
You can politely punch someone in the
face. Here's what people would freak out.
Here's what, here's what people
get all like, oh well, you know,
that's what you're talking about, Jocko.
You're, you're a kiss ass. It's like,
actually, let me tell you
what I actually want to do.
What I actually want
to do is I want to win.
What I actually want to do is I want
us to have my platoon able to get the
support that they need.
What I actually want to do is I want to
be able to have my platoon and get the
support that they need so that we can
actually do a better job doing our
mission. That's what I'm doing.
What I care about is
my guys and my mission.
That's what I actually care about and
if I've got to be polite to someone to
make that happen,
if I've got to overlook the fact that
someone might not be the personality type
that I particularly like, I don't
care. I don't care. Guess what?
I'm going to deal with it.
I'm going to accept it.
I'm going to absorb whatever kind of crap
that they want to throw and I'm going
to deal with it. It's fine. Now,
do you get into situations where you
actually have a bad boss that you have to
show? Let's face it,
if I'm treating you like a piece of shit
and and you or I'm making really bad
decisions and all you do is
support me and you're a yes man,
well your guys are going to
lose respect for you. So you,
there's times where you have to say,
hey listen guys, here's what's going on.
I don't agree with everything that
the boss says, but you know what?
He's the boss right now. And what we're
going to do is try. The easiest way,
the way for me to get him to make
better decisions is if he trusts me.
So right now what we're going to do is
we're going to kick ass and so suck it
up. Quit complaining,
we're going to do a great job and I'm
going to get a better relationship over
him where he will start listening to me
and we'll move forward. And by the way,
unless we're going to have a mutiny,
which we're not going to have,
this is the best option.
The other option is me to have an
antagonistic relationship with the boss,
in which case all he's going
to do is screw us over.
So how do you guys want to play
this? You know what I mean?
So sometimes you got to be transparent
about that stuff and that's fine too.
I mean, I've, I've been in situations
where I've had to do that where it's like,
okay, hey guys, here's what's going on.
I know this seems a little bit crazy.
I know that the boss may seem like
he's making a rash decision on this.
Here's what we're going to do.
Let's explain his perspective.
Here's what the boss is saying. He
doesn't want this to happen again.
He's tightening the news.
He's tightening the bleach way more
than I want them to, but guess what?
Let's show him that he can let loose
on the leash again. Let's get in line.
You'll see you've got to have those
conversations sometimes, but broadly,
I'm going to get along with everybody.
Why not? I want to do my mission.
I want to take care of my guys.
The best way to do that is if I have good
relationships up and down the chain of
command. Boom. A question. And you know,
I don't like you even in
secret, the secret is out.
Kind of got that either
way. In your view, what um,
what's the difference between that?
How you say like you get along,
like even if you don't,
if you really don't like someone
they will never know in your view.
What's the difference between
that and being like, oh,
what do you call like a to face
or you know, I'm like love to say,
oh he's a toothpaste person or whatever.
One big thing is I'm not, I'm not,
I'm not, I'm not getting along with
them so that I can so that I can uh,
better my own life. I'm not doing
it so I can take care of me. Yeah.
Cause I don't really care about me.
I'm doing it so I can do my job well so
I can take care of my platoon so I can
take care of my team so I can accomplish
my mission. That's number one.
If I'm doing it so I
can get the promotion.
I'm actually the guy that I
don't like the guy that like, oh,
I'm doing this so I can get
promoted. No, I'm not doing that.
And that's another thing.
The troops see through that every single
time they have a name for it in the
teams. That guy's a ticket
puncher. They're trying to
get their ticket punched.
Oh, he's just trying to
get his ticket punch.
He's trying to grab onto that guys,
grab ahold of that person's
coattails and ride him up. You know,
ride them up to the next rank. It's
like, no, everyone sees through that.
If you're doing the right things for
the right reasons, people are like, hey,
you know what, Jocko European, I mean,
and many times people will look, dude,
you're your patient guy. Leif Babin
told me that, hey, you're so patient,
I don't, I don't see how you do. I don't
want to see how you do it. You know?
This is when he was younger. Like,
Bro, how do you deal with that?
I care about our task unit. I
will make this happen. I can,
I can absorb some impacts,
no factor, bring it.
I remember when I was working the club
is a guy who I thought was two faced and
when I listen to you like you're like,
oh yeah cause he said that'd
be four that you like.
If you didn't like someone they probably
wouldn't know. And I was like, Oh yeah,
yeah, that makes sense. You know, cause
it like it helps the relationship,
helps morale, like health helps all
these things. Right. And then so I think,
well yeah a face guy,
there was a distinct difference and one
of the main things on top of what you
said because what he said was like,
I think it wouldn't work thorough.
Ultimately view minus a little bit more.
How should I say? Straight forward,
ground level I guess. Can I guess what
you're going to say? Sure. You can.
Well cause the other option,
the other answer I was going to give
is I'm not acting differently in one
situation or I don't go,
hey boss. Yes I got it.
And then go back to the platoon
and go, he's an idiot. No, no, no.
I don't do that. I go, Hey
boss, I, you know what?
And even if it was a situation
where I was saying like,
I might go back and tell the guys like,
hey guys, this is what's going on.
I would tell the boss,
I wouldn't say boss.
That sounds like the greatest plan ever.
Yeah, no, I'd say, Hey boss, I'm not,
I don't think I'm 100% on board with this.
I see some other ways
we could get this done.
If this is what you're
telling me you want me to do,
I'm going to make it happen. But I think
we could, you know, I'm, I'm going to,
I'm so I don't act
differently. Yeah, I'm not,
I'm not a different person
in front of, you know,
was I was doing an event the other day
and I was like talking to a company and I
was backstage talking to CEO and we were
just, you know, and all of a sudden,
you know, there's like, he's like, hey,
it's only another half an hour before
you go on, do you need some time?
And I was like, no,
I don't need any time because the person
that's going to walk out on that stage
is me and I'm not acting any different
way. It's just me. I'm going to,
you know, I don't need to get
into character. I'm in character.
I'm walking around. I mean, this is me.
And he was like, oh, that's awesome.
So same thing. I don't,
when I'm dealing with the boss
that I don't like or whatever,
I don't show that to anybody.
Yeah. I go act differently.
But you're also,
you're doing a good idea.
You're doing a good,
you're managing what hills
are worth dying on for sure.
When you go to your boss, so that
you built up that equity with them,
no doubt about that. When you need it,
you can cash it in.
And that's why you have to establish
those relationships with them.
And that's what I really failed as as a
young leader before my aperture started
to get opened up,
before I got introspective and I started
thinking about all this stuff from a
big picture.
Okay.
And then my little ego was in
the way. Yeah. And, uh, um,
okay.
You know, if you're not,
if you're not the guy that is bitching
every time when you do bring something up
in a respectful manner,
then they're going to at least
consider what you have to say.
And nine times out of 10, they're
actually going to go with them. Oh
they're going to go with it.
Yeah. That's, that's the, uh,
that's the extreme
ownership story at the end.
It was me sitting around with your
task to command to the other tasks and
competitors from all the different
teams and everyone's, you know,
say they got this problem, that problem.
The other problem, you know, and the,
the commodore at the time who was
a friend of mine says, Hey Jocko,
what do you need? And I was like,
Hey sir, we don't need anything.
We're good to go. And you like
it. You know, for whatever reason,
I was like the last guy to go.
So it had even more impact cause everyone
was complaining about this thing or
the other thing used to lose
and he goes, he goes, Jocko,
which this that they gave it even more
in back cause he's just like, you know,
he knows me. He goes, Jocko, what do
you need? And I'm like, nothing sir,
we're good to go. And
you can say, you know,
four months later when I go in there
and I say, hey sir, we need x. He goes,
cool, go to supply. I'm calling them
right now. Boom. Taking care of. That's,
that's how it should be.
Another thing that I was thinking
about when you were talking,
somebody asked me at some
point, you know, which,
what point did you start sort
of like looking at yourself,
kind of what you're talking
about. At what point did,
did I start to look at myself from an
external position and say from a detached
perspective and same weight, are you
being jealous? Are you being resentful?
Are you complaining?
I can tell you right now that when I
stepped into a leadership position,
what I knew was that as you said,
every guy in my platoon is looking at me.
And I looked at myself the same way
I s because as a young enlisted guy,
cause my first leadership
inside of Mattoon was as an,
as an assistant platoon commander. You
know, it was an ensign and so sure,
I was a little bit, you know,
when I was an e five Oh is this,
oh is a three platoon e five and
are you in a leadership position?
You know, a little bit. Sure.
But not really a little bit.
When I was a platoon ensign,
I was thinking the whole time these guys
are looking at me just like I used to
look at my officer.
So if I complained that it's cold or
I complained that it's because when my
officers used to do that,
dude, this sucks. Oh really?
I'd be like, I would,
I would just, I would,
I just fee. I would get
furious and that's why,
that's when I really started
looking at myself and I'll,
I'll quite frankly,
when I started putting in an officer
package as a young enlisted guy and I was
like, wait a second, these guys,
I want these guys to think that
I actually should be in charge.
I needed to tighten it up. They're
looking at me right now thinking,
why does Jocko think he should be
an officer? Here's why. Here's,
I need to act like I
actually deserve this.
So that was a real precursor to me
looking at myself from the outside saying,
man,
I know what it's like to be an e five in
a platoon looking at the officer going,
Oh, you forgot that piece of gear.
Did you? And you're in charge of me.
You're making more money than me.
You're making the decisions
tonight on this operation.
You didn't bring your handset.
Really that's where we're at.
I know what that felt like.
And so I held myself to a high
standard because I didn't,
didn't want somebody to be looking
at me thinking jock was complaining.
He's weak, he's making a, he's,
he forgot a piece of gear.
He didn't show up on time.
You know how many times I was late when
I was in the u s navy for 20 years.
Zero, zero times late.
Zero never wide paranoia,
high level of paranoia.
Don't want to have guys like when my
officers were late and I look at them and
think, oh, you can't even show up on
time. You're in charge of me. You know,
that's a young arrogant kid for sure.
Absolutely. That's me. But I, I,
I ate that and I held onto it and that's
one of the first things that made me,
and at some point it turned from
this kind of hostility into like,
you need to be a better person. You
know, if you're going to be in charge.
It went from like this attitude that I'm
kind of portraying right now of like,
oh you suck into like, hey,
you need to do a better job. You need
to hold yourself to a high standard,
you need to be a better person. If
you're being charged with these guys,
you need to hold the line and you need
to elevate that line. So that had,
that definitely had a big impact on me.
And Bro, if anybody knows this, you do,
you knew me when I was at
e for 20 years old maniac.
Right. And then you, you
know, you ran into me what,
however many years later and you're like,
let me seems a little bit different,
you know,
not totally different but cause even
when I was a young kid I was fired up.
Oh yeah. But you know, I had to elevate,
had to elevate some. Yeah. That
introspection is something that,
that I didn't figure out until way later,
but I'm sure glad I'm dead
cause I think it paid off.
It's, that's one of the things,
and it's one of those things that,
you know, did your dad
ever give you any advice?
Yeah. So did mine. How much I listened to?
This is about the same amount
as I listened to my dad.
It's one of those things
where you're, you just,
there's some things
that you have that you,
it's like you can't be taught Yay,
but you, you can use it. Like,
someone can't tell you
this for some reason.
There's somethings that people can't
tell you unless you can just completely
open your mind and get humble
and put your ego in check,
which is really hard to do when you're
22 2124 like there's things that I look
at and I go, Oh, you know what? I've
heard that before. I learned that lesson.
I got told that lesson,
but I didn't learn it.
But it's, you can pick it up pretty
Dang quick by by example. And so,
you know, how often do you
get people asking you, well,
how do I get that guy over there
to take extreme ownership? Yeah.
It's like you do it. That's true.
You take extreme ownership and it
will be contagious. Yeah. Yeah. Um,
and in, in that manner, when
people see those modeled behaviors,
then it just goes out and it, it goes
back to that thing that life talks about.
There's no bad teams, there's
bad leaders and I've seen groups,
seal platoons and seal troops that have
brought talented them. Oh, for sure.
And then they'll have kind of a,
a guy come in that's a tyrant and an
egomaniac and that will permeate into
everybody the same way as you know,
the one all I see that
you're talking about that,
that I've worked around
everywhere that guy goes,
he lifts everybody else.
Everyone that's around him becomes
better by his example. Yeah.
Yup. Any other mistakes
or major mistakes? You know,
it just back to being a,
when I was at the troop,
senior enlisted advisor
over in Afghanistan and we
were doing the remain over
day operations and there were a lot of
my younger guys that didn't understand
why we weren't going, why
we weren't just going in,
hitting a target and coming out
during the same cycle of darkness.
They felt like that
would be more effective.
And instead of sitting down with them
and explaining to them why we were doing
what we were doing, I would just
tell him shut up and get out.
And you know, hindsight not,
not the right thing to do because then
they really don't know why they're doing
what they're doing. And then there's,
there's resentment that's building and
then they're just not going to be the
most effective at what
they've got going on.
Man, I wish we could do
this whole job over again.
We kind of can though. I mean it's, it
goes back to the resentment thing and,
and another bad, our word
is that regret. I've,
I've learned like all these Dang mistakes
I've made and every big setback that
I've
experienced in my life,
I feel like it's kind of set me up
for success through moving forward.
So it's Kinda like glacier, you know,
every time I've taken like a foot back,
I then move forward.
Yeah. Three feet. Yeah.
Learn from it and press on.
What's interesting for me is as
I look back at my career now,
and I was actually doing this when
I was thinking about mistakes, man,
and I was actually talking to,
uh, Dave Burke, the deal, Dave
and like all the things that
I talk about all the time now,
I did those things. Like when I was a
platoon commander, I was doing this stuff.
I wasn't, I wasn't as crystallized, but
like when I was a task unit commander,
boom, I was, this is what I was
doing, this is what I was doing.
It wasn't like I had it crystallized.
It wasn't like I had this like, oh,
this is what I had seen enough. And
most of it I'd seen, as you just said,
through modeling from some good officers
and from some bad officers and some
good chiefs and some bad
chiefs where I'd say, oh,
that's all what that I'm going to,
hey, why does that guy do that?
He always tells me what's going okay,
I'm going to always do that. You know,
like that kind of thing.
It's, but, but like you said,
when you get done with the job,
you look at it and be like, man,
let me just do that one more time cause
I will knock this thing out of the park.
So when is the moment, do you
think for you that you're,
the collective light bulb went off and
you kind of put a lot of this together,
the collective well that, you know,
the first FTX is a trade at when you
got there. And that was part of it.
Like I like my assistant
platoon commander in my OIC,
um, I was telling him this stuff,
you know, I was like, hey man,
here's what's going on. Like, Hey,
we needed to do this. Hey you,
when you go in and brief this guy,
you need to be like this, this stuff.
I was doing it, but then the next
deployment, it was like when I was,
you know, when I was working with Lafe
and Seth, you know, it was me saying,
hey man, come here. And, and you know,
those guys would whip out the freaking,
uh, the wheel books. You know, like
after they realized what was going on,
which was like three days
into our, our, our task unit,
I'd be like, hey, check
this out. And Boom,
they'd get out and they'd write and they'd
write down like, okay, this is what,
okay, got it. Yes, that makes sense. And,
but as far as actually taking it and
crystallizing, I was absolutely my first,
the first FTX I went on with [inaudible]
and watched it watch a task and you're
out there just fall apart and, and,
and all I was doing was
sitting there thinking,
if this was my task unit number one,
here's what I'd be doing. And number two,
when I got back, I'd be telling the
platoon commander this, this, and this.
I'd be telling those guys, Hey,
this is where you screwed up.
And I just was watching it
and go, okay, all right. Here.
I basically condensed everything that
I had told my guys and said, okay,
here's what you guys need to do. And
that was cover move, simple, prioritize.
Next you can decentralize
command the answers to so many,
the answers to all problems.
Oops. Boil down to four things and
they all kind of overlap. Yeah,
they definitely are
intertwined and they overlap.
And you do have to throw extreme
ownership on there only because,
okay.
If you don't take ownership
of the problems then they're
not going to get solved
and that is going to hurt you.
So yeah. Yeah. At at the muster,
JP was saying some stuff that really
stuck with me and he said it out at the,
at the PT and he's like, hey everybody,
we get to be here.
Okay,
this is an opportunity
that you have to be here.
And he said that. And I thought, man,
that is just an awesome perspective to
had. I called him up yesterday, I'm like,
Hey I want to talk
about this and you know,
just fill me on and on what your
mindset is. And he goes, yeah, he goes,
you don't want to cause,
cause when he was at buds,
the way he looked at a four mile time
Brun which I hated four mile time runs,
I just, I would throw up
every four mile time run his,
his attitude was I get
to do this for bile time.
Brun so if you take that and you
start applying that to everything,
heck yeah. They just don't have,
there's no room to bitch
about a damn thing. You know,
I moved through the airport today and
I see a guy with no legs and I'm like,
man, my life is so good.
Both my legs work and,
and I shouldn't, I shouldn't
have a complaint in the world.
One of the, one of the last thing,
and we're getting kind of like getting
pretty long here, but um, you know,
one of the things I w I
wanted you to talk about,
and I know this isn't really well, it's,
I guess it is because as
a leader of your family,
um, I know that we, we have to,
we have to lead our family. Right.
And what you, you, you posted
something the other day that was legit.
Um, I think it was called a
promise to my daughter and I was,
I just asked if you could
bring it in cause I think if,
if you don't mind
reading that to everyone,
I think it's a pretty cool set
up of how to take ownership of,
of your family and how to, how, what you,
what you as a leader and as a dad
and as a father and as a husband,
what you are putting forth as your goal,
as your objective, as your
strategy with your daughter.
And I thought it was pretty awesome.
So if you wouldn't mind reading that,
that'd be cool.
Absolutely. A promise to my daughter.
Okay.
I will love you always,
unconditionally. No matter what.
I will not pamper you.
This will forge a resilience that will
help you conquer all of life's obstacles.
Yeah.
I do not intake intent
to raise a princess,
but rather a warrior with fire in
her heart and ice in her veins.
In my mind there is nothing you can't do.
No job or goal beyond your reach.
I will challenge you so that you stand
confidently on your own two feet.
Yeah.
And I will set the example on how to
treat those you love so that when you
choose a partner, it will be
someone that lifts you up.
Fine.
I will invest my time and energy
in you so that when I am gone,
enough memories of me will be with you
in your heart to keep forever stand tall
with your shoulders back. This
world is yours for the taking.
Boom. Yeah. That's awesome man.
And obviously I would think the
same stuff for my son. Yeah. Yeah.
But
well, you'll have to write one a little
bit specific to him. Very similar,
I'm sure. Yeah. Yeah. No,
that's awesome. And uh,
that, that's really cool and I'm
better, a lot of people will a,
listen to it and B, plagiarize it
and eh, you know, ab absolutely.
Yeah. For their own family. But
no, that's awesome man. And um,
like I said, we're, we're
going pretty long right now,
so that's a good place to wrap
up. This one. What is this?
Now we've done something
like seven or eight hours.
Seven or eight hours. Awesome. So, uh,
echo speaking of,
okay.
Having a strategy to get to where we want
to go to be a little bit better across
the board in all aspects. What do you got
for us yet? Some tips. Oh, by the way.
Yeah, I read that on
Instagram if I'm not mistaken.
And I considered plagiarizing
it please. My daughter.
Now I got the confirmation or what
do you, what do you guys call it?
Cleared hot. Yeah. All
right. There you go.
And you were right about the, the
two phase things when you said, oh,
let me guess what you're gonna say. Oh,
you're absolutely a hundred
percent correct. Cool.
Yeah. Like act one way like,
hey boss, hey, you know, hates them.
Nope. Didn't they? I think you're awesome.
Yes. And then right when he leaves,
then you know, yeah. You see that guy?
Let's see. Okay. Yeah. Go do that.
Alcohol last. Yes, we are on
the path. Okay, good. Straight.
The strategic versus a tactic. Tactical,
long game. Short game. I know you've
been in new long game picture,
small picture, all the same thing.
When people ask Echo what's
like the big takeaway?
I think that's his primary
takeaway. Biggest yes.
Focusing on the long game, which
he's a football so you know,
he like thinks the game thing
or Super Mario brothers.
Well more appropriately is, but you
know, as opposed to thinking short game.
Yeah. And if you look at your
life every day in long game,
slash strategic instead of short
game, slash tactical, yeah.
You're going to end up in a better
spot. Yeah. And when I say the biggest,
I mean that's the one that applies
to like the whole my whole life.
There's the other stuff. No complaining.
The Allan was, that's a big one.
No complaining, no blaming of
course. And then, um, resent.
I never really had the
resent the jealousy thing.
That's something I really
had kind of entwined. Um,
that one to me always felt obvious
when I, when I, when I discovered, um,
like anger. Like when you're mad, that's
like something up with you kinda thing,
you know, it's natural, whatever.
That's one of the biggest,
one of the biggest things I got from
doing this podcast is captain plumb seen
when they were in the,
in the Hanoi Hilton.
Yeah and him saying if you were annoyed
with your prison bunk mate it was your
fault. I was like hit
me diamond bullet. Yeah.
Right between the eyes.
That was extreme ownership.
Next level cause always
annoyed with that other person.
You don't know actually know what. That's
my fault. Yeah that was good. When I,
when I discovered it was a book
I was reading called Mind Games,
I mentioned it before and it said
small little passage said basically.
Um, in a nutshell like
when you have anger issues,
not to say that when you get mad but
it just as if you have anger issues,
it has something to do
with your self esteem.
Like you have low self esteem
and that hit me really hard.
Like aw man that hit me so hard that I
was like man I can never get mad ever
again.
That's like a reverse psychology on
your ego because then your ego is going,
not going to turn myself down because
I got low self esteem here. Oh yes.
Genius. Same thing with
the drinking. You, you uh,
you put it into words good
where kids drinking, right?
I ended up figuring out or it
being revealed to me that drew,
like when you drink,
when you have a drink and you want another
one and you want another one and your
mind and the more you have,
the more you sort of want,
you can't really stop or
whatever. You don't want to stop.
It's just your brain tricking you,
you know, it's your brain tricky.
Like your brain is chemically saying,
oh, we need this. Hey, we need this.
You know, we need more of whatever you
felt like you were getting manipulated.
Felt like I was a sucker as you said.
And my ego was like, Whoa, Whoa, whoa.
I'm not a sucker. I don't
care if it's my own brain.
I'm not a sucker or whatever.
And it was just that easy man
that easy to control it. But yes,
it is a reverse psychology
on your ego. Good.
As opposed to regular
psychology on your ego,
short term and longterm
did you get to right?
I thought I'm going to use
the word reverse reversal
reversal that that's a true
going to handle the transition
negative, negative. I'm saying. Yeah,
I'm on the first, uh,
long game and short game.
Jujitsu is one of those long
game short game situations,
hundred percent part of the path.
Part of the many activities that
we're all doing on the path.
Jason Gardner got into good shape,
uh, easily. So we're exercising,
we're doing Jujitsu, we're eating
healthy. We're not getting mad at people.
We're not showing resentment.
We're not complaining
various other things. So we'll go
over it anyway. Did you do this?
What did you do? Did you just said you
going to need a g? What gear do we get?
Origin G, get it from origin main.com.
This is where all their stuff,
by the way, is made all in
America from the cotton.
They grow from the ground
all the way to the end,
from the dirt to the shirt
shirt, all that. Anyway,
origin main.com so you get the
stones. Yes. American Americana.
Yes. Which we are producing right now.
We are hiring more people to produce
even more so my apologies on it.
If you're ordering right now, maybe we
don't have your size. We're working at,
we're working it hard. We're
growing. Yeah. That was good.
Some people at the higher appreciate
them. They have the 28 inch in seam.
Usually I can only get 30
oh, there you go. Boom.
Accommodating everybody. Yeah. There's a
few guys at the muster who had them on.
I was like, I'll hold couple of
people crowded, man. It's good.
I don't have anybody that, those are the
breaks and that's just the life I live.
Also, if sweat pants and shirts
and whatnot, other stuff on there.
Also supplements, supplements, the
best kinds of supplements. By the way.
There was some,
there was some people freaking
out on the strawberries that,
have you tried to strawberry slayer
yet? Yeah. That's just not me. Oh,
you don't want, I'm not
that kind of strawberry guy.
I definitely got some and tried. It
didn't work. I'm, I'm a hardcore mint.
Chocolate chip and then
the vanilla for Mega,
you get that vanilla gorilla and
throw it inside your, uh, your coffee.
That's your sweetener kind of.
That's your [inaudible] boom.
Dope. Yeah, that was good. Methane.
And then that's iris is
mixing that in when you,
when you drink that in the morning.
Like what time? Like right at,
right after I PT. And then how long, when
do you feel hungry for your next meal?
Oh, I don't eat until like one
cheering or two o'clock check
in. I was just putting it in everything.
She's making multiple pancakes,
making milk, whatever and
smoothies and all that stuff.
So we go through quite a bit of milk in
our house. Yeah. And the kids love it.
Yeah. That's strawberry can make
like a, it's like a milk shake.
Smoothie hybrid. Here's
what I said the other day.
If you put in front of me
Haagen daas strawberry
milkshake. Yes. Right? Sure.
Nestle's strawberry quick. Yes.
And Strawberry slayer milk and I
was going to die in 15 minutes,
so we're just going pure satisfaction
short. You're short term.
The long game is out of the picture.
I'm going straight to the strawberries
are moke cause that's what tastes the
best. That is the taste test, right?
No one does a taste test like that.
I'm not filling a caveat on there,
but the hoggin downs is going to be sugary
or the Nestle's Quik is going to give
you a sugar. No, we're taking the
long game. Totally out the picture.
We're going to cure short term
tactical taste. Where you at?
Strawberry slayer Brigit
names awesome too.
You know. I agree. Also joint Pete.
Pete was trying to like tell me
product names and he's like, he's like,
and Pete Goes, you know pizza
like Mr Creative. Yes. Right.
He's like getting to be creative. And
he even told me, yeah, yeah. Oh yeah.
He'll tell you. He was like,
that's his creative stuff, right.
So pizza hit me up. He says, so
he set up sending me all these,
all these things. Strawberry sniper.
I'll have to pull out the list.
It's so funny. Everything
these random military terms.
But yeah, don't catch Pete.
He gets into these moods.
Creativity is just coming out of his
coming out of his brain and he'll start
hitting me up with texts
about strawberry sniper.
I'm not ever, I'm not that mad at that
man. He had some ones we used to slayer,
so when he hears sniper I'm like,
oh I see why that was
like a distant second one.
I'm trying to think of some of the
other whack ones that came cause sorry.
Yeah, some of them were real
funny actually. I texted him,
he texted Brian and me, he's texting us
all these names and I was like, okay,
stop no more. He just
started laughing. Yeah.
So check that. Yup. Well he's
probably had a, he had a pray.
A little too much discipline go.
Yeah, potentially. Yeah. Yeah.
How many discipline go are you
on right now? For daily? No.
Per Day? Yeah.
Just cause I had to get up at 3:00
AM what time did you go to bed? What?
10:10 PM so you're on five hours of
sleep, right? Did you sleep on the plane?
No. Can you sleep on planes? Yes.
I can see sometimes when I was,
I was just writing all these notes
and you're ready for this. And some,
sometimes I can just turn it off, but
I wasn't able to sleep on the point.
I can sleep on planes, not
as well as echo though.
Echo gets the world championship belt.
We're seeing my plans. We get on a plane,
I got to play with them within
within 38 seconds. He's asleep.
He looks and he puts his sunglasses
on. He looks like he's awake,
but it's a lie. So yeah, so discipline go.
That's a good situation. I
take two every morning check.
So get up in the morning to
discipline, go and then um,
joint warfare taking morning and
night. Yep. And I noticed a different,
how many do you take? I'm taking
two in the morning and two at night.
And then what's your body
weight? Right now? One 16.
I take three. I take three.
Joint Warfare, three curl oil,
mourning three joint wear for
three Carrillo night. If I'm,
if I got a little little situation
going on too, I might, if I'm around,
I'll take three during the day.
For the lunchtime too. Dang.
She just got the infusion infusion
situation fusion. That's good man.
So that's that. Yeah. Don't forget
about the warrior kid milk too. Yeah.
For the warrior kits. Yeah.
Well, so, all right, well let's,
let's talk about it then.
What to what in your opinion or you can
mock strawberry or strawberry slayer,
strawberry slayers. Thicker. It's like
a shake. Yeah, I think it actually,
I think the way that they are,
they are actually suitable
for their audience,
so that's true. The
strawberry, the warrior kid,
strawberry milk is just a little bit,
a little bit in the lighter we'll say,
cause it does have less
protein and the one,
the adult one is a
little bit heavier Gush,
a little bit more like that hog and
Naas hit her. I just think that,
where are you at Theo
Vaughn with that hit her or
also Jocko white tea. Yes. Very
reframed. I'm going to say the light,
the nice stuff about it. Very refreshing.
Certified Organic pomegranate
white tea doesn't sound hardcore,
but it can after you dead
lifting 8,000 pounds,
that is kind of hardcore proven. By the
way, Jason Burton or scientifically,
you know, you go on about that. What
I'm talking about 100% guaranteed.
Can I get sued for that? I, you know,
maybe I guess if there was some that
couldn't hit at 8,000 pound deadlifts,
then they might come at me. Yeah, come
at me. Burlington. I'll say lift harder.
Yeah man. Drink more. You can't. Yeah,
you gotta train 'em cause there's no
way everyone else is dead lifting a
thousand pounds. What's wrong with
you, the guy? Yep. Yeah, yeah,
it makes sense. Also, we have a
store, it's called Jocko store.
I think we all know that. This is where
you can get rash guards, tee shirts,
going to represent discipline equals
freedom. Truckers, hats, truckers,
hats, beanies, some beanies. That man,
I gotta refill the beanies. Go take.
So maybe you don't have beatings
there. Well, politico never wears hats.
So these apparently on no on the bro.
Have you even had a cold head before?
Yeah, I haven't had a
cold head before. Sure.
Well depends on what you mean by cold,
but you know, yeah, you put the lid on,
you know, put the lightweight,
put the coldness on the head,
and then right when you shave it,
like with the, what do you call the,
the braiser never the bakery. They say
when you bake your head. That's what,
that's an expression. Oh yeah. I can
get a little nippy, I guess. Kinda cold.
Well anyways, the rest of us would
like some more beanies online. Yes sir.
You got it. And for the
summertime, yes sir. No problem.
You're up in Maine in
the summertime. Yeah.
Or you're up in Michigan
in the summertime. Yeah.
Or you're up in Washington in the
summertime. Once the sun goes down. Yeah.
You can get that little Chile.
Yeah, yeah, yeah. I agree.
And that's how it is
here too, in my opinion.
And you might as well have a beanie that
says discipline equals freedom. Yeah.
Man. Represent with everything.
Also, the hoodies, like I mentioned,
lightweight hoodies, lightweight is
Jason Guy. I saw you down at the muster.
I look good, right? Not
Bad. Well thank you. Oh,
now we're on the how everyone looks.
Wow. Well it's part of the game.
They can be part of. Maybe not for
you. Uh, aesthetics wise. Right?
We got functionality. We have
aesthetics. They're not exclusive. Yeah.
And you remember I was asking you about
the heavyweights cause that's what I but
that's what I need up in northeastern
Washington on the Canadian border.
We all work functionally. You're current.
We are working currently at this time
so that by the time fall walls rolls
around we offer the heaviest
of heavyweight hoodies. Yeah,
that's the plan. Yes.
I'm talking big time.
The real deal for free yet where there'll
be no doubt in your mind you're like
Oh yeah this is a,
this is the heaviest Hoodie I've ever
heard that putting on five pounds. Yeah.
That's what we want to lead.
But aesthetics, how let's say,
and a factor of 10 is function, right?
You don't have to answer this question.
You need, you need level 10 functionality
obviously aesthetics. What are we,
what are you at what number? A
seven. That's pretty significant.
What do you at zero, zero,
straight up. Zero like the like
the lightweight. Any anything
having to do with fashion? I think.
I think you're at a one.
That's what I think. You know,
if there are some things where
I'd be like this looks stupid,
therefore I will not wear
it so that we are correct.
That puts me in a level one. All
right. Well how about this? You got,
you got three t four t shirts. One
green like green, green not
oh d green, green, green,
one red, one black, one purple.
Which one are you choosing? Black.
Why looks better, right?
Doesn't get dirty as easy.
Nah Man. Anyways,
punk card boy. Anyway, some
women's stuff on there too.
It is Jocko store.com this is where
he can get stuff to represent. Yeah,
check it out like something.
Get something. Did you
say origin maine.com yes.
That's for it. Yes. For the
words. Somebody might want
somebody that strawberry
of course. Man of course. Yes. Also
strawberry, slayer, snap like a, like a,
like a theme. Like when you say it,
it should be like in the background.
She goes, strawberry slugger, double bass,
drum Yammer, and you could do,
could do good. Do, could do good.
You railing you, I don't know if
I agree with that, but you know
named for sure 100% also subscribe to
the podcast if you haven't already on
iTunes and wherever you get your podcasts
and don't forget about the warrior kid
podcast. Yes. Which comes out
not as frequently as it should.
It should step up this summer as time
opens up to create and record that
particular podcast and then you can
get some of that more your kids.
So you're friends with
Matt, right? Yeah. Up there.
Aiden making it on his farm. Irish jokes,
Irish show trends.com how do
you know him? Through Iris.
You come to your farm? Yeah, we
were going to buy meat from him.
Then when he came to deliver it to
you, he swung by and visited us.
I was gone that day so I didn't meet him,
but him and I have chatted on the phone
a whole bunch of times. Awesome. Yeah,
he's a firefighter up in Aventura county
and he's got a farm as well and his son
Aden was a young warrior kid,
makes soap so that everyone
in the world can stay clean.
That's a cool, that's a good soap
too by the way. External soap,
it's not the decorative,
you know the ones that you little neath
makes and it's like here, it's not,
not even supposed to really use it as a
decoration like gift, if you will. Yes.
Also we have a youtube channel,
the Jocko podcast, youtube channel.
This is where you can
get the video version.
Of course you wanna see what Jason
looks like, right? Handsome looking guy.
I'd say, Bro, Jocko,
what? Just take it easy.
Hey Man. Either way, if
you are interested in that.
We have a youtube channel also
some excerpts on there. You know,
we'll cut up little excerpts and sometimes
echo puts cello music behind him and
he puts explosions in them sometimes
when I want to enhance them. Maybe,
maybe like a certain message that you
talk about hits me hard. I say, Hey,
let me express this, you
know, put some stuff on them.
You ever feel like maybe we should just
get a couple of cello players in here?
No, I don't tap. I don't ever feel
like that at all. And you know,
I think we should stick with what
we're doing. That's my opinion.
Here's the thing about youtube
though, as far as subscribing,
so it doesn't even matter. And you might
notice Jay, you spend time on Youtube.
Yes. Like, okay, so here's
what I learned and observed.
If you subscribe to someone on
Youtube, it doesn't matter that much.
Like their stuff won't show up all
the time. Like how you'd expect,
you'd think like, Oh, if you subscribed,
their stuff is going to sort of show
up on your, what do you call it,
the home page or whatever. It
doesn't so much to do that anyway.
When I get an email, every time
you post something new, okay,
now you're talking,
now you're talking because when you
subscribe to some money and you do that
additional step, you
click on the little bell.
I think it's like right next to or on
the subscribe button or wherever it is
right there. If you do that,
then you'll get the alert email.
You know my alert ever, my alerts
actually come onto my phone.
They like spring up on that from
youtube or for your Junko podcast.
Just posted a new video that's from
my, from the app. From the Youtube app.
From the Youtube app. Yes. Which
is pretty cool. Yeah. Yeah.
So if you want that, this is what
I'm saying. So when you subscribe,
it's almost like a half
subscribed, not even a half.
It's like a quarter subscribed. That's
what it is. Cause you're sorta like,
oh yeah, I officially sorta subscribed,
but you do like, cool. Okay.
I think we're not going
to let you know a lot of,
since he described this is way
different. This is different.
I'm saying if you want to subscribe and
you want to get alerts and you want it
to sort of be in your, what do
you call it, the feed or whatever,
you've got to get the little bell.
This is what I'm worried about.
Since you're very decentralized,
since there's a lot of
decentralized command here. Yes.
I'm worried that if
people don't subscribe,
all of a sudden you're just going to
start putting the little thing at the end
of your enhanced videos that says that
says like Sharon's click subscribe,
like it shows the little finger. Click
subscribe there and if that happens, no,
we're going to have a problem. Yes sir.
The videos make it centralized
real quick, real quick. Well,
we're not going to worry about that
because I agree with you 100% like share,
subscribe. Yeah. Hey,
before you watch this video,
go down to the bottom line
and click subscribe. Now
I'm just saying, I'm sure there's some
knowing I hate it when I see that,
but I'm sure there's some
functional, what's the,
what's the equivalent of when you meet
someone, like what's the equivalent of a,
of a human interaction
where you say that we, we,
that'd be somebody dropping the
s bomb. Would it be like that?
But it would be like, like,
hey, good to meet you.
Can I have a pat on the back please?
Like, isn't that basically what it is?
That's the human interaction equivalent.
Like, Hey, nice to meet you. Um,
give me your phone and I'm going to index.
I'm going to put my phone number in there
so I can text you what I'm doing all
the time. Yeah, give me a pat
on the back. All right, sorry.
I know I might figure that out.
That's actually a good little
analogical annaleigh analogy.
I'm like comparison task.
Take find the analogy is what I'm
saying. Psychological warfare, iTunes,
Google play and be three
platforms if you want to. If,
if you want to wake up call.
Yes. Which a lot of people say,
can't you make an long? Can't you make
an alarm? Can't you make an alarm? Yes,
you can use psychological
warfare as an alarm.
There's a bunch of alarm options
there. There's also something on there.
If you're,
if you're feeling like you want to eat
a doughnut or you want to eat a bag of
Cheetos. When's the last time
you ate a bag of Cheetos?
One time I ate a whole bag of Hershey's
kisses and this was when I was in the
teams. I'm talking to grown man. How big
was it back like a black, a good size,
like the size of a book, the
size, a regular size book.
Like it was one of those,
it was like six years ago my mom came
over to my house and put a whole bag of
candy corn.
It was around Halloween and every time
I walked by it I was stuffing the things
in my mouth and pretty
soon they're all gone.
You like Candy Court there? They're good.
I bet I couldn't eat one
right now cause I, you know,
kind of cut sweet stuff out. And every
time I slip I taste something. I'm like,
holy cow. The thing I noticed
that is with, with Coca-Cola.
Oh like I can't even, can't even come
close to drinking a coca cola. I haven't,
haven't had one, a legit like, hey,
I'm going to have a coke and probably
10 or 15 years or something like that.
A long time or two. Probably even
longer than that. But when I,
when I look at them or like the last time
I tried to sip when I was like, yeah,
they're like syrup. Yeah. So anyways.
Yeah to make sense. Like see that?
I can drink coke though. So
that's psychological warfare.
You can get that on any of those
platforms. Also, flip side,
canvas.com if you want the visual
reminder or something.
My brother Dakota Meyer has a company
called flipside canvas.com and he's making
all kinds of cool stuff. He's about
to run out some warrior kid stuff too.
Some little warrior kid and like
his Teddy Roosevelt's definitely,
he's just getting after it. So
he's making some really cool stuff.
Art with layers, by the way. Art with
layers. There you go. I like that.
You know also on it, if you're
expanding your home gym,
you're getting more kettlebells,
which I did by the way. Darth Vader,
how much does it weigh? 70 okay. Here's
the thing about the 70 pound like, sure.
I'm not, you know, I'm
going to be more abreast.
What's your hundred pound
to Kettlebell that whatever.
Bragging to me about one oh six one
else. There you go. There you go.
One Oh six but the 70 and the
72 the gorilla one or whatever.
Those in my opinion, have the most
like play universal usage. Yeah.
University what you said. Yes. Yeah,
those are great. I agree. Yeah.
Plus the Darth Vader. I mean, come on
man. That's the ultimate one I think,
but they should've, they
should've made the old,
they should've made the dodge Vader
like a a hundred at least over a hundred
pounds in my opinion. Maybe Jason,
you're the star wars expert. Yeah.
You should definitely be the
heaviest. Who's the most?
Who's the most powerful character
in star wars? Darth Vader.
This doesn't seem like he's kind
of a Trump. Some no negative. No.
You'd think the emperor may be,
but it starts Vader. Darth Vader.
Your matching you're about
to get. Yeah, I mean,
I don't know. You know,
Darth Maul was pretty Dang bad ass is
like the get chopped up pretty quick.
Who would, I mean Darth
Vader lost their theater.
Lost to Luke Skywalker who cobbled
immediately, by the way. Yeah.
Later on. Say start the later,
man. I think it starts later. Yeah.
I like Vader.
The real leader lifts people up.
You ever see that meme and
Darth Vader's holding that
[inaudible]. That is so funny, but
guy fader went through the whole arc.
He was good, bad, good. Boom. You
don't know what I'm thinking. Well,
I'm sure all the people dog side,
unless yes, I got that Kettlebell.
There's a lot of good
stuff. There's these,
there's these electrolyte minerals
that are part of my daily daily Manga
meetings with the discipline. Nonetheless,
go in there on it.com/jocko and
check out some stuff on there.
Some really good stuff. All right.
Some books weigh the warrior kid three.
The book is called where there's a will.
There's a good message to talked
about it already. Check that one out.
It is available now also where the warrior
kid one and to Mark's mission is to
number one his way of the warrior kid.
Check those out for your kid to
teach your kid these lessons,
these lessons that Jason I just talked
about for two plus hours are broken down,
simplified and,
and sprinkled sprinkled throughout these
books so that your kid is gonna read
when your kid is going to
save things to you. Like Dad,
I think your, that might be your ego talk.
That's so that the idea of ego gets
introduced in way the warrior kid three,
that's where it gets introduced
for the first time. So why?
Because I wish somebody would
have told me about my ego.
I wish somebody would have explained to
me that I was resentful. I was jealous.
I was, I was
okay
whining. No one did. Hm.
Or if my dad did, I didn't listen
cause I was a young punk. So, uh,
get those books. Also, if
you've got a younger kid,
you can get Mikey and the
dragons as well. Which again,
this is the thing where your
kid gets taught a lesson. Hey,
I didn't listen to my dad. Oh
my, I didn't listen to my mom.
Jason didn't listen to his mom.
Jason didn't listen to his dad.
I've been sitting around
with a bunch of like real,
okay,
really squared away
people, business people.
And we start talking about kids and,
and then I say, Hey, wait a second.
Who here? Listen to their parents.
No one raises their hands like very few.
There's the one occasional to occasional
uh, Eddie Haskell's. Do you ever? Yeah.
Yeah. I always listen to my heart. No,
you didn't liar most mostly, but you,
what, what happens is when they
hear it from another angle,
they listened to it and go,
Oh okay, I understand that.
And they think it's cool. It's uncle
Jake. It, it's not my dad cause your PR,
your kids want to rebel against you
because they know they have to leave the
nest. They got to set up
some kind of a barrier.
So they need someone to give them
advice. Let that someone be uncle Jake,
let that someone be the king in Mikey
and the dragons. So there you go.
That's that also we got obviously
disciplinary treat them field manual.
Yeah.
If you're an adult and you need to know
how to get on a path and stay on the
path to just get that book and put
it by your bedside and read that.
Read a page in the morning.
Have you ever had a book that will get
you out of bed? No. Okay. Discipline.
It was freedom field man. Who put it
next to your bed. Yeah. You'll be like,
I'm getting out of bed.
I'm going to go get some.
So then there's extreme ownership
in the dichotomy leadership piece.
Are there books about leadership written
by me and my brother Leif Babin about
the lessons that we learned overseas.
Now you can apply them in your team,
in your business, in your life. Also,
we got echelon front
leadership consultancy.
Okay.
And we're very busy. You know why?
We're very busy. We're very busy.
Because no matter what problem you
have in your team, in your business,
the problem is a leadership problem.
If you want to get it solved,
you got to solve the leadership.
Okay.
The leadership problems that you have
and if you can do then n****r solve the
problems in your company. So it's
me, it's Leif Babin, JP Denelle,
Dave Burke, Flynn Cochran, Mike Cirelli,
Mike by Ma and Jason Gardner.
If you want us to help you go to Ashland,
front.com for details. We've
got the muster. Chicago's done.
Did it sell out? Yes it did. How'd you
like the monster as your first monster?
Jason? How'd you like it?
Wow, that was amazing.
Don't you wish you got to go to
that when you were 25 years old?
Yeah, years old. I was
super impressed by it.
There were people that had
their kids there. Yeah. Yeah.
That's not normal or right. It, I
mean when you say there was people,
there was probably okay. And by,
by kids there were, I'm talking to,
there was one 13 year old that was there,
but there was a quite a few like
teenagers and high school age.
Yeah. I would say 16 to 21 there'll be,
there'll be a good amount, maybe a dozen.
Right. And then, but there's, yeah,
there was one 13 year old,
the warrior kid that was just
straight getting after it.
He was coming home early morning
PT the other way doing it.
He didn't mentioned that warrior kid
rash card. If you want to get that.
Anyways, that's the monster. They always
sell out. The next one is in Denver.
It's 19th and 20th of September and
it's going to sell out to Sydney,
Australia, December 4th and
fifth it's going to sell out.
We've got people in Australia.
Yes we do. When I went to Brizzy,
there was people from all over
Australia coming to hang out
home of David Hackworth Brisbane.
That's where we moved. Take it. Yeah,
and if you want to come to that code,
extreme ownership.com get on early. Yeah.
If online,
if you can't come to the monster or
you can't bring your entire company,
the muster cause the musters expensive,
then get go to ETF
online.com and what that is,
it's leadership training,
but the thing is leadership
training is not an inoculation.
You can't just go to leadership training
one time and then you're like, oh cool,
I've got extreme ownership now. I'm
good to go. Doesn't work like that.
Just like you can't go to ones you did
two class or even one week's worth of
Jujitsu class, you can't go to a two day
Jujitsu seminar now you're good to go.
No, you need to keep training. And
that's what happens here as well. So you,
it's not a, it's not an inoculation.
You gotta get it repeatedly and
that's what e f online does.
Or if you can't make it to the monster,
go to [inaudible] dot com
and also e f Overwatch,
taking proven leaders from Spec ops
in combat aviation and putting them in
companies in the civilian sector that
need leaders that you might think,
well, they don't have any experience
in my industry. Cool. They'll learn it.
That's what we do. Hire
for their character,
hire for their leadership capability.
Then teach them the industry specifics.
They'll pick up and they will fill in
the leadership holes that are causing you
problems
and if you want to hear more about
nineties TV shows or Super Mario brothers
from eco no
or you want to hear more about war or
leadership from Jason or me than all of us
are on the interwebs. Jason is
on Instagram. Jason Dot N. Dot.
Gardner. He's on Twitter,
Jason n Gardener,
he's on Facebook as well.
Jason Gardner and obviously
echo and I are both on those
platforms. Twitter, Instagram and
Echos at Echo Charleston and I am at
Jocko Willink and thanks to all the
veterans out there like Jason who did
their time on the line and thanks to
everyone else out there
right now in the fight.
Thanks for protecting our way of life.
You got any other closing
thoughts? Nothing further.
Group check
and also thanks to police and
law enforcement, firefighters,
paramedics, EMT, dispatchers,
correctional officers, border patrol,
secret service and all
the first responders.
Thank you all for keeping
us safe here at home
and remember that we all make mistakes,
but the mistakes that you can't recover
from are the ones that you don't own,
the ones that you don't admit.
So step up, admit your
mistakes, and own your mistakes,
and then no matter what,
keep getting after it.
And until next time,
this is Jason Gardner
and Echo n Jocko out.