So are you going to college for
the either back to college? You're,
he'd been in the military. Okay.
Number one out of the gate. Crush it.
That's what you should do in college.
You should crush it.
You should study hard
and you should crush it.
Now in order to do that, you've got
to get a mindset. Cause guess what?
You're going to think when you get out
of the military, you'd be like, go,
this is nobody do and all of this does.
This doesn't matter. You can be like, Hey,
I was in,
I was in Iraq eight months ago,
or I was in Afghanistan six months ago
and now you're sitting here telling me to
read a book and write down words on a
piece of paper. This doesn't matter.
That's an easy,
that's an easy path to go down.
It's pretty easy to say that. You
know why? Because it's actually true.
And what you did in combat has more
gravity and more consequence than anything
you're going to do in college.
And if you want to go down that path
and be, this stuff doesn't matter.
This is an important compared to what
I've done, so I'm going to blow it off.
That's a path you can go down if
you want to. I don't recommend it.
What I recommend you doing is straight
up crushing college. That's what I meant.
Recommend you doing. How'd he
do that? Because everybody,
if you make that decision
that you want to crush it,
if you want to make the decision that
you're going to prove to people that,
you know what? Yeah, I was
overseas, I was in combat.
Now I'm coming back and your
little games that you're playing,
I'm going to beat you in your own games.
So how do you do that? Number one,
do the reading that you get assigned to
do the assignments that you get tasked
with. Do everything. Let
that be your new job.
These silly little games that they're
playing. Let that be your job.
Just like I was talking
about ocs when I went to ocs,
I made that like a game for
me that I was going to win.
So do that with college and then
on top of that, make it a game.
Yes. But then on top of that
as a deeper commander's intent,
make it that you're going to not
just do well there as a game,
but you're going to do well
so you can get smarter.
So you can really actually
learn information that's
going to make you a better
person and give you better
ability to dominate in the
world of, that's what you
should be doing in college.
Now, these kids that you're going
to be going to college with,
they're not going to have this attitude.
They're going to be, you know, hey,
what do I need to do to get by?
What's Sally doing tonight?
I'm more concerned about that than I am
about going out dominating this course
so that I can get an a so that I have
knowledge so I can go and crush some,
some vocation later on in life.
So don't just do it as a game. You've
gotta play the game a little bit. I mean,
you've got to, for me, I get
the game mentality going,
but I think game mentality is a rooted
in something deeper and it's rooted.
It is gaining knowledge to be smarter.
And better as a human.
Now a couple things about
college and the actual tactics,
techniques and procedures to dominate.
Because when I went to college,
I did dominate and when
I went to high school,
I did not dominate. Why don't the high
school, I didn't care about high school.
I was like, whatever, got
waiting. Can I go in the military?
It can I go now. So, but when I went
to college, I had a new attitude,
which was I'm going to dominate.
I'm an,
I'm in a battle against these people here,
I'm going to beat them.
So there's some of the things
that are important. Number one,
college is all about time management.
Getting ahead of the curve
because it's so easy.
That's what happens with kids in college.
That's why they don't do well because for
the first time there's no one tracking
them.
No one's imposing discipline on them.
You have to have in order
to do well in college,
you have to have self discipline because
no one's going to tell you to start
that paper that's due in six weeks.
No one's going to tell you to
start it tomorrow. Yup. Yup.
You can just blow it off.
You can blow it off for five and a half
weeks and then you've got to write a 30
page paper in two days and it's gonna.
It's not going to be quality.
No one's going to ask you have you
done your homework before dinner?
That's right. So you need to
get the time management going.
Do you need to get a disciplined
time management schedule?
You need to get ahead of the
curve as early as possible. Right.
You know when you want to write papers,
do a 30 page paper due,
you need to write it in chunks
and it makes it so easy.
I mean it was a joke when
I was going to college,
I would have my papers
completely done like a week out,
like a week out.
I would be done with a 30 page paper and
then I would just be reviewing it and
getting it all completely dialed in.
I'd turn it in two days early
and then move onto the next one.
Same thing with studying.
You don't want to study.
You do want to study hard right
before the day of the test,
but you want to have knowledge already
absorbed in there so you wanna.
You want to study leading up to that.
When you do reading that I talked about
highlight, break out the highlighters.
That's what I do and all these books
that were hammering through right now,
we don't always,
I always send out pictures of,
they're all highlighted and marked up.
That's how I'm getting the
good information out of them.
So highlight and then another little
trick is to make the flashcards I used to
highlight and then I would make
flash cards about what I highlighted.
Turn everything into a question and
then you go through the flash cards and
you're going to, you're
going to memorize stuff. Oh,
here's the big one. This is
really obvious, but guess what?
People don't ask questions,
ask questions.
I used to raise my hand straight.
I would sit in the front row.
First of all in college,
I sat in the front row.
I was 20 what was I 20 I think I was
27 or 28 years old going to college.
I would sit in the front row in the
little desk and I look like Arnold
Schwarzenegger in like
a little kid's desks.
I then I'd raise my hand all the way
up like all the way up over my head and
they'd be looking at me,
you know,
cause in college they kind of stop raising
their hand. But I did it anyways. Yeah.
Just to be be you. Just
to be, just to do it.
So I'd raise my and but you ask questions
cause guess what? The college kids,
they don't ask questions and, and
guess what? Adults don't ask questions,
why don't they ask us? Cause they got an
eagle. They didn't want to look stupid.
Right. I don't care. I'm here to win.
Exactly. Oh I you don't think I'm
smart. Let's check out the GPA homeboy.
You know what I'm saying?
So ask questions if I and ask
questions as soon as that,
as soon as the knowledge,
as soon as the understanding train
starts to get derailed a little bit,
ask the question right then maybe give it,
maybe give it a minute to see if you
can get it back on track by yourself.
But the minute you realize
you're not understanding,
raise your hand and say, Hey,
you know what teacher, I don't
understand that. Can you reexplain that?
Because I'm not understanding. Yeah,
you don't want to miss that train.
I don't want to miss the train.
You don't want it to go too far off
course and then you're just lost.
So when you feel it coming off,
try and catch up real quick, clean.
You'll take a look and
then just raise your hand.
Put your hand all the way up in the air,
sit in the front row,
put your hand all the way up in the air
and look at the teacher with with a dead
serious face and they're gonna look
at you all nervous and be like, yes,
that's the only one. I went to
college. They called me John Because,
because that's what the
attendance sheet said,
cause my real name is John and that's
what the attendance sheet said.
And so they'd say, yeah, I'd
be sitting there and they'd
say yes John. And I'd say,
yeah, I don't understand that.
Could you re explain it please? Hey,
when they called you John, did
that fuel the fire? No, not at all.
It doesn't matter to me,
but it's the only time cause like I didn't
know these people because normally if
I'm going to work with someone,
when I introduced myself I'll be like,
hey my name is chocolate. Cause
that's what everyone always calls me.
But these people would call my name and
the tendons and I didn't want to have
this, you know, adversarial releasing
shit. Sorry. Oh yes John. That's me.
The other thing is, you know, do
some psychological warfare. You know,
I would line up my pencils, I do it
on the podcast you bought right here.
Eye Line up pencils. It's a, it's
a, it's also getting into character.
You're priming,
you're priming myself.
I'm looking at the teacher like I am
so ready to take notes that if I have a
downed pencil it will not cost me a
single letter. I'll be back in the game.
All your contingencies.
Yeah,
contingency passes a standing by it
and then so they sit in the front role,
line up your pencils,
have your notebooks ready,
personally challenged the
teacher you want it to.
You want your personal
challenge to be the pole,
every piece of knowledge out of them
and then go beyond what they know.
I was, I was, I was
competing with the teachers.
I was trying to learn more
than they actually knew.
And then they bring their little tests,
a little exams,
you and you just crushed
them and smash them.
Now they'll see the thing you gotta be
careful of here is this can get political,
this can get political.
And if you start being
offensive with the way you act,
if you start rubbing it in their face,
then guess what?
That can affect your grade. And part of
the game here is to get a good grade.
So you actually, it's a time for you
to start building your relationship,
building skills, time to start
building your leadership skills.
Cause you're gonna start
manipulating the teacher, right?
You want to make them think that you're
actually super interested in stupid crap
class that they're teaching. I want
them to think that not out. Now,
some classes you're going
to love and they're gonna,
you're gonna learn a lot from,
like if you're into English and you get
to take advanced grammar and syntax,
you're going to be sitting in
there like, yes, this is rocks.
But there's gonna be some
classes you don't want to take.
But you got to get in there and make
your teacher think that you're super
interested in,
super fired up to learn that thing and
that you're not just interested in the
grade. But at the same time they got to
know that grades important to you too.
So you want to get along
with them and again,
go into college and if you're a veteran,
you're representing all of us out there.
So you should be going in there
and just smashing college.