What's your opinion on
calisthenics versus weights?
Again, for me, both, I
like them both. You know,
with calisthenics you get
that endurance strength,
you get some flexibility
and some mobility out of it.
They're pretty natural movements, right?
They're pretty natural movements or
things that you're doing with your human
body. So they're going to be more natural.
Weights obviously make you
stronger, more explosive.
At a certain point they also
can be more injury inducing.
Sure.
And at another point they're
also less injury inducing.
So there's a certain point where if you
have an injury in your shoulder and you
normally would do handstand pushups,
which means you're lifting up 230 pounds,
well with weight training you could
lift up 40 pounds if you want to.
Right? So, so there's,
it goes both ways where
sometimes calisthenics might
be the more injury inducing
thing and sometimes weight training
might be the more injury inducing things.
That's why you got to balance the two
of them, you know? And for instance,
when I,
if I like I hurt my ankle a couple months
ago and I could not put any weight on
the squat bar. So I was just
doing, you know, pistils and,
and you know, air squats,
jumps and box jumps. You know,
I was using things that didn't have
any way cause I could do all that.
But the minute I put weight on my back,
you know, anything above body weight,
it started to hurt. And so I just
needed to let that thing heal.
And I used the calisthenics to
get me there. And then the same,
exact opposite. I had a,
my shoulder was tweaked six months
ago and I was having a hard time doing
handstand pushups cause it was just the
wrong angle. And so I was just using,
just using,
I was doing press with a lighter weight
than my body weight in order to keep the
blood moving in court
in order to keep the,
in order to keep the system moving. Cause
that's what I think you've got to do.
So I think you gotta be, you gotta
find a balance of both, which means,
which means I'm not great
at either one of them.
I'm not going to win in any
weightlifting competitions.
And I'm not going to win in a
gymnastics competition either. And
there are some guys, especially now,
I mean there's some guys that are
getting in sick shape. Um, you know,
you watch the guys in the
crossfit games right now,
they're savages and they're doing both
the calisthenics and the weight lifting.
And actually I was reading something
about it the other day and it's becoming
more weightlifting focused,
you know, whether it's Olympic,
what is crossing the crossfit, I shouldn't
say it's getting that more focused,
but if you wanna win the crossfit games,
you got to be able to
lift some heavyweights.
You got to be able to dead lift a lot,
snatch a lot, clean and jerk a lot.
And if you can dead lift a lot, clean
and jerk a lot and snatch a lot,
you're going to be able to do end, at
least you practice the other movements,
the muscle up, the pullups
you're going to have,
you're going to be much more apt to be
able to do those things then the other
way around. So yeah, I mean, it's,
for somebody that can do a body weight
snatch is more likely to be able to do 50
pull ups in a row than somebody that's
able to do 50 pull ups in a row.
And that's their focus in life is able
to automatically do a bodyweight snatch.
I mean, that's just the reality of
it. That's what I think right now. Um,
but the bottom line is on those,
I use both of them. I find,
I like to try and find that balance and
I think I use both of them according to
what my body prescribes me.