This is Jocko podcast number
49 with Echo Charles and me,
Jocko Willink.
Oh,
it starts off quiet.
Wait,
when you're young,
you don't quite know where it comes from
and at first you don't even know what
it is,
but you know it's something.
You feel it,
you feel it growing.
You're just a child, but
you feel it. Something,
something inside of you.
And at some point,
that thing
it crosses over.
It goes from being something
that you don't fully recognize.
Something that you don't
completely understand.
It goes from that
to being you.
Those things become you.
It is you.
Eat is your emotions.
It is sadness and happiness
and passion and anger and joy,
and it is rage
and those things,
those emotions,
the burn.