This is Jocko podcast number
55 with echo journals and me,
Jocko Willink. Good
evening. Echo could evening.
Well,
our last podcast,
which I guess is no surprise at this
point when a little loan did he not have
room for Q and.
A.
So because of that we have,
we will dedicate podcast number 55 today
to Q and a questions from the inner
webs.
Thanks to everyone that has submitted
questions through the interwebs so that we
can attempt to answer some of them.
Yeah.
And with that Echo Charles. Yes.
Questions from the interwebs.
What do you got? Well, first
question is how important
is purpose,
reason or cause and being successful
like the Perp, your purpose, right?
Well,
clearly purpose and reason and
cause are extremely important.
This is,
this is the why of of your actions.
This is knowing why you're
doing what you're doing.
This is the commander's intent.
And so you,
you absolutely, absolutely.
These are important.
If you don't know why you're
doing something well then
let me ask you a question.
Why are you doing something he does?
It's very clear.
It's very simple to understand.
So yeah, you got to know,
if you don't know why you're
doing something and didn't,
what were you going to do when you
hit an obstacle, you're going to stop.
What do you,
what adaptations are you going to make
when things go wrong to overcome them?
You're not going to make any cause you
don't know why you're doing it. Yeah.
So if you have no reason,
if you have no reason for doing something,
you're not going to do it.
So you got to have a longterm goal.
You've got to understand the underlying
purpose of what you're doing.
Now this doesn't necessarily meaning
that it mean that it has to be rigid
because it doesn't have to be rigid.
You know,
I'll tell you an interesting case as an
example I'll give you is my own case,
right? So of course, you know,
I'm all about planning in,
in always having a longterm plan and all
that stuff. But to be honest with you,
the situation that I'm
in right now as a human,
I didn't have a long term plan for
this. You know the, the, the, I,
you know,
Lafe and I wrote the book,
I had no intention of writing a book
that kind of happened, you know,
cause people were asking us and
as we worked with businesses,
they said you have this stuff written
down. So we ended up writing the book.
Once we wrote it,
we thought maybe we'd be handing it
out when we go and work with companies.
Literary agent saw today, let me,
let me show this to some publishers.
Publishers on said, let,
let us publish this. Okay,
so you figure you're going to publish it.
Well, even when you're published a book,
you don't expect it.
A bunch of people are going to read it.
You expect that you could have a
book published and that's cool.
But it ended up doing really well.
So that kind of happened with that.
All of a sudden I was on a couple
podcasts. Well, I didn't, you know,
I didn't have any intention when I
went on Tim Ferriss, his podcast,
I didn't say to myself, this is going
to propel me into my own podcast,
or Joe Rogan's part didn't say,
now if you know Joe Rogan's going to
launch me into the podcast world. No. Hmm.
I didn't expect that, but it happened
and you know what? It happened.
It made sense to me. Okay,
these two guys are squared away.
They're square to wait in this particular
genre and they're recommending my mind
is open. Okay, let's
try and make a podcast.
Did I know that the podcast was
going to be super popular now?
I just thought we were making
a podcast so that you know,
the few people want would want
to listen to it. Cool for,
I mean then look what happens. Next
thing you know we're, we're making tea.
You don't know the next thing
I'm making tea. I had no,
no idea that that ti
would be part of my world.
So all this stuff happened, right? But,
but the goal,
really the underlying,
the reason for me doing all this is
still the same through the whole thing.
And that is that I want to help people.
I want to help people with something that,
the lessons that I've learned,
I want to help them. So how can I do
that? Well, you write them down. Okay.
You wrote it down so people can read it.
Great. How else can you help them? Oh,
you can make a podcast so people can
access it easily and cheaply. Cool.
Here you go. So the underlying go, oh, you
know, I want people to be healthy. Well,
what's a good way to be healthy?
Stop drinking monster energy drinks.
Stop Drinking Red Bull 12 a day and it's
our drinking something that's healthier.
Oh, okay, cool. Jocko white
tea. Next thing you know,
that's what we've got going on.
So it's, it's, that's been my,
that's been my goal and I haven't really,
even though I,
even though I strayed from what maybe the
original path I thought I was going to
take, I still stayed.
My reason is the same.
And I think that's what I'm saying.
When your reason is clear
and your purpose is clear,
that's going to make your drive clear
and that's gonna make you execute well
because you know where you're going,
you know you where you want to be,
you understand your purpose and why
you're doing something and that's what's
gonna help you be successful in my
opinion. Do you think that like, oh, um,
you know, people, they'll be like,
this is my why and it'll be like
their kids or something like that.
Do you think that falls within
this like, you know, like reason,
purpose and all this stuff? Yeah, I
think, I think that that's the same,
this same general, the guy could've
said purpose, reason. Cause why?
I think that the question
could have said that.
I think that if your purpose is your
kids really clear example, right?
I have a lot of people might say
that. Well, that's cool. But that's,
you're going to have to clarify that a
little bit more because if your purpose
is your kids then quit your job and
just spend all day with your kids,
well then obviously you're
not supporting your kids.
Cause now you can't afford
to buy him food. So your,
your goal should be taking good care of
and providing for your children's now
and in the future. Wow. Okay. Now that
makes sense. Now you're looking longterm,
short term, you gotta you know
that you have to work hard now.
You don't have to make
investments for them. So that,
that's the kind of thing that's beyond
just a simple, I'm doing this for my kids.
Cause what are you doing for your kids?
What are you trying to achieve for him?
Yeah.
So like for using that example,
like this is my why, it's
my daughter, it's less.
This is why I'm, you know, I don't
know, writing a book, it's more,
this is why I can endure the hard days
or this is why I'm going to continue to
work hard kind of thing out.
Whatever it is I'm doing.
Yeah. And I just have an underlying
yes and underlying reason. That's,
that's a question that I think that's the
answer. Yes. Yeah, it's pretty, actually,
I should've just answered that
in two words. I should have said.
How important is purpose, reason
cause and being successful? Answer.
Very important.
There you go.
You can have a lot of
different reasons to, you know,
or like a few core reading more than one.
Yeah.
You know what I'd say if there's anything
to be taken away from this question,
ed is if you don't feel, here's the,
here's the, I would say the takeaway.
If you don't feel some
kind of drive in your life,
if you don't feel
passionate about something,
if you feel like you're wandering in,
meandering through the world,
then it's time to assess. Then it's
time to say, okay, what is my reason?
What am I trying to do?
What would I like to do in the world?
Now we get something valuable here.
We all know that you got to have a
purpose so y'all didn't get out of reason.
So if you feel yourself meandering down
the path with no reason, no purpose,
dig in and find one.
Next question.
I want to begin training in Jujitsu,
but financial constraints dictate that
I can keep my gym membership to keep
getting after it at 4:00 AM
or begin training Jujitsu,
but not both.
Oh, it's a black and white question. Is
it one or the other? Okay. First of all,
check around your area and see if
there's a gym that has both. Right.
I know that's one of the reasons
that we created my gym. Victory. MMA.
There's an an fitness on there too. Yup.
Cause no matter what you want to do,
if you're in the game, you can
do it there. You can do striking,
you can do Jujitsu or you can
do wrestling, you can do boxing,
you can do weightlifting, all kinds of
crossfit. You can do Olympic lifting,
you can do power lifting, you
can do calisthenics. You could,
so you knew everything there. That's
why we created the gym. And you,
it's not more expensive than a straight
Jujitsu gym where it's not more
expensive than a straight crossfit gym.
It's actually cheaper than most
of both foes. So look around,
see if you have a gym
that has both any fee.
If there is no gym around there that
has both, maybe you do what I did.
And you start a gym that has both, right?
I mean you could do that. I did it,
did it with some of my buddies said,
hey, you know what? We want to,
we want to train all the time
and all these different aspects.
How can we do that? Can
we go to one at, you know,
four o'clock in the afternoon.
We have to go to another gym at five
o'clock then we have to go to another gym
at seven o'clock do we want to do that?
No. So what do we do? Make our own gym.
Make it what we want.
And guess what?
When you do something like that in the
business world, if you, if you, I think,
I think Tim Ferriss said,
scratch your own itch, right?
You have an itch that you want to scratch.
There's other people that are going
to have the same match and that's what
happened with our gym. So everyone
goes, yeah, I want to train.
Of course I want to drain.
So maybe you start your own gym and Oh,
you're not a skilled boot, a Brazilian
jujitsu practitioner. Guess what?
For the first time ever in America,
there's actually a bunch of really
good Jujitsu practitioners in,
maybe you couldn't get a black
belt to come to where you live.
Maybe you could cause there's a good
chance you're good, but a brown belt,
purple belt, they can be a
good or great instructor. Yeah.
So you might open up a gym and start that.
Now that doesn't mean also that you have
to make a huge investment to do that.
You could start off with
your garage and some mats.
So that's an idea. Another thing you could
do for you. Okay, so that doesn't exist.
How would you find Jujitsu is,
this is a tough one, right?
We want to stay healthy,
we want to stay fit,
but you Jitsu is kind of the priority.
It's kind of the priority.
Don't tell you why it's
learning, right? If you take,
if you take me and you and we go through
this situation and you decide that
you're going to do Jujitsu and I decided
I'm going to weight lift in 10 years,
who's happy and who's sat?
We know the answer.
The answer's clearly now I start
because I now I have enough money.
So six years into it I started training
Jujitsu and you're a brown belt or a
black belt and I don't have this knowledge
and it's going to take me six years
to get there. Meanwhile you,
while you were training,
guess what else you were doing? You were
doing calisthenics, you were sprinting,
you are,
you are lifting rocks,
you are doing cheap stuff for free and
you're still getting a massive benefit.
So for me,
my priority is going to go to the Jujitsu
because you can go and spend $40 on a
set of rings for your garage or
your basement or your hallway.
And next thing you know you can
do pull ups, you can do dips,
you can do muscle ups, you can do
squats and sprints all day long.
You don't need anything for that.
So you can get a massive benefit with a
set of rings or you can just get a pull
up bar and you can just do pull ups and
you go to Home Depot and buy a pipe and
a couple nails and nail it into the
wall and you've got to pull a bar.
Now you can do pull ups,
push ups and squats and you're good to go.
You could become a beast
with those exercises,
so I would prioritize and at do that,
I would prioritize the Jujitsu and I'd
make some kind of a home gym or I'd go to
all why MCA or some cheaper kind of gym.
The other thing you go to do your
Jujitsu school and become the mop person.
Start cleaning up our mob and maths.
That's another thing you
can do to make this happen.
Maybe you can get a little
deal cut at both places.
Most gym places that you know, if you go
in there and say, hey look, I, I need,
I can't afford this right now.
What can you do for me?
Maybe they'll cut you some kind of a deal.
Yeah.
The other thing that you can likely do.
Now you're saying you don't have
the budget for this situation.
What is it in your budget right
now that you can cut out? Yeah,
that's my question. And the funny
thing is what can you cut out coffee?
A lot of people drink two
or $3 worth of coffee a day.
Probably even more than that. I
don't know. You're a coffee drinker.
You are going to trigger how,
how much,
how much does a coffee addict to
drink a day from Starbucks? Yeah.
That's the spectrum.
And the, you know, the,
but we're talking Starbucks cups a day.
Yeah.
If you're going to Starbucks and
buying. Yeah. I think, I don't know.
I don't buy it. Well, I get coffee
from on it to be honest with you.
So you can make your own
at home and stuff. But um,
but if someone would
works near a Starbucks,
they stop on the way to a gym membership.
It's for four bucks a day.
So that's 120 bucks a
month. Yeah. So boom,
you cut out coffee or you make your own,
make your own coffee
and you're good to go.
What about the nights that you go out
to eat? You're like, oh, you know,
I don't feel like cooking down.
It'll go out and do it.
A little restaurant that costs you 30
40 bucks a shot. Get rid of that Kate.
Well, bunch of cable
bill, your cable bill,
you're watching TV, nothing. Zero
productive. Coming out of that zero,
you're not doing anything beneficial
for yourself. Get rid of your cable.
Next thing you know,
you get rid of your cable and now
you've got enough money for your gym
membership. You know, sell another
one cell phone usage, right?
We rack up the big numbers on cell
phone. What are you doing? What?
What are you doing? Is it to
surf the interwebs and get,
you know, lose your mind.
So what can you cut down on that?
Because I'm thinking now you could
scrape away a little bit here and there.
Just lower your plan and use your,
use your phone less watching the UFC
get into u of C's. I love the UFC,
but instead of watching it at
home for 50 bucks or 59 bucks,
go to a bar and pay 10 bucks to get
in and watch it there for 10 bucks.
You just save 40 bucks or however many
about bucks that was cause actually I
want to try second. See, you know
there's all kinds of movie night.
What about the note? You want to go
see the new movie in the theater? No,
don't go see the new movie. The theater
that costs. That's an expensive now,
isn't it? Yes. Is it more than $10?
I don't even remember. Less than,
I think it's like 10 or 1511 yeah.
Well I went one time is the 11 that
was is over a year ago though. Yeah.
So cut that out. Bike to work, you know,
do something to get you started shaving
a little bit of money because in the
long run, what you're going
to get from these two things,
from fitness and from Jujitsu are going
to be going to have so much value in
your life. There's going to be,
they're going to be worth way more.
What these little marginal
things that you're cutting
out are. Yeah. And that way,
like in the beginning how you said
like what is it that you can cut
out?
So basically you're,
you're identifying what is it right now
that you're considering more important
than you did two where
the gym or whatever,
which the term actual answer
to that is nothing there.
There's nothing more important than your
life then your fitness and really your
Jujitsu is part of your fitness and
also its knowledge and its confidence in
it's, yeah. Okay. Um, I know that
people are gonna Freak out. Okay.
I'm not saying it's the most important
thing in your life in terms of,
in terms of, of purchases
that you can make. Yes.
These two things are of the highest level.
Now you need a car to get back
and forth to work. Understood.
You need a house for sleeping. Understood.
You need food on the table. Understood.
You need to take care of your family.
Understood.
As soon as you get into the
optional things in life.
These are the top two. These
are the top two. I think so too.
And tell me I'm wrong, I don't, I'm
not, I can't tell you you can get good.
But when Phil, but making the, as
far as making the decision goes your,
you're essentially identifying what you
currently are holding more important
than it. Regardless of what you
think is more important. Your,
you got to identify it and the
actions are a statement. Yeah. Yes.
Of what you believe get and that
I'm a big one too is like drinking.
I got to know not everyone drinks.
So who knows? I don't know.
Some person might not drink at all,
but if you buy a six pack of beer,
let's say you do that, you know,
I don't know,
twice a week or something like that.
That's like more than a gym members to
that's your coffee thing is big too.
But yeah, there, yeah, there is a lot
of little, little ways. The cable thing,
I gotta be honest only because you're
probably not the only one that watches TV.
I know it, the argument is like, Hey,
TV isn't good quote unquote for anybody,
so everyone should just be signed
on in the household kind of thing.
So what's your point? It's not that
easy all the time saying you know,
like there is going to be
some ripples in the, you know,
especially when you first
make that transition.
If you choose to take it upon yourself
to cut out cable because you want to go
to Jujitsu. No. Oh. And you
make everyone in your house.
You improve everyone in your
house mentally and physically.
I know what it's like surgery.
He got to make that initial incision
and open up everything and make a mess
before you can repair, you know, so that,
that initial part is going to be
most of the ways around that too.
You get Netflix or Hulu or
one of those things that were,
you get streaming on demand, right? The,
which is kind of where everything's going
anyway, really right now. Yeah. But yeah,
there's some, there's some good stuff
too. Good. So as far as the job,
find a way to do both. It can be done.
Know you can do it. Get creative.
The home gym is good.
That's good because that's something
you could just start slowly and start
adding to slowly four bucks. You've got
rings. Don't have your start. Yeah, me,
you'll be good to go for
sure. Um, okay. Next question.
Jocko had an incident. I
wanted your opinion on love,
your book booking podcast,
always listening to apply your
lessons to my life, job and family.
I was driving home one night with my wife
and four year old son in the car when
some junk idiot was walking
in the middle of the roadway.
He stood in front of my car
refusing to move, running his mouth.
My wife begged me not to get out of
the car. Guy Reached in his front,
reached into his front waistband like he
had a gun and and although myself being
a police officer and having countless
incidents and experience like this,
I didn't feel he did more like drunk
and bravado or grandstanding any case.
Those I was armed and having trained in
boxing and a little bit of Jujitsu felt
I could have handled this situation.
This lasted about a minute of him
standing there and eventually I just drove
around him while he was running his mouth,
calling me names and all that stuff.
My first priority obviously is getting
my family home safely and making sure
nobody will ever do any harm to them.
But another part of me felt like,
what am I teaching my son? I mean,
is that okay? Um, you know,
is that okay to let people disrespect you
and act any way they want towards you?
So I dropped off my s uh,
so I dropped off my family and went
back looking for the guy. He was gone.
I guess lucky for me as well as him.
I'm questioning my decision,
not out of ego,
but only because of the
example I want to be to my son.
That you never go looking for
trouble and confrontation,
but you don't back down from it
ever. Okay. Well just first of all,
you one, just so you know, you won,
you got a wife and a kid. Yeah, you won,
right? So options or three
options here. Well, for one,
if you're a police officer, you could
call the police. You could, you know,
gone get on your radio and call them to
say what's going on and have this guy
arrested before he causes on the of an
actual accident. Being out in the strode,
like an idiot being out in the road
like an idiot. So that's an option.
But, but the other thing is like what
are you trying to teach your son?
Are you trying to teach your son that
he should fight every idiot that offends
him? He's, if you, if
that's what you teach him,
he is not going to have a very
productive life or a very nice life.
So there's too many negatives,
right? That can happen there.
This actually happened
to something similar to,
this happened to me a little while ago.
I was down by the ocean down by the pier
in the neighborhood where I live and
there was a like a tweaker crazy, you
know, drunk on drugs and all that.
And it was, it wasn't as
direct as this. He wasn't,
he wasn't saying anything at me,
but he's yelling swear words and,
and he's in front of my kid,
my kid,
this was when my son was probably six or
seven years old and he's just alone and
he's isolated, but he's swearing
and just acting crazy. Right?
And what I did was I said to my son,
okay, you see this guy right here?
Have you heard of what drugs are? This
is what drugs do to you right here. This,
this guy, this is where it ends up. So
this guy's a miscreant, he's a criminal.
And the other thing I told him, I
said, what if this guy attacks us?
What do you think would happen?
And my son was kind of, you know,
will you would choke him cause my
son trained to do two at that time.
And he goes, well you would choke
him. And I was like, that's right.
I'm not afraid of this guy.
We're not afraid of this guy.
This is no factor because we know how to
fight, we know how to defend ourselves.
But that being said,
what we want to do is we want to
avoid the situation. You know,
there's all kinds of, all
kinds of bad things that can
happen there. We know this,
I told my son, like this guy could
have a knife, Scott could have a gun.
This guy could have, this guy could
just have a blood borne disease, right?
This guy could have a bloodborne disease.
Now I go and get in a fight with him
and now I have a bloodborne disease.
You know what? What, what, what? That's
horrible. That's a horrible situation.
So like I said, I told him that
this is, this is why we train.
This is why we know how to use firearms.
Because when people are maniacs and if
they're insane and psychopathic and they
have weapons,
you need to have a weapon yourself.
You need to be able to defend yourself.
So our PR, this is what I teach my son.
My primary objective is
to be safe, right? To,
to not get to avoid these situations.
And guess what?
If you still feel the need to like be
a man in the situation or prove that
you're a man or proof to your son,
that which is valuable.
I'm not trying to put that down.
You want your son to see that, that,
that you should be strong and that you
should be able to stand up for yourself
and that you will don't ever
have to back down to anybody.
But that's why your son comes with you
to the gym. That's why he trains Jujitsu.
That's why you train Jiu Jitsu. That's why
he watches you day in, day out, day out,
working out, being strong,
being tough, going to the gym,
training with firearms. That's why he
sees all that stuff. So he knows. I mean,
I'll tell you right now,
my kids,
if you were to ask my kids like
against a random person in the street,
they would, they pro basically think
I could beat up anyone in the world.
You know what I mean? That's
the thing. Because as I said,
me training all the time, right?
That's all they see me do. So,
so that's that.
Now the disrespect part,
d disrespected me, right?
Disrespect. And sometimes you know,
disrespect me is one thing, but
now you disrespect my wife, right?
Well again,
how can you be disrespected?
And that's what I explained.
I would explain to my son,
you cannot just be disrespect,
be disrespected by someone that
has no respect for themselves.
And if you are a drunk idiot in the
street, you have no respect for yourself.
You don't,
you cannot disrespect me.
It is impossible for you to give me
disrespect and even respect yourself as a
human. Right? So, so that's just, that's
just added. It doesn't get any account.
And I'll tell my son that all day long or,
or any of my kids that all day long,
you can't be disrespected by someone
that doesn't even respect themselves.
You know what I am respect.
I'm even respectful to this drunk idiot,
giving them the benefit of the doubt.
I am respect.
So you know,
then the other pieces, not
backing down from trouble, right?
And I'm not gonna back down from
trouble, but I am going to avoid it.
We're going, I'm going to avoid it.
And you know what?
Trouble avoids me.
Kate avoids me.
And if you are working now in you're
staying strong and you have the confidence
because you know you can handle yourself,
trouble is going to avoid
you 99% of the time.
And the other thing is
you got to tell your kids,
I mean my son is getting older now.
If he gets in a fight with
someone he could kill them.
I mean that's a straight
up what could happen.
And so now I've got an [inaudible] and
you know he's a young kid so he's got a,
he's got to do the things that you're
talking about in this question.
Prove themself and prove that he's
not going to back down. I was,
I got to explain to them,
listen,
let me tell you what comes with
getting in a street fight. A cool rush.
Cause it's fun, right?
It's fun. So you get that.
Maybe you get a little bit of props,
you get a little bit of respect from the,
from the, you get accred right?
Some street credit from your people.
Let me tell you what else comes with it.
Along with those two things, which are,
which are cool, right? Possible jail time,
possible injuries, possible
lawsuits, the broken hand.
I mean even if just, okay, those
are the big ones, right? Jail time.
Which there's been plenty of cases
where there was a claim case here in San
Diego. Guy Punched another guy, fell
on the curb. Dead died. Right? Yeah.
Those things really happen. Not to
mention you could get, you know,
so you get jail time, you get an injury.
Not, not to mention you could get killed,
right? Cause you think you're
a tough guy. Guess what?
The greatest MMA fighters in the world
get caught with a crack in the face and
they get knocked out. You fall down
and hit a curb. You, you could die.
So there's that aspect too. But
then you get to the injuries, right?
Cause you're getting a street
fight, you're going to get
some kind of an injury,
you're going to get some
kind of an injury. It's just
going to happen. You know,
whether it's just a little cut or a
little brazen and you're going to have
something that's a pain. It could be a
major injury. You could break your hand.
That happens all the time, lawsuits
because now you're going to get sued.
Now they're coming after you and if you,
it's just a stupid thing like a rip jacket
or a scuff me. It just isn't worth it.
It isn't worth it.
Especially because we're talking about
an individual that you can crush in an
instant and that has no value
as a human in this account.
What this person's doing,
none. This person is an idiot.
Don't go down to their level
and play that game. Instead,
avoid that and go to the gym
and train more and be ready.
Yeah. That's my opinion. Good job on
walking away, going out to find the guide.
Luckily you already said,
luckily you didn't find him
because right now who knows?
Maybe you'd be the guy that's on you.
You're going to jail. The cop that, oh,
you're a cop and you were armed and you
went and got in a fight with this guy
and you've pulled your weapon because
you were losing it. And he shot him.
And then what do we see when she's
somebody that had cell phone and they
recorded the whole thing and they see
you pushing this guy around. Yeah.
It's not a good situation.
And you gotta be ultra responsible when
you're carrying ultra responsible when
you're carrying, you know that we all
know that when we carry, we got to avoid.
That's, that's what we have to
do when we're packing. Wow. Okay.
Yeah. And you can kind of tell
when someone's scared. You know,
when like if this guy and a guy in
the street and you're in the car,
that's another, that seems real obvious.
You drive around and you go home,
but it's, you know, it's
someone's like, get it.
Like if you're walking on the sidewalk
and he gets in your way, that's, you know,
it's kind of different and whatever,
but avoiding the situation. Yeah.
And you're not scared because
you prepared to whatever and you,
you simply walk around or go the
other way or something like that.
The people with you, they can tell,
they can tell you, not scared.
You can tell that you're making the
right decision, but if you are scared,
whether you fight the guy or you run away
scared, they can tell that too. Yeah.
So I had another situation the other day,
I was walking out street with my whole,
well yeah with, with my whole family
thing going to get some ice cream. It was,
it was a couple months goes in the
summertime going to get some ice cream.
Haley had a discipline, disciplinary
breakdown in my own mentality,
which you're going to get ice cream.
So we're walking down the street and
out of nowhere this guy just gets in my
like stood up and got in my face with
really fast and I just kinda looked at him
and sort of did the,
you know, into the um,
semi, not a full on fight
stance but I turned, you know,
like a quarter turn and just looked
at him because I thought, okay,
we're going to rock and roll,
we'll make this happen.
And it almost instantly what happened,
what you just described happened
as soon as the guy got in my face,
he like immediately within one,
within a half a second immediately
backed down and walked away.
It was like he was just
trying to prove something.
Then you realize really quick he was
going to get crushed. But anyways,
that's the same thing. You
know, the guy could tell, oh
you want to fight, you know,
if you're telling that
story about Euler Euler,
Gracie coiler told me this story and I
guess you know when there's a really good
surfer and Euler was out surfing at
a spot in San Diego and San Diego,
like all surfing areas is, is pretty um,
territory, territorial. And there's some,
there's some are some aggression
in the surf. And anyways,
some guy started getting aggressive with,
with boiler and oh and they're
said to him some classic line.
It was something along the lines of,
hey man,
you surf for a living. I fight for a
living. If you want to go to the beach,
let me know.
Otherwise be quiet.
I thought that was a great
line. Nicely done. Holding
bread this time we went up.
But it's the same, you know,
boilers small for those of
you who don't know who boiler,
Gracie isn't wholly there is a small
small guy and he's obviously a master of
Jujitsu but he's only 150 pounds,
155 pounds maybe.
Really small guy. And he's a
nice guy. So he's not a guy that,
he's not a guy that's going
to be intimidated. He's not,
he's not his looks are not
going to intimidate anybody.
I don't even think he has
cauliflower ears. I mean it's just,
he just looks like a nice guy and he is
a nice guy and he's got a nice presence
about him. So what I'm saying is what
again, to reinforce what you just said,
when someone is confident to that level,
even though there are 145 or 150 pounds
and look like a nice guy with a smile on
her face, when you confidently say, look,
you know what I do for living, I fight.
If you want to go to the beach and
fight, let me know. And the guy says, Oh,
you know what? I'm good. I'm
good. I'll just leave you alone.
That sounds like a plan.
Yeah, the little detector
goes off like danger, danger.
I'm going to get my ass beat.
But, and some, but some guys are,
as far as decision making goes,
some guys are crazy.
You know where like how you said like
if they're like on drugs or this guy in
this case if you sit in the middle of
the road acting like you know boys in the
hood kind. We've got a problem here.
That's what he said he was doing.
Like he's obviously off, you know like
he's not a decision maker kind of thing.
So you know, if you jump into
a situ situation with them,
it's kind of unpredictable
in that weird way, you know?
Let me tell you something else.
Let's say the guy has a
gun or doesn't have a gun.
You had the moment to get away from
it. Yeah. If you thought he had a gun,
you get away from him, right? Let's
say you said, Oh you know what?
I'm going to confront him right now. So
you, let's say you get in a shootout,
you kill him. Guess what you got to
do now? You got to hire a lawyer,
you got to hang up, you got to take a
break from work cause you're a copy.
There's all these things,
so not worth it.
It's just a pain in the ass is what it is.
It's
almost like, I mean, maybe I'm wrong
here, but it's almost like you can't,
like what?
What's the thing,
what's the goal we're going for when
we go ask question today? What's the,
what's your reason why
your reason for doing this,
I'm going to go out and look for,
I'm going to look for the guy,
but then like what's the goal?
Like what's the outlook?
What are we going for there when we go
look for him to tell him not to do that
again or to what? To arrest them or
to kick his ass or belief, right.
What's going on. Yeah. And then even
that you don't, a lot of times we don't.
I know when you're in that moment, you
don't think past that. You're just like,
I gotta get my whatever,
my revenge really is what it is.
He shouldn't have done that to me.
I'm going to go teach them a lesson kind
of a thing. I mean, that's the feeling.
I don't know. Yeah, but
guys are weird, man.
You can jump into that weirdness spreads.
Go home with your family and watch
when the confrontation happens.
The best case scenario isn't good. The
best case scenario, if you jump in there,
just the best case scenario that's
going to happen. It isn't good. Yeah,
because you got, even if you walk up and
knock the guy out with one clean punch,
you got to, you got a broken finger,
you know you've got a broken knuckle.
Even if you walk up and choke the guy,
you got his grimy puke all over it.
You know what I mean?
It's just there.
There's nothing that good is going to
come out of it other than it feels good to
fight.
But that can easily be remedied by
going to the gym and finding all of your
buddies. And in this case, I don't
know, you know this guy, oh, you,
you'd knocked out a weird homeless
guy in the, in the middle of the road,
in front of your family. Like I don't
see how that's cool. Yeah, I know that.
I mean, maybe, I don't know if that
would feel good. I don't think so. Yeah.
But yeah, it's kind of weird. This
one time we went on this cruise
and it was me, Terry, Tim, you know,
it's kind of like Terry's huge,
like I'm kind of big or whatever.
Tim and art or girlfriends,
this guy was behind us in the booth. We
were at a restaurant or something and um,
we were like, what are, I guess the booths
were flimsy, so we're shaking the booth.
He was behind us. He got up
all crazy. It's like, Hey,
what did he say? He said,
yeah, you guys are big,
but you guys keep knocking the booth.
We're going to basically
called us out to a fight.
He had like tattoos everywhere on his
neck and stuff. And at first I was like,
man, is this good joking? Like
we're like, what's going on?
I was confused and to be honest, I was
like stunned. Like almost like I didn't,
this scenario was so foreign to me. Oh,
styling and not even know what to say.
I don't even know what everyone else
was doing. That's how stunned I was.
But then Tim, he was Kinda, he
stuck and stuff. So he was like,
it's just a series right now. He just
jumped out east that he likes stands up,
goes to final, but the guy was
a Weirdo. That's the thing.
It was like all of us big guys,
you know, and Tim was like,
he wasn't scared at all.
He was ready to fight.
So he gets in his face face there about
if I want us cruise by the way we're
fighting. You can't fight on a cruise.
No. So it's this big scene, you know,
and the guy like, he
was like, I don't know,
I guess he was ready to die or something
cause he was like Kinda down the fight
and guys came in like I think
broke it up or whatever.
We had to make this big report
and he was like this big thing.
So it was all just a pain in the
ass is basically what we're saying.
You're right. I'm saying like what
if we fought that guy, you know,
they taught him a lesson or what if Tim
father or whatever getting arrested and
you got a lawsuit against him
and we were on a cruise Zachary.
It's all stupid. Yeah, don't do
that. Can stuff. Next question.
Jackie loved the podcast part of the
question. Oh, thank you. Right on.
Any suggestions for leading command
staff to understanding the ground level
troops in a mission?
Okay,
so for those of you that are not
in the military command staff,
that's sort of for the business world,
that would
be like corporate headquarters.
You know the corporate headquarters,
you've got the command
staff and it happens in both
situations where you end up
with,
with the command staff,
with the corporate headquarters
that kind of loses track of what,
what they're actually therefore
the ground level mission,
the troops that are on the ground.
And this is a tough question,
but it's also kind of a simple one.
So I go back to trying to constantly
remind people what the mission is,
what are they trying to do. And I had to
the admiral and I was the admiral's aid.
I worked for the admiral, great
guy. And one of the things,
I've probably talked about this before,
but one of the best things
that he did was cause he's,
he's so detached from the seal platoons.
Like there's layer upon layer upon
layer in between him and them. And,
and actually believe it or not,
the job of the admiral that's
in charge of the seal teams,
this is gonna sound strange to everybody.
The job of the admiral that's in
charge of the seal teams is to
get equipment and gear and training for
the seal teams now and for like the next
10 years because that's the way the
budgetary process works in the Pentagon.
And there's so, so don't think
of when you think I know you,
you want to think of the seal admiral
as the warfighter. Let's go in forward.
The guy that's actually in charge,
the senior seal.
Now there you can be a special operations
because there's other places you could
be, but the guy that's in
charge of the seals of,
of naval special warfare command,
that's what it's called,
naval special warfare command.
The adults in charge of that,
which puts them in charge of all
the seals. That guy, his main, his,
his job is to train and equip seals,
train and equip,
not take them into battle but train and
equip and so you end up with this whole
organization where the purpose of the
organization is to train and equip,
but the organization is huge and even
that command organization gets very big
and so what they start doing is they
start losing focus that 10 levels below
them out somewhere overseas is,
is an eight man squad and a Zodiac
off the coast of some nation.
Doing a reconnaissance is very,
they, they don't even think about,
they haven't thought about that for years
and so they lose track and it happens
in the corporate world as well
where the the the head shed that's,
they're dealing with stuff too, right?
They're dealing with legal problems,
they're dealing with compliance problems.
They're dealing with financial problems.
They lose track of the fact that there's
a guy on the front line that's trying
to fix a car or replace
a an air conditioner, you
know, that's the way it is.
So you lose the vision of that,
you lose track of that.
So what was great about this animal
that I work for is in these big meetings
where they would be talking about s,
you know,
hundreds of millions of dollars of
expenditures over the next 12 years,
various training commands and all
this stuff. Huge. And he would always,
he would always say, how does this
impact a seal platoon overseas?
How does this,
how does this help a seal assaulter go
out and shoot a bad guy in the face?
That's what he would ask.
And that gives them snaps.
Everybody snaps everybody back
into reality of what they're get.
It connects exactly what this question is.
Um,
suggestions for leading command staff to
understanding the ground level troops.
And you've got to ask that question and
the business side of seeing the same
thing. You know, the guys totally lose
track of it. So, so you, you ended up,
you got to ask the question,
hey, everything that you're
talking about, you know,
this, this compliance thing
and this regulatory thing
and this new software that
you're talking about.
Let me ask you a question.
How is this going to help one of our
frontline sales people close a deal?
That's the question.
That's the whole reason that we're here.
The whole reason that
this big staff is here,
the whole reason we have this building,
the whole reason we have this base is so
that a seal overseas can close with and
destroy the enemy or so,
or if we're in a big corporation is so
that this repairman can make it to a,
a house and fix an electrical
problem in a short period of time,
efficiently and effectively.
That's what we're all here for.
So I think that's what you have to do.
You have to keep reminding them of
what's going on down on the phone lines,
what the mission is, what the men
are doing, what issues are out there.
Another thing you could take is you want
to take these people with you or you
want to get anecdotal information.
That's, I know it's cheap,
it's cheap to do this,
but you go out and you gather anecdotal
information that you can bring back to
headquarters and say, Hey, you know what?
I know we're all doing a good job here.
Let me tell you, the troops on the ground
need this cold weather gear right now.
They don't have it. Here's
a, here's a message.
I just got bumped from a guy overseas.
They're up in northern Iraq.
We thought it was going to be warm.
Guess what? It's 32 degrees there.
Snow on the ground. These guys aren't
prepared for it. We need to get into gear.
Okay,
so you're using anecdotal information to,
to paint the picture of what's going
on in the front lines. Same thing with,
you know,
if you're a corporate guy and you
want to make sure people stay engaged,
go out on a call with that electrician
that's visited in a house on a,
on it where there's been
a break or have blown.
And the guys working through the payment
system that you devise that you thought
was so smart,
it doesn't get connection while you're
out in the field and now he can't run a
credit card. You want to come back and
tell them, tell the head shed that.
So those are some of the things.
Another thing that you could do is you
asked those questions all the time and
maybe you just come up with some kind
of a mantra that you repeat all the time
and that you sign your emails with. It
says, you know, we're here to support,
we're here to support the front line guys.
We're here for the front line.
You know, or ask yourself the question,
does this help the front line?
Every decision that we make, we got to ask
herself, does this help our front line?
Does this help our frontline personnel?
Um,
and I think that's what you gotta do.
Now.
One thing that you've
gotta be ready for on this,
you gotta be ready for someone to say,
Dave, don't understand the big picture.
This is what you got to be ready for it.
Cause I've heard this well,
who's going to say that? Corporate.
Oh you go to the corner and say, look,
you know we've got the guys on the front
lines. We need to get them this gear.
And they go, look, they don't
understand the big picture.
We can't afford that right now. We didn't
look okay. I hear what you're saying.
But be ready for it.
It's an excuse.
It's an excuse and you gotta be ready
for it in the way that you get ready for
it. I've talked about this and they only
get in times the way you get ready for,
as you have ammunition,
you have ammunition.
You've got to have your ducks in a row.
If you're going to raise
your hand and say, Hey,
here's what's going on the front lines,
here's, here's a problem that they have.
You can't, but you can't just
back down. When they say, hey,
they don't know what's going on. They
don't get it. They don't get the bill.
That's a big thing. They say in the
military, they don't get the big picture.
I would hear that threaten and say,
you know what,
actually we do get the big picture.
We're living the big picture.
You don't get the big picture.
Here's the big picture.
I got frontline troopers that need cold
weather gear or they're going to freeze
and not be able to operate. The picture
doesn't get any bigger than that.
Now you can't call it of course,
come across like that and which you
have to do is you have to look at it
systematically and over
a long term and say,
this is about plan and I've got a plan
for the long term of how are we gonna get
these guys as cold weather
gear in the future.
But right now we've got a little fixed.
It's going to cover these guys
that are in the field right now.
You've got to come armed with
ammunition so that you can,
you can refute this.
Common call that gets made,
which is they don't understand
the big picture out in the field,
so don't worry about them.
No.
The only reason we're here is
for those guys in the field.
So what's her number them?
That's pretty good.
Next question.
You talk about stepping back or
detaching to better assess situations.
Can you expand on how
you detach?
Okay, so this is again, this is
one I've been asked. I probably,
even if I answered this before,
yes. Should we just skip it?
Uh, no. I think it's worth it, you
know? Okay, I'll, I'll go over.
I'll go over quickly since people ask
me all the time. Okay. First of all,
you wanted to attach step back,
literally step back.
If you're online with a bunch
of people in a combat situation,
literally step back. If you're, if
you're in a combat situation, high port,
your weapon, your weapon at the seat,
at the roof, at the sky, whatever,
you're not going to engage in your target.
You're gonna step back. If you're in a,
if you're in a business environment,
step away from the computer,
step away from the terminal,
put down your pen back away.
There's a year and a meeting,
heated meeting you need to attach,
stand up back away from the table, but
it's literally stand back and step away.
Once you do that, you,
you relax. Now that,
that physical part that I just talked
about, it literally stepping back,
that's something that it's a,
it's a physical reminder of what to do.
You can get to a point in your life
where you don't need to do that. Yeah.
Or where you usually
don't have to do that,
but things can still escalate quickly
to where even the most highly trained
detached person still lasts
it step back and take up,
take a wrap off and take a look around.
So in most of these situations is,
especially when you're first starting
to try and do it physically, step back,
physically do something that indicates
to you as a person and it actually
indicates to everyone around
you that you're doing this.
Like when somebody stands up from the
table and steps back. It's an indicator.
Okay. He's, he's taking the wrap off,
right? You're Madec we get it. Yeah.
Actually we're trying not to be dramatic,
but it's going to be dramatic anyway.
It is now. Take a breath, take a breath,
look around and make a call.
That's, that's it. That's
how easy it is to detach.
Now the actual hard part of detachment
is being self aware enough that you know
when to detach the,
that's the,
that's the challenging part because they
end up in this situation. By the time,
by the time they go, man, I should
have detached. Yeah, that's right.
You should have detached. You lost
your temper. You got involved.
He couldn't make a decision.
You got dragged into the
weeds like everybody else
did. It's it's, if somebody,
if I would have,
and I've done this plenty of times
when I was training seal platoons,
I would just go up to the leader who
was getting dragged her situation.
I'd be like, Hey, step back with me.
I'd take them two steps off the line
of like look around and then they'd be
easily be able to make a decision.
That's the, that's the easy part.
The easy part is step.
Stepping back.
The hard part is knowing that you
need to do it because it's like,
I guess it's, and then to use the
stupid analogy of the boiling frog,
right where you put a bowl, you put a frog
in water, you slowly start to boil it.
Next thing you know it's next
thing get knows it's dead.
It didn't realize that though where if
you throw it into hot water it would just
try and jump out immediately. It's
the same thing here. You don't,
you'll get walk into a room
and the chaos is going on. No,
you walk into the room and everything
seems okay and then it starts to escalate,
escalate,
escalate and next thing you know you're
in it and next thing you know something
bad has happened and you
didn't detach and time.
So you lost the bubble and you lost
control and everything went sideways.
So you got to know when you got to
understand when it is you needed to adapt.
You've got to have your own personal
red flags to tell you that it's time to
relax. When you feel yourself
getting frustrated, we just
start getting like that.
You needed to detach.
When you feel you're,
if you're getting foster
to go back cut to detach,
you've started feeling the anger,
you're feeling the white knuckles or
you start pecking hard at the keyboard,
right? Right. When you type an email out
and you're hitting the keyboard hard,
that's an indicator to cater for you
better not hit send because whatever you
wrote isn't good. It's not going to solve
any problems. You're raised voice, right?
You start raising the voice. You start
getting angry and agro with people.
Those are the little things.
Those are the little indicators
that tell you you need to detach.
Step back, take a breath, look
around, walk out of the room,
put your weapon at high
port. Just relax. Look
around. Make a call. One
more thing. Sometimes.
Sometimes what?
What?
The reason you need to detach is just so
you can see something from a different
angle and you can ask a question. I
love, I personally love doing this.
I'm in a in a meeting,
right?
And I work with a bunch of businesses
and it actually gets pretty, you know,
I'm getting involved in what they're
doing and they'll be all basically staring
at a problem,
right?
Staring at a problem and they
can't figure out what the solution,
whether it's a leadership
problem or a process problem,
and they're all staring at this problem
and they can't come to a solution while
I come in. First of all, I'm
totally detached, right? It's,
it's one of the benefits of my job is
I'm totally detached. So when I come in,
a lot of times my,
what I bring to the situation of what
I can see is I can just ask a question
that none of them could think to ask
because they're all looking in the same
direction. As soon as you flank that
idea, you see it from a different angle.
You come up with a solution.
So,
so what I'm my point in this is don't
only use detachment to prevent your
emotions from driving your decisions.
Also use detachment as part
of your creative process
to detach from your current
thought pattern and move to a new thought
pattern where you can create new ideas
and different plans from different angles
that we're not seen from your previous
vantage point.
Good. I guess we did get a little bit
out of that to dance meant there. Yeah.
Revisit revisitation
next question.
How to deal with people who use military
vets status to excuse bad behavior in
civilian world.
Yeah.
This is an unfortunate one to have
to answer and it unfortunately,
I have to start it off with the same
way I made this point about Jujitsu and
Jujitsu practice practitioners not
necessarily being good people. Oh yeah.
Unfortunately it's the
same thing with veterans.
Just like it's the same thing
in every aspect of life.
Just because someone is a veteran does
not mean that they are a good person and
being at war is certainly not
an excuse for bad behavior.
And I,
couple of examples,
couple of examples just
to think about major,
Major Kurt Chu evenly.
You remember this guy,
navy cross. This is the guy that
wore the pink at at in John's,
so his men could identify him. The
enemy, you can identify him clearly too,
but he was the leader.
He saw hell right.
Wounded men died. 27 of his men
made it. I mean, just ridiculous.
Guess what he did when he,
when he got out of the Marine Corps,
went to work for an insurance
company for 20 years. Right?
So Joe Owen, Joe Owen, who,
you know, same, same
chosen reservoir battle,
never regain the use of the,
of his arm that was wounded,
was medically retired
from the marine corps.
Guess what he did with all
that [inaudible] horror.
Guess what he did? Yeah.
He created and ran his own
marketing business until I retired.
Hmm.
Now you remember John
Chafee from that book,
the coldest war.
He was the captain that I kind of wanted.
The reason I did that book was cause he
was profiled in there and he just was a
great leader. Well, I, I
don't even know if I were,
I don't remember if I talked about this,
but he turned 20 years old at
the bottle of Guadalcanal, right?
World War II. He fought at [inaudible]
World War II. Then he went to,
went back and went to school with,
I went to either Yale or Harvard or both,
but then Korea kicked off. So then
went to Korea and got after it more.
So all of this war, what did he do
with all that? And came home, you know,
became the mayor of Providence there
and Rhode Island became the governor of
Rhode Island and they became
secretary of the navy. But so
my point in saying these things
is veterans are not broken humans.
They're not deranged people.
They're just people.
And they've seen some stuff in,
most of them are Gary on and do awesome.
The greatest generation,
they get a good, great generation
holds a World War II vets.
They saw horrors of war. Guess what
they did? Came home and dominated.
That's what they did.
So men and women can overcome
the impact of war or,
or at least they can learn to work with
it. Because even if you, you know, you,
even if you have those things
that stress you out, okay,
but guys learn how to deal with it.
Of course that being said,
war,
it does leave a mark and obviously
sometimes it can have a extremely negative
effect.
So if you know someone like that,
well let's get those veterans some help
if they need it in and get them some
support. Also make sure you're
not enabling this bad behavior.
This is what you don't want to do.
You don't want it.
You don't want to enable
this bad behavior. The vets
that I meet, they're there,
they're fired up,
they're not,
they're not complaining about
anything they're getting after it.
Don't enable the bad behavior.
It doesn't help anyone.
And it's one of those things that it,
it might make you feel better.
It might make me feel better to, to
help someone out and say, Hey, no,
I understand cause you know,
here's,
let me enable your binge
eating behavior some more.
And it might make me feel better cause
I feel like I've done a good deed.
But you haven't done a good deed.
You've actually not helped them at all.
That's one thing.
I think that's good if you find other
vets for them to talk to because other
vets will say, man, I
understand bro. It's okay,
but let's not dwell on that past stuff.
Let's move forward.
This guy's offering you
a job or this guy has a,
a job for you to do or this guy has
a position you can feel do that.
Do that. Don't dwell on the past.
The past is gone. Wars. Hell,
I know now let's live in the heaven we
got here in the United States of America.
Let's, let's take advantage of
that and not dwell on the past.
You know what this is.
This is another small thing,
but I just hear so much
about it. Um, from people.
If you got somebody having
listen to the podcast,
to this podcast a year from a vet,
every single day I hear from vets
around America that are like,
hey man, thanks. Thanks for having the
podcast. Thanks for what you talk about.
I get it, Bree. She ate it. Okay.
I just, you guys just, you know,
sent me a message today. He's like, look
man, I didn't have a gun in my mouth,
but he goes, I wasn't doing good. I'm on
track. I'm trained in Jujitsu. Literally,
I'm trying to Jujitsu, I'm in the
gym. I'm busting my ass and my job.
Appreciate it. That's all
it is. That's all it is.
Cause I think when people
listen, when vets listen, the
podcast, they go, okay, cool.
There's other people, they know
we're, we're in the game together.
They feel that they feel that connection
and they know that they're not alone
because that's the thing that's
jacked up. Man. Veterans that get,
they go to war and they come back and
they go somewhere there where they're just
not, there's no one there. Yeah. And
all this is, is a big bullshit session.
You know what I mean? Between, you know,
a veteran that's in a book and I'm
having a bullshit vet, a session with,
with Joe Ellen, you know, that's what
it is. And so I think guys, veterans,
they hear that and they go,
yeah man, I appreciate it.
So have them listen to the podcast and,
and that might be helpful to get them
feeling like they're not alone out there.
Yeah, I would think that that's the
main thing. Like people don't like,
you don't understand me, you
know, you don't understand like,
I mean,
not to sound too self,
but like you don't understand how I feel
about this. And even day to day stuff,
like the way I'm seeing this right now,
you don't understand. Yeah. So yeah,
you ended up feeling like,
I'm assuming that's what it seems like
you guys ended up feeling alone and
they're out there and they're like,
and the other thing is they feel
like people don't understand me.
I'm here saying, you're right. They
don't, they haven't been to war. And the,
the experience of war is all over
the place. I mean, I wouldn't even,
I wouldn't even, I would shine, you know,
I would shine major Kurt Chu inlays boots
every day for the rest of my life if I
had the opportunity to, like that guy has
expired. I mean, just, I, I'm not gonna,
I'm not even the same ballpark. You know
what I mean? Not even the same clothes,
not clothes for what those
guys went through it,
that shows reservoir and it goes
all the way down to some guy that,
you know was overseas
that was in the military,
didn't even deploy to Iraq or Afghanistan.
Not Their fault.
They might've wanted to, but sometimes
he just doesn't happen. Yeah. So the,
the military experiences,
all those things and you don't
know what you're dealing with.
But one thing we do know is that it
is a common experience, you know,
going to war.
It does have some common threads to it.
And I think that it is hard for people
that haven't experienced it to understand,
and it makes people feel a
little bit like alone out there.
So when they hear other vets talking
about what goes on, they go, yeah man,
all right,
cool.
These are not abnormal feelings that
I'm having and they can move on.
And I don't know if I've really
answered the question of,
of how to deal with people who use their
status as an excuse to bad behavior.
I think just like any, anyone else, man,
you gotta you gotta do your
best to put them in their place.
And I think what makes non veterans
feel intimidated. And when I was a kid,
I looked up to all the Vietnam
veterans and I just thought these guys,
whatever they, they could do
no wrong in my eyes. You know,
when I was a kid it's not,
that guy's awesome that goes
and I was a non, you know,
that guy could do no wrong.
And I think that's a feeling
that a lot of civilians have.
Like they don't want to approach the
subject. And if you feel that way,
it's understandable. It's hard. But
find some vets around that can help you,
that can, it can help that person that
can talk to them about what they're doing.
I mean, you know, every
company that I work with,
there's veterans in every company.
I work with some, you know,
usually have multiple veterans,
so find some other vendors.
A lot of the one thing that's another
cool thing that the companies do is within
their company they'll have like a veteran
program or a veteran club basically
inside their company. That's another cool
thing. Do that, get that thing started.
You know,
even if you're not a vet,
find the senior vet or the
vet that's fired up to do it.
Bring him in and then those
guys can get together,
talk and talk about doing better and talk
about bringing some of their military
experience to bear in the company
and it just will turn out good.
So there's little veterans organizations,
that's what they call them.
Veterans organizations inside
of companies are pretty cool.
I've spoken to a few of them.
It's a pretty cool deal.
All right, next question.
How does default aggressive
apply to Jujitsu?
Or does it apply to judge
it? Well, good question now.
Well,
first of all,
it doesn't apply during training.
Okay.
It,
but it completely applies
during competition and
obviously it applies in the
streets.
So,
so this is what I mean by
that is in training it's
okay to get in bad positions.
It's okay to let things happen.
It's okay let somebody grabbed that
color or grab that sleeve or get across
sites. Okay. I mean those, it's okay to
put yourself at risk in competitions.
That's okay. Matter of fact, it's,
it's encouraged in a lot of
weight training and training.
It's encouraged in training,
but in competition you
can't do that. You, you can,
you can not do that in street.
You definitely cannot do that.
And in fact, in the street,
you've got to proactively and
aggressively, first of all,
avoid the bad situation.
But if they come,
then you've got to handle those
situations with aggression and speed and
violence of action.
That's what you gotta do.
So competition is kind of
the same way in competition.
If you give a guy an inch, if you give a
guy a grip, if you give a guy a position,
they will not, they will not let go
of it. It's not happening. They will.
They will hang on to that thing like,
like would the ghee in competition,
somebody gets a grip on some part of
your di they white knuckle that thing.
Especially especially in the lower belts.
What he, it's the higher belts too, man.
It's every belt because that,
gee,
that grip can be the difference
between winning and losing period.
So you, you got to, you got
to aggressively avoid that.
You've got to be aggressive with your
positions. Now in training, again,
you let it happen. But here's
something that can happen in training.
Sometimes you get guys that get used to
training and they go into competition.
I get overrun. They get overwhelmed
and overrun because they thought, man,
I'll just, oh, the guy grabs my color,
they Jocko grabs my color all
every time we roll. Right?
And they don't realize that when this guy
grabs your color, he's going to attack.
And so what you have to do and the
other thing is in, in a competition,
there's a time limit because there
is, there is kind of a, a uh,
there's such a thing sort of as a counter
puncher in Jujitsu, right? Someone that,
and I'm kind of like
that, right? Like I don't,
I don't usually force a move to happen.
Usually I'm going to let
you make your own mistakes.
I'm going to let my opponent make a bad
move and then I'm going to capitalize on
it. He uses a lot less work
for me. I mean it's, it's,
it's a lot less work when
your opponent gives you,
gives you the submission or gives you the
transition or gives you the sweep then
trying to make it happen.
But again,
in competition
it doesn't really work because
they're not going to give,
they're not going to take any risk.
They're not going to take any risk and
there's probably not going to be any
openings. Now again, another piece of
this long match. Maybe my, you know,
maybe I'm just trying to hire
somebody out now in the gym.
I have an unlimited time to do that.
I can somebody out for 20 minutes,
just try to let them pass my guard and
they're trying to pass my guard the whole
time I'm getting,
I'm tired of getting them tired,
getting them trying to find the, they
expose himself. Boom. I put the choke on.
Good. I win. That took 20 minutes.
This happens on a daily
basis in a competition.
I just lost because it was a 10 minute
match and the other guy was on top for 10
minutes trying to pass and he got the
advantage and he wins. So you can't,
that can't be your strategy
if there's no time limit.
It's the same thing in war, right?
In war. You can have a strategy of,
I'm just going to where the other
personnel, I mean the, the, the Va, uh,
Vietnamese data to America, right.
They just kind of wore us out.
Look at what the Russian strategy
of that they used against Napoleon.
They used against the Nazis. Oh,
you want to come out of school,
we're just going to back up a little bit
at a time, back up, a little bit of time,
backup a little bit time.
Here comes the winter in and now you're
going to freeze to death and we're going
to surround junior and kill you.
But that's the same type of strategy.
It doesn't work if you, if you have
a limited amount of time to win,
you have to have, if you, if you
have a limited amount of time,
which most cases you do, you have to
have a default aggressive attitude in.
Make things happen the way
you want them to happen,
not the way your opponent wants to happen,
to have them happen,
not the way your enemy
wants them to happen.
And it's the same thing obviously
in business and in life,
the good things, the good
positions, the good details,
the good promotions,
the rewards,
they're not going to come
and knock on your door.
You got to go out and
you got to take them.
You got to make them happen on the mat,
in business and in life.
So get default aggressive.
So my recommendation. Yeah,
it's weird and Jujitsu is still ambiguous
as far as like a like an art and
there's like this big spectrum
and there's all these exceptions.
You know how you see the
counter puncher and you did too,
where like some guys even like making,
you can be a counter puncher in Jujitsu
and still be like aggressive bite.
So your first move won't be like,
okay, if you're going for a sleep,
your first move won't be
to sweep. You'll go, okay,
I'm going to do this other thing.
I know his reaction is going to open
him up for the sweep. Well for sure,
for sure. That's, that's, that's covered
move. Actually it's covering move.
It's flanking flanking violas.
Yeah,
because you know I start attacking your
neck and you pull your hand up to defend
it. Boom. That took your base away. I'm
sweeping you. Right, right. Boom. That's,
that's what it was.
It was a cover move covering my
actual attack with my other move.
Or you can call it a flank because you
think I'm going to come at the front,
but then I'm flanking you from
the side with the sweep. Yeah.
When you put all your chips on
the front, you know? Yeah. It's,
it's almost like that's
like a philosophical
question where you can answer it as
it applies to something specific.
So like for example, like default
aggressive in Jujitsu, meaning
my default aggressive way of approaching
it will give me advantage in this way
where I'm going to impose my game or
whether that's the counter punching game,
whether it's the wear him out for a
while game, whether it's, you know,
overrunning with my conditioning,
whatever that game is,
I'm going to aggressively put it on
him before he puts it on me. Default.
Like right from the time
the guy says go or you know,
when it goes down the street,
whenever, even in training,
whatever you're training
like that if you want.
So that'll keep him in the defensive
where he can't get his game going on you,
you know, he's defending your game
the whole time. Yeah. You definitely,
definitely want to impose your will
and say that all the time with the UFC
fighters.
You,
the UFC fighter that imposes his well
on the other fighters are going to win.
Yeah. They're going to win. And
it's the same thing with war.
You impose your will on the enemy.
That's what you do.
You impose your will on the enemy
and you'll break them. Yeah man.
That's why you see guys like in USC,
they'll don't front of the
middle of the ring, you know,
cause they're like controlling during
or like a Bj Penn would all be,
if he's coaching somebody, he'd be like,
be first be first before you put them.
So the guy got to defend the whole time.
And when you,
when you're going against the striker,
that ad has that attitude and
is being first. Oh it's not fun.
They're hitting you and you're not. You're
just defending the whole time. Yeah.
And it's hard to turn
it around. Yeah. Yeah.
Then you can tell like when
you roll against the guy,
and we talked about this before,
when you roll against the guy and
even if he's not like his game isn't
aggressive,
but right when you lock up with them,
you can tell he's like just in the
correct position. You're like, Dang,
I can't get like a good like,
and when you you're like, okay,
I'm going to get in my position.
And he just adjust like immediately you're
in trouble. Yeah. You're like, Oh Dang.
That's in a way,
even though that might be like kind of
like a passive game sometimes it's like
just his game being put on you.
Position-Wise in this case is that default
decree as opposed to like, you know,
like you know sometimes like in training
you're training with me and he'd be
like, okay, I'm going to, it's
essentially letting someone get in an,
into a good position on you. So you're
training your defense or whatever.
That's different. That's like,
that's not default aggressive there.
You're talking about.
I'm really good from the half guard,
so I let you get past my full guard to
the half guard and now you're in my world.
Like something like that.
Yeah, that would be, I guess,
would that be the default?
It's like stilts.
Stilts has this weird game because he's
tall and lanky and and flexible and so
he does things like he'll stick his foot
in a place where any normal situation
in Jujitsu you'd grab his foot
all day long. Yeah. That's
what he wants you to do.
Yeah.
And I was just telling him the other day,
I said to all these little
things that you want me to do,
I'm not doing any of them.
Yeah. Pretty Great. And if you
just stopped doing them and so we eat,
the way he imposes his will
is by giving up these bait.
He just throws bait out there all day
long and he wants you to get you into
these positions that he's good at.
Yeah. And so you can't take the bait,
you can't take the bait.
And sometimes the bait is ripe looking.
It's like ripe for the harvest.
And it's everywhere and it's everywhere.
And so you got to just say, no, I'm
going to stick to the game plan here.
I'm going to impose my will, which is,
I'm not going to grab the bait. Yeah,
and that's so crazy because like I said,
kind of philosophically that is the
default aggressive thing when all you're
throwing out is absolutely.
So instead of imposing my game,
I'm like kind of lured by this bait.
Even if you know the bait is there,
you're on your heels because
you're watching out for the track.
Well this is just to kind of,
I think down in the same vein that
you're talking about. I talk about,
I talk about safety, like I'll talk
to companies about safety, you know,
industrial companies or
construction companies,
manufacturing companies that have,
you know,
can have people get killed
if they're not careful.
And so I talk about being
aggressive and you know, it's okay,
well then Jocko, how does default
aggressive going to keep us safe?
Because if I've got guys that are out
in the construction site being super
aggressive all day, guess what? They're
going to take risks that they shouldn't.
And I said absolutely wrong because
guess what you're going to get aggressive
with. You're going to aggressively
implement your safety procedures.
You're going to aggressively
like, Hey, you know what?
I see a guy walking around the job site
without a helmet. We're all over him. Hey,
Jack Ass, put your helmet on.
Get over here. I'm writing you.
I'm to whatever you're going
to do. Right, right. Oh,
I see a guy without a seatbelt.
Hey,
you're not allowed to be on the site
without a, without a seat belt on.
Get over here. You got to, you
know, we're docking your pay.
You're going to get aggressive in the
implementation of your safety procedures
and yes, that will make you safer.
Yeah. So it's, yeah, I guess, um,
when you hear the word
aggressive, oh, automatically.
I'll give you another example.
I'll give you another physical example.
Another physical example is, okay,
we're in a defensive perimeter.
I don't have enough men to move,
or I've got wounded guys.
I am going to aggressively
set security, right? Right.
I'm going to put a big
machine gun over here.
I'm going to get that high ground over
there so you can do things aggressively,
even though by their nature they might
not seem aggressive at first. Yeah.
I think that's what you're trying to
say. Yeah. Yeah, fully. So it's, it, it,
it's almost like it's deeper.
It's deeper than just like physically
just jumping in. It's more like the,
the idea of whatever's going on.
Here's another one.
I am going to aggressively,
okay,
ignore.
You know,
I'm going to aggressively
counsel you and mentor you.
Now, the worst thing I could do is
go echo. You better. Listen to me.
That's the worst thing I could do.
But to be aggressive in doing that,
what am I going to do? I'm going to set
really good goals. I'm going to flank you.
I'm going to get into your mind.
I'm doing, I'm being aggressive,
but not an external aggression is an
internal question that only I know is
happening.
You're going to know what's happening in
a year when you've all sudden improved
and you've been successful
and you go, Dang, man.
Jack was really helped
me out with some stuff.
I didn't really realize that
was going on, but he did. Yeah.
I was aggressively doing it.
But you would have never
called it aggressive from
an external viewpoint. Yeah,
so it's as opposed to, let's say like
some sort of a laid back approach. Right?
Like if, if you have a laid
back approach to security,
if you have a laid back
approach to mentorship or
laid back approach to safety.
Yes.
None of those things are good.
That's why we have a default aggressive
attitude about things. There you go.
We clarified it after it.
I Dunno though.
One could say that.
Back to the question.
One could say that having a
laid back attitude in Jujitsu,
then again on the street, that'd be
less likely to have a laid back. Yeah.
Did you just in the street, there's
exceptions everywhere I would think,
but let's see. You know, if it's going
down, it's going down default aggressive,
but aggressive in the street. Yeah.
Right now. Yeah. Once it goes,
once it happens. Once the
decision has been made, yeah,
get after it, it's go time.
It's not good to avoid it as long
as you can avoid as long as you can,
but when you got to go,
go hard go. God Dang.
I think we're at our last question,
my friend.
Cool.
Jocko,
does complacency come with age?
I see a lot of guys that
back off as they get older.
Do you have the urge to back off?
Does is a complacency come with age
and do I have the urge to back off?
Negative. Negative. Back off.
Not Happening.
I hear that.
I'm over 40. I'm pushing 50, whatever.
Bring it back off.
Negative not happening.
In fact,
I'm stepping it up.
Um, training harder. Eating cleaner.
Okay.
I'm training more.
I'm learning and reading and studying
more now than I ever have in my whole
life. Do I get dinged up? Of course I do.
Yeah.
They're,
it takes them some injuries.
Yeah.
You know what?
No factor. No factor. Deal with them.
But you do you know what?
You know what I hear?
I hear the clock ticking.
That's what I hear.
And the end is nigh and
time waits for no man.
Okay.
And you young guns out
there, 18 old, 20 years old,
24 years old.
Listen,
life goes by and it goes by quick.
Don't waste those years.
Don't waste them. Live them.
Now I know
I,
I know that you don't think you're going
to live to be 30 much less 40 but you
are and you will.
Okay.
In the earlier you get in
the game and get on track,
the better life you're going
to have. Healthier, wealthier,
stronger, smarter, better,
better.
Eight.
If you're an old man like me and
you haven't gotten on track yet,
get on track. Get on it. Now
everyone,
everyone listening to this,
okay,
here's the deal.
No complacency.
Yeah,
no complacency,
no backing off,
no slack whatsoever.
Fight,
fight that ticking clock
with everything you got.
So like the end of a hard day,
you can put your head down with ease,
satisfied
that you've given your best.
Okay,
and I think that's
all I've got for tonight.
Now Echo,
if anyone wants to get in the
game as far as this podcast goes,
what's the best way for them to do that?
Well as far as this podcast
goes and as far as they go.
Hmm.
I don't know if I'd call it help.
I'd call it supplemental additions to
your life supplements on it.com/jocko you
get 10% off
for real supplements.
Then I said this before,
but I think we should say it again.
That sometimes when you buy something
tells me you're Gunna say, yeah,
I'm going to say it again cause I don't,
I don't think you're going to talk
about chalk. Yeah, I'm good. I'm okay.
Cause sometimes I don't
know how it is now.
I've been out of the
supplement game for a while.
It's as far as taking protein powders
as far as the bad supplements.
Yeah. Or just, we'll just say the general
mix of supplements,
you know,
power gainer 5,000 or whatever recovery,
uh,
you know, x, y, Z, whatever. Sometimes
it can just be nonsense in there,
but on it, you know, going in, I
think we all know that it's the,
it's the legit one.
The only legit one that
I know of for sure.
The one that I know guaranteed is legit.
Put it that way, that I do anyway. Um,
I would recommend Krill oil.
100% Krill oils. Real. Yeah.
It's for your joints.
I take
three 500 milligram Krill oil in
the morning at three in the evening.
All Dang six. Yes. Dang.
Okay. What I do, I take a day.
Okay,
that's fine.
My daughter list them up to the sun and
she thinks it's like a red jelly bean.
Oh, it doesn't taste like or don't eat
it. Don't chew it and swallow. Yes.
Little things. Anyway, that's a Krill
oil. Uh, though the warrior bars,
that's a big deal I think.
Oh,
is there like a,
they're the opposite of a donut in
every way except for taste. Yeah.
The gluten free too, by the
way. Yeah. They teach well.
They taste different than a donut,
but just as good, if not better,
my opinion better. Eight,
three of them all at once.
I just called it a meal. My meal.
Do you stack reading individually?
Individually, but anyway. Um,
and also shroom tech soap. A lot of people
eat, you know how people, they'll say,
hey, a lot of people been asking
me when, you know, like Bro,
a lot of people haven't been asking me,
you're just making,
like a lot of people are asking. I'm not
saying anyone that says that does that,
but I'm just saying sometimes
you think butter's for real.
A lot of people have been asking me
is shroom tech real issue in tech row.
I hear good things. All this stuff. Okay.
Shroom tech, Israel, shroom tech sport.
I haven't tried shroom tech immune
be, I haven't tried it either. Yeah,
because I'm more in the sport mode. Right,
right. It usually sport not sick. Oh,
oh. But you can just have it because you
just want your general immunity to be
solid. That's like a good
solid thing. Nonetheless.
Shroom tech sport is real and
I made this analogy again.
I think it's worth saying again or before.
So again,
I think you're going to say
it again regardless if we
think it's worth it or not.
Yes. So let's just so like, okay,
this is how it works in Layman's terms.
You know when you're driving
a car and it's about to read,
little needle's going to go into red.
You'd like revving at 100 rpm spoon,
boom, you're going to be in the
green. I'm going to get to the yellow.
Even the orange, when you get,
when you hit the red, you can't,
you can't pull the head.
Can't pull ahead if you're in the red,
so what the shroom tech does? He take
the shroom tech, boom, you're going,
you're in the green.
You're going to hit the yellow little
bit a little bit later than normal.
You're going to hit the
orange maybe and you,
the shroom tech is just going
to keep you in the orange,
going to keep the needle in the orange,
maybe even in the yellow,
and you're going to notice that,
okay? That's how it works. Anyway,
get 10% offers to go on [inaudible]
dot com slash Jocko there you go.
Boom. Support Yourself. Support
your wallet, support the
Podcast, you Baja. Good way.
Also, if you shop at
Amazon, which we all do,
okay.
Christmas has probably gone at this point,
but we still need normal stuff.
Duct tape,
what
pens? Pins, cables,
right from your TV or whatever. Anyway,
when you, before you shop on Amazon a,
you click through our website, which is
Jocko, podcast.com on the side there.
There's a little Amazon banner. You
Click there, boom. Do your shopping.
You can support that way.
I use the analogy of the little sodium
piece that when you throw it in the water,
it makes this big explosion
situation. That's kind of the, the,
the comparison as far as supporting this
podcast because when you click through
the Amazon banner, it's like
such a small thing. It's so easy.
It doesn't cost you nothing, but then
the support that it brings is like a lot,
you know? Yeah. I'm telling you,
we're good. We appreciate, yes.
Small gesture of,
of support to the podcast.
The small gesture goes a long way.
When you team it up with
a bunch of other people,
the death of a thousand cuts
will kill someone, you know.
But the life of a thousand clicks is
what we're do just to just the small
cliques is echos looking at
me like I said something bad.
No, no. Good. Oh, it is the
life of a thousand clicks.
The life of a thousand clicks.
Yeah. Click on that
thing. Just, yeah. Yep.
You're going to get some duct tape
might not seem like a big deal,
but if a bunch of people, we've got
duct tape and they all click through,
maybe it turns into a big deal.
Yeah.
Then we don't have to put advertisements
on here. Yeah. Which we don't want to do.
Yeah. Or we could, maybe we will. Jack
would be reading it. I don't think so.
Yeah.
I don't think it's happening because we
got support from speaking to duck tails.
Um, remember the Penn state duct
tape? Yeah, sure. Sarah. Two blades.
Yeah. Sorry. I need some more tough team.
Um, anyway. Yeah. Back to the Ama.
Amazon. Yeah. So go to the website,
click through the Amazon
before you do the shopping.
That's a good way to support.
Good way. Thank you guys for that.
I'm also subscribed to
the podcast on iTunes
or on Google play or on stitcher.
You're on.
What's the other ones? Those are the
big ones. Yeah. Other stuff. Yeah.
What other
things you might need? You know, whichever
one it's on, man. Um, that seems obvious,
but that's a cool way to support. And
then the youtube as well. You know,
we'll put some excerpts on there. More
excerpts. That's the right word, right?
Excerpts.
Yeah.
A little bite size nuggets.
Jocko wisdom that if you
are inclined to share,
you can share and kind of be ensured that
there the likelihood of them listening
to the whole thing is higher than if you
just share that. So the podcast. Yeah.
Because if you're like, Hey,
uh, you know, here's the,
here's the good way to approach college
and you want to share this with your
friend because they got a son that's
going to college or you're sharing it with
the frank because
they're going to college,
they're going to listen to that way more
likely then listening to two hours of
that episode. There's a long time. Yeah.
Cause maybe they're going to
college like that day or something.
You know what I mean? Or they could just
listen to it while they're in college,
whichever, but anyway, they're just
more consumable we'd say. Yes. Yeah.
Bite size, bite size, like a
mcnugget Jocko McKnight's. Yep.
Exactly. So anyway, the point there
is youtube, that's a cool way to,
to support and whatnot. Um,
anyway, the, and there's a store,
Jocko has a store,
it's called Jocko store and there's
tee shirts and whatnot on there.
They're, they're cool
shirts, I think. So I don't,
I'm not like one of those
people where they're like,
they're cool tee shirts because that's a
subjective thing. So I would encourage,
invite
people to go to Jocko store.com
look at the t shirt. That's it.
That's all. That's all. Look at
them. If you want to buy one,
if you notice the layers,
if the layers resonate,
I thought you gave up on the layers.
Now you're back in the day.
We're still doing layers.
Yeah, we're still doing it.
If they resonate with you and
you're compelled to get a shirt,
support the podcast. Represent the
layers in your part of the world.
If you're a cadet at west point,
if you're a guy with a truck
with a bumper sticker on it,
no matter who you are, if you choose to
want to represent, do all that, get it.
Get a shirt, get a sticker, get
a patch, a Hoodie, a Hoodie,
get a rash guard. If you're, you know,
if you don't have a rash guard and you're
doing Jujitsu or cycling or running,
crossfit,
anything with like a lot of activity,
get a rash guard if you haven't
already, if you want. Anyway,
there is also psychological warfare.
We went through really the, the, the
what? The beginnings or the [inaudible],
not the purpose, what do you
call it? The to formation.
The formation, the story, the
story behind it. Last time.
Basically it's Jockos version of
those days where you kind of got it.
This is my words in my own words.
Jockos version of the, you know,
those days where you got to talk yourself
into doing the workout or not eating,
you know,
a whole thing of Oreos or whatever.
And you got to talk yourself into
Oreo. Yeah. Not the whole thing.
Yeah. The moments of weakness. Yeah.
When you got to talk yourself into it or
out of something, you know, like Amen.
Hey, do you have to do this?
Workout? Doesn't sound like that,
but that's essentially, you know
what it is anyways. Jockos Virgin,
you go on Itunes,
you purchase either a track nine,
9 cents or the album like nine
bucks, I think. Something like that.
I think it's actually nine 99.
Yeah.
And there's a wake up one
you can put on your, um,
your alarm clock on your
phone to wake you up,
clear it with your wife or whoever
you sleep with. Go over it,
go over the whole plan, like a drill,
like Kinda like a fire drill. Really.
Because I'm telling you if the few here
that even if you forgot that you put it
on your phone and you hear that Bro,
I'm going to have some explaining to do
the feedback has been really good. Yeah.
People that have had trouble waking up,
they don't have trouble waking
up in the morning. You know,
people that have trouble when they,
when it's snack time,
people that have trouble that they can't,
they can't say no to the donut.
You get it,
get this,
get the psychological warfare
attack going on against the donuts.
The psychological warfare will
win. Yes. Every single time. Yup.
And if you're having a hard time,
if you're having a hard time figuring
out which day is workout day in rest day,
you know when you, you're tricking help
configure that out. Yes, exactly right.
Exactly right. Yes. That's a
good, good point. Rest Day.
It isn't today.
Yeah.
The way if you're in or
if you're switching your
workout day to the rest day,
like if you're doing those, which I used
to do, this will help that for sure.
All I can all say that right now in
public with 100% certainty that at that
it'll solve that problem.
Sweet.
Also Jocko white tea,
it is available.
It's in stock.
It will 100% increase your dead lift
by 500%.
Uh, no Jocko White Tea, pomegranate,
they will make you dead
lift a lot more weights. Um,
and that is 100% proven
in all scientific manners.
No, just kidding. It tastes good
and it will make you better.
You can drink it from a get after it Mug
AMUG that will tell you exactly what to
do in the morning and
that is get after it.
And if you like what we talked about
on the podcast while you're on Amazon,
after you clicked through
the Jocko podcast website,
then you get there and you can pick
up a copy of a book called extreme
ownership. You might like it if
you liked the podcast. Talk about,
talk about leadership and talk about war.
Two of my favorite things also,
once again,
extreme ownership muster zero zero to
May 4th and fifth at the Marriott Marquis
in New York City. Come
to it. You will dig it.
The first one we had, people had
no idea what we were going to do.
They had no idea. We didn't even
put up a barely put up an agenda.
People came anyways, we
delivered, we had an awesome time.
The testimonials are cool.
So you can know what you took,
you can look forward this time Warner,
it's not so such a mystery.
You can know what you're
going to get out of.
It echoes making some videos question
well is that you're talking about the
schedule like this one you'll have like
a schedule, we'll have a little bit more,
but just people didn't,
people just wondered what we were going
to be doing there. Right. And you know we,
they kind of just took it in faith that
we're going to have that they knew one
thing that we were going to do there
and that was get after it and we did.
And so you know we're going
to do it again. Like I said,
I think I said this last time echoes
making videos in once the video has come
out and kind of show what's going on,
it's gonna sell out it cause the footage
from the first one is awesome and it's
going to sell out quickly. So get in,
get there now and get your
tickets now so that you can come.
You can hang out with a bunch of leaders,
CEO's from mid level
managers, vps, the vps,
owners,
presidents.
It's just everybody and
everybody that's in the game.
Of course Lafe and I are going to be
there. We'll be right in the mix with you.
EC will be there. Jp is going to
be there getting after it with us.
Deep discounted tickets if you're
law enforcement, firefighters,
of course military,
if you have questions about that
or if you have like a corporate,
you're going to bring 10 people, 12
people, 20 people from your company,
that's fine.
We can get you a discount as well.
Contact the email muster@echelonfront.com
or you can just go to the website,
extreme ownership.com.
Look forward to seeing you there.
And furthermore,
if you like hanging around with us here
on the podcast and you want to keep
hanging around with us a little bit,
you're in luck because we are
hanging around on the interwebs,
on Twitter and on Instagram.
And if you're going to be inside,
that's Facebook [inaudible] you going
to be there with you, my friend.
So Echo is at Echo Charles
and I am at Jocko Willink.
And finally thank you for
all the questions and the
feedback and the downloads
and the support to the military personnel.
Stay on your game and be
aggressive to the vets.
Thank you for your service to
the police and firefighters.
Thank you guys and girls for
keeping us safe on the home front.
Yeah.
End of the rest of you.
Fighters, grinders,
troopers, leaders. Keep pushing,
keep grinding,
let there be no complacency
and let there be no slack.
Let their only be
getting after it.
So until next time,
this is echo and Jocko
out.