In regards to subordinate leadership.
How do you begin to change the culture
slash school of thought of an industry or
a company?
You know,
I'm not sure if they mean in regards
to how do you change your subordinate
leaderships or if you are subordinate.
I'm not sure what,
which one of those it is,
but regardless,
doesn't matter because guess what I'm
going to do? I'm going to lead you.
That's what I'm going to do.
Whether I'm on,
whether I'm the subordinate guy or
the superior guy, I'm going to lead,
oh, we're going to, I want to change
things and make them a certain way. Cool.
I'm going to do those things.
I'm going to make those things happen.
That's how you do it and if you're doing
the right things for the right reasons,
your message is going to spread.
Yeah.
You know how many bad sequel
platoons I was in? How many? Zero.
You know why? Because me and my
buddies, we always had a good attitude.
We always had the right attitude and
that spread to the other people that were
with us. [inaudible] now
there's a red flag that
you can get for yourself.
And this is frustration when
you start saying yourself,
which I'm not saying this necessarily,
but this kind of question is coming from
somebody that wants change to happen,
but it's not happening.
So they're getting frustrated and they're
thinking they aren't on board or they
don't care and they aren't professional.
They're not motivated like me,
and they don't have a good attitude.
So there's a lot of blame
going on right there. Yeah.
So this isn't about them though.
It's about you.
And it's about leading from any
level in the chain of command.
If you're leading,
if you're doing the right
things for the right reasons,
that's going to spread. So
when I, the classic example,
I talk about it all the time is if
you're exercising extreme ownership,
if you're saying, you know
what, I got this, it was a
mistake made, it was my fault.
That spreads.
If you're humble,
that spreads.
If you have an open mind that spreads,
if you're being aggressive, not, again,
not aggressive towards other people,
but if you're being aggressive in pursuit
of your goal, that spreads [inaudible].
You know what doesn't spread is when
you're aggressive at people. Oh,
actually it does spread, but it's
negative. You don't want that, you know,
it doesn't spread.
It doesn't spread when you're trying
to get people to do things because it's
gonna make you look good.
Yeah. That doesn't spread.
You can't get people to behave
better because you want to look good.
It doesn't work. Yeah. People
see right through that. Oh,
he wants to look good. You know
what? I'm gonna do sabotage.
Now,
the other thing I've been seeing lately,
because people are surprised or whatever,
or not surprised,
but they're concerned,
they don't see how it's going to work
so fast. And I say, you know what?
It's not gonna work fast. It's
gotta be, and here's the word.
It's got to be a campaign.
It's gotta be a campaign.
It's not like World War
II was not one battle.
World War One was not one battle.
It's a campaign to win in Europe.
It's a campaign to win in the Pacific.
They takes battle after battle
after battle. And guess what?
You don't win them all. Yeah. You lose
some of them. And so you're going to,
on this campaign, you're going
to win and you're going to lose.
But you got to have the persistence and
the patience and the persuasiveness to
continue [inaudible]
and another piece of this is, okay, cute.
You are best off if you go
indirect and not be like,
Hey, you need to act like me. No,
people don't like that.
[inaudible] you need to
just act how you're acting.
And if you're doing it though,
like I said,
the right things for the right reasons,
people are going to see you and
they're going to follow. Mm.
So that's how you begin to
change the school of thought.
Yeah.
That genuineness like tends to show
itself or that like if you're not genuine,
it tends to show itself,
you know,
just because of the dynamics
of Vinny mind tends to,
it just straight shows itself.
So when you're doing it for
the right reasons like you,
you can't help but expose that, you
know, that will be explicitly, yeah,
people will sign up, sign right
on, and then you end up gaining,
like how you say it's a campaign. It's
like you'll gain a little bit of ground.
You might win this guy over,
like, hey wait, that's, you know,
that's a cool way of doing it,
or whatever the group is.
And you make these small little steps
and you kind of hold that ground and yet
before you know it, it's Kinda of, Dang,
the whole culture of this, I don't know,
office or whatever.
It's Kinda changing you.
It just happens.