This is Jocko podcast number
78 with Echo Charles and me,
Jocko Willink. Good
Evening Echo. Good evening.
Nightmare.
Now that's a word that I use oftentimes
to describe the most horrible things in
a most wretched things.
And in my hierarchy of adjectives,
nightmare is right alongside of hell.
Okay?
And I'm not sure which
one is worse in my mind.
That's why I say they're right alongside
each other because hell is beyond the
worst thing your mind can imagine.
And that's basically what a nightmare is
when you're asleep and your mind delves
into the most horrific things beyond
what you can consciously and willfully
imagine in your own head.
That's what a nightmare is.
Now, what if there was a place
that was worse than a nightmare?
Yeah,
and it was a real place.
Who could create
such a place?
And the answer to that is we can,
I shall never forget how I was roused
one night by the groans of a fellow
prisoner who threw
himself about his sleep.
Obviously having a horrible nightmare
since I had always been,
especially sorry for people who
suffer from fearful dreams or Deliria.
I wanted to wake the poor man.
Suddenly I drew back the hand,
which was ready to shake him,
frightened at the thing I was about to do.
At that moment,
I became intensely,
intensely conscious of
the fact that no dream,
no matter how horrible,
could be as bad as the
reality of the camp,
which surrounded us and to
which I was about to recall him.
And that's a quote from the book man's
search for meaning by Viktor Frankl,
which will be
peering into today and it's a book
about the Nazi concentration camps,
which
are really,
as he pointed out there,
worse than any nightmare we can.
Here's a holocaust survivor,
Edie Weinstein on the death
and the atrocities in Treblinka
by now, the transports were coming
every day. One was much like the next,
the same incidents recurred
again and again once.
As I swept out the interior of a car,
an ss man suddenly struck
me with his weapon,
ordered me to help a woman who was
unable to stand and climb out of the car.
The idea was to show his victims how
well the ill we're being treated.
Then he ordered one of the
workers to take the women,
take the woman to have the field,
the field hospital for care.
The newcomers are really believed that
the alien alien woman would be taken to
an infirmary.
None of them realized that the field
hospital was in fact just a giant pit,
about 30 yards in diameter,
which was always a blaze.
They would place those who were sick or
disabled on the ground at the edge of
the pit facing in the ss man and the in
charge circulated among them and shot
them in the back of the neck.
Then the workers cast them into the pit.
Some of the victims were still breathing
when they were tossed in with the other
bodies.
The pit was separated from the spacious
field by a barrier of fresh pine
branches,
which were replaced from time to time
to conceal the infirmary from the
newcomers until the last moment,
20 minutes after I helped the woman
climb out of the railroad car.
I was told that some infants were sitting
by the pit and no one else was there
because the SS soldier
had taken his lunch break.
I gathered some trash and went over there.
I saw the woman who I had removed
from the car, still breathing,
sitting at the edge of the pit and
staring in fright into the burning inferno
and its contents,
the half cremated bodies of old people
and children mixed with smoldering trash.
She tried to stand up,
but her legs would not hold her.
She looked at the workers
who stirred the embers,
remnants of human beings
so they would burn better
nearby were about a dozen infants to
young to have learned how to walk.
They were not crying. They certainly
did not understand what was happening.
They looked about almost certainly in
hopes of finding their mother or Father
Bader. I heard that right after
he returned from his lunch break,
the ss man shot them all in order the
workers to throw the tiny bodies into the
flames.
Of all my memories of
that occur said place.
The vision of these babies
is undoubtedly the worst.
I see their faces whenever
I remember Treblinka.
As I write these lines more
than 50 years after that day,
I still cannot overcome the horror.
Okay.
Eight another report here.
Martin spat of Tar.
Now Poland describes the massacre
of Tarnow Jews in an interview.
Okay.
We heard the columns of Jews
under the German escort at night.
It was going constantly.
Okay.
They were passing our house because
this was already on the outskirts of the
city, the cemetery, and they were marching
them to the woods behind the city.
As we found out later,
they were all shot over there
during the day. I looked out through
the shingles. My father said,
I shouldn't look, but anyway,
I was a kid. I was curious.
And the roof was overlooking the
cemetery and wagons with bodies.
Dead bodies were coming in groups.
They were bringing in groups of Jewish
people that had to dig trenches.
They had to dig ditches
and the body's dumped in.
And after those Jews that dug the ditches,
they were shot also and pushed in by
another group that came in after them into
those ditches and lime was poured over
the bodies and the next group covered up
those ditches and Doug,
other ditches
they brought in.
Okay.
Pregnant women.
And they didn't use any bullets.
They used bayonets,
the screams of the mothers,
that their children,
they tore their children out of their arms
and the screams of the children.
I still here
and Solomon [inaudible],
who is the only survivor
from the 78 people in his family
described the concentration camp.
They throw the people in the crematoriums,
the children,
I will never forget alive.
Yeah,
they throw them in the crematoriums.
They grabbed by an arm,
by a leg by the head and
throw them into the ovens
there.
It was so tragic.
The cries and people when crying there,
you know,
it was so terrible.
I can feel it now.
I can even see the people.
The other people were crying. The children
were hollering, Mama, daddy helped me.
Mama Daddy helped me.
Okay.
It was terrible.
And one more report or
Treblinka from Henry Gold.
And the worst thing that happens
to a person in that instance,
he loses self respect.
And that's exactly what happened
to the majority of the people.
Some of them even lost their minds.
They couldn't take it.
They couldn't take the hunger.
They couldn't take the beatings,
they couldn't take the cold.
No clothing and the uncertainty
and the uncertainty.
I think that was the worst thing that
can happen to a person you didn't know
from one moment to the next
what was going to happen.
Okay.
Life was very cheap. A person was alive
one minute, the next minute he was shot,
killed, beaten up, beaten to death,
torn apart by dogs and so on.
Life was very, very cheap and
that's the way the Germans liked it.
That particular camp was governed by
the Jewish Jewish police and so on.
The Germans did not stay in the camp.
They were on the outside,
but the life inside of the camp was just
as bad without the Germans being right
there.
Then if they would be,
the Jewish police was,
I don't know,
you take a person in that situation
and you give them a little power and he
becomes the same as the oppressor himself.
Okay.
There were some policemen
that were not bad,
but there were a lot of
them that were ruthless.
There were others that would beat people
and do all kinds of things that would
degrade them and so on.
Especially women.
They cut their hair off
and they look like men,
they look like scarecrows and they would
get beaten up by the Jewish police just
as bad as the man for no reason at all.
If they want it a little more soup
where they were distributing soup and
there was some left and they were going to
give everybody a little and the Jewish
police with their sticks and rubber hoses
would beat them half cents senseless
and that's what happens when the
conditions are the way they were.
Then when a person becomes an animal and
loses self respect that is willing to
get a beating and get beaten
half senseless just to
get a little bit of soup.
Either you died
or if you didn't die,
the Germans would come and take you away.
The filth was just terrible. In the
camp, in the barracks you had cots,
I mean bunks where everybody
slept on Straw. There were
no covers was no pillows,
nothing.
You slept in your clothes and the winners
in the winter because you're afraid to
get cold. The only heating
was a pot bellied stove in
the middle of the barrack.
When somebody stole some wood in the
factory or something, then we had a fire.
Otherwise it was freezing
and the only warmth they had if you
huddled together and they kept warm that
way,
but nobody would get undressed.
The lice were eating you up alive once a
month you were allowed to take a shower
and we had to walk to camp a to go to the
showers and that means a 10 mile walk,
10 miles there and 10 miles back.
A lot of people were too weak to walk and
those people hardly ever took a shower.
There was no hot water in the washroom.
It was only cold.
And in the winter you are afraid to wash
up because there was nothing to wipe
yourself with.
Therefore you would walk out in the
cold winter and freeze to death.
Dan Henry Gold brothers and both of
his parents were all killed in the gas
chambers.
Yeah.
And from the boot can Wald report,
which was translated and edited with
an introduction by David a Hackett.
I will now describe the crematoriums
and the transports at the station.
2000 people got off the trains.
They had to throw away all their luggage.
Afterward,
the men and women were divided into two
groups at which the larger boys were
assigned to the group with the men.
Then that great devour of Jews Mengele
drove by in a car seeking out the
strongest from each transport.
They numbered around 30 out of 2000 the
remainder were led away by ss technical
sergeant mole.
Okay.
The officer of the crematorium,
the elderly,
were loaded onto dump trucks and then
dumped into burning trenches while still
alive.
The remainder will lead to
the gas chambers. Meanwhile,
new transports were arriving
in front of the gas
chamber was a dressing room
on its walls,
was written in all languages,
put shoes into the cubby holes and tie
them together so you will not lose them
after the showers,
you will receive hot coffee
here. Poor victims undressed
themselves and when to the chamber,
there were three columns for the
ventilators through which the gas port in
a special work detail with truncheons
drove the people into the chamber.
When the room was full, small children
would thrown in through a window.
Sergeant mole grabbed infants by their
legs and smash their skulls against the
wall.
Then the gas was led into the chamber.
The lungs of the victim slowly burst and
after three minutes allowed clamoring
could be heard.
Then the chamber was open and those who
still showed signs of life were beaten
to death.
The prisoners of the special work
details then pulled corpses out,
took the rings off and cut their hair,
which was gathered up,
put in Saks and shipped to factories.
Then they arranged the
corpses in piles of 10 each
after sergeant mole had counted them,
they were taken to the ovens or if
the crematoriums crematoriums were
insufficient,
thrown into fire trenches.
Once it happened that a victim
crawled out of a burning trench,
he was beaten to death with truncheons.
Once sergeant mole pole put a naked
woman in the trench and shot her in the
genitals.
Another time mole found a ring on a
member of the special work detail.
He ordered nat NAPFA,
poured over him and had it lighted.
He hanged a man by his hands and shot
him until his arms were torn through.
Then he hanged them up by the
feet and repeated the process,
wants sergeant mold,
took a family of six.
First he shot the youngest
in the presence of the rest.
Then he shot the older ones and finally
their father and mother.
Then that's the testimony of John de Weiss
who was 15 years old
at Birkenau.
So I think it's safe to say that
this is a situation that is
definitely worse than a nightmare
and
what possibly can we take away from that?
I think the best thing we can do
is try and learn,
and I think one of the best places to
learn and take lessons away from the
Holocaust is from the book that I started
out with today called man's search for
meaning by Viktor Frankl.
Okay,
let's go to the book.
Let us take the case of a transport which
was officially announced to transfer a
certain number of
prisoners to another camp,
but it was fairly safe to guests that
it's final destination would be the gas
chambers.
A selection of sick or feeble prisoners.
Incapable of work would be sent to one
of the big central camps which were
fitted with gas chambers and crematoriums.
The selection process was the signal for
a free fight among all the prisoners or
of group against group.
All that mattered was that one's own
name and that of one's friends or crossed
off the list of victims. Though
everyone knew that for each man saved,
another victim had to be found.
A definite number of prisoners
had to go with each transport.
It did not really matter which since
each of them was nothing but a number
on their admission to the camp,
all their documents had been taken from
them together with other possessions.
Each prisoner therefore had an
opportunity to claim a fictitious name or
profession and for various reasons,
many did this.
The authorities were interested
only in the captives numbers.
These numbers were often tattooed on
their skin and also had to be sewn to a
certain spot on their
trousers, jacket, or coat.
Any guard who wanted to make a charge
against a prisoner just glanced at his
number
and how we dreaded those glances.
He never asked for his name
to return to the convoy about to depart.
There was neither time nor desire
to consider moral or ethical issues.
Every man was controlled by one thought
only to keep himself alive for the
family, waiting for him at
home and to save his friends
with no hesitation. Therefore, he
would arrange for another prisoner,
another number to take his
place in the transport.
As I've already mentioned, the process of
selecting capital's was a negative one.
Only the most brutal of the
prisoners were chosen for this job.
So Kappos or prisoners,
Jewish prisoners that got selected to
help run the prison camp and and Capco.
I tried to find the etymology of where
that came from and the best or the
closest or the thing that made the
most sense to me from what I read was,
was they had two words combined together,
comrade police than the in German.
Those got shortened to Cappo.
So some of these,
and you already heard one of those earlier
testimonies talking about the Jewish
police inside the prisons and how they
were just as bad as in many cases as the
Germans themselves
back to the book.
But apart from the selection of
capitals which was undertaken by the SS,
there was a sort of self selecting
process going on the whole time.
Among all the prisoners
on the average,
only those prisoners could keep alive
who after years of trekking from camp to
camp had lost all scruples
in their fight for existence.
They were prepared to use every means,
honest and otherwise even brutal force
theft and betrayal of friends in order to
save themselves.
Will you have come back by the aid
of many lucky chances or miracles,
whatever one may choose to call them.
We know
the best of us did not return.
So there's a dynamic that you don't think
of immediately when you think of the
concentration camps. Number one,
you don't think about the Kappos,
the Jewish police that are
forced into this situation.
And then the other thing you
don't think about is this.
The fact that the people
that were going to survive,
we're basically,
I'm making it very broad say but,
but you know from what Viktor Frankl
Sane here it was the people that were
willing just to do anything to survive,
including betraying their friends
and he's saying straight up,
we know the best of us did not return.
And that is something that
you don't think about.
Okay.
Hey, we probably don't think about it
cause we don't want to think about it.
Because when you start thinking
about what would you do to survive,
what would you do to survive?
What would I do to survive?
And that's a question I don't think a
lot of people want to know the answer to
and it's very easy to go through life
and never have to answer that question.
Talking a little bit now
about what life was like in the camp,
back to the book somewhere it is said
that man cannot exist without sleep for
more than a stated number
of hours quite wrong.
I had been convinced that there were
certain things I just could not do.
I could not sleep without this or I
could not live without that or the other.
The first night in Auschwitz,
we slept in beds which were
constructed in tears on each tier,
measuring about six and
one half to eight feet,
slept nine men directly on the boards.
Two blankets would be
shared by each nine men.
We could of course lie only on our sides,
crowded in huddled against each other,
which had some advantages because of
the bitter cold though was forbidden to
take shoes up to the Bronx.
Some people did use them
secretly as pillows in spite
of the fact that they were
caked with mud.
Otherwise,
one's head had to rest on the
crook of an almost dislocated arm
and yet sleep came and brought a Bolivian
and relief from the pain for a few
hours.
The thought of suicide was
entertained by nearly everyone,
if only for a brief time.
It was born of hopelessness
of the situation.
The constant danger of death
looming over us daily and hourly,
and the closeness of deaths
suffered by many of the others.
Okay.
From personal convictions,
which we mentioned later.
I made a firm promise on my first evening
in the camp that I would not run to
the wire.
This was a phrase used in camp to describe
the most popular method of suicide,
touching the electrical electrically
charged barbed wire fence,
who's not entirely difficult
for me to make this decision.
There was little point
committing suicide since.
For the average inmate life expectation,
calculating objectively and counting
all likely chances was very poor.
He could not without any assurance,
he could not with any assurance expect
to be among the small percentage of men
who survived all the selections.
The prisoner of Auschwitz in the
first of shock did not fear death.
Even the gas chambers lost their horrors
for him after the first few days.
After all,
they spared him the act
of committing suicide
and Viktor Frankl was a psychiatrist
going into this situation.
So that's the,
that's the view.
That's the perspective that
he takes throughout this and
he's now been in for a couple days in
Auschwitz and another guy comes in to talk
to him who's another colleague of his,
and we're going back to the book.
A colleague of mine who had arrived
in Auschwitz several weeks previously,
smuggled himself into our hut.
He wanted a calm and comfort
us and tell us a few things.
He becomes so thin that at first we did
not recognize him with a show of good
humor and a devil may care attitude.
He gave us a few hurry tips.
Don't be afraid.
Don't fear the selections.
Dr m the SS medical chief
has a soft spot for doctors,
but one thing I beg of you,
he continued shave daily
if at all possible.
Even if you have to use a
piece of glass to do it.
Even if you have to give your
last piece of bread for it,
you will look younger and the scraping
will make your cheeks look row Rudy,
or if you want to stay alive,
there's only one way look fit
for work if you even limp,
because let us say you have a small
blister on your heel and an ss man spots
this. He will wave you aside and the
next day you are sure to be gassed.
Now his mind and his thoughts,
he describes what he would
think about back to the book.
My mind still clung to
the image of my wife.
A thought crossed my mind. I didn't
even know if she were still alive.
I knew only one thing which
I have learned well by now,
love goes very far beyond the
physical person of the beloved.
Okay?
It finds its deepest meaning in his
spiritual being, in his inner self.
Whether or not he is actually present,
whether or not he is still alive at
all ceases somehow to be of importance.
I did not know whether my life wife was
alive and had no means of finding out
during all my prison life.
There was no outgoing or incoming mail,
but at that moment
it ceased to matter.
There was no need for me to know.
Nothing could touch the
strength of my love,
my thoughts and the image of my beloved.
Had I known then that my wife was dead.
I think that I still would have given
myself undisturbed by that knowledge to
the contemplation of her image and that
my mental conversation with her would
have been just as vivid
and just as satisfying.
Yeah,
sent me like a seal upon thy heart.
Love is as strong as death
and continuing on.
Doctor Frankel talks about
images from inside the camp.
Standing outside,
we saw sinister clouds glowing in the
west and the whole sky alive with clouds
of everchanging shapes and colors
from steel blue to blood red.
The desolate gray mud huts provided a
sharp contrast while the puddles on the
muddy ground reflected the glowing sky.
Then after a few minutes
of moving silence,
one prisoner said to another
how beautiful the world could be
and beyond looking for beauty around them,
they were able to find humor and I've,
I have people ask me about this from
time to time about humor in combat
situations and isn't it important and yes,
it absolutely is and you'd think in a
concentration camp even humor would go
away,
but not true.
Back to the book to discover that
there was any semblance of art in a
concentration camp must be
surprised enough for an outsider,
but he may be even more astonished to
hear that one could find a sense of humor,
could find a sense of humor there as well.
Of course,
only the faint trace of one and then
only for a few seconds or minutes.
Humor was another of the souls of weapons
in the fight for self preservation.
It is well known that humor more than
anything else in the human makeup can't
afford an aloofness and an ability to
rise above any situation if only for a few
seconds.
The attempt to develop a sense of humor
and to see things in a humorous light is
some kind of trick I learned
while mastering the art of living.
Yet it is impossible to practice the art
of living even in a concentration camp.
Although suffering it is omnipresent.
To draw an analogy,
a man suffering is similar
to the behavior of gas.
If a certain quantity of gas is
pumped into an empty chamber,
it will fill the chamber completely an
evenly, no matter how big the chamber.
Okay.
Thus suffering completely fills
the human soul and conscious mind.
No matter whether the
suffering is great or little.
Therefore, the size of human
suffering is absolutely relative
and I think the point that I took away
from that was that chamber that can be
filled up with suffering fill
it up with some humor as well.
Otherwise that that suffering will just
fill the whole chamber will fill your
whole brain
back to the book.
We were grateful for
the smallest of mercies.
We were glad when there was time
to d Laos before going to bed.
Although in itself this was no pressure
pleasure as it meant standing naked in
an unheated hut where icicles
hung from the ceiling.
But we were thankful if there was no
air raid alarm during this operation and
the lights were not switched off.
Okay.
We cannot do the job properly.
We were kept awake half the night.
Okay.
So you're at a point in life where you're
grateful for being able to stand naked
and pick the lice off of your friends
before you go to bed so that the license
will keep you awake at night
by chewing it, your body.
Okay.
And you know,
I talked about
how or he talks about how,
you know,
it was the person that was
going to survive, had to be
ruthless basically. Yeah.
And here he says,
but it's not for me to pass judgment on
those prisoners who put their own people
above everyone else who can throw a stone
at a man who favors his friends under
circumstances when sooner or later
it is a question of life or death.
No Man should judge unless he asks
himself in absolute honesty whether in a
similar situation he might
not have done the same.
Yeah,
and here he says,
I mentioned earlier how everything that
was not connected with the immediate
task of keeping oneself and one
closest friends alives lost its value.
Okay.
Everything was sacrificed to this end.
Yeah.
A man's character became involved to
the point that he was caught in mental
turmoil,
which threatened all values he held
and threw them into doubt under the
influence of a world which no
longer recognize the of human life
and human dignity,
which had robbed the man of his will and
made him an object to be exterminated.
Having planned however,
to make full use of him first to the last
ounce of his physical resources under
this influence, the personal ego
finally suffered a loss of values.
Okay.
If the man in the concentration camp
did not struggle against this in a last
effort to save his self respect,
he lost the feeling of
being an individual,
of being with a mind,
with inner freedom
and personal value.
He thought of himself then as only
part of an enormous mass of people.
His existence descend it to
the level of animal life.
The men were herded sometimes
to one place then to another,
sometimes driven together than apart like
a flock of sheep without a thought or
a will of their own.
A small but dangerous pack.
Watched them from all sides,
well versed in methods
of torture and sadism.
They drove the herd incessantly,
backwards and forwards with shouts,
kicks and blows and we the sheep thought
of two things only how to evade the bad
dogs and how to get a little food.
Yeah.
He's going to delve into this deeper,
this idea of this inner freedom.
Oh,
and how hard you had to fight to maintain
that and how easy it was just to roll
in and become one of the pack,
one of the herd
back to the book.
It is very difficult for an outsider to
grasp how very little value was placed
on human life and camp.
The camp inmate was hardened to possibly
became more conscious of this complete
disregard of human existence.
When a convoy of sick men was arranged.
The May,
she hated bodies of the sick were thrown
on two wheeled carts which were drawn
by prisoners for many miles, often
through snow storms to the next camp.
If one of the sick men had died before
the cart left, he was thrown on anyways.
The list had to be correct.
The list was the only thing that mattered.
Okay.
A man counted only because he had a prison
number one literally became a number
dead or alive.
That was unimportant.
The life of a number was
completely irrelevant.
What stood behind that number
and that life mattered even less.
Yeah.
The fate, the history,
the name of the man.
Yeah.
The camp inmate was frightened of making
decisions and if taking any sort of
initiative whatsoever.
This was the result of a strong feeling
that fate was one's master and that one
must not try to influence it in any way,
but instead let it take its own course.
In addition,
there was a great apathy which contributed
in no small part to the feelings of
the prisoner
at times,
lighting lightening
decisions had to be made,
decisions would spelled life or death.
The prisoner would have preferred
to let fate make the choice for him.
And so some of the examples that he brings
up in the book on that or they'd get
told we need people to go to
a different camp for rest.
Okay.
And they had no idea. Sometimes
it actually was some kind of rest.
Sometimes it was some kind
of actual medical facility.
Sometimes it was just you're going to
the gas chambers at another camp and they
had no idea which one it was.
And so they got into this mode of
they were just going to externally,
just whatever was going to happen there
was going to happen and they wouldn't,
they go beyond where they're trying to
in the beginning to like get me off that
list or I want to be on that list.
And they realized that they just were
born messing with fate as they got into a
mode of I'm just going to let things
happen and whatever happens, happens.
Okay,
and they got this,
this feeling of apathy.
You can just imagine how that,
that having no control
externally of what's happening,
how that leads number one
leads to this apathy of just,
I don't care what happens,
but number two,
how that they can then sneak in and start
to get control of your inner thoughts
and your inner feelings where you just
feel like you don't have control over
anything in life and that's it.
Okay.
That here he talks about apathy some more.
The prisoners apathy was also
the result of other factors.
Hunger and lack of sleep contributed
to it as they do in normal life also
and to the general irritability,
which was another characteristic
of the prisoners mental state.
The lack of sleep was partly
due to the pastoring of vermin,
which infested the terribly overcrowded
hots because of the general lack of
hygiene and sanitation.
The fact that we had neither nicotine nor
caffeine also contributed to the state
of apathy,
irritability.
Besides these physical causes,
there were mental ones in the
form of certain complexes.
The majority of prisoners suffered
from a kind of inferiority complex.
We all had once been or had
fancy ourselves to be somebody.
Now we were treated like
complete non entities.
The consciousness of one's inner
value is anchored in higher,
more spiritual things that
cannot be shaken by camp life.
But how many free men load
alone prisoners possess it
without consciously thinking about it,
the average prisoner felt
himself utterly degraded.
This became obvious when one observed
the contrasts offered by the singular
sociological structure of the camp. The
more prominent prisoners, the Kappos,
the cooks,
the storekeepers and the camp policemen
did not as a rule feel degraded at all
like the majority of prisoners, but
on the contrary, he felt promoted.
Some even developed miniature
miniature delusions of grandeur.
Clearly we can all take a lesson out
of that one and that is, you know,
you get put into a promotion position
or you've got authority over people.
Don't let that go to
your head. Yeah. It gets,
that's a natural thing where they did
this experiment test in the university,
whatever, and they're all just random
students. One played the prisoner,
one group played the guards and
that happened. Yup. Like a act.
It's just an experiment.
It's not real life, you know?
And they still happen. Yeah.
And it happened in real life,
which I think is even more insane.
It's even more insane. Yeah. In a way.
But then again,
how can we sit here and judge when,
if you're in that situation and you need
to survive and you need to do the best
to get your, you to survive in your family
survive and you have an opportunity,
oh, are we going to say,
nope, nope. I'm going to,
instead of doing this where I maybe can
do something good in the long run, nope.
I'm not going to go across my values.
I'm going to die in three days.
And that's it. Yeah. That's a hard
decision to make. Yeah. I mean,
it seems easy when you're sitting
in the comfort of your home. Like,
I wouldn't do that.
Or you can say,
and this is what I would have done or I
wouldn't have done. But yeah, you can.
You know, I, I, I talk to
people about, again, it's,
I'm not going to compare anything
to what we're talking about here,
but in the military for instance,
a lot of times I had to make decisions to,
to,
you know, I've got to do something
that maybe I didn't fully agree with,
but I knew in the long run it was going
to get me something that was going to be
beneficial to my team or
to my platoon or whatever.
So you make those little adjustments
and you got to suck it up and you do
something that you might not want to do,
but in the long run,
it's going to be beneficial. I mean, this,
I don't even know if this is
even a remotely close comparison,
but what I am saying is this, you
take a human being and you say, look,
you can either step up and act a different
way and be abusive to these people,
or you're going to be dead in three days.
That's it. Those are your choices. Yeah.
And it's not that hard to figure out
that a lot of people are going to step up
and say, cool, all abused those
people. Cause I need to live from the,
to live my choices. Either death.
Yeah. And by the way, maybe the,
maybe the best person in that group
is going to say, you know what?
I'm gonna do this and I'm gonna step
up and when I abused these people,
I'm going to do a little bit
less than someone else might.
And therefore I'm doing the
best I can. Yeah. I mean,
these are decisions how to even think
about these decisions. Yeah. Know Man.
And you have to think about it.
You have to understand that you have
to understand what human nature is.
That there is a survival point for humans.
You have an instinct instinct to survive
that very few people can overcome.
And I don't even, you know, again,
how do you judge whether it's right to
overcome it or not? When is it right?
I mean, obviously when is it right? We're
sitting here, it's easy to say, Hey,
don't you know these guys? Why
would you kill yourself? Well,
if you don't do these things,
you're basically killing yourself.
If you don't step up, if you don't
say, okay, I'll work as a cappo.
If you don't do that, you're
killing yourself. Does that
make it okay man? Yeah,
it's brutal.
It's like you got to figure out whether
or not you're better off dead in the
evening in the grand scheme
of things like these,
these people that they're going to kind
of succumb to these positions or do all
these low things to survive so
they can survive and you know,
live on and all this stuff.
So it's either that or am I
better off dead overall? You know,
like that's the decision you gotta
make Tang. Who knows what you think,
especially with all these
conditions. Yeah. You know
the opposite of that. It was,
it was a dick winters,
and was talking about how he,
and I don't know if I talked
about it on the podcast,
but in the book conversations
with Dick Winters,
he t he goes through a big section where
he talks about some of the guys in his
company and he called him the killers.
And he actually went on and said, hey,
you know,
I don't want to call them killers
because that's going to give the wrong
impression. But these guys were my most
aggressive guys. They were my best guys.
And he's, and he said they
didn't make it past, you know,
he said most of them didn't make
it. I forget which, which battle.
But he said most of them didn't make it
past this certain time because they were
so aggressive.
They were such good guys.
They were so brave that
they didn't make it.
And this is sort of the opposite,
where you have
the people that are brave, I guess. No,
it's the same in that people that are
brave and gonna hold to their values,
they're gonna die. Right. And,
and if you think about somebody
that's cowardly in combat that says,
oh, you know what, you
know, Echo, you go first,
I'm going to sit over here behind this,
you know, uh, uh, covered position,
I'm going to live longer.
And it's a micro example of what
we're talking about here. Yeah.
In this, given the book and
what we're talking about,
his plate come off as borderline
insulting if not full fledged insulting.
But you ever watched this show survivor?
I watched the first one when it was kind
of a thing and there was an interesting
psychology happening plus Rudy
Bosch was on it, you know, this, uh,
see what retired seal master chief,
you know,
everyone kind of knew in
the seal teams. Yeah. So,
and especially what you're going to say
is that the people that are not good
human beings are the ones that win.
Will they get far,
put it that way because they have this
weird mechanism at the end where the last,
you know, few people who get voted
off, they become this sort of a jury.
So it's like if you went through
the whole game screwing people over,
the jury's going to get you
kind of thing. So it's uh, yeah.
And this is just how the show
just sorted itself out over time.
But the first ones didn't have any
jury. Right. I don't, I don't know.
I did in fact have been like,
I'm going to go ahead and say I,
I'm almost positive they didn't cause
Rudy had his hand on some log and they had
to keep it there for like x and for a
long time. And one person, you know,
he actually thought of something else and
took his hand off and then he was out.
That was it. But yeah, there's
absolute comparison there.
There's an absolute comparison to,
you know,
if you're willing to be a snake,
you can,
you can, you can win the game. And I've
talked about that too, in promotion,
people getting promoted and if
you're willing to be a snake,
you can get promoted.
But the thing that I will say in a work
environment is that that snake might get
one promotion,
they might get two promotions.
They're not going to go the distance.
And if you hold the line
on doing what's correct,
then you might miss that first promotion.
You might even miss that second promotion,
but eventually if you're
on the right path,
you will get the recognition and
you will win in the long run.
You gotta be patient
though. Yeah. Yeah. I mean,
obviously in your job it's not
life or death. You know, death is,
it's so close that you know, one slip
up, you're dead, you're dead. You know,
so that's, you know,
obviously the dynamics are
different in work in that way.
But otherwise, I think so. And survivor,
there's also that other thing that kind
of what they talk about where or what
you were just talking about is if you,
it's kind of in a matter
of speaking plain,
it's safe where you're just hiding under
the wings and you might attach yourself
to someone or you'll avoid
any kind of, you know, uh,
risky per situation for sure.
In survivor,
you can make it far like
that as well. Yup. I mean,
nowadays everyone knows
about those things. Like,
oh you backstabbed everyone or you just
hid behind this guy cause he's strong.
But at the same time,
just so they call you how you were
saying if you're brave or you're going to
stick to your morals and
be honest with everyone,
like you'll get voted off real quick.
Even if you're really good at it.
You know the challenges are
something I'm going to go,
we don't even like really
good leaders get voted.
Like if someone just says a dynamic
leader, they get voted off. Exactly right.
Too much of a threat. Too much of
a threat to every second counts.
And actually what you're talking
about going through seal training,
I would hear it and it was,
I didn't hear it when I went through,
but I heard it later.
This idea of the gray man.
And I think we might have
actually answered a question
on the podcast about that
was going through training
and just being a gray man,
meaning just don't stand out
and you'll be good to go.
And that's, that's a, that's
a, that's a strategy, Ryan,
the seal teams is that it's the
strategy going through buds. Oh,
it through seal training,
the initial she'll training course because
the minute you stand out and people
start knowing who you are and now you've
got an instructor's looking at you and
the more they watch you,
the more they can see.
Maybe you're making some mistakes or
maybe you're not doing everything right or
maybe you're not. And so it's better
just to be that guy in the middle.
I was the guy in the middle,
not because I wanted to meet,
but because I was not the fastest runner.
I wasn't the best swimmer.
What you don't want to be as
the guy on the tail end. Right.
And it's weird because I put so many guys,
not through the basic seal training,
but through the advanced seal
training and the guys that I remember,
there's two types of guys that I remember,
the guys that were awesome and
the guys that were horrible,
and the guys in the middle, all the gray
guys, I know him when I see him. Right.
But a lot of times I don't,
100% I might not know their name.
Whereas some of the pipe hitters,
the young pipette or some e five pipe
pinner that was just getting after it.
I'd always remember those guys names cause
they would take control of everything
and they'd stand out.
And then the other guys,
you remember the guys that
are totally jacked up.
So that idea of being a gray man,
it seems like a good policy to have
in the concentration camp. Look,
I just don't want to stand out. I don't
want to have a limp. I don't want to,
you know, come across as I just want
to fit in. And then the gray man,
unless you're going to go the
distance, right. Which is, and,
and that's a horrible way of saying
I'm going to stand out by saying, Hey,
I can whip these prisoners into shape.
Right.
That's going and raising your hand
and saying, I'll be a cappo. I,
I'm going to step up.
And what you're risking there is we
don't know where this war is going to end
and where are you going to be at
the end of this thing. And you know,
I read some stories about that.
The war did ENT and they did liberate
these camps and it didn't work out good
for the Kappos.
So there's,
there's the same thing.
You might've been done all right,
getting your promotion
the first couple times,
but eventually it comes
around exactly right. Yeah.
You know,
Harley Flanagan was talking about Karma
and I don't know how much reality there
is that,
but there's,
there's the reality of you reap
what you sow and if you people,
if you,
if you take advantage of your position,
if you maneuver and screw people
over to get ahead of them,
they'll remember that. They'll remember
that. Yeah. And that makes sense. I mean,
Carmel [inaudible] it's
never worth it by the way.
It's never worth it.
I mean,
could you possibly come up with
some scenario where, where,
you know,
I did this to get a promotion so that I
could take care of you and everyone else.
You could come up with a sense,
but it's very, very rare and,
and my gut feeling was always like,
it's not worth it.
It's not worth it to do those little
maneuvers in and to try and better your
position on other people's backs.
We're screwing someone over in,
cause you've got to live with that too.
I mean,
unless you're like a sociopath
or something like that,
you have to live with that and men. Yeah,
and even at the time it seems like, oh,
I could live with that because oh look,
you know what?
You're actually,
you're actually taking the higher
road than me because you're saying you
personally have to live with it. And
that's definitely, I'm saying beyond that,
even if you're a person
that can live with it,
you're still gonna pay in the long run.
Even if he didn't look yourself in
the mirror and be like, I don't care,
I got promoted. That's good. That's okay.
So you can live with that. That's cool.
But guess what?
There's something else you're going to
that's going to come back around and that
is one of those other people that you
stepped on their back is going to invent
something new at work and he's
going to take over the division.
Then you're going to pay not to mention
the 10 people who watched it happen and
you know, yeah, you're just
making enemies, enemies.
And that's really what
Karma as far as I mean,
Karma could be this mystical thing that
personally watches you and has this
judgment system must be real. Just real
life. Just like if I walk up to, you know,
even mean you're even,
we don't know each other.
I don't have any bad or good feelings
towards you and I come and I slap you.
I created a deficit. Now, now
your intention, big deficit.
So your intention, whether you
do it or not, you're what you,
you're compelled to slap me
back if not more, usually more.
So that's kind of really what it is.
I mean, really in a small, teeny,
tiny nutshell. Yeah. I go out
and start acting mad to everyone.
They're not going to be
like, oh, I love you. I mean,
they might because they might
be intellectual or you know,
they might be able to think about it,
but they're natural.
Compulsion will be to be mad at
you back. And, and this, you know,
the podcast, human nature,
talking about human nature.
And I always say that war reveals human
nature more clearly than anything else
because it's so much pressure on the
people. Obviously a concentration camp,
it's revealing human nature and that's
exactly what we're talking about.
And it reveals itself in crystal clarity
on a massive scale in terms of being
able to see it in a concentration camp
and you see it reveal itself on a TV show
called survivor and you see that reveal
itself in, in the work environment.
And what I'm saying is from all that,
what you want to do is you want to make
sure that when you get into a position
of authority,
you don't abuse it. That's what I'm
saying. Yeah. You don't want to abuse it.
You want to treat people
with respect no matter what.
And you don't want to step on people's
backs to get ahead because ultimately
it's not going to pay off.
It really isn't. Yeah.
You're only going to full
like that leader that you see,
that you fooled into thinking
that you are a great guy.
It's only gonna last for so long. Yeah.
And eventually you're gonna get found out.
Okay.
Now. All right, let's get, let's
get back into the book here.
The experiences of camp life show that
man does have a choice of action and this
is, we've talked about the capitalists
and he's gonna talk about some of the more
heroic people and in some of those
actions very briefly, and he says,
because it's the reason there was very
briefly because there wasn't a lot of
them.
Yeah.
The experiences of camp life show
that man does have a choice of action.
There were enough examples,
often of a heroic nature which
proved that apathy could be overcome.
Irritability,
irritability,
suppressed man can preserve a
vestige of spiritual freedom,
of independence of mind.
Even in such terrible conditions
of psychic and physical stress.
We who lived in concentration camps
can remember the men who walked through
huts,
comforting others giving away
their last piece of bread.
Okay.
They may have been few in number,
but they offer sufficient proof that
everything can be taken from a man.
But one thing,
the last of the human freedoms to choose
one's attitude in any given set of
circumstances to choose one's own way,
eh,
and there it is. I mean
that is it. That is it.
This idea,
and you know,
Captain Plumb talked about it as well
and captain plumb had a quote from
Stockdale and we got to explore this and
I've got a bunch of Stockdale books and
are we will get to some Stockdale books.
Who is the senior guy in the Hanoi Hilton
and he's a fighter pilot philosopher
guy.
Brilliant guy to hero.
One of them was awarded the Medal
of honor and one of the things that,
that that captain plumb was talking to
us about is his captain plumb said that
they got word from Stockdale
and I'm going to misquote it,
but I'm going to do my best.
It was just because we're in a prison
camp doesn't mean we have to be on
defense. We're going to be
on offense in a prison camp.
That's just a completely different
attitude. It's choosing the attitude.
We're not going to sit here and
be abused and and be put down.
We're going to step up. We're going
to, we're going to go on offense and,
and they did. They did hunger
strikes, they passed word around.
They wouldn't stand up when people
enter their, they did these things,
they went on offense and that's
what he's talking about right here.
This last human freedom to choose
one's attitude in any given set of
circumstances,
we always have that choice.
No matter what the circumstances are that
surround you always have that choice.
Hmm.
Back to the book and there will
always choices to make. Every day,
every hour offered the
opportunity to make a decision,
a decision which determined whether
you would or would not submit to those
powers which threatened to
rob you of your very self,
your inner freedom,
which determined whether or not you would
become the play thing of circumstance.
Renouncing freedom and dignity to become
molded into the form of the typical
inmate.
Okay.
Again, there it is. You,
you're in a concentration camp,
doomed,
and yet you can hang on to that last,
that last bastion of freedom in your soul.
I'm not let them win and
not let them own that.
Back to the book scene.
From this point of view,
the mental reactions of the inmates have
a concentration camp must seem more to
us than the mere expression of certain
physical and sociological conditions.
Even though conditions
such as lack of sleep,
insufficient food and various mental
stresses may suggest that the inmates were
bound to react in certain ways.
In the final analysis,
it becomes clear that the sort of person
the prisoner became was the result of
inner decision and not the
result of camp influences alone.
Think about that.
The sort of person the prisoner became
was the result of an inner decision and
not the result of the circumstances here,
and that doesn't matter what
kind of person you become. Hmm.
What matters is the
decisions that you make
unbelievable
back to the book fundamentally.
Therefore,
any man can even under such circumstances
decide what shall become of him
mentally and spiritually. Okay.
Physically you can have that one.
Can't control that. All the Delta all
the time, but mentally and spiritually,
I get to decide what I'm going to be.
Hmm.
He may retain his human dignity
even in a concentration camp.
Dusty Yefsky said once,
there is only one thing that I dread
not to be worthy of my sufferings.
Okay.
These words frequently came to my mind
after I became acquainted with those
murders, who, whose behavior and camp,
who's suffering and death bore witness
to the fact that the last inner freedom
cannot be lost.
It can be said that they were
worthy of their sufferings.
Yeah.
The way they board their suffering
was a genuine inner achievement.
Yeah.
It is this spiritual freedom
which cannot be taken away,
that makes life meaningful and purposeful.
The way in which a man accepts his
fate and all the suffering it entails,
the way in which he takes up his
cross gives him ample opportunity,
even under the most difficult
circumstances to add a
deeper meaning to his life.
It may remain brave,
dignified,
and unselfish, or in a bitter
fight for self preservation.
He may forget is human dignity
and become no more than an animal.
Okay?
Here lies the chance for a man
either to make use of or to forgo the
opportunities of attaining the moral
values that a difficult situation may
afford him.
And this decides whether he is
worthy of his sufferings or not.
So think about that.
When you get faced with
this ultimate challenge,
brutal challenge,
when life is just about to crush you,
that's when you have the biggest
opportunity to prove who you are.
Yeah.
You know,
speaking of,
of of unworthy topics,
but this is something I,
when I was, when I first got to see
what I, when I was at seal team won,
I ran a communications class
and when I ran the class we,
I was like super hard.
And I know it comes as a big shocker,
but we would great test, test, test on
all these different subjects. You know,
what radio, what frequency, your
bandwidth, what do you know?
All these different subjects.
And I would say the guys, Hey,
you know,
tomorrow we've got another test,
another opportunity for
you to prove yourself.
And that's the way I looked at.
They didn't always look at it same way,
but that's exactly exactly
what he's saying here.
When you have these brutal
circumstances that you face,
that's your opportunity. And if you
think about all heroic tales, right?
There's no heroic tales where the
hero doesn't face any challenges.
And as a matter of fact,
the worst challenges he faces,
the more of a hero he becomes.
Yeah. If he rises to the occasion,
if he doesn't rise the gays, and guess
what? We don't hear about them. Right.
Not a hero,
not a hero.
Okay.
Yeah.
In fact,
let's say you're considered a hero and
then this big chance to prove yourself
comes about and you fail
or you don't step up,
you're kind of like this
big failure in a way,
even though you've been a hero of the
whole time. Yeah. I would say that's true.
Although if you do something heroic
enough, people are like good with it.
Right.
I think if they're significant enough
to say so it's kind of the same thing.
Yeah. I mean, the bottom line
is you face these challenges,
you get challenged to, to have
this attitude of, you know,
basically good opportunity, opportunity
to solve the problems. Right? Oh,
big challenge. Cool opportunity. Good.
Yeah. It's like those guys who, you know,
they start a business,
the businesses like grows and then it
just massively fails because of some
mistake or I dunno, something and some
or the kind of out in or whatever,
and then they,
oh,
they reach rock bottom and they build
themselves back up and then, you know,
it's this massive success. That's
an impressive story. Yeah. You know,
that's much better than, hey, I
went to this school, I graduated,
I worked this job, I made a bunch
of money. Everyone goes, oh, cool.
Right, cool. Yeah, yeah. They
want to hear the struggle.
They want to see that you are challenged.
Yep.
Back to the book,
everywhere man is confronted with fate,
with the chance of achieving, of achieving
something through his own suffering.
God, think about that. The, the,
the suffering that you're going through
is an a chance to achieve something
through your suffering.
That's an incredible thought.
Now,
this next part is something that I get
asked about on a fairly regular basis.
Back to the book.
Take the fate of the sick,
especially those who are incurable.
I once read a letter written by young
invalid in which he told a friend that he
had just found out he
would not live for long,
that even an operation
would be of no help.
He wrote further that he remembered
a film he had seen in which a man was
portrayed who waited for death and
end courageous and dignified way.
The boy had a thought.
It agree,
the boy had fought it
a great to meet deaf.
So well now he wrote fate was
offering him a similar chance.
Okay.
Yeah. I mean there's,
there's, you know, diseases,
terminal diseases and that's it.
And then what do you do?
Well, I think you have to choose
the best possible attitude you can.
And again, I've never been
in that situation obviously,
but
that statement seems to be the
best possible attitude to take.
Again, that's, that's when we see
people doing something heroic.
That's what we see. And you
know, it's funny, some of those,
when we were doing a lot of the
native Americans on the podcast,
they all had that attitude. When you
go to face death, hold your head high,
be afraid of it.
And that's really,
like you said, an easier sitting here in
the, you know, in the recording studio.
He of course,
easy for me to sit here and say that.
Yeah.
But that's a hard one. And you know, um,
the other day all the Joe Rogan
podcast Everlast was on there.
Yeah. And Joe Rogan, he, you know,
Everlast who's saying, hey, you know,
I'm not in good shape right now.
I wish I could better shape,
but I have, you know, back,
I think he's got a back injury and he's
got this and he's got a daughter that's
got some kind of illness,
bad illness and Joe put on the good
video that you made and you know,
Everlast when he got done Everlast
was like, hey, that's cool,
that's inspirational. But how does that
help me with my sick daughter? Yeah.
What's good about that? You know, and I
wished I could have jumped through and,
and talk to him because this much,
I will say when you got a
bad situation like that,
I'm telling you right now, it
could be worse. Absolutely.
100%.
And the fact that he's talking about his
daughter and how she's sick and how he
has to spend so much time with
her to take care of her. Well,
well that's what I'm saying.
Be Thankful that you're in a position in
life where you can spend time with her.
Be Thankful that she's in a condition
where she can spend time with you. Yeah.
And you know, there's, she's
still here. If nothing else,
that's good, if nothing else. And so
what are you gonna do? I mean your, your,
your other option is to say, my daughter
is sick. This is horrible. I got cursed.
It's, it's not fair. And
what does that do for you?
Where does that get you? It doesn't
get you anywhere. It matter of fact,
that takes you backwards.
So you really truly do have to
look at these horrible situations.
I remember I got a call
back from, from, uh,
overseas that a guy was a seal,
was really badly wounded.
And,
and a couple of my friends were kind of
distraught and I talked to one of the
guys overseas and I, you know, and,
and your man, I had at this point,
you know, lost mark, lost Mikey.
I don't think Ryan had died yet,
but like I was familiar with guys dying.
Yeah.
And I talked to one of the guys that was
overseas and they said, hey, you know,
this guy, he's really, really messed
up. And I'm like, is he going to live?
And they're like, yeah, he's stable. And
I go, then don't worry about a thing.
Be Happy he's alive.
And it doesn't matter if he's missing
a leg or two legs or whatever,
he's going to be coming home and
he's going to carry on with his life.
And it's going to be hard
and it's going to be hell,
and it's going to be a
challenge. But guess what? He's
going to be here, you know?
And that, you know, again, it's
like, man, what's the alternative?
The alternative is he's
dead. The alternative is we
never talked to them again.
That's the alternative versus
he's going to come back.
Right. And this guy,
the guy that got wonder,
he wasn't like a great friend of mine,
but I knew I was talking to people that
were very close to them. And so, you know,
I had to make sure I wasn't coming across
like, hey, it's no big deal. I, you know,
look, he's going to be fine. No,
it wasn't like that. But look,
look what the alternative is.
You know,
let's be thankful that he's alive and
he's going to come home and you know he's
going to carry on with his life. And
that's what, that's what's important.
So it's really when you do look at these
situations, when things are going bad,
and then you say, okay, well what
good can come of that? And then the,
the one step further is then what
happens when someone does die?
Then what good comes of that?
And my thought is always the same thing.
I'm thankful that I got
to know that person.
I'm thankful that I got to
understand their personality.
I'm thankful that I got to spend a day
with them laughing and having that memory.
That's what's good.
What's good is I got to experience them
in my life and they got to experience
other people's in their lives. And that's
what's good about it. But just to say,
hey, you know, my friend,
my family member is dead.
This is horrible and I can't
escape from this wrong attitude.
And of course you're going
to go through that. It's the,
there's the whatever those
things are that you go through.
It's shock and then denial and
then anger and then acceptance and,
and all that. That's, I get it.
And it's not going to be easy,
but I'll tell you what will make it easier
is to look at the situation and say,
what here is good. You know, and you,
one of the worst things is parents
will that have young children that are
terminally ill.
It's awful.
And the best you can think of is a
hold them while you can. Yeah. Right.
And and get what you can and grow
the memories that you can right now.
Because just to focus on the fact that
life isn't fair isn't going to help you.
And guess what, you're right.
Life isn't fair. Life isn't fair.
It's, it's, it's a random, horrible thing.
And if you want to focus on the
randomness and the horribleness of it,
that's where you're going to end up.
But if you can focus on the good
that comes out of those situations,
try to you, and again, I haven't been
through that, I haven't been through that.
Thank God, not that level for
sure. But the best I can do,
the best I can assess is say,
man,
at least try and look at what positive
is coming out of this and, and,
and focus on that instead of
focusing on what is negative chew.
It's going back to what Frankl said.
You choose what your attitude
is going to be. Yeah.
Don't become a victim of the
randomness. Yeah. And that's,
so that goes on like all levels.
You know how even if like something
isn't horrible, it's just kind of junk,
you know, all the way down to just
something that's, that's pretty horrible.
There's still a lot of good
going on in the situation.
But in just like are you saying like
your attitude or another way to put it is
what you're looking for to,
to internalize. You know,
a lot of times and it's natural and I've
been there where it's like everything
just seems bad.
Even the smell,
like if something real bad happens that
you think is real bad and then the same
day or the next day or whatever,
something small bad happens,
it'll just add big time to the badness.
Like nothing's going
right kind of attitude.
Meanwhile all the good things
are going on all around you,
but you're not looking for that.
All of those things. Yeah. So,
and a lot of times we
like real bad situation,
especially especially with
kids cause that's like the,
the most weak you can ever
feel really when like your kid,
like when my daughter had,
she had a big staff infection Murcia
in her lymph node. So her neck was be,
she's in the hospital for
a week and we're there.
That's like the most weekend
that that you'll feel in.
Of course there's way
worse situations than the,
you know then that that's nothing
compared to situations. I know that.
But there are good things that a are
still going on in your situation,
your life, that's a B, there's good
situations that can come of it.
And a lot of them, a lot of them is
just our strength related. You know,
like if you let something beat you
down and you don't get the stray,
like that's a loss,
you'll lose. Like you'll
call it some kind of conditioning from it
in a way. In a matter of speaking. Yes.
So like if you have a quote
unquote good attitude,
when you emerge from the situation, you
will have strength. Now, if you don't,
you won't. You'll have weakness, you'll
be gun shy. Everything happens bad.
My life sucks. And you know, you'll
continue down kind of that road.
So the good part,
like if you said like
are you said, if you keep that good
attitude and when you make it out,
you will have this among the other
good things that can come from it.
You will have the strength and
you're, you're right. And I mean,
just look at captain plumb and look at
colonel reader ado for those guys to go
through what they went through and,
and maintain a positive attitude.
And then they come out and you talking to
those guys and it's like, yeah, I don't,
you can't think of more positive
people in the world, you know? I mean,
not in the whole world,
but they're just have so much positivity
because they've been through something
and they had to maintain that attitude.
So you're right, when they come out,
it's like,
how are you going to make?
And I think that's what happens a lot
of times with guys that have been to war
is they come back and they're like happy
to see the sunrise. I know I am right.
I'm happy to see the sunrise.
I'm happier than a lot of people to see
the sunrise. I appreciate that thing.
And I think when people go through some
kind of devastating disease in their
family or themselves, same
thing. Once they get through it,
they at least come out the other
side and they can appreciate it.
And yet if they let it beat him
down, it's going to, it's going to,
everything is going to look down.
If you're looking down,
you're going to look down. If you're
looking up, you're going to look up. Yeah,
that's gotta be a, it's hard. I
mean, it's so hard for people.
It's so hard. Yeah. And again, I'm over
here talking, you know? Yeah, for sure.
Both of us are, you know,
when I was on Joe Rogan,
we started off talking
about Chris Cornell.
It just killed himself and we kind of
cursory kind of talked about depression
and neither Waldo. I mean, I
definitely am not claiming,
claiming to be any kind of expert at
all about it. And I even said on there,
I was like, look, I've
never felt this way.
And I had a couple people hit me up on
social media, like, you know, you should,
you should read this or you should
do this or, and, and you know,
or you're not right. And I'm like, no,
I wasn't even trying to say anything
that I'm right. I'm just telling,
I was saying I don't actually even
know. Yeah. And, and so, yeah,
I'm not certainly an expert
on how to overcome, you know,
horrible situations,
but I've been in some pretty horrible
situations and this is what my thoughts
tried to be.
And it's not always easy at all.
Yeah. Jordan Peterson has
some good, good, um, you know,
good content on that where he's
basically in a nutshell, he says,
get yourself together. Where in his
example, one of the men, it was, you know,
a family member dies or whatever,
get yourself together. So, you know,
what are you going to do?
Are you going to wallow with the rest
of the people so no one can get ahold of
anything in the funerals,
a mess or whatever.
Or are you going to get yourself
together? Grief for sure, game,
but get yourself together so you can
kind of lead and get the funeral together
and take care of the business. And it's
such a cold blooded thing to say, right?
It's the complete, and that's
what I think is hard about it is,
you know, think about this, Oh, if someone
in your family died and I was like, Echo,
get yourself together. Right. You know
what I mean? Like I who says that,
but that's probably the best thing
I could possibly say to, you know,
I might need to say it in a more
tactful way, right? I may just say, Hey,
echo man off feel for you. Hey
Man, what we need to do is grieve,
but we also need to focus on moving
forward. You know what I mean?
It's that kind of thing. But the
reality is, what am I really saying?
I'm really saying, Hey, get yourself
together. You got to move on.
We got to move on, we got to move forward.
You got to move forward in your life.
And that's like such a hard
thing to say to somebody. Yeah.
That's probably the right
attitude to take is okay,
like this is horrible and I
need to keep it together. Yeah,
yeah,
yeah man.
Especially when there's no majorly
prevalent things that are at risk at that
moment as well.
Like you know,
like why you're sitting with like
in a combat situation, I think, uh,
BTF Tony was talking about this one.
If like you're in a firefight or
something like that and some gets hit,
you don't just quit. No exit. The
firefighting beauty. Oh my gosh,
my guys hit use it. It's like, okay, he's
hit boom, let's continue the firefight.
But let's say there was no firefight,
then the guy gets hit. It's,
it's seems like a harder thing to,
to just move on.
So what are you finding
need is you need to, like,
you need to have a firefight going
on so that you can say, okay,
I'm going to deal with this,
but I need to also think about
the rest of life so hard.
And you know, again it's, it's, I,
you know what I'm feeling like right now
I get some social media sometimes where
someone will say, Hey, I'm not a vet,
but like a friend of mine is going through
problems and I don't know how to talk
to them cause I'm not a vet. And that's
kind of like what I feel like right now.
Like I haven't been through
those kinds of suffering,
so I'm throwing darts but I'm
throwing them based on what I know.
So it's the best like, you know,
yeah, best I could do right now. You
like you're at risk of someone saying,
hey,
you simply don't understand
when the fact is there.
My by my statement of that would be
yes, I don't understand. You know,
it's like in the, when I was talking
to veterans saying, look, people,
you feel like people don't understand.
They don't. And that's okay.
And so definitely not sitting
here saying, Oh, uh, you know,
I know this is what you do in a situation
like that. I know. I don't know. Yeah,
I don't know what you do when your
family members suffer something egregious
like that, like a terminal
disease or death. I don't
know, haven't been through it.
What I have been through as losing guys
in combat that I have been through this
is this is darkness.
It's a different kind of darkness.
But this is what I did in those situations
and that's what I would think would
help you in these other situations.
Hard. It's just the question, right?
What do you mean? What do
you do hard? And we are,
we are sitting here reading a book by a
guy that was in a concentration camp and
he's saying this thing to
do, you know? So that's,
that's another sort of reinforcement
of this thought pattern.
Yeah.
All right.
He talks a little bit about the passage
of time here in camp or a small unit of
time a day.
For example,
filled with hourly tortures
and fatigue appeared endless.
A larger time unit, perhaps a
week seemed to pass very quickly.
My comrades agreed when I said that in
the camp a day lasted longer than a week.
How paradoxical was our time experience?
And that's something,
this actually reminded me, I was
talking to us, Sarah Armstrong and she,
well now it's actually
around the conversation when
Leif was talking about he'd
come out here and seeing all my kids,
my kids are all grown up now basically
except for my littlest one. But you know,
my oldest daughter's graduating
high school, you know,
a couple of weeks and she's going
to go to college. And you know,
when Lafe met her, she was,
what was that, 12 years ago?
So she was, you know, no,
six, six, something
like that. So you know,
younger than me. And when
he came out here, you know,
he'd just come left his apartment in New
York City where he's got his wife and
kids and there and you know,
it's chaos and the little kids and
they're crying and screaming and spilling
stuff and throwing up milk and pissing
everywhere. And it's just, you know, it's,
that's what life is when you're a parent.
And you know,
he came out here and saw how my
kids were now grown up and those,
that time has gone by the way,
gone can't get it back. And,
and he, you know, he talked about
it on the podcast, just, hey man,
make sure you appreciate those.
And Sarah Armstrong, you know,
said something along the lines of, uh, the
days are long, but the years are short.
That's a very true statement. And
you can, you can see that cure.
It's the same thing,
you know,
all of a sudden this time
is just going by so quickly.
This is starting to talk
again back to the attitude.
We could say that most men in a
concentration camp believe that the,
the real opportunities of life had passed.
Yet in reality,
there was an opportunity and a challenge.
One could make a victory of
those experiences turning
life into an inner triumph
or one could ignore the challenges in
simply vegetate as did a majority of the
prisoners. Same. Same thing, same
topic. I know what's interesting,
and I told you this before we started
this book, you know, is a great book,
but I,
I kind of wanted to talk about how bad
concentration camps were and I went and
found some other sources for that because
Viktor Frankl doesn't highlight it
that much. I his ad, I mean, he was
in Auschwitz for crying out loud. Hmm.
It doesn't get any worse.
And you know,
to really give the
impact of how bad it was,
I went and found some other
sources that were a little bit,
a little bit more directly written
and a little bit more horrifying,
to be lack of a better word
because in his accounts,
he doesn't go into those,
some of those graphic details,
which I feel like you should know and you
should understand what before you talk
about, hey, he's keeping a good
attitude. But no, no it's not.
He's keeping a good attitude cause
he was in a concentration camp,
but I wasn't that bad. No,
it was freaking hell. Yeah.
And that's what he's dealing with.
And in his mind,
you could make a triumph or a
victory out of those experiences,
which is incredible attitude to have.
Yeah.
Going back to the book, the prisoner
who had lost faith in the future,
his future was doomed with his
loss of belief in the future.
He also lost his spiritual Holt.
He let himself decline and became
subject to mental and physical decay.
Usually this happened quite
suddenly in the form of a crisis.
The symptoms of which were familiar
to the experienced camp inmate.
We all feared this moment,
not for ourselves, which
would have been pointless,
but for our friends,
usually it began with the
prisoner refusing one morning
to get dressed and wash
or to go out on the parade
grounds. No entreaties, no blows,
no threats had any effect. He
just laid there, hardly moving.
If this crisis was brought
about by an illness,
he refused to be taken to the sick
bay or do anything to help himself.
He simply gave up
there.
He remained lying in his own extra extra
to and nothing bothered him anymore.
And that's similar to
what colonel reader said.
How if you didn't actively stay alive,
you would die.
You couldn't just passively exist,
you weren't going to make it.
If you want to die, all you had to do was
stop trying, then you are going to die
back to the book.
As we said before,
any attempt to restore a man's inner
strength in the camp had to first succeed
in showing him some future goal.
In Nietzsche's words,
he who has a why to live for
can bear with almost any how
that could be the guiding motto for all
psychotherapeutic and psycho hygienic
efforts regarding prisoners.
Whenever there was an opportunity for it,
one had to give them a why,
an aim for their lives in
order to strengthen them
to bear the terrible how of
their existence.
Woe to him who saw no more
sense in his life, no aim,
no purpose.
And therefore no point to carrying on.
He was soon lost. Got To know why
you're doing what you're doing.
And that's all there is to it.
He who has a why to live for
can bear with almost any how.
And obviously that translates right
into a leadership perspective.
Making sure people understand why
they're doing what they're doing.
You just don't bark orders at them.
But from an individual perspective,
why are you doing this?
Find that.
And I actually,
I actually made a,
a a a post on social media the other day
and it was something along the lines of
finding your inner y or something
like that. Sure. And I was, I was,
uh, you know, mocking that
attitude. And I was saying,
you know,
sometimes my inner voice is trying to
find out why I'm doing what I'm doing.
And I'm like,
when I'm doing something hard,
my inner voice doesn't allowed to talk
and be quiet. I'm over here working,
you know.
Um,
but there is obviously just like a
leadership perspective and from a personal
perspective,
why are you doing what you're doing?
And that should be the driving force.
And if you don't have that,
it's hard to overcome these challenges.
You can't just overcome challenges
just because you know they're there.
You need some greater reason.
Yeah, and when that gets lost,
you get lost.
I don't know why I thought those.
I think the
when,
why you were mocking that
this is my why and my inner
voice. It wasn't, it wasn't,
now that I think about it,
it wasn't really the why thing. It was
more about the inner, the inner room.
Oh, the inner voice. But yeah, no,
I definitely said why in there too,
because I think people do you like,
it's like a lot of good expressions or
sayings or whatever, or people just, Oh,
I liked that.
And they'll just start throwing it out in,
abusing it and it dumbs it down and
then not everyone's saying it now.
It just sorta sounds cheesy
because no one's actually doing it.
No one's actually understanding the
real, what it really means. You know?
Like the person who's like, Hey, I'm
going to lose weight, and you know,
they've basically spent their life
neglecting their health or whatever.
Then they're like, okay, I'm going to,
you know, I'm going to get in shape.
And then they go on this, you
know, program, they quit, you know,
but when they're doing
good on the pertinent,
let's say the first or second day
they'll be like, this is my why.
And they'll show their, I don't know,
their, their dog or something like that.
My why or my kids or whatever,
you know.
But then the next day
they quit the program.
Like it's such a weak thing and
you're like, whoa, whoa, whoa.
You can't just do that. You know, like
that the whole thing, my y or whatever.
That's way too powerful
for people to just be like,
hey my white and then just not do,
it shouldn't be just like a little
thing can just throw together a, uh,
38 second into Instagram
posts. That's about your why you need
to dig. Yeah. You got to do that stuff.
So that's why it's funny because
like people just throw that out. No,
no means like nothing. And it's, it's
almost like they seen, it seems like,
it seems like it's totally
my interpretation of it.
But it seems like they're saying it and
thinking that they sound so profound and
deep and new, an inspirational, you
know, but everyone's seen it end to,
to counter your point,
I've had plenty of people that
have talked to me about, you know,
I was in bad shape.
I wasn't taking care of myself.
I wasn't healthy and had my
first kid and I said to myself,
I need dude, I need to
be there for my kid. Or,
or I was doing bad at work
and I didn't really care.
And it wasn't focused on my career and
it wasn't focused on being squared away
and I was wasting all my money on dumb
stuff. And I had my first kid. Yeah.
And then I said, I got to, you know, this,
this is me taking care of my kid
and I need to do a damn good job.
And that's exactly the point right
there is that the, it's a real thing.
And if that's for real,
you're,
you're why conceptually now I'm just
saying the expression. Sure. For sure.
But there's a big difference between the,
well,
there's a big difference between
the contemplation that goes into,
I'm doing this for my kid. It's cool.
Yeah, I'm going to go on weight watchers.
Right? It's like, um, no.
Like, think about this.
Think about your relationship with your
children and where you're going to end
up and now you want to see them live
and what guidance you can give them as
human beings and the example
that you're setting for them,
and you align all those things up.
Then maybe you can put down the doughnuts.
Yeah, exactly right. In other words, you
got to do it. Yeah. Actually, you know,
so yeah. That's why it just sounds cheesy
because everyone does it. He says it.
This is a great section.
Going back to the book,
we had to learn ourselves and furthermore,
we had to teach the despairing men
that it did not really matter what we
expected from life,
but rather what life expected from us.
We needed to stop asking you about the
meaning of life and instead to think of
ourselves as those who were being
questioned by life daily and hourly.
One answer must consist
not in talk and meditation,
but in a right action and right conduct.
Life ultimately means taking
the responsibility to find
the right answer to its
problems and to fulfill the tasks which
it constantly sets for each individual.
Again, you're turning your
flipping this idea around,
it's not about what I want from life,
it's what, what does life want from me?
And it's putting these challenges in
these hurdles in front of me and I got to
go and jump over him and then I got to
smash them and then I've got to set fire
to them and then I got to use that fire
to fuel the domination of everything
that's in my path. Is it Kinda like, hey,
these weights aren't going to
lift themselves the exact same
thing.
It's the exact same thing.
Yeah.
And again,
going back to this idea of that
war reveals human nature and,
and this is Dr Frankel's way of putting
this exact same thing that I say back to
the book of life in a concentration camp
tore open the human soul and exposed
it's depths.
It is.
Is it surprising that in those depths
we again found only human qualities,
which in their very nature we're
a mixture of good and evil.
The rift dividing good from evil,
which goes through all human beings,
reaches into the lowest depths and
becomes a parent even on the bottom of the
abyss, which is laid open
by the concentration camp.
So we've got this idea once again
that there's a dichotomy in people,
in people,
this dichotomy that you're capable of
doing extreme good and you're capable of
doing extreme evil.
And we've seen it a bunch,
we've seen it a bunch on this podcast
be you look them Ui massacre.
Those guys were normal guys
that committed extreme evil,
straight up evil.
Hmm.
Normal guys that were,
you know,
four days earlier probably would have
done something heroic to save someone.
Yeah. And here they are, the
other end of the spectrum.
And I think that you have to,
we have to face that not only
individually do you have that,
but then obviously as the group you
have that as a group of human beings,
we have that capability and we've
seen it over and over again.
And if you want to know
what that good part is,
you got to know what that darkness is too.
Yeah, yeah. The group
thing is interesting. Like,
you know, you know how you
always see it, not always,
but you hear sometimes about
these riots on college campuses,
whether it be after game
or something like that.
At a glance you'd think, Dang, is this
college fill of full of just hooligans?
Like if this bit like huge riots,
you know,
but it's that it's like as
an individual or you know,
under quote unquote normal circumstances,
they just, they're just normal people.
Yeah. You know, guys, girls,
whatever, they're just normal people.
But then you put them in this particular
situation in some way extreme or
whatever, you know, it's a spectrum but,
and they just act different. And the,
the whole group dynamic to act different
Hammock is a, uh, is, it can
be a very, very scary thing.
Mm.
There's
no doubt. It can be a very, very scary
thing. And that's, that's why, you know,
even when he's talking about,
and I mentioned this on when I was on
Joe Rogan's last podcast, I'm like this,
the idea of individual freedom
and acting as an individual yeah.
Is so important.
Yeah.
As to, to structure your life around, to
say, look, I'm not part of this group.
This group is not me. This group
is not me. They don't represent me.
I represent me and I'm,
I have my own individual choices.
And that's what he saying in here. The
minute you give away to the herd, yeah.
That's when you start going, you
don't know. You no longer control it.
And when you give up that control,
that's a scary, scary thing.
And that's when these evil
things take place. And that,
once again, it's, it's like,
it's easy to say no because grouping
yourself is actually a survival mechanism.
True. Sold you, you know, it's
not going to be just that.
You're not going to naturally just be
an individual and act like an individual
and conduct yourself in all of these
extreme situations as an individual,
not just going to naturally true.
So I guess it just helps to,
to know these things.
That's your,
you're 100% right on both
facets. Number one, yes.
Grouping and fitting in is a
survival instinct that people have.
And that's why trends happen. And that's
why nations happened. And that's why,
that's why groups occurred.
People and politics. Yeah, new
politics and in everything,
right?
To get these groups.
And I mean it's weird now because
with the Internet you can have groups,
you can be part of these
groups autonomously,
then you can connect with
all these different people.
But it's also important
to make sure that you,
you do remember that you are
an individual then candy,
that you don't want to give up that
last shred of human will to decide
what your attitude is going to
be. Dang. And today, you know,
in our luxurious society,
if you can consciously navigate your
waist clear that have of falling into the
group trap is what it is.
It's a trap because you don't have,
if you can do that successfully,
probably won't fall for the tricks man.
Like that's the thing.
You get air,
we all get trick all the way down to
just something as seemingly benign as
marketing. Just man, you'll
just fall for way less tricks.
You don't like those tricks out there
in the world. Do you know? I don't
probably fell for too many
of them. I think this is a,
I'm going to, I'm going to wrap
this book is this book is not long.
It's a very fast read and,
and actually he goes into,
um,
sort of goes into the
more of the psychological,
the psychiatrist, the actual
academic of it. Then I covered, uh,
but this is a fast reader.
I mean it's only 150 pages
or so and you definitely get
a raw look at human nature.
But this closing I think is very,
very powerful. Going back to the book,
a human being is not
one thing among others,
things determine each other.
But man is ultimately self determining
what he becomes within the limits of
endowment and environment
he has made out of himself
in the concentration camps.
For example,
in this living laboratory and on this
testing ground we watched and witnessed
some of our comrades behave like swine
while others behaved like saints.
Okay.
Man has both potentiality.
He's within himself,
which one is actualized,
depends on decisions
but not on conditions.
Our generation is realistic for we
have come to know man as he really is
after all man is that being who
invented the gas chambers of Auschwitz.
However,
he is also that being who entered those
gas chambers upright with the Lord's
prayer or the Shamah Israel on his lips.
Okay.
And I think that fought,
that man has both potentiality is within
himself and we've seen them over and
over again.
These grand
expanded potentiality in extreme display
and we've talked about these situations
in the podcast over and over again.
And the the Burma railway that was
built by the prisoners of war and the
prisoners of war war,
tortured and killed by the Japanese
and the genocide in Rwanda.
And the rape of Nan King.
And we've also seen
the other
potentiality.
And we've seen that over and over again
that that potentiality of goodness
and of sacrifice
Lowe's men that we've seen over and over
again that laid down their lives for
their brothers.
And,
and in doing so,
protect our freedom.
But it's important to note that again,
that whether the good or
the evil is actualized
in the minds of men that is not
based on conditions but on decisions.
Okay?
In this doesn't only apply to good
and evil, of course, that's the,
that's the most expansive fought
that we can apply this to.
But it also applies to everything
we choose to do or choose not to do.
And everything we choose
to become or not to become.
It's us.
It's our choice.
And we are responsible.
We are responsible to
be good instead of evil,
to be strong instead of weak,
to become what we want to become,
not what we let ourselves become.
We own the course.
And with every decision that we make,
we actualize ourselves.
We become what we choose,
swine
or saints.
So when you make decisions,
every decision think,
think about where that decision leads
and what that decision will make you
become.
And then self determine,
self determined,
choose
what will make you a better person.
Then even in situations where you
feel you have no choice at all,
you still have one last freedom.
And that is to choose your own attitude
in any given set of circumstances.
Keep
that choice,
keep that freedom,
that hard choice,
the disciplined choice
and with the discipline
to make the right choice.
Maintain
your freedom.
I think that's
all I've got for tonight.
Powerful book.
Yeah.
Isn't it crazy how,
I can't help but think of this like where,
how they talk about the,
the SS officers, the Nazis,
the guys there who are savages obviously,
but are they really savages as people
will or is it a circumstantial thing?
I mean I know they're trained to
kind of regard this, you know,
the Jews are these groups of people as
you know, beneath them and all this stuff.
But like are they savages just as individ
cause it takes a savage to do some of
this stuff. You know, especially like
grabbing a baby and smashing his,
as the book said skull against the wall.
That's like sub human behavior,
you know, but when he goes home, you know,
he has kids, you know, is he like, yeah, I
don't care if the, these kids ultimately,
if their heads get, but you know,
I'm sure he's not like that.
I'm sure he's just a normal person
would just be just as weak as all of us.
If your kid stubs it toe
and starts crying, you know,
well,
we're going to explore,
I got some books in the queue to explore
the other side of this and they're very
revealing about some of
that. But again, it's, it's,
you're right that some of these guys,
you know,
we're, we're normal, right?
Some of these Nazis were normal and they
were doing their job and that's one of
the worst. You know, there's
a whole, there's a whole, uh,
argument on whether that even is
allowable. Like if you're doing your job,
and I'll tell you what, in
the u s military you, that
doesn't, that doesn't work.
That's an excuse that we don't
have. You can't say, Hey,
I got ordered to do this thing that
was against the law or against ethical
values. Doesn't matter. I still
can't do it. That's not an excuse.
And that came directly from this
attitude that Nazi said, Hey,
I was just following
orders, you know, hey,
it wasn't my fault as just fallen
orders. No, actually you can't,
you can't say that. You're
not allowed to say that. Yeah.
So as far as the normalicy sure.
They might've been normal,
normal when they went home, but that
doesn't remove their guilt at all. Yeah,
fully. And you can't take a baby and
smashed his head against the wall.
You don't get a pass on that one
whether you ordered to do it or not. No.
There's certain moral standards that
exist and you can't violate them.
And if you do, you're guilty. It
doesn't matter what else you did
back then. Who, who was Kinda
the, the, the, the, you know,
the authority on that. Like where the
moral, was it like a global, you know,
or is it because obviously Hitler, it
was B would be like, Hey, I'm whatever.
Well, there's different societies
that had different viewpoints,
obviously did not war.
Hence the war.
The Nazis and the Japanese both felt,
okay,
we can do what we need to do to dominate
and whether that's the rape and Nan
King or whether that's the concentration
camps and the final solution.
Both those things were in their
societies. Now there was, of course,
there was people inside those societies
and I don't know. I haven't, I haven't,
I don't know of any Japanese.
I'm sure there were some Japanese
that that were against I,
and even when we'd read the raping and
King, there was a Nazi in Nan King.
Remember that sheltered people.
So there's an example.
Here's a guy now he didn't know what was
going on with the final solution back
in Germany.
At least it doesn't appear that way.
But yeah,
this is what makes morality and
ethical decision making so challenging.
But there is, in my opinion, you know,
a certain standard moral code
that human beings live by. Yeah.
And that is a universal relatively unit.
How that has now lasted, actually
you can say it's universal, right?
There's the way that I believe that
there's morals and standards that human
beings should live by and when you start
stepping outside those bounds, you're,
you're going on the wrong side.
Yeah. And like candy thing, men,
that's like obviously a spectrum
and then what you're talking about,
that universal line that you cross,
it's like actually when you really
look at the line, it's like a,
it's a universal gray area of
when you really look closer,
but I think that the circumstances don't
really fall within the confines of that
gray area very often. So it's easy
to be like, that's obviously right.
That's obviously wrong,
but then every once in a while these
gray areas of emergent and it's like this
big debate and it depends on who you are.
I,
I don't spend a lot of time in the
gray areas to be honest with you.
Like in my thought pattern, I don't spend
a lot of time in the careers, right.
I spend time because to
me it is pretty obvious.
Like when your Isis and
you're systematically raping
a 12 year old girls and
boys, you don't get to live that.
That doesn't work. That's not that.
It's not part of my deal.
Over here you, you, you die.
And when you take people and you put
them in cages and you burn them to death,
right.
Do you don't get to do that?
Just like these Nazis that are putting
people in con, you don't get to do that.
No. We go to war. We fight and we
win. That's the way it works. Now.
These grey areas that
you're talking about,
I don't mess around in those gray
areas. Yeah. I think there's too much.
There's too, there's turbulence
in there, right. And,
and a lot of times you look at it
from the outside and you don't,
it's hard to tell what it is,
what it actually is happening
in there. Right aisle.
And maybe that's not the best policy,
but I won't escalate something personally
until I see it go outside the lines of
what I deem to be. Okay. Yeah. You
know, once you get outside those lines,
you're done. We'll, thankfully
you're, you're, you know,
a little bit smart in a way where,
you know,
whether you name these things are not,
there's always a particular standard that
you go by. You know, so just like the,
like the difference between killing
someone and when someone says murder,
you know, murderer is, uh,
is clearly defined. You know,
so if you murder someone,
like killing someone is this broad thing,
you killed him, accidentally killed him,
you killed him after planning, there's
a mill killed him, revenge and all that,
you know, that's killing someone.
But murder is defined, you know.
So while somebody asked me when I did
Tim Ferriss his second time and someone
asked me something along the lines
of, well, who defines these rules?
Which is basically what you just asked me.
And I think it actually,
there is an answer to who
defines these roles in warfare.
It's the law of armed conflict.
It's like the Geneva Convention.
We follow those laws right there.
They're very clearly defined what you
can and can't do. Boom. That's it.
Next question. Yeah. And I mean,
unless you straight up disagree with
the Geneva Convention, you know,
because of your personal moral code.
But as long as you have, again,
a standard that you're going by,
that will reduce the gray areas
by a lot and we'll be there.
But it's easy to operate in black and
white when you have standards and it won't
always be easy. But you
know, it's like, well let,
let me this,
this,
when we start getting the gray area
and you're sitting here saying,
I'm all black and white and that's an,
I'm actually saying that like, Hey,
once you cross this line, but guess what?
Those lines can get blurry too. Yeah,
that's what it was.
I heard about a guy that was on
a documentary who is, he was,
he was in a western journalist of some
kind and I got to watch this documentary.
I'm sure someone will tell us what it is,
but somebody else told me about it.
The Western journalist,
he's imbedded with insurgents in Iraq and
he's filming and they're going out and
attacking coalition
forces thing. Yeah, right.
And I guess he was, while
he's doing it, you know,
he's trying to get his
story and do his job,
but then all of a sudden they're
attacking coalition forces.
Right now there's a gray area.
Now let's say if you want to
take that example to the extreme,
if we're in a firefight and I see a guy
with a camera who's wearing of press
badge following in, in Third Gen, right?
I mean it ain't gonna work out good for
him because it's not like I'm going to
say, okay, well I, you know,
he's clearly is within surgeons,
but what I'm saying is that's,
that's one example of many that that you
could get into where also another thing
that happened in Iraq a lot was
people change sides and they went from
supporting the terrorist to supporting
the coalition and then back again and
then back again.
So how do you,
how do you balance those?
And I'll tell you how I balanced them
was how can we achieve our mission?
And that sounds like one of those, hey,
mission focus. But it's true. I look at,
okay, this guy, you know,
a year ago was being targeted by
coalition forces for being a bad guy.
Now
he has changed course,
so what am I supposed to do still
prosecute him or is he going to help us
achieve our mission of overall victory?
Guess what I'm gonna do,
I'm gonna cut him some moral
slack because we're going to win.
So those are hard things to,
that's exactly what it mean.
They'll see the standard.
The standard in your case
became the overall mission. Yes.
So you know,
you have that say it's not like just
some guy floating down the road through
life being like, Hey, I don't
feel good about that right
there, so I feel this way,
so I'm going to do it.
It's not that it's like there's a
standard very concrete attached to,
it's still gray areas gunny emerge.
But like I said,
it just reduces that gray area.
Yep. Standard in the bottom line is,
this is why leadership is hard.
Yes.
The whole idea of leadership,
whether it's in combat or whether it's
in the business world or whether it's
part of a team or whether it's part
of a family or whether it's in a
concentration camp or whether
it's in a prisoner of war.
Camp leadership is hard. There's gray
areas. Like when captain plumb was saying,
Hey, he got told in order, you know,
make communications with this
guy at all costs at all costs,
that means I'm going to get beaten and
tortured and died by the guards to get
this guy, this piece of communication. Is
he going to follow that? Gus Smart? No.
He had to make a judgment and say, you
know what? No, that doesn't make sense.
That doesn't make sense.
So this gray area that went outside the
bounds of the gray area and he said, Nah,
I'll do my best.
I understand that it's critical,
but I'm going to stay within
me staying alive. Right?
So that is what's makes leadership heart
is you have to constantly make these
decisions where there's they're gray
area and you're doing your best.
You're assessing. And that's, that's
again, to me it was always, I love that.
I love that about leadership.
I loved weighing those decisions out and
I love discussing them with my guys up
and down the chain of command and
saying, Hey, here's where we're at.
Let me tell you exactly where we're at.
You know,
I'll use Lafe Lafe here's what's going on.
This is the situation.
What do you think? Well, I think
this, okay, that's a good point.
But did you think about that? Ooh,
that's a good one. You know what I mean?
We're going to have those conversations
and I had never had any problem opening
my mind up to these various opinions that
people have. And I think as a leader,
that's a huge piece of building trust
up and down the chain of command is when
you have an open mind to
discuss things with people.
And that also double gravitational pull.
Echo Charles helps you
build the relationship,
helps you build the relationship and
helps you to say, oh, you know what,
like what's the minute I'm in
there? I'm talking, I'm like, hey,
how we got a gray area here?
You know,
we got a customer that is
threatening to put us on Yelp,
but we didn't do anything wrong. How
do you think we should handle it? Okay,
well you think we should just tell them,
go ahead and put it on Yelp.
We don't care, and we'll go to
Yelp and we'll talk to them.
That might be the good answer, but also
it might be good to say, Bro, wait,
why are you so mad, right? Customer, let's
talk that, hey, we want a refund. You,
we want to take care of you because
our customers are important to us.
Maybe you'll give us a positive thing
on you. You know what I'm saying?
There's all this gray area.
Yeah,
and if you have an open mind to discuss
things with your team team up and down
the chain of command, you know what
you'll do is you'll, you'll get to,
in that gray area, you'll start to get
clarity. You'll start to get clarity.
You'll start to see better and you can
move through the gray area without being,
without being so decisive that in a gray
area you don't know if it's black or
white. Right? Right. So if you decide
as the leader, I'm going black,
going black,
then when the gray area clears up,
it was white that you should have
gone with. You don't need to do that.
In many cases you can say, okay, I'm a
lean a little bit towards the black cause.
That's what I'm feeling.
And then all of a sudden
you started moving there and
you start seeing that, no,
this is going to be a white decision.
Yeah, okay, I can recover from that.
I can move backwards and and repair what
decision was made and the best way to
do that and say, hey guys,
here's the situation.
I thought that black was going
to be the right decision.
I started leaning in that direction.
I was wrong.
Now I see that white is the right
answer and we're going with white.
Does anyone have any questions about that?
Does everyone understand why I did
that? Oh, you don't understand why?
Let me explain it to you. Here's
what I thought. Here's what I saw.
Did you next time,
do you want me to contact you so you can,
that's what I'm talking about. And
by the way, when I'm doing that,
I'm building relationships with my team,
which is what I want to do.
I just was talking to a leader the
other day and I told him and reiterated
something,
I've said it over and over again,
but people that did things for me
and the teams that were in the army,
the Marine Corps in the
seal teams in my platoon,
up and down the chain of command,
doesn't matter.
99.9% of it wasn't because I had some
kind of rank or privileges over them.
And it was always because I had
a good relationship with people.
And when you build that good
relationship with people,
that's what it's all about. Then they
do things for you and you know what?
You do things for them too. It's not a
one way street that I'm talking about,
cause you won't build any relationships
if you're building a one way street.
Right? No one's going to
be your friend after you.
Just take advantage of
them over and over again.
Like those people that call you only
when they need something from you right
now.
I actually don't have a problem with
that cause I don't communicate with a lot
of people. Right. I,
I communicate on social media with a
boat with a bunch of different people.
He'll get you there.
But as far as like when one of my
buddies called me up and says, Hey,
I need this favor. I'm like, cool on it.
I haven't talked to him for nine months.
He's only calling me because he needs
something from me. It doesn't matter.
And people do that with me
all the time and it's cool.
Now this isn't a big group of people.
It was like six people in the
world and those same six people,
they don't call to wish me happy birthday.
Don't call and tell me, you know, uh,
merry Christmas. They call me up and say,
Hey, I need this from you. Can you do it?
And I'm like,
God,
no factor that you even have a birthday
negative. I haven't manufacturing date.
So funny like
I'm just trying to imagine someone
calling you to wish you happy birthday.
I mean maybe like your wife or was it
awkward when I got in the civilian sector
and people be like when's your birthday?
And I'd be like, why one? Yeah.
What do you,
what are you talking about?
Why are you trying to get my
personal information or attack you?
He would sign or you know,
you know the uh,
what was the other funny
thing about the birthday deal?
Well that's like getting presence.
I'm not good with presence. Yeah man.
Like don't get me any presence cause
I don't want what you got me. Yeah.
If I want something I already
have it. Get it. Yeah.
So what you got me isn't
going to be appreciated.
There's a one gift that my wife
got me one time and I haven't,
I've been thinking about why
haven't talked about this
particular hole situation
and that's, there's a band
called the white stripes. Sure.
Lights and the white stripes.
Jack White, meg white.
The white stripes are awesome.
They're awesome band.
And there's so many layers with the white
stripes. Yes. First of all, there's,
I'll tell you two layers that I love
about the white stripes. Number one,
all their clothing, guitars, drums,
keyboards,
everything that they have on stage and
everything that they have on their record
albums. Everything that they
have is either red, black,
or white on all the records. Since day
one, that's number one. Number two,
they only have free sounds in any
of their songs at any one time.
Hmm. So those three sounds
could be drums, vocals, guitar.
They could be drums, keyboards,
vocals. They could be keyboards,
guitar, vocals. But they only
have three sounds at any one time.
Vocals is one of the things
is one of those tanks.
There's only two and there's only
two people in the band. Anyways,
the white stripes is awesome band.
And my wife bought me tickets
to go see the white stripes.
Now I didn't even think about,
I never pay attention to when bands are
playing and whatever. So I was, I was,
I don't use this term very often,
but I was overjoyed that she got
me tickets to the white stripes.
I was so stoked.
And then meg white had some issues and
they canceled the whole tour and they
never played again.
And we're like a little couple of weeks
away from being in San Diego where I was
going to go see the white stripes.
So the question is ultimately ultimately
the grand scheme of things and with
that a good gift to give Jocko.
That was an awesome gift to give me.
Still the it was it the thought that
counts in this case it was a beautiful got
me and I was and I couldn't
believe she thought of it. Yeah.
Cause normally it's like, oh you got me
a sweater from some store that I hate.
No,
I'm really hard to shop for if I want
something I have it and I don't want that
much. So I was like, oh I want something.
I have it once every 18 months I
want something and then I get it.
Yeah. I'll get you like a new tee
shirt or something. You wear that?
Well this tee shirts, fine. Don't get
me a new one. This one works good.
Mm hmm.
So yeah.
Yeah.
It seems like
we just went off on a tangent. I feel
like you went off on a tangent, you know.
You know why?
Cause I was listening to the white
stripes the other day and I was thinking,
I never give the white stripes the
props that they deserve. And Jack White,
the props that he deserves
as a singer songwriter.
I don't think brother and sister, they're
not allegedly legend husband, wife.
They got divorced, but they always
claim to be brother, sister,
my little sister meg white more later.
No, this is my big sister. That's right.
Yeah.
That's what he always said.
Dang. That's good man. Cool.
Well the original point was
these crazy savage type people,
maybe normal people other
than their crazy job. Yeah.
And what's, and I'm, but I'm
not saying so. It's cool.
And this is you're, you're, you're
accountable for your actions. Yeah.
Regardless of how cool you are.
And that's something from any leadership
position you need to be aware of.
And when I say new leadership position,
I mean you as a frontline trooper because
if you as a frontline troopers getting
told to do something that you know is
morally, ethically or legally wrong,
and you still do it,
it's on you sure you can point the finger
and blame the higher ups in the higher
ups would be burned to if they told
you to do something that was wrong,
but you need to be accountable for what
you did and that's all there is to it.
Yeah. Okay. It's a rough tour.
No one wants to play that game.
The Nazis wanted to play that game off,
not mine. Hey, I was ordered to do this.
You can't do that. Can't say that. Don't
get that excuse. You don't get the,
I was a good person and I took care of
my kids even though I was shoving people
into, into a gas chamber. You
don't get to play that game.
No. Yeah man, it's too much.
But there's a small little
documentary on the line. I don't know.
I didn't watch the whole thing,
but it was about the executioner in the
Middle East somewhere in one of these
countries where you know, he has his
sword and it's his job, you know,
and he's a straight up executioner.
Yeah. That's it. That's just his job.
Modern Day job. And he's
like, yeah, yeah, it was,
it wasn't an old school you don't see
on Youtube. Yeah. Like last week. Yeah.
But it's like, it's funny cause
the whole feel of the document,
she was just real like, oh
yeah, this guy has a cool job.
And he's like slicing people's heads off
with great precision and he's so good
at his job, you know, lit here's his
family and they're loving, you know,
and they're, you know,
he's playing with his kids.
It's like all this stuff's just weird man.
Anyway, there's those another culture.
It's weird. A lot of gray areas
and Allen to my man indeed.
Kind of anyway or not.
I feel like we should go into the support.
Yeah,
we should go into the sun.
Porch support is one of those good things.
Very dynamic. Supporting
others, supporting yourself,
supporting others and yourself, which is
a separate category. Support my opinion.
So there's yourself, others and yourself
and others. That's another category.
Want to talk about on it.
We're talking about all three categories.
Support Yourself.
But when a supplementation,
and we talk about supplementation
all the time, but you know,
you talk about supplementation will,
you're the one who turned
it turned me onto it.
So actually some of it I took shroom
tech before you talked to before.
Pre podcast pretty podcast
sells on shroom tech. Um,
I was on Alpha brain shroom tech.
I got my shipment of
Alpha brain pills back in.
I had run out then I only had the instant.
And so now like I said,
what's Nice about the pilsner is
you got something come to good.
Come and do the podcast.
Yes.
What Alpha brain pills and I might double
up on the Alpha brain if I think I got
to really get my get engaged. But
it's good to have the, the capsules.
Yes. Well, I dig it. But what's cool about
the drink is it tastes good at, and I,
if you get the sweet tooth itch going
and you want something sweet and you get
the peach. Yeah, the natural peach,
not the spicy spicy has a
different situation going on.
So the peaches just straight up like
tasty, like peach. Yeah, peach juice,
peach juice kind of situation. Yeah, kind
of like that. Agree. I dig it. The pills,
I dig it. And that's actually
what we had with the pills.
I said a week because me and my brother,
we were awful brain.
But when they came out with an incident
that was better and it starts to become
like this little kind of ritual, you know,
eat makes up your Alpha brain, you know,
kind of thing. And it's
instant. I don't know,
just seems like either way it doesn't
matter if I haven't mentioned it already.
I think I did.
These are supplements from on it
on a.com there'll be, we talked about the
supplements, but there's like workouts.
I just bought a jump
rope. Did you? Yeah. See.
So when I was young I was good at Java.
Going to be being a Joe jump rope too.
Yeah. And then as a, you know,
as I think kind of when, when,
I dunno, maybe early twenties kind of
stopped. So that's a long time ago.
Jump Rope is awesome. Yeah. So as,
and you know, you know how like,
like riding a bike, he couldn't stay good
at something a little bit. You're rusty,
you're rusty. Yeah,
definitely. Gonna be rusty.
You can't shred and you can go as long,
you know, like that kind of stuff.
It's weird cause it, you know how
to jump rope. Yeah. You know what,
you were just back in the day of boxing,
boxing, jumping rope for three minutes.
It was like no factor. Yeah. Go
junk blurb. Five, 10 minute warm up.
Go get your jump right out, get out, get
out, get out three minutes on the rounds.
We feel it. Yeah. So yeah, I
bought one of those and it's,
so the interesting thing about that is
jump rope technology has changed a little
bit. So what is it made of?
Steel? No. Well there's, I'm
sure the steel in there so,
but it's like each handle has a swivel,
the little simple,
but this is like way
more to it than before.
Last time it was like two wooden handles
and our rope for sure. Actual real.
This one is like a cord that survives
all of this stuff. I don't know. Anyway,
I've got to jump rope. Jump Rope is on
there if you want. Well the jump off.
Yeah, I was pretty good too. Hey,
remember when like when you
jump rope and then when the,
you know how like this was like elementary
school and if you'd get tired or you
couldn't keep her rhythm, they'd say,
Hey, just just wave it from birth.
You know what I mean? Yeah. Uh,
what's it called when you turn it to
Tara? Tara, when you boom, like I'd like a
matador,
isn't it called matador when you just
go side to side because you can't get it
or whatever. Yeah. I just get that rhythm
going. Oh yeah. I don't know the name.
I never had to do that cause I was
expert level even in elementary school.
But that's Mac.
That's going to be you.
If in fact you want to step up
so you can get that on on it.
Not just if you want kettle bells
on there too. The good kind.
Well, kettlebells are good. Straight up.
They're all good and but on it has those
artistic ones because even those add
another layer,
but they have the regular one,
I think they're called the competition
ones. Don't quote him. Yeah. Oh yeah.
So yeah, you get the legend bells,
which is like what? The cyclops,
the Werewolf, I look at them,
they're, they're dope primal bells,
which is like all the primates and stuff.
I think I got the chimp to
chimps in two werewolves.
See I have, I have Zombie bells.
Mine are just evil zombies.
How big is the one? You know? I forgot.
I got to look. Yeah, that's like,
it's like designer Yuki
probably keep it inside too.
You really do know.
The one that I keep inside is not the
ones in my garage or for the long heavy
work. This one is for, oh, I'm
tired of writing right now.
I'm going to bang out some
snatches. Right, right. Boom, boom.
God feel a lot better now.
Right. More harder. There you go.
But yeah, this is anyway,
the point there is,
there's very cool things on the website,
on it.com and the supplements,
it's not to mention this,
the fact is the supplements
are straight up,
the best ones straight up because
from the beginning and how has this,
and I dunno if we already mentioned this,
but I hear it.
Joe Rogan talks about all
the time how namedrop Yep.
I listen to Joe Rogan all the time and
he says these things and I believe him.
Um, if you get like, I dunno, shrink tech
and you're like, hey, I didn't feel it.
I got tapped out. So you know, I
expect more out of stream tech.
I expect this to make me
tap out everybody. I don't
like it. Send it back. No,
you don't even send it back. You
send them an email saying, hey,
I don't like this stuff.
They'll just send your money back.
You don't even have to send it back.
That's pretty awesome then. Yup.
But don't be trying to be like,
I'm going to give me my money back and
the next month after you're done with it,
order some more and then do it again.
Yeah,
you're going to get
ostracized nonetheless. Um,
Krill oil, that's the one.
You don't want to not have krill oil.
Even if you're like a young guy,
in my opinion,
we should,
I should always been on Krill oil
and if you're not in Krill oil,
I think you are like a
step behind joint wise,
which puts you behind it around a few
different ways. A lot of different ways.
Yeah. You get an hour working out as
hard. And I was working on this hard, uh,
struggling through various activities
in everyday life. I told the story,
whatever, but I do it
all the time. You know,
when you fill up water in the
big five gallon jugs, you know,
and Brett do that at night when
it's kind of cold. It's like bright.
You can carry those things
from the thing to your car.
You don't want to be worried
about my knees or whatever.
You're back on the trials and
he's got to put it in there, Bro.
You think I'm going to write your own
book, Dude. What about like the truck?
That kind of crazy trials you've been
through caring warm on a cool night in
southern California.
Very fresh.
Pure water by the way,
doesn't make it any lighter though.
You still have to struggle, right?
Here's the thing. No, there are micro,
they're critical.
They're called micro struggles is
really what they are standing in line.
Actually the sending in line thing,
that's not a struggle.
That's manufactured struggle,
so it's like an exercise in discipline
and embracing struggle. That's what it is.
It's not an actual struggle bestowed
upon your heaped on your shoulders.
You know that you have
to bear in everyday life.
That's not what's the standing in line.
That's why you need your little
book about echoes struggles. Right,
and you can document these various me
looking for a specific wine wine section.
We've got a tomato sauce
struggle.
The wives struggle the groceries. Now
we've got to fill in the water bottles.
There's four chapters.
Micro struggle and filling up the water
is not a struggle because I'm on the
Krill oil. Oh Omega threes fright into
my joint straight into my joints. Uptake,
high percentage uptake.
Anyway, get on the Krill oil.
I'm on the strong bone now too by the way
for that's for tendons.
The tendon attaching to the bone.
Strontium does need about it does it?
I feel really good about it actually.
More PR preventative cause like cause
I lift nonetheless strontium that's in
strong bone that get doesn't,
that doesn't hit the like the
limelight isn't on that all the time.
It's all on calcium. Most of the time
like calcium makes your bones strong.
Strontium just as much.
So we get on this trombone,
a bone strength also off of brain.
Obviously shroom tech for high,
high performance. Go on the website.
Whatever you need.
They got it.
They even got like try blend
peanut butter nut butter.
It's not peanut butter. It's like all
almond cashew and walnut. Don't know.
Anyway,
it's delish get on now anyway.
[inaudible] dot com slash Jocko if
you want 10% off pay full price,
that's all that's up to you. Really.
You know what I'm saying? Hmm.
I wouldn't recommend it. I don't even
know of anyone who would recommend that.
Awesome.
Also good way to support if
you're interested in the book,
man's search for meaning Viktor Frankl.
What I've done is I put on the
website a page with all of the books,
all of them that Jocko is covered.
Every once in a while Jack will
cover an article that the links,
maybe I'll do that, but nonetheless the
books are all on their all in order to,
by the way, so the most recent
is going to be at the top.
This one will be on there. It is on there.
Do you want to support? Click on there.
If you're going to get the book,
Click through their directs,
you straight to Amazon. What if
you're doing other shopping? Amen.
Go ahead and do the same thing.
Click on it.
We have a banner on the front page too
and then you can click on there. Yeah,
and then you can do shopping. Yeah. If
you want. That sounds like a good plan.
Even if you're buying duct tape
also,
do you have a link to your favorite
duck tape on there? Dang. I don't know.
Sometimes I say things that are just so
inherently brilliant. It makes me wonder.
So we will have a duct tape
link link for sure. Yeah.
Just in case everyone needs duct tape
and they especially need it when they get
done,
listen to the podcast or they're thinking
about the things that they're going to
be duct taping together
yet. So yeah, that's true.
You know why I mentioned duct
tape in the beginning and I,
I didn't really realize it because they
didn't think about it until a handful of
people asked me, you know, why? Why? Cause
I used to watch macgyver all the time.
Actually I still watch
macgyver. No, no, no.
It's on a channel called clue
c l o random random channel.
It's like a retro channel
kind of. Okay. For a man.
Well, there's a new macgyver, by
the way. A new one. It was, it lame.
I don't think it's as good as the old one,
but it could be just my,
you know how you get attached to your
old shows. It could be that, but look,
everyone was dope back in the day so you
know, whichever, and that was his thing.
Duct tape people. People
like to say, Ooh, paper clip.
Right macgyver with the paper. He,
I, he never really had a paperclip.
He had duct tape. That was his thing
and Swiss army knife TV I play.
That's on you and I, I dig
it, but I was busy getting,
after he had the Swiss army knife and
the duct tape, that was his thing.
Everything else he just founded
in its environment is environment,
which which changed from
episode to episode. Nonetheless,
subscribed to the podcast on
iTunes, stitcher, Google play,
all these platforms that provide a
podcast. We're on all of them. Boom.
Subscribe, which are when you use, even
if you use too, I guess, right? That'd be,
do people use to platform?
Why did I do that?
There's some reason I had to
go to a different platform,
so I have a backup platform. Boom.
Subscribed to boat. Yeah, right.
Is that kind of like Youtube and Vimeo?
You know,
some guys will have a Vimeo account as
well. I don't know why that got escalated.
You too bad. I'll tell you
what. Well, I don't know why,
but this could be the reason
why cause youtube kids.
Vimeo is kind of for for like professional
people who fancy themselves as like
film makers.
Like here's my piece that I've made in
her artists tends to be that youtube is
just like guys, Utah kind of that
too. But overall. Yeah, exactly right.
Just throw my video to youtube,
like you know the tube TV to you,
whatever you are. Vimeo is, I don't know
the name. I guess I could think about it,
but nonetheless, that's what it
shook itself out to beaten, you know?
So it's funny when people were like,
I'm not on Youtube, I'm on Vimeo.
Do you,
do you have to do anything to be on Vimeo
or you're just still the same thing?
Same exact thing.
It's exactly like youtube,
except for the fact which
now that I'm thinking about,
it makes sense where if you upload
a video and you're like, oh man,
in one of these titles, midway
through the video, I spelt it wrong,
which happens to me.
Sometimes you can go back into your
account and to replace the video.
Even if it's been up for a week, you can
just replay or youtube, Vimeo, youtube,
you cannot, yes, a new video. Yeah.
It's like you got to upload
again and here's the thing.
You can't upload the same file. Got to
rename as youtube. No, you've got to read.
It'll, it has all these little little
information in the file. There'll be like,
hey, that's a duplicate file.
You can't do that. You know?
Probably had something to do with the
advertising. I Dunno. Nonetheless,
subscribe to Jocko podcasts on Youtube.
If you like that channel. We're trying
to provide what you call providing value.
You know, that's, don't own.
Say that uncle, that's another,
it sounded cool when I first heard it,
but that's another,
that's another one of those things
where it sounded cool and then everyone
thought like me or I think
like everyone else, whatever.
And so everyone started using it.
Now it's like people are
abusing it and move here.
Just trying to provide value and it just,
you know,
it starts to sound voice you just
threw out there and there's only,
I don't do voices other than escalation
thinks Jocko. Anyway,
so subscribe to Youtube.
We're trying to provide some value there
with the excerpts and various other
clips aside from the video
version of this podcast.
Your Memorial Day one was really good man.
I liked it and it was a
powerful, powerful letter. Yeah.
Bunch of other stuff.
I'm like,
Jocko has the store,
it's called Jocko store.
If you didn't already know Jacqueline,
store.com. What do we have on Draka store?
We have t shirts.
If [inaudible] also has a podcast
called Jocko Jocko white tea.
It's called Jocko white tea.
I think I see a trend here.
The trend is real for
sure. Um, nonetheless,
the shirts of originality
in name will know me things.
So in a way,
because here there are layers in that too,
and there is sophistication to that.
Even though it seems simple. Oh,
because there I was being sophisticated.
You aren't being somebody out.
There's more to than just [inaudible].
There just happens to be my name.
There's two, there's more to that goes
beyond this podcast beyond the TV. Okay.
So just, let's just start with that
fact, which is complex in and of itself.
Then you're like,
okay,
this is what roughly considered
a company technically,
maybe. I guess if you had to,
if you had to ask me today,
what do I do for a living?
And I was like, I was like,
oh, just like stuff. And he goes,
well what would you, how would you,
what did he say? He said,
well how would you describe
what you do? And I said, stay busy.
That's what I do is okay, fair
enough. Yeah, there you go.
But technically cause Baras Dang,
I haven't heard that one in a all cool.
Jocko podcast.com. That's an entity,
we'll call it an entity. I Dunno,
company business.
It's a place where we have the web
snuff nonetheless. Oh, you know what?
I'm going to go ahead and out on a
limb and call it a brand, brand, dish,
whatever. Nonetheless, if you
call. Okay, well Jocko store,
that's the name of the store. Well,
that's true. And to be honest with you,
the reason that I called the podcast
Jocko podcasts when I was on Tim Ferriss's
podcast, I said, Jocko hungry. And I don't
even know. I don't know if I'd just said,
I don't know if it's all in
the podcast or not, but he,
I think he said something like, Oh, you
know, we've got to go get some food.
And I was like, Jocko hungry.
And then I was like, well,
we're going to do a podcast record Jocko
podcasts. That was the initial fought.
There's the layer. Makes Sense. Yeah.
And that's even with
naming the other worries,
I wanted to be able to do whatever
I wanted to do and not care. Yeah,
and that makes sense.
I knew we're going to talk about Jujitsu
and fighting and music and an hardcore
and war and death.
And I just wanted to not
have any limitations.
And the only way I could do that, because
if you can give the podcast a name,
like you know,
the ultimate of this podcast,
you know, it's like, okay,
well then next thing you
know we're talking about war
and or if you call it the
war podcast,
but you're talking about business or if
you talk and talk about the leadership
podcast,
but you're talking about Jujitsu.
So how do you get all those things into
one thing called the Jocko podcast and I
can do whatever I want. Yeah, there you
go. And if people are looking for you,
they see you talk about x, Y,Z , and
they're like, I sure I can look on that.
Easy connection.
Yeah. And it's simple, which is like, you
know, simplicity goes a long way. Yeah.
You know, and that's kind of like a
thing. So why are we talking about this?
I'm just saying that's why it's called
Jacques Cousteau. Yeah, that's right.
So because it is a store,
people want to do other things in their
life besides listen to our own guys.
Well you're the one chime in him and
I'm over here trying to talk about the
north side.
The other day when we had Roger Hayden
on and I gave you the silent treatment
and, and when you looked at me for
affirmation while you were given the
advertising's, I didn't even nod.
I just looked at you and you got,
you actually got uncomfortable.
You actually got uncomfortable.
You were like Amy,
you,
you look on your face like where you'd
look at me like I was going to give you a
smile. I know. I'd just look at you like
hurry up and then you got uncomfortable.
And I said, well he's, he's starting
to feel it. You gave me no mercy. Yeah.
That's like subtle. Sure. Nah
Man, it's all good. You know?
So do that again right now.
You know,
so I can talk about this store Jocko store
Jocko, store.com if you like t shirts.
No, I'm not saying if you
like tee shirts in general,
I'm just saying if you want to represent
discipline equals freedom. What?
Get after it. No, the darkness. No,
that darkness. That's a
good one. Anyway, go on.
List or jumpstart a column. You can
see shirts if you like him. Go ahead.
Get one support that way. That's a good
one. I've got some rash guards on there.
One new rash guard out already says get
after it on it. Discipline on one sleeve.
Freedom on the other sleeve.
Jocko approved. Really good. Um,
I think it's good.
I feel that the people
who have witnessed it
is that pump has to say witnessed it.
Like there's some kind of a little bit
anyone that's witnessed my rash guard
said I bestowed upon them by way of visual
people that call. How about people that
saw it? Thought it was a pretty cool,
it was cool. They thought was realistic.
They thought it was cool. And um,
so there it is. You go in the story,
you look at it. If you think it's cool,
you want to get to witness the glory
of Echo. Charles is rash guards.
You may go to Jocko,
store.com and revel in the glory.
Exactly right and whatever else you
want this some good stuff on there.
We added this little thing too.
If we're out and I'm trying to be like,
I'm trying to restock, restock, boom.
But I added this little thing where if
like let's say size medium or whatever is
out, it just says, oh little button,
notify me book, put your email,
boom notifies you when it's back in stock.
And again,
I'm trying to put them back in, stock
it asap. Boom, boom, boom right now.
But you know, give me a day or two
or whatever. We'll notify you. Boom.
Also psychological warfare,
if you didn't know what that is,
it's an album which tracks cop.
I'm not music tracks,
word track scent, like
spoken word, you know.
So basically what it's for is,
you know, it's not like poetry,
well arguably not poetry but stuck
on there talking, talking to eat us.
To me,
Jack was talking to me that I actually
quite literally was talking to you when
that was made. Exactly right. So you
know you can help and talk to you. Well,
so basically what it's for is he's
not just talking like everyday stuff,
so when you have hard time waking up
in the morning or you have a hard time
because you're tired and you want to
skip the workout or you have a hard time
because it's lunch time and I'm all
hungry and all they have is doughnuts here
or whatever. What, what else
are you procrastinating?
Also if you're procrastinating or what
do you call it, ending the podcast.
Maybe you could listen
to that one right now.
I'm trying to explain
this thoroughly so that,
so we can all have a really good
understanding of what it is and its value.
That's,
that's it's downloading important me
talking about moments of weakness so you
can get through them. Yeah.
Next, next comment. Yeah,
I guess, let me add this
one more thing. Actually,
you can even take it at moments of triumph
end strength. Oh, and it'll still work.
You'll just want to do
it more, you know? Yeah.
It's like drinking coffee when you're
not tired. You know what I mean? Yeah.
Double Down,
let that sink in.
Psychological warfare on I tunes, Amazon
Music, all these music, Google play,
Google play. I think the, I think it's
on everything. Cool, but yeah, man.
Right on. All right. I'll see.
You can get Jocko white tea on Amazon
and when you order Jocko white tea,
make sure you also order more weights
for your barbells because you're dead.
Lift is going to go up to
approximately 8,000 lbs,
so you need to get that much
weights when you order it.
Weigh the warrior kid book.
It's been out for a couple of weeks
now and thank you for getting it.
Also little warning that someone
put on Amazon in their review.
I thought it was worth hearing and
thinking about parents be ready.
I bought this book after listening to
Jocko on the Joe Rogan podcast where Jocko
was the guest.
Great podcast,
bought the book after Learning
Jocko has a book for kids.
My son who isn't very motivated yet,
was excited about the book when
he started reading the book,
a fire lit underneath
him. He said to me, Dad,
I'm going to get up tomorrow at 5:00 AM,
will you get up with me?
And that moment I realized
that I was what I was going,
what was going on and I
couldn't let him down.
I enjoy my sleep like everyone else,
but I was amazed that my son got excited.
So are applied? Yes, let's do it.
Got Up at 5:00 AM and his alarm
clock must not have gone off,
but I turned on his light in
his bedroom and he got right up.
He got his clothes and shoes
on and we went for a jog.
We've never done this before.
I had him do some sit and
pushups after and he gladly did.
Couldn't quite do pushups if that's
okay, we'll get there. Long Story Short,
this book only being a few chapters and
the only a few chapters in that was kind
of surprised when I saw that only a few
chapters in made the book worth getting
in this day and age of
electronics and iPads and tablets.
Kids don't seem to be as motivated
to do activities as when I was a kid.
I'm 39 so I edified him after for making
the decision to get up at 5:00 AM on a
non school day and I told him that he
can apply that mentality to anything in
life. Boom, way the war your kid.
Get it for your kid to be prepared
to get yourself back in the game.
Also,
discipline equals freedom field manual,
the instructional manual
for getting after it.
Feel free to preorder that one. Also,
extreme ownership, combat leadership,
combat leadership and
also combat leadership.
That's what the book is about,
how to apply the fundamental principles
of combat leadership to your business
and to your life.
Also for more hands on experience,
you can call Ashkelon Front our leadership
and management consulting company,
myself, Leif Babin, JP Denell, Dave Burke,
you can contact us@infoatechelonfront.com.
Also the Muster Austin,
Texas,
July 13th and 14th at the Omni
Barton Creek resort. No fluff.
Okay.
No,
there's no fluff.
Just pragmatic information
you can act on immediately.
You can literally in a break,
email your team and give instructions
that's going to move them in the right
direction. In the Austin
Monster, there's only 300 seats,
smaller venue
it's going to sell out.
Okay,
so get online,
get registered.
If you can't make it to that one
to come to San Diego in September,
September 14th and 15th from muster zero
zero four will be there live and while
you're waiting for the monster,
if you need to communicate with us,
you can find us on the interwebs,
on Twitter or on Instagram,
on death. Facey ball high
echo is at echocharles and I am at Jocko
Willink and to the military personnel
out there holding the line in places.
No one wants to be doing things
that no one else wants to do.
Thanks for keeping US free to police
law enforcement, firefighters,
EMT,
and other first responders.
Thanks for keeping us safe.
Okay,
and for everyone else out there.
Yeah.
Remember,
remember what human are
capable of suffering through
and remember that even in
those situations,
okay,
where everything seems to be taken away,
when you seem to have no
choice at all in the world,
remember,
remember that you can still choose how
you react to the things around you.
You can still choose your attitude
and you can still choose to
actualize the best person
that you can be.
Okay?
In every aspect of your life,
you can choose
to get after it.
So until next time,
this is echo and Jocko
out.