Imagine. Imagine what Eugene Sledge
that we talked about tonight.
Imagine what he went through on Pella
in the tens of thousands of marines
that suffered debt, unimaginable horror
in any imagined Hackworth
who we talked about here,
who wrote about face assaulting
enemy positions in Korea.
And he was wounded over and over again
and all in the line and still went back
for more.
And then you got Alan Seeger, the poet
who in World War One went over the
top over and over again to make his
rendezvous with death.
And there's been thousands and hundreds,
thousands,
millions of warriors that have been in
very stressful situations and faced evil
and face death much
worse than the situation
I'm in or urine that we
might consider stressful.
And I even did this when I was
overseas, when I was on deployment,
when I was a combat leader,
I was feeling stress.
And you know what? We took casualties and
it was awful and it was heartbreaking,
but there were other soldiers and warriors
throughout time that had been in much
worse situations.
Gettysburg or Vicksburg
or the battle, the bowls.
Okay.
In, in all those horrible situations,
they prove really that humans can
withstand almost lost unimaginable stress,
which meant to me that I could too.
And you can't. And,
and the first step for me is doing that,
taking that look to gain some perspective.
And then in order to gain perspective,
you got to do something that we already
talked about. You've got to detach.
You've got to detach from the problems
or the stress that you're experiencing
so that you can get that
perspective of them.
Now
there's a couple of different
types of stress. Now,
if it's something that you can
control that's causing you stress,
well why aren't you getting control of it?
Generally it's a lack of discipline.
So you got to have the discipline
to grab control and make it happen.
And when I say you need
discipline for that,
what that means is these
stresses that you're avoiding,
they're not going to go
away if you avoid them.
So take the discipline to face the
stressful situation. Get ahead of it.
Don't be afraid of it. Now,
there's also stress that's caused
by things that you cannot control.
And if you remember talking earlier
about artillery and how horrible that was
and what made it so horrible was
that there was no control over.
So if you can't control something
and you can't get control of it,
yeah,
I have to at least embrace
what you can and not,
and I'm not saying you're going
to embrace artillery shelling,
but I'll tell you what,
when it comes to things like artillery
or for us in Ramadi was ids and we could
do everything we could
do to mitigate that risk.
But eventually there's only so much
you can do and you cannot completely
eliminate it, but you can't control
it. So why you going to worry about it?
Why you going to stress about it?
If there's something that's completely
beyond your control, you cannot.
You've got to detach from it and not
let yourself get stressed about it.
And on top of that,
if it's something that you can't control,
how can you look at it
in a different light?
How can you see it in a way that you
could actually take advantage of it?
How can you take
that stress and make it into
some kind of ally? You know, the,
the chaos of combat is something
that I couldn't control,
but I had to embrace it so I could try
and figure out how to take advantage of
it. So when it comes to stress,
don't fight it,
turn it on itself and use it. Use it.
Use it to make yourself sharper and more
alert and use it to make yourself think
more in, learn more, and get better.
And use that stress
as a catalyst to make yourself better.