This is Jocko podcast number
92 with Echo Charles and me,
Jocko Willink. Good
Evening Echo. Good evening.
The concept of finding an
IED is relatively simple.
It is essentially identifying what doesn't
belong in the natural area in front
of you before one proceeds. However,
one must ensure that all of the marines
with them or at a safe distance such
that if the searcher unintentionally
detonate an IED during his investigation,
the marines he is with will not be harmed.
The first step is to take a good look
at where you are and where are you
planning to go identify anything
that looks out of the ordinary.
With respect to nature,
the world naturally doesn't often
have patterns or perfect shapes.
Essentially you are looking for areas
where you suspect man has been in contact
with nature.
When one patrols in the same area,
frequently one can establish a baseline
observation for what to look for and
what the area looks like normally.
Thus on subsequent visits,
it is possible to identify
elements that are out of place.
The next step is to investigate the
route that you have chosen through this
danger area.
The three main tools used for this
investigation are the eyeballs,
a metal detector and to cutting edge
digging device called the human hand
proceeding slowly in a forward direction.
One swings the metal detector in a fashion
that covers every square inch of the
chosen route.
In order to do this,
start with a metal detector
to one side of the route.
Okay
and move it straight
across to the other side,
keeping the search head an inch or
two above and parallel to the ground.
Once it is a cross,
move the detector forward half the length
of the search head and swing it in the
opposite direction to the
original side of the route.
This is a process that continues for
the entirety of your time moving through
the danger area.
At some point during your
movement along this route,
you will want to investigate certain
spots that you think may contain an IED.
You can be alerted to these spots in
multiple ways from your early assessment
before proceeding through the area,
newly acquired suspicions as you move
through the area and also from sounds that
your metal detector makes
the process of swinging the metal detector
back and forth and inching forward is
time consuming.
The best of the best are the ones that
can optimize safety and keep time spent
to a minimum. It is
always better. However,
to err on the side of caution,
except in the most extreme of emergencies,
the investigation of a suspicious area
must proceed with extreme caution.
You start by kneeling down,
being sure to be well balanced and stable.
You must ensure that no gear is going
to accidentally fall off or slip out and
touch the ground.
You reach out with your fingers and with
the gentleness of a butterfly landing
on a daisy,
move the dirt in front of the
front edge of the metal hit.
Proceed forward a nanometer
at a time in this fashion,
uncovering more dirt over a wider space
until you either find the metal that set
off the detector or you are satisfied
that there is no danger from this
particular metal hit.
If metal is found,
the area must be rechecked to ensure
that the metal was found was not a decoy.
One may think that the tension during
this time is akin to being Tom cruise
dangling inches above
a motion sensor floor,
but the necessity of having a clear
mind and the amount of practice that has
gone into this exact process makes
it seem second nature and ordinary.
After you are satisfied that you
have cleared this suspicious area,
proceed forward
as you move forward.
You are also proofing the lane.
That thing proofing the lane or confirming
that is free from IED is usually done
with a special mechanical device
but it is now being done with your feet
and don't forget as you go forward to
lay down markers for everyone else who
comes behind you to follow.
This is the way that I handled
the situation I was now in.
I inched forward with my metal detector.
I didn't see anything
special about the area.
My metal detector was making noises,
but nothing large enough that I thought
at warranty did an investigation.
The marines in our patrol
watched and waited.
As I cleared and proofed the lane,
then it all went black.
No,
that description
is about as good as I have read about
the act of searching for IED. Yes.
I actually never searched for
IED in that type of method.
And of course in Ramadi everyone
was always searching Fridays you,
you were always looking,
you inspecting.
We were suspicious of
every pile of rubble,
every piece of junk on the road,
every off colored piece of dirt
or pavement or concrete or sand.
But we were in the city
and there was pedestrian
traffic and most of the eds,
we're targeting vehicles,
not foot patrols,
but whether
in a vehicle or on foot.
The IUD for the most part has been the
biggest threat and the biggest cause of
casualties in our recent wars.
And for the enemy,
it's a low risk,
high reward weapon.
And for us it's an evil weapon.
It's a cowardly weapon and
it is an effective weapon.
It's a weapon that plants
itself in your mind
always there.
Yeah.
Waiting
around that corner under that curb
on the other side of that sidewalk,
it's waiting.
Now
there are those whose job it is
to actually interdict that weapon,
the,
the IED.
It is their job to face that fear up
close and personal day in and day out.
You've got EOD explosive ordinance
disposal is one group that does it.
Complete professionals and
the EOD technicians that I
deployed with in the seal
teams were just outstanding
in everything that they did,
which by the way was not
only find in disarm IED,
they also did everything that we did.
They'd cleared rooms and patrol through
the streets and maneuvered in firefights
just as the seals did.
They were awesome.
And in addition to EOD
combat engineers in the army and the
Marine Corps also do mine clearance.
And of course I talk about
combat engineers a lot.
Okay.
Because of the incredible role that they
played in the battle of Ramadi and the
combat engineers were outstanding in
their standard job of building combat
outposts.
And building and maintaining the,
the infrastructure of the bases.
And they were,
they were awesome in that
performance under fire.
But at some point
the combat engineers job morphed into
mine clearance and it's because I would
suspect, you know, they
work with demolitions. So,
so combat engineers do
breaches two doors into walls,
they build bridges,
roads and bridges and they also clear
obstacles from roads and bridges.
And so eventually at some point this
morphed into combat engineers doing IED
clearance both on roads and
then out on foot patrols.
Now
there's jobs in the world
that I wouldn't want to do
and this is one of them.
It takes a massive amount of patients.
Yeah.
It takes an incredible amount of skill
and it takes an incredible ability to
overcome fear to,
if you're going to actually
seek out and touch the thing,
the very thing that is trying
to kill you in order to stop it.
Yeah,
that's a job that I didn't
want then and I don't want now.
And I am thankful that there was others
that stepped up and did that job.
And I'm honored to have
on the podcasts tonight,
one of those
brave men,
a Marine Corps combat engineered who
served in Iraq and in Afghanistan.
And the guy by the way,
who wrote that opening description of
what it was like to go out and hunt
for ids.
Guy By the name of Mr Rob Jones.
Rob, welcome to the show. This is an,
this is an honor for me to be,
I just really appreciate,
appreciate you giving me the opportunity
to, to come on the show. All man,
trust me, the honors all, all
ours off a thousand percent.
You can't even argue with that
point. We won't let it happen. Uh,
give us just before we jump
into your Marine Corps career,
just give us a little pre marine corps
background on growing up and what that,
where that was and what it was like.
Can I answer your question about how it
combat engineers came to find it yet?
Please do.
So when you go to combat engineer school,
one of the things they teach you is
minefield and placement and defeat.
You do that, you use mine
detectors and metal detectors.
So I think that's the main reason that it,
uh,
I wonder at what point you think that
came from World War II? I don't know.
That's a good question because,
yeah, when I said it morphed into,
I was thinking like back,
it must have been sometime in World War
II where they said, okay, we're, we're,
we're gonna get over this river.
Okay.
So common engineer's going to get over
the river. Uh, we're going to, um,
secure this compound.
Okay.
We're going to secure the
compound or we're going to
rebuild this compound. Okay.
Well at some point they said, you know
what, what if there's mines there? Okay,
well we've got to get them cleared out.
Yeah.
So at some point they realize that you
can't build if you can't clear it, right?
Yeah. And you can't move if you
can't clear. So he's got to do it.
Somebody's got to do it.
And,
and they weren't able to slough
off that job on to somebody else,
which is what I,
what I would have been trying to do,
which is what I would have been
absolutely been trying to do. Like, Hey,
can we get somebody else to do that
jump? Uh, yeah. So that's good. So,
so how'd you end up with a Marine
Corps? Oh yeah. My background,
I grew up in on a farm. Uh, nothing
really special about my upbringing.
The side cut a farm that was a horse farm.
Um,
I hated horses because I have to pick
up this. What is, what do you do?
What is the purpose of our horse farm?
The farm that I grew up on,
the purpose of it was my parents would
take people on horseback riding trips,
pay them money, and they take him out
for a couple hours in the forest. Got It.
Got It. And so it was my duty
to clean up after the horses,
feed the horses, stack their hay bales
in the summertime, get them their water.
So I didn't really enjoy the horses
as much as most people would.
But uh,
you know,
I'm thankful that I had that experience
because I think it did instill in me a
work ethic that doesn't debt a
lot of people don't get. Yeah.
I think when you come from,
cause you know a lot of guys when they
come in the military that they've never
worked hard before.
But the guys I've met in the military
that came from some kind of a farming
background, they're like,
Hey, I'm so happy here.
I'm up at three in the morning,
you know,
milking cows or whatever,
or cleaning up horse shit.
In your case.
The number of times I had to wheel this
wheel barrel full of manure up a offense
board onto this big
pile. And the were times I fell off
that thing every time like this,
curse those horses,
I hated them so much.
Now I like horses fine that I don't
have gotten over. You're a horse PTSD
and so what you, you, you graduated
from high school and then you,
you went to college, right?
Yeah, I went to Virginia Tech.
Uh, I was actually a
computer science major. Um,
I'm already suspect. I'm
impressed. That goes impressed.
I'm suspect
point during that, uh, during my
college career, my sophomore year,
I decided that computer
science was not for me.
And how have you feel?
Betrayed.
And I decided,
I dunno,
I felt like I had spent the first 20
years of my life kind of looking after
myself and now I needed to do something
that was beyond my own self interest.
And a buddy of mine had just
joined the Marine Corps.
So I read a couple books about the Marine
Corps Brotherhood of heroes about the
battle, the Palae Lu and I said, Yep,
that's what I want to do.
I want to join the Marine Corps.
So before telling my parents
before telling anybody
looked up where the recruiter was,
went down there, he wasn't there,
marine corps recruiter wasn't there.
Air Force recruiter tells me to come in
his office and tells me about the air
force and I said he had just
told me when the Marine Corp,
yeah,
nothing against the air force.
But I had already decided on
marine corps and so I joined up
I, this may be right or wrong,
I'm pretty sure it's right.
The Marine Corps has the like the lowest
a recruiting budget and they have the
highest recruiting numbers
because it's the Marine Corps
there. Their approach, I guess it was
like, Oh, you want to be one of us, right?
Maybe. Yeah. See if you can.
Good luck. I do. Yeah. Um,
so I joined up as a reservist,
my original plan because I
was after my junior year,
so I wanted to finish college at least.
So my original plan was I did the 92 day
reservists program where I went to boot
camp after my junior year.
And then I finished my last year of uh,
college and then I went
to job school and MCT.
How did your academic performance change
or did it between pre boot camp and
post boot camp?
It didn't a whole lot because I think I
kind of checked out a college after my
junior year. I was like, I
just want to go deploy it,
but I just kind of want to get this
degree done just so I have it. Um,
now after I deployed a few a couple
times and had a little bit more life
experience would probably
be a lot different.
But just those three months at
bootcamp didn't really change my,
your academic academic
approach. I was funny. Smart.
I was smart enough, I just didn't
care that much about it anymore. Um,
so my, my original plan was
to do that and then have the,
a little bit of experience as an,
uh,
an enlisted guy and then you use
my degree to become an officer.
But when I was in engineer school
after that, that second summer,
my company, my reserve company said we're
sending a volunteer platoon to Iraq.
So I said, well, that's the whole reason
I joined up was to go fight the war.
So screw being an officer,
I'm going to deploy.
And so then we go to my first appointment.
So, um, I thought it was pretty,
you got a good note in here about,
uh, about the Marine Corps and I'm just
going to, I'm just going to read this.
I'm taking this stuff from your,
your journal that you have online,
which is awesome reed. So here
we go. Back to the journal.
The Marine Corps began to shape me long
before I ever have ever arrived at boot
camp in Parris Island,
South Carolina, Carolina.
It started when I read the
book Brotherhood of Heroes,
the tail of the battle of
how Lou in World War II.
It was through the stories of the of the
Marines told and those pages that I was
introduced to, the
courage, Spirit, tenacity,
altruism and brotherhood
that the marines possess,
qualities that I would soon
be ingrained with as well.
The basics of these qualities were
taught to me and my fellow recruits in
bootcamp through rudimentary but
effective means the proverbial stick.
It was through punishment that we
were shown what it meant to possess.
The attributes of a marine punishment
would come in a variety of modes based on
the same comp concept, countless
pushups, sit ups, sprinting,
caring,
and of course screaming.
The drill instructors
would use any excuse,
not that they needed one to inflict
pain upon us, not being loud enough,
looking in the wrong place in perfection,
in uniform,
dirty squad bay and not moving fast enough
for their inspections to name a few.
The reality of the situation was
that we were never loud enough,
always looking in the wrong place,
never had perfect uniforms.
The squad bay was always too
dirty and we were simply too slow.
The idea wasn't simply to
pointlessly inflict pain,
but to teach lessons using
the pain as the instructor.
It was to force us to
make ourselves better,
so the whole platoon as
a whole would be better.
Yeah.
The idea was to form a brotherhood
through shared suffering and shared
dependence.
It was to teach us to
keep fighting pain so that
the platoon as a whole
could stop being punished.
The point was that once
we reached perfection,
the requirements changed so that we
were forced to constantly reach for it,
thus forcing us to become better
than we ever knew we could be.
This is how the Marine Corps takes hunks
of iron and turns them into juvenile
steel.
That's why the Marine Corps doesn't
need a lot of recruiting money,
but so true, and I liked that.
I liked what you pointed out,
the shared dependence and how when you're
going through bootcamp scenarios and
training scenarios that are really hard,
you realize that you're not going to be
able to do this alone and you're going
to have to rely on these other guys who
you may not in the civilian world you
wouldn't have even been associated with
and now you're not only associated with
them, you depend on them for, for
your survival and to get through it.
And that's,
I think that's what makes,
that's what makes that
military experience.
And certainly the Marine Corps
does an outstanding job of it.
They think of formulating that bond
that is is unique to the military.
Yeah, that's what, that's the thing
that makes marines what they are and,
and brings out the best in people's
when they're doing something,
not for their own self interest,
but for somebody else.
And I would volunteer for the worst
stuff so that I could prevent my buddies
from having to do it.
Like walking through the Euphrates river,
looking for whatever,
trying to find weapons caches in Iraq,
and then getting back
at the end of the day,
just totally soaked and covered
in trash water, you know,
and they come in and say, we're doing it
again. Who wants to go and be like, yeah,
I'll go, I'll go again. You know? And
that's, I think that's why I really,
I kind of enjoyed the combat engineer
role too because I'm going out there
protecting people, protecting my
buddies, protecting other marines,
and taking the risk on me.
And I mean,
that's what being a marine is all about.
Anybody else would've done it too.
Yeah. And so you go your
first deployment to Iraq and,
um, what was that deployment
like? Where'd you go? Uh,
how Binya over?
So this is 2008 to 2000 names
are pretty mellow at 2008. Yeah.
UH, Iraqi kind of slowed down at
that point wasn't much going on.
We had one
tiny little incident where we were on
a convoy and some guy knows were fired,
maybe three Ak rounds and then ran
away. And it was still, you know,
nothing and that, but that was in like
the first couple of weeks. It's like,
what was your response to the
three rounds from an AK 47?
I continued sitting in the back
of the seven ton, dude, a dude,
like an 18 year old,
uh,
lance corporal unload with
700 rounds of 50 cal or
no, it was a long convoy. So it was
way up there and I was like, oh,
I got to get out. I gotta get up
there. But it was, it was over.
Did they shoot back?
Did they returned fire at him?
No, I don't think so. I mean, he, like,
he did one of those things where he
raised over and then left by the time
anybody who was able to figure out
where he was and it's gone. So that was,
but that was in the first couple of weeks,
so it was kind of off to a good start.
And then, uh, oh, nothing
else happened really.
So what were you guys doing
during that deployment?
I guess it was kind of the,
uh,
the build portion of, uh, of the strategy
at that point. You know, we were,
we were helping the local population
build up their cities build.
We were helping to build a,
uh, Iraqi police stations.
And,
but what I spent most of my time doing
was when we would go out and find buried
weapons caches,
so just these old stores of Rpgs and
stuff that the al Qaeda used to be using,
but they had just left there.
And then,
so the local population would sort of,
somebody would give us a tip, right?
And we would go out to this
big field and they'd say, yeah,
it's supposedly somewhere in
here. There's a, a weapons cache.
So we take out a metal detectors and
sweep every square inch of that field or
hill or wherever we were,
tree tree line.
And until we either does certain,
determined there was nothing,
or we would find it and we dig it up and
stack it, and then EOD would come and
blow it up. And were
you attached to a, uh,
like an a combat engineer platoon for
or where you're attached to an infantry
platoon?
Yeah. So the way it works for the,
what we call division side engineers,
like combat engineer battalion is one
combat engineer platoon is attached to an
infantry battalion.
And then you kind of break it down.
So one squad of that platoon goes with
each company and then one team goes with
the platoon.
So you kind of help that put tune out
a just pretty much attached to them.
The entire,
so when you guys would be doing these
clearances of like, let's say a big field,
it would be a platoon,
a Marine Corps platoon,
and you would be doing all,
all the sweeping.
Yeah. So it'd be a Marine
Corps platoon or squad.
He used to be a squad Lod would,
uh,
we'd go out on a squad
patrol troll out there.
They would set up security on the
area and they would just wait.
And then you'd be me and one other guy
and we would sweep and sometimes we would
have one of the infantry
guys have a e tool.
And be like Dick there
and then he would dig and
nothing. And then would
you, when you'd find
caches, would you guys blow them
in place or would you recover it?
I guess it would depend.
We would take pictures of what we found
so we could write the report when we got
back and if it was out in the middle of
nowhere, a lot of the times they would,
they'll blow it in place. We have to
wait for EOD. They wouldn't let us do it.
That's actually really jacked up.
I it's so stupid. It's so jack.
Cause there was only one EOD unit for
EOD guys for the entire battalion.
And not to mention that's the
fun part. That quickly. Right.
I know how to,
they used to back in like
2005 combat engineers were
doing all that all the time.
He just lay it out and
you just sympathetically
designated with the sticker.
That's all it is. It's because the
war slowed down. Yeah. Slows down.
All of a sudden people start putting the
rules and regulations in weight and we
could have Eud do that.
No one has that same thing.
We had the heaviest,
I've,
I'm sure when you guys were in Ramadi,
you just had the standard flak vest.
We had this ridiculous turtle shell,
Front sappies back, sappy
side, sappies neck protector,
groin protector, everything but
protector. Like it was just the,
the vest itself was 70 pounds.
Let me tell you something interesting
about that. When we were in Ramadi,
not everyone had that and
everyone wanted it and okay.
They did their best. I remember
actually, uh, the kernel,
the brigade coming down and bringing side
Sapi plates down to combat outpost to
hand them out to guys because
everybody wanted them.
They wanted the neck protectors, the
shoulder protectors, the groin protectors.
They wanted everything. I mean, most I'll
have many guys just, hey, you, you know,
especially if you're sitting in a
turret or, yeah, like load me up.
I want all that, the neck. And they
wanted it all because it was gnarly.
Yeah. And then go try and
do a hit on a house with it.
Yeah, no, that, that part's not fun. But,
uh,
but so it's probably that same thing
where they're just coming up with all the
safety rules and you have
to have your helmet, gloves,
eye protection on at all times
when you're outside the wire.
So for whatever reason,
they didn't let us blow it up.
So we'd have to wait for EOD to come out
and then they would either blow it up
there if it was out in the middle of
nowhere. But if it was in the city,
they would usually take it somewhere.
And meanwhile the rest of
the combat engineer battalion
are out helping with the
building, the structures,
building schools,
helping the infrastructure
and stuff like that.
It would depend, I mean, yeah.
So whatever that platoon that
they were attached to was doing,
they'd just be doing that.
And then every now and then if they
needed all of us back to build up an Iraqi
police station,
they would call everybody in or everybody.
But a couple of guys in and then we'd
all go out as a platoon to build that.
Got It. But I spent most of
my time just doing the cash,
sweeping and going on patrol.
So within the platoon or certain people as
like mine sweepers or does
everyone get trained in that?
Everybody should be able to do it.
Got It. How come you kept getting the,
cause you've volunteered for that. You
said, hey, I'll go find these. Yeah.
And my fire team was more,
my squad was kind of,
we didn't want to do the construction
and stuff cause we thought it was boring.
I wasn't great at can I can
swing a hammer, but you know,
I wasn't like good at it.
Um,
and so we kind of tried to put ourselves
in positions where we wouldn't have to
go do that stuff. We tried to always
be out with the, with the squads,
with the platoons as often as we could
so we could avoid the construction stuff.
But then yeah, that's what I
wanted it to be doing. Yeah.
Yeah. Be Out on patrol. Yeah,
exactly. So then that deployment,
you come home and you had
already graduated from
college at this point, right?
Yeah. And so you come home and then
what happens when you get home?
So what's your plan when you get home?
When I get home, well, so we
were in Iraq and my buddy, uh,
Ronnie and Daniel,
we were all drinking and we were like,
that was not what we wanted.
You know what the good thing
is when you're drinking,
that's when you make your best military
decisions about what to do with your
career.
But yeah.
Well you were just sitting there.
Go ahead.
That was not what we
were hoping it would be.
Um, we wanted to do some
fighting, do some killing.
Um, so we were like, we got to figure
out a way to go to Afghanistan.
And so we started trying to look
up cause we were in the reserve.
So sometimes there's,
there's programs where you can be an
augmentee, an individual. Augmentee
did you have a civilian job at this point?
I didn't cause I just graduated college.
Just graduated college.
Then you go on deployment, then you'd come
home and now you're saying, all right,
what do, how do I get back?
How do I, how do I go fight?
I had 25,000 bucks from deployment, so
I bought a motorcycle, you know. Yup.
That's good investment.
Good longterm investment crashes.
But yeah,
so I was looking at,
I was looking for a
job to tide me over and
trying everything I could
to go to Afghanistan.
But luckily it was pretty
shortly after we got back,
we go to drill and company says sitting
volunteer platoon to Afghanistan and
boom right here. Cause Afghanistan
was heating up at this time,
if you remember.
But,
but we had still had to wait about eight
or nine months before we went to the
workup for that. So I just took a
job putting out traffic counters,
like there's a little to go across the
road and you attached a little electronic
box to it.
So I just took a job doing that.
That's sorta like related to IED,
isn't that a little bit of,
it's on the side of the road, you know,
fresh water fish wire on the road. That,
and it just got in shape and partied.
Now did you,
did you do more drill once
you're, uh, getting ready to deploy?
Uh, yeah. Well, uh, so when I say drill
I guess I should explain that's the,
the deal, uh, for reservists, do you go in
when weekend? One weekend. A month. So
your drill, that's called the drill. Yeah.
Did they escalate that at all
when you're going to deploy?
Yeah.
So they kind of,
they kind of cater the drills
that you do based on what,
what you got to need upcoming.
So I do recall we did a couple
where we would do go a go do a,
like an IED training, uh, section.
And then we would, since I had
experience now we would just take,
whenever we were at a drill,
we would just start training the other,
the new guys that were going to
be going with us on machine guns,
metal detectors, and just try
getting them trained up. But yeah.
And so a lot of the training was kind
of on our own because you only get that
one weekend a month and they only have
so much money and they have to train the
whole company as opposed to just
the platoon that's going. Right.
So, so then do they activate you? How
far before deployment do they activate?
You see,
you can do some legitimate real training.
We,
so we did that.
We actually managed to get a month
at Camp Lejune at courthouse bay,
which is the combat engineer a school.
And so we did manage to
get a month long school of,
you know, just doing
demolition, a refreshment,
uh, more IED stuff,
patrol practice, you know,
just doing all sorts
of training like that.
And then your workup is pretty much
just however long it takes to do Mojave
Viper with your battalion and
then maybe a month before that.
Yeah.
So,
so maybe three months total
before you're going on for three,
four months. Got It. And were you,
uh, with the rest of the guys?
So it's one platoon that's
going one platoon, one puts,
it wasn't even a full Patina.
There's three squads. Okay.
So how many guys that total?
It was actually even short squads too.
So it was a, let me think each other.
There was a fire to nine, 10, 11 per squad
and then three for the,
the brass
platoon. So back then you go,
you do your desert drill and everyone's
unified in the new d leave before that,
and then, then you, and
then you go on deployment.
Yeah. So they give you
a little bit of a, yeah,
they give you a little bit
of leaf before you, uh,
have to go over and it's like four or five
days. So everybody flies home and then
got it comes back. So now you
show up in Afghanistan and what's,
how's that different from Iraq?
You know what, the first portion
of it was not that different. Um,
the terrain was a lot different.
So where'd, where'd you first
go?
So, uh, in Afghanistan we
were at, we started, I was,
I deployed with three, seven as
an attachment, third battalion,
seventh Marine Corps regimen.
And we were in Dell Rom,
which I, I'm pretty sure
it was in Helmand province.
It was kind of right on the border,
so I don't recall exactly, but,
and pretty much kilo company was the
company that my squad was attached to and
they got sent out just in the
middle of nowhere to a file.
And then they had a patrol
base that was even smaller.
You didn't even further
out that I got sent to,
I was a team leader and so usually you
would have one team in the one spot in
one team in the other spot.
But since we were kind of short on guys,
it was pretty much,
I was the only engineer for that platoon.
And yeah, so we were
in, in Dell Rom and so,
and how Binya was urban, everything
was able walking through a city,
everything was urban, but
Afghanistan was just barren. Yeah.
And what, when you got out to
this Ford base, what would you do?
What were you guys doing out there?
What was the,
what was the infantry thing that you
were attached to you doing out there?
Uh, patrolling. So it was kind of similar.
That's why I say it wasn't a whole lot
different from Iraq because we were
basically just interacting with the local
populace, uh, find out what they needed,
providing security for that area.
Like they had a bizarre,
that would come every weekend. So we'd
go out, provide security for that.
And so I was still using my metal
detector to clear danger areas if we can.
There's a lot of Wattis out there,
so we'd have to funnel through the Wadi.
So I checked that.
Um,
how often were you where you
find in Ids and that information?
I didn't find a one on there now. There
was, it was a pretty pacified area.
I think we had one firefight that one
of the squads got into and that's it.
Um,
so, so your first part of the
deployment and how long was that?
How long was that part of the deployment?
That was two and a half,
three months I think.
So there's kind of like a little tuneup,
right.
And then we pass that area off to the
Georgian army and that's when we moved to
Sangin to,
to take over from the Brits
and now saying in Zen,
like that's the Hellman province central.
Right. I mean that's, that's, that's it.
Yeah. That's Taliban central
down there. Uh, yeah.
And as soon as you get
on the ground there,
did you feel it when
you got on the ground?
We knew. Yeah. I mean
we kind of did a push into that area
before we actually moved out there and we
knew shit was getting real when we,
uh,
they just,
they're like pack up a pack and we got
on the helicopter and they just flew us
out and just dropped us off in
the middle of absolutely nowhere.
And we just started walking it,
just leave your packs here and
start walking that way and just,
just basically just taking
territory from the Taliban.
Now did you,
do guys do a thorough turnover with them
Brits? I wasn't a part of that, but
not really.
I mean we,
we pretty much came into Fabi
Anchorman and we're there for a day,
day and a half. And then
the Brits were gone. No, no.
Oh, we left. And then, yeah,
you pushed out. So the Brits
were there when you were,
when you were there on the ground.
We were both there at the same time.
Probably the headquarters elements. We're
doing a turnover. Yeah. They were like,
hey,
we're getting our boys out,
pushing immediately.
And we had a couple world marines with
us and it's in British army or this,
I think they had a small or
maybe a toe that we didn't have.
So like units that we,
we needed from them,
they would send out with us and
they were great. Um, but uh,
from what I understood, they just didn't
have the manpower to really do much
where they, the guys that
were with you, were you,
were they giving you any turnover items?
Like, Hey, you need to look out for this.
Hey, this is what's going
on here. No. Were you doing
receive any cause I don't think they
really went out much so I don't,
not really sure how much they really
could have told us about what was outside
of the patrol basis.
And I never,
I don't even remember. I think we may
have talked to their combat engineers,
we've got some demo from them like hey
can we have some deck decourt and they
gave it to us and that's about it.
Yeah.
And that's cause they were
just completely undermanned.
Yeah. The, from what I understand,
I mean I obviously I'm not a part of
the upper echelon out there and stuff,
but I think that's the reason they just,
they set up a patrol base and
they had the patrol bases,
but they pretty much just sat there and
got ambushed and got shot at every day
and didn't do a whole lot of patrolling.
So then you guys roll in and the like,
the broad strategy is you're going
to start moving from patrol base,
you're going to push out, take
another compound, secure it,
and then operate out of there for
awhile and then push, push on.
Pretty much just take the
Taliban's territory, um,
by going out,
clearing a compound.
And that's what a major part
of what I was doing it on.
This push was clearing compounds just in
case there are a booby trapped and then
we, yeah, we take over that
compound, sandbag it up,
knocked down some trees and some
explosives, create those fields of fire.
And then once I was set up to start doing
some patrols, security patrols and then
repeat. And where are you guys getting
in contact with the Taliban? Yeah,
more often.
They were pretty much shooting at us
most days.
Mortaring us most days.
Not very accurate.
MMM.
But yeah, they were shooting at us at
least. And we, we would go out on patrols,
they'd shoot at us.
MMM.
But they're always shooting from way
far away. And you know, we'd shoot back,
but it wasn't like further on in
the deployment when the corns,
when the corn grew a lot taller.
I wasn't there for it cause I got hurt by
them. But that was when they were like,
people were shooting at each other in
the cornfield like five feet away. So,
so, but, but while you were there, it was
more distant, really far distant contact.
We were you guys taking any casualties?
I think not, not times. I mean
obviously every one is a major,
major sacrifice. But, uh, there
was one sniper that got killed,
uh, on the initial push on Lusa
Cola before we even got to Sangin.
And besides that,
I don't remember. Oh, my buddy Ron, he
got hit in the face with a piece of RPG.
Um, he didn't go home, he just
had to go get it taken care of.
So minor stuff like that.
But yeah, minor stuff only
happens when stuff is going on.
And by the way, that little
piece of shrapnel, you know,
that thing can kill you just as easily
as a, you know, a full piece of shrapnel.
Yeah, exactly. Um,
but I would say so.
So you're,
you're like now every patrol that you
guys are going out is like, hey, now how,
how often are you finding
ids at this point?
Not Tons.
Um,
okay.
Trying to think. And then not very
often. Yeah. I mean cause the,
I think the area that we were in initially
was still pretty close to the main
farb and then as you went
out there would be, um,
just fields of them.
And the way that we
were getting out to the,
the patrol basis,
we were using Mikulics.
And so that was mitigating a lot of the
searching that we would've had to do.
Um,
so in that initial area weren't finding
tons, just every, every now and then.
And I, I don't, I don't know
if this is right or not,
but do you know what the
closer you get to a fob,
do you have security on the fob?
You have guys that are looking out.
So it's hard for someone to come in
and dig out and put it in an IED in the
ground.
So you're,
you got some level of security
around the fobs most of the time.
Obviously there could be something there.
Preexisting and um,
day to day life. What are you
guys, are you guys on the Mras?
Are you guys getting chow or what's,
what's going on day to day life?
Man,
I wished we had MRI.
So at some point during the
deployment we started on Mras and I,
you know, I like Mrs. I think
there were good, you're sick.
I used to like him Mre is a point.
I was like 22 and then I oded on them.
Yeah, I didn't, I didn't
mind them too much.
But then when we started
doing these pushes,
we got these things called first
strike rations and like the new MRE.
But here's the problem with these first,
right?
They were awesome when we first got
on the first week. They were awesome.
But the Marine Corps only decided to do
it would be good to buy three different
meals
and kind of at the same time
we had outrun our water supply,
so we were just stopping
off at wells and guess what?
Nobody be kind of purifying stuff.
Um,
so we were just drinking well water
and obviously what you would expect to
happen happened. Everybody was
getting sick. Jazz, you know,
diarrhea,
vomiting.
That's crazy.
No purification tabs or no,
I guess maybe they didn't
expect us to need to use wells,
but the first day everybody
ran out of water by the,
by the time we ended and we're like,
well, we just got to go get well water.
Isn't that crazy?
A purification pill is like,
I'm talking at you echo like
it's a little tiny thing. We,
you can carry them so easily and they
completely changed the game because you
can take that water out of the well or
a stream that's got whatever bacteria on
it. Put that pillow, put that thing in
there, shake it up, you're good to go.
Does it taste different? No, not really.
Not really. If people use them. Camping.
Yeah. This iodine tablets. And
you can also bring a filter.
Like when I hike, I bring a filter,
which is a little Plinko Britta pump. No,
it's not a Brita pitcher. Knows about
that. A little pump. A little pump.
And how long are you guys
going out in the field for?
Um, let's see. The first push
Nimbus cloud was about two weeks.
And so we just, yeah, walk for two weeks.
We walked to a compound stop for the day,
set security, spend the night, walk
to the next one. If they shoot at us,
fight back, kill him, whatever,
do whatever we got to do.
And then we just kept
pushing out and pushing out.
And then eventually we got to a point
in that first, most of Galop push where,
uh, for whatever reason they
just, they just said, all right,
now you're going to walk back.
I think, I think maybe our, uh,
I think maybe our battalion commander
had actually been a little bit too
aggressive and had gone beyond his
limits that his boss wanting him to do.
So we ended up having to give up
territory we had just taken and yeah,
so that one was two weeks.
But then once we got to Sangin it was
pretty much spend a day doing the push,
take the compounds and then you kind
of in the compound you just go out and
patrol and then you come back. So we
weren't really out in the field field,
uh, for all that long. But you know, being
in a compound still not exactly luxury.
Yeah. You still want to have showers or
it's not the Kona Kai resort. Definitely.
All right man.
I'm going to talk about,
I'm going to go to your journal here
cause obviously on one of these uh,
patrols you got hit
and here's what you wrote about it.
Okay.
Two things happened simultaneously when
whatever explosive device that hit me
exploded.
First the shockwave cut through my toes,
severing them,
it didn't slow as it cut through
my shins, severing them. Next,
it's sent dirt,
Grit and shrapnel upward into my legs,
buttocks, and any other part
of my body that was exposed.
Okay.
Next. It launched me a few feet into the
air and deposited me onto the ground.
Unconscious
blood was pouring out of the newly
opened arteries and into the dirt.
Okay?
Muscle and bone dangled from
the remnants of my legs.
Okay?
Vicious bacteria latched on and
invaded through the note. New Openings.
The dust rose
and settled and I woke up
the first 10 seconds after waking up
all I could hear where my own screams
all I could see you as a blurry
tunnel looking up to the sky.
The weird thing about the screams was
that my brain wasn't telling my body to
produce them.
It was almost as if my mind was no longer
present and my body was just reacting
or more like panicking.
Okay?
They were the kindest screams that are
emitted from a person regardless of the
consideration of the personal
pride that the person has,
no matter how much their pride
makes them resist crying out,
they don't have a choice in the matter.
They inhale to lungfuls of air,
open their mouth as wide as it will
go and expel that air with full force
producing a scream that pierces the air
and change his pitch with no control.
As seconds clicked away,
my mind started to come back
online and my body calmed down.
Okay.
I stopped screaming and my
other sense is returned.
I smelled dust and the unique chemical
spell of the recent explosion.
I tasted it on my tongue and in my throat.
After that, my feeling came
back. It wasn't so much pain
as one would imagine it,
but more like my lower legs had
fallen asleep for so long that it hurt
except magnified by 50 times.
I knew that they were gone,
but how much,
okay.
I had decided before I left
on this deployment that I
could live with below the
knee amputations, but anything
higher than that, no thanks.
I'd rather bleed out.
I could hear Keith Johnson telling me
that they were coming for me and soon he
and Shane Ottewell were over me applying
tourniquets to the bleeding stumps that
used to be legs.
I mustered up the courage
to look at my hands intact.
I move them downward to check on
something vastly more important.
Yeah.
The numbness I felt down there
left me unsure of its status,
just kill me.
I croaked out.
They ignored me of course and kept
telling me how everything was going to be
okay. They were holding my hands as the
corpsman knelt over me and delivered the
sweet,
sweet morphine that made it all better.
Okay.
Kill me man. I said again. I don't want to
live like this. I think my dick is gone.
Your Dick is still there, man. Do you
want me to touch it? Johnson asked.
I chuckled. Were with
relief as I replied. No.
I asked whether the lug legs were
gone above or below the knee.
I was reassured to hear that
both were a few inches below.
By this time I was high from the morphine
and was saying everything that crossed
my mind.
As the corpsman continued to work and
we waited for the 10 line CAS evac to be
called in. I thought about all the
things I wouldn't be doing anymore.
I thought about playing racket ball.
I thought about working out in the gym.
I thought about being in a
wheelchair for the next 50 years.
I never thought about how I was breeding,
bleeding profusely from two
major arteries and could die.
I never once thought I would die,
which may seem unusual for
a person in my position.
Naturally optimistic,
I suppose.
Although it is hard to claim that I was
being optimistic considering I wanted to
cash out permanently.
In my defense,
I had no idea what life was like as
an amputee and if I had back then,
I wouldn't have made that request
either way.
I'm glad I stuck around.
Around this time I decided to sit
up and take a look at the damage.
I took a deep breath and gulped.
I slowly started sitting up,
but when I got to the point where going
further would reveal my shredded legs,
I had a change of heart.
I didn't see the blood soaked dirt.
I didn't see the disjointed lower parts
of my calves and Chins along with my
feet or the jagged edge
of my remaining limbs.
The skin roughly burned and
shorten the bone sticking out.
Then the rip muscle dangling
along the ground. I didn't want
that image to be inside of my head because
I knew it would be one that I would
never be able to forget.
I deeply regret the fact that there are
those that I consider friends that were
forced to have that image in their mind
and will have to live with with it for
their entire lives.
Secondly,
I was afraid of seeing the wound
would make it hurt even more,
much like a scraped knee.
As a child,
I laid back down and let the
morphine keep doing its job.
I started getting sleepy.
I just wanted to close my eyes.
I thought maybe if I closed my eyes,
I would pass away easily.
Slap Atwell's hand slap my cheek
as he yelled at me to stay awake.
Just let me sleep. Just let me sleep.
I mumbled closing my eyes again,
another slap.
That was the last time I did that.
Finally the stretcher that
was going to carry me out,
arrived for strong men,
lifted me onto it,
grab each one of the handles and started
carrying me to an assault breach or
vehicle.
They were carrying me away from the war
I volunteered to participate in and the
marines that I was supposed
to be leading and protecting,
they would have to go on without me
all because I had failed in my job,
failed to find the Iud that I
knew was somewhere around us.
That failure was a hard pill to swallow
then and it remains so. To this day
I didn't feel good about leaving them
behind, but I knew they would understand.
I knew they would be okay without me.
We got to the assault breach or vehicle
and I asked Jimmy Goodwin one last time
to put me out of my misery
after his refusal.
That was the last time I ever
contemplating accepting that avenue.
They slid me into the back of the vehicle
and with some marines I had never met
whose faces I can remember seeing but
don't remember any of their features.
The corpsman said he was going to give
me something to put me to sleep and I
finally got to close my eyes
as everything went black.
Okay.
You're pretty clear about what happened.
I remember it pretty lucidly,
surprisingly. Yeah, I dunno.
Yeah,
I was,
I think I was unconscious for maybe 20
seconds I would estimate because they
hadn't even,
it hadn't gotten to me by the time I
woke up and I don't think they would have
spent a whole lot of time.
Yeah.
I think one of my guys might have cleared
over to me, but I, I, I don't know.
I'm kind of wish I had thought
of something better to say like
it got me boys like free lesson learned,
preload a really cool sentence.
Dramatic moment and script to go
with just in case the critical point.
Oh Man, no, I wish I would have thought
of something better than Duke do there.
It makes sense. Oh yeah. That's
actually more important. Like I said,
that's something vastly more
important, but the interesting, yeah.
The thing about,
they said I was a below the knee.
And so a lot of the
[inaudible] times what happens,
you might be below the
knee at site of injury,
but like I said, infection,
that dirt over there is nasty.
We're not used to their bacteria.
It'll get in there, it will in fact,
and they have to end up chopping you off
higher to save your life because of the,
the infections,
just uncontrollable.
And also if they don't have viable tissue,
bones and muscles that they can sculpt
in such a way that you can put a
prosthetic on there,
they'll just cut you off.
Where at the next, you know,
viable spot, it would be
right.
And um,
there's gotta be like you,
you know,
you had to have known or you, you'd
know this is a possibility, right?
When you're over there, how much did
you think about that possibility?
Okay. It's probably the same thing as
when you were going through Amani. I mean,
you know, everybody knows you could,
you could die, you could get killed,
but it's not going to be me. It's
fine. Not going to happen. Um,
but you kind of have to do that,
don't you? I mean, if you, if you,
if I'm sitting in there sweeping
and I'm thinking, okay, here we go.
This could be it every step.
I'm not going
effective.
Yeah.
There's gotta be whether people refer
to it the way I referred to as the,
like the idea of detachment. And you're
just like, not going to think about that.
Everybody must be doing that because
otherwise she'd go freaking crazy.
Like if you were just thinking this next
step could be the one, I don't know, you,
you'd never be able to take a step.
You could handle it.
And you go out there on patrol and you
see Marines and soldiers and the seals,
they bear, no, everyone's doing their job.
Just completely setting that fear aside
and saying, okay, that's possibility.
Cool. I don't have time to worry about
that right now. I'm going to get it done.
But, uh, I have,
I made a dark joke before
I went to Afghanistan.
I did this five k with a buddy
and he said, all right, well,
we're going to do it again. And
when, when we get back from Afghan,
when you get back from
Afghanistan, I was like, yeah,
except you're going to be pulling me in
a rickshaw cause I'm going to have both
my legs blown off.
He has yet to pull me in the rickshaw.
But
I talk about, you know,
fate or whatever. I don't know what, what,
that's just bad humor.
I think that's what we call that.
But you know what that is? That is a
way you deal with these things, right?
I mean like, hey, we were kind of
talking about in the car over here,
just like sick humor that you end up
with in the military because you have to
take that thought, which is in your
head. Like he's gotta be in your head.
So what are you going to do with it?
Are you going to let it like burden you
down and make you inoperable and make
you not be able to do your job?
Are you going to, you know what?
We're going to make a joke about it and
that's how we're going to get through
this. So more than anything
else, it's actually great.
I shouldn't have said bad
here and I should have said
great humor because that's
the kind of humor that we'd hear
that all the time, you know,
all the time from guys from my seals were
ridiculous. My guys are just, I mean,
the sickest sense of humor you
could imagine. And, but yeah,
the same thing with the soldiers and
there wasn't even, there's no barrier.
Like there's no barrier for that sixth
sense or humor when you're in the
military,
it's just like there and you're allowed
pretty much to say it across services.
You know,
you can make a joke to marine or an
army soldier about something and they,
they're not going to beat,
they're not going to be offended by it.
It's everyone's got that same
twisted sense of humor that really,
if you think about it, we're all probably
using to cope with, you know, the,
the fact that these bad
things might happen.
Yeah.
I think
I've often like try and
wonder why they say,
you know, laughter's the best medicine
and why it's so true. And I think it,
it acts to normalize your situation.
So you know how if you're about to try
and dead lift like thousand pounds per
hour for you, something like that. Sure.
You're trying to deadlift 8,000
pounds and you're sitting there going,
there's no way I'm going to
dead lift this 8,000 pounds,
you're going to go up to it and
it's going to stick to the ground.
That predetermined a self
pre determination. Right?
And so if you're sitting there,
let's say after I got hurt
and I'm sitting there going,
this is the worst thing to ever happen.
This sucks.
I hate this. It's so serious.
It's such a big deal.
Then yeah, it becomes the
worst thing that ever happened.
And I just kind of get into that groove.
But if you can make a joke about it,
it kind of makes fun of it.
So it's not as serious.
And so when something's not as
serious or not as big a deal,
you make fun of something,
it kind of becomes normal to you and
a little bit easier to to accept.
Like if you saw, if I saw my drill
instructor crack a smile at any point,
if you like sit this
or anything like that,
then they automatically lose their,
their persona.
So if you could tell sometimes they
were getting ready to crack a smile and
they'd be like,
they just walk off.
I think you'd have to just walk away.
So I think,
I think that that's probably why you
have to maintain your humor in order to
survive. You really do. Yeah,
no doubt about that. That's awesome. Um,
okay.
Going back to your journal here, it
took me five days to make it from dusty,
uncomfortable blast crater
and Afghanistan to a sterile,
uncomfortable hospital bed in the ICU
at the Nae National Naval Medical Center
in Bethesda, Maryland. Luckily for me,
I was much too high on what's that
Dilla Dilla. The loudest dilaudid.
Dilaudid. Yeah. To notice
the bed or the trip.
My amputation said started
out below the knee,
but somewhere during the three
hospitals stops along the way,
the need rows for the remaining
portions below my knees to be taken off.
A lot of the time.
This is due to infections that are
picked up from the dirt and Afghanistan,
or maybe there wasn't much that
existed below the knees to keep,
to make keeping them viable
on the bright side. However,
the stumps that were remaining were of
a significant length for an above knee
amputation.
I was left with the entire femur on my
left leg and only a few inches shy on my
right leg. I found it funny that
throughout my entire hospital stay,
the remainder of my legs
were always referred to as
stumps by the medical staff.
I had expected a more elegant
term considering the fact
that this was a hospital.
At the same time,
however,
I enjoyed the casual nature of the word
stump and even considered naming them at
one point later when perusing my medical
records, I found the elegant term.
I had been looking for residual limb
along with the major injuries I sustained.
I also had a few minor injuries.
I use the term minor loosely here.
Seeing as how these minor injuries would
be considered major if they weren't
sustained in tandem with the
severing of one's lower legs
starting from the lower person portions.
First,
I lost a portion of the muscles making
up the inner part of my right Fi.
In order to close that wound,
I would require a skin graft taken
from the skin of my left fi my buttocks
contay or sustained several
large wounds from shrapnel,
some close to the sphincter,
but mostly in the more meaty parts.
That was okay though I have always
had an extra butt muscle to go around.
The close proximity of these wounds
to the working parts of the digestive
digestive system resulted in the doctor's
diverting my intestines to a colostomy
bag that came through my abdominal area.
The reason for doing this wasn't
because of any damage to the intestines,
but because the doctors wanted to make
sure that the large wounds on my butt
didn't get infected.
As for upper body injuries,
I had some minor burns to my hands
and to totally perforated ear drums.
The hands were Keel and my ear drums
would be replaced with cartilage.
I consider myself extremely lucky that
I still have all 10 fingers in perfect
working condition,
my eyes and most significantly a brain
that made it through the blast with only
a grade three concussion and no
residual traumatic brain injuries.
While I may face hardships and have
some sort of discomfort constantly
throughout the day as a result of wearing
prosthetics, at least it doesn't hurt,
hurt. I don't have constant
pain. Constant pain is much more.
Har Wing is a much more harrowing plight
than mine and I can't imagine how hard
it is to withstand.
I spent my first week at Bethesda
in the intensive care unit.
I had a tube down my throat,
one tube going into my arm,
a breathing tube in my nose, a catheter
pads, monitoring my heart rate,
an epidural in my lower spine
and a wire from my pain button.
Both my hands were wrapped
in gauze from my burns.
My legs were all so wrapped in gauze
along with having wound vac machines
attached them to suck out excess
fluids leaking from my wounds.
My rear end had a pat of gauze for
the wounds there. The incision down,
the center of my abs use from our
colostomy had been stapled back together.
And the bottom part, parts of my stumps
were where the skin was reconnected,
were stitched together.
Man, like I, you know,
you just, you, it's just piling
all that, all their stuff on too.
And it just, like you said, you, you lost
your legs and you're like, oh, you know,
that's pretty much what a guy like me, I
focused, oh, he lost his legs, you know,
obviously freaking horrible. And then
you don't, you're like a guy like me.
I'm not thinking about all these other
injuries that you're sustaining and all
the medical things that have to happen
to get that stuff straightened out.
Yeah. I mean, any one of those,
just like if it happened
to one of us right now,
any one of those would be major,
but they're just pretty much nothing
compared to the actual major thing that
happened.
And, and you're just so, were you
just drugged up at this point? Yeah.
Uh, that first week. I mean, yeah,
just dilauded Hayes hallucinations
and that kind of thing and surgeries.
Um,
I would hallucinate nasty things like
being hit by a mortar and CMI leg
splattered for whatever
reason my mom was there. Uh,
and then I recall for the
first couple of weeks,
every now and then, I don't know
how to describe it with something.
What happened?
You felt explosions before and there's
kind of that when the shockwave goes
through you and you kind of feel
your brain kind of jar a little bit.
And I would kind of feel that.
And then for a split second,
I would kind of,
it would be like I was getting hit by an
explosion for a split second of it like
that. And I'd be like, did I just,
did I just pass out or something?
And we'd be like, no. I was like, what
is that? So, but that, you know, that
some kind of way,
like mental aftershock.
Yeah, I, yeah. I don't know what it
was. It's, I asked the doctors about it.
They said, well, I'm never, I don't know
what that is, but luckily it went away.
And after maybe it had something
to do with the, the drugs,
I don't know. But, uh, yeah, but you know,
eventually you get used to that body kind
of gets adapted to it and you get your
senses back.
And it's hard to look at a computer screen
for the first couple of weeks still.
But eventually I would
see ants crawling on me.
Uh, but yeah, as you know,
so eventually all that kind of goes away
and you're just stuck with your little
button for pain.
I remember they,
you can only hit the little only
unless you hit it every three,
four or five minutes
or something like that.
And they would come in during the first
little bit and they would say, you know,
you can only hit that thing like
12 times in a minute. Right.
Is that, yeah. And then they
say, well, you hit it about
110 times in the last hour.
And I'm like, well, I'd be, I,
cause I'd be kind of like falling asleep
and then I'd hit it and be like, oh,
make sure I make sure I got that hit the,
so I just hit it again.
And so, yeah. And then,
but eventually kind of get used to
it and then paint starts to go away.
I am sitting here thinking about like,
I've been hospitalized a couple times
for a couple of different surgeries and
what a complete pussy I was,
you know, in they're like, oh,
this hurts. You know, and I, I, you
know, this is, this is true, you know,
repair something. Like I had a
hernia operation, I had neck surgery.
Like these are planned operations.
The openings in my body were made by
a highly skilled surgeon, you know,
and I'm in, they're like, oh, this
sucks so bad. I mean, I can't,
I like what you have is
like a thousand times,
a thousand times worse and it's,
it's hard to even imagine.
And then on top of this, I'm going back
to the journal here, to top it all off,
I had my pirate hat on my head.
I was practically being
held together by duct tape,
like an old dilapidated chair.
You're trying to get one or one more
good year out of what's up with a pirate
hat.
Well,
so you're not supposed to wake
up when you go through Germany.
So basically you go from site of injury
to Camp Leatherneck to Bagram air force
base to launch still Germany to Bethesda,
Maryland for marines,
and then just go straight to
Walter Reed for anybody else.
Marines and sailors go to Bethesda.
And so for whatever reason,
I wake up in Germany
for, I don't know, 15,
20 minutes and my squad leader was there.
Uh, he was there for something else. I
don't remember what he was there for,
but he, so he was there and I go, hey,
you kind of told me what
happened and that kind of thing.
And I just,
I couldn't help but think,
even though it was super drugged up,
it was like,
my mom is gonna not and
she's going to be sad.
And so all I could think of,
I'm always trying to crack a
joke or whatever. So I was like,
see if you can see if you can
find a funny, he had heroin
and he couldn't find one.
Right.
They're not going to have funny hats
in a hospital. It's a serious way.
So he went and looked, I guess maybe
he just went outside the rooms, the,
I couldn't find one.
A bog room has a lot of thing or
Germany has a lot of things, but uh,
maybe not a funny hat store.
Uh, so couldn't find one.
I get to Bethesda and when
you get to the hospital,
they pick you up from wherever they fly
you into in these big basically semi
tractor trailer, Haas, uh,
ambulances and they,
they have,
they alert the hospital or we're coming,
we're going to be there 2:00 PM and all
the doctors come down and they rush you
in and, uh, do what you need to do.
And so a lot of the times that's
where families will see there,
there are service men
when they first get back,
when they're unloading them and they give
them Kinda, you know, 15, 20 seconds to,
hey, good to see you. And
then they take you off.
And I don't know how it happened,
but I'm rolling down the thing and there's
my mom and she has this pirate hat in
her hand.
I don't know if somehow they got
bored back to her. Still don't know.
No, I haven't. I think I think
somebody else brought it.
I don't think she brought it,
but I don't know why they would've brought
me a pirate hat unless somebody had
found out that I had asked for a
stupid hat or something. Cause I have,
I've never been known to wear
pirate hats are stupid hats before.
So there was my mom with a stupid hat
and then so it kind of became a theme.
Like people would bring me a stupid
hat. What did, they came and visited me.
So I had a big bag eventually.
But,
so I guess what happened,
you know,
I hope it kind of helped ease the pain
little bit from my mom. And that initial,
that initial, uh, meeting
maybe a little bit, but uh,
I dunno.
So then you spend,
how long are you in?
Are you in like Icu for where they're
trying to get you more stabilized?
I was probably there for about a
week and then you move up to the,
the fifth floor for the hospital,
which is kind of where they put all the
amputees and there were actually three
Joneses there at the time.
So the nurses had to be very careful.
And on top of that,
my I'm Jones are our first two initials.
My buddy who got hit and maybe an
hour before me, his name is Jones,
d d and then the third Jones was Jones,
Jay Jay Dang.
So they had to be on it with,
you know,
with checking what medic cases
are going to, to who is, but yeah,
so that then he'd go up to the fifth floor
and that's kind of where you start to
become lucid and that's where they
physical therapists start to come in and
that's where once you're kind of ready,
like you start just lifting a leg,
want 10 times, just lift your stomach.
Then you describe that in your journal,
what it was like exhausting
for you to yeah. And it hurt.
And what's making it,
is it because you've been laying there
for so long is because it's a movement
that you haven't been able to do in a
while? I don't just all of the above.
I would imagine a lot of that stuff down
there. It's just swollen and painful.
You know, it's, I think that's probably
what it would be. And so yeah. Uh,
it hurts so bad just
to even move it at all.
And so they start with that and then
eventually you get in your wheelchair and
it takes about 10 minutes for you to get
into your wheelchair and tape belt for
people to get you into your wheelchair.
Cause you're just like sliding off
and you just so sore. But you know,
eventually you get better.
And I could, you know,
I made a big deal about the first day
that I got in my wheelchair by myself and
then I would go for
little rolls around the,
the floor and somebody would
have to like, we all, my, uh,
my little ivy pole and I have
to hang my catheter bag on the,
that was so scared. I was, I was like,
watch that tube to not let that
tube get caught into anything.
And so yeah, I would, I would just do
a few laps around the ward, get out.
And then when I was done,
I go visit my buddy Daniel
because he couldn't get out
of bed yet cause he had a,
I don't, I don't know why
you couldn't get out of bed,
but he couldn't get out of bed.
So I'd be on in his room and
hang out for a little while.
And then how long is it before
you're thinking to yourself? Okay.
Or what makes you start thinking,
oh, well this is my game plan.
This is where I'm going with like you
see guys that are further along the
process and you say, okay, I see what
that guy doing. You know? Yeah, I,
I'm going to do that too. Well, I sent
a little,
uh,
I phone message to Daniel who is too down
in the store down on the fifth floor.
And my body took a little,
and he was like, why don't
you say something to Daniel?
And so I said, listen, first step,
make a workout program to get back to
where we were before to get on our feet
again. So it was a media, I was like,
we are going to just work out
and we're going to get better.
And you know,
so they don't do a whole lot of
prosthetics at Bethesda. Well they do now,
but they didn't back then.
And so the nurses would kind of have a
general idea of how the prosthetic stuff
went and the physical
therapist would know.
But the major thing was the
visits from Walter Reed.
So the wounded warrior battalion people
would bring people that were further
along in their recovery over to visit
the guys that had just been freshly
wounded.
And so I got to one of those visits,
I don't remember
there being a double above
the knee amputee that came
to see me that was in legs
yet, but they had a better idea.
And they would say, look, you know,
you're going to get over there and
you're going to get your prosthetics and
you're gonna be able to walk again.
You're going to be able to run,
you're going to be able to
do this and that. And so the,
at that point I'm like,
oh, so I'm not going to,
I don't have to be in a wheelchair
forever. Oh, okay. You know,
so it was about at that point.
And then what did w how'd you
develop your workout program?
Well,
uh,
once I became lucid, I was doing pull
ups on my little triangle. You know,
how they had the little triangle thing
dangling down, started getting after it.
I wasn't doing well,
I was doing pull ups.
I was probably doing like a
horizontal rows or something. No,
it's just like lifting myself up whenever
the physical therapist couldn't come
in and do her stuff with me, I was like,
all right, well I'm just going to do,
he's going to pull myself
up on this thing. And
so that was, and I kind of, I
went off the therapists, um,
experience for the,
for most of it in the,
in the beginning until I kind of got on
my own because I don't, you know, they're,
they've been doing this for
nine years at that point.
So they had a lot of drills and
strengthened exercises that I can do and,
and that kind of thing.
So I just kind of let them take the
reins and just did whatever they said and
then did it again.
Um,
but then once I got to a point
where I was, were kind of like,
where you see me now, I'm
walking around, no problem.
That's when I started venturing
into trying to do regular gym stuff
and I invented my own way of doing
straight leg dead lifts. So it's,
I strapped myself to a pole and I
sent it down to leaned down and I do a
straight leg dead lift as it put,
cause I can't squat.
Right, right. Yeah. Uh,
I thought this was a really cool part of
your journal that you wrote and you're
talking about getting through
that kind of stuff. So here we go.
Back to the journal is easy
to be motivated to succeed
in the beginning of an
endeavor and when you
are close to the end,
the most difficult part and the part
where people quit is when they are in the
thick of it.
And it is unclear whether they have the
strength and stamina to make it the rest
of the way.
While I never actually doubted my
ability to walk again during my recovery,
I am certainly subject to the
inner monologue rationalizing,
why does o k to quit or to not push myself
to the goal that I've written down on
paper.
One Way I've recognized to aid in
shutting that monologue the fuck up is
celebrating milestones.
The hardest part of working toward a
goal is when we are either making slow
progress or negative progress and having
the patience and confidence to know
that the improvements we make over the
long periods as opposed to the short
periods are what matter.
Okay.
Milestones are what reminds us that we
are making progress even if it isn't a
parent every day.
Okay.
In rowing,
I've heard of people that count strokes
until the finish line using sets of 10.
Personally I like to count two
fifties for making up a race.
When I ran the nation's triathlon, I
picked points ahead of me to make it too.
And when I got there I'd pick a new point.
Anything we can use to keep our minds
from succumbing to the monologue will work
not only in shirt,
short term goals,
but also in longterm goals like
graduating from college or learning to use
prosthetics.
Great advice for anybody
to pay attention to.
Now you mentioned rowing there.
So this was no like a weekend
row that you decided to do this.
You got after it. Yeah.
So how'd that come about?
Um,
so I was,
I was looking for that workout
program. I knew at this point, hey,
I'm alive, I'm going to still try
and have the best life possible.
And so
I'm trying to get back what I,
what I lost so to speak.
And I used to like working out and
go into the gym getting after it.
And so, um, I'm sitting there going, well,
what's the new, what's another
way that I can work out now? Um,
and so I started looking up,
I forget what I looked up disabled
sports or disabled work at like Google
something
and Google getting Africa at Google.
And
so the Paralympics comes up.
I don't know what the heck is apparel.
I know the Olympics,
I don't know what the Paralympics is.
Is that like the Special Olympics?
And the answer to that question is no.
And so the Paralympics is the
Olympics for disabled people,
for people with disabilities.
It was like, all right,
well I fit into that category.
Let's see what sports they got.
And I saw they had rowing I so well,
you know what I used to,
I used to hit the rowing machine when I
was working out getting on the concept
two. Yeah. The concept to
doing some sprints on that
thing. That was pretty tough.
And I want something that's tough.
So I was like, you know what,
I'm going to see, I'm going to look
into this rowing thing and maybe I'll,
maybe I'll make the Paralympics one day
and this is when I would just got to the
hospital like my second
week in the hospital.
Not, not real strong point
in the page that says, Hey,
you got to set yourself a goal right away.
You don't have something you're
working towards, then you're just,
yeah. Tread water. Um, and so yeah,
and a lot of things fell into
place. Uh, there was, uh,
I probably didn't go out and try and
learn to row on the water until the next
year,
so I was,
my main focus at that point was still
learning the prostate's getting my
strength back. But once I kinda got
my strength back and I was really,
I felt like I was ready to move
on kind of outside of the therapy,
uh,
angle on it.
I looked up places where I could
learn to row and just, I mean,
just so happened there was one in DC.
And so I went down there and I learned,
and I mean I don't want to brag,
but the guy said I was a natural.
So, uh, this is like,
well, maybe I can do this.
And so I convinced the,
they didn't have real machine in the
physical therapy clinic at the time.
They had an elliptical,
they had all sorts of equipment.
They didn't have a rowing machine.
So I convinced the
clinic,
whoever was running the clinic to get
a rowing machine for me so I could row.
And then when I was trained
for the nation triathlon,
I convinced them to let me bring my bike
in and, and ride my bike in the clinic.
So I had my own,
I've starting to build my own gym inside
the gym and I convinced them to get a
kettle bell for me and stuff.
Um,
and so I convinced them to let me,
uh, let me have that roll machine.
And so a couple of times a week I would
go down to the water and train on the
water. The other times I would
just do some sprints on the,
on the rowing machine. And then it just
kind of kept, I kept getting better. And,
and this was 20,000,
a 2011 so then the Paralympics or 2012.
And
is there like a specific
coach that runs the, the,
the rowing team?
There isn't
in some sports there are,
there's like there's a head coach is
in charge of everybody in hell train
everybody.
But for my category and Paralympic rowing,
it's pretty much you find your own
coach and you show up at this race.
And if you win that race then
was that America and all the races
for that year. How far is the row?
It's a thousand meters.
So what is that like?
It takes you a couple minutes.
Three minutes.
Um, so rowing, trunk and arms only,
it was my category,
so it would take me my best ever time
on the Erg was probably like three 38,
I think. Um, and that's like
puke level put now. Yeah,
for me. Yeah. Um, and then on the water,
the best in a double.
So two people,
um,
my category,
you have to have two people in the boat
was just right around four minutes.
If you could do four minutes,
then you had a shot at winning
and that's a thousand meters to,
it's a thousand meters.
So you're always gonna be a
little bit slower on the water.
And you say it's four minutes, you
said? Yeah, about four minutes.
So it's like a complete gut check.
It's,
it's the equivalent of
sprinting like the mile. Yeah.
Cause you're going four minutes, right?
Forming a mile. I mean it's, it's no joke.
It's a, it's a tough, tough, tough race.
And where was the Paralympics that year?
Oh, the Paralympics.
We're in London in 2012.
And so I was just getting ready for that.
I was getting ready to retire.
I need something to do too.
And just so happened that my coach that
at the time knew somebody else and do
this, this other coach that had a female
that was, uh, looking for a partner,
also a double above the knee amputee.
And so my boat classes, one guy,
one girl. And so we met up, rode together,
look like we were pretty good pair and
once I retired, moved down to Florida,
started training for the Paralympics.
How long did you have to train?
So I got out in
late December,
so say called January 1st and
I,
we had the Paralympic final
September 2nd or September 3rd.
Okay, so you had a decent
chunk of time, but yeah. Good.
Nine months of crushing yourself.
Yeah. Train twice a day every day
or twice a day. Six days a week.
Take off Sunday and
just sprints, you know,
technique a lot. Technique. Uh, yeah.
Do you have to do the
technique in the water? Yeah.
I mean you can do it outside of the
water a little bit, but it's really,
you got to practice your technique
in, in the water. It's absurd.
It's like Jujitsu, you just got
to, it doesn't matter if you,
if you're doing like in an a
fake fake scenario you had,
it doesn't really have the same effect
unless you're doing it in the real thing.
Yeah. So you get to
England and boom. Yeah.
How many races is there an
England? Is it just one race? No,
luckily there was a couple of races.
So we had to do when the trials race,
which was to find out who
represented America. Well, one that,
and then we had to go qualify
our boat for the Paralympics.
And so we had to go to Serbia about,
uh,
maybe a month after winning the trials
to qualify the boat. So we won that race,
qualified our boat,
and then Paralympics,
you show up and you do your heat
and then if you win that right,
how many boats are in heat?
A six.
So there were 12 boats stole
six in each eight, two heats.
So if you win that heat, you automatically
go to the final. If you don't win that,
he,
you got to go what's called
the [inaudible] stands for
second chance in French.
And uh, you have to come first or
second in that. So we want our episode,
we lost our heat to the Chinese,
which still makes me so mad.
And, uh, we want our rapid shock.
So we were in the final and we started
the final and dead last and just slowly
over the course of the race.
This was our race plan.
We kind of wanted to start
slow and build slowly.
We just wrote in one boat and the next
boat and the next boat until we got to
the end.
And we're about
six. She, between us and the
great British vote, the home team,
everybody's cheering for the home team.
And so third place gets a metal
fourth place. You don't get anything.
You got nothing. Yeah. So,
and we're doing our final sprint and then
we crossed the line and I don't know,
I, I wasn't looking over
there, my forearms were numb.
I was just trying to hold onto the oars
and then it comes up on this little
board, you know, first place,
China, second place friends,
and then there's this,
this long pause,
look it over there. Then it goes
third place USA. And I'm like,
and you look at the video, it's literally
like the length of one of these knives.
Yeah.
That close point,
2.2 seconds between them and
us. That's crazy. So close.
So did you meet anyone while you draw
on that event? Right. You're right.
You're telling me you met, avoid
over. I got it back. Oh, well, um,
so I'll tell you
when we were first got
there and we were training,
we were doing, we would go out, we were
probably there a good week beforehand,
so we'd go out and train on the
lake and continue our training,
get used to the area,
my partner and my,
my role and partner and I
were watching the other teams.
And then there's another boat class
called the four. So it's four people.
And I saw this great British for rode
by and there was this gorgeous blonde
in the bow of the four.
And I said,
I just bit my lip,
like that's a good looking
chick, Eh, you know, I didn't,
I never expected to meet her
or anything because you know,
we're not racing against each other and
she's from another team and you kind of,
you know, until the race is over,
you gotta be professional. Sure.
She, even though she was
super nice, she was very high,
but you know, and she, she, uh,
she'll tell me back when she told me
what she saw me around, I was looking,
because I was in, I was just in serious
Marine Corps modes. Don't talk to him.
Yeah.
And so, uh, racing's over, we're
back in the athletes village.
It's time to get after it.
There's a casino outside the
Athlete's village. So, uh,
the American contingent goes out
to this casino starts, we're part,
I'm still at this point,
I'm still kind of in like serious mode.
It takes a couple of days to get out of
it, you know, serious, serious mode, uh,
still a little bit pissed that
we lost to China and France.
And it's like the two people, the two
countries that my buddies were like,
don't lose to China or France.
They were taking shots like every two
feet they were following on at home and
they take the shot.
They woke up so early in the morning.
Um,
so we're out there. Then the, the British
team comes in for that. Just one gold.
Right. And they're all, they're all happy.
So we're the only two groups
that speak English. So,
uh, yeah. So our two groups, you know,
kind of end up together and it
took, it took them a while to, uh,
get me to out of my shell
because I was like, you know,
still kind of on my guard.
I, yeah, this is the first,
then maybe the second time I'd ever
traveled outside of America for anything
besides deployments.
I had never traveled outside of America.
Serbia was the first time
England was the second time,
so it was kind of still
on my guard a little bit,
but they started feeding me,
fosters lightened up and
then just so happened the,
the gorgeous blonde I
saw was there. So, hey,
you guys know how charming
I am. So charmed her, well,
you at least fooled her.
I'm sure the alcohol helped, you know,
but a charmed her and now we're married.
So that's awesome. After four years
of long distance relationship,
because he kept rolling,
she,
she actually defended her a gold
medal in Rio and did it again. Yeah.
Got Gold again. So we did, we did about
a, we didn't get together right away. We,
we did a long distance
for about three years.
She live in England and I was
living in America, but uh,
finally got her over here. We're married.
Yeah. Her name's Pam. Nice. Okay.
Well obviously I have a certain
affinity for British ladies as well.
Pretty well known.
Uh,
now you mentioned real quickly you
were training for triathlon in there
somewhere too. Yeah. So
the people at the clinic,
it was a, I mean it was
a team effort. Everybody,
so,
okay.
They were other,
other amputees in there.
And I mean we talk about
this a little bit yesterday.
Dan Can Austin navy seal that was
there for a year before me and Anne
Paralympian as well? Yeah. Oh yeah.
Paralympian to the biathlon. Um,
he was my,
my idol I guess for
when I first got there,
cause he was pretty much done with
therapy. He was about to get out.
He was walking everywhere on his legs,
Karina backpack around.
And he was almost the exact same injuries.
You just above the knee.
Yeah.
And so I could see him from when I
was just sitting in a wheelchair.
Right. All right. That
is, it's possible. Yeah.
Because I'm seeing it with my own
two eyes. It is possible. And so,
and he's a stud and yeah,
if you want us to,
if you want to try and be like anybody,
it's be like damn. Cause Yeah. Um,
and so that's kind of the,
the environment that they had there at
Walter Reed was you could ask somebody
that had been there before,
tips, tricks, anything like that.
And so I saw Dan and I was asking him
stuff and just watching how he did stuff.
And then eventually he left and I
kind of noticed, you know, I am now,
there's new guys coming in and I'm
now that person that has been there.
And so I need to step into that role
and offer advice and work harder than
anybody else in the clinic and show
people what's going on and show people
what's possible.
And so the therapists would always be,
hey, you want, who wants to run the army
10 miler? Who wants to do this triathlon?
They'd always be getting offers.
They ought to be getting slots in races
because people love having wounded
warriors out there.
So they make a big deal.
But they get let them go off
first and everything. So yeah.
So,
and every time they asked me if I could,
if I wasn't doing anything else that
day, I'd be like, yeah, yeah, I'll do it.
And so they're like,
you want to do the nation's triathlon?
It's a Olympic distance triathlon and
there's like two people doing it and no
other, it's like a single below the
knee amputee doing it and that's it.
And you're a double above
knee amputee. You want to do
it? Yeah, I do. And it just,
so, cause it just so happened at the
time I was learning how to ride a bicycle
again,
normal bicycle.
So you're learning how to
ride a bike, might as well do
a triathalon. Exactly. Hey,
you got to give him, one of the
things that's going to drive you
to push yourself is having skin in
the game. Having something to lose.
Having said that in a risk.
So if you say to everybody in the clinic,
I'm going to do the nation's triathlon
and you don't do it, you're an idiot,
you're a loser.
How long has the Olympic
triathlon? Uh, Olympic
stents,
the swim is 1500 meters.
The bike is 40 kilometers
and the run is 10 kilometers.
Um, luckily for me, cause I
wasn't not that good at swimming,
luckily for me the swim got canceled that
year because there was a huge storm as
a ton of debris in the Potomac.
So we didn't do the swim,
but we did the bike and the run and yeah,
so I was,
I was relearning how to ride a bicycle.
Nobody had ever done that before in the
history of Walter Reed double above the
knee amputee trying to ride a bicycle.
And I had figured it out and I kind
of wanted to put it to use, you know,
like I finally figured this
thing out. Um, and so, oh,
what better way to do it then
do the nation's triathlon.
And so it was like,
you know,
baptism by fire in a way.
And so it took me like four hours
to do the whole thing. Okay.
Did you enjoy it?
I enjoyed having done it.
Okay.
Cause I'm just wondering at what point
you made the brilliant decision that you
are going to ride a freaking bicycle
across the United States of America.
Well which was your next we'll whatever
freaking psychotic idea you got again.
Where'd that come from?
I had just learned how to ride the bike
going. I got to do something with it.
I can't make it just this pointless.
I learned that okay I did it. No,
never got to do it again. I was
like, you know what might be fun.
It's just like riding my bike across
the country at some point in my life and
this is what I have. I'm not
even, I'm still in the hospital.
I just learn how to ride the bike.
I should do something like ride my bike
across country, something like that,
you know,
some something cool like that.
And I was rowing, I didn't do it
right cause I, I had, I had made the,
to do the rowing. Right. So
it's, I'm going to do rowing,
but eventually I will do
this cross country bike ride.
And so I did another year
of rowing after that I,
I took the time to kind of plan
it out how I wanted to do it.
And so it took another year of rowing and
then finished world championships that
year and forth.
Um,
and about a month later drove up to Maine,
started riding.
This is in October. And so what was
that? What was that all uh, what was the,
what did that day to day look like? Uh, so
okay,
I had a box truck or you haul box truck.
I bought like a used 200,000 miles.
You help box truck check my,
I laid down some carpets in the back
check, uh, had a couple of cots,
couple of sleeping bags,
supplies
and my little brother who is
about to turn 18 check, uh,
rogered up to drive. Good to go. That's
all you need right there. Box truck water,
two cots carpet and a little brother.
And so,
you know,
really trained much.
What I did was I made sure
that my prosthetics fit
correctly and I was able to
ride the bike. That's all I
really did. I didn't, you know,
go out and ride a hundred
miles or anything, any kind
of formal training for it.
Yeah. Cause I figured what
is the point. Yeah, exactly.
Just start and the beginning is the
training for the finish. Yeah. So
the day to day would be
wake up probably six,
seven o'clock,
you know,
drive out to wherever I was starting
for the day cause he couldn't,
you can't just like
stop and then pull over.
So we'd have to like
drive the truck somewhere,
park it in a church parking lot or a
fire department parking lot and then uh,
don't get apprehended by the cops.
So the first time,
so I had,
I was right,
I mean I'd be riding my bike and then
my brother would be kind of half on half
off the road. And I picked a route
that we didn't have, you know,
not super busy roads.
So I wouldn't get in too many people's
way until I got the Pacific coast highway.
And then people were super pissed.
And uh,
at one point this cop,
the for the first cop I encountered
pulls over in front of us. I'm like,
all right, here we go. He's going
to tell me to stop the ride's over.
And then he gets out and he's like,
I just want to shake your hand, man.
It was like, phew, okay,
this is how it's going to go.
This is so I'm going to
get the cops love me. Um,
and so I wake up,
start riding probably around seven 38.
I might eat breakfast
beforehand. Um, probably ride.
Yeah,
I would do 30 miles a day,
so I'd just break that up however
I felt for the day. Take breaks,
hop in the back of the truck,
sit around for a while and run.
I'd ride 30 miles and then
wherever I finished 30 miles,
I might go a little bit further
for a better spooling off point.
Stop getting the truck drive
off to wherever we might
be able to park the truck
and then spend the night in the truck and
then a drive back out to that spot the
next day. Do it again. Luckily for me,
a lot of hotels started
to offer us night's sleep.
So we really on this sleep in
the truck for the first month,
and then after that we were
mostly in hotels. Okay.
And this was like a six month journey.
Six months, October to October to April.
So she did it through the winter time.
Yeah. You ever heard of the polar vortex?
No. No. What those pull
their Fort Texas here,
like this freezing temperatures that
came down and attacked the nation with
cold, they called him the polar vortex. It
sounded very threatening. It's one step,
one step higher than a shark.
Nedo
uh, 5,000, 180 miles.
Yeah. In the winter time.
Every day for 180 days.
Okay.
Um,
talk about fortitude.
Okay.
In your journal, and I'm going
to read it. It was through,
it was through the true purpose of the
Marine Corps that I became what I am
today. And it is that, it is that,
and that is the act of fighting
the battles of the United States.
It is through the preparation for and
the fighting of America's wars that
marines gain.
They're fine edge and an idea
of the true meaning of courage,
Spirit, tenacity,
altruism and brotherhood.
After having been imbued with the
essential qualities ascribed to marines in
bootcamp,
it is up to the individual marine and
his leadership all the way from the fire
team leader to the commandant to
make him the ideal tool for the core.
Yeah,
and there's no better place
than a war to do this.
Yeah.
It was during my two deployments that I
learned what it means to be courageous
almost on a daily basis.
My fellow marines and I would be subjected
to situations with high potential for
danger and situations
with infinite unknowable,
possible outcomes.
Okay.
The dangerous and unpredictable nature
of these conditions elicits fear,
nervousness and uncertainty in all people.
Okay.
However,
without fail,
when the time came to strap on our gear
and proceed forth into these conditions,
we did it with no hesitation
because it was what we needed to do.
Okay.
To me,
that is courage.
I learned it from the example set by my
leaders and my compatriots and when it
was my turn, I endeavored to
teach others by my own example.
Okay.
My favorite among the many mantras of
the Marine Corps is adapt and overcome.
It is my favorite because it embodies
the spirit and tenacity that marines must
possess in order to be the world's
greatest war fighting force
two marines.
Accomplishment of their mission is of
the utmost importance above that of their
own lives and the ability to
adapt and overcome is key.
Okay.
The idea is straight forward
change whatever you need
to in order to become what
is required to transcend an obstacle.
If there is no bridge over a river,
a marine will swim.
Yeah.
If there was a wall in front of us,
we will blow it apart.
If there was an enemy on a hill
that we want, we will remove him.
Marines do not stop until they
have accomplished their mission,
regardless of any monkey wrench
that gets thrown into their plan,
they will change their plane plan a
thousand times if it need be until what
needs to be done is done,
and then they will move
on to the next mission.
It was these two qualities that kept me,
that allowed me to keep
fighting after hours wounded.
Okay.
My plan of accomplishing something with
my life and making my life as good as
possible was met with
obstacles and monkey wrenches.
Okay.
But since I had already
learned these lessons,
bypassing these obstacles and
moving on was easy and natural,
okay.
The Brotherhood that they're marines
share is the defining feature that
initially attracted me to the Marine
Corps and over the course of two
deployments,
I experienced it to its fullness.
The reason that I was able
to be courageous and adapt
and overcome was because
of the men that stood beside
me doing the same thing
and is because we were experiencing war
and hardship together that we goo grew
close enough that I cared for
them more than I cared for myself
and which sacrifice my safety for
their wellbeing even if it meant being
extinguished
and although it never needed to be said,
I knew this was reciprocated.
Okay.
To me, this is the definition
of brotherhood and selflessness.
Okay.
And from my having been part of such a
relationship is why I am loyal and put
others before myself as if
it were a default setting.
Without the Marine Corp,
I have no idea where I would
be or what I would be like.
All I can say for sure is that I am what
I am now due in large part to what I
was taught and what I experienced during
my five years in the Marine Corps.
Yeah.
Yeah. Awesome. If there's anything
that the Marine Corp teaches you,
it is brotherhood.
It is
endurance.
How to endure
situations. You don't
want to have to be, uh,
whether it's humping around with
a pack or fighting in Afghanistan,
Iraq,
or if it's sitting in the back of a seven
ton and getting drenched in rain and
then having to set up a tent, blah, blah,
blah. It teaches you those things. And so
I already knew all this stuff.
I was good at it by the
time I became an amputee.
And then I got even better
at it once I was an amputee,
even more experience.
And then,
so that led into being able to endure
whatever I had to for the bike ride.
And I think the slogan slogan for the
wounded warrior regimen in the Marine
Corps is, I don't know if this is,
it's Latin, I don't know if it's,
I'm pronouncing it right.
It's [inaudible] and [inaudible],
which is still in the fight.
And you know,
I'm not still in the main fight that's
going on in Iraq or Afghanistan.
I've been taken out of that fight,
but the overall fight,
I'm still in that.
I'm still a representative of America.
I'm still representative of marines.
I'm dedicating myself to help my
brothers that are struggling or come back
wounded.
I'm still in that portion of the fight.
And I mean, just remember,
you just have to remember that that
slogan to stay, stay in the fight,
just keep fighting
are obviously you're staying
in the fight. And I, I, I
again,
reading through your journal stuff is
awesome and there's a bunch of different
things that I wanted to pull
out and obviously I can't
read the whole damn thing,
right? Maybe I could, but I'll leave
that for you. Uh, but one of the things,
you know, I'm always
thinking that what, you know,
what can I pull out that I think will
be really helpful to other people.
And I thought that this thing that you
wrote right here was just something that
can be used by,
by anybody,
especially people that are
facing tough situations,
which as you just mentioned,
you are pretty Dang good at
dealing with tough situations.
And I think this gives a
little insight into that.
So here we go back to your journal.
The Kubler Ross model explains the stages
by which an individual grieves for a
lost intimate. The five stages
are denial, anger, bargaining,
depression, and acceptance. In this case,
it could be said,
I was grieving for myself,
the former me that had died in Sangin.
Yeah.
Since I had a natural understanding of
conservation of energy and an awareness
of the time required to reach my goal,
I instinctively skipped the first four
steps and proceeded the acceptance
portion of the process.
I had decided that to spend my
limited energy resources on denial,
anger,
bargaining,
and depression would be a pointless
waste and would be better left off of my
itinerary.
Okay.
I want her to be able to expand as
much energy as I could toward my goal,
which would not only allow
me to reach it faster,
but would improve the
quality of my success.
Okay.
The sooner I had accepted my situation,
the sooner I could get
to where I want it to be.
Having one's legs amputated above
the knee is categorically a negative
experience. If I hadn't had
the right mindset afterward,
the rest rest of my life could have
also become a negative experience.
Fortunately,
I was able to react to the loss by
accepting the negative energy from that
occurrence and using it to open doors
for myself in order to be sure that my
life would remain a positive experience.
Okay.
No matter who you are,
whether you are healthy or
ill injured or able bodied,
everyone's main purpose in life
is to make it as good as possible.
This is an unchanging objective for
all people. No matter what happens.
Thus, now that I was a double
above the knee amputee,
I needed to figure out a way
to keep my life enjoyable.
With this in mind, I researched the
Paralympics to see if I could participate,
which led to a bronze medal at
the 2012 games. Not only that,
I accepted people into my life who
have enriched it beyond what I could've
imagined from the experiences
associated with sports.
I've learned lessons that have and will
continue to make me a better person.
Lessons that I can pass on
to others in the future.
It was in this way that I was able to
transform the negative experience of
having lost the lower part of my legs
into the positive experience in energy of
participating in a sport and
all that has accompanied it.
Okay.
If you are ill or injured,
use it as a way to discover
a new hobby or career.
If someone is rude to
you and makes you angry.
Yeah,
use the anger to fuel a workout.
If someone you know
has a terminal illness,
use it as an opportunity to make a
difference in their life and in the world.
The most important part of transforming
energy from negative to positive is
being aware of opportunities as they
are presented and having the courage to
seize them.
Energy is all around us.
Constantly fueling and transforming.
It will affect us in ways we
cannot beat per, we cannot predict
be a person that uses
energy intelligently.
Okay.
Instead of wasting it.
I like to say you use the weight
and I kind of analogize it.
I like to lift weights. Sure.
You guys can probably tell,
I like to analogize it with
maybe like a strict press.
So the weight on the bar,
his whatever girlfriend broke up with you,
whatever possible issue you're having.
And you can hold that bar
on your shoulders and you
can just leave it there and
eventually start to hurt.
And then eventually if you
leave it there long enough,
you'll just be on the ground
with that weight on your chest.
You can't move anymore.
Or when you have that weight on
the bar and it's on your shoulders,
your shoulder, press it
and then do it again.
You'd do it again and again.
And then you let your body adapt and
next time you try and lift that weight,
it's nothing you can do that wait
easily, I can handle that, no problem.
And then you can handle even more weight.
And then when you get good at that,
you seek out the weight.
You purposefully try and make things
harder for yourself so that you can just
become even stronger and even stronger.
And you embrace that and you start
to enjoy it a little bit. And so,
I mean, I think that's what
I was trying to say there.
I think you said it. Not
only did you say it, but, uh,
you actually are living that currently
at this time seeking out more.
Uh,
I guess maybe I would even go so
far as to say stupid things to do.
So the next
challenge that you put in
front of yourself is the
thing that you're about to do
right now. And I've never heard
of a challenge like this before,
but you're going to do
a month of marathons.
Yeah.
So these things are only stupid or crazy
rides.
Not Crazy because I did it.
If I had failed, then people could
say it's crazy, so I failed this one,
then it's stupid.
Um,
Nah, man, I'll tell you why did you,
you going out there and making
these things happen. You know, it's,
it's awesome whether you finish or
not. Well, no matter what you do,
the fact that you're putting
these hardcore challenges
in front of yourself is,
it's unbelievable.
Yeah.
So, yeah, all this stuff that I've
written down, what we've talked about,
all the wisdom I've been able to,
to gain through my injury and
through being in the Marine Corps.
I think this the month of marathons I'm
about to do this and everything else
that I,
that I try and do.
I'm trying to be an example because
there's so many people out there.
When I was trying to learn
to ride the bike again,
I didn't know anybody that had ever done
it before until I saw somebody that had
done it and it just made everything.
Once you realize it's possible,
it makes it so much easier because
you know it's, it can be done.
And so
I want to be an example for people to
look at and they see me and they say,
well,
they might not be trying
to run 31 marathons in 31
days and 31 different cities
or ride their bike across the country.
But they can say
there's a double above knee amputee
that ran 31 marathons in 31 days.
I can probably go walk on the treadmill.
So if I just want to be an example of
that and I want to be an example of all of
these lessons that I've learned,
a person that uses the weight instead
of lets it destroy their life,
somebody that stays in the fight
keeps fighting no matter what.
That's what I'm trying to do.
I want to serve to show people
what they can do and especially,
you know,
wounded veterans and people that might
be struggling with what they saw.
And you know,
I'm lucky enough that my mind is clear.
I had a great three concussion.
That's it. No traumatic brain injury,
no post traumatic stress,
nothing like that.
And so I want to show
civilians and veterans like
that it is possible to have a
traumatic experience and come
through and be fine and not have,
not have to suffer from post traumatic
stress that just overwhelms you.
Um,
cause I think in society these days it's
almost becoming expected that you're
going to go to war and you're
going to come back. And so
a lot of people might
end up just being a wall.
I'm supposed to have
post traumatic stress.
So I'm going to manifest it in myself
or they let it get worse or they don't,
they don't fight it.
They just let it happen.
And so I want to be an example of somebody
that uses their experience and it's
just goes and has this terrible
experience and you know,
don't make a big deal about it.
And part of you doing that is running
31 freaking marathons in 31 days.
Yep.
So when do you start a,
so I'm going to start in 31
different cities, different cities,
first city,
London,
a London on October 12th and then
I'm going to fly to Philadelphia.
So basically the way it's going to work,
I'll run in the city,
probably take about the whole thing. I'll
take breaks during the, during the run.
So probably the whole thing will probably
take five and a half, six hours to do.
I'll,
I'll do the run on my own just like
in a park or on a trail out and backs,
loops. I'll do it on a 400
meter track if I have to,
um,
do that,
getting my RV drive to the next place,
spend the night there.
We upgraded from a box truck
with the clots in the back.
Well the wife's going to be coming along
so she wasn't going to get all going to
have a crew for this.
So when I got my wife,
Pam is gonna be my team leader.
She's just doing so much stuff.
She's a team leader or the everything,
every job that you
could possibly think of.
She's doing it and my mom is coming cause
he a massage therapist and she's going
to give him a saws and I'm
going to have a driver,
not my brother this time
I think I blew him out.
That was the first time of I'm been to
have a driver and so we're going to all
hop in the RV drive too.
So from Philadelphia to New York,
run in New York,
repeat until I go all the way around.
I'm going to end November 11th
veteran's day DC on the National Mall.
And,
and your goal obviously is to show people
and lead people and to set an amazing
example. And on top of that you're
going to earn, you're going to,
you're going to earn money for
some real specific charities that,
that you believe in and stand behind.
And what are those charities?
Yeah,
so my goal,
my main goal is obviously the to be the
example and all these kind of grand uh,
objectives. But you
know, how do you really,
you can't quantify that really.
So the way that I'm quantifying it is
I'm going to be raising money for three
veterans charities that I've had
personal contact with that have helped me
during my recovery. Um, and
they are the semper fi fund,
the tunnel to towers foundation and the
coalition to salute America's heroes.
And so that's how I'm going to be.
That's also,
I'm going to be showing veterans that
America loves them because that is
something that's been made abundantly
clear to me. Everywhere I go.
Like all the time,
I think I did three breakfasts in a row
where somebody paid for it anonymously.
I get thanked all the time.
And so if they're saying that stuff to me,
it's obvious that they love all veterans
and I'm trying to help connect that
does reduce that gap between the military
and the civilian worlds and get them
to,
to talk and,
and show that show veterans that
they're coming back to a country that
appreciates them and loves them more
than pretty much any other thing.
And so I think by the donations and by
having people come out and run with me
and show me support, then that kind
of helps us to prove that to people.
So where can we go donate?
What's the, what's the link?
Rob Jones, journey.com
there's a,
there's a donate link there and you can
also see my schedule there and I'll have
details of where I'm going to be.
It's the whole country. It's east coast,
west coast, Yep. Middle of the country,
all the way around. You can drive
in a day to get to the next spot,
to run 26.2 miles.
My longest drive this 1214 hours.
And that happens maybe once or twice.
So it's they're all pretty close to
each other and major cities and yeah,
you can go to my website, Rob
Jones, journey.com donate there,
see my schedule Rsvp that you're going
to show up. You don't have to if you,
but if you want to that's cool.
I'll have all the details there and
then social media's all at Rob Jones
journey.
Awesome.
I,
yeah,
it's awesome man. It's just awesome
and you're freaking awesome.
And I grabbed a couple this a little
short piece from your journal.
Again,
this is something that I just thought is,
is just going to be helpful to me when
I read it and will be helpful to anybody
that that listens,
hears or reads this and here we go.
Back to your journal.
The conscious is in
control of forming habits.
Every time we are faced with
the decision of whether to quit,
slowed down and rationalize a reason why
that's okay or keep pressing forward,
one of those habits is strengthened.
The more times we choose
to push on,
the stronger that habit will become.
It takes time and purposeful effort
for these habits to become ingrained.
But once a person
develops them in the gym,
doing something as simple as choosing
to keep rowing hard for another minute,
they can apply what they have
learned to the rest of their lives.
Yeah.
They will learn to take the harder
path so that they are challenged more.
They will learn to put extra
effort into daily tasks.
Who you are depends entirely on your
influences and the level of effort that is
put into forging yourself
into what you desire to be.
And that's awesome. Yeah. I mean, every,
every decision you make either gets you
closer to your goal or moves you further
away.
And I'm not saying I'd never make
the decisions that movie to the left,
maybe further away.
I'm human just like everybody else.
Yeah, yeah, definitely. Yeah. You know,
we were hanging out yesterday and I was
like, I was busy. I was like, Hey man,
I've got to go. So in that buisiness you
know what I had for dinner last night,
Mrs? No, I did have Mras
that's not happening. Okay. No.
My entire dinner was a leftover piece
of a Caesar Salad and a giant mint
chocolate chip milkshake.
I actually said, my wife is like make me,
cause I was working and I did. You know,
you can't stop and eat when you're
trying to work and so I just said,
can you make me just a giant mint
chocolate chip milkshake now?
I didn't get closer to my,
you know, physical goals. No,
but I got a lot of work done.
Yeah, I got an extra whatever,
28 minutes worth of work though because
I didn't stop to eat dinner. Yeah, yeah.
You got to take the wins with the losses.
I dig it,
Isabelle. You know, making that,
it's like you plot your progress
on a graph and you're going to have
as long it's going to go up and
it's going to go down a little bit,
then it's going to go up
and it's going to be down.
So as long as that trend is upward,
then you know you can relate to,
have nothing to worry about.
But if that thing starts to level
off and then go the other way,
then you need to ask yourself
some questions and you
need to give yourself some
honest answers.
Yeah. You know, we had a
conversation not too long ago,
a guy asked about Jujitsu belts and said,
you know,
I understand that you shouldn't pursue
cause in Jiu Jitsu it's like, hey,
you shouldn't just like go to get a belt.
Uh,
you go cause you want to get better and
you want to learn. And, and he said,
you know, I understand that you
shouldn't just do it to get the belt,
but
it's good to mark your progress
and figure your progress out.
And I was it. And that's true. And
that's what you're saying like, yeah.
And I've talked about
that too. Um, you know,
I related to shooting where when you,
when you focus on the target,
your, your vision gets blurry and
so you lose track of the long term,
the long term goal or
the long range target.
So that's why we focused on our front
site because we can keep that little thing
that's right in front three feet
in front of us on our rifle.
You can keep that in focus.
So that's what you focus on.
And every once in a while if you start
that, maybe that gets a little blurry.
Well then you look at your
longterm targeting cause the,
that daily grind will beat you down too.
And if you just lift the daily grind,
the daily grind, the daily grind
beating you down, and then you, you,
you forget what your goal was in the
first place. But so every once in a while,
yeah, you've got to look up
at your longterm goal and say,
I want to be doing this or achieve that
or whatever. I want to do 31 marathons.
See some people would have
picked like February, right?
We'll do 28 marathons. You're,
you're going to the full 31.
Uh,
that's the difference right there.
If I want to make it,
if I want to make these points,
that's why I rode my bike from
Maine to southern California.
I was sitting there going, yeah, I could,
I could ride Florida to San
Diego. It would be technically
be all the way across,
but technically,
but there'd be that.
But I don't want any buts
associated with anything that I do.
I don't want anybody to have any
reason to say, Oh yeah, Rob Jones,
he ran 31 marathons in 31 days,
not 32. Did you got to do a good job
on, on your social media when you're,
when you go out on this thing,
you got to document this thing
and post it so people can like,
I'm hoping so I'm working
with a sports illustrated.
I think they're going to do a video. I
heard of them. Um, yeah, good outlet.
Do they do good videos?
That's to discriminating judge
of videos. Right. So yeah,
I plan like,
you know,
I documented the a bike ride that's
documentaries on my website too. So yeah,
I do try and document these things and uh,
just in case people don't happen
to catch it while I'm doing it,
they can go back and use that as
their example for, for what I've done.
And they can find out that way.
Yeah.
Well I know you get stuff done and
you hammer out your daily tasks.
We're going to let echo hammer
out his baby task right now.
Technically we porch
time, we can task. I do,
I extra respect on the
weightlifting analogy.
I think like weight lifting
and exercising in general,
like Chris is like the perfect
analogy for those things. You know,
cause it's like, yeah, I mean I could
into it, but yeah, it was good. But that,
that is an APP,
that outstanding analogy like,
hey that waits on you.
You're either going to use it to get
better or are you going to let it bare you
in the ground? Yeah. The choice is
yours. What are you going to do?
Yeah. And like, and it goes to show,
we talk about this sometimes where you
can take let's say a random person, right?
And you'd be like, Hey, let's
go to the gym. And there,
there can be literally opposite reactions
if you get two different people.
So one guy, you can be like,
hell yeah, let's go to the
gym. I'm going to work out.
And it gets dry, need to get in shape.
Good. You know, it's this thing.
Or he can get someone to be like,
that's the worst thing in the world.
I don't want to go to the gym.
I don't like,
that's hard and it hurts the
next day it hurts, you know?
So meanwhile it's the same exact
activity by the way, you know?
So you can look at in
those two different ways,
you know,
what else is messed up is
there's activities that are
also good for you and move
you in a direction that you want
to be moving. But maybe like,
let's say the got, you can, we
can give you a real good example.
You take a meat head,
right? And you go, okay,
you want to go to the gym? What does
the meat head say? Yes, let's go get it.
But then you say to that same guy who
seems all motivated and fired up to
improve himself. Yeah. And you say, Hey,
let's go read a book and
try and understand better
this concept of whatever and
what did they say? Then
they go to the gym. So it's
interesting. Yeah. The weight,
the weight isn't necessarily
just a physical weight,
it's pressing up against whatever it is
that's going to improve you and you can
either use it to beat you down or you
can use it to make yourself better.
Yeah. And again, just as a concept, right?
I think the exercise and weightlifting
and like your body just kind of
figuratively can demonstrate just so
much, you know, that'll place so much
and you especially feel that way
about curls. Is that what I'm hearing?
Depends on the thing, but yeah, generally.
Anyway,
speaking of curls,
which should I go into this?
No.
Your daily tasks. Weekly tasks,
yeah. Yeah. Might as well. Well,
Rob Jones here to listen so, and then
wait to hear the support, the support
you get to witness the supports live
honor. So Watch, watch echo, do his work.
His life's work. His life's work right
here. Support. You have to do this.
We can go to my house and you watch me
edit a video. So, so dope. You know?
Anyway.
Made in America or Gin,
that's the company or didn't
main.com you started in Maine. Yeah.
By credit cross city. Yeah.
That's where this place is.
We just got back what last week?
Yeah. We can ask whatever. Yeah,
that's a cool spot.
You know he has a side note.
He is like this I think is on like the
history channel or something like that
where it was kind of like a show and you
know the story you told about getting,
he got this, the loom right where he
got to actually make right, right.
They came and filmed some stuff
but they can produce it. Yeah.
He showed it to me but it
was great because when he's
telling the story I'm like
man that took you took like eight
hours or something or more than two.
More than that.
Yeah.
I like to get it and it's this big
thing and it kind of showed it.
They were there for that
bill moving the looms.
Loomis and me neither and
that he asked me, he's like,
you know what illumines I was like loom.
I've heard that like Warren was
familiar fruit of the loom. Right? Yeah.
And when you think about it, it makes
sense because fruit of the loom is like,
right. It's the fabric, you know, it
has all the strings, right? Yeah, yeah.
It makes fabric anyway.
So when they say made in America,
in this case it's for real made in
America. They get to cotton from America,
they make it with a loom in America.
This guy p Roberts up in origin,
which were in league now with origin,
but we went up into old mills
cause all the mills up there,
a lot of them shut down. And actually
I think all of them shut down.
And these were,
these were,
these were factories that were like
half a million square feet and they were
filled with looms and filled with
production and filled with a war.
American workers.
And it all went overseas and he
went in and literally bought Allume.
Um, for that, I think that,
I think it was like $3,000,
the cost of the scrap metal that
it was worth and anyways, took it,
hired some old timers that new,
still knew how to work.
It brought them back to work
and then started making clothes.
Well making Jujitsu gies where he
started with but, but you know,
got everything being lined up to get made.
And that loom,
they only had that one because they're
going to put in a museum or something.
Yeah.
They were literally going to take that
one loom that they had left and they're
going to make it a museum over on it
some because there are so many people
out there now that they're like,
oh our country has to make problems,
our country has to may problems.
We need to do this,
we need to do that.
And are they say somebody is to do this,
somebody needs to.
And it's like, Hey, yeah, why want you
and here's the guy that's doing that.
No, it's all guess what bull. Yeah. Yeah.
And it's interesting too
when we went there, you can
tell he's into it. He's like,
he were driving up there, he's talking
about how yarn is all made and stuff.
And he's like, Hey, I got, I got to
calm down because I'm getting to,
I need to say he's into it. Cause he went
out and bought a broken rusty Lubrin,
refurbished it and moved it into a
factory that he built on his own property.
It's ridiculous.
And it shows to the gies like
you might do Jujitsu right today.
Piggies are like, they're cool, you
know, martial arts, Giza, whatever.
But he brings like this added like
element to it because it's specifically
designed for, yeah, for Jujitsu. That's
not the kind where it's like, Hey,
let me get a g blank from overseas or
whatever and then like embroider my logo
on it. So it's kind of like
the same thing. You don't,
you don't have much innovation freedom
with a physical product. He does though.
So it's like I took all his
role and the other day GE,
whenever I take off the top and
you'd left with just the pants.
So the pants are like,
they're by, um, like sizes.
You know you wear a 36 are in regular
stuff is just the like numbers a one,
a two, a three, four, five, six.
This is like fitted to you. Right.
So I'm wearing the pants and they feel
kind of like normal pants and I was Greg
in one. They're like, they were noticing.
You always don't mind getting
choked out by [inaudible]. So sweet.
Here's the thing. My streak everyday and
I wear it everyday. I've to two tops.
I wear it every day and the streak is
still alive every single time someone asks
like what up the key and they call, let
me see, let me see. Yeah, they're dope.
Fabric is woven is legit.
This is legit. Yeah.
And see these shorts I have on right
now, I should, I kind of in a way,
should it mention these
cars be sticking out.
We're not making those shorts
because they don't make these shorts.
I've worn these three days in a row by the
way. Oh, nice. That smell was whatever.
I watched the ones, but yeah,
they're my favorite shorts.
They're made out of the same material
as one of the one of the keys. Yeah,
that looks nice. Yeah. I spilled some
eggs on it. You know, it leaves them,
these shorts are black by,
so you know how you,
when you spill eggs or out of nausea feed
my son yogurt and stuff and it's built
on it.
So you just take a brush like you know
like a brush you find under your sink or
whatever. Put some water and I scrubbed
it. You can't do that on like your shorts,
cattle start to wear it out,
you know. But it gets tough.
It's supposed to be tough. Did
it? You'd have to wash it anyway.
I can't get the shorts. I don't get
robbed and fire it up. We'll make it,
we'll make them. Yeah. So
stand by for that nonetheless.
Do ciggies all kinds of the
rash guards and even like,
like regular clothes,
shirts, hoodies and whatnot.
The joggers acute putting on the joggers
and walking around in front of my wife,
she likes it. That was a weird thing
cause I didn't actually know what,
do you know what joggers are there?
New joggers, you know, they're like,
there are like, what's a
passion thing? No sweat pants,
but they're somehow more high
end. Yeah, the shape is different.
They kind of taper down your leg. Like,
you know, I like skinny jeans and said
I'm going to go ahead and say I don't
endorse that product. Neither did I,
but I put them on and I was like,
I was like these,
I don't know how I look because they
didn't have a mirror in the cabin
except in the bathroom. But nonetheless,
um, so I couldn't see how they look.
They look kind of strange from up here,
but I don't know. So I was like, Eh,
whatever origin he wore,
the origin jogger pants and the matching
origin, the sweatshirt or Hoodie.
And he went, he rolled out
like that. Like it was like,
it was the deal and he looked, he was a
straight up leisure suit is what it is.
Rolling up,
not playing around.
And then when I came in I
thought people would be like, oh,
you know you don't match in that cause
I'm not used to wearing but B if that I
that I looked good in it and then my wife
said I looked good in it. Oh that one
Pete made it.
Of course
he was a moment of honesty because
he mentioned either you, I don't,
I think it was you or someone.
He was like,
I don't think just Jocko could pull
it off or something like that. No,
it might've been someone else. I don't
think he was talking about he's right.
He's away.
Pull it off.
Whatever coes design for
what I did notice though,
not happening there.
I'm maybe I'm not secure in my man had no,
I just know for girls clothes,
rarely, not nonetheless.
Functionally. That is what I noticed
right when I put them on though,
like when you roll out,
you know how like if you have,
and not that it's even a big deal.
Even me talking about things like you
know how it is when like something
happens. But actually when
you wearing skinny jeans,
I actually have no idea
what he's talking about.
But I roll with it cause we're trying to
condense the timeline of the supports.
Speech speaking,
which is hard in the spirit of accuracy.
I'm going to go down this
whole, you know, when you were,
have you ever worn sweat pants ever in
your life? Not really. Kind of sweatpants.
Okay. Rob Jones. I have
warrants pre-injury IIF. Yeah.
So consider this. When you,
let's say like, I don't know, you're
running or walking or whatever.
He's like the sweatpants or you loose.
They flow. Not a big deal. I dig it.
I understand. But the
skinny jeans, sweatpants,
joggers,
I,
we shouldn't even say skinny jeans are
going to get this off my podcast now they
function cause they don't
flap around and they're like,
if you're running with them, they
work. I'm just finally shorts.
Right for that very reason. It's three
feet of snow. I just run in short. It
nonetheless built,
knock it till you try it all.
So Jocko, some supplements, I don't
know if you knew this, Rob Jones,
but super krill oil
available now available boom,
or domain.com or [inaudible] the top labs
labs on the top of the menu.
What do you call it?
The top menu on the website labs.
Super Krill joint warfare.
That's a big one. I mean we know Krill is
like the base, the joint warfare. Yeah.
So good. And the significance. Well
layers if you will. I think, you know,
maybe that's a stretch with layers,
but this is the,
the stuff that you've been taking from
jump as with some bonus bonus stuff,
bonus stuff that I now
can take in one shot.
So like when you're even
before this podcast and stuff,
you're like taking glucosamine and Krill
oil and all this stuff and you're like,
you know what would be make this
even better. It's like, you know,
those little elements or
whatever. And one day, you know,
I'm going to make my own and boom, it
happened kind of. Yeah. So we're in it.
A joint warfare. That's a
good one. A Super Krill.
Describe it has an added thing right in
the Super Krill oil and it's like Super
Krill. Yeah, yeah. Oh that's it.
Super Supergirl. Dope Krill. Okay.
What else is going to add?
It's already super duper
duper.
That'll be super duper all calling us.
He now he's going to take the
market from us. Rob Jones,
super duper Krill oil to just pat it.
Well he does make things have just gotten
the website and that Twitter handle
the domain. It's true. Uh, but yeah,
so basically everything you need for
the joint situation, you're covered.
And then what about that pre work?
A preadmission preadmission pre pre
workout. It's not available yet.
It will be coming soon. It's, we're
not going to talk about that one.
We'll talk about it. We are, it is,
is in the testing phase and has
been being tested and legit so far.
So good. Boom. I'm kind
of addicted to it. Yep.
Also on it.com/jocko.
Okay.
So I get all my kettle bells from on.
I got into kettle bells after this
podcast kind of started. And you know,
ana has awesome stuff.
Specifically the kettlebells
because they're the designer.
Once you seen that guy before it.
So I get the whole set.
Well I don't have the whole set.
Technically I have the weights that
I think I'm going to be able to use.
What's your heaviest one you
have at home? Uh, 40 kilograms.
So what does that 80, 80, 88 pounds.
That's cool man. Cool story. I
got the 90 pound one, so whatever.
So basically all 88 pounds that you have.
I have that plus more and more.
No big deal. All right,
there you go. Go ahead.
And you wear skinny jeans,
skinny joggers,
contemporary joggers from time to time
tracks at least four pounds kettlebell.
It, it functionally it,
it adds it by the way,
got the gorilla ones a few weeks ago.
Um,
the 90 pound one is the big foot,
just for informational purposes ever.
Gonna make a hundred pound Jocko head.
Actually, they said that people
have been saying there's been some,
there's been some requests if anyone
would actually want that. I saw,
I saw a guy sent me a two.
It was a 200 5,200 something
pound kettle bell. Dang.
I don't even know what I mean. Yeah,
I guess. Right? Goals. That's a legit,
there's like, you know, some
people are just mute and strong.
One of my team Guy Buddies, just mute and
strong. I ain't Jiu Jitsu. Great Dude,
but he got the beast. I
don't know who makes it,
but there's a kettlebell called the beast.
I think it's like 102 pounds or something,
but there was like this little test taming
the beast and he got the kettle bell
out of the box. Did the
test passed it? I was like,
I mean things that I couldn't do at
all. I was like, okay, you're legit.
Kettlebells are crazy.
Yeah. Actually it's cool.
That's like one of those exercises
that you, if you learn that the form,
it's like an added element because
you've got to learn the form.
Then the strength and the learning,
the form is good for you
because you're developing.
Okay.
You're developing a neuro
muscular connections. Yes. Boom.
Thank you. Amen. You know, it was lost
for words and you've had me covering move.
No problem. I got you.
But yeah, so you need,
it's basically you have to learn to
balance something that's not balanced.
Yeah know it's good. Like that bag I
lifted in Maine, these guys, it'd be left.
That's good. 200 pounds by
the way. No worries. You know,
it's super hard. I feel the first time
also they got what? Jump ropes. Macy's,
you know, if your workout gets boring,
jacket doesn't have that problem. We know.
We know because you just won't care
here to win and all this stuff.
But some people they get bored,
you know, with a workout,
you get all this cool stuff anyway.
A on it.com/ chocolate's a good one.
Also,
when you buy these extra,
I'll put a link to your journal
if you don't mind. Yeah. But yeah,
it was nothing to buy. It's
free. Yeah, yeah, yeah. But
if you know, you go on there,
I'll put in the book section
and Oh, that'd be awesome
if, yeah, man, it's good.
And if you,
if people want to get some of the
other books that Jocko talks about,
you go to our website.podcast.com books
from podcast that's on the top menu.
And then you click through there to get
your books, takes you to Amazon, boom,
click through there. Or if you do any
other shopping, boom, click through.
That's good way to support small action.
Big Reaction.
It is a legit way to support
for sure it is. I'd be,
I got to ask that two times
now. Yeah. Once in Maine
and I think I was at an event the
other day, uh, and someone asked me,
he does it really help and I was
like, yes it is. Yeah, it, I,
I said it's exactly what echo says it
is. Yup. Small. Actually it takes what,
like three extra seconds.
Yeah. Small action. Boom. One,
two clicks, whatever. And you,
big support. Big Reaction.
Also subscribe to the podcast
if you haven't already. I know.
Seems kind of obvious,
right? Itunes, subscribe.
But if you haven't subscribed or
stitcher or Google play, yeah.
Anything that provides platforms just
subscribed. Good way to support. Easy,
you know, boom. Also Youtube Channel.
We have a youtube channel I put was
the last video. I put it on there.
The book video.
Oh yeah.
Freedom fuel manual. Vdl Awesome job on
that by the way. We're both. Thank you.
Very cool. Pretty good video. I
thought it was pretty good too.
I felt Jocko did all the work really
lifting. That was a hard night too.
I mean you were lifting after
like a whole day. I was like Bro,
I'm not like a long day,
long day. You know him.
He's the kind of where I'm like okay,
I just need like the shots, you know,
cause we're doing it for like other stuff
and I'm going to grab the steels and
whatever and I was like,
I just need the shots.
What I'll do is I'll make it here so you
don't have to put on all that weight.
And he's like, no, I'll feel like plus if
I don't put the weights. I was like, Bro,
you're the man.
Same exact thing.
I was just shooting a video doing
lifting weights and they're like, yeah,
we're just going to do it
with no way. I'm like, no,
but kill the video that I want.
The weight that I want to be on there is
135 pounds. I want that to be on video.
I don't want no wait to be on video.
He even went one further that there
was a few shots that I was getting that
didn't show how much weight. It just
showed the front of the, you know,
it was like an angle you could kind of see
part of the way. Kind of. He's like, no.
He's like, he wouldn't
allow him, so you know,
I took the Rob Jones
approach. I was like, okay,
I've got to move somewhere it around.
I'm going to use the opportunity
to make myself better. I out.
I was getting after it. He's a
method actor. That's exactly right.
Yeah. Hey, it worked out for him
and I dig it, but yeah, nonetheless,
back to youtube. Boom. We put
some videos on there including,
but not limited to the video version of
this podcast. Also additional videos,
excerpts and various other videos,
deleted scenes if you will.
A lot of times we talk rubbish
before we actually include,
you know, or we don't
include in the podcast. Um,
so sometimes we'll cut that up and put
it on there too to add in entertainment.
You know, here Jocko swear a lot. You
know, he doesn't swear that much on on,
on the record, but you know, he
gets after it from time to time.
Also myth on the hanging out
with like one of my bros.
Effin just effing get nuts with F in
squats and your effing thing. He was like,
yeah, he like over did it
nonetheless. Yeah, youtube,
that's a good one. Um, also Jocko has
a store, if you didn't already know,
guess what it's called. I want to go
on a limb. Say Jocko store the store.
It's that Jocko store.com. We've got
some t shirts on there. They're cool.
They're cool. You know, some
layers on those t shirts,
layers meaning not physical
layers. Uh, what do you call it?
Poetic layers.
Poetics that's really reaching.
It's reaching a lot of
good. It's pretty poetic. Is
that one myself. You know what the
layers are with that though, right?
If you look at the good shirt it has
jock was head. That's good, right?
But the good is backwards.
And here's the thing.
That's why when people try to
counterfeit that one, they don't,
they don't get the layers. They just
see jungle shaded old little old.
That's a marketing thing or whatever and
let's sell that. But they don't get it.
They don't know the layers. The good is
backwards. It's backwards for a reason.
That better write it in the mirror.
Cause who are you saying that when you
hear that? Who are you saying that too?
You're not saying you know to your poor
daughter who's crying cause she skinned
her knee. You don't say good. She's like,
oh she cries more. That's not her main.
It's not your missing message to give
somebody else your message to give to
yourself and your daughter cry in the
first place. Well, she's sensitive.
I'm cultivating her sensitive site.
That's all.
You're not wearing a tee shirt for
yourself to look down like that.
We're in it so other people can read it.
You can read it in a typical case,
but not these teachers. That
tee shirt is for you. Create a,
for you with the message with Jacqueline's
face. Apparently that's free to,
not for everybody,
but this is for you.
And unless that's just an example
of the layers on the shirts,
Jocko stark.com. There's also some hoodies
on there, some travel mugs, bumper,
bumper stickers.
The Jocko 2016 I took it off.
We lost that election. Yeah, you did.
Sorry, I got like 27 votes. Yeah,
I got some legit votes.
People posted them on Twitter.
Some people wrote me in straight
up. I did. You know what?
I don't want Hillary Clinton. I don't
want Donald Trump. I want Jocko.
Yeah. I think it might've been
a good choice actually happen.
I think it might've been a good choice.
Yeah.
Someone actually told me that I
should run for vice president.
That wouldn't have been a good
choice. Uh, I don't know if you would,
would've gotten my vote and I don't know.
I wouldn't have got my booty.
Nonetheless. There's some cool
stuff on Jocko star. That's
the point. Um, you know,
I'm not saying go buy some stuff. I'm
thinking go on there, see what up,
see what's on there. And
if you like something, get
something good way to support.
Also, there's a little thing
called psychological warfare.
You ever heard it? Yeah,
I think I have. It's pretty dope habit.
I'll tell you what, all day. Okay.
So I don't have to let you know that
it's an album with tracks Jocko tracks.
So basically if you don't already
know the Rob Jones notes, John knows,
I know obviously
let's say you're on your
campaign against weakness.
That's, that's the official
going turn candidate campaign
against weakness. Right.
And I'm going to be disciplined
in all these areas on my life.
Waking up early diet. I'm
going to work out, you know,
however many times a day study,
study, get smarter, work harder.
Yeah. Just normal stuff. Normal
getting after it. Yeah. Campaign.
Yeah. And you have a moment
of weakness like Jock,
go with the mint chocolate chip ice cream.
Avoid that. Jock obviously didn't
listen to his own album with tracks,
taco tracks of psychological warfare.
What you do is anytime you,
you come across these moments of weakness,
listen, put a track, put a track in.
Like if you're having a hard time waking
up you to hit the snooze, whatever, boom.
Get wake up, get up, wake up,
wake up, wake up and get after it.
That's the track name.
Help you right through that
weakness. Smashed the weakness
out actually. But yeah, psychological
warfare, Jocko Willink, MP3,
iTunes, wherever Amazon mp3s
are being distributed, that's
where you can get them.
Uh,
you can also on Amazon,
you can get something
called Jocko white tea.
Rob Jones had his first Jocko white tea
today. Delicious. Not only delicious,
but I've noticed you've
been very attentive.
You're words are crisp and clear.
I mean, you feel the power, right?
Yeah.
It totally angry at him.
He's ready to rock and roll.
Tenacity by a mental capacity
and Carissa at least tenfold.
Yeah, if not more. So there you go. Jocko
white tea. You can get that on Amazon.
It t legit though. How good does it taste?
Oh, it's really good. And it does it,
it doesn't really taste like tea,
right? He likes kind of tastes like tea.
Does have any sugar in it.
No.
You're telling me Jocko white tea doesn't
have any sugar and taste that good and
it tastes that good. What does it taste
like? Vegetable. It tastes like victory.
Uh, they, we got some books on Amazon
and wherever you want to buy books.
Extreme ownership,
combat lesson,
combat leadership lessons learned and
how you can apply those to business and
life way of the warrior kid.
Yeah.
Weigh the warrior kid. That's what you
need to get for every kid. You know,
it is so helpful for kids.
I wish I had that book when I
was nine years old, 10 years old,
11 years old.
It is so helpful and I'm
getting such great feedback.
So by that,
for the kids,
you know for sure coming up soon.
The discipline equals
freedom field manual.
Okay,
that's right.
It is a field manual.
How to implement and execute
operation discipline into your life.
Fall the field manual.
You can get it from your local bookstore.
You can get it from Barnes and noble.
You can get it from Amazon.
Let them all know what's up.
Okay.
Also Echelon Front leadership
consulting for Your Business or team.
That's where we do.
You can email us@infoatechelonfront.com
and in the meantime if you need us or
you just want to check in,
we are rolling kind of deep
on the Inter webs on Twitter,
on Instagram
and a face sheet ball hockey.
Rob Jones is at Rob Jones
Journey at Rob Jones journey.
He's going to be documenting all this
awesome slash could be stupid but could be
mostly awesome stuff that he's doing and
we like to watch people do crazy stuff.
So yeah,
we're going to watch you do that and I'll
post a picture and then usually I like
to put a little snippet
of wisdom in there.
It's a little paragraph for people to
read. Nice a day. So the New York Times.
Yeah. Don't, don't do that.
Just go straight to the,
to the Rob Jones snippet of wisdom.
Yeah.
I like the example how you say you want
to be the example because some people
they say, I just want to be the
exempt, but they don't explain it.
You just explained her actually in a way
that was kind of revealing to me where
it makes sense. You know,
you're like, Hey, I'm going to,
and this goes for everything by the way,
like if you want to,
I do like a special effects sometimes
and I'm like, man, I want to do this,
but man, that's like some high enough,
I can't do it on this. And then,
but then let's say look it up on
Youtube and be like, oh wait, look,
he did it right here. And then, you know,
sometimes it show him house show house,
sometimes they don't. But like how
you said like if you don't think,
like if you think, oh, you had
that kind of can't be done.
You don't like for so many of my
position or whatever, you know?
But then you see someone all the way,
he's doing it and then you're doing it
where it's like you're doing even more.
So it's like, ah, you're kind of
reaching more people in that way.
Cause still you're doing
these crazy things. Maybe one,
maybe two other people be
like, yeah, I can do that too.
But most people there'll be like,
can do that easy stuff,
but I can do all this other stuff.
You know what I mean?
Other stuff that they didn't
think they could do before.
That's good. That's the word.
It's crazy. That's stupid.
The stuff you're doing is
awesome. It's crazy. You've
got to be crazy to do it. Uh,
so yeah, Rob Jones Journey
and that includes Rob Jones,
journey.com as well,
which in that from there you can get the
d to the donation page for when you're
starting all this, all this, uh,
31 marathons in 31 days.
Most people run a marathon and it,
I think I've read it takes like six months
to actually recover from a marathon.
Yeah, I guess it depends on
your level of preparedness,
but try and do it in about six hours.
That is awesome.
Echo is at echo.
Charles and I am at Willink Echo.
You got anything else for today?
Thank you for coming on. Rob Jones. Rob,
any closing thoughts from you?
Oh,
I just want to start by pointing out that
I think every guest you've ever had on
this podcast is somebody that I
consider to be a hero and I it,
I don't throw that around.
They're patriots and they are heroes and
it is humbling for me to be included.
For you to have me on the
podcast is vastly humbling
for me to be included among
the people that you deem
worthy of being on the podcast.
So I just want to thank both of you for,
for having me and giving
me this opportunity and I
just hope that some of the
stuff that I said can resonate
with with some of the,
some of the listeners and beyond that
I've done a lot of stuff,
but
nobody does that by themselves. I have
had so many people that have helped me,
therapist, prosthetist, coaches,
mentors and family,
friends.
And then especially Pam,
I mean
I told you before she's doing everything.
She was instrumental in getting
this podcast done, getting me on as,
as a guest here, took it upon
herself to, to tweet you.
She's calling press, she's
helping me get venues. She's,
it's been incredible and she's
my number one supporter and uh,
you know, too good for me, but
hopefully she doesn't listen to that.
Hopefully he's still, she'll
continue to be diluted. Um, but yeah,
I mean I'm,
I'm at the top of the pyramid.
Like I get all the kind of the notoriety
and the congratulations for doing the
stuff that I've done. But without the
base of the pyramid, the pyramid is shit.
It's to block on the ground.
So without all these people,
I mean, I wouldn't have accomplished
it. I would have, I might have tried,
but I wouldn't be, I wouldn't be where I
am. Probably wouldn't be on the podcast.
I've wouldn't have actually done anything.
Well, you know, for everyone
that's come on and, and,
and to sit here and have you,
you know that they have you and the
people that have come on this podcast and
have you sitting across the table from
me and be able to spend time with you
yesterday and hang out with you.
I am rewarded a thousand fold
a thousand fold from you.
To me, that's, that's
where the reward comes.
And it's an honor a thousand fold for you
to be here and be sitting here talking
to me.
And I thank you for coming on.
I thank you for your service.
I thank you for your sacrifice.
I thank you for the example that
you're setting, which is awesome.
And,
and showing everyone
what it really means to,
to persevere
and to not only
not only overcome challenges,
but you are in bracing those challenges
and turning the harshest of challenges
into something positive
and something good.
And that is what I'm thanking you for,
for explaining what it really means to
adapt and overcome no matter what we
face.
And to everyone out there that's listening
and you're going through hard times,
or you're facing a rough patch or a
challenge or an obstacle in your life,
adapt to it,
grow from it,
overcome it,
transcend it,
and use the weight of that challenge
to make you stronger.
And until next time,
this is Rob Jones,
an echo and Jocko out.