This is Jocko podcast number
one 70 with Echo Charles and me,
Jocko Willink. Good Evening Echo. Good
evening. It is time for some Q and a.
Okay. It has been awhile.
It's been awhile for sure.
So let's, yeah, from the interwebs. Yes,
indeed. As it is said.
Okay. First Question Jocko.
I'm taking over leadership of a team of
six people to I know and for I don't.
When you've taken over leadership,
did you one give a group talk to meet
with each individual in three what did you
say? Good question. Yes.
Obviously give a group talk.
That's affirmative. You get
everyone together. Hey guys,
my name is bill [inaudible].
I came from this place
I'm here to take over.
Now there's a some judgment calls Jeff
to make because you're going to introduce
yourself, but if you're taking over a
well functioning team, then guess what?
You're not going into revamp everything
immediately cause everything's going
fine. So your hey, I'm happy to be working
with you guys looking forward to it.
I know you guys have a great reputation.
Glad to be a part of the team. Awesome.
If you have any questions, let
me know. I'm here. That's easy.
If you're taking over a team
that's not working well, right,
there's problems and that's why somebody
got fired and that's why you're coming
in there. You might need to address
some of those things. Hey listen,
I know things have been a
little off track. I'm going
to look at what's going on.
I'm going to take input from you guys.
We probably need to make some changes.
We're going to do it together as a team.
That's where we're moving from here.
We need to get back to where we're
supposed to be. Boom. Something like that.
And again,
there's gonna be people on that team that
had been busting their ass and working
really hard. And if you go in there
and just disparage everyone there,
you're going to start off
on the wrong foot. So yeah,
have the keep it pretty broad when
you meet the whole group, hey,
this is who I am, this is where I came
from, this is what I'm looking forward to.
All that stuff. And then yes. Do
you meet with people individually?
Absolutely. You go around, you
meet with them and when you,
what do you talk to him about and
you talked to them about them.
We talked to them about them.
You want to know about them,
you want to know who they are.
You want to know what their,
what their family situation is, what
their interests are, what's going on,
how they feel about the transitions
that have been taken place.
A little bit of that stuff is
not about you, it's about them.
So go yes and talked to everyone. Take
notes. Maybe not right in front of them.
So you look like a nerd but
you know afterwards you go,
hey bill has three kids.
His wife also works at the company,
he's interested in soccer and basketball,
whatever. You just take those notes.
You know it's, I'm actually good before
you take some on over a situation,
if you already familiarize yourself
with this, you look at the,
maybe the HR website at your company has
a picture of everyone so you'll kind of
know who they are, gives you less
stuff to remember. So there's that
make good first impression.
Don't go in there looking like an idiot.
Don't go in there thinking that,
oh, I just, I'm the boss man.
So everyone has to bow down and,
and bow down to my superiority.
No,
they're actually mad at you. Right?
The, the thing is they're mad at you.
So I remember one time I was taken over
a small element and one of my friends
was a part of the element
and I went in like 20 guys.
I went in Hay and I walked in,
but I just had a notebook with like five
things I wanted to talk to them about.
And as soon as I walked in and I opened
up my notebook and he's said something
like, you brought a notebook,
you're always squared away.
That's why you're putting in charge.
That's why your boots are so like just
a little impression of hey man, I'm,
I take this stuff seriously.
And I would say overall your main
goal when you're meeting your team,
when you're meeting the individuals on
your team is you are looking to build
relationships with the people on the team.
That's what your goal is.
Because when you build these relationships
that's going to make your team
stronger, et cetera. Yeah.
Remember the time you were when you were
on Joe Rogan the first time when he was
like, Hey, you're the only one who's
ever brought a note pad and you're like,
just trying to be prepared to just try
and be prepared and it was good in case
there's anything, you know,
you hop, it comes up to you.
I want it to slip your mind.
Yeah. Yeah. That's funny. Uh,
and I'm trying to imagine
being a worker and you know,
when you get a new manager,
you know, whatever new boss,
um, you know, they come in.
Yeah. If there were, I like having the
individual meeting, I would, oh, dig it.
And then, but if they're like
taking notes, I'd be like, wait,
why aren't you taking notes? Like, well,
how are you going to use this against
me later as they like, hey man,
how's it going? How long have
you been here for? Oh, I've
been here for four years.
All cool. Do you, you married? Yeah.
Yeah, I got two kids. Oh, that's awesome.
That's awesome. How long have you been
married for? Oh, six years like that.
You're getting to know the person.
If I go in there and I go,
how long have you been here?
And you're like six years.
And I write them and
I say, ah, what? What?
What is your primary function here
at the team? You know what I mean?
If you just jump right into that.
We're not looking to build a relationship.
We're just looking to find out how I can
use you. Yeah, that's what it feels like.
I mean, you said it like how long you've
been married. You said it like that.
No men, it doesn't matter how you
say, you can say it the most nice,
polite way ever. And when you write
it down, it's kind of like, Bro,
like you gonna take all this information
and sort of do some sort of evaluation
for me, you know, kind of is what it
feels like. It does feel like that.
That's why I specifically said when you're
having a personal conversation with a
person that you're meeting
for the first time,
you're not scratching it into a note pad.
Now, that being said, if the guy says,
you know what, I've noticed some things
here around here that need changing.
You go,
really hold on a second.
Let me break out my notebook here and take
the notes on what you're about to say.
Yeah, that's, that's you know, if it's
like when you get a micro manager,
you're working for a micromanager,
bring a notebook.
They see you writing stuff down.
They think it's they they're like happy.
Yeah. Trick anyone. Yeah cause well cause
when you're writing down their stuff,
yeah that flips the screen. It's like
it makes it like all, yeah. Yeah.
He's taking notes.
It's important what I'm saying.
Like he's can evaluate like my
opinion of what Ha Yeah. That's good.
Roll in there with a notebook.
It's like the doctor,
you know when you go to the doctor
and he's asking you, oh yeah,
like all this stuff. You see
him writing down, you know,
and your chart or whatever.
Even though doctors situation is good
cause you want them to go evaluate it
later whenever you don't give you a
cure. But same deal man, same deal.
Be careful with those notes
and my sake to check echoes.
Not Prepared for you to take notes on
them. We're not with personal stuff.
How long have you been married?
Oh, nine years old kid. Nine years.
Anyway, you understand? Next
question. Next question.
I'm a sergeant and I want to know how
to deal with my men in a way without
punishment but still make
them better for next time.
Here's something for you.
Punishment is actually the last straw in
how you deal with people that you're in
charge of. In fact, I will tell you this,
if I ever had to punish someone when
I had to administer punishment on my
troops, I always felt that I had somewhere
I had, I had done something wrong,
right? Like, even if a guy got in
trouble out in town, got drunk,
got in a fight,
did something stupid,
I would still look at
that and think to myself,
how could I have allowed this guy to
not realize what a disaster it is,
how much trouble he's going to get in,
what kind of international
incident he's going to cause,
how that's going to hurt us in the
team strategically. All those things.
How did I let that happen?
So doling out punishment is not optimal.
I mean,
you've pretty much,
you've pretty much made a mistake if you
have to punish people because if you're
doing, if you're being a good leader,
people are doing what you want them to do.
There's no reason for punishment.
Hmm.
So that's what you should not be looking
to punish. And just like I just said,
you should be looking
to build relationships.
You should be looking to show
people a better way of doing things,
a way that's more smooth
and more efficient and
doesn't disrupt what the team
efforts are. You got to explain to people
why they're doing what they're doing.
This is all stuff, right? This is explain
why things are done a certain way.
Explain how it impacts the team.
Explain how it impacts them.
That's also important.
Um,
you got to have people
rehearse in and retrain.
Cause now what?
Now I'm talking about how do you get
people to do the right thing, right?
Without punishing them.
So we're trying to avoid punishment.
How do we avoid punishment by training?
How do we avoid punishment by people
understanding what they're doing,
why they're doing what they're doing?
How do we avoid punishment by
setting goals that make sense,
that are small enough for them to get to
and then have fun with the goals and get
in the game yourself and show them that
you're not perfect
and that is what you need to do.
You need to make every effort to make
people understand why they're doing what
they're doing,
how they fit into the big picture.
And when they figure all that
stuff out and they're on board,
you shouldn't have to punish people.
You shouldn't have to punish people.
So I know it's, yeah, that's what it is.
If you're a sergeant and you want to deal
with your men away without punishment,
well think of what the mistakes you're
making when you're, when you're,
when you're fire team or your,
your,
your platoon does something wrong.
Why did they make that mistake
that they make the mistake?
Because they wanted to.
Now they made it because you were a
bad leader at that point in time. You,
what could you do better? Hey guys,
where, what didn't you understand? Oh,
you guys messed up this
training operation.
I'm going to restrict your weekend duty.
I'm going to restrict you to weekend duty.
Meaning you can't go out in town.
What good did I just do? Right?
Are they going to try harder now?
Right? Yeah. But if you say, hey,
listen guys, we did a bad job.
I know I must have made
a mistake in trying to
explain this information to you all
because we didn't do what we were supposed
to do. Let's look. Let's dissect
this thing. As a matter of fact,
let's spend Friday night
dissecting this thing.
I'm buying pizza and we'll
sit around the the uh,
sand table and we'll figure out what,
what we did wrong.
That's not punishment.
That has the opposite effect
of punishment that has, hey,
I'm bringing everyone in cause I
want to win. I want us all the wind.
So that's what you gotta do.
Don't punishment should be punishment.
Should be, I mean, do you have to
punish people sometime? Yes. Yes you do.
When they're blatantly out align, when
they do something that's blatantly wrong,
yeah, you gotta drop the hammer on them.
You've got to set the example sometimes,
hey,
you're not going to get away with this.
Sometimes that happened in the dreams,
you know,
somebody would do something stupid and
the command would just drop the hammer
and everyone goes, man, that guy
got a Dui and they, you know,
docked him, dig, dig,
busted him in rank and they pulled him
out of his platoon and they're sending
him to a, to a fleet billet for
two years. But Room, my God,
I'm going to make someone think right.
Maybe I won't step behind the wheel.
So sometimes you do have to punish
if people do something stupid,
especially after they've been warned
a couple of times. But I always look,
if I have to deliver
punishment onto my team,
I made a mistake somewhere.
I don't like it.
Don't they say that like
reward and encouragement is
like way more powerful than
punish? Definitely women. A
powerful way more powerful for sure.
I almost never punished people.
Yeah,
but the reason is why did I punish people?
Because people were doing
weren't doing stupid things.
They were doing what they were supposed
to be doing. They were doing. Yeah.
I mean I probably, I don't
even know if I, I probably,
I think I had like a one or two captain's
mast where I had to bring somebody in
and drop the hammer on them
and it's because they did
dumb stuff. It's like, Eh,
you know what? You can't do that.
I didn't think of it. I'm sorry,
but you can't do that discussions. Yeah.
Next question, Jocko. In the
discipline equals freedom field manual.
The section fear reads,
how do you overcome feel
fear of failure step go,
but a previous entry reads,
I don't want you to overcome
fear of failure. I want you
to be afraid of failure.
Mind elaborating. Yeah, clearly
there's a dichotomy here.
I know it's my favorite word apparently
according to Dean lister. Yes, I agree.
There is a dichotomy here because fear
is something good that you should take
advantage of.
So it's kind of good to be afraid
because it keeps you on edge edge.
It keeps you from slacking.
It keeps you preparing as much as you
possibly can and all that stuff is good,
but at the same time, yes, if you go too
far to the other end of the spectrum,
fear gets a hold of you
and you can't overcome it,
so you freeze or you cower or you run
away and none of those are good reactions.
So what I obviously failed to
communicate well in the book,
discipline equals freedom field manual
is the dichotomy between these spectrum,
the spectrum of fear that you can have.
So if you have no fear whatsoever,
no fear. Well guess what? You get
cocky. You can get arrogant. Um,
if you have too much fear, you can't even
get out of the gate. You just freeze.
You hesitate. So like all dichotomies,
you got to balance those two.
And
the way you balance those two is to try
and do things that make you feel fear.
Right?
Try and do things that make you feel
fear so that way you get used to it.
You can overcome it, you can
deal with it, you can utilize it.
If you have a fighter,
you ever hear UFC fighters that I'll
come afraid every time I get in the ring.
Right? Pretty much everybody. Yeah. Pretty
much everybody I'm afraid. Cause you're,
you're afraid, you're gonna get
knocked out. You're afraid this,
you're afraid that afraid I'm to lose in
front of all my family and friends and
all that.
So everyone's afraid.
So what does that fear do and drives you
to train harder? Drives you prepared,
drives you to keep your hands up and
your chin down when you're in the cage.
So yeah, there's a healthy
level of fear. It can also get,
get the best of you. So
keep it balanced. Yeah.
We will talk about this and I think Sam
Harris talked about it for as far as the
first, I heard it and made a
point not to go too deep into it,
but they were, you know,
like this. Okay. Fear. Uh,
how do you overcome fear step go. Right.
It's essentially like take action,
be brave in the face of fear.
Right? But if there's no
fear, it's kind of like, hmm,
you're not really being brave.
You're not, you know, kind of
thing. Well that's true too. Yeah.
So could consider that, that
notion, right? So you say, yeah,
I want you to be afraid of failure.
Oh yeah. Be Afraid of failure,
but you still got to step. You still
got to go. He's still got to be brief,
you know, kind of thing.
So they do actually kind of
compliment each other. Really.
Um, unless you think like, oh
yeah. Overcome fear, meaning like,
I'm not scared of it anymore.
It's literally not figured
that it's always fear,
but it's more,
it's less about the fear being,
you know, it reduced to zero.
It's more about being brave,
training yourself to be embraced here.
Embrace the fear and the,
and so to continue with that thought,
in order to embrace the fear,
what do you do? You step, you
go into it. So there you go.
There's your answer. Cool.
Next question.
I was wondering when does standing up
for the right thing take precedence over
avoiding conflict?
This is something that leaders
have to deal with all the time.
So clearly out of the gate, things that
are immoral or unethical or illegal.
If you participate, you're
guilty. That's the way it is. Now.
Things that are a matter of opinion,
that's where you might have to play
the long game. Like maybe you won't,
don't want to do something a certain
way and if you, but if you think, oh,
well,
uh,
I think the Jujitsu class warmups
should be doing these exercises and echo
thinks it should be those exercises.
So echo these things.
We should do it this way. No, we should
do it this way. Do you dig in? I dig in.
Now we, we just end up saying, well, I'm
not going to teach the class. You know,
you end up in these situations.
Well, what's the big deal? What's,
you know what I'd rather do? I'd rather
play the long game. I'd rather say,
hey man, can you explain why you do those
exercises? Oh, here's another exercise.
Cool. And that I learned isn't
as good for this technique. Oh,
you know how you like when I do this move,
this actually helps me do it.
Even though it's just a warm
up move. Oh, that's cool.
We build a little relationship. You get
to understand me. I get to understand you.
Boom. Gelson you say, Hey, I'm going
to incorporate that into our warm ups.
We're going to warm up here.
Boom. There you go. Down.
I understand that that's the right
thing, right? Because in my mind,
I ma in my mind I'm thinking,
Hey,
these students need to know this escape
is the right thing to do. So I do that. So
you have to weigh it out. What am I doing
to my relationship in this situation?
If I go along with this,
like if you asked me to do nine things
that are pretty menial and you're my boss
and I said, Yep, cool, got
it, Boston, no problem,
and then you asked me to do something
else as meal. Yep. Cool. Got It, boss.
No problem. Then you asked
me to do something else.
Menial. Cool. Got It, boss.
No problem.
Then you asked me to do something that's
downright stupid and dangerous and I go,
hey boss, I need to talk
about this. I'm not sure.
Can you explain to me why
we're doing it this way?
Because there's a possibility that someone
could really get hurt and you go all,
well, you've done your, in your mind,
you're thinking you've done
these 10 things for me,
you've done nine things from your
dump, seven things from, you didn't,
well you didn't question me and now
all of a sudden you have a question,
you must have a legitimate question.
That's what we're hoping for.
That's why we're trying to build
relationships now. All that being said,
yes, we're playing the
long game. There are times,
and this is a really
sketchy area to enter into.
There are times where something
that is happening, is it immoral,
unethical or illegal,
and you might actually have
to kind of go along with it.
I tried to think of a good example
of that and I thought of one
Oscar Schindler from Schindler's list.
What did this guy do?
Right? This guy was a Nazi. He was a Nazi.
They were exterminating Jews and
instead of him standing up and saying,
this is wrong to exterminate Jews,
I protest.
How long would he have lived if he had
done that? 30 seconds right there. Oh you,
oh, you don't think Jews should dicho
we're killing you. That was that.
How many people did he save?
Zero. In fact, he, he costs,
he went negative one negative. What
did he do? He played the game. He,
he befriended the Nazi leadership.
He bought them gifts, he bribed him,
he bought him gifts,
he built relationships with them.
He ended up being able to move his
factory and all this other stuff to save a
bunch of Jewish people.
And he,
even though he knew like he would,
he would see them executing people,
he would see them executing
Jews and he knew it was wrong.
He thought it was wrong.
He felt it was wrong.
And if he would have stood up and
said, hey, what you're doing is wrong,
then he wouldn't have been able to save
anyone. He would've been killed himself.
So even in that situation,
it's,
it's not a guarantee that you,
you need to stand up to do the ethical
thing because perhaps there's a chance
you can do the more ethical
thing by playing the game,
building relationships. Who knows?
Who knows? Maybe if that war went on,
maybe he would've said, oh, you know what,
he maybe he would have risen to
a position where he, you know,
maybe if the Germans would have won and
he could have said, hey, you know what,
the Jewish people are making
good workers here. I'm going to,
I'm going to continue to use
them, or whatever. You know,
maybe he built up a whole new,
you never know.
But when you get rid of your influence,
when you lose your influence because you
stand up, it might not be the best move.
And the thing that you
have to wait for this,
you have to wait with this is you are
participating. And actually, you know,
they say Oscar Schindler felt completely
guilty because he did participate and
he was a part of,
of what was happening.
And he did his best to
stop as much as he could,
but he wished he would have stopped more.
And you know,
at some point maybe you see a little
six year old girl getting shot and you
think, you know what? I should screw it.
I should stand in front of that bullet
and take that bullet for that little girl.
You know?
That's the kind of guilt that he felt.
So there are times where you
really have to weigh this out.
And also I'll tell you,
I mean even in things that
aren't this big ethical dilemma,
head on conflict is generally not
the best way to solve problems.
Most of the time it's much smarter to
maneuver and it's much smarter to flank.
And it's much smarter to come from another
angle and it's much smarter to build
allegiance and alliance with people so
you can have influence over so you can
move them in the right
direction. Yes. So almost like,
well actually straight up where doing
the right thing and avoiding conflict is
kind of like, they're not that like
opposite, you know, were doing,
they're avoiding.
You should,
and I'm totally just interpreting this,
trying to anyway of wedding conflict,
you should always be essentially trying
to avoid comp conflict as far as maybe
not always,
but generally speaking,
we do a better job then the outcome
is better when we avoid conflict.
Now of course, anyone listening to this,
thanks. Oh, you take that to extreme.
This is someone that never stands up for
anything. Yeah. You know, and that's bad.
That's all. That's also bad from
a leadership perspective. If,
if your team is looking at you and they
think, hey, Jocko never sticks up for us.
He never gives the boss any push back.
So we just,
we're just at the whim of this tyrannical
boss and jock was no buffer to it.
That's what they see. So you can't just
be a pushover, but at the same time,
if you go to your troops and you say,
Hey, listen guys, here's what's going on.
The boss has got a lot of ideas right now.
Some of them are good,
some of them not so good,
but guess what, what,
what I'm doing right now and the reason
that we're pushing hard to carry out
what he's trying to get us to do is the,
to the best of our ability.
The reason we're doing that is because
I'm actually trying to build some trust
with him so that he will
listen to me right now. He's
not really listening to me.
He knows I don't have much experience,
but I'm trying to build
relationships so he can listen to me.
So we can actually do this and what
I think is going to be a smarter way.
Can you guys help me build
this relationship by kicking
ass for the next three
projects that we've got so I can build
up some clout and come back to him and
get the tools or the people,
whatever it is that we need. Yeah.
You always have this real
finesse sort of way of,
of saying stuff like you
wear it I guess who you were,
you were saying,
and I think you were wrong actually.
You were saying that that um,
standing up and doing the right
thing is this same thing as
avoiding home as avoiding conflict.
Yeah, no, I didn't mean it like that.
I meant that they're not necessarily
always opposite, you know,
like doing the right thing in avoiding
conflict like there, you know,
there's just some wishy washy kind of
room wiggle room in there a lot of times.
And when I say avoiding, you should
always be quote unquote avoiding conflict.
I meant, of course, not always,
but I meant more like even if I'm going
to confront someone or something about
like something that's wrong,
I still should be while I do that,
I should be avoiding conflict for sure.
Do it in a finesse sort of way to actually
just keep everything rolling forward.
We've just nudge it in a different
direction kind of thing. But I actually,
now that I'm sort of reading this again,
I understand what he's asking. You know,
it's like is there a time where it's
like, hey, there's gonna be conflict.
Is there a time where it's worth the
conflict to? And where is that point?
Did I always give? Is if you're telling
me, hey Jocko, go do the mission this way.
And I'm like, you know what? I'm not doing
it. And you go, okay, fine, you're fired.
And now is do you put someone some yes
man in my place and then that yes man
gets everyone killed.
Cause it was a stupid stupid plan.
Did I really help or should I have said,
hey boss,
I'm really going to recommend
we do it a different way.
Here's some different options.
And then finally you say, no doc,
are you doing it my way?
And guess what?
Even then I can go out and mitigate
in the field. Even then I can say,
you know what? And the classic example
of that is in band of brothers,
when Dick Winters of awesome leader,
they send a recon mission across
the river. One night someone dies.
They come back,
the war's over,
it's all but over and the next night
they wanted to do another reconnaissance
mission and Dick winters is like, sir, I'm
not sure. That's a great idea. He's like,
do it. He goes, okay Roger,
that the guys go down,
they'd drink a couple bottles
of wine in the bottom of them.
They don't do the mission.
He mitigated the risk if he would
have stood up and you know that's the,
that's a great example of where he
avoided conflict. He stayed in the game.
He wasn't he, she said yes, yes sir. Got
It. We got it. And then he did disobeyed.
Sure.
He put his,
he put his rank at risk and probably
could have gotten in some trouble,
but he knew it was the right thing to do.
Yeah.
That was like the best sort of
way to do [inaudible] again,
you,
um,
you're always thinking of like the long
game versus the short game, you know,
where it's like, man, if you
can keep that in perspective,
these things be become a little bit
more clear, you know, they always do.
Yes sir. All right, next question, Jocko.
I recently interviewed for a team lead
job but wasn't selected because I don't
have leadership experience. How can
I lead when I'm not in charge? Well,
you're in charge of something years,
certainly in charge of something.
You're in charge of some piece of gear.
You're in charge of some task.
You're in charge of maybe a couple people
here or there, but even if you're not,
you're in charge of something. So whatever
you're in charge of, take charge of it.
Take charge of whatever your task is.
You take charge of it, you own it.
You do it to perfection. Then once
you've got that completely dialed,
then you know what?
You reach out and you see who else you
can help you help with other tasks.
You look for work. If you look for
work, you're going to find it right?
You're gonna find it.
You're going to find it.
You're going to start taking
things from other people. Now,
what you have to be careful of is
that you don't step on toes, right?
Because just about everyone
thinking about this,
just about everyone is offended by someone
that wants to be in charge. Hey y'all,
let me, let me, let me
take charge of this year.
That right there makes people cringe
to take lead on this. You know what?
Hey listen up guys. Right? If you're
that guy, and then everyone goes,
now there's a key point. This, this
is beautiful. This is beautiful.
So let's say we're in a platoon,
there's something going on, um,
in a mid grade position
and I realize like,
I want to be leader right now. If
I just go in and goes, hey guys,
let me run this next mission. People
are like, dude, what are you doing?
What are you talking about? You don't
know anything. Hmm, okay. And they,
and they're kind of dug in against
me by the way. At that point,
if I give it enough,
I let things escalate a little bit.
What I would usually do is I would,
I would let things escalate to a
point to where when I took charge,
people were waiting for it and
they were happy that I took charge.
Even when I was even,
I was to ask you to come in,
like if you're a tasking to commander,
okay,
so I got Lafe and stone
are working for me.
I'm tasking you to commander
were out on an operation.
Something starts going wrong,
right?
Let's say life's doing a building
clearance with his platoon.
Something starts going wrong. I jumped
down there and say, all right guys,
push over that way. Start clearing
that hallway. How does lay feel?
Kinda phased.
He feels like I jumped down
and micromanage his platoon
and why are you doing
this? Everything was going
fine, so I don't want to do
that. I want, first of all,
I want him to work things out. Of course.
So what? Let's say, same things happening,
things are going a little bit bad.
They're starting to be a little bit of
confusion. Just starting to be escalated.
Voices. They're starting to be, you know,
hey, wait, wait, no, don't go there.
You can hear it. It's really
obvious when things are going wrong.
I might let that escalate a little bit.
Let it get to a point where life knows he
doesn't have control. This anymore. Now,
like I'm down and go, hey, everyone, lock
it up. You four, hold on that hallway.
You to start clearing that back room.
Everyone else gets to the
rooftop and hold security.
You know what everyone thinks,
including life. They go, Hah,
thank God that just happened right now,
and that can happen from anywhere
in the chain of command. I'm happy.
I happen to be given an example of
when I was the task and the commander,
but I would do the same thing
when I was an e five which is, oh,
things are going a little bit sideways.
No one wants to hear the guy
that as soon as the opportunity,
as soon as there's any void of leadership,
you just like jumping in. They're like,
okay guys, Captain America to the rescue,
right? You don't want to do
that. You want to let that voice.
I'll tell you what happens if there's a
little tiny void that you try and jump
into, guess what you're gonna do. You're
gonna bump into everyone else. That's,
that's in that void. It has to
meet an actual void of leadership.
Once that actual void of leadership
opens up and it's big enough,
you jump in there and you,
and because you've detached because you
are detached because you're watching it
happen, you jump in there and you have
so much confidence in what you're saying.
You have so much understanding
of the situation.
You look like a genius and everyone's
happy that you just did that.
And by the way, as soon as that
problem gets solved, you step back out.
The leadership void is closed up by
someone else and you're good to go.
And next time people,
people will not be surprised at all when
something goes wrong and you step in
and you've solved the problem.
So that's what you should do.
You yes you want to be in charge
of, yes, you should look for work,
but you can't step on toes.
Don't jump in every time.
Chance you get like Captain America, I'm
going to save the day. No, you're not.
Let there be a real problem.
Assess it from the outside.
And like I said, you've got to be
careful about being captain America.
You gotta be careful about being,
I'm going to say I'm ready to stand up
every moment and that that's a problem.
You know it's a problem when someone,
when someone's goal,
this is going to sound weird.
When someone's goal is
to be a leader like my,
to be a leader, like if that's what
they're thinking, that's gonna,
that's gonna offend people.
It's going to offend people because,
and I'll tell you why it
offends people to rightfully so.
You know why it offends people
because what is it about themselves?
It's about me. I want to be a
leader. I me, me want to lead.
That's what it's about.
And everyone recognize that if what you
really want to do is you want the team
to win and you realize that sometimes
you're going to be in a supporting role
and sometimes there might be in a
situation where you need to lead almost
hesitantly. You know what?
Leadership needs to happen.
I'll go make it happen because the team
needs it to win. I'm here for the team,
so don't be the person about yourself.
We don't like that person.
I don't even like that person.
As much as I love people that
want to step up and lead,
I don't want that person that's
like looking for themselves.
Sometimes you gotta be following, I
want someone that's like, Hey, oh cool,
I got your back. Don't worry
about it. I'm over here.
I'm over here a part of the
train. I'm over here cleaning
rooms. Oh wait a second.
There's a leadership void, and now
there's an actual problem going on. Oh,
and then that person suddenly
steps up and solves a problem.
Then it goes right back down
to their level. Awesome.
That's the person you want and that's
the person you want to be. Yeah.
Yeah. You know, like nowadays,
the lie I hear a lot nowadays
where they add value to add value.
So that's essentially what you're doing.
If you're not,
I'll at least of situation,
it's like boom, I'm going
to add value. So one, okay,
if we want to start with my own role,
you know,
that's where I'm gonna add
the most value of my own role.
But if there's little voids in whatever
capacity that needs some value added,
I'm going to go ahead and add that value.
We can't just be piling on
the value or it's not needed.
Don't pour it additional value. No Man to
non-value needing areas. Exactly right.
That's problematic and what you value.
That's true. All right, next question.
Hi Jocko.
When you're trying to take ownership of
a mistake made by a fellow team member,
what do you do if the team
leader asks for a step by step,
step by step breakdown of events.
I've said it was our
mistake and not to end,
not made excuses,
but a step by step breakdown would expose
the fact that he alone was responsible
for that error.
Interesting.
So he basically
it is, wait, wait. So He's, he's basically
saying, okay, it's our mistake, right?
I don't want to individualize
this guy or assault, you know,
make him stand out or whatever.
Um,
it's our mistake and
we're going to fix it kind
of thing. And he's like, no, I want
the step by step and this step, step,
step by step is going to reveal,
reveal the Solo. Actually bill's fault.
And now what? I tried so hard to
take ownership, but here's the car.
It was actually build. It was
all jacked up. Actually not mine.
It's actually not my fault
is what we're saying.
It's it's the truth, right?
You get that right? Yeah.
Cause cause check it out.
Who's responsible leaders when you're
taking ownership for something,
when you're taking extreme ownership for
something, who's fault is it? Mine. Yeah.
Does that include when someone else
on your team makes a mistake? Yes.
But how can that be God's man?
It's here. It's your seam.
So let me ask you these questions
and here's what I'd be thinking. Um,
the teammate was in error.
Why?
Well, why did the teammate make a mistake?
Why didn't the teammate have backup?
Why didn't the rest of
the members of the team,
why didn't I actually go through with
him and make sure that he knew how to do
that procedure properly?
He's part of my team.
We are responsible for this taking place.
I knew he was a little bit shaky
and I didn't do anything to fix it.
That's why it's our fault. It's not our
fault because we say, oh, it's our fault,
but it's really bill. That's not,
that's not what we're talking about.
The point is, the point is to actually
own it. So if my coworker fails,
I'm literally saying to myself,
what mistake did I make that
my coworker dropped the ball?
What mistake did I make?
My coworker dropped the ball.
Did I not show it to him?
Did I not ask him if he knew how to do it?
Did I not ask me if he needed some help?
Did I not confirm that he
knew the procedures correctly?
All those things are my fault.
Did I not do a good job of identifying
that bill was a little bit slow on the
uptake and therefore he needed a
little extra preparation for this
and now, now think about this. What can
I do once I make those mistakes? Okay,
we're going to do to fix him.
And now think about this from a leadership
perspective. You go down and you say,
hey guys, you guys messed up this
thing a wider than it happened.
And now think about the team
where everyone goes, well,
you know it's our fault.
Mostly Bill,
right?
And I'll tell you when I,
when, when, when I look at, uh,
a platoon and bill made a mistake,
I don't look at bill.
A good leader doesn't just look at bill.
A good leadership looks
at everyone on the team,
especially certainly the leadership.
But I think this guy's
talking about from a peer,
but it doesn't matter from a
peer perspective. If there's
a mistake that happens,
we are truly responsible.
And then from a leadership perspective,
when I go down to the team and I say,
hey guys, what happened? And they
said, well, it was our fault,
but this is what bill did. I go, okay,
so you just dropping dime on bill.
I'm not going to say that, but I'm
like, I'm thinking to myself, okay,
so it's all bills fall. Cool. I'll tell
you what. Whereas if you say, hey, listen,
bosses, what happened, here's
the procedures. We went,
I don't think we did a good
job of briefing bill cause
here's what bill did. He,
he did step three instead of step
for my fault. We went through twice.
But why should it gone through it a
couple more times and confirm he knew what
was going on.
It's not gonna happen again.
We got this which guy who you want
to work for, which guide you, which,
which team do you want?
You want the team where people are
taking ownership of the problem,
not blaming bill.
Ah,
ownership is not just saying we own it.
Ownership is actually owning it and
that's what makes it so powerful.
What makes it so powerful
is if you actually own it,
then you actually look at bill
beforehand and you go look in our team,
do we have any weaknesses?
Yeah we do. We got bill.
Bill doesn't bill can't get this
part of the procedure done right?
Here's what we're gonna do. We're going
to put bill in his other position.
That's an easier part of the procedure
were to make sure he knows how to do that.
Meanwhile,
we're taking Mike and Mike is going to
go down here and he nails this procedure
and, and he's going to spend, by the way,
an extra 15 minutes a day during lunch,
he's going to get bills trained up.
So bill can eventually,
that's the kind of thing
you'd do on a team. Yeah,
you made it pretty clear, which is, um,
which is kind of,
cause it's not that easy to
understand or it wasn't for me anyway,
I mean put it this way,
it was,
it was very valuable when I didn't
understand this about extreme ownership.
I said this before too,
by the way. So there's,
there's essentially two parts of it
that make it extreme ownership. Well,
actually there's three, there's the
dichotomy, but aside from the debt cloud,
I mean this is what it is.
You take responsibility and then you
say what you're going to do to fix the
puzzle.
And then actually there's a third part,
which is you implement the solution.
Yes, yes. Okay. You identify it,
you own the problem,
you identify a solution for the problem,
and then you implement the
solution. That's what you do. Yeah.
So a lot of times in the associate,
in the beginning, like I would just,
as far as me just kind of
casually trying to understand it,
I would focus so much on taking
responsibility, you know, it was my fault,
you know, kind of thing. It's like, well,
the taking responsibility,
I mean is arguably more important than
saying that it's your fault kind of
thing.
It's essentially you're,
you're taking responsibility of
the solution as well, if not you.
Because in a way,
in a lot of practical cases,
you don't even have to
identify who's fault it is.
If you take responsibility of the
solution. Like if a, if I'm okay here,
so if there's a football team, right,
that's like the epitome of team,
not the epitome,
but want a good example of teamwork.
Nevermind the seal teams or whatever.
But we'll go with it.
It'll be more simple because
it's a, so let's say, okay,
we've got a pass or
whatever, and boom, the play,
the play starts and a guy gets
through the frontline, uh,
let's say the guard missed
a block. Obvious, right?
You missed it. Maybe he looked one way
and it was supposed to look this way.
He was supposed to not pull
any tried to pull or something.
Maybe he just made a mistake. He just
made a mistake. He's not in company.
Just made a mistake. Whose
fault is it? The guards fall.
Okay. But if the quarterback's
gonna take extreme ownership,
he's going to be like, hey, no part
in the, hey this happened. You know,
next time we review, I'm going to remind
them, hey, on this play that play,
you know, this red 46 nope.
Curve twist or whatever.
Like you don't pull and he pro probably
be like on Matt. I know, I know it.
Don't go scold them. Just see like,
hey, you don't go, hey, no problem,
but we're just not going
to do that anymore.
And then next time I call that play
and be like, you're good. Right?
I'm gonna check with them.
I didn't check with them that first time
you made a mistake in my check with him.
He won't make that mistake again.
Kind of like key when we're now we,
when we were driving navigated me, you
know, it's kind of one of those things.
The quarterback took responsibility for
solving the problem more so than he was
like, okay that was my fault and making
a big deal out of it being his fault. No,
in his head it is, you know, it's like,
okay this is my fault. I should, you know,
I should make sure things are clear
kind of thing. I think the weather too,
you know your,
whether it's,
well what bothers me the most
about this question is I feel like,
I feel like I don't do a
good job of explaining this
because what bums me out is
someone, whoever wrote this question and
it's a good question. I get the question,
I get scared that the person that's
listening to the question goes, now Jack,
who doesn't quite get it,
he doesn't quite get the fact that there
was this one guy who is part of the
team who made this mistake and no one,
you know,
we just, we can't hold his hand
every time. Like that's not my fault.
It's not our team's fault.
When bill drop completely drops the ball.
That's not my fault.
It's not anyone on the
team's fault and my point is,
is exactly what you are
saying. Echo. Yes it is,
and if you look at it,
when bill makes the mistake himself,
he's alone in a room and he's supposed to,
you know he's supposed to put part a on
top of part B and Bolt them together.
That's his part of the job.
He's alone in a room doing that
and he doesn't do it right.
That's 100% his fault.
The answer is no actually who's
in charge of training him?
Who's in charge of checking, who not
even in charge of WHO's responsible.
We are a team.
That means we work together.
That means we confirm that we know how
to do our individual parts of the job.
That means we check and say, hey
bill, are you good? Hey Bill,
let me check your first three that you
do to make sure you understand what's
happening. We do this together as a team
and it makes me feel like a failure,
that people have a hard
time understanding this and,
and I know it's, it can be a stretch,
it can be a stretch. And you know,
I give all those examples,
hey, the machine gunner
shoots in the wrong direction.
Who's fault is that?
It's not the machine.
The machine gunner literally pointed
the machine gun in the wrong direction,
pulled the trigger and shot in the
wrong direction. Who's fault is it?
It's the squad leaders.
It's the fire team leaders.
It's the platoon leaders because they
didn't make sure that they understood his
field of fire. Make sure you
understood how to operate his weapon.
And by the way,
there's a chance that the reason that
bill screwed this up and bill is incapable
of putting these parts together correctly.
And if that is the situation,
guess what?
It is the responsibility of the team to
either get him trained up to where he
can't do it or to tell the leadership
that this guy cannot these incapable of
doing the job and therefore
he needs to not be here.
That's what ownership is.
That's what extreme ownership is.
I think I know what it is. What, what,
what makes it confusing or sometimes
kinda kind of slippery like to grasp,
you know,
cause it depends on who you ask.
So a lot of times the thing is when,
when it's the machine gun, his fault.
The thing is if I'm,
if I'm not even a human being,
I'm just the disembodied brain.
Okay.
It's the machine that is fun and the
leader's fault and that it's everyone's
fault if I'm dealing, you know, but,
but if you ask the individual person,
cause you ask a machine
gunner, hey he, okay Jocko,
you're the machine gun and you
shot in the wrong direction.
And I asked you who's fault is that? What
are you going to say now? Leaders fault.
Well it's your fault. Well let
me, let me tell you right now,
there are plenty of people and definitely
plenty of machine gunners that when
they shoot that weapon in the wrong
direction, you know what they say?
I didn't get a clear brief on what
the field of fired war. No one too.
I didn't see the,
the markers for what the range limits
where I didn't know where the other blue
forces were.
No one told me.
So they're looking at it like
it actually isn't their fault.
Now you get some good Michigan
and actually guess what?
When you have a guy that's
a machine gunner that says,
well, it wasn't my fault,
it was my leader's fault.
You know what the leader says?
You know what the leader says? Well, glues
or bad leader. The leader in this team,
the leader in this team,
you know what he says? No.
It was a machine gunner
swapped. Yeah, that's right.
And now guess who's fault it was?
It was no one's fault.
The machine gun and think
it's the bosses fault.
The boss thinks it was a
machine gunner his fault.
Now who's going to fix the problem?
The answer's no one knowing. Yeah.
When you get a good team,
the machine going to goes to my fault.
I should have paid better attention
to the leaders is my fault. I should.
And now you have everyone taking
ownership of the problems. Yes. Yeah.
That's the way it's supposed to be.
But that's my point.
And that's why it makes it so,
nevermind.
You're disembodied brain that's
making decisions over here.
I'm saying this is why it's
hard for people to understand.
That's why sometimes,
and I'm with them. I'm like, I was there.
It's Kinda like, it's Kinda like sure I'm,
and extreme ownership, you know, the
typical, I'm taking extreme ownership,
but at the end of the day,
we all know as well bill's fault.
But the reason that it is so hard because
if I ask, okay, we have three guys,
one of those guys as a machine gun and
the other guy's a leader, the other guys,
just another team member, uh, he's,
you know, he's the sniper or something.
If I say, Hey, this machine that
a shot in the wrong direction,
individual meetings, I, they
all take extreme ownership.
All of them are down there in the game.
All of them.
I asked you machine gunner, who's
fault is that? What's he going to say?
You're my fault. Okay, next guy who's
faulted fires you leader my fault.
I shouldn't squad leader my fault.
I should've told them, right? Yes.
So it the re now go back to
the disembodied brains. It's
kind of like, wait, wait,
wait, wait. So it's like he did it.
It's hard to grasp like that one guy,
it is his fault thing. It's
not just his fault, apparently,
because everyone said it's their fault.
Right. So he was obviously his fault,
but wait,
it's everyone's fault kind of thing.
So when you're the guy and you're
saying, okay, his fault it,
that little thing creeps in your brain
that's like, yeah, wait, it is his fault.
Yeah. You know? Yeah.
Yeah. And you're wrong.
And I'd need to do a better job of
explaining that to people because I see
questions like this on a
fairly regular basis, which is,
but hey, really? You know, there's like,
Hey, I get ownership. But really? Yeah,
that's what it means to,
but really that you need to check your
cell phone because the reality is you're
responsible. Yeah. You
wait. If I'm responsible.
What about the machine that he just
said he's responsible machine gunner.
You're a wasp. No, but the machine
going, I said he's responsible.
See what I'm saying? No, I think
that's the feeling that that jam,
if you let that creep in and
that's going to be a problem. Yeah.
Pray you ever seen office space?
So really when you think about,
okay, what's the big thing?
I think he has the movie. Remember you.
Okay, let me, let me remind you case.
So in the beginning they were like,
Hey Peter,
you were putting cover sheets on the tps
reports from Nala or we've been doing
that. You forgot to do that. All right.
So first lumbered comes his boss,
the first lumbered comes, he's like,
yeah, you know, saying, Hey, let me read.
He didn't do it in a Dick Way and
knowing for sure, but he said, hey,
this is basically a reminder.
Did you get that memo?
We're putting cover sheets on
the tps roots part to say, Hey,
I just forgot it was a one time thing, no
problem. And he's like, cool, all that,
you know. So if you just do that, do
that, that'd be cool. And he's like, cool,
no problem. You saw, I'll even
give you another copy of that memo.
He almost like over did it.
Not only was he did overdo it,
so he left and then the other boss boom,
who's like one level down, he came,
same deal. Hey, we're putting, did
you get that memo? TPS reports,
cover sheets now, blah, blah,
blah. He's like, I got the memo,
I forgot one time thing. It's like, yeah,
I'm just, all of those bosses were do,
doing is making sure the
problem got solved, right.
Doing everything in their power. Even
his other, his friends were like, Hey,
what's up? I heard you guys, you're
having problems with your tps.
So they were just taking
extreme ownership, taking
ownership of the problem,
trying to solve it, but we give
them crap about it. Who Do,
who do we give for the movie in
a movie somewhere? Yeah. Yeah,
because they're trying to make
it funny, Dude. I know, I know,
but that's kind of ironic, but yeah,
I know. But it's ironic, right? It is.
So I'm not even mad at Lemberg for that.
Let's see, next question. Hi Jocko.
I have a question for you.
I know you're very busy guy.
How do you find time to
read so many books? I have.
I have many that I want to read,
but I have trouble having enough time.
Any advice on how to set
aside time to do so? Uh, sure.
All right.
Lay It on me.
Make time.
What are you,
what are you doing all day?
The cock second.
What are you doing all day? Are you
watching TV? Are you surfing the Internet?
Are you watching youtube videos?
That's my question.
What are you doing before you go to sleep
at night? Are you looking at Twitter?
Are you looking at Instagram posts?
The Instagram videos tell me
they're not like an addiction.
You get the, you get the Instagram
video. Every one of them is funny there.
38 seconds on the one minute long.
Get to see people hurt themselves.
Get to see people do dumb things and
make you feel good about yourself.
I didn't do that dumb thing and
someone else did. I can laugh at them.
How long are you going to look at those
videos for when you could be reading? So,
so there you go. Stop wasting a bunch of
time. And then what about audio books?
What do you, what are you doing
when you're mowing the lawn?
What are you doing when
you're trimming the hedges?
you're pulling weeds?
What are you doing when you're cleaning
the dishes? Get some audio books.
Get some audio books. What are you
doing first thing in the morning?
What are you doing?
Are you waking up,
checking your email,
sitting around waiting, you
know, wasting a bunch of time?
Are you getting up early enough that
you could just get up, get out of bed,
go and read for 30 minutes,
30 minutes? That's what you have
to do. You have to make time.
There's plenty of time to read.
There's plenty of time to read it.
You probably don't want
to read as badly as your,
as you think. If you wanted to
read that bad, you'd make time.
You make time to breathe somehow.
You can make time to breathe.
You can make time to read. Yeah. I
wouldn't say it's the best. Yeah,
he would be a better one because
like, yeah, eat I think because read,
you can read while you're doing other
things sometimes, especially with just,
just kind of like as a,
as a, so I'm reading,
I'm always have to be reading a book
to read a book for the podcast. Right.
I had only read the first maybe 10 books
that we read that we did on the podcast.
We've done a hundred or something now.
Probably more than that.
I would only read like 10 of them
and maybe it may be a few more,
but I'd read them so long ago.
Maybe I'd read 30,
but some of them so long ago that just,
I had to reread them.
And so then you say to yourself,
okay,
so when would you know when I read all
the time or we'd go to bed and greeting,
wake up reading, um, uh,
going in an airplane. Oh,
see people, what are people doing?
An airplane sleep or watch a movie.
I know you sleep, they do all this
stuff. I sleep sometimes in an airplane,
but we're from not sleeping. Get
us. Guess what I'm doing? Reading,
prepping for a podcast. I
can attest to that. Yeah.
Uh, what do you think is the, like
the biggest ones that people are, um,
you know, that, you know, the, the biggest
activities that they could, yeah, they
could just stop and it just, uh, for me,
I think the biggest time sucks.
Our Youtube.
I think Instagram.
Yeah.
I think those two are really, um, what's
the word? Stimulating to the brain.
And you actually get this weird
like, well, I actually like,
I'm going to learn a little
something from this right here.
I'm gonna take something away from this.
I'm going to veg out.
I'm going to escape
from my world right now.
It's like escapism, right?
Yeah. And, and they,
they actually have
algorithms that are stat,
know what you will click on.
They actually know that about you.
They mapped your little brain and know
that if they put up a video that has,
if they put up a thumbnail of a video
and it's got a heavy machine gun in it,
they've, they know they got a good
chance. I'm going to click on it. Right.
And then they give it a catchphrase title,
right? Nope. They give it a catchphrase.
Title. Isis gets massacre.
I got to watch that.
Oh,
click 50 cal vs Taliban.
Oh, cool. Click over the
anything, right? Oh yeah, yeah.
And actually no words you're going
to click on. And that's, that's so,
and what do you get out of it?
You Watch it for 20 minutes.
You weren't game. Yeah. You get nothing
out of it. You get a book, you read,
you learn, you'll write
something. That's what you do.
Yeah. That, and actually
the youtube thing is,
it's funny if that's one of your things,
it's worse than,
it's not just youtube who's trying
to get you to watch the video.
It's the video makers themselves.
So you do has the Algorithm, oh,
they got it all kind of sorted out there.
And now the video makers,
they make titles like 50 cal versus
Xyz and awful bunch of those too.
And guess what?
50 cal versus you can fill in the blank.
You're probably going to watch that video.
The main motivation speech ever. Yes.
They, oh yeah. So, so in,
so destroys whatever destroys
reporter in interview.
Exactly right. So once
you really owned the
floodings cause those are actual
things are actual. So basically we'll,
right when you log onto youtube, once
youtube pops up on your screen, Bro,
everyone on that screen is all
sucking your attention. Literally.
That's their job. Sucking your attention.
So yeah man, that's a big one, right?
Instagram. So here's the,
here's the, here's one that
it really hit me really hard.
Graham Graham and I like Instagram.
It's like good.
But if you're trying to read,
you don't, if you want to read
more or whatever,
consider like even like,
let's say we start
recording just for a second,
we're going to look at
the bus on our phones.
We're going maybe checking email
and maybe we got a text or whatever.
And the Cha, the probability of Instagram
coming up on there. We're going to,
you know, open it. But the probability
of US opening Instagram is,
it's pretty significant. It's pretty
high. And you can scroll through there,
whatever. Even if you school
for two, three minutes, right?
You scroll through there and maybe you,
what you looked at a, I don't know,
1520 people's posts,
read what they had to say.
If you have a, what do you, what do you
call it, like kindle or something, right?
You do that same thing. It's like can
the end, like you're saying you can read.
Yeah. Read instead. So
if you had a camera,
like once you said like imagine
you're giddy being videotaped.
Like what if you're being videotaped all
day and all he did was calculate every
time you opened up Instagram or
Facebook or Twitter and or youtube,
all those put every time you open up
and you had that scenario in one average
day. I mean you take all that
time and replace it with,
you opened your kindle to read
more bus out of book, you know,
you've bringing books or whatever we do.
And that's how to, instead of doing that,
you did the book,
right?
You know how much reading you do that
you'd read so much reading. Yeah.
So it's like, yeah, those are the time
sucks man. Your phone, it's so available,
you know? But probably you can read
on your phone too. That's a big one.
TV Too.
He watched TV and not really.
Probably I watched one show now it
actually to Hawaii, five o and that's it.
Sometimes Shark tank. That's it
man. 100% it's weird. What does it,
how often does the Hawaii five o on
once a week and it goes in seasons.
So you got, how long has this Susan?
I Dunno. 13 episodes I guess. I Dunno.
I Dunno.
But on the last,
I have watched one TV show recently.
It's called billions.
Oh,
well
there's a little scenario unfolding
on billions. All right. Well yeah,
actually, yeah. And keep in mind,
it's not like I've never seen any
other show ever. It never will.
It's not that I'm just saying,
you know how people
no watch Tino routinely. And actually, um,
I will separate the fact that nowadays
you can watch TV in a different way.
Right? It's not like at eight
o'clock on a Thursday night.
You've got to sit there and watch 30
minute show with the 30 minutes worth of
commercials in it. Right?
No, you can. You're,
you're
on a flight somewhere.
You've read,
you've got to take it easy
on your eyes a little bit.
If you start reading too much,
you've read for a long time. Okay.
You're going to stare out the
window for a little while,
listen to this part of a podcast or
something. Then you're like, okay,
my brain is like barely functioning.
Okay.
I'm going to watch an episode of billions.
Yeah. On ballers. He everything I
have not, I don't know the different,
well I do know the difference.
I watched that for a little bit but you
know like people will have a routine
like tonight,
you know,
every night for 30 minutes they
watched TV with their kids or whatever.
It's like that doesn't really happen.
Yeah.
Next question. Really Sad.
How much time you can waste these days
with the distractions that are people
trying to get that time from you?
Yeah. Your discipline. Like when
you, when you first start thinking,
disciplining quick. Oh, when I
first started hearing it from you,
that was like one of the things
that popped into my head.
Like as being really obvious. Like if
you are disciplined with your time,
you will have a lot of free time.
Like a lot, a lot of free time,
way more than you would think
anyway because you know,
even when I'm like real busy, you know,
if I can accurately remember my day,
I can remember like just like five
minutes here, 15 minutes there like that.
I did something that was a waste of
time and if you add up all those little
minutes you have probably hours,
probably hours for to do.
Yeah, do something progressive, you know,
productive, progressive, progress,
your life, valuable, valuable,
all those things. Check.
All right. Next question.
Would you,
would your extreme ownership philosophy
have changed or lost confidence if you
had been relieved of command when taking
ownership of friendly fire incident you
described in your first book?
The book extreme ownership
by the way. Yes. Just
to,
to be perfectly clear about this,
I wasn't taking ownership of the
situation shifts so that I could keep,
my job wasn't a political maneuver
to set myself up to look good.
I was taking ownership
of the situation because
I was the leader of the
situation that took place.
I was the guy responsible
for what was happening.
I was taking ownership because
that was the correct thing.
The correct thing is something bad
had happened and I was in charge of it
and yes I could have been fired and if
I would have been fired I would have
accepted it and I wouldn't
have done anything different.
So again,
this is sort of similar to a couple
of questions go like that's extreme.
Ownership is not about avoiding trouble.
It's not about avoiding trouble.
You don't say,
well I own it and then you don't get in
trouble. No, you actually could get fired.
You actually could get fired.
And that's why,
that's why that idea of
preemptive ownership,
I talked about that at one of the
monsters. If, if in the back of your mind,
in the back of my mind I think, you know
what, if the platoon makes a mistake,
I can just blame it on them.
I'll be good.
Well now I'm not really that worried
about their plan cause I got that little
out if I need,
I'm not worried about if the
guys understand the rules
of engagement because I
got that a little out if I need it.
I'm not that worried about deconfliction
cause it's got that little out if they
screwed up.
So I have an out for myself and so I
don't really put 100% effort into the
planning and uh, of the,
of what we're doing,
if I have preemptive ownership,
which says, hey, no matter
what happens out here,
it's my fault. Guess what? Hey guys,
do you understand the honorees?
Let me talk to you about them.
Get, Hey, hey leaf. Do you,
do you guys understand where the,
where the lines of limits of advance our,
so you know where you get desire. You guys
don't understand, hey dude, do we see,
do we have it marked out clearly?
Okay, great. Hey, do the, you know,
like dig in and when you dig in on
stuff then you have less of a chance of
something going wrong.
But when something does go wrong and
you take ownership of what you take
ownership of it. Not to avoid
trouble but to face trouble. Hmm.
That's what you have to do.
So my,
my idea hasn't changed.
In fact,
if I would have blamed someone else and
then kept my job and someone else gotten
fired,
I would have had a real problem with that.
I could not have lived with myself
maintaining that position,
knowing that I had sacrificed someone
below me in the chain of command for my
own good. That doesn't sit with me man.
I wouldn't have been able to do that.
And that's why when I was trying to
figure out who to blame it on cause I was,
cause I was looking at this big problem
because there was a lot of bad things
and I'm thinking about a cookie,
who's fault was this snack?
Couldn't figure out why I didn't feel
comfortable saying it was this guy who was
that guy. It'd be like this guy and the
previous one guy that wireless bill,
his fault.
I don't feel comfortable saying that.
Especially when I'm in charge and I
don't feel comfortable when I'm a peer
either. If I'm, if my peer and when,
but we're part of a team
and something goes wrong.
I don't feel comfortable saying it
was the other guy who does that.
Who feels good about that.
Right? Don't be that person.
And only that when you're,
when you see people acting that way,
everybody can identify that
that's a bad thing to do. Yeah,
but they do it anyways because their ego.
So keep it in check. Yeah. Yeah.
X question whether directly or indirectly.
I know Jocko follows this principle.
The way you do anything is
the way you do everyday.
This is an intro.
This question I had to pull out
because what you're going to see,
it's very,
I think it's a question maybe you might
be even more suited to answer than me.
We'll go ahead. Proceed. Interesting.
Now let's say you're sitting on the
couch and you want to switch the light on
the switches to your right and you know
there's a 95% chance that you can reach
it from where you're sitting
without having to leave.
The couch, what do you do?
Do you take the chance to reach it or
to reach for it in vain and then get up,
walk to the switch and turn it on?
Or do you get up right away and make and
make the extra effort and get it done
in the most efficient manner regardless
of if there was potentially an way.
And
I get you, I know I'd love to give
some big profound answer about this,
but here's the deal.
I would accurately assess the distance,
the light switch right accurately,
accurately,
and I'd figured out the best way to
turn it on and then I'd turn it on.
That's what I do. I mean, if I've
got to get up out of bed to get up,
get to get out of bed or I'd pull,
uh, pull, uh, we on the couch.
Is that the situation? I'm going to
need the light off, so, yeah. All right.
Get the light on my phone out and
just see what I got to see with the,
cause I'm thinking out of the box over
on my side. Right. That's what I'm doing.
What she did as far as the,
as far as the thing,
the way you do anything is the way you
do everything, and it's partly true,
but at the same time,
guess what?
You got to prioritize and execute and
there are some things that are not as
important as other things.
My famous example is that my gym
floor in my home gym is not clean.
It's there's chalk on it,
there's some sweat stains.
I don't go in there three times a week
with a mop and swab it and get all the
chalk out and power wash it.
That's what it would take maybe two
times a week if I power washed it,
pulled all this stuff out of the
garage, power, washed the mats,
pull them back in there,
set the garage back up.
That's what it would take to keep
the mats clean. That doesn't,
I don't care if those mats or clean
or not doesn't matter me. Right?
I have to prioritize. There's much, much,
much more important things than whether
my mats in my garage gym are clean.
Doesn't matter. Yep. Did you do
maths are different, right? Jujitsu,
Matt's gotta be clean.
Those guys,
this is why we got people to clean
those mats after classes. Sure.
That's a priority. The ones at my
house that just me don't matter.
That doesn't mean that I'm
slacking in other areas, right?
There's a minimum standard in
certain things like there's,
and even my home gym mats,
I have a vacuum and I hit him with the
vacuum when I get too much dog hair on
them, which actually I do that
like every one or two days.
It takes three minutes
to just vacuum dog hair,
but there's a minimum
standard to hold the line.
And as far as doing things
the most efficient way,
I try and do things the right way, but
didn't try and do things the right way,
which generally that coincides with
the most efficient way generally,
generally. But here, that's not
what he's talking about here.
So when you say it again when you said,
here's the thing man, Bro, this guy,
you don't,
we don't have his name but man,
we need to get together
and like talk because this,
this is the kind of stuff that I think
about all the time in this obsessive way.
But this enters my mind, man.
That's a good question too.
So basically he's asking like, okay, and
it happens for literally half a second,
maybe one whole second or like, okay man,
I need the light on. What do I do? Do I
like how he said do I reach for it?
Because that's the easiest way I
don't have to up use on my leg and
back muscles to stand up and walk over.
Like just reach for it.
But if I can't reach
it now we've got to do,
expend all the energy of reaching for it,
failing,
bring my hand back and then doing the
standing up being that it was trying to
avoid in the first place. So it's one
of those things. So what do I do, man?
What do I do? We just chance
it or do I just be like, hey,
you don't have not got
a chance to anything.
I'm just going to expand the extra energy
and turn on the light, so what do I do?
Right? Yeah, man. It's a conundrum.
Same thing with the soy sauce polls.
Same thing also. Here's the, here's one.
You might, did you see the meme? Yes.
There's,
there's a couple of standards.
There's a couple of meetings about you
and the soy sauce balls. One of them,
one of them was like a black and
white photo. Did you see that one?
I was like a black and white photo,
but it said something.
It was this black and white photo of, of
soy sauce bowls. Oh yeah. What did it say?
This is better than the struggle is real.
Yeah,
and then they had the superhero
looking guy that had but two buttons.
Anyway, here's one, and here's when
that, this is, this one's a real problem.
Small but a real problem for
most of you from when you're,
when you're laying in bed at night,
you're, you're sleeping and you wake up,
you're like, man, I gotta I gotta take,
I gotta use the bathroom but not too bad.
I don't have to use about their bad
just a little bit. So what do I do?
Do I hold it power through the discomfort
because discomfort isn't that that,
and hopefully I'll fall asleep cause I
don't want to get up and wake myself up
more and turn on the light and do all
this stuff and walk around and get the
blood flowing. And then what if I
can't fall asleep as quick or whatever,
or I'm tired. I don't even want to get
out of bed, you know? So what do I do?
Because if I go use the bathroom on man,
I'll be fully relaxed. It'll be done.
I don't need, it won't keep me up.
That discomfort won't keep me up.
But if I can fall back asleep,
I didn't even have to get out of bed.
You see what I'm saying? So what do you
do? You're at that. And if you really got,
he's about to miss no issue
because it's obvious, you know?
But if you just have to a little bit,
it's a hard question, right? It's true.
Don't even ask. Don't even, I
didn't know. What do you mean?
I said I spend zero seconds.
I spend zero seconds thinking
about that issue. Zero.
This is no factor whatsoever. You're like,
I'm going to go use the bathroom here.
Here's my, here's my answer to your
question. If I have to go to the bathroom,
I go to the bathroom. If you kind of
have to go to the bathroom though,
there's no kind of yes.
No, no, no, no. You're,
it's like if your bladder is full.
Okay. You got, he's about 20 feet.
What if your bladder is one third full?
Then I don't have to go to the bathroom.
Oh, okay. So you have a distinct
like cutoff then in feelings.
So you didn't have that great end
up most or, I don't. So most of us,
we don't have it like that. No.
We got to like consider, you know,
the same way that this guy was no
done than others. Anyway. Anyway,
I dig it and man that's going to
be one of those ongoing challenges.
I think you know,
I think the main,
I almost left that whole second half of
the question because the main point of
the question was the way you do anything
is the way you do everything. Yes,
that's true to a point. You
should definitely keep, you know,
you try and maintain consistent effort
and hold the line and everything,
but the dichotomy is that if you try
and hold the line on every single thing
that's not possible and you'd spend
your whole life cleaning up everything
around you and fixing things and
you'd be wasting time when you have,
you need to prioritize and execute,
pick the biggest problems,
pick the biggest things are going to have
the most impact on you and then focus
on those things and don't worry
about some other things. Shoot man.
That's that little
conundrum as everywhere.
But sometimes it'll be vacuuming and then
you know how like when you vacuum over
it, like I don't know what to say.
It's a piece of big piece of lint.
You go over the vacuum once, you know
and he doesn't go in, you go again.
It doesn't go. You need to go, you go. I
could've picked that thing up like three,
four seconds ago.
So why didn't you?
Cause I thought he could have actually
could have got it with the vacuum and I
wouldn't have to bend down. You know what
I mean? It's like that kind of stuff.
It depends on the topic. Laziness. Too
Old. It's efficiency. Not Laziness,
but either way. You know
what though? This guy,
you combined with this guy's question
answered the question with how you do
everything. You just establish a
protocol. If there's a question,
you just do the guaranteed ones. Yeah. If
I see a piece of the land, I vacuum it.
They didn't go up bone, pick it
up. That's it. A hundred maybe.
You get a double tick.
Right.
Generally you got to go forward
and back when the vacuum anyways.
You know what I'm saying? You can
just rerun that same track. Yeah.
Cause you know you're going
forward back but you're,
you're offsetting a little bit.
Yeah. And sometimes the back,
depending on your brush,
depending on the back or the back ones,
sometimes it's more powerful. Okay.
Cause the brush spins a certain way.
Interesting. But either way.
Yeah, either way. Repeat.
Okay. No. And then guess what?
On the forward stroke, you can go now to
your next track and you can bend down,
grab a piece of lint.
You're good to go. Yeah. So,
and the point is establish a protocol
where it's like, you know what,
I'm not going to waste my time. No. You
know, risking it and all this stuff.
I'm just going to go for the real deal.
All right, next question.
Jocko. I'm a firefighter
slash.
Emt.
I recently and recently I went on
a call where a patient didn't live.
Not unusual by any means.
Unfortunately I deal with loss
of life on almost a daily basis.
I detach and do my job,
always working to get better.
This call I failed to detach.
It hit me hard when the patient's husband
let out a chilling, let out, chilling,
screams.
As third year old wife went from alert
and talking to dead within minutes,
I let myself enter into his shoes.
At that moment.
I got over it quick during
my days off and moved on.
It's part of the job and I accept that,
but my question is when does
it become inhumane? To Detach?
Do we sometimes need to let some
weakness through to remain grounded when
dealing with such major
incidents is loss of life.
Okay? First of all, sympathy
and empathy are not weaknesses.
They're not weaknesses.
In fact,
it actually takes strength to be able
to deal with these types of situations
and these types of emotions.
The week move would actually be to
cut those emotions off completely.
So
that being said,
as you know,
obviously there is a dichotomy because
you cannot let the emotions overwhelm
you. As a matter of fact, if you
get overwhelmed by your feelings,
then you can't do your job properly,
which in its own right is inhumane
because now you're not able to treat the
patients that you're trying to save
because you're getting too emotional about
it. So where do you have
to do the answer for the,
for the millionth time of a different
subject, but comes up all the times.
You've got to find balance.
You have to find balance between being
emotional enough about not being too
emotional.
You have to learn to recognize if you're
going too far in one direction or the
other and you have to
do a self assessment,
you have to look and see
and make sure that the,
that you see the people
you're treating as people,
you have to look at them and make sure
that you're seeing them as people,
that you're not seeing them as a hunk
of meat. Right? You have to do that.
You have to make sure that you're
doing that. At the same time,
you cannot afford emotionally
to go through the pain of
loss every time you see
someone die because that's
also going to be a problem.
You can't afford emotionally to do that.
You can't go through that pain
over and over and over again.
So
you have to, like you said, you have to
detach, normally do a good job with that.
Um, I've seen guys get wounded.
I've seen guys get killed,
I've been around a lot of deaf and when,
when it was around me,
I didn't have time to stop and
think about it. I had to work to do,
I had to detach myself and do my job
at the same time when it's over
and the time was appropriate.
It's like you got to connect with what
happened and make sure that you are
dealing with it appropriately.
And you know, I always think firefighters
and paramedics and mts and, and,
and police and military, but you
know, paramedics and he, mts,
you're only showing up if
someone is in a bad way.
And I know that's hard physically and it's
hard. Mentally, it's hard emotionally.
So find the balance.
Keep yourself balanced,
make sure you're not going too
far in one direction or the other,
and thanks for doing your job
easy.
But sometimes you forget that about UMTS.
Yeah, fire for it. The only
time you know where they spray,
I mean pretty much, yeah. This getting
called because someone is in a bad way.
That's what they're showing up
for. You know, cops too, like
with it,
like it's easy to be on the outside
when you're going to parks and you know,
if your job is like, you
know, well I don't know me,
I press record and make coop v or
make videos and whatever, you know,
and this is like every day, so it kind
of forms this kind of vision, you know,
of my world,
whatever.
But he empties and day every time you get
to call it, it's, it's it, it's just a,
it's just the question is just, Oh, how
bad, you know? Wow. That's where it is.
How bad, how bad of a situation is the
person I'm about to go contend with?
What's their situation? Yeah, they are.
They could be everything
from a minor situation too.
They're going to die in front of me.
Again,
I guess a new person and their life
and their kids and their family and you
know, Peter Attia talked
about some of that. They're
becoming a bit jaded. In fact,
it's a pretty horrific story and it's
worth listening to that podcast when he
was on and he talked about how he got to
a point where some patients he started
to look at, I like Ma, he'd be
mad at them. I'm mad at them.
And that's what you have to
avoid is getting to this point.
You got to,
you got to do your best to
stay emotionally detached
enough that you can do your
job,
but at the same time you can't be looking
at other human beings as if they're
just a piece of meat. Yeah, so hard job.
I think we've got time
for one more question.
I have good ideas,
but I have trouble executing.
Do you have any tips?
I have good ideas,
but I have trouble executing.
Do you have any tips?
Oh yeah.
You have some good ideas,
do ya,
but you can't execute you.
You want to know what those are?
Those ideas are worth
when you don't execute on them.
You know what those ideas are worth.
They're worth nothing.
Ideas by themselves have zero value
unless they can be brought to life.
And I have known plenty of people
with plenty of ideas over the years,
great ideas,
amazing ideas,
but very few people can
actually turn ideas into action.
And those people end up old and bitter
and angry because they didn't execute
their great ideas. And so
here's what you do. You execute.
You actually
make things happen.
And sometimes I'm going to tell you,
when you execute your idea,
it reveals the fact that your
idea isn't all that good.
It's not the brilliant
idea you thought it was.
And some people are actually afraid
of that and that's what stops him.
But I'm not afraid I say,
but bring on that failure.
Let me learn that my idea is no good.
Because even if you learned
that your idea is garbage,
at least you know not to waste any more
time dreaming about it or thinking about
it.
Go onto your next idea.
But don't let these ideas just
wander aimlessly around in your head.
Get 'em out, bring them to life,
poured them into the world,
run with them and get some
friends and family or partners,
someone to help you.
Maybe get some people that are better
at execution than you are and give them
some ownership giveaway those ideas.
It's better to give away those ideas then
let them rot inside your head and die.
And whatever path you take,
whether you force yourself to execute
or you bring people in to help you,
whatever path you're
gonna take, do it. Do it.
Pour some life into your idea
and like I said,
you've got to remember that there's no
guarantee that when you pour life into
idea,
into an idea,
there's no guarantee that that
idea is going to come to life too.
You might pour everything you've gotten
to that idea and it can still die
and you might have to let it die.
You have to let the dream die because
some ideas aren't good enough to live.
That's just the way it is,
but,
but you don't want at
least give it a chance.
Don't let that idea die inside your head.
No more waiting,
no more putting it off or waiting for
the right time with the right people or
the right alignment of things
in the world. No more of that,
no more excuses,
just execution.
Just go and make it happen.
Okay.
And I think that's
all I've got for tonight.
So Echo Charlie,
while we are over here
trying to make things happen.
So we have to go hard.
We have to execute.
You got anything that could
possibly help us execute? Yeah,
our mission. Sure. Well,
let's talk about origin first.
This is an outstanding way to
execute and maintain the execution.
So while we are doing Jujitsu and you
don't know what kind of gear to get yet,
which would be crazy, but hey, people are
starting every day and when you start,
you do have that question
most of the time.
What's the maximum age for
starting Jujitsu? Death.
I think it's the day before you die. The
day before that can be hundred. Whatever.
The reason you don't start the day
before you die is you don't want to go to
your death bed with regret because as
soon as you even learn a little bit of
Jujitsu, you'd be like, Dang, I wish I
would've started that a month ago. Yes,
it had a month of solid Jujitsu to
try and learn what was happening,
how these people were
choking me. Yeah. So yeah,
we have people all the time starting
to adjust to all ages from four or five
below that. Yes, you should be
trained in your little kitchen.
Be Training did you too,
but it's more of a playful thing that
you do with them because you know the
techniques and you start
having them escape the mount.
He started to have them arm lock.
You have to have them put in that rear
naked choke you to make sure you tell him
that the rear naked choke is dangerous
and not to do it if you're not around.
Because that is actually a scary thing.
I used to,
I used to be a little bit nervous about
that when my kids were real little.
You know, they know how to
rear naked choke, you know,
oh maybe my five year old daughter slaps
a rear naked choke on my two year old
son and decides to hang on to that
thing cause he's crying or whatever.
So you gotta be, you gotta be very
careful with that. Yeah. Yeah.
And that's a simple deal where
it's not like a, you know,
a knife or something where it's like, hey,
this is dangerous. Don't let you know.
It's like, it's a little bit more cut
and dry with the rear naked choke.
It's Kinda like, okay, you have to,
you have to deliberately apply the
choke and execute the job for it to be
dangerous.
Not like a knife.
All I'm saying is if you got little
tiny kids below the black for two,
three, four, five, yes.
You teach them basic moves,
you need to explain to them that
the moves are real. Yeah. Um,
and they do work. Yeah. And that's,
I always warn the little kids about
the ones kids are a little bit older.
They understand cause it happens to them
and they know what's going on. Yeah.
So be careful with that part
of Jujitsu for the little kids,
but whether kids are four or whether
you're 60 or 70 or 80 years old,
go get your Jujitsu on going to need a
g g and or rash guard actually Mirage
beat and the rest guard
shack at least one check.
So what kind of Geek origin [inaudible]
planning to choose from planning and be
increasing by the as time goes on,
straight up,
all made in America and factually
the best cookies in the world.
Yeah and when you buy an origin g you are,
you are investing not only in yourself
but you're also investing in this great
country.
As we rebuild manufacturing
inside our country,
bringing back the old New England
factories that they sent overseas,
we're bringing them back.
We are actually bringing them back.
We are buying equipment
back from overseas.
Who bringing it back here on ships. Can
you imagine that's happening right now?
We are doing that.
You are doing that.
You are making that
happen also we got jeans.
Here's the deal.
I talked to Pete p Roberts origin.
I said, Pete, how many people do you
know the do Jujitsu? And he's like,
oh a hundred. I said, how many people
do you know that own a pair of jeans?
And he said 200 million. I
said, we need to make jeans.
Everyone wants genes.
Everyone needs genes.
Everyone would want jeans that are
not only high quality but also made in
America sewn by craftsmen in Maine.
So yeah,
we've got origin jeans.
They're awesome. We got our
can denim, American denim,
like cotton,
cotton cock tineas sewn here,
Jean and grown.
There you go.
Was probably p Robert's hadn't
come up with that one yet.
Grown and sold in America baby.
Boom. There it is. Well also joggers,
speaking of pants,
jeans or pants.
Obviously joggers don't get
into a joke cause you're,
you're not allowed to do joggers.
But for us who like
comfort and functionality,
maybe of twist of style of whatever.
This is younger so isn't there.
Why don't we keep bringing
up joggers specifically?
Is it because of my experience
with the younger, like the joggers,
people like joggers and you can also
get supplements. We have supplements.
We have joint warfare, we have krill oil,
we have discipline. You have discipline.
Go according to Jp Denelle,
when he takes discipline go,
he can see people's thoughts.
I was like, there were so fired
up. He did, you know, an event,
fresh lawn in front of you. It's
like, he's like, I was so fired up,
I could see people's thoughts and I'm
like, I liked the way that sounds.
So discipline, go nootropic
get the uh, mind kicking.
And then you've got disciplined for
pre workout. Krill oil, joint warfare,
keep the bones, the tendons, ligaments,
ligaments, keep all that
stuff good to go. Maintained.
Uninflamed so there's inflammation.
What's the anti inflammation.
So keep them anti inflamed and keep
them moving. Keep them lubricated,
keep them functioning. Very
important. And in milk we got milk.
Some people don't even know what mark is.
And it's really easy to explain.
Milk is milk happens to have what?
22 grams of protein in there.
Clean protein by the way,
which is different, you know? And it
was just very delicious. And those,
I'll talk to my friend Kenny
the other day. He's like, oh yeah, what's
so special about this thing? And it Kinda,
I got past, I detached, you know, I got
past that emotion a little bit emotional.
But I was like, I started like going
into this whole pitch to my friend.
By the way, it turned out to be a
pitch, but just like how it's all clean.
And then we use know monk fruit
to sweeten it and it's like,
it doesn't taste like some
day I think or whatever.
It's like a dessert at the
end of the day I think.
I think he accepted the bid thing to do.
If someone wants to know,
he'd get mixed one up. Yeah. Cause as soon
as you mix one on people like, Oh yeah,
I'm pretty, I'm ordering
it. I'm getting this now.
Cause how can this be good for you?
That's the question.
How can this be good for you?
Yeah, it tastes like that.
It's true. Milk, chocolate,
peanut butter, chocolate,
vanilla, gorilla, darkness.
The darkness.
And then there's,
this is what I believe to be
kind of epic warrior can Moke.
Yes,
because warrior kid milk.
You can go to your grocery store and you
can buy something that will flavor the
milk so that your kids will drink milk,
but while your drink,
while you're giving the milk,
you're also giving them poison.
Right. Is Sugar or is enough? Yeah. You
can eat enough sugar that you die. Right.
People do it all the time.
They get beat us. Yeah,
so we don't want to give our kids poison.
We want to give them power.
How do we do what we got? Warrior Kid
Moke we've got strawberry and chocolate.
They taste amazing.
They are engineered.
The best possible food that
your kids gunny eat. Yeah.
Think about it. You can say,
Oh, you want some dessert and
they'll get all excited here.
Have a strawberry milkshake and
what do they think? Thank you.
Can I have more? And you know what
you say? Sure, of course you can.
You can have all you want because
this is pea protein and probiotics and
vitamins.
This is everything you're supposed to
be eating as a child to grow up and be
strong and a world beater.
You the tower. All
right, check. Yes. Okay.
Also,
if you want to stay on the
path and represent at the
same time attire wise jock
was store, it's called Jocko store. So
you get a chocolate store.com that's,
we can get your tee shirts,
rash guards for the Jujitsu.
And it's good to have more than one
rash guard for multiple reasons.
One is that if one gets dirty,
you don't have to rush to wash it.
A rush to get it back
into rotation necessarily.
It can be a whole decision making process.
You got to deal with Iran,
which can be problematic for
Echo Charles. It's possible. Yes.
But you know what I ran into and this is
so psychological, so I were, you know,
whatever.
I have a bunch rash guard so I get
injured wearing this one rash card I got
won't wear it anymore cause I'm like
superstition.
Yeah. But here's the thing. I know that
superstitions is fake, but you know what?
I'm superstitious. Superstitious
about being super superstar.
No, no, I don't care.
Yeah. See for sure didn't hurt you,
bro. Bro. I know exactly what hurt me.
That's what makes it even worse.
Either way, whether that's your issue,
retire the rash guard that you weren't
today when we were training. No, no,
no. Are you sure? No, because
I see, I see what you did there. No,
that none another white rescue or
the word today was all good. He was,
the problem I had today was psychological
and it wasn't really, actually,
you're my problem. You
are my problem. Yeah.
It's funny though, for all my
Jiu Jitsu career, you know,
if I have a good role with someone
and I and I and I, you know,
do good against them. A
lot of times they say, Oh,
you're really strong. Right? They never
say like, oh, you got good Jujitsu.
They never say, oh, like I liked
your guard passing, or hey,
you got a really good hip
movement. No, they don't say that.
What did they say is your strong,
yeah,
that's what they say today I got my first
kind of alternate compliment from Echo
Charles. You didn't
say I was strong? Nope.
You said I psychologically destroyed you.
Yeah.
What was it? The whole
thing. Okay, so you,
and you've been doing this kind
of recently where like I can't,
I don't even have to be breathing hard,
but just maybe just a little,
you'll like act, you'd be like put on
this little charade. Like oh I like,
oh we're all like pushy or
something. You'd be like, oh man.
Like you want to say that? But
you'll, your body will be like,
oh that pushes so hard.
So you'll do that and I know what you're
doing obviously because you make it
obvious. But then what that
does to me is like, man,
that's like so you don't really
take me seriously right now.
So it kind of makes me angry but little
bit like frustrated cause I'm planning
to do a little something against,
he sounds like there's something
and then yeah.
Then when you wind up like doing things
and then I'll kind of look at you and
kind of feel and then you do this real
good, normal face kind of scenario.
And I think that I can do good normal
face two, but on the inside I don't,
I don't feel normal face, you know,
but all I see is like you're just,
we're just being whatever, making
jokes. If your hand doesn't look like,
just so you know,
on the inside and the outside on the
inside you don't feel normal face.
It doesn't look normal. On the outside it
looks pretty evident. What's happening?
Well I don't know yet. At the end of the
day it's Sorta just crept in and yeah,
I didn't like maintain the composure that
I think is required to function at a,
you know, at a better level than
I did today. Put it that way.
And the thing is right when the timer
goes off, when we're done it like,
it's like an avalanche of like reflective.
It's about shame. I always think
it's all part of the process.
No matter how long and painful the
process is. Did you come in today with,
uh, with a good positive attitude on the,
what the outcome was going to be? Yeah.
Do you feel you were feeling good today?
Yes. So, and it just to be accurate.
Like I don't,
we always joke about this.
I don't come in thinking [inaudible]
I'm gonna get y'all go in of whatever.
I don't ever really positive.
Are you're sure about that?
I don't think of that for a fact. There's
been days where if you've come in, you,
I can see it in your eyes
and you're thinking, I can do
this today. Well, no. Well,
I do think that yes, I can do,
but it's not up. And you kind of,
sometimes you go up out of fear,
you just try to convince yourself you're
trying to be like a peacock. Right.
Sometimes that happens. That's cool.
I don't, I don't hold it against you.
I just accept it.
But sometimes you actually think like
today's the big day and when I see that
look, yeah, I think, okay,
well good luck. Not about like,
okay, I'm going to like
beat up John. It's not that.
It's more that like I have a hip thing
is all you need to do is capitalize on
one mistake.
That's all that it is.
You can just play the numbers game now
you know you're good enough at Jujitsu.
Now if I make a mistake, you can
capitalize on it. You can just,
you can just play the odds.
I can beat you a hundred times and I
can beat you a hundred times where I can
tap you out. No, we don't
even care. It doesn't even,
it doesn't even doesn't
mean mean anything.
You roll the dice one time and you
get snake eyes. You get the big win.
That's where it's at. Yeah, it, it'd be
a seven or 11 but yeah. All good. Yeah.
It's like an insurgent situation for sure.
You can smash me all you want,
but I just get you on time
and devastate. Yeah, but it's,
and it's normally not like I'm not
necessarily trying to get actually most of
the time pretty much all the
time. I'm not trying to, like,
the goal is never to tap anyone out
today. It's not that. It's like to,
to practice new things that I feel
like I'm getting a hold of okay.
Against certain levels of people. And
then so you're not trying to tap me out.
Well then of course I am, but that's not
like a good goal for the day, you know,
kind of thing.
It's more like okay I'm going to put
together this like defense and combined
with this little thing and whatever.
And for you it's real specific cause it's
like rolling with you isn't like this
Wah.
It's like very specific scenario and
which in like includes the psychological
part and that's why I
noticed the psychological
devastation that you sorta had
today is because after the time
the timer went off, we're done.
It all came to me like,
man,
you just got destroyed psychologically
so bad that that goals that you had for
that specific role and for all
roles with chocolate today,
like literally didn't have anything
to do with the role that you just did.
We talk right now because of like
your whole mindset and mindset,
you know, and it was all because
of the stuff you're doing.
And here's the kind of the dichotomy of
it. It's like Super Fun when it happens,
but the cause like the frustration
is like pushing you, you know?
But then it's like at the end of the day
it's all just one big game, you know?
But it, it, there is a legitimate
amount of frustration in there for sure.
It's funny cause I can see
that dichotomy in your face.
Like I can tell that you're mad, but I
can also tell that it's fun, you know?
But you do get frustrated. Yeah. But
some, sometimes you get legitimately
like,
like you make noises that frustration
like groans or growls and you know what I
mean? Yeah. But it's like at you know how
like when you know what else you'll do,
let's go get right now. Right. Like
a little kid, like a six year old.
The thing is like for real. And I said
from the outside I can see how that,
that could,
you know,
like you know what I don't
like is when I tap someone out,
let's say I'm in,
I'm in half guard and I tapped someone
out with something and I let go and then
they're like, then they want to keep
going. Like as if that just didn't happen.
Oh from that exact position. You kind of
need that to me today. And I was like,
I mean it's not, it's not like
it's a big deal, but I was,
I then I'm like okay,
cause you know,
I mean I did whatever move
I did and then I let go,
you tap and then I let go of it and then
it's like we'll just keep going and I
don't know why. I'm like, what, why
would we keep going? And you just,
you just submitted I and there's other,
the other thing is sometimes people,
I think you've done this to
me like maybe 10 times, no,
maybe five times where you tap and then
like I let go and then you let come at
me like you like you like double leg or
whatever you like grab you and you try
it, you know, and that, that's
another one I'm like, okay, cool.
I see where I see how this is going.
And I think you're doing that
out of frustration. Yeah.
Tyler Shirley partially out
of like you ever understand,
sometimes you want to learn
what just happened, right?
Like he put me back in that position.
Yes. Cool. Yeah, I get that part too.
Even that kind of bothers me I guess.
But I could see, you know what though,
from an offensive standpoint, like from
Europe position and someone's like, oh,
can we start from there? It's
kind of like, you know, the flow,
it's like not linear, but
you know, the path of,
of like from start to finish,
that whole path is like a big
creative learning battle. Fights,
wins, losses, like it's a whole path.
I think that's why it bothers me because
I like that whole fit and a completed
that whole thing, that whole
thing of, cause let's face it,
it's a big,
there's a lot of things that go on.
There's a lot of things that happen from,
from we start rolling or you start
rolling with someone to someone submits.
There's all kinds of things,
especially your starting standing
you've got to take down to contend with.
You've got guard pass and
you've got guard recovery,
got sweet to get all these things to
get to this point where you can actually
submit somebody and all of a sudden we're
just going to skip 85% of that battle.
Which by the way, from my
perspective, all that time,
all of that battle is I'm, I'm maneuvering
the whole time. You know what I mean?
Like it's a part of my game. It's all
part of me getting that submission.
Submission doesn't start when
I hit the mat. The submission,
it starts before we shake
hands. You know, Sam,
when we skip a big chunk of the,
I liked that whole part of the battle.
When we skip it, I just feel like,
oh that's kind of weird. Yeah.
Like we just jumped to the end of the
good song that has the Guitar Solo.
Like no, you've got to listen to the
whole song man. I appreciate that thing.
You're right. Right. A good movie. Right.
Let's just skip to the scene
where the battle takes place.
You have you ever done that?
You just watched the battle scenes and
not as good as when you watched the whole
breakup to Colin and I
want to hear the whole,
I want the whole buildup to take place.
I don't just want to watch the battle
scene. Yeah. That's actually that good.
And I might actually glad that
we kind of analyzed it because,
cause you cause it could be looked at.
I always looked at it because I've
done that. Like I don't always do that.
[inaudible]
you've done it probably five times.
We've rolled thousands of
times and um, it's like, okay,
can we start from there kind of thing.
And I it because he's a
little bit different, a little
bit different. It's like,
Hey, can you just wait, put that back on
me. Let me see if I could get out. Okay,
you got out. Cool. Now we'll start
again. I'm not talking about that. Yeah,
I'm talking about what I did. Yeah.
Today where I was like, I didn't say it,
but I just sort of stayed there kind of
like, let's kind of take it from here.
It goes, you. Yay. That was me. And um,
and I've done that before. Really rarely,
but I looked at it as shoot,
that was like a pro.
Like I made it a legitimate
mistake right there.
Let me like get back in that mindset
and continue actually rolling. Nothing.
That's part of what bothers
me. Yeah. It's not up to me.
I think part of what bothers
me is I think to myself,
Oh, you just made this little
mistake and it was kind of a fluke.
That's what you're implying is like,
oh, this is just a little fluke.
You were lucky that won't happen again.
That's like,
sometimes people get mad when
I submit them. Not very rarely.
I'd say rarely and I'm always like,
man,
is that this is that much of an
insult that I just have to out.
You know what I mean? Like I'm not, when
somebody taps me out, I'm not mad at them.
I don't know. I'm like Dang, nice
job. That was awesome. Good job.
But yeah,
I think people are mean anyway.
It's like anytime water get like
anything's out of frustration and it's
literally like maybe a 30% frustration,
70% you're just a guy that can
take that kind of abuse. You know?
Like if you're like,
okay good,
you tapped me out and then I you
turn your back to reset and I yeah,
I jumped on your back or they're
taking it down, whatever. Like you can,
I won't do that normally to say no.
And even when you do it to me,
it's not like you,
you haven't ever like jumped in like put
a rear naked choke on or something like
that.
You've kind of jumped into a slightly
advantageous but normal position for us to
be in, which is no big deal. Let me give
you, I've taken my back a couple times.
Yeah. But, and then even then like, Bro,
we been in this thing for a long
time where it's let's say I got it.
Maybe that might,
would that even bother you?
Let's say I jumped on your back
in one of those situations.
Then I got the room naked
choke and I finished it.
Well, I would kind of be like,
well, well we both know, you know
like Friday didn't catch you. Yeah.
But I'm real quick back to the, uh,
the path, you know like when you, when,
when you want to like you have a guy
and he wants to start from that same
position or whatever. Yeah. If you look
at that path, that whole path that is,
so let's this fate, that's a valuable
path. Every path that you create,
it's like learning and
it's this big and it's fun.
There's little competitiveness
in there or whatever.
And at the end you finish each path as
like this tree or whatever it's done.
You finish it with your submission when
you win or when you lose two in training
or, or even in competition for sure
you win or you lose. You can't,
like after you win and complete your
masterpiece path of wins and losses and go
through the whole thing and you're done
deck, I just can't step in and be like,
no, it's not done. It's just sort
of paused on my team. Like Bro,
you can't jump in and dictate that
kind of stuff. You lost brother.
You got to start all over and try to
create something else. No, you know,
try new song. Can't just meet
her. But at the same time
if you're looking at like training,
rolling as just practice, just training,
just you know, whatever. And so
there's a big difference between, hey,
we're going to actually practice right
now. You're right and we're going to roll.
Yeah. Cause Rolling is
understood that it's competitive.
That's the whole reason it works so
good. It has to be competitive. So yes.
That's why when you taught me out,
I do consider it,
no matter how much percentage
of whatever I do consider it.
You beat me straight up
and practice in training,
you beat me because there's a significant
amount of competition right there.
So yeah,
you can't be messing,
messing with the other guys
wins and knew that I can't,
I'm never doing that ever again.
If you want to do it, it's fine.
I'm just saying that's noted. If
not fine. I'm not doing noted.
I don't want to be that guy to do it.
Even just being in that guy. Nonetheless,
back to representing [inaudible]
from Jocko store chocolate stuff.
Shirts and rash guards and hoodies,
hats.
Cool stuff you want to represent
on the path if you, okay,
so it made the new a new good shirt. I
think it's on there. Yeah, it's on there.
It's just, it's good.
It's good. Literally, um,
says good on it with the font and,
but it does not have your head on it,
so it's way more basic, you
know? That's the one where like,
you really gotta be in the know.
You see it in, in the wild.
You're going to be like, listen,
you know? Yeah. Is that good?
Do you see the dude that got good on his
dms? I think it was this thumbs. Oh yeah,
she,
oh,
on one and Odi on the other and then I
had to dig it in proper font by the way.
It's the game. So yeah, if you want
to represent on the path Jocko,
store.com if you like something,
get something white tea
Jocko white tea available,
drinking it right now from the cam,
which it comes in tasty and good for you.
And also the tea bags.
You can get that stuff on Amazon
and if you get it you can deadlift
8,000 pounds, which is awesome. Yeah,
so that's something also subscribe to
the podcast if you haven't already.
I'm just gonna we're missing to leave
it at that if you haven't already.
Hey subscribe if you want,
you don't have to.
And don't forget about the warrior
kid podcasts. Just released
two new where your kid podcast 22 and
23 get some questions for uncle Jake.
Hear some stories from Uncle
Jake about when he was a kid.
Okay.
Also you get warrior kids soap from
Irish oaks ranch.com there's now trooper
soap. Yup. With the rope, with
the ropes opener. Oh yes. Yeah,
so Irish oaks ranch.com Aiden is up
there making soap on his farm and what he
wants us all to do is stay clean.
Did you tell him and then now he wants
us to stay clean or are you just sort of,
you know, imposing your
tagline? I imposed deal.
I dig it either way.
Also youtube if you want to,
if you're interested in the video version
of this podcast or you want to just
see excerpts or whatever
from the podcasts, get on
Youtube. That's where you get,
there's also videos that echo perceives
as very legit cause he made him,
you're the one who use word, legit check.
Also psychological warfare
on iTunes, Google play, MP,
three platforms everywhere.
This is a album where I can help
you in little moments of weakness.
Get over that moment of weakness and
get yourself to stay on the path.
If you want something visual to help you
stay on the path. Checkout, flip side,
canvas.com
it's a little company owned by my brother
Dakota Meyer podcasts one 15 by the
way.
Absolutely an epic podcast to hear and
listen to and to be a part of with Dakota
and we became good friends after that
and he's got this company flipside
canvas.com and he is making
pictures,
canvasses posters that are cool and
we'll help you stay on the path.
There's a discipline. He goes freedom
one. There's one that says good on it.
If there's anything else you want,
let me know on the social media
and Dakota, we'll make it happen.
Take it also when you're
expanding your home gym,
going to for free stuff, rinks,
jump ropes, kettle bells,
primal bells, Star Wars,
kettle bells as well. Anyway,
a lot of good stuff on there. You want
some immune stuff for your immune system.
Some of it's a lot of
real good stuff on there.
Go to [inaudible] dot com
slash Jocko really good stuff.
Also we got some books,
Mikey and the dragons,
Mike and the dragons is about a little
kid that's trying to overcome some fear
and he does it by reading a book.
The book was called the Dragon Prince.
Check it out. Mikey and the dragons
also weigh the warrior kid one,
two and soon to be three.
That's a series of books
about a kid that's happened,
kind of normal trouble that kids have,
but he's got an uncle,
uncle Jake who used to be in the tames
and he comes and helps his cousin out or
he's, yeah, his, his cousins. His
nephew comes and helps his nephew out.
So those are called way of the warrior
kid marks mission and where there's a
will is book three also discipline
equals freedom field manual.
That's a book that you need or to book.
You can give.
I'm super stoked when I meet
people and they say, Yup,
I've given 28 copies of the discipline
equals freedom field manual away way to
other people in my family,
other friends that I have. Why?
Because it will help people get on
the path and live a better life.
That's a powerful thing. If you can
actually help someone live a better life.
There's a manual on how to live your life.
It's called the discipline equals freedom
field manual. It's not a normal book.
It's not normal. My publisher,
when he was publishing it,
he said,
this book is the biggest risk that he
has ever taken in his publishing career.
And the, he also said, and we're actually,
my agent told me once the book came out,
the book,
the book's sold more than any scenario
that they had predicted for the book.
So they, you know, they do these
predictions. It's like, Oh,
if it tells us it sells out, it sells
this thing that sells it. It sounds,
the other thing, there's something called
a hundred percent sell through rate,
which means every single book that got
shipped to got sold, this does not happen.
And then they're back ordered
and I had to make more.
Now the book is still selling like that
discipline equals freedom field manual.
Why does it keep selling?
Because people read it and they get it
for people they know. So check it out.
It is the manual telling you how to
get on the path and stay on the path.
The audio version of that book is
not on audible, it's on Itunes,
it's on Amazon music, it's on
Google play and other MP3 platforms.
Of course there is extreme ownership.
The first book that I wrote with my
brother Leif Babin about the combat
leadership principles that we learned
on the battlefield and how you can apply
them to your business and life,
and we followed that book up with a
book called the dichotomy of leadership,
which,
well,
some people are saying it's better
than extreme ownership. Read it,
judge for yourself.
Tell us what you think.
I think if you read extreme ownership,
when you read dichotomy,
a lot of things are gonna fall into place.
A lot of little,
little,
little things that you didn't quite
have it that we you wanted it to be.
When you read dichotomy, it's
going to come into place. Also,
we've got echelon front,
which is our leadership consultancy.
We solve problems through leadership.
That's what we do. It's me, Leif Babin,
JP Denelle, Dave Burke, Flint Cochran,
Mike Cirelli, Mike [inaudible],
and our latest addition to the team
master chief Seale retired Jason Gardner.
Go national on front.com if you want
us to come work with your company, the,
we got three musters this year.
All musters ever have sold out.
These are going to sell out well as well.
There's May 23rd and 24th in Chicago,
September 19th and 20th in Denver,
December 4th and fifth in Sydney,
Australia.
Go to extreme ownership.com if
you want to come to these things,
just go and register.
I had friends,
friends that said, hey, you know
what? I didn't really sign up.
Can you just give me a couple of
tickets? And I'm like, actually no,
I can because we, we can't fit
any more people in the building.
So No.
So I can't help you if you wait too long,
register,
get on it early enough online.
This is our interactive
leadership training.
If you want to get everyone
in your company aligned,
if you want to everyone in your company
to understand the fundamental principles
of extreme ownership.
If you want them to understand the
fundamental laws of combat that we used on
the battlefield and that we have
now talked to scores of businesses.
If you want to have that training,
you can go to GF online.
It's interactive.
It's you have to make decisions.
It's choose your own adventure.
It's tests,
it's it's briefings,
it's everything and it's awesome.
So check out [inaudible] dot com
also ETF Overwatch where we are connecting
proven leaders from the SPEC ops and
combat aviation communities with
companies in the civilian sector.
Now here's the thing.
You might think,
well I've got to hire somebody
that's experienced in this industry.
That's a good thought.
I understand where you're coming from.
What I recommend you try is instead of
hiring a person that has experienced in
the industry,
has hire somebody that has experience
in something more important that is
leadership.
You can teach them on,
they can learn very quickly the industry
that you are bringing them into.
What you can't teach someone and would
you can't give them as 20 years, 25 years,
22 years of leadership experience in
the most high stakes business there is.
And that is war,
so go to EDF,
overwatch.com if you want to hire
someone like that or if you are in that
position,
if you're a vet and you want to look to
get placed into a company that's looking
for leadership Efo,
overwatch.com and if you want to spend
even more time with Echo Charles and
myself because for some reason you think
500 hours of podcasts isn't enough for
you. We are out there. We are
lurking on the inner webs on Twitter,
on Instagram and on Facebook.
Okay,
bookie,
Mohan Echo is adequate.
Charles and Imr,
Jocko Willink and thanks to all the
people in uniform for your service.
That's our military personnel.
Also our police and law enforcement,
correctional officers,
border patrols, all first responders
and tonight especially the firefighters,
paramedics, EMT, yes,
who face suffering and death on a daily
basis and they learn how to handle it.
They learn how to stay balanced. They
learn how to detach, but not too much.
Thanks for all of you for providing us
the freedom and security that we enjoy
every day.
And to everyone else that's listening,
you have ideas and you have
dreams and you have vision,
and that's cool.
That's awesome.
But none of that means
anything unless you execute.
So execute, move forward, take
action. And you know what?
Maybe your idea works and maybe
it doesn't. And if it doesn't,
then try another one. And maybe none of
them will ever work. And that's fine,
because in the end, at
a minimum, you know,
at least you went out there
and got after it.
So until next time,
this is echo and Jocko out.