You know, something I realized, so as
Lafe and I had been talking about why you,
we wrote the book, the
Dichotomy of leadership,
why we picked that topic and what we've
been saying is most of the questions
that we would get asked would be
about that iconomy leadership.
That's completely true. But I'll tell
you on top of that, more important,
most of the answers that I give are that
there is a dichotomy in leadership and
you needed to be balanced. That is what
you, even today I got asked at Camp,
Hey Jocko, I'm a white belt, but
I want to be default aggressive.
But I also hear you telling me to
relax all the time. Which one is it?
What do you want me to do? Should I be
default aggressive and get after it?
Yeah. Or You tell me relax.
And I actually, you know,
I say relax harder, right? Charter,
which one do you want me to do?
And I said, well luckily, and
lives there too. I'm like left.
Luckily for this very reason Lafe and I
just wrote a book called the dichotomy
of leadership. And there's
a dichotomy with aggression.
Even though I say default
aggressive, and I say you've got,
that's gotta be your mindset.
That's gotta be your default mode as
you're going to be aggressive and you're
going to go get after it.
And there's a chapter in the book that
doesn't mean that you run to your death,
right. You have to balance
that with caution with,
with energy conservation,
with not wasting movement on the mat,
with not wasting capital in
business without burning bridges.
Like all those things, you have to be
balanced. And that's why I think like you,
and that's a great way of
putting it. It's going to,
it's going to recalibrate
and fix your brain. Yes.
I've had a lot of these conversations
with be little, you know. OK. Uh,
because something, cause he's, he's a
different beast than I am. I'm pretty,
I'm pretty passive. Like, like
do your job, do it, right.
Like I'll help anywhere I can. And, and
that's just in general, right? Like,
I'm, I'm there, like I'm there, I'm always
on contact me anytime a day in some,
in some. And so be littles in, uh, in a
leadership position sometimes be like,
Jocko says, you ever get
that? Jocko says, oh yeah.
So the Jocko says thing in, you know,
Junko says default
aggressive Jocko says this.
And the idea isn't that in your
brain you're thinking Jocko says the,
the idea is that you, you,
you rewire your brain.
So that innately your saying something
and not thinking about what Jocko would
say, you know, you want to make it
your own. And that's a real ownership.
And we were talking about
a little a little bit ago,
real ownership is that
you're not just saying it,
but you're understanding what you're
saying and why you're saying it and the
words are coming not as a game, but as
truth because that's what you believe.
And that I think takes
a long time for people.
I thought where you're going
with the Jocko says is when,
when the subordinate uses your name
to make something happen. Right?
Well exactly, exactly.
Hey, well, hey Giacosa,
this is where we're going to do things.
And it's like, okay, well that's not,
why do you need to say that? That's
the same as saying I outrank you.
That's the same as ankle. Look.
Exactly. Rank you. Yeah, and just do it.
We're going to do it. Yeah. Hey
Jocko said that's what he wants.
It doesn't make any sense.
Like you can't do that. You can't do that.
You can't use your boss's
name as your authority. Right.
If what your boss has told you to make
happen doesn't make sense and you can't
explain why it makes sense and you need
to go to back to your boss and say,
Hey boss, I'm having some trouble here.
Can you explain to me why
we're doing it this way?
So I can explain that down the
chain of command to the troops.
They know what's going
on in the field and,
and you know what else is real important
and valuable that I think I took away
this year is like the 70
30 the 80 20 the 90 10
if, if,
if there's a decision that
needs to be made and, and
yeah,
someone else's 70% there.
And you're the leader and in
your mind you're 90% there.
What do you do? Yup. All Day long. Pick
that up. Set a Saturday set or set.
Yeah. And that has been
a hard lesson for me.