Uncle Jake wanted to tell a story about
a fighter pilot that he knew when he was
a kid and this fighter pilot taught
uncle Jake some very important lessons.
So here is a story from Uncle Jake
when I was a kid,
I had a kid in my fourth grade class named
Jonathan that sat behind me in class.
He wasn't really my friend, but he
was friends with some of my friends.
And this boy Jonathan used to talk
all the time, talk, talk, talk, talk,
talk. And it really annoyed
me. Not only did he talk,
but he had a voice that kind of came
out through his nose and it made it even
more annoying. He would say, Hey, when
are you guys doing? What are you up to?
What are you doing? What's happening? How?
How are you guys doing
nonstop all the time.
And the more I was around him, the more
I got annoyed. Sometimes I even got angry
one day.
It really started to get to me.
So I told him to just be quiet.
Okay.
And he was quiet for a little while,
but not for very long.
And then it was talk, talk, talk,
talk, talk again, talk, talk, talk.
Yeah.
I couldn't stand it. It was
so aggravating. Finally,
one day I got super annoyed.
We were sitting on the ground during
reading time and how it's just trying to
read and he kept talking.
I'd had enough and I finally
looked at him and I said,
would you just shut your mouth
only instead of saying it quietly because
I was so mad. It came out way too loud,
so loud that everyone in the
classroom heard me say it,
including the teacher and my teacher
did not like that at all and I got in
trouble. The teacher,
Mrs Tally was her name.
She came over and sent me
to the principal's office.
I was the one that got sent to the
principal's office even though it was
Jonathan had been talking. Now what
was I going to do? As you can imagine,
the principal called my house and
told my parents I had been in trouble.
Now pay attention here because I have
to tell you another part of the story.
It's a story within a story,
but it will lead back to Jonathan and
how that whole situation turned out.
You see, there was a man that
used to come over to our house.
Sometimes he was older than my dad,
but not by much.
My Dad called him captain.
The captain had been in the navy,
but he didn't drive ships.
He was a pilot in the navy.
He flew planes and during the Vietnam War,
his plane was shot down and he parachuted
to the ground, but when he landed,
he was surrounded by the enemy and they
captured him and put him into a prisoner
of war camp and it was an awful place.
Yeah,
there was horrible food and they didn't
get much of it and the water made them
sick and they lived in baron rooms called
prison cells and it was hot and it was
miserable
and the prisoners were treated
horribly by the guards in the prison.
They were beaten and they were starved
and they were given no freedom to do
anything.
The only good thing that the prisoners
had is that they were not alone.
There were other prisoners.
They're mostly other pilots that had
been shot down and most of the time they
lived with each other in
these tiny prison cells.
Okay.
I only knew about all this because my
dad had told me what had happened to the
captain.
Well,
after I got in trouble at school for
getting annoyed at Jonathan who talked all
the time and I yelled at him,
my dad invited the
captain over to my house.
Yeah.
And my dad said that the captain
wanted to tell me something.
Then when we sat down after dinner,
the captain looked at me
and started to talk and
when the captain talked,
everybody listened.
Yeah.
The captain spoke slowly and clearly and
you could tell that he meant every word
he said,
and this is what he told me
that night. He said, Jake,
okay,
I know you got into
some trouble at school.
Yeah,
I know you've got annoyed with another
kid and yelled at him during class.
Now I want to tell you something.
When I was a fighter pilot,
I was shot down and got
captured by the enemy.
I was put into a prison camp
and it was a horrible place.
And in that prison we had cellmates.
Okay.
Those were the other prisoners that we
lived with and the rooms were small and
we were hungry and we were sick and
we were tired and we were miserable.
And in that
terrible situation,
it would be very,
very easy for me to get annoyed
with my cellmates. In fact,
we all could have gotten
annoyed with each other.
Okay.
Maybe my cellmate snored or maybe
he coughed all day and all night.
Or maybe he cracked his knuckles all
the time or picked his nose or scratched
his feet in a gross way.
That made me really annoyed.
But Jake,
I was in that prison camp with
those other guys for six years.
Okay.
Six years.
Yeah.
That is a long, long, long time.
To be in prison. And that is a
long, long, long time to be annoyed.
And in that prison we didn't have
many other choices for friends.
It was just us and our cell mates.
That's it.
Okay.
So we came up with a rule
and the rule was that
if someone annoyed us,
it wasn't their fault.
It was our fault.
If we let their snoring bother us,
if my roommate snort,
it was my fault. If I let that
bother me, it was my fault.
If I got aggravated at the way
my cellmate scratched his feet,
it was my fault.
If I couldn't stand the way that my cell
mate coughed or talked to or cracked
his knuckles,
it was my fault.
That was the rule.
We couldn't allow
ourselves to get annoyed.
Being annoyed would've
made that prison much,
much worse than it already was,
and we couldn't have that
and we didn't have that
ever.
So Jake,
if you let someone annoys you,
you're allowing something that
shouldn't control you to control you.
You're letting it get inside your head.
And I know you're young,
but that's no excuse.
You can't do that.
You have to learn to ignore the little
things that annoy you. I promise you,
yeah,
that there are enough things in
life that can go wrong. Big things,
important things that
you'll have to worry about.
So don't let these
little things bother you.
Just accept them and shake them off.
Think about something else
and don't focus on little
things that annoy you,
but that don't really matter.
Does that make sense to you,
Jake?
Okay.
And I said to the captain,
yes sir. And I meant it.
I couldn't believe what the captain had
been through and I couldn't believe that
he had this amazing attitude.
I could see in him how strong you have
to be to stay calm and not let things
annoy you.
It made me feel like I was a giant Wimp
for letting little things bother me.
And that was the first lesson
that I learned from the captain.
And he taught me much,
much more over the years.
And I'll tell you more about those
lessons later. But this first lesson,
it was an important one.
And after that,
when I went back to school and I
heard Jonathan Talk, talk, talk,
talking in his annoying voice high,
just let it go.
It wasn't a big deal anymore and I
was strong enough to deal with it.
And that's the lesson I learned.
I learned it from Jonathan,
but more I learned it from the captain.
And to this day,
even as a grown man,
all these years later when some little
thing is bothering me or annoying me,
I think of how much worse things could be.
And I just ignore that little thing.
And even if I can't ignore it,
I just keep my thoughts to myself.
I keep it inside and I put a smile on my
face and I worry about bigger things in
the world.
And you know what?
When you act like things don't bother you,
eventually they don't.
So be strong and don't let
little things annoy you.