This is Jocko podcast number
66 with Echo Charles and me,
Jocko Willink. Good
evening, Echo. Good. Even
at three 25 the true once again
received orders to attack.
I gave an order full of enthusiasm.
I told the troop we attack and
five minutes to the 70 [inaudible].
This is the movement we have all awaited.
Although we knew the general
locations of large enemy units,
we had not received detailed intelligence
about the enemy we were to encounter.
I had a feeling however,
that this time we would meet the enemy.
Lieutenant Gaultier known for his deadpan
sense of humor, asked on the radio,
what kind of contact can we expect?
I replied,
enemy contact. He said, Roger,
that's the best kind and the troop
rolled forward through the blowing sand
and that's a,
that's a little excerpt from a personal
account from a guy by the name of HR
McMaster.
You may have heard about recently
coming into a higher profile job in the
current administration.
But he's a very interesting guy.
And I wanted to talk a little bit about
his experience in some of the things
that he said about this
is the way he sees things.
And so he was in this big battle
in the first Gulf war as a captain.
So you know,
in charge of a a group of 140 guys and
he fought in this battle called the
battle of 73 east.
And I'm gonna go to a little excerpt
from Wikipedia that sort of gives you the
broad idea of what was going on in the
battle of 73 eastern refers narrowly to
the violent armored combat action that
took place in the final hours of second
acrs covering force operation in the zone
of Second Squadron and in the northern
third of the third squadron zone in
the battle for of second acrs armored
cavalry, cavalry troops, troops,
e g and I with troop k contributing
to I troops fight totaling about 36
[inaudible] tanks,
defeated two enemy brigades,
the 18th brigade. And later in
the day, the Ninth Armor Brigade.
So it's interesting you have a
legitimate tank battle, right?
Like a World War Two style tank battle
that took place in the first Gulf War.
And that's what this is talking about.
And McMaster at the time McMaster's
was in charge of eagle troop,
so they got some good details in here.
And again, this is a very simple,
one of the best,
clearest descriptions of what happened.
It was actually on Wikipedia, so I just
pulled some of that. So here we go.
A little bit of what Eagle troop did
at 4:10 PM Eagle true perceived fire
from an Iraqi infantry position in a
cluster of buildings.
Eagle troop,
Abrams and Bradley's returned fire,
silenced the Iraqi guns,
took prisoners and continued to east with
the two tank platoons leading the nine
m one tanks of Eagle troop
destroyed 28 Iraqi tanks,
16 personnel carriers,
and 30 trucks in 23 minutes
with no American losses.
So you've got nine tanks against 28
tanks and 16 personnel carriers and 30
trucks and the nine tanks.
When that's,
that's this domination,
battlefield domination.
And there was a bunch of technical
reasons as well as leadership reasons that
we're going to get into.
Next at about four 20 eagle crest at a
low rise and surprised and Iraqi tent
company set up in a reverse
slope defense on the 70 easting.
Captain McMaster leading the attack
immediately engage that position,
destroying the first of the
eight enemy tanks to his front.
His two tank platoons finished the rest.
So they're just,
they're just hammering,
hammering these I Iraqi tanks
three kilometers to the east.
Mcmaster could see t 72 so those are
the tanks at the Iraqi's are using in
prepared positions continuing
his attack past the limit,
the 70 limit of advanced. So the
way maps are set up, there's,
there's coordinates on them
and each one of the core does,
has each one of the lines that runs
north, south has a, has a label to it.
69707170270 three so he had been told
not to go past the 70 easting that's what
they're saying.
That was his limit of advanced.
These are all really common
military terms. They say, Hey,
you're not allowed to go past this
road or this, this coordinate on a map,
and they just call that
a limit of advance.
So he was supposed to stop at 70 he has
to get after it a little bit harder.
Continuing his attack past
the 70 limit of advanced,
he fought his way through an infantry
defensive position and on the high ground
along the 74 easting and this is going
now that I mix this in here with the
Wikipedia, which was a very simple
explanation of what happened.
Now going into a personal account that
McMaster wrote himself when he was a
young captain.
Okay,
so here we go.
From captain mcmasters account,
Lieutenant Gifford called me from the
command post to remind me that the 70
easting was the limit of advanced. We
were already beyond it. I told him,
I can't stop. We're still in
contact. Tell them I'm sorry.
Gifford explained the situation to the
squadron headquarters on the radio.
Major Mcgregor was forward with our
tanks and fully understood the situation.
If we had stopped,
we have forfeited the shock effect we had
inflicted on the enemy. Had we halted,
we would have given the enemy for
farther to the east and opportunity to
organize an effort against us while we
presented them with stationary targets.
We had the advantage and had
to finish the battle rapidly.
We would press the attack until all of
the enemy or destroyed or until they
surrendered.
So that's a pretty bold move to just
push and it's also a risky move.
And I'll say the biggest risk of it is
having a blue on blue situation unfold.
I think it makes a lot easier the fact
that this was day time and that that just
makes it, everything's so much
more clear in the daytime.
But you could obviously make
some mistakes if you're,
if you're pushing you that limited
advances there for a reason and you might
have some other group that's
controlling that sector.
You also might have air power that
the air power might be told, hey,
if you see any vehicles moving past 70
easting you can start dropping bombs.
So you do have to be very cautious when
you make an aggressive move like this.
And I bet McMaster himself
would go back and say,
you know what I should have done is I
should've given him a heads up. Hey,
I'm pushing past 70 easting please,
you know, let everybody know.
So now this is going back to the,
to the wiki account here.
There he encountered and destroyed
another tank unit of 18 t 70 twos in that
acts in the Iraqi stood their ground and
attempted to maneuver against the troop.
This was the first determined defense the
regimen had encountered and it's three
days of operations still.
The Iraqi troops had been surprised
because of the inclement weather and we're
quickly destroyed by the better trained
and better equipped American troops.
After defeating that force,
McMaster send a scout platoon
of two Bradleys north to
regain contact with troop
g and doing that,
the Scout Platoon encountered another
Iraqi tank position of 13 t 70 twos which
they destroyed with tow missiles.
So as these guys are just
everywhere, they find these, these,
these Iraqi tanks,
they're just crushing them.
And this is going back to
McMaster's account again.
I jumped on top of my tank to give the
crew room to cross load ammunition.
While I monitored the radio.
I surveyed the fires,
which the which surrounded the troop.
It seemed as if the action,
it only lasted seconds. I felt no
significant emotion during the battle.
I think I had simply been too busy.
I realized that I had not eaten all day.
I tore into an Mre package and devoured
a dinner of cold potatoes and ham.
I gulped down some water and the quick
infusion seemed to slow the flow of
adrenaline. So I thought that was
interesting. He was just doing his job,
you know, he wasn't getting
emotional and just getting it done.
And then the ceasefire comes
the next day and that's it.
The war's over like,
I mean this was the world.
The war was 72 hours and
the war's over and so
he kind of talks about
what he was thinking here.
Once they hear the cease fire
back to McMaster's account,
Eagle troop had taken no casualties.
I and other soldiers offer
prayers of thanks to God.
We did not gloat over our victory.
We'd simply done our part and
liberating Kuwait from the treachery and
inhumanity of Saddam Hussein and
his Republican Guard. Henchman.
We surprised the enemy
on the 26th of February.
That surprise and the bold action
and teamwork of the troops soldiers
contributed to the route that is now
known as the battle of 73 easting.
In general, the Iraqi's were
unprepared for the United States army.
Americans are better trained and equipped.
The true decisive factor,
however,
was the American soldier.
He is the best at what he
does and absolutely dedicated
to serving his country.
Our soldiers were aggressive and battle
yet demonstrated great discipline and
compassion for their enemy.
I am grateful that I had the opportunity
to serve with them in this action.
Captain Hr McMaster,
each troop two to ACR.
So, and I didn't go into too much
of a, I didn't go into it at all,
but they took a lot of prisoners as well.
They weren't just killing everyone.
There was a lot of people that were
surrounding a lot of Iraqi soldiers that
were surrendering and they were doing
their best to take care of those guys.
And there are also some that pretended
to surrender and then attacked.
So they had a little bit of both
and they, they as, as McMaster said,
they showed great discipline and
compassion for the enemy. Now I didn't,
you can,
you can go online and you can read the
full account of what this whole battle
felt like. But he, he recently wrote,
so now he's a lieutenant who
was a captain at the time,
an o three and now he's
a lieutenant general,
a three star and there's a a website
called the strategy bridge.org and there's
an article there which is written by
McMaster and he goes through the lessons
that he learned in that
battle. And the, the,
the article is called something
along the lines of Hey,
guidance for small unit leaders.
So I thought there were some,
some good solid lessons learned that
he brought back. So I'm gonna go,
go through it.
Number one,
lead from the front leaders must be
forward to gain a clear picture and make
decisions. As Sergeant Harris engaged
with 25 millimeter lieutenant,
got ta moved forward to assess and
further develop the situation. So,
so to explain that you've got a sergeant
that's like engaging the enemy and then
the lieutenant,
he doesn't just sit there,
he goes forward to find out what's
going on and assess what's happening.
So as a leader, when your
troops are getting busy doing
the work, what can you do?
Don't get this.
Don't get target fixated on your own
guys and the work that they're doing.
Look around, go forward. Move to a
different position where you can see more.
Back to the book,
Go ta fired a tow missile into the center
of the enemy position in the village
to Orient our tanks.
After our gunner,
Staff Sergeant Craig Kotch fired a
subsequent tank round to mark center.
All nine tanks fired high explosive rounds
into the village simultaneously just
suppressed the enemy position despite the
secondary explosions in the village to
itself. First platoon maintained
its primary observation to the east.
So he's basically marking their position.
Lieutenant go ta basically
marks the position.
Okay,
so not only did he move and
observe what was happening,
then he's directing.
Everyone else wants it once he does that.
So it's a really simple combat. You hear
it all the time. Lead from the front.
Now can you get too far forward?
Yes, you absolutely can. If you're,
if you're the guy that's actually
engaging the enemy and you're having a,
you know, either with your
weapon in a tank or your weapon,
your personal weapon on eight your your
your rifle and you're the leader and
you're actually shooting bad guys,
well then you,
you got some issues because
you need to be looking around.
You need to be seen what the next move
is going to be. So lead from the front,
but always the dichotomy is there.
Don't go so far forward that you lose
the ability to look around and observe
what's, what's happening. Number two,
shoot first
if you know we're friendly forces are
and there is not a danger of civilian
casualties, do not hesitate to shoot
or conduct reconnaissance by fire.
The side that shoots first
has a tremendous advantage.
Staff Sergeant David Lawrence was the
commander of first platoon's northern most
Bradley when his gunner,
Sergeant Bradley Feltman's said,
Hey, I've got a hot spot out there. I'm
not sure what it is. Lawrence responded,
put a toe in it, see what it
is. A toe is a tow missile.
Lawrence identified the hot spot as a t
72 as the term was ripped from its hall.
In the ensuing explosion,
our troops experience was consistent
with Erwin Rommel's observation in his
world war one book, infantry
attacks. And this is Rommel talking.
I have found again and
again in encounter actions,
any counteractions the day goes to
the side that is first to plaster its
opponents with fire.
Okay
shoot first and how do I translate
that? Real simple, be aggressive.
Now he points out very clearly here,
you know where there's,
where you know where friendly
forces are. Yeah. Right.
You know we're friendly forces are because
obviously that can go sideways and by
the way,
when he pushed past his limit of advanced,
now also no one knew where he was. So
he need to be careful in that situation.
But that that aggressive being aggressive
with fire is something you have to do
and you can see like they saw
hotspot out there on their thermal,
I don't know what this is. We
have put a toner, which is,
we know it's not good guys.
Okay. Blasted. Yeah. We had a,
I had been in Baghdad on my
first deployment for like
a couple days and we went
out on a, on an operation in any
ways. When we were coming back,
we got ambushed and wasn't a big deal,
but like w you know,
we received fire and so
we returned fire and,
and basically we returned fire heavily
in and we were getting after it.
This is when we didn't have any armor
on her home. These, they were just,
they were just open, they didn't have
doors. So we didn't have armored Humvees.
Not many people did in Iraq at that time
in 2003 so what we had done is we had
taken the doors completely off and then
we'd taken our seats and turned them so
they faced outwards. So we, and we,
we'd have our feet like hanging out of
the Humvee or maybe sitting on these,
these big rails that we built along the
side. And so we'd be facing out. It was,
you were in a position, you were basically
in a position to shoot at all times.
And because of the way a Humvee set up
with doors on either side and then people
in the back,
you had 360 degrees of,
of visibility and of fields of
fire coming out of every Humvee.
And so when we got, we were
driving, we were on that,
we'd just done a little operation.
We were coming back and as we were
coming back, we started taking fire.
And so we just returned fired.
It was a massive return of fire.
Like I think the enemy was
pretty overwhelmed with it.
And we got back and everyone was
kind of like, well we kind of,
we kind of laid it down.
We went through a lot of rounds
in a very short period of time.
And the reason I'm saying this story
is because that was my platoon.
And so we get back and,
and we're kind of debriefing and then
the next day we're going out in another
operation. And I don't know if the
story is going to make any sense,
but the next day we were going out on
another operation and one of my Bros who
wasn't, who is my senior
enlisted advisor at the time,
but he wasn't on that mission that we
just did and he's, he goes, listen,
if you guys take contact,
you need to shoot back. You
can't be afraid to fire it.
And I made some combat like, don't worry,
we'll be good to go in the one on one,
here's afraid to shoot.
Then everyone laughed because they
knew that we put down a lot of lead.
If you want to, if you want to trade
bullets with us, we'll play that game.
We don't mind trading some bullets.
So the same thing though,
if you start feeling like you're
going to get contacted and then they,
that's another thing they just teach us,
you know, when you're in a firefight,
where do you think the enemy might be?
And we heard this a lot.
The Korean marines were talking,
or the the marines.
The US marines that were in Korea.
We were talking about that, hey,
you're going to put fire down where we
think the enemy might be cause that's
where you know you're looking at a
an area and there's a a good covered
physician. If there's a bad
guy it's probably going to
be there. Put fire on him.
Yeah.
Shoot.
First lesson number two from
general McMaster. All right.
Number three,
fight through the fog of battle.
Be prepared for confusion and concurrent
activity as we suppressed enemy
positions in the village.
While Lawrence was launching a missile,
the troop received permission
to advance to the 70 easting.
I instructed first platoon to resume to
resume movement to the east lieutenant
pest check did not respond immediately
because Lawrence was reporting on the
platoon, radio net
contact, contact east tank.
Simple orders and complete reports
are essential to maintaining common
understanding in battle.
So there's another example of got to
keep things simple and he's specifically
talking about how you communicate
with other people on the radio.
That's what he's talking about.
You have to communicate simply and
clearly in order for people to understand
what's happening. That can mean if you
give Troy, a lot of times you see this,
people try and give too much detail,
right?
That listen to this contact
contact east tank. That's it.
Where's the contact? It's to the east.
What is it? It's a tank. That's it.
That's what we need to know. Now everybody
knows it's going on. If you said, hey,
I've got a contact, he's about
480 meters. It is a t 72 tank.
It's moving in an eastward. No, we
don't care about any of that right now.
We don't care about any of that.
Just tell us what is happening.
And that's one of the things that can
help you fight through the fog of battle.
Now that contact called is actually
a standard operating procedure,
I'm assuming, which is we, cause
we would do this in the seal teams.
You'd give what type of contact it is,
what direction or sorry,
what bearing and what distance.
So you'd say machine gun,
fire hundred and 50 meters,
four o'clock and now everybody gets
a very quick read of what's happening
because you can't, not everyone's
gonna see where the firing came from.
So even having a standard
operating procedure to keep your,
your verbiage limited is important.
There's calls the whole,
all everything we do in the seal teams
basically has a very simple call that you
can make and it's broken
down into like three words.
Contact Front online, you know,
that's it. Everyone knows what to do.
Every seal you tell them contact
front online, they know what to do.
Number four,
follow your instincts and intuition.
As Sergeant Feltman
launched the tow missile,
I decided to go to a tanks lead formation
and instructed green and white the
tank platoons to follow my move.
First platoon pulled in behind as the
tank wedge moved and covered the tanks.
Rear Third Platoon,
retain responsibility for flank security.
Gotta maintain that flank security.
As we began moving forward,
first platoon responding to the contact
report on their platoon radio net began
firing 25 millimeter high explosive
munitions across the front.
It was a little unnerving for the tanks.
As we moved forwards,
I gave first platoon a
cease fire order red one.
This is black sex cease fire.
The two tank platoons were slightly
delayed as our tank came over the crest of
the imperceptible rise north of
the village Sergeant Craig Kotch,
the gunner reported tanks direct front,
I counted eight t 70 twos and in prepared
positions they were at close range and
visible to the naked eye.
So east talking about trusting
your instincts and trusting
your intuition and my,
and that's what he's doing here.
He's seeing things happening,
he's seeing things unfold and he's like,
he says, Hey, go go into this formation.
Boom. Everyone goes into his
formation. He's acting off of instinct.
But what's important here is where
do your instinct and where does your
intuition come from?
It comes from training and experience.
That's where it comes from. Now, it
could be hard to get combat experience.
We hadn't had a tank battle in,
well since World War II,
there's been no major tank battles
and here these guys are, no,
none of these people ever been in a tank
battle before and now they're in a tank
battle. So how do you do that? You got
to do realistic simulated training.
That's what you have to do and
you have to make this realistic.
It's gotta be surprising. It's all
the things I talk about all the time.
It's gotta be surprising.
It's got to be an unknown.
You've got to do things that
people aren't expecting.
That's what you have to do so that they
can develop their instincts so they can
develop their intuition.
Because if you're inexperienced and you
don't know what you're doing and you
just decide you're going to follow your
instinct, your instinct can be wrong.
It can be wrong. And the law,
it's like Jujitsu, right?
You take a new person in Jujitsu, their
instincts are going to be wrong. Period.
End of story, right? I mean, the
classic is it someone is mounted on you.
Then they knew. Yeah. You
either do one of two things.
You try and push them off of you, you're
getting are locked or you turn around,
you turn over and they're choking you.
But each one of your instincts is wrong.
Your instinct needs to be elbow
scape or you know, uh, Oompah escape.
Got To be one of those two things.
But those are instincts
only come from training.
And it's the same thing
with these combat scenarios.
How you ha you can't just try,
don't just trust your instinct
as a matter of fact. Yeah.
Make sure you've trained yourself,
make sure you've prepared yourself
and then make sure that you detach.
Cause that's another thing that can screw
up your instincts is your instincts.
You're feeling pain. You know, I
was rolling with Andy yesterday.
He will put like pain on me.
He'll,
he'll put his elbow in my ear or something
and all he's trying to do is get me
to,
to make the instinctual move of all,
I'm going to greet you up and pull his
hand away if I do that I'm getting are
mocked, right. No. Can't do that. You
have to just accept the pain. Yep. Just,
just deal with it. Go grind
harder, Andy, bring it here.
Your instinct, if you start taking
fire from a certain position,
that could your instinct to be, oh, we're
going to get down and move over here.
You got to remember you've got to
detach enough that you say, oh,
I need to check my flank.
I need to see what else is going on here.
I need to assess these other situations
that might be unfolding. Yeah, that's the,
and that's where that kind of,
well I am training you come in and a lot
of it can be things that aren't really
conscious to and it comes with like let's
say, you know, relationship situation.
Let's say,
I know I'm sitting over here trying to
talk about war fighting and you want to
go straight to relationship to this
earlier in the show when not even
necessarily saying, you know,
romantic or boyfriend, girlfriend,
any kind of relations.
If you know the person really well,
you can tell when something's off
just a little bit and be like,
hey something buddy. The guy would be
like, oh no, no, all good. And they can,
you know, they can be real
convincing with, yeah, yeah,
no, I'm all good, but you,
you know your instinct because you have
so much experience with them, you know?
Yes, you're right. And you're
right in the fact that, you know,
when I talk about deescalation,
right? If you come in and you say,
Hey Jocko, this crap, what we were
doing this, if my instinct is like, no,
it's not crap, that's my instinctive
response. Like, no, screw you. I'm right.
You're wrong. But what I really need
to do is say, hold on a second. Detach.
Let's assess what Echo Sierra echo
normally doesn't do this. Right?
Why is he doing this?
Something is going on. Don't,
I'm not going to trust my instinct
right now. Luckily, like you said,
through training, through
knowledge, right? In this situation,
I know that you don't act that
way. So yes, follow your instincts,
follow your intuition, but make sure
that you've trained to develop them.
And also I like to question
him when I feel something,
I just don't go with it immediately.
I want to go with it.
And I most likely will go with it,
but there's also a possibility. I say,
well not a possibility, but what as I say,
hey, we need to move. Here I go, okay,
what could be happening? Is this a
position that the enemy might be in?
Is this a a move that could be getting set
up on me? No, I think I'm pretty solid.
Or at least as I move there,
I'm going to be aware of it.
I'm trusting my instinct, but
I'm being cautious. Yeah. Yeah.
It's crazy how like you
hear that talking police,
you know like cops have
like good in for sure.
The repetitious patterns. Sure.
Of Bad guys. Yeah, for sure.
I was going to say something else too.
Oh,
there's plenty of times where if you
don't trust your instinct you will get
crushed. Right? I mean you think
about in a Jujitsu perspective,
but when you get good, you're
not thinking about anything. You,
you have to just use your
instinct, your, you're training,
your muscle memory is what's working.
And the same thing with police. You know,
they get to a point of you going into a
situation and if they're not going off
their instinct, they're gonna get,
they're gonna get burned. Yeah.
Cause they learned, you know? Yeah.
And that's the trained instinct.
How you were saying they train as opposed
to the untrained in kind of get a one
being a, being a police officer out
on the beat. You're not going to have,
they're not going to have an a fraction
of what you deal with that cop 10 years
later. Yeah. And you and that
cops, hey listen, I see your hand,
I see you got some blood on your knuckles.
I know what happened here.
Tell me what's going on.
You know what I mean?
Whereas a young guy might be old
school in your face about softer. Yeah.
Or guys like being too nice.
You know how like the cop can tell like,
oh this guy's being tuned ice.
Yeah. You know what I mean? Yeah.
There's like a mediocre level of niceness
that's like, okay, that seems like,
like he's mellow,
but if a guy's being like too
aggressive or too defensive or too nice,
they can tell you. I know there's
something I'm suspicious, you know? Yeah.
He'd be a new that might not be able to
tell that. You know what I mean? Yeah, no,
absolutely. All right. Next one.
Number five,
use standard unit fire and battle drills.
Aim to overwhelm the enemy upon contact
and retain the initiative through speed
of action.
As sergeant catch fire the main
gun and destroyed the first tank,
I sent a contact report to the troop.
This is black. Six contact east,
eight armored vehicles,
green and white. You with me?
Sergeant conch destroyed two
more tanks as our tank platoons,
accelerated movement.
All nine tanks began engaging together
as we advanced in approximately one
minute. Everything in the range
of our guns was in flames.
Fire distribution and control allowed us
to destroy a much larger enemy force in
a very short period of time.
So how do they do that?
Good solid, disciplined,
standard operating procedures.
And you, I'm telling you, you, you
think about how simple this is. He says,
this is black six contact east
eight armored vehicles or green.
Why are you with me?
That's the whole,
that's the whole detailed plan.
Hey, there's bad guys over there.
We're moving east, let's go.
And everybody says, all right,
we've done this thousands of times.
We've drilled it, we rehearsed it. What?
What do we do right now?
And they probably had little standard
operating procedures. Hey guys, on the,
you know,
on the left flank are going to start
flying at the left vehicles of guys on the
right flank.
And they had all these procedures work
out so that in less than a minute victory,
less than a minute. So develop those
good standard operating procedures,
disciplined procedures. And when I
talk about freedom on the battlefield,
this is exactly what I'm talking about.
Discipline equals freedom on the
battlefield because when you have those
discipline procedures, he doesn't even
have to see it. The freedom to maneuver.
He has a freedom just to say,
hey guys, there's the enemy.
Let's take care of them.
Boom. It's done. Yeah. Next one.
Number six foster initiative.
Every trooper understood how our
platoons and the troop conducted fire and
maneuver our tank driver,
special ed specialist Christopher Heden.
Sog knew that he had to steer a path
that permitted both tank platoons to get
their guns into the fight.
He turned 45 degrees to the right and
kept our frontal armor towards the first
enemy tanks we engaged,
he drove through a minefield,
avoided the anti tank mines
reporting on the intercom. Sir,
I need you to know we just
went through a minefield.
He knew that it would be dangerous to
stop right in the middle of the enemy kill
zone.
Heden Skog saw that our tank platoons
had a window of opportunity to shock the
enemy and take advantage of the first
blows that Sergeant Kotch delivered.
So clearly this is decentralized command,
right?
And you just think about this first.
Every trooper understood how our platoons
and the troop conducted fire maneuver.
Everybody knows what to do.
Everybody. And here's this kid,
he's probably 18 years old. Is he
a specialist? Yeah, specialists.
He'd probably 19 years old and
he's got he leaving, right?
The commander's in charge.
But there's the guy that's driving that's
picking the course where they're going
to go. And again, think
about this, the captain,
he's not saying like 86 degrees, the
left six degrees to the right, get 40 no,
he's not giving any of those orders.
And if you think about it,
could he have been able to do that?
He's dealing with all this other stuff.
You're dealing with fire
control. He's dealing with, uh,
the position he's reporting
back up the cheese,
got all this other stuff going on.
He doesn't have time to
tell this guy where to go,
but it's decentralized command.
That specialist that is leading the
tanks from an actual driving perspective.
He knows what to do.
He knows the procedures,
and so he's able just to do it.
He even knows,
he knows it so well that when he
sees that we're in a minefield,
he assesses the threat. Okay, we're
in a minefield by c three minds.
I'm going to steer around them the best
I can, but if we stop, we're going to be,
we're going to be open to getting
attacked by the enemy. So you know,
we're gonna do,
we're gonna keep moving.
And he made that decision on
his own of the right decision.
He made that decision on his own because
he understood the overall objective and
the procedures that they would
follow and what was most important.
So that's a great example
of decentralized command.
Number seven,
use tanks to take the brunt of the battle
tanks drove around the anti tank mines
and Bradley's and other vehicles
followed in their tracks.
Our squadrons s three tank commanded
by major Douglas Macarthur.
Mcgregor hit an anti tank mines but the
blast damage to the tank only slightly.
It continued the attack and made a repair.
When we halted,
we ran over anti personnel mines,
but they sounded like pop
microwave popcorn popping
and had no effect on armored
vehicles.
The rate of our fire of our tanks allowed
enemy tanks to fire only to aerate
main gun rounds at the outset of the
battle and to later as the troop assaulted
enemy machine gun fire had no
effect on the troops advance.
The psychological shock of our tanks
advancing undaunted toward their defensive
positions paralyzed and panicked.
The enemy.
So if you don't know anything
about what I'm talking about,
I apologize.
But tanks are massive.
A one Abrams tanks are massive and
they have extremely heavy armor.
They're 68 tons. And as
he's saying here, these,
even the anti tank mines aren't,
aren't,
aren't stopping the tanks and the,
the Pr Anti-personnel just has nothing
but Bradlees are smaller, not as big,
not as big and not as heavily armored.
So the,
the tanks are laying down,
you know,
driving and then the Bradlees are just
falling in their tracks in case they hit
any minds the,
they would hit the Abrams tank.
But what I said when I take about, so
how can we apply this to, you know,
everyday life,
how can we apply this to business?
You know the saying technically
specifically use tanks
to take the brunt of the
battle, right? This,
this is the way I look at this from a
business perspective and from a life
perspective,
play to your strengths,
right?
What is the strongest thing they've got
are these tanks and it's the same thing
that we run into in business,
and it's the same thing you run
into in life and Jujitsu everywhere.
What are you, what are you strong
at? What are your strong areas?
And that's what you focus on. That's
what you use to lead your, your advanced.
Now, do we train for our
weaknesses? Absolutely. You know,
we do that all the time. Do we? Do we,
when we have a weakness in a business,
we don't go, hey, let's
just cover this up. No, we,
we focus on it so that we can prove it,
but if we're going to go
to market with something,
let's go to market with something that
we're good at, right? If we're gonna,
if we're going to try and set up
some expansion into a new area,
let sucks set up the expansion into
an area area that we're familiar with,
that we're good at, that we're
strong in. Let's not say, Hey,
you know what we've been making,
we've been making cars
for the last 50 years.
Let's go over here and make computers.
No, we're going to make cars. Okay,
let's make trucks too. We know how to
build vehicles. That's what I'm saying is,
and you see this all the time, would
you do to, what do Jujitsu guys do?
What they should do, which is try
and try and play to your strengths,
right? Yeah. In in competition.
Competition. Yeah. Right.
Of course, when we're,
when we're training, we prayed our
weaknesses, right? We want to, Oh, I'm,
I don't like people being across side.
Cool. Let him get across side. Yeah.
I don't like being on the bottom.
Cool. I'm going to be on the bottom.
But in competition,
what are you good at and how do you
get the person to play your game? Yeah.
That's the question. And that's
everything too, right? Like even at work,
you're going to train the new guys,
but you're not going to send the new guy,
you know, to make contact with a
potential client or something. Be Quiet.
Don't send the new guy.
Send the strongest and the tank and the
m one Abrams to meet the new client.
That's got big potential.
So play to your strengths.
Use tanks to take the brunt of the battle.
Next,
be prepared for misfires
and degraded operations.
Lieutenant Jeff Desantos tank
crew came around the village,
destroyed an enemy tank and acquired a
second tank at very close range that was
traversing on them around.
Got Stuck in the breach of the cannon,
meaning this,
this can is not going to shoot anymore.
The loader grabbed hold of the loaders
hatch kicked around in the breach,
came up and the Gunner Sergeant Matthew
Clark destroyed the t 72 in another
example,
staff sergeant Digby ordered Private First
Class Charles Brewer Toobin to reload
tow missiles per tubing.
Could not get the cargo hatch open.
However,
when the lightweight wrestler
guys a wrestler, good for him,
kick the hatch release.
He sheared it off.
Rather than tell Bradley his Bradley
commander that he could not get the toes
reloaded,
he jumped out of the back door while the
vehicle is under small arms and machine
gunfire. He climbed onto the back of
the Bradley, loaded both missiles,
then tap the his Bradley commander on
the shoulder while yelling toes are up.
Staff Sergeant Digby nearly jumped out
of his skin because he thought an Iraqi
had climbed onto the Bradley.
So here's these little malfunctions going
on with your weapons and what do you
do?
You deal with it,
and I think I said this on
the last podcast with life,
we have a little saying nothing
works. Everything sucks, right?
And that's what you got to prepare for.
You count.
If you rely 100% on those radios,
those radios aren't going to work.
If you rely 100% on your weapon,
okay, you better learn those drills.
You better learn how to, how to fix
and adjust your weapon very quickly.
Go to your secondary, whatever the case
may be, you've got to drill those things.
Got to be ready for problems. You gotta
be ready for Murphy's law to kick in
next.
Number nine,
coordinate between platoons
and ensure mutual support.
The burning tanks and personnel carriers
of the enemy's first defensive line
formed a curtain of smoke that concealed
enemy further to the east as our tanks
assaulted through the smoke,
we saw other enemy,
armored vehicles and large numbers of
infantry running to get back to subsequent
trench lines and positions.
We destroy the enemy armored vehicles
quickly and shop the infantry with machine
guns.
As we closed the distance with them,
pockets of enemy soldiers threw up their
arms are soldiers were disciplined.
Turrets turned away from any enemy
soldier with his hands raised tank platoon
leaders asked a scalpel tunes to pick
up observation of the enemy infantry as
their Bradley's came through the smoke,
the scouts saw that the enemy had used
a false surrender to gain a better
position.
Enemy soldiers were re shouldering the
rifles and rocket propelled grenades are
Bradley's surprised the enemy and killed
them before they can engage our tanks
effectively covered move,
cover move real simple.
That's what that one
is mutually supporting.
That means we're helping each other out.
That's what cover move is
next.
Number 10
take risk to win because
eagle true press the assault,
the enemy could not respond effectively,
right?
That's that.
You're going to find that in 80 case.
You want to get the person on their heels.
You want to get your
opponent on their heels.
As we cleared the western most defensive
positions, our executive officer,
Lieutenant John Gifford,
broken on the radio.
I know you don't want
to know this right now,
but you are at the limit of advance.
You are at the 70 easting. I responded,
tell them we can't stop.
Tell them where to contact and
we have to continue to attack.
Tell them I'm sorry we and
that's a part I already covered.
We had surprised and shocked the enemy
stopping would have allowed them to
recover. As Erwin Rommel
observed an infantry attacks,
the man who lies low and
awaits developments usually
comes off second best.
It is fundamentally wrong to Holt or to
wait for more forces to come up and take
part in the action.
Eagle troop continued to attack toward
another very subtle ridgeline on the
enemy position on which the
enemy position his reserve,
a coil of 18 t 72 techs,
major Mohammed later
told one of our troopers,
this is the enemy commander of this unit.
Major Mohammed later told
one of our troopers that he
had not known he was under
attack until a soldier ran into his
elaborate command, bunker yelling tanks,
tanks.
By the time he got to his observation
post all the vehicles in defensive
positions to the West,
we're in flames.
He ordered the reserve behind him to
establish a second defensive line.
It was too late.
The Eagle troops tank crested the
rise and entered their assembly area.
The tanks were starting to move out
when we destroyed them at close range.
So it's not only take risk,
it's to be aggressive.
That's gotta be your default mode.
Default mode is aggressive
press attack and it,
it's interesting when,
I mean clearly it happens in combat.
You start getting the upper
hand, keep going, keep going.
And it happens in Jujitsu as well.
You know,
if you can get that person on the run,
you're attacking them with two, three,
four different things at the same time.
That's when they're done and
that's a bad feeling when you're,
when that's happening to you,
you're falling behind in the Ooda
loop and they're just getting,
getting all inside your loop.
You're defending something that you
feel the other thing happening. Yeah,
not good, but again, take risk. But yes,
be aggressive.
Now those word,
the lessons from this,
this one battle,
you know this one battle
at 73 easting and now
obviously McMaster stayed in the army.
He went up through the
chain of command and,
and now we're going to go to 2005 2006
the battle of [inaudible] in Iraq,
which this,
this battle was led by who
is now our kernel McMaster.
He was a captain at the time
of this 73 easting battle.
Now he's a commander who's
commanding the third ACR,
the Third Armored Cavalry Regiment,
and
this is very similar to
the battle of Ramadi.
What happened in
California and the reason,
one of the reasons why it's so
similar is that Colonel Macfarlane,
who was the commander of the one
one d that led the fight in Ramadi,
that I was there to support.
The first thing he did
when he went back to Iraq,
when when Mcfarland went back to Iraq
for that deployment in 2006 he took over
for a McMaster and McMaster was in
tallow far so mcfarlane shows up and
[inaudible] and says, Hey, this is what I
did. I did a little something called cs,
clear hold and build.
This is the strategy.
We pushed into these NV
controlled territories and,
and then it becomes so pacified in Talla
far that they were able to take most of
the one one 80 and send them down to
Ramadi. And when they got down to Ramadi,
Mcfarland, who's a brilliant guy, had
listened to everything McMaster said,
looked at how he did it, and then
applied the same strategy in Ramadi.
Now he had to make adjustments to it for
sure because it wasn't exactly the same.
But luckily he was a smart
creative guy that said, oh,
we've got to make these adjustments.
But he did it.
But the overall concept came from what
McMahon from what McMaster did up in
Taliph are.
And so there was an article in the New
Yorker written by a guy named George
Packer.
And the article is called the lesson
of tallow far is it too late for the
administration to correct
its course in Iraq? And this,
this article came out April 10th,
2006,
probably three or four days before
I arrived in Ramadi in 2006.
So that's when this article came out
and you can see he's saying, hey look,
is it too late to correct
the course will actually, um,
a lot of people in 2016
weren't even admitting that
we were on the wrong course.
You know, cause what we're doing at that
time, and I've talked about this a bunch,
what America had been doing at that time
is his going out grabbing bad guys one
at a time, two at a time and bringing
them back to base and putting them,
arresting them, capture, kill missions.
And what's interesting is that's that's,
that's an attrition, that's
a war of attrition, right?
You have certain number of bad guys,
we're going to go catch them all.
And he really wasn't working.
It really wasn't working.
That's why in 2005 2006 enemy
attacks were up 300% and you know,
2005 2006 our whole country,
well I shouldn't say our whole country,
but many people in our country,
including a lot of major politicians were
saying it was unwinnable and you know,
we, we just need to get out and it
was a quagmire and all that stuff.
So that's because we were
not on the right strategy.
And actually if you take this and
you apply it back to Hackworth,
when he basically said during the end
of the Vietnam War and he said, look,
we're not going to win. He wasn't talking
about we couldn't, when he was saying,
we're,
we're fighting the wrong kinds of tactics.
We're doing the wrong thing here. You
keep saying, Hey, what's our body count?
What's our body count? What's our body
count? That's a war of attrition. Hey,
we lost this many guys. You lost that
many. That's an attrition warfare.
It's World War One. I always use World
War One is the classic attrition warfare.
Hey, we're going to go over the trench.
We're to kill as many of you is.
You can and hopefully it's
less than, well, awesome.
We're going to see you can last longer.
That's a punchy. That's, that's, hey echo.
We're just going to stand here. You
Punch me, I'll punch you. You Punch me.
And whoever goes down, you
know loses. Well, guess what?
What do we look like at the end of that?
We're all beat up her, right? Both of us.
It doesn't matter.
It doesn't matter how good we are.
So these guys were thinking maybe
instead of doing punches to the face,
we should do little Jujitsu, a
little something, a little bit more,
more tactically sound.
And it wasn't just go out,
grab bad guys,
just go out and try and kill bad guys
because we learned 2003 2004 2005 that's
three years of doing those type of
operations and real progress wasn't being
made. It's certainly wasn't made.
And in Ramadi at this point, again,
there was guys that were doing incredible
work and you do have to go out and,
and attack the bad guys and go
after those critical notes for sure.
But we were focused so much on that that
we were at ignoring a lot of what was
happening with the populace
and politically other,
other areas that needed to be addressed.
So this article came out,
and again,
it's from the New Yorker written by George
Packer came out 10th 2006 and here's
what we're going to this
article back to the article.
The lesson that McMaster and his soldiers
applied in Talla far were learned
during the first two years of
an increasingly unpopular war.
When we came to Iraq,
we didn't understand the complexity,
what it meant for a society to live
under brutal dictatorship with ethnic and
sectarian divisions.
Yeah.
He said in his course, energetic
voice. When we first got here,
we made a lot of mistakes.
We were like a blind man
trying to do the right thing,
but breaking a lot of things later.
He said,
you gotta come in with your ears open.
You can't come in and start talking.
You really have to listen to people.
I mean, okay. That is just,
this whole thing is just a,
a great summary of a humble
man, right? He's saying, look,
when we came here, we didn't understand
the complexity. That's humility. He says,
we didn't understand what it was like
to live under brutal dictatorship.
That's humble. He says, when we first
got here, we made a lot of mistakes.
He's not saying all, we did everything
right. No, we made a lot of mistakes.
We were like a blind man
trying to do the right thing,
but breaking a lot of things. So they're
trying, he admits it. We're trying,
but we're breaking a lot of stuff
later. He said, listen this,
you gotta come in with your ears open.
You can't come in and start talking. Okay.
Leaders around the world pay
attention to that right there.
You don't need to come
in and start talking,
come in with your ears open and listen.
And he says,
you really have to listen to people.
Okay,
very clear. Very great
leadership guidance right there.
Back to the article.
Yeah.
They didn't even want to say the I word.
One officer told me it was
the specter of Vietnam.
They did not want to say the insurgency
word because the next word you say is
quagmire.
The next thing you say is the
only war America has lost Vietnam.
And the next thing you conclude is that
certain people's division of war is
wrong. So we had a hard time again,
just as America admitting,
Hey,
this isn't just a bunch
of thugs running around.
There's an organized insurgency here.
We needed fight it like an insurgency.
We had a hard time making that
mental transition as a nation.
And I'll tell you when I,
I've told this story before,
when I got to Ramadi and I
looked at what was going on,
I literally read the counterinsurgency
manual that was written by basically by
General Petraeus who's a brilliant
guy. And these guys, McMaster,
I think macfarlane, they all helped him
write that article or write that book.
So this was a totally different attitude.
And you know,
you hear it here that people,
people back in d c they didn't even
want to use the word insurgency.
They want to use that word because it,
it makes everyone think
of nom and we lost,
right?
So the article, I'm going going
a little bit deeper on that,
back to the article, the Pentagon
strategy in 2003 and 2004 was to capture,
was to combat the insurgency simply
by eliminating insurgence and approach
called Kill capture.
[inaudible] SAP,
a retired special forces officer who
now teaches at the naval postgraduate
school in Monterey, California. Set of
the method. It's all about hunting people.
I think it comes directly
from the secretary of defense.
I want heads on a plate,
so he's talking about Rumsfeld right
there. You'll get some people that way,
but the failure of that approach
is evident. They get Hussein,
they get his sons, they continue
to work every week to kill more,
capture more. They've got facilities
full of thousands of detainees,
yet there's more than surgeons than there
were when we started in dereliction of
duty.
Mcmaster wrote that a strategy of
attrition was in essence the absence of a
strategy one a great line.
That is right and so,
so McMaster wrote a very harsh critique
of the Vietnam War and the way it was
run. Again, not,
not a critique of the boots on the
ground and the troops that fought,
but a critique of those back
in BC that were running it.
And you know,
this is just,
this is just an incredible statement
that a war of attrition is in essence the
absence of strategy. This is
like, okay, what do you do?
What do, I'm just going to,
we'll go kill as many of us and
we can't. Okay. That's if the,
if that's your strategy, not a strategy.
It's like when you get new an MMA fight,
what's your strategy?
And the guy goes,
I'm going to punch him in the face until
I win. Right? That's not a strategy.
Put My head down. And definitely a
good strategy. Don't, don't do that.
You need to have a little bit
more strategy than that. Yeah.
Um, back to the article. If we're
not stupid and we don't quit,
we can win this thing. And again,
what's important is the 2006, this,
this major McCaughlin Maclaughlin,
he's another person that's interviewed
in this article. He's talking about like,
we could lose this thing, right? So
if we're not stupid and we don't quit,
we can win this thing.
Major, Major mclauchlan said,
history teaches you that war at
its heart is a human endeavor.
And if you ignore the human side,
yours,
the enemies and the civilians,
you set yourself up for failure.
It's not about weapons,
it's about people.
That's very, it's very true. And
I'll tell you where it's true.
It's true in war, clearly.
And it's true in business too.
And you get people that don't
understand the human side of business.
They don't understand that they're
dealing with human beings and they treat
people like numbers.
They're not going to be successful.
Now you also get people that go
so far in the other direction,
that's all they care about is
their people. And guess what?
Now they're making bad business decisions
and they're hiring more people and
they're keeping them.
They're not letting anyone go and
they're running themselves in the ground
because their overhead's too
much and they caused destruction.
But on the other side, you've got someone
that's now bean counter, right? Nope.
You let that person go no severance or
whatever limited you do that methodology,
you're gonna end up with no business
either because they've people there.
Because there are people,
if you treat them like robots,
they're not going to work for you.
They're going to,
they're going to rebel against you.
The robot will do what the robot is told,
but people aren't robots.
So you got to remember that human
side and obviously in war and that's,
that's one of the reasons that we're able,
if we're able to talk about
this stuff to businesses,
we're able to talk about combat
leadership to businesses. The first,
oftentimes,
the first thing that the business that's
bringing us on has to get a grip on is
the fact that we were in charge of people,
not terminator robots, right? We Lafe
and I use that term all the time,
that people think, oh, you're in the
military. Oh, you run a navy seals.
They do whenever you, no, no,
not true. There are people,
and guess what?
The enemy are people,
they have thoughts, they have passions,
they have desires, and guess what?
The civilian populace that
you're working amongst,
those are human beings too,
and they're not just going to listen
to what you say and you can't just for
instance, can't just throw
money out them, right?
You can't just throw money at them.
They don't care about that money. You,
you know, it was really
interesting. I talked about this,
this new story I saw on vice
news of a guy going into,
he was, uh, I don't remember
the reporter's name, but
he's a young reporter,
spoke Arabic and he goes into Ramadi wall.
It was surrounded by Isis and Isis
was getting ready to take over.
And he's saying, Hey, he's
talking to just normal people.
And he's talking to this one guy. And
he says, you know, the guy saying, look,
we really need help. We hope America
comes back. And the reporter says, well,
why don't you just leave? You don't want
you to get out of here. And the guy says,
I live here. I live here.
I'm not going anywhere.
That's a human right. That's a
human, that's a sentimental value.
It's like my house that I live in,
you're not going to take my house from me.
Like if you, if people came to try
and take my house away from me,
there'd be a fight.
[inaudible]
it wouldn't end well for anybody.
No, that's sentimental, right?
So you have to remember that these human
beings are human beings. And that's the,
one of the key things that,
that McMaster really
mcmasters really understood,
really understood this
fact. And, and you know,
I'm giving a lot of credit to
McMaster, but there, there's a lot of,
I mean there's way more guys that I'm
talking about that I don't have them going
through their names,
but there's a lot of guys that contributed
to this idea and did an outstanding
job. Um, you know, he's getting the
credit because he's gotten charged, right?
I'm giving him some credit
because he's the guy in charge.
But I guarantee if you asked
him, he'd say, well, no, I
had this captain that this,
and I had this major that did that.
And he had all these people,
but he's the guy just like if something's
gone wrong, he'd be responsible.
We'll some stuff went right. So you
get the credit. They're general.
Now he wrote these,
these four fallacies of warfare,
which I find very,
very interesting.
And so we learned kind of the tactical
side of what he learned from his battle.
The 73 he stings easting. You
know, he had 10 lessons learned.
Pretty tactical stuff.
Right?
Now we're getting into a little
bit more strategic level.
We're talking about war as
a broad in a broad sense.
And so here's what he says about
these four fallacies of war warfare.
There are four fallacies about future
war that are preventing us from learning
from our most recent experiences.
Mcmaster said,
these fallacies are portrayed in such
a way that they reduce risk to United
States interest,
when in fact they exacerbate risk because
they over rely on capabilities and
they purposely ignore
continuity's in the nature of war.
Okay? So he's saying, look, the,
the way they portray these things is
it makes everything good for America,
but they actually make
things worse for America.
Hmm.
Because they ignore things in
war that are always the same.
This is war we're talking about.
The nature of war does not change.
Okay?
His first fallacy,
okay?
The vampire fallacy,
it's a vampire fallacy.
It's a vampire because you can't kill
it and it comes back every 10 years.
This is the belief that a narrow range
of technological capabilities we'll
deliver fast, cheap, and
efficient victory in future war.
The latest manifestation is the
belief in a new range of technological
capabilities.
Everything from big data analytics to
artificial intelligence to drones and
robotics and so forth. So,
so what does that mean?
We have an idea that we can,
as a,
as a nation just we are,
we're so technologically advanced that
nothing can stand up to us and we can
just use these precision weapons
to take out enemy targets.
And then it's over. It's a fallacy.
It's a vampire. It's going to come back.
You can't just kill it.
It's gonna come back.
And you know, obviously we've
seen, we saw that in Iraq.
We had all kinds of technological
advances over the enemy,
but
they continued to come back.
And when we walked away,
they came back strong.
They were called Isis.
Now I think that's pretty self
evident what that means now.
What does this mean in business
and in, in, in life? Well, to me
what this means is
there's no easy solution.
There's no easy solution to things,
right? We look at something, we go, oh,
we can just do this.
We can just use some new technology
or we can just use some APP,
right? Oh, if I get an
APP to track my diet,
then I'll be good to go.
No,
you've got to stop putting the sugar
in your mouth to be good to go.
People want the shortcut.
They want to, they think that there's
an easy way to get things done.
And there's not. You have to do the
work. There's a vampire out there.
What you got to do is you
got to grab that vampire.
You gotta cut its head off.
You got to soak it in holy water,
and then you got to dry.
It's bones out in the sun that that's
what kills a vampire. All right?
That's the attitude you have to take.
You can't just think there's going
to be a shortcut. We'll be able to,
we'll be through with this of empire.
You know, tomorrow, cause I have a, uh,
a cool gun. I'm gonna shoot him. No
bullets. Don't kill him. Got to go harder.
Yeah.
I think the
correct, the way to kill a vampire
isn't to cut his head off. It's the,
it's the wooden stake into the heart.
That's,
I think you might be thinking I'm
going to do so or something. Okay.
Just kind of Fyi. The holy water
part with correcto. Yeah. Just,
just so Fyi, I don't, I don't
mean to call you out here.
I actually googled how to kill
a vampire that's wrong though.
Mythologies. It says otherwise he,
you stick a wooden stake in his heart.
Crucifix. We'll get them. If you
have faith, sunlight will kill him.
So that was correct. Holy
Water. Holy Water. We'll get
a murmur. Sure. Yeah. And um,
yeah, yeah. I Dunno what, what
website said? Cut his head off. Uh Oh.
Don't trust Google lesson learned.
See, you know what I did right there.
Took a shortcut. Oh yeah. I
took, I thought it was a vampire.
Just Google it real quick. We're going to
go, you know what you did. This is what,
this is what I think you did. I
think you googled it, which is fine,
but here's the thing about googling
something. Googling is not the answer.
It's what you find from Google.
And if you just go for the first
one or the one that looks like,
because most people see the Iraq.
The irony here is that I tried
to take a shortcut and I'm wrong,
and that's the same. That's the
vampire fallacy in its own right.
Proves the point. All right, next,
the zero dark 30 fallacy.
And that's the name of a movie about the,
the killing of bin Laden.
This is the idea,
the zero dark 30 fallacy.
This is the idea that all
you have to gain to do,
to gain a victory in war is to gain
visibility of an enemy's network structure
and then conduct raids
against that network,
either with special
operations forces or notes.
So the problem with both these fallacies,
of course,
they represent important
capabilities you need to have,
but these are capabilities that masquerade
as strategies and simple solutions to
the complex problem of war,
neglecting wars, political nature,
neglecting wars, human
nature, neglecting wars,
inherit uncertainty based
on the interactive nature.
And finally neglecting that it
is ultimately a contest of wills.
So the idea that you can,
again,
it's attrition warfare and I,
I'll be honest with you,
I never really looked at this as
attrition warfare until I was reading
researching for this podcast. I
never, I always said, hey, you know,
it's raid mentality. Hey, we can just
capture all the bad guys. But to say, yes,
that's attrition warfare. That's exactly
what it is. And especially for me,
because I look at World
War One as so awful,
and it's an example of attrition warfare,
and that's what makes it so bad.
This is attrition warfare to, Hey, we're
just gonna capture, kill all the bad guys.
How do you do that? What we're
forgetting is the, what about this line?
When you do that, when you just say, Hey,
look, all we need to do is, is captured.
Kill the bad guys. This is what
you do. You masquerade this,
that capability to be able to do that,
which is an awesome capability,
awesome capability.
But that mass back capability masquerades
as a strategy and what you listen to,
the things that you forget
about this list is classic.
The complex problem before you
neglect wars, political nature,
human nature,
inherent uncertainty,
interactive nature, and you neglect
that. It's a contest of wheels.
So
that's,
and there's some great youtube videos
where mcmasters talking about that big
lesson, learning that this raid
mentality was, it's part of,
it's part of the way you
defeat an insurgency.
Part of the way you defeat insurgency
is capture. Killing the bad guys.
It's awesome. But there's so much more
you have to address. That's like saying,
Hey, the way you win a Jujitsu
is to arm lock the person.
You can even say as broad as that way
you win in Jujitsu is to submit somebody.
Right? So if I taught you
every submission I knew,
but I didn't teach you how to transition,
didn't Chichi hourly positions you would.
There's no way you could win.
It's the same thing here. Is Submission
important? Yes. That's what a rate is.
A rate is the submission. It's one piece
of it. It's not the whole game though.
It's not the whole game.
And I think that's what he's making very
clear here through that zero dark 30
fallacy.
Next one.
Yeah.
Is The wild kingdom fallacy.
Back when America was wholesome,
there was no reality TV,
no Kardashians or anything.
So on Sunday nights,
American families would
watch this wildlife show
called mutual of Omaha's wild
kingdom.
And that show,
what happened on that show is the host
Marlin Perkins would send his assistant
Jim to conduct exotic and
occasionally dangerous fieldwork.
This is the belief that we could be
like Marlin and just get gym or other
militaries to do are fighting for us.
And this is a way in the minds
of some people to reduce risk,
but it actually increases risks because
you were relying on other people whose
interests are often times
in crew incongruent with
your own interests and not
only don't have the capability to
fight and do what you need to do,
but oftentimes don't
have the will to do it.
Yeah.
So he's saying this idea that we can just,
hey, we'll just have the Iraqi's do it.
Sounds like a good idea, right? Cause I
don't want my guys to get hurt or killed.
There's a problem with that.
The problem is they can't do what we do.
They can't do it as well as we do it.
And they probably don't
have the will to do it. Now,
credit to the Iraqis right now
they're moving through Missoula.
They're getting after it there.
They're heavily backed by American forces,
but they're, they're taking
the lead for sure. Hmm. So,
but when we were in Ramadi, those
guys didn't have the will that we had.
They didn't, didn't mean as much
to them. If you can believe that.
I know it sounds crazy.
We had a battalion of Iraqi soldiers
to talking about this with life.
We had a battalion of Iraqi soldiers,
so 500 Iraqi soldiers that it come to
Ramadi as to to help out in the fight.
They left,
they abandoned,
they quit a battalion of Iraqi soldiers.
And here's the weird thing. The reason
they brought this battalion in one,
we needed more manpower.
Number two, they were Sunni.
So Ramadi was a Sunni city and bulk
of the army at the time was Shia.
So the, she is coming in and fighting in
Ramadi. Sometimes the Sunni's would say,
hey, hey, wait a second.
Why these? She is in here.
So the idea was to bring
the Sunni's in to help.
And the Sunni's got scared.
This is the Sunni battalion
got scared and left.
And one of the reasons they said, well,
it's an a Sunni city. I just said, wait,
wait a second. That's the whole
point. These are your people.
These are other Sunni's that are
getting murdered by insurgents.
So it was just,
it was a tough situation.
And my point in saying that,
and there's a whole,
there's a whole nother
discussion we could have on that.
But the point is that
in order to win that fight,
we had to be on the ground.
The Iraqi's were not going to do it
by themselves. They were not going to.
And that's what this fallacy is.
Hey,
that if we just direct other people to
do it, yeah, then we'll be good to go.
And we don't have to take any risk.
Now again,
how does that translate to
what we do, you know, business.
How's that translate to business? How
does that translate to life? For me,
it's real simple.
Okay.
The important things that you gotta do.
You gotta do the hard things that you
gotta do you gotta do you know it?
Okay, Tim Ferris, can we outsource
some stuff? Yes, we can. Don't worry.
Tim will outsource some stuff,
but the important stuff you have to do,
you gotta do it.
Gotta do it yourself. If it really
means something, you have to do it.
You have to have the will and
you have to make it happen.
Because if I outsource something
to somebody, if I say, hey,
I really don't feel like
reading this book. You know,
I really feel like reading this book for
the podcast, can you read this for me?
Well, yeah, somebody's going to read it,
but they're not gonna have my perspective
on it and they're just going to give
me some notes. I'm going to
sit here and read them. Yeah,
we're not going to get the product
that we need because that's important.
I have to do the work myself. No one
can. I can't outsource that piece.
Can't do it. There's actually
been, people have said like, Hey,
I can read the books for you and
give you notes. I'm like, Hey,
I appreciate the offer. No, I got to
read it. I gotta do the hard part. Yeah,
yeah. Now you say trying to outsource
that stuff. Echo Charles. No, no, no,
no. Keep it in house for sure. The, the
congruency of, of interest, you know,
that's a big one because you can't
even think that the person has the,
the same interest in really.
You both can think that,
but just maybe in a different
way. Especially when
you're thinking creatively,
like how you present this and what parts
do you think are important are going to
be slightly different.
Even if the person has the same interest
is it's going to be different. Yeah.
So then at the end of the day,
when you expect a certain result,
it's gonna be different. Yeah. We'll
let yourself down. Yeah. You know,
just somebody just wrote, cause
we're Musashi, it's a giant book.
And someone was highlight massage the
other day and kind of took a picture of it
and he said,
you know,
I wonder how close Jockos highlights
are going to be to my highlights,
exactly what they're going to close.
They might even be right on maybe,
but they might not be.
And I can't say, hey bro,
send me your book and your notes and
then we'll do the podcast and I'm just
going to cheat. Can't do that. Just
like you can't say, Hey, you know what?
Iraqi forces that aren't ready,
that don't have the same,
here's the big problem with
the Iraqi forces at the time.
The Iraqi forces at the time didn't have
a vision of what their country could be
like. So think about that.
We Americans, we had,
we had inherently being from America,
we have a vision of what freedom is like.
We know what that is.
Iraqi soldiers didn't know what that is.
They thought, man, they lived under under
Saddam for their whole lives. I mean,
all the soldiers that we worked with
lived under Saddam their whole lives.
That's all they knew. So for them, we
say, no, you're going to have freedom.
They're like, oh yeah, I don't know
what, what does that even mean?
What does that mean? I don't know what
that means. We're, we're thinking, Hey,
don't worry. These guys will fight.
They're going to fight for their freedom.
They're going to fight
for their Sunni brothers.
They're going to fight for their Iraq.
They're kind of like, we don't even know.
They didn't even really have
a good vision of what Iraq is.
Iraq is a country that we used to be
underneath Saddam and now it's not.
And we don't know what that means.
We don't know what that looks like.
We Americans had a vision of what
that looked like. They didn't have it.
So how are they going to fight for it?
So to your point,
they don't see what we see.
They had a different opinion.
So who's got to go on there and,
and have,
and who's gonna have the will to fight
the answers us in that particular case.
And it's the same thing right now.
Like even in Missoula,
even in the last time when
Ramadi was taken back by,
by the Iraqi forces. Good, good on
them. Props to the Iraqi forces.
Right now they're backed up by Americans.
Americans are, are saying, hey look,
this is the vision.
This is what you're going to do.
This is how we're going
to take this part of it.
And that is the big difference
of why they didn't have the will.
They didn't understand what
they were fighting for.
And you take anybody and
put them in that situation.
You don't even look at
Vietnam War, right? You could.
The Vietnam War are our American soldiers.
Some of them you can go watch
interviews. You know, they were saying,
I don't know what I'm fighting for. Yeah.
Hey, they were actually questioning,
I don't know what, we know what
America's like anymore. Right.
Who's really reading,
reading this book by Jim Thompson,
you know, longest held pow ever. And
when he got back, he was kind of,
when he got back to America,
he knew he was gone from 1964
until 1973 when he got back,
when he left,
America was fairly conservative in
and patriotic. When he gets back,
people are burning flags, people are
protesting. He was taken aback by it.
And so,
so if you took somebody that for Vietnam
in 1970 in America's in turmoil and all
that,
it's hard to have the same vision
that they'd had in 1964 which is like,
Hey America, we're going to go stop
the communists. Communists are bad,
communists are bad.
But then you start having the
American Socialist Party that Tony,
you that communist are good. And all
of a sudden the kids over there going,
hey look,
I don't even know what's going on but
I'm not sure I want to die here in this
jungle. And that's problematic.
And it's the same thing with,
with the Iraqi soldiers. They just
didn't know what they were fighting for.
If you asked them what they were fighting
for, they might say a paycheck. You.
Very few of them would say,
I'm fighting for a free and stable Iraq.
The very few of them,
some of them fought against truly
heartfelt fought against the insurgents.
They didn't like the insurgents.
Insurgents were murdering people and
raping women and torturing people.
They didn't like that. Then they'd fight
hard against them, but that wasn't,
not everyone experienced that.
Not everyone saw that. Yeah,
and I'm sure they're kind of like,
you can tell him what you're fighting for,
you know? And they can answer you for
sure. You don't feel, it's like, you know,
like your dad tells you when you're
young, you dead tells you, hey,
clean your room. I want this room spick
and span like you don't get it. Yeah.
All I'm going to take this whole meth.
I'm just going to put it in
the closet just so he'll stop,
leave me alone kind of thing. You
know? And then meanwhile, the Dad,
your dad has this vision is like,
look what's up with you?
Why didn't you clean your room? Don't
you understand kind of thing. Yup. No,
you don't.
You don't understand that.
Your Dad's trying to teach you
that discipline equals freedom.
My kids were running late
this morning going to school.
Why are they running late? Cause their
rooms are messy. It w you're running late.
Everything stressful now when we're
heading to school. Why is that? Well,
because you're, your room is
messy. Lack of discipline,
lack of discipline causes mental stress.
Mental stress is not freedom. Yeah.
But to your point,
even trying to explain to the Iraqi
soldiers why they're doing what they're
doing on a really big level like
that is difficult is difficult.
Now occasionally you get a good leader.
There was some,
there was some good leaders.
There was one of the generals that the
Delta platoon commander worked with.
He was a good dude.
He was a good leader and,
and the Delta platoon commander actually
had some really good Iraqi scouts as
well that really believed
in what they were doing.
And I know that be the reason
I differentiate a little bit.
The Delta platoon commander worked
very consistently with the same guys,
a bunch as, as Lafe was working
with multiple different groups.
So the Delta platoon commander had some
more tight relationships with some of
those guys lifted too.
But anyways,
some of those guys understood what they
were fighting for, but it's hard to,
just like you said,
explain what freedom is.
And the other piece of it is in the,
in those situations,
explaining what freedom is,
is no guarantee at all, right?
That freedom is coming your way.
These guys had been through so much
turmoil that country has been through so
much turmoil there. Like, Hey,
you know what? We don't even know.
You can promise us that but doesn't
seem like we're doing too well.
How do we know you're going to win?
How do we know we're going to win?
We don't know that. So you know
what? I'm going to lay low.
You see where this thing falls and then
all they don't step up once I know who's
going to win.
Tough
next,
the RSVP fallacy.
Thank you for the kind invitation to the
war, but the United States regretted,
is unable to attend. This is the belief
that you can just opt out of war.
It's a narcissistic approach to war,
which we define w only war in relation
to us and what we'd like to do.
So this idea that you can just be
opt out doesn't work. The, the, the,
the bottom line there is that
you gotta get in the game,
the game's going to take place,
the game's going to happen and
you're going to be affected by it.
That's the key point. It's not a
game that takes place on a field.
It's a game that takes place on a field
and expands out the crowd into the
stands and into town and still scars.
Stuff starts getting burned. Yeah.
And riots take place.
So you have to get in the game.
That was the,
that was the fourth fallacy of worn out.
I think that all those really show,
not just how smart McMaster is,
but also how
open minded to yes.
Which is a very important quality.
I also think he's a realist.
He's a realist and looks at
things in a very real way.
You know,
this is the,
what's happening and this is what
we needed to do to deal with it.
And also what's great about McMaster is
that he is not afraid to speak his mind
and he's got kind of got in
trouble for that along the way.
So I'm definitely
looking forward to seeing how McMaster
handles all the challenges that are ahead
of him right now,
not only in DC but in the world.
So it's going to be an interesting and
we wish him or I certainly wish him the
best of luck in that pursuit.
So leading off of little McMaster,
and I'm thinking about going to a
little Q and a at this time. Sure.
It's been a little while since
we did Q and a here. Yeah,
I've been doing Facebook
live. Can you tell? Yeah.
And what I've been doing
Facebook live, I have not, I,
I'm purposely not preparing at all.
That's my goal.
My goal is to not prepare at all
because in the second or the,
yeah,
it was the second one that I did.
I started looking at the questions
ahead of time and I was saying, okay,
well maybe we'll just
take a couple notes here.
And all of a sudden I started preparing
for Facebook live and then I realized if
I'm going to prepare, I'll
make it the podcast. So No,
don't prepare Facebook live.
Ask me your question and I'll answer
it there on the spot. It's fun.
It's different, right? It's easier.
I can't do two podcasts a week because
don't have time to prepare for him,
but can do Facebook live.
You can slide that thing in.
Does it preparing for a live thing
with the dynamics of Facebook live.
Doesn't that defeat the live
kind of purpose in a way it does.
But we could do this podcast on Facebook
live so we could prepare it and we
could put it on Facebook live.
We could do that,
but then it would be a rehash
of what we're doing. And
the other piece of it is,
is I think the Facebook live is a way
of people seeing a little bit more of me
as a normal human being and not me as a
guy with all the answers on stuff like,
no, you asked me a question, I don't
really know. You know what I mean? And,
and also, you know, obviously on this
podcast is, is usually pretty serious.
And so I'm not like that all the
time. So maybe they could say, well,
I, I have a serious side, no doubt.
Sure. But am I like that all the time?
Yeah. So I think Facebook
live is a good way to say,
and plus, I don't want to
answer some questions here, B,
for a couple of reasons. Number one, man,
when somebody listened to the podcast,
I want to make sure they're getting
something of high quality, right? Not,
not just some fluff, right?
Yeah. We're not doing fluff here.
If we need to do fluff on the podcast,
we just won't do the
podcast because I don't,
I don't want to somebody to press play
and waste time. Oh, you know what I mean?
Yeah.
I don't mind fluffing around and talking
smack on Facebook live because it's,
that's what it is. It's an open
forum. We're going to have some fun.
We're going to get after it a little bit,
but it's not going to be super heavy
because if you want that come here,
get your podcast on. Yup. Yes, kind
of more lightened up a little bit.
Yeah. It's not like that's, it
is not like I said, okay. Hmm.
Let's see. I need to show them my light
side. No, but if you talk to me live,
it's like when Jody came on,
Jody came on like after we were hanging
out for like an hour. He's like, yeah man,
when I was coming down I just thought
you're going to be like full on cycle the
whole time I was like, yeah, I'm
not falling cycle the whole time.
If we're eating a burger,
we're good.
I'm not going to be sitting there
while I'm eating a burger St.
Let me tell you what, no, I didn't want
to do that when I'm eating a burger,
when I enjoyed that Burger. It makes
sense. But yeah, if it's a live Q and a,
you know how like at like the
muster or you know when you guys,
okay we're going to do some
Q and. A. That's the example
of like a live Q and. A.
You don't prepare for those
questions. You know, and, and, and,
and also what's interesting about those
questions is those, I've given some,
I mean, if you think about any of
the podcasts that I've gone on,
Tim Ferriss', Joe Rogan,
Sam Harris, the, those,
those guys ask me some heavy questions,
right? Those guys weren't just asking me,
we weren't just be guessing right.
During those.
So there's no guarantee
that I'm not going to get,
get a little bit serious on your Facebook
live or whatever I'm going to do.
I'm gonna do what people
ask me. Right? Yeah. But
yeah,
yeah. During the muster, who we do
a lot of Q and a during the muster,
we get all kinds of questions. There's
some really funny questions at Reus Choir,
funny responses.
There's also some,
some real serious ones that
require very serious answers.
And what's interesting,
and this happens on Twitter to,
somebody asks me something dead serious
question, like a very serious, you know,
something that's emotional to me,
like about losing guys or,
or something like that. Guys killed in
combat and I'll, I'll respond to it.
And then two tweets later,
someone says, you know,
I'm going to have some mint
chocolate chip ice cream tonight.
You know what I mean? And so you go
through these. If someone's read,
they must think I'm schizophrenia
because I'm answering real serious.
Then it's real light. And
then it just kind of weird,
Eh, rollercoaster math. Yeah,
it's an emotional
rollercoaster on the Twitter.
Oh Lord.
All right.
So Q and a Qa Echo Charles back
in the game. Back in the game.
So yeah, first question Jocko, an echo,
should you defend bad leaders?
It your superiors to your man.
Think about that question. This
is a good, it's a good question.
And we haven't done Q and a in a while.
And that's why I want to
start off thinking about that.
Should you defend bad leaders that
are people that are in charge of you?
Should you defend them to your men?
Now this is really a perfect example
of the dichotomy of leadership.
Hmm.
And this is one of those situations
that makes leadership very,
very hard because it requires a nuanced
balance to handle this correctly.
So on the one hand, if we, if we,
okay,
say our boss is a bad leader and doesn't
know what he's doing to figure out the
boss, hey echo, our boss does know
what he's doing. He's an idiot.
We undermine his authority for sure and
we undermine the authority of the whole
chain of command.
So should you call out
when someone's sucks,
you say, Oh that guy sucks. He's terrible.
Should you do that to your leader?
The answer is no.
You can't do that.
You can't do that cause
you're undermining everything.
So you've got a horrible leader. You
can't just sit there to your boys and say,
Hey, this guy's an idiot.
Can't do that. However,
if you give full support
to this horrible boss,
then your troops who know a
good leader from a bad leader,
they know what stupid and what doesn't.
They know this, they know this.
And if you are sitting
there backing them 100%
then they're going to know that you
either actually agree with the bad leader,
which is bad,
or that you're too weak
to stand up and say,
hey boss, what we're doing is wrong,
so you can't go to one extreme.
The boss is an idiot. You can't go
to the other extreme. The is awesome.
Think about how hard that is. Think
about what I'm saying. This is a very,
very challenging, so
what can you do? Well,
okay, first of all, as a subordinate
leader, it is your duty to push back,
right? To to say, Hey boss, I think
we're doing the wrong thing here,
and this is why we spend a lot of time
trying to build relationships with our
bosses so that we can have candid
conversations with them, right?
Sometimes it's hard to do
that. It is, I understand,
but when you have built a relationship,
then you can go to your boss
and say, Hey, look, this isn't,
this isn't good. Now, once you've
done that, then you can go to your,
go to your book, your troops,
and you say, hey look,
I went to the bosses when I told
him, you know, I told him that, hey,
doing this method isn't gonna work. Well,
he explained to me while we're doing it,
this is what he said.
So this is why we're using this method.
I know it's not popular with
you guys, but it's, it's,
here's the reason why we're doing
it. So, so you made progress, right?
Your guys are saying,
okay,
well he at least stood up to the
man and now he gave us an answer.
He told us why we're doing what
we're doing. And so that's good too.
But the other thing is when,
the easiest way to do this is
to provide an honest truth.
Truth is going to be your friend here.
Truth is going to be a friend.
Now I should,
I should put a caveat around that because
the truth might be you think your boss
is a complete idiot and everything
he's saying is stupid. Okay, so I,
I take it back. Don't use a
full on truth. And this is so,
this is so interesting too,
because clearly truthfulness is a huge,
you know, it's a value that
I've hold very dear, right?
And you gotta be truthful and all that.
I'm telling you right now, do not be true.
If you think your boss is an idiot and
you think the method that he's picking or
the plan,
he's got his stupid,
don't be truthful your guys and
go down there and say, Boston did.
He is not going to help your team,
right?
We have to be smart about
what we're doing. But
when you,
when you do that,
what you need to do is to keep
it somewhere in the middle. Okay?
So when you say something negative,
don't get all crazy with the negative.
Don't get all nuts with a negative.
What you want to do is say, you
say something like, Hey, look,
I'm sure there's some
better ways of doing this,
but this is the decision that was made
and we need to make it work, right?
So I'm not saying it's horrible
and to say, look, hey guys,
I'm sure to some better ways,
but guess what?
This is what we are being told to do right
now and we're going to do the best we
can notice that I'm putting it from
like them to know we are making,
I'm taking ownership of it. This
is now ours to execute. Yeah.
So you want to do that and,
and I also want to focus more on
as much as I can. I want to focus
on not the personality of the boss,
but I want to focus on the what we're
being told type thing or what the mission
is because I don't want to bring, I want
to keep the personality, the boss at bay.
Sometimes you get a boss that has such
a raging asshole personality that you
have to say something like,
you just, you have to explain.
And that's when even then you want
to ratchet it down a little bit.
You don't say, Hey, the
boss is an asshole. You know
the boss is an idiot. No,
you don't say that. You
know, you say, hey look guys,
I know the bosses is not exactly perfect,
but I think he means well with what he's
trying to do and that way we need to
focus for that reason.
We need to focus on executing because
not going to help us to sit here and
complain about the boss. He might
not have the greatest personality,
but you know what? His intention
is good, so let's support him.
You know what I mean?
Something like that where you're not,
you're not giving him full support,
but you're not completely
throwing him under the bus. Again,
this is so hard to do
because let's face it,
the boys, the troops, they know what's up.
They know when that boss is an idiot.
They know when he's unprofessionally.
They didn't know when he treats you
like shit. They know that stuff.
And so if you bow down, if you break and
you give that to them, yes, you're right.
The boss is a jerk. Yes, you're right.
The boss treats people like shit. Yeah.
If you give them that you're
hurting the situation.
And that's why also when you're
in a leadership position,
your job oftentimes is to buffer
between the jerk boss and the boys.
You don't,
the boys should never know that the kind
of stupid harassment that you get from
your boss, the boys should never
know that and they should think, hey,
Jocko says this guy's good to go.
We're good to go.
There's never think that
this guy's an idiot.
So
again,
in both cases it's like
you can't go hardcore.
You can't go hardcore against
either the plan or the person,
but you also,
at the same time,
you need to give a little
bit of a pressure release.
Just a little bit of a pressure release,
you know,
got to give them just enough that they go,
you know what you want them to think.
Do you want them to
think, hey, Jocko gets it.
He knows he's not admitting
it to us and good on him.
He's, he's keeping it
professional. They know how they,
they know that John [inaudible],
they know I don't love the boss,
but they know him keeping it professional.
So therefore they,
they accept what I'm saying
and they stay part of the team.
Yeah. It kind of feels like, I'm kind
of imagining myself as one of the boys.
Oh, you're my boss in re we don't
really like your boss. Right.
I feel like, sure. If I was made
to feel better in whatever way,
just a little bit better,
that pressure release.
I said just a little bit
better about the mission. Okay.
And I trust you because of how you
always handle things or whatever.
You know what? All right. It's
not the best funnest, whatever.
It's not my first choice, but at least
we're doing it together. You know,
I trust you and all right,
let's do this kind of thing.
And one of the key things
you just said is trust.
So if you trust me and the boss is saying
to do something completely ridiculous,
and I come down and say, Echo, guess
what we're going to do? We're going to,
we're going to dig this hole and
then we're going to fill it back in.
I want to do it six times today.
Let's get to work.
And you know it's stupid and I come down
and try and sell that to you without
any explanation with that voice,
that voice,
I'm going to lose trust. You're
not going to trust me as much. Now,
if I come down and say, hey, hey boys,
hey, bringing in, this is what's going on.
Yeah. See, I'm going back to another
voice here. Going back to the leadership,
I said, hey guys, here's what's going on.
I know this is going to come
across as a strange task.
We're going to get it done.
We got to dig these holes.
I know where to fill them back in and
we're actually going to do this six times
today. Again, I know it's not exactly
what we were planning to do today,
but look,
let's get after it.
Let's get it done and let's prove to
everybody that we can make this happen
faster than and all of a sudden were
wherever you were going to get after it.
You know what I mean is no factor.
Whereas again,
if I go into like a Dorky
nerd voice and try and say,
we are going to do this because
it's the best plan ever,
I'm losing trust with you. I'm actually
hurting my trust. So this is a really,
really nuance thing.
And my best advice here is to
try and keep it in the middle,
right? Trying to be, and I'll tell
you, probably lean a little bit,
lean towards being professional.
Lean towards supporting the
chain of command because,
because the guys are going to know
when you give them that little little
pressure relief when you
say, Hey, I know this is,
this is a little bit of a strange plan.
As soon as I say that, if it was like,
okay, he understands working with, I know
we'll do whatever he says, Hey Jocko.
Okay Jock, we get it. You gotta you
gotta you gotta have us do this. Cool,
let's do it. Yeah. It's when I come
down and say, hmm. And again the,
you'll realize that this is, this is the
opposite. I see all the time. You know,
if you come down and say the boss's plan,
we got to do this.
I always throw that as like the
worst possible leadership is, hey,
we got to do this because
we were told to do it.
That's the worst possible leadership.
Not saying to do that.
What I'm saying is a little pressure
relief. Just a little pressure relief of,
hey look, I threw up a different plan. I
thought my plan was a little bit better.
Boss came up with this, this idea, we're
going to go for it. It's close enough.
Just something like that. Just
like, I know, I know. Dig It.
Yeah, that's it. A little,
let's give him a little,
a little nugget. Yeah.
I feel like I would feel
if you were to be like,
this is such a dumb plan and I don't
know why we got to do it or whatever.
I'd be like, wait, wait. Then why
are we doing that? Then my like,
why are we doing it? Then you know, and
I wouldn't want to do that. No. So yeah,
it's like right in the middle of there.
It's leaning towards being professional.
It's leaning towards supporting the
chain of command with just enough of a
pressure relief too to have them say,
I'll tell you a story. It's cool.
This is real, real quick. This
was in the take your time.
I want you to tell me the longest store.
We're going back to ninth grade
through high school, College.
It's weird that I even thought of this.
So we, we, you know how like in in class,
right, this high, early
high school, freshmen,
you know in class they're like, hey, get
into groups, we're going to do this thing.
And um,
so we got into these groups and we did
some project little thing during class.
We're done halfway through glass,
we're done and we're about to present.
The teacher looks at it and it was
like, oh, you guys got to do it again.
But the teacher didn't tell everyone.
She tells me this one girl,
Marla is her name come Marla.
So Marla comes back from talking
to the teacher and she's like,
she was kind of the leader. No
one desi. But she, at that point,
she was kind of the little leader that
liaison between the group and the teacher.
So she comes back, she like, cause
like we gotta do it again and were,
and everyone was like, what?
She goes, we gotta do it again.
Like you could tell she hit accepted it,
but just her being like sighing
kind of demonstrated that a,
she feels the pain too. I dig
it, but hey guys, you know,
we're not going to complain right now.
Let's just that little subtle thing.
But that's exactly what it did.
It kind of,
it basically accepted the order that
none of us really wanted to hear.
But at the same time she demonstrated
that, hey, she feels it too, you know,
and let's do what we did
again of course and whatever.
I don't even know what grade we had.
Got an a plus,
I'm sure Marlo work working her leadership
skills. It was weird that, I mean,
I don't know necessarily
that she intended to do that,
but that was the exact effect.
And you can, thinking back,
I can see the elements,
you know,
the little pressure release was her
not saying don't talk to me like dad.
She said we gotta do to get, you know,
she didn't like oppose anybody heard,
just heard little shit, mannerisms.
You know what she didn't do?
She didn't jump completely
on board the teacher. Yeah.
And be like we gotta do this
again. It sucked. No, she was like,
hey look we've got would have to do
this again. You know what I mean?
She just hated it enough. And
I'll say this, this question,
I'm surprised it took so long to get
this question because this is a really,
really good question and it also is a
incredibly important skill to be able to
walk this line.
And it's tricky to do and it's,
it's, it's sort of, this
might be one of the,
this is like the type of thing that
helped me a lot in when I was in the teams
was just being able to do this enough
cause you get have to do some dumb shit
teams man. And you know
what it's like. Okay.
Being able to translate a stupid,
something stupid and give enough pressure
relief too to make guys not just go
jock was just, you know, company guy,
right? He's a company guy. He look,
he just lives. Oh he doesn't stand up
for us. No, actually I do. But this is,
you know, like lifestyle. Tell him that
story about doing paperwork when I'm like,
no, we're going to do all the paperwork.
I went, I held the company line.
But like in such a dynamic or her such an
overboard way that guys are like, okay,
yeah we're going to win. This is a
competition. So that's good times.
Yeah. It's like a meat cause it seems
like okay. All that paperwork, it's,
it's almost like the paperwork was
like in a front dude's like, Hey,
what the US against them kind of thing
where it told us to do the paperwork and
you were like, yeah, and
we're, yeah, exactly. You know,
so it's like you take it to the,
that's something I'd done.
I've actually done that a fair amount.
I talked about the story before,
but like an officer candidate school,
every little stupid rule
that they threw at us,
I did it to the nth degree and had
everybody in that class to the nth degree
where they were just going,
yeah, yeah. Going ballistic.
So a story like that
where we're just going,
we're just going to take what's there,
take the order,
and carried out to the extreme
and take pride in doing that.
That was another little tactic that
I use by me along the way. Yeah,
we're going to do that. We're
going to do, it's so hard.
You're not even know what your name was.
That's another tactic you can take for
sure. They want us to Polish these boots.
They want us, they want us to clean
this thing. We'll do it. Watch this.
All right. Next question.
Six question Jocko.
Has there been a situation in which
you took something to personally?
How do you avoid taking things personally?
So the initial reaction is like,
no man, I don't take things too
personally. You don't want to keep to,
but the actual factors. Yeah, I take, I
take everything personally, right? Like,
I mean I,
if I do something bad,
I am very personally, I don't like
it at all. If I do something poorly,
I don't like it at all. I take it very
personally. If somebody gives me feedback,
I take it personally. This
is like, it's an ego thing.
It's a pure ego thing.
Right?
And I just had to say this at a group I
was talking to just because I say ego is
bad all the time. He goes
good to egos. What drives you?
Eagle is what makes you want to be
number one. Yeah. Ego is what is,
it brings you pride in your work
and makes you work harder to give,
deliver good product and and be a good
leader and a good employee and a good
person. Right? That's ego.
The problem comes when ego or taking
things personally actually prevents you
from listening to the critiques
that you're being told. That's,
that's the problem. So, for instance,
we'll take this little podcast right
here that's got some critique on it.
The other day I got somebody,
somebody sent me a little critique and
they said that I didn't explain cause we
had Andy Stumpf on here and Andy was kind
of rattling off that has his career in
the teams and he's, he was rattling
off the career and the teams,
he lost some people, not a bunch
because it wasn't that complicated,
but he lost some people. And,
and for instance, he used an,
an an an acronym, um, or an acronym
Lpl, which stands for leading
petty officer, which is the,
which is the second senior
enlisted person in a seal platoon.
And I didn't explain that when he said it.
So there's an example.
So when I heard this, my
first reaction is like, oh,
you don't know what Lpl is called,
gold. Google, go Google it.
Why are you asking me?
Oh Bryce, just stop talk.
And then that was pretty much, you
know, my, my ego was saying, hey,
I can't believe this person doesn't dare
you. How dare you? As I thought about,
I was like, well, you know, I need to,
I need to make sure in the
future that I'm more than,
I'm more aware of what guys are talking,
especially when I'm
sitting here talking to it,
another seal who we have a common language
and we are talking about things in
very conversational mode.
So we're not caring about anybody else.
And that's sort of what the
podcast is often is like we're not,
we're not talking to everyone
that's listening at this moment.
We're just kind of talking to
ourselves or amongst ourselves.
And so when he throws out this words,
I need to be more aware of them.
So if I took it personally, I might
not listen to, if I actually listen,
I can do a better job.
So that's,
that's kind of it. And basically
that's the same with anybody.
When anybody receives any
criticism of any kind, they get,
they take it personally.
And I think the thing is two things.
Number one,
get over it so you can listen
to what the criticism is in.
And also remember this, this is kind
of weird, I think maybe I'm wrong.
What do you think the more angry and
the more personally you take some
criticism, the truer it
actually is. Is that possible?
When something really bothers you,
it's probably something that really
bothers you because you know it's true.
Like when somebody says something
that just doesn't matter to me it,
it's, you know, I don't take it
personally. Oh they just think that don't
worry about it.
I'm not worried about it.
But when somebody says something that I
know is true and they're pinging me on
it,
that's means I get even more,
take it more personally and
get more angry about it. And,
and then that should be an indicator,
hey,
this is something you
actually need to fix.
It actually has to do with insecurity
more than anything. So it can be,
it can be super true or it can be kind
of true or you can just be questioning
whether or not it's true.
If you're insecure about it,
that's when it's going to,
cause you can be like, there
can be, okay. You know,
let's say guys have a receding
hairline and they're like, oh, I don't,
I don't care about that at all.
It's totally true. You know, and,
or let's say I do care about
it. I don't like it, but I,
I've known it for the last time I was 20
years, whatever. And someone's like, Hey,
you know, you're hairline's receding
to care about that. I don't,
I don't think they know. I don't know of
any, but I'm just saying certain things.
Um,
and if you know about it or you know,
and you know it's true and c, you
won't necessarily be bothered, but,
but if you get someone who's like,
it's starting to recede or
early on or it's like Dang.
And they won't necessarily be, this
is just an example, hypothetical,
but they won't necessarily be concerned
about the actual hairline receding.
They're more concerned about, oh, do
I look older and my unattractive now,
or am I losing it now? Or something like
that. That's what they're insecure about.
So when someone points out some
symptom of that insecurity,
that's when they're like, well, you
don't go to say that. Are, you know,
they get all mad and that goes for
kind of anything. So maybe, I dunno,
maybe it's someone saying, hey, you didn't
explain this enough. Maybe you're like,
wait, what do you say? Was
that a junk episode kind of
thing? Or, or something like,
did I not, um, you know how you,
you're good at explaining stuff
and simplifying them or whatever.
Maybe it was like a, an attack ad or
something. He's a personal point of pride.
Yeah. Yeah. You know? Exactly.
I don't know, but maybe,
but that's typically what
people get mad about.
It's not necessarily if
they know it's true or not.
It's if they're insecure
about it. Right. Well,
you wouldn't be insecure about something
that wasn't true. He was a thing.
But sometimes you do, cause
you know, sometimes it's like
a weird, like mental, uh,
like problem. But you know,
girls for example, I'm not
saying all girls, but listen,
I'm going to totally generalize right
now. But you know, the girl was like, Hey,
do I look fat in this? The
girls I can awesome shape or
whatever. And you're like,
ah, or worse. They always think
they're fat, that it's not true.
That's not the response by the world.
That's a perfect example though.
You know what I mean?
So it's like that kind of stuff.
You know,
people are just insecure
about stuff sometimes. Oh,
and even though the girls are
in really good shape or, or,
or even guys when especially like if
they're into like their physique or
something like that were,
I dunno,
they're at a party or so I've heard guys
like they go to parties and they'll do
like dips or pushups before they walk in.
Cause like, so they're like more pumped.
Aye, I swear. And is that why
you're doing some push ups?
You know what I mean?
So like you were just a little
insecure about what I have said
anyway. You know, they'll get that
kind where there'll be like, oh I'm,
they'll think that, oh, I'm not looking
very cut up or something like that.
You know, like that kind of stuff when
it's not true. Yeah. Yeah. No, I think,
I think that's a good point.
And I think the bottom line is
when we take things personally,
I think it's actually not a negative
thing because it means that you're,
there's probably something
that you need to work on.
But I think what we need to watch out
for is taking it personally and therefore
being mad and either be mad at the
person that told you which the person
probably could be out aligned, you know,
saying some stuff that's offensive.
But even if someone
offends you, well, okay,
well let's fix it so you don't have that,
that,
that weakness or that insecurity anymore.
And so just know what your red flags
are. No, when you're taking somebody's,
everybody take stuff.
Personally,
I'm like Mister detachment and I
take so personally all the time.
When somebody says something
to me, I'm like, oh, okay,
why don't I go when I do to do better,
do good job with seeing the big
picture though. You know, like,
cause a lot of times, you know, when I
always think back to the, you know, the,
the relationship like okay,
let's say, let's say I'm at
home, I'm mowing the lawn,
I did all this, these great
housework, chores, whatever.
You know, dad comes home, mom
comes home and they're like, hey,
I thought I told you
to take out the trash.
Meanwhile everything else is spic and
span. So I'm like, I'm mad. You know,
how dare you say that to me when I
did this? Me, me, my thing, my thing.
But at the same time, they're right.
You know, so you do a good job of like,
you'd be able to kind of recognize that
even though you'd probably feel those
same things. You won't,
your default isn't wounded.
We'll do it and fight back
and make the problem bigger.
It's kind of like you'll feel it on
the inside and recognize the red flags,
what's happening and you
go, Oh yeah, I'll kill her.
But I got to remember to take
all the tress because the
truth is, that's correct.
That is correct. It doesn't
matter if you did the lawn or not.
The trash was a thing,
you know, so yeah. Yeah,
you did good job of recognizing that part.
I think a lot of times in our
case we don't do such a good job.
No, I'm going to throw this out
there. This is a little off subject,
but it just made me think of it.
I was talking to Dave at the gym yesterday
and he was listening to the podcast
and he, he lost his,
he lost his dad. Yeah.
And like six months ago and he was
listening to a clip from the podcast of me
basically saying,
hey,
because someone asked what good
comes from when someone dies and he,
he said, look, you covered a lot of stuff.
And it was super powerful and it was,
was very helpful. And he said, but
there's a one more thing. He said,
there's one more thing that has come
from my dad's death that it's good.
And I said, what? And he said it was
like a slap in the face of go out and,
and get after it. You know, and
I kind of left that out and I've,
I've talked to other people and clearly,
you know,
when you lose someone that's
close to you and see the reason,
I guess the reason that I didn't think
of this is because in the teams you kind
of like, you guys get killed, you know,
and we all kind of already live with
the feeling of, hey man, I mean,
I say it all the time.
I'm going to live the best life I can.
But for someone in the civilian
sector, and they haven't had any, any,
they haven't lost anyone day,
haven't had anyone died close to them.
They get the feeling that many of us,
many people walk through through the
world with of I'm going to live forever.
You know, I'm not going to die. And
I got all the time, I've got time.
And so he made this great point. He said,
you know, for me, when my dad died, he's,
you know, he's in his mid
twenties and he's been kind of,
you know, I don't want to say the word
relaxing, but he's been, you know,
fairly crude. He's been
cruising kind of, and he's,
he realized he can't, he can't
do that, you know, he needs to,
he needs to get after it. So
cool. Cool story. Cool feedback.
I thought I should let everybody know.
That's another good thing.
When w if you lose someone and you,
you're not accustomed to that and
you don't see how precious life is,
cause a lot of the times it's pretty easy.
Forget,
it's pretty easy to forget
how precious it is when,
when it's right there, when it's given
to you, you know, it's, it's like food.
It's pretty easy to forget
how mean how precious was the,
was the crappy loaf of French bread with
sticks and bugs in it that Colonel Rita
got, we got to the prison camp and Hanoi
and that was precious. And you know what,
even colonel reader, three weeks later
he was like, oh, this, that bread. Even,
he's here, he's laughing. He's like,
that bread sucked. I was like, sir,
here you said it was like the best
thing you've ever had. He goes,
well it wasn't first.
So we all get,
we all get this attitude that you know,
hey, this is always going to be here.
Well it's not always
going to be here so don't,
don't treat it like it is taking
that for granted, you know,
next question.
Hi Jocko.
I'm being told in Jujitsu that I'm using
too much strength to execute techniques
and dominating roles.
I get after it in the gym and
try to be stronger and fitter.
All were already limit my strength
against same weight training partners and
definitely don't pull,
don't bull rush or
overpower lighter partners.
I want to improve my Jujitsu knowledge
and understand the intent of reducing my
strength and uh, it reduces my
strength to learn the skill. But where,
where's the balance?
I feel like I feel like I'm doing uh,
being penalized for working hard and being
strong and there has to be an element
of strength.
Two technique right
now that I'm trying to do zero strength
working week positions and they still go
100% on me. I'm not learning
anything. Right. What he's asking,
what is, what is my 25% stronger
than my training partners?
100% of trained Nogi for four years.
But Gee only for 12 months.
Don't judge the white belt warrior.
Okay. So you know,
I don't think anyone is saying
use zero strength, right.
It just be a or used to have a uh,
kids in the kids class that would just
like flop around like the use. No,
they'd be like noodles. You
know, especially when you're
a partner and I say, Hey,
don't be that. So no one's telling you
to use zero strength. That's not the,
that's not the,
the goal here.
You just want to use less strength
and I'm the same way, man.
I work out so I can be strong
and when we're rolling,
if I have to use strength,
I'm going to use it.
You bench pressed me off off you the
other day from across side wall technique.
Can you even claimed it at the time?
That's all weight, so, so that's
good. Right? And, and you,
you used it cause you had to use it,
you are going to get punished and
you're like, oh no, I'm not gonna,
I'm not gonna have Jocko across aside,
discerning in the role. So boom.
Got Bench press or watching
too, by the way. So, so yeah,
we, we want to be strong for sure.
But I'll tell you, this is the music,
the key thing when I'm
going to train with someone,
I'm going to use just enough skill and
strength to stay slightly ahead of him
just enough.
I'm not trying to crush them.
If someone's, and it'll tell you if
someone's a way lighter than me then,
but they have kind of equivalent skill,
then I'm going to try and limit
my strength as much as I can.
So it's a Jujitsu versus
a Jujitsu for sure.
But I'm definitely gonna use my
strength if needed for really,
for a couple reasons. The first
reason is because of ego. Sure. Right.
I don't want to tab, I want to get caught
in a bad position. I don't like that.
Yeah. If you call, if you train,
like when we're done training there,
I'm definitely using strength cause
I'm dripping with sweat, right?
I mean I'm using physical attributes,
but that's not the only reason.
The other reason that you have to use
your strength sometimes is you don't want
to give people the false sense of
security that a, that worked. Right.
Even your good training partners,
like you don't want to say,
oh the guy gets a position
so you just tap, right?
Because he's in a
competition or in the street.
The person is not just going to
tap, they need to do it. Right.
So that's it. I guess the
bottom, the bottom line is,
my guess is is this dude is
probably using too much strength.
He's probably one of those guys
that's naturally really strong, man.
He works out and he's thinking,
I've been trained in Nogi for four years.
So now when I put this guy on,
man,
I'm angry about it because I'm
falling behind a little bit.
So I'm gonna use some strength.
Yeah. I would say man, just try it.
Try and relax and just
one of my favorite pieces of
advice to give relaxed Harger
this,
relax,
try and flow when you roll a little
bit and it definitely will make you,
it'll make you better in the end.
The more you relax the the,
the more the better you'll get at the end.
And certain,
I found that like certain guys,
that's just,
they're just their method
really just strong. Yeah.
And that's how they roll and they're
just aggressive physically. That's how,
and I found that they can,
a lot of times they
can get more technical,
but really that's kind of their,
their strengths in a way. And that's,
it's just their way of ruling
and some guys in the opposite,
what now that you mention it,
there's some people that are like that.
They have like an on and off switch
then either all on or they're just super
docile. Yeah. It's almost like got to
find that middle ground if you can.
If you can't.
But people are different.
Like let's say like remember Franklin
mistruths phrase lexical at crazy.
Okay.
Consider him where he's going to be real
technical and flexible and flowy and
stuff. And that's his
Jujitsu. You can, he can,
I need to be more strong and rigid
and aggressive. He can train that.
But his default is that
flowy, flexible way. And,
and guys who are like this, I think
that's going to be kind of their default.
They can train kind of deviate a
little bit and get it more for sure.
But that's kind of just there. That's
the vehicle they have, you know,
and uh, it's, it's almost like a genetic
thing. It's not genetic but it's,
it's kind of,
it's almost like the foundation of
their Franklin was a trip to roll with
because he was so flexible
but not just in a normal way.
You know what his is flexible and his,
his spine was like when you put your
weight on him and he would just like,
like jelly fish. Yeah. It was like an
octopus. It's exactly what I was like.
Well she kept training man.
He was so good. That's all.
I'm pretty not too long ago. Yeah, he's
trained at like occasionally. Yeah. He,
he was getting good for awhile. Yeah. It
really feel good though. Still good. Um,
but yeah, it's kind of,
it's more of a mental thing.
Like if you mentally, there's drills
like you can do you remember? Um,
Jerry allowed in was his name.
He jammed into the needs but we used
to do this thing. He's like, Hey,
let's just flow. Right. And you know
how people say, let's just look,
so then they're trying to kill you.
He wouldn't though. He would be like,
his flow would be like a fast pace and
you could even try to hold them down and,
and he just be like falling flat employee.
He would get you in a good position and
they need to get right out of it into
another,
you know,
like he was really good at flowing to
the point where you get kind of tired
because you're moving so much.
It's not full speed flow.
It's almost full speed though.
So I remember doing that a lot with him
and it really translated when I would
roll, it would be like, I felt
like that difference in technique.
That's really good. I, I do. I
always do a warm up run with Andy.
Like that would just go position possess.
We were going, but we're going like,
you know, we're just go flowing. Yeah,
that sounds, I don't like the word,
but that's what it is. I mean, that's
what it is. Don't ever do that with dean.
No, I'm serious. Don't ever, no,
don't ever say listened to him.
Say like, Hey, let's just get warmed
up because he's not going to do that.
He's going to flow until he's in a
good position that he's going to smash.
You said don't do it. You have
to just go hard. Good. Yeah.
Yeah. And he's real good at that stuff
too, but that's a good way though.
Like if you, yeah, that's a
good way. That's a good way.
If you can see that's a good,
I see what you're saying.
That's a good way to learn
to relax more. Yes. Yes.
When that becomes more common because,
let's face it,
I mean if you're strong and you're
going into roles and people,
if to the point where people
were saying, hey, you're,
you're using too much strength from him,
you're getting,
if you're hearing that from multiple
people, there's an issue. Man.
That's my point is even though
you're saying, well saying, hey,
some people are just that way,
don't accept that.
Like who the guy that asks this question
don't accept echos thing of saying some
people just that way because that means
you're just going to keep doing it and
you to get better because he will. The
more you relax, the better you get. Yeah,
for sure, and of course I don't
mean it like that. I know. Yeah, no,
I know you don't,
but I'm saying like don't get that
miss conception that that's what Aco is
trying to say. Hey, you're just that
way. Go with it. No, don't go with it.
Listen to what echo is saying when he's
saying, hey, find somebody to flow,
roll with and just let it flow.
It's going to be rare.
You find a person who's kind
of default method is this.
And then by the way,
I just realized I don't say flow role
cause I was thinking about when I say to
Andy or we don't say it anymore,
we just do it. But I used to write,
hey let's a get a warm up round as I
call him a warmup. Okay. Hello role.
But sometimes not along. Sometimes it's
just like a technique sharpener have.
Let's see. He does do it.
Say does do some flow rolling
drills and gets better at it.
I would,
I would guess that there is going to
be a significant remainder of his game
that's going to be this aggressive
game. Oh for sure. For sure. Yeah.
Homes is aggressive on the mat for sure.
Another little mindset that might help
is think less competitively cause you
know how like a lot of people from
there and really it's true though. He,
here's the thing, this, this element needs
to be there where it, when it's time to,
to spar, it should be
competitive. Otherwise it's like
what are we doing? You know,
I want to know if I want you
to be competitive because
I want an accurate look
of what it's like to roll with Jocko
or a guy like Jocko, big, strong,
good at Jujitsu,
whatever.
If you're just flow rolling with me and
non competitively every single time I'm
not getting the work done I need no,
that's what I was talking about earlier
too is that's why you go, yeah, yeah,
yeah. You got to use strength. Yeah. So
it should be competitive, but if some,
if people are complaining you're going
too hard, you're going straight up.
Like every role is ADCC. Yeah. On
the line. Life or death, you know,
kind of more in that direction.
The Mood Giles, snare.
So if you think maybe less of that and
understand that this is, this is training.
If you want to get less using strengths,
they'll pay.
You got to kind of train that stuff. I
like it. The middle. The next question.
Next question Jocko. I need
some advice. If you've got time,
we've got time. What's a good
course of action when someone lies,
betrays trust or just plain destroys you?
Move on, straight up, move on,
forget them.
They are lying and they are untrustworthy.
So move on.
Now sometimes this can be hard,
especially if they've somehow
tied themselves into your life.
Especially like for instance,
you get the kids involved in a divorce
scenario. You, you can't move on,
but you have to mentally move on.
You have to emotionally detach from
that human and that's hard to do because
obviously they were someone
that you trusted. It'd be.
And the reason I know that you trusted
them is because they got to a point where
they were able to betray
your trust and destroy you.
So they, they, it's hard.
But the fact that they
trust that you trusted them,
the fact that you had that relationship,
that's even more reason to walk away.
It's even more reason to move on.
You got to see them for
what they are.
And this is an important piece right here.
This is an important cause.
This is something I learned as a
young lad out there in the world.
That person is not who
you thought they were,
right?
They are not who you thought they were.
The idea that this person
okay,
was a trustworthy,
faithful companion is not true.
It is not true.
That person does not exist.
They didn't exist and they don't exist.
It was in your head.
It was in your head that this
person was trustworthy and you the,
they were everything you wanted them to
be and they were faithful, commanded.
That is a lie.
They are not that person.
They have proved it.
They've proved it by their actions.
So move on and at the
risk of sounding callous,
get over it.
Okay?
Get over it. Do not
dwell. Do not dwell on,
do not dwell on,
on on what it was and don't
dwell on what it could have been.
You were year when guys go through bad
breakups. You know it's, I just thought,
well, you're going to, it's
like, no, don't dwell on that.
Deal with what it is right now.
What that person is.
Deal with reality except
reality and be be thankful.
Free Alley.
Be Thankful that you were able to learn
before you invested morale more than to
this person.
Be Beat.
Be Thankful that you found out when
you did that this person was a liar,
that this person was unfaithful
as untrustworthy beat. Be Thankful
that you know it and you
know it now instead of later.
And you know what else is going to
make it a lot easier to get over these
situations is recognize that there's
plenty of people out there in the world
that are trustworthy and
there are faithful good people
there. They're out there.
Go find one of them.
But
don't think that that person that you
had was the only one in the world.
They're not. And you know
what if that I have sometimes,
sometimes people have a hard time making
that trust because they're so caught up
and they, they, they don't want to meet
someone else right away. That's fine.
Start with yourself.
Right? Rely on yourself.
Trust yourself because we won. When
someone breaks our trust, we, we,
we question ourselves to yes,
like we think are my judgments bad.
I'm not a good judge of human character
cause I totally put my faith in this
person and look what they did to me.
So now we don't trust her.
So you've got to build that trust up.
You got to build that trust up back again
with yourself. How do you do that? Read.
Okay.
Right.
Learn workout.
Be alone.
It's okay to be alone so people
get freaked out when they're alone.
It's okay to be alone. It's okay. It's
okay to be alone. There's no big deal.
Enjoy it.
Okay?
Do something productive and build that
trust up in yourself and you'll look back
at the situation. Learn from
it. We do that. It's an owl
post operational debrief.
Oh, you've put too much trust in somebody.
Cool. They broke your heart. All right,
Roger that. Let's see. What were the
steps? What should I have recognized?
How many times did I say? Well,
you know, they didn't call me,
but it's probably just because
their phone was out of battery. No.
Once your phone runs out of battery once,
okay. You don't let it happen again,
right? Yeah. So you start
seeing those red flags to you,
the mistakes that you made and then look
for them next time around because you
deal with people all the time that
they made mistakes. The first run,
they go back and they
make the same mistakes.
The second run they go back and make
the same mistakes. The third run.
That's when you got to start
blaming yourself on your situation.
That's why, that's why I said you got to
like build a relationship with yourself.
You got to learn yourself.
You've got to trust,
you've got to learn to trust yourself,
so spend some time doing that and
then when you go back and you start
dealing with people, because that's what,
that's what you got to watch out for
is that you become a hardened criminal.
If you don't trust anybody,
like you were talking about cops,
you know sometimes cops have a hard time
because they're dealing with scumbags
all day long and it builds up this,
this mistrust of other people.
So you don't want to have that happen.
You want to be suspicious of people,
but you want to be able to build trust.
Once they proved themselves.
So take those small steps and
start to build up over time.
Don't just jump in and give someone a
hundred percent trust out of the gate.
You don't know him. Don't know
him. You know, back in the day,
back in the day when old hardcore bands
used to have this t shirt that just said
trust, no one was like, yeah,
that's legit. Right? You don't,
don't go out of the gate with the big
trust on somebody with important stuff.
Don't do it. But the good
news is, like I said,
there's plenty of people out there that
are good people that you are giving you.
You can give all your trust to
just take it slow brother. Yeah.
So crazy how you just explained that
so simple and it makes total sense when
you're in the situation now the motions,
you know like you can't
just detach and be like,
what are the red flags that
I know you're too busy.
No missing the person or
whatever your disasters.
But even
throwing things and looking at pictures,
that's the worst to get out the picture
and stare. I've seen guys do that.
I'm like, Bro, give me that.
Let me throw this away for you.
It's not going to help that person.
Yes.
Always to me was,
was explaining like listen,
cause guys was no,
no, she wasn't. That is a lie.
That person that you put put together in
your head that you've assembled in your
mind, that person doesn't
exist. They don't exist.
The person that you dealt with was a liar,
was unfaithful, is a
cheater. That's the person,
the person who wasn't this person that
you're putting forth in your mind.
That person doesn't exist. So stop. But,
but you don't understand the good time.
Yeah, I know. I know. I know. It's
a choice. Here's the trick. Okay. So
if,
okay, that person lie at that part of the
cheater and what I kind of said there,
it was, look, you don't understand the
good time. That's a real part of it.
That's really it. It's like sure
they did this. Sure. She, um, uh,
flats my tires when she gets messier,
all that.
But the good times we have
are so good. So it's, it's,
it's proof that it's not about the person.
It's not about the person that you
can see all the red flags and how they
mistreat you from time to
time or they'd be true.
It's about yourself and how you're
sad now because of all these reasons.
But the trick comes with what
one of the tricks come with. Um,
same thing I said about drinking,
where it's your brain.
Cause it's like chemicals. When you bond
with someone in certain, in certain ways.
And it's different from, you
know, it varies from person
to person, but it's like,
I think it's like oxytocin or I
don't know where it's, it's it. Yeah.
It's so I don't want to go into it.
But you feel this bond
with this specific person.
That's why you have these feelings.
Even though this girl like lies to you,
you see her lying text messages on your
phone right now. You're looking at him.
Meanwhile,
you still still miss him.
It's a trick because it's saying that
your emotional wellbeing is attached to
this person kind of thing.
Right. And all the other stuff,
you just kind of ignore it. So it just,
like I was saying with drinking, right?
Why know consciously like I'm
going to be hung over it tomorrow.
I won't get anything done. All this stuff.
Why do I want a drink so bad right now?
You know, kind of thing.
Um, and it's the same thing.
The chemicals in your brain are telling
you like this girl is essential for you.
You know, for your wellbeing's not, yeah.
Oh, that's the logic though. That's a lie.
It's a trickle. Listen to the,
don't listen to your brain.
Listen to me that she is not
essential, bro. I'm telling you.
But that's the logic.
Those chemicals are blocking.
I have seen so many situations
where guys are just in,
what's horrible is, I'm
sitting here saying this, it's,
you could be smacking someone in the
face telling them, move on, move on.
And they're not going to listen to that.
So that's all. So you to make a decision,
that's, that's, that's, it's
hard. And guys ruined their lives.
I mean the others do too. And Roseanne
guys ruined their lives, you know,
with over somebody that is completely
abusive, whether mentally or physically,
that just completely abusive and they
will ruin their lives for this person,
that person. And you see in my mind, I
think it's because they build a person,
they build a person on
the framework of reality.
They build a fantasy and they're in love
with that fantasy and they want to keep
it going. Right? It's a fantasy.
So stop and they get away.
They ignore like all the Quona version
and they remember the good times,
even if it's like 10 minutes a week,
they remember those good times.
They ignore the red flags
foe because of that,
that you know that trick,
that chemical trick in their brain.
And so it reinforces that thing
that they built. You know,
that fantasy that they build. It's true.
This big. The reality is this big. Yeah.
And look the fantasy state
and they just attached to it.
You ever see a friend or whatever,
cause I'm assuming you've never been
in this situation like you ever had a
friend where they're really into it.
They're almost ruining their life.
They're in bad shape or whatever,
and then whether it be all of a
sudden are years later, whatever,
they're thinking back and they're like,
whoa.
Was I think because of the chemical trick,
so to speak.
Whereas off and then they can see all
of that logic that you're talking about
and like all my gosh man,
it's, it's almost like,
it's almost like you feel like you were
a different person when you recovering
from cancer.
I mean,
just the fact that you can't
talk any sense into people
and no to that situation.
That's the trick. You got to try
and, yeah, it's hard. It's hard.
But I think knowing that that's it.
It's a chemical in your brain that is
tricking you and it goes for a lot of
stuff. Donuts, like all this
that's tricking you. If you
know, like, Hey, and you say,
I'm not going to be tricked.
I feel it. I feel this.
I feel the sadness. I feel missing this
person, but it's a trick, you know? Yeah,
that's, that helps. It
totally helps. I like it.
So move on, man. I know
it's hard. Trust us.
Speaking of moving on,
next question,
unless we want to talk about
this anymore. No, exactly right.
Let's move on.
In what circumstances do you
recommend direct? I will hold on. Oh,
we're not moving on.
You're stuck on it.
But what's horrible is been people killed
themselves in these situations over a
lie. Yeah, that's, that's
to me the trick, the trick.
But it's a lie in and guys or girls get
so distraught over this fantasy that
doesn't exist.
And what's really jacked up
is if they could just move on,
they'd find a reality that was actually
congruent with what their desires are.
It's out there. You could see people
all over the world. They're there,
they're in relationships, having
fun from every level, right?
There's someone out there,
but you,
you get caught up in this mental trap and,
and obsessing over a fantasy.
It's a fantasy. Don't, don't,
don't obsess over the fantasy,
man. There's, you can,
you can get over it.
And there's plenty of other human
beings out there that are awesome.
So go find one of them.
And in the meantime,
hang out with your Badass self.
Right?
And become a better person and working out
is a big one for sure. For sure. As it,
that's 100% just get it,
get in the gym and get after it.
Jujitsu solves everything. Yes,
lifting solves every leg. Right.
Okay. So what circumstances
do you recommend direct
attack in combination with
indirect, if any? Or do you
have any examples? Yeah,
so we talk about flanking all the time.
I always recommend a combined attack,
right? If you only attack the flank,
well then the enemy's going to Justin,
they're gonna put all the defenses there.
Now it's not a flank anymore.
Now it's the front and becomes so,
so you need to feign attack,
or at least you need to attack with some
minor level of force directly so that
the enemy has to defend what you're
doing. And I mean, clearly when,
when we were,
examples are pretty easy to come up
with where when we're doing raids like
assaults on buildings,
you're gonna attack that building
from multiple directions at a minimum.
At least you're gonna set distractions
on some of the other directions.
And it was same thing we were setting up
Overwatch's. Yeah, we're going to have,
a lot of times we'd have a main
Overwatch and we'd have a little,
another little flanker Overwatch.
I said, when you come to get us,
you're going to pay and like
a classic l shaped assault.
There's a reason it's called an l shape.
It's shaped like an l. You have a,
you have a,
a fire,
a base position that's going
to put down fire on the target,
and then you have some newer element
that's going to come in from the flank,
but even with that you, you, you have to
do a base element and a maneuver element.
There's a reason because you're going to,
the base is going to put down fire and
then the maneuvers going to maneuver it.
So yes, those are, those are clearly some
of them. And it's the same thing. Yes.
It's the same thing in the
business environment, right?
In the business environment,
if you're going to
maneuver into a new market,
you don't just walk away from your
other market, right? You don't,
if you're going to develop a new product,
you don't throw away your old product.
No, you keep, that's your base. You
keep that going and then you frank.
So it makes sense there.
Um, yeah. So absolutely.
When you,
when you're going to attack
attack from both directions.
I, in fact, I do that most of the time.
So
next question.
This actually isn't really a question.
It's more of a comment. Yeah.
I kind of turned it into a question. I
know you responded to the comment, right?
Yeah, sure. Just want
to say quick. Thanks.
I struggle with the daily
grind trading days for dollars,
but you helped me make it happen.
Yeah. And my comment was like, okay,
well thank you.
I guess
because I hope at the same time that
you're grinding that you're trading that,
that you're,
I hope that you're not trading days
for dollars long term because long term
that's a losing proposition,
right?
If you're grinding and it's not
doing something you want to do,
if it's a grind that you can't embrace,
then you got to find a way out of
that. Right. You got to find you can't,
Trey,
you don't want to trade days for dollars
because dollars don't mean anything.
Days. All you got. So you've
got to find a way out.
Now, this does not mean you
need to be rash about it.
This doesn't mean tomorrow you walk,
you know what to do with this job anymore.
I'm out and now you're
broke. No, don't be rash.
And don't throw the baby
out with the bath water.
But do come up with a longterm
plan about what you want to do,
how you want to do it,
where you want to do it.
And this might take one year
or two years or five years.
It might take five years to get to
where you want to be. That's okay,
that's fine. It's, it's actually kind
of cool when you're grinding right now,
cause you know there's something that
you're working towards in the long run
that's actually awesome. So, but,
but you gotta have an exit strategy.
You got to have an exit strategy.
You've got to plan and figure out how
much money it's going to take and what are
you going to do?
You're going to work two jobs.
I'm going to save all my money right now.
I'm going to invest here.
Then pay off my or whatever
it is you're going to do
so that you can get yourself
into a position where you
actually enjoy doing what
you're doing.
That's what you want.
And the one other cool thing about this,
like,
like I say, man, it's cool to grind,
man. That's what we're here to do.
You're here doing stuff right?
If you're not doing anything well
then what are you doing that? So the,
the other thing that's cool though
about grinding and working is,
is that when you get that freedom right,
that you work hard for it,
it can be so much more worth it.
The discipline that you put into place
to get to that freedom that you want.
It makes that freedom so much
more worth it. So I appreciate it.
I'm glad you're grinding.
I'm glad you're grinding hard,
but don't just make that trade.
It's not a square trade.
Days for dollars is not a square trade.
Get it back under your control.
And we've had,
I've actually had some
really cool feedback on the
podcast of people that have
hit me up and said, hey, I, you
told me to plan an exit strategy.
I wish I could find this. The Guy said,
you told me to plan an exit strategy.
He's like, that was whatever, nine months
ago I saved my money. I just did this.
Now I'm in another business. I'm kicking
ass. Thank you. Right. So it can be done.
It's one of the things about
cool about being a human being.
You've got free will,
you can make stuff happen.
Oh it's a go make it happen man.
Isn't that a lot of tricks
there too where you know the,
we'd talk about the disc,
hyperbolic discounting when you,
when you basically go
for the short term payoff
in at the expense of the longterm payoff.
So let's say you have an
exit strategy for five years.
It helps actually it,
it's,
this is like for real help night and
day where if you look at that end exit
strategy as like a,
you know,
a goal or whatever and the time in
between now and then is preparation time.
That's all that is like.
So a lot of times like I remember one
when I was working at the nightclub that
was, that was a full on like
Ooh, nightclub called job,
all short term payoff stuff. Kind of day
to day, week to week. I get my paycheck,
I go hang out, go work paycheck, hang. So
it's all just short term payoffs. Right.
So I was in there for years, like
years. How many years? Seven.
Eight? No, six. That was the end of
like almost seven. Yeah. Nightclub.
So I remember thinking when I was like
over it already. Um, I remember thinking,
Dang,
I feel like I wasted a lot of years.
I think back now I didn't cause I learned
a lot of like psychological stuff.
But um, I remembered like
reflecting and being like, man,
I spent and yeah, I went to college,
all this stuff really slacked through.
Call it. I spent it the
same way, just like, okay,
I'll take this class because I
may or may not pass it, whatever.
I just want to play football and be cool,
whatever. And I reflect and I think,
Dang, I spent my life preparing
for nothing really consciously.
I mean passively I did because I liked
certain creative things and that,
you know, materialize for sure, but
actively like consciously, I was never,
you know how certain people,
they're like,
I want to be an architect for sure
and that's it. And I'm doing it.
And I know a lot of times if there's
family history in certain things,
it's like they know, you know, and
they wind up doing it a lot of time.
But I reflected and
thought, man, I'm here.
I spent my life up to this point
preparing for nothing in life.
I know about working out.
That's it.
So a lot of times when you're making your,
you find yourself in a grind that without
an exit strategy or something like
that,
a lot of times that will be the case.
Like I've spent my life kind of
preparing for nothing really.
But that's the good thing how
you're saying it can take a year,
it can take two years,
five years, whatever.
Start preparing for that five years and
at the end when the five years comes,
you are prepared straight up. If you spend
one year doing something, focus like,
Hey, I got to get even something
like I'm going to play the piano.
I don't know anything.
Bow and Arrow, I dunno,
you spend one year focused on it at
the end of the year you can be pretty
prepared. Yeah. Compared to the average
person. So he spent like two years,
five years preparing whatever
that exit strategy is.
And you're for real prepared spend.
Look at that time as this is
preparation time. Yeah. And it's,
if only
somebody comes up to you,
you've been working at the nightclub
for a year and says, hey, echo,
what are you going to do with your life?
And you're like, oh, it wouldn't eat.
You would immediately say, well, well
let me phrase that another way. Echoed.
Are you planning to, uh, you know, be a
nightclub bouncer for the next 25 years?
You're answered clearly be no. Okay. So
what are you getting ready for? Yeah,
cause a lot of times this person
is aware that they're in a grind.
A lot of times people don't even realize
that what they're doing, they're,
they're, they're marking time is what we
call in the military. You're marching,
but you're not going anywhere. You're,
your feet are going up and down.
You're spinning your wheels.
So think about it.
That's a great point that you just made
is what, what were you preparing for?
If you would have been learning
to play the piano, boom.
You can be in the game right now.
But so that's an important thing.
Especially when you start talking to
people that are younger, you know?
Oh I'm when they're 15, 16, 17 years old.
Cause there'd mark and time
they're having fun. Yeah.
But it's cool to have fun.
Let's make sure we're making some progress
and building some capacity to have a
better future all the time. What can you
do to build capacity for your future?
Hey,
you know,
you heard Andy Stumpf and I talk about
this and we didn't even recognize that
there's anything else you could do besides
being the teams. That's it. That's it.
And that's kind of,
that's kind of good because when you're
having teams you don't want to be
thinking about anything else.
And luckily the teams does give you
preparation for other things in life.
Cause you're in leadership positions,
you're going up, you learning skills,
you're learning whether you're learning,
parachuting and you're learning stuff.
Guys get out of the teams all time.
They become cops,
they become firemen.
So they can be all kinds of good jobs.
But if you're not in a job like that,
you're in a job like a bead,
a nightclub bouncer. Hey,
it's a fun job, right? Yeah,
it's cool you're having a good time,
but let's make sure we have an exit
strategy on that one, right? Yeah.
And it doesn't even necessarily mean like
if I want it to be ultimately in Devon,
just saying,
being conscious of it where if I want
it to be a nightclub owner or something.
Perfect. Yeah, I'll stay right in there.
And, but here's the difference is I'm not,
I wasn't consciously spending
that time preparing for anything.
I was going for tomorrow for
it, you know, this weekend.
That's all I was going for. And a lot of
times, I mean in the nightclub it was,
cause it was like a very
recognizable payoff, you know,
cause it's fun and there's this party
going on. But even in these grinds,
like let's say working for
a moving company one time
it was the same thing I was
looking for the weekend. It sucked.
But I was like the work part stuff,
but I was looking forward to getting
off work. Okay. The relief is so it's,
it's the same dynamic, just
kind of negative, you know,
it's like a negative versus the
positive is the relief kind of thing.
The moving company made you want to eat,
eat forced your hand to want
to go do something else,
like a different lifestyle.
Whereas the nightclub,
the sooner you can get,
you can get distracted and
in that way you're like, hey,
this is just going to be cool.
Right? Yeah. So it's that
that carrot and the stick,
you know, the, you know, the nightclub
was, I was just eating that carrot,
those right in front of my face
every day or every week or whatever.
The moving company was like,
fine,
I'm just trying to run away from the
stick that's hitting me every day kind of
thing. Yeah. So I guess it just depends
on how much you hate sticks and carrots.
It's just so good.
And like you said,
we don't listen to our parents or we
don't listen to our people around us.
We don't listen to it, we just
don't do it. It becomes noise.
That's why even you saying, what do you,
what do you wanna do with your future,
bro? I've heard that since, literally,
since I could understand English.
What are you going to do with your PR?
What are you doing to prepare for
your future? What are you going to do?
You see yourself doing the fruit? Well,
yeah, no, I don't know Leila. It's just,
it's a meme or Eddie, you
know, you hear it all the time.
So it doesn't mean anything.
That's why a lot of times it takes
like someone to either rephrase it or
straight up like show it to you somehow.
You know where it hits you.
Like Davis sock in his is he was cruising
and his dad died and you got shown.
Yeah. Okay. What am I doing? So
good stuff to think about. Yeah,
I mean personally I just
got tired of it man.
Well I'm glad you did
x question. I think we got time
for one more question. Yeah.
Okay.
Jocko,
I have read your book extreme ownership.
My son and I listened to your podcast
on the way home from hockey practice and
while I can see your message,
I can't bring myself to employ it,
which I would like to do so very badly.
Any suggestions?
Well,
everybody wants to employ extreme and
disciplines so very badly,
but everybody also wants it to be easy,
right?
They want some,
some secret power that just makes
it happen and they think that I
hold the magic key that's going to make
discipline the easiest thing in the
world. Well, I can tell you that
taking ownership of your life,
it isn't easy
and living the life of
discipline isn't easy.
In fact, it's hard. That's why it works.
And so if you want to employee discipline,
there's only one way to do it.
You employ discipline.
Stop looking around for suggestions
on how to employ discipline,
because I'll tell you that
listening to this podcast is not
going to give you discipline.
Reading the book is not
You have to impose discipline on yourself.
You
ain't.
You do that
with steps that you execute.
Small steps. Get up early, workout heart,
attack your daily tasks,
crush your job.
Don't waste time on on on
meaningless activities.
That's how
you employed discipline.
You get aggressive in
making things happen.
Be The discipline.
That's it.
That's it. It's that simple.
And I'll say it again.
If you want to live a disciplined life,
that's what you have to do.
You have to be
the discipline,
and I think that's
all I've got for tonight.
So Echo.
Yes,
I know you've been kind of stepping
up the discipline and ownership.
Why don't you take some ownership right
now of telling people how they can
support this podcast if they want to.
I will
before supporting this podcast.
I think we all should support
ourselves in this way.
Similar to like on the airplane.
Like I said before,
you get the airplane and the oxygen mask,
you got to put it on yourself
before you can help the infant.
Not that, not that this podcast
is an infant or nothing.
Well maybe it is one year, whatever.
Anyway. You know what I mean?
So if you're, I've been into
working out more, more consistently,
we just ain't locked cause those, and you
know, I'm no stranger to the workouts.
MMM.
I've been supplementing
my workouts with supplements as you know,
um, Krill oil just got some more boom,
you know, that when you get new krill oil,
like I get it now before I run out. You
know? I mean, it seems obvious like,
Oh yeah, you're, you're an adult
now and you're prepared. I like it.
Yes, exactly. Which is new for me. The
buzz is still doing, I'm out of Krill oil,
how order, so now I know. Yeah, no,
no, no. That's not going on anymore.
Which is another demonstration of
discipline really. We count that. Yeah.
That's kind of counseling as a daily
discipline bordering Krill oil before
you're out. That's right. It's true.
I like what you've done there when it
comes in. I'm not even out of my old,
but when it comes in
and feel it feels good,
oils in it feels good to
be prepared. Yeah. So yeah,
you feel prepared. You are
prepared. Yeah. You are. You like,
cause you are straight up. Anyway.
Krill oil. If you don't know
what's Krill Omega threes
is it? Yeah. Anyway,
it's real good for your joints. It can
really, that's, I mean Omega Three's good.
Cool.
But the question is if you don't know,
it's kind of like what does
that do for me? You know?
Well how's that going to look?
How's the Omega three is going to
benefit me in the Krill oil situation?
It's your joints.
Especially if you do a lot of pressing
exercises and Jujitsu actually shouldn't
say especially, I'm just saying
including, but not limited to,
hard pressing as you just exercises.
Like where are you done there?
I'm telling you man, it's the truth. Um,
anyway. Yeah. So get on that Krill oil.
If you have joint, a joint
session situation, really,
or if you don't or if
you don't prevent it.
If I needed to do more preventative
stuff in my life, yeah,
it's funny. I'll take them like
I'll pull them out, you know,
and they look like jelly beans. I didn't
realize it looked like my daughter.
She's four. So look what jelly beans. But
did she smell up? Nah, she don't bite him.
She, you know, you smell them. Smelled
like Krill oil. Hey, I was on deployment.
So they make disgusting jelly beans.
Have you ever seen those before?
They make jelly beans that tastes
like Puke, that tastes like what?
Like on purpose.
It's like a joke.
So I was on deployment in Iraq and
somebody sent me a care package,
a care package,
yet they were being funny.
They sent me some of them bad tasting
jelly beans. I didn't look at the label.
I've just opened them up because
I hadn't had any candy in a while.
I wanted some candy.
Boom. Took a mouthful.
Just pure Dang. It's disgusting. Yeah.
So the Krill oil jelly beans,
more or less,
the same thing with vitamin Itam eats
up. Yeah, the packaging is different,
so they don't, you know, you
get those things anyways.
If you're interested in
these krill oil tablets,
this is what they are. I'm not krill. I
had a little tablet to yeah, eat them,
chew them if you want.
Swallow my recommend because they
smell and taste like krill oil anyway.
But they're good for your
joints. Yeah. On it. Okay.
So the really all the supplements you're
going to want to take is from on it.
So go to on it.com/ajiaco
if you want the 10% off.
But like I said,
back to the support part where,
okay, so you know how like when you
work out and then you ever work on,
you're like a my knees or my elbow
or something is bothering them.
It's like your whole body's working fine.
You can bench a bunch, you can squat
a bunch, but it's like your elbow,
it's like holy, you know, you're, you're
only as strong as your weakest link.
Elbows, knees. That's your
weak link right there.
That's what the Krill oil does.
That's what it alleviates. You know?
That's important is what I'm saying.
Yeah, I agree with, here's the thing,
I didn't really understand
that, but at Bro, I've,
I've done it where I've taken
like Ibuprofen to like, okay.
It's cause it's just pain.
It's not like I'm going to pull like
if it's your muscle or something like a
strained muscle. Yeah, it's like a pain,
but it'll inhibit cause you have a little
chain decide to start taking krill oil.
Um, I mean I know I take and I
was like, yeah, you should try it.
Or did I say that or did you just start
trying it on your own? It was you,
but I heard about it. You know,
my wife's, my father in law would,
oh screw it was better than
fish oil. I was like, cool.
I don't even take fish oil.
So it didn't really mean much
to me. I lift nothing. I'm,
I'm looking for gains bro. C'Mon,
I leave me alone with a girl.
But yeah, that was it. And you
mentioned it and um, you know,
like you're not hobbling around
in pain and other, so I said, hey,
if chocolate doesn't let me go try.
And then I got it from a guy that was
like a power lifter really strong and he
was, you know, 56 years old
when I met him. He was a
great shape and I said, what,
what'd you do? He said, yeah, I
told that's not the only thing.
He also works out hard and all that stuff.
But yeah,
it's a good thing to know
about. That's really, that
was my point really. You know,
like my,
you know,
you can be strong but when you got
your elbow jacked up from being strong,
really you got to patch
that little thing naturally.
Like cause it's not like
you're putting quarters,
cortisone shots or in my case Ibuprofen,
just to mask the pain so you
can get gains. It's different.
It's like a whole thing. I was telling
them, Taylor, I was talking with him,
we rolled through a little,
did we know? We didn't know.
We were just talking and uh, I told
him how old I was and he's like, what?
You know,
it's the Krill oil man.
Notice I didn't mention how old
nonetheless, if you like Krill,
I actually there's some good
soul, you know, the per case.
So there's this total strength
and performance to um, I was,
I was looking at that because it's real
interesting like stuff in the clinical
studies, it's over time. So
it is considered a preworkout.
So typically when people
take it consistently,
consistently out your gains,
it's like a cumulative effect.
What I mean,
just like Krill oil though,
really like because here's why I
got traded. I didn't get trick.
But here's why I misunderstood.
Is usually a preworkout has like caffeine
and stimulants and Cheryl have like
other stuff allegedly,
I don't know.
But usually you take a pre workout so
you get fired up physiologically to go
lift, get big pump,
get all this, you know,
this performance stuff or whatever
from the caffeine and all that.
Total strength. And performance doesn't
have caffeine. Yeah. So it's a different,
it's a whole different kind of
system that's giving you the benefit.
Feels good though. Yeah,
that and but true tech too.
Same thing where you can take it that day
and you'll feel it that day because it
helps.
Oxygenate guy said I double at double dip
on those to get all of it all up on it.
And downfall trip to South Africa.
I didn't have either. Oh Dang. Um,
what do you call it when you don't
take what's up? Go on slick. I guess
here we had some good rolls
down there too. Yeah, I was,
I was thinking to myself back to
the guys that were down there,
chef and Richie, they're like,
Hey, do you know tomorrow night?
Because I went and rolled the first night
at their fight fit and the the first
night, you know, we'd trained
a little bit, you know,
but we were hanging out
and then they said, hey,
when you come back tomorrow we're
just going to do like 10 rounds,
ten five minute rounds.
I was like, okay, cool.
And then I got the home and the
next morning or the next afternoon,
we were heading over there. I said, yeah,
I wouldn't mind having a little bit of
shroom tech. Right. But I didn't have it.
He had to go slick. Good
Times. Amen. You know, and hey,
go and slick. That's cool. But you
don't have to. Yeah, no. I mean,
we didn't want her, I wanted to
have a little bit that some of us,
we don't want that be, I mean, also
we're going to take this room tech,
we're going to take the,
the cro to me, again,
back not to go too deep on the Krill oil,
but that one I think is like an essential,
that's like an everyday thing.
You know, like people, they'll
drink coffee every single
day. You know what I mean?
Yeah.
And Co I say cool drink coffee,
but it should be like that because the
crew is way more beneficial than the
coffee. I mean, coffee is more like,
it's like an immediate thing anyway.
Anyway, you'd like to stuffs,
um, these cool supplements, good.
Simply the best supplements.
Everyone knows this already.
Go to [inaudible] dot com
slash Jocko for 10% off.
Also a good way to support the podcast
is the Amazon Click through all how all
that is is before you do your Amazon
shopping, click through the website. I got
a banner, little Amazon shopping banner,
got the dot.com got the.com.uk one and
I want to say the Germany one two mm,
yeah.
Over there on the side of the website.
Uh,
Jocko podcast.com and also up top on the,
on the navigation menu as we
to find is what you're saying.
Easier than it was before for sure.
Well that's good. And then on the store,
I think it's like in the
support tab anyway. Before
you do your Amazon shopping,
click on that first then do your shopping
regardless of what you're buying.
I always make the sodium in the water
reference cause really that's what it is
really. That's the best reference. I
mean the best analogy, you know? Okay.
It is bro. Okay. I said okay. Yeah,
but the way the tone where it's over,
but here's the thing that's a big deal.
Small piece of sodium. Drop it in water.
See what happens. Just see what happens.
Actually don't do that. Look at it
and look up a video. See what happens.
That's what's good. And that's what
you are really, you do this law.
Actually the biggest thing is people
don't. People think it's not a big deal.
That's a thing that can kill
the little piece of sodium.
Tell that to the sodium
when he hits water. Yeah,
you go and you did smell action takes
to set literally two seconds. Boom.
Click and big reaction. Good support,
good reinforcements. What if you,
you kind of needed some reinforcements
and it took just one click of a thing and
it brought just a full on reinforcement
into your situation. That's good, right?
Yeah. Small action.
Sounds good to me. Anyway,
that's what the Amazon Click through does
and that's how you do it. Good as junk.
podcast.com. Click on the Amazon
battery, free to do the shopping. Boom.
Instant support.
Um,
and you can subscribe to the podcast on
whatever iTunes provider platform you
use, iTunes, stitcher,
Google play
and others. Um, yeah, subscribe. If you
haven't, haven't already. Leave a review.
If you're in the mood,
if you are moved by Jockos words
or echoes words or echoes words,
leave, review, see what up. I'm
also subscribed.
Subscribe to our Youtube Channel.
We have a youtube channel and all that.
People already know that
and a lot of people have youtube channels.
Yeah.
How do you distinguish which ones are good
and which one's not good? Right. Well,
here's the good thing about subscribing
to youtube channels is you just click
subscribe and if I guess it, you know,
it shows the new videos in your feed,
you can elect to have a notification or
not when you come up notification and it
doesn't annoy you because for something
to annoy you would have to happen a lot,
but since you don't,
a lot of videos I do actually,
it depends on what you mean by a lot, so
at least two weeks will be uploaded. Oh,
one will be the podcast. One
will be something else. I see.
That is it that you just
threw down the gauntlet.
Now everyone's going to track your
beard. I know about do it. Hey,
if echo doesn't put up at least
two videos a week from here on out,
we can attack him on the
interwebs. Verbally, please.
Yeah, man. Hey. Ah, I'm
accountable. Yeah. Okay. Yeah,
you just made yourself accountable
so that's good where it is. But yes,
it was great. A little bit
better. Extreme OraSure anyway,
good thing about subscribing to youtube.
You can just subscribe like anything else.
It's not like these,
you know these marketers and
email you stuff. It was like, hey,
unsubscribed you like
chicken with from four years ago
and you're still emailing me.
I didn't think it was good. Yeah. Stop.
Why do I have the option to
unsubscribe to your email list one,
I didn't even subscribe to
it. Get away from this. Yeah,
so it's not like that kind of where you
click unsubscribe and then the email you
again, by the way, this insisting confirm
we're sorry to see you go, why this,
why and then you've got to fill
out. It's not like that. And then,
and you will stop receiving email in six
to eight weeks. Yeah, some something.
Yeah. It's not like that
unsubscribed, done. Problem
solved. And then you can read,
subscribe. If you, it's totally up to you.
Empower yourself on the subscribing
situation. That's youtube.
Um, so yeah, some videos on there.
We'll um, we'll try to keep you,
yeah,
somewhat occupied on there. It was good
anyway. And also Jocko has a store,
it's called Jocko store,
Jocko store.com if you wear shirts and
you want to represent that way I think,
and we're going to put some new
shirts on there, some new stuff.
You know what I did,
what we did really is people
will listen to you Jocko.
I listened to you. But the
good thing about you is
actually, actually one of the,
one of the reasons that listen to you
is because he listened to me and you
listen to others, you know, we
visit the others. So people be like,
Hey Xyz,
make that into his shirt or you know,
hey you said make that into a shirt or
they'll just come up with their own thing,
you know, prioritize x out and
whatever and make it a shirt.
So during that listening.
Okay.
I kinda, we kinda just took it
to heart in a real general way.
And there's some new stuff. I like that.
Yeah. It's good. It's good options. Yeah.
But you can't, we can't make every shirt
that everything. No. And I just don't,
that wouldn't be practical.
No. Would it be, and some do.
I mean, I gotta be honest.
I say some cool stuff. Also say some dumb
stuff. Dumb stuff. Yeah. Or you know,
something that made be,
wouldn't translate onto a shirt that
someone would actually wear other than
maybe a handful of people.
Then we'll just say some short ideas
and make more sense than others.
We'll just say that. But
nonetheless, uh, we are,
and this is going to be a result of it
with some, you know, maybe some new stuff.
Oh, there's also some patches,
patches, the velcro ones and whatnot.
Um, hoodies, rash guards, performance.
I think we do another
crash guard design as well.
Not going to get rid of the old
one. The old ones. The current ones.
That one's dope to none. The
less, just more options. You know,
guys want to get after it
and have different looks,
maybe even have to in rotation that
looked different. Boom. So yeah,
we do that anyway.
All these things,
you can look at them if you like what you
see, one, two, three things, whatever,
however many things. Get it support that
way. Good way to support such a good way.
Yeah. Um, yeah. And, and
you're representing, so
it was kind of like, it's,
it's like an official way to kind
of just jump in the game, you know?
You know what I mean? I
do. I saw, remember, um,
ah, I dunno if, yeah, you met
him, right? Yeah, that's Sam.
He came in the gym and shaved head.
So he was just sitting there in the den,
in the lounge downstairs. I'm, I'm going
to get something to my car real quick.
I see. I see the shirt. Of
course I'm gonna say something.
But before I say anything,
I'm thinking in my mind,
look at this guy representing hard. And
the thing is, I don't know him. You know,
there's a guy I haven't met or whatever.
And you get that feeling
like that guy's representing.
And that's the feeling you get really,
you know when you see somebody in
the wild with it. Well, I actually,
speaking of that, I got a little story to
tell. Somebody hit me up and they said,
hey, I was out in the
wild, saw someone with uh,
with the Jocko podcast tee shirt on,
walked over to him through
the bone of fees on them.
Like you ever seen like a spy movie
where I come up and I say it is cold and
dark in the winter and the
person responds in March,
it will be warmer and now
we know we're going to go.
So what was the bone of fees?
This dude walked up to the other dude
with a trooper tee shirt on and he said,
good evening. I go and
boom. They knew what was up.
So I think that's become the official bone
of fees of Jocko podcast. Yeah. If you,
if you see someone who didn't
know wild well you know,
it might be a situation where
you can't just get crazy. Nope.
You just got to walk up and say
good evening echo and then they'll,
then you can do your burpees
and that.
That feeling is real though.
That feeling that I had when he,
when you see it it's like, ah, yeah.
You kind of know, you know. Anyway,
it's cool that way you'll have a
little added layer if you will.
Anyway. Also psychological warfare. If you
didn't know what psychological warfare,
this is what it is.
It's an album with tracks
and they're not music tracks.
They're not.
Jocko was hardcore band tracks.
Bronson's children's tracks.
It's not that.
What it is is little.
They're not even excerpts cause they're
just loan tracks for specific things and
those things are,
if you're feeling weakness at any point
while you're trying to consistently get
after it,
wake up early or workout or
stick to your mental QRF.
Quick Reaction Force. Yeah. Weakness
in your, yeah, here we go. Boom.
Call the QRF. Who they are. I
kind of look at it as like a spot,
you know like when it goes to those
people that don't lift a spot is when
someone helps you lift whatever
weight you're trying to lift and,
and not to split hairs, but really it's
not necessarily there to help you. It's,
I mean ultimately a help general med.
Sure. You don't go down. Yes, exactly.
So they're sleeping.
If you want to really get after,
if I'm going to work every single day,
no days off one year,
big,
big tall order right there.
Just like if I'm going to
bench this 10,000 pounds, what?
I'm going to make two videos a week,
I would have bench more
than I've mentioned before,
but I'm going to go from
go from my one rep Max.
It makes sense to have a spot.
You might get that one rep Max and not
need the spot, but it's there if you fail,
like if it's like too much or it feels
like too much with that guy, stand up,
just nudge you as much as you need.
That's really how,
this is just how I look at it.
Accurate. Yeah. Potentially right.
Based on what it is, is you put
the track on like, oh shoot,
I'm about to skip this workout. I'm about
to make this workout day a rest day.
No you're not. Yeah. You don't want
to do that. No. You can rest tomorrow,
today at work or rest on the day that you
have scheduled for rest for really new
thing.
Don't just impromptu make it arrested
cause you feel like it's not how it works.
If you need a little spot in doing that,
you listened to a track called workout,
get workout. I don't know. One of
the workouts spots cause there's,
there's a couple for workout,
there's one for waking up.
There's three for waking up. Yeah. See.
And there's one for kind of
sticking to the Diet plan, you know,
like there's that kind of stuff and um,
yeah,
you put it on and there's one for getting
for forcing yourself through creative
blocks. Yeah. Right. Which kind of
sounds like impossible, but you know,
tell you who it's possible.
I would say,
I will say that this will get you
through it 100% of the time. Like I,
I'm trying to imagine the
feeling that you would,
that would result in your heart if you
listen to this and you still skip the
workout thrall.
Yeah.
It's hard to fathom the
feeling you would have anyway.
It's very helpful and I'm
a real good spot, you know,
and it's chocolate talking to you.
So he's like kind of there with you.
You know that guy you want there.
That's my opinion anyway.
It's called psychological warfare. It's
on iTunes. So if you just do a search,
psychological warfare, Jocko Willink,
get that you can support that way.
But this is one where this is
real good support for yourself.
Make it your ringtone. Wake up, wake
up, call, clear it with your wife first.
You could have some problems. Spouses
do not like. Yeah, that's a good one.
And it happened.
Happens to be number one still on iTunes.
That's awesome.
Yup.
Since day one, by the way. Yes. That's,
thank you for the support and on that one.
Um, all right, while you're
on Amazon real quick,
this is a couple of things
I have to cover. Um,
I've legally have to do this
Jocko white tea. We're, we're,
it looks like we're gonna have to go put
a warning on it cause there's a little
situation going on. Got a uh, uh, uh,
trooper hit me up on Twitter and
this is what he said. Warning,
I started drinking Jocko t
and the wife became pregnant,
should be on the label.
So he was also wondering if the child
would arrive as a brown belt in Jujitsu.
Now to be honest with you, we should
have tested this further. You know,
we should have tested this further.
We didn't and we aren't a hundred
percent sure if babies produced under the
influence of Jocko white
tea will be a brown belt.
They will be a purple belt minimum
but they might not be a brown belt but
fertility.
Yup.
It's confirmed prenatal Jujitsu skills
confirmed and confirmed to the level of
about 147%. So order
the t make it, drink it,
it tastes so good.
It tastes like victory.
So you can get that.
You can,
you can also preorder where
the warrior kid book. Now,
Uncle Jake is trying to explain
to mark what a warrior is,
so he gives him a notebook that
has various warrior codes in it.
He's got the ranger creed,
he's got the seal code,
he's got the marine core core values.
He's got the the seven virtues of Bushido,
the Samurai Code.
He's got the code of Chivalry for nights.
He's got the Viking laws.
We've got all these like war your codes
in there so that young mark knows what
is up and we should all,
we can all kind of need to know
what is up with some of them.
The Vikings,
you know,
you might not thank you might think
yourself out viking laws. What you know,
what kind of liking teach me,
why would I need to know if viking loss,
how could I possibly get anything? So you
get way the warrior kitty, you order it.
You won't even start going
through the Viking laws.
Let me tell you what they say.
Viking laws,
be brave and aggressive.
Be Direct,
grab all opportunities,
use varying methods of attack.
Be Versatile and I agile
attack one target at a time.
Don't plan everything in detail.
Use Top quality weapons.
Be prepared. Keep weapons in
good condition. Keep in shape.
Find good battle comrades.
Agree on important points.
Choose one chief,
be a good merchant.
Find out what the market needs.
Do not promise what you can't keep.
Do not demand overpayment arranged
things so that you can return.
Keep the camp in good order.
Okay.
Keep things tidy and organized,
arranged enjoyable activities
that strengthen the group.
Make sure everybody does useful work.
Consult all members of
the group for advice.
Hey, this viking laws, 1200 years old,
is there anything you might be able
to get out of that? Yes, absolutely.
We can all take something away from that.
So
bunch of warrior codes in
there and by the way, mark,
he ends up writing his own
war. Your kid code. Yeah. Yeah.
Kind of kid code that I wish I would have
lived by. You know what I'm saying? Yes.
It's going to help some people out.
Also just released.
We got the discipline equals
freedom field manual coming.
This is what you were asking for a book.
It pretty much represents what we
talk about this on this podcast.
Faults and action.
The thoughts are aligned with
what you hear on this podcast.
The actions are more detailed than what
I say on the podcast. More granular,
more specific workouts of food intake,
martial arts.
So disappointing because field
discipline equals freedom field manual.
You can get some of that.
You can also pick up a couple of
copies of extreme ownership of course.
Okay.
Lessons of combat leadership that
we talk about on this podcast.
By the way from Henry the fifth to HR
McMaster spans a pretty good time and
those lessons of combat
leadership translate to
business and life and the laid
out in extreme ownership
very simply and very clearly.
So what you do is you order one for you
and then you order one for everyone in
your chain of command up
and down, get some monster,
May 4th and fifth the New York
City Marriott Marquis Register now,
book your hotel booking travel, come
and get it. You know it's morning PT.
That's where we start with full days
of leadership training, leadership,
discussion, Q and a lot of Q
and a. Also just hanging out.
We're going to, we're going to be
sitting there with you, eaten lunch,
eaten breakfast,
whatever life's going to be there.
Jp is going to be there.
Dave Burke,
who's coming on the podcast
is also going to be there.
A bunch of you all are
going to be there at,
it's one of the best things
about his meet and everybody.
Then of course echo is going to be there.
We knew that cruisy he's
going to be cruising
so
okay,
come on to that.
We're in the game in that and we're gonna
be in the game with you getting stuff
solved and while you're waiting for that,
if you want to get in the game with us
now you can find us on the inner webs in
front of some Twitter, Instagram and
I'm going to be on that Facebooky.
We're there to echo is that Echo
Charles and I am at Jocko Willink
and thanks for listening to this podcast.
Thanks for supporting the podcast.
We appreciate it.
We're glad we have you out there in
the game with us and to the military
personnel that are out
in the field right now
in harm's way.
Protecting freedom around the world.
Thank you
to the police and law enforcement
that are out on the streets right now,
protecting us from criminals.
Thank you.
And of course, to the firefighters, EMT,
and other first responders that are
waiting right now for us to call when an
emergency takes place.
Thank you.
And everyone else that is out there
doing your best builders and biologists,
farmers and framers,
scientists and sales reps,
engineers and educators.
Okay.
Leaders and front line sled dogs.
Thanks to all of you for
taking ownership of your life,
for being the discipline and for
getting out there into the world with a
clenched jaw in a furrowed brow.
Okay.
And getting after it.
So until next time,
this is echo and Jocko
out.