This is Jocko podcast number
99 with Echo Charles and me,
Jocko Willink. Good
Evening Echo. Good evening.
It is a day for Q and. A. Let's
go right into it. All right,
let's do it Jocko. Hey Jocko. As the
director of our sales department,
I require my guys to fill out
sales call interaction logs.
I have one guy who thinks
because the sales are up,
this no longer is important,
nor does he have the time.
How did you handle situations like this?
Okay, so as I got this question mark,
okay, I've answered this before,
I'm not going to answer it again.
I've gotten something close enough
and you know it's interesting,
I talked to some people now, I talked
to a lot of people and they say, hey,
you know on a Q and a, I know what
you're going to say. Yeah. You know,
and I'm like, Oh yeah, that's awesome.
They say, I still need to hear it. Sure.
But I know what you're going to say
and I should. Okay, cool. That's good.
That means, you know, people
are are starting to expand
their brain a little bit.
Maybe. See a different perspective
that they might not have had before,
so that's good in my opinion right now.
Also,
what I realized is as you mentioned,
as I answered these questions,
there's additional information,
right? That comes out.
Once you make a certain
level of understanding,
then there's more understanding to be
had and so that's what I realized with
this question as I thought, well, okay,
there's the standard answer, right?
The standard answer is okay that you got
people in there not doing what you want
them to do and what do you do then?
Well,
the fact is the real standard answer
that everybody now knows if you've been
listening to podcasts is they need to
know why they're doing what they're doing.
They need to know why it's important.
They need to know how them filling out
those forms will help the company and
therefore help the individual that needs
to fill out the forms because it'll
provide better intel with to the company
that will provide them more accurate
advertising, which will in turn
make them be able to sell more,
which will in turn make the
cost to produce the product.
Go down because they're selling more
and that means he has better pricing to
sell things with and he'll be able
to sell more and make more money.
And so you have to tie
that whole thread through.
That's kind of the standard answer,
which everybody should know.
If someone's not doing
what you want them to do,
you need to make sure they understand why
they need to do it, why it's important,
how it ties back to them. Okay, so boom,
we get done with that standard answer.
Now there's the next level.
Right now we're going to purple belt
and,
and here's the nonstandard answer.
Here's the advanced dancer with a
purple belt. The answer is, okay,
now let's ask yourself this piece of
paper that you're having them fill out.
Is it really actually important?
Is it actually important?
What purpose does it actually serve?
Because you're,
you want this guy who's a,
who's a good producer,
his sales are up and you want him
to continue to fill out these sales
interaction logs so that you can and
make sure that he's making enough calls,
that he's got to write the right approach,
that he's using the right verbiage when
he's talking to his customers or clients.
And so you want him to fill this out,
but now he's actually doing well and
you got to ask yourself like, okay,
what purpose is this thing serving
now that the guy is doing well,
what purpose is it serving? Maybe at a
certain level you say, you know what?
You don't need to fill that out anymore.
If you'd sell 10 units a day,
you don't need to fill this out anymore.
If you sell eight a day,
you've got to fill out your logs because
we got to check and see what you're
doing.
That's,
or are you just making this person do
it because that's what everyone does.
So if you can't, if you can't answer the
question yourself, why it's important,
then maybe you should check the
why you have this thing in place.
So again,
we put things in place to help people,
but at a certain point it is possible
that they don't need to do it anymore.
The some salespeople,
if you don't,
maybe you want people to make eight phone
calls a day and you want them to log
down what they did,
okay?
What if this guy is doing 28 phone calls
a day and he wants to get to 38 phone
calls a day, but he can't because
he's filling out your paperwork, okay?
So if people are meeting the numbers,
maybe raise the bar a little bit,
make him and you give him more freedom.
He's got the self discipline,
right?
He's got the discipline to make call.
He's making the numbers is numbers are up.
Okay,
give us more freedom.
Maybe can turn that into more production.
If he starts to lag off, guess what? Hey
Bud, if you keep selling 10 units a day,
we're good. You don't need to fill
out this crap. You go to nine,
you're back on the back on
the filling out of paperwork.
Guess what he's going to do?
You're going to sell 10 every day,
is going to sell 12 going to sell 15 and
then I would tell him, I'd say he, look,
if you sell 15 units a day,
I'm going to fill out a piece of
paperwork that says you're awesome dude.
Every time you sell 15
units, boom. Little Fun.
Yeah. So that's it. There's,
there's the, there's the white,
maybe three stripe white belt answer.
Everyone should know at this
point followed by a little
bit more advanced purple
belt move Ooma Plata
at the same time.
That's not to say that it's
guaranteed, not important. Not at all.
You just see and make
that evaluation at all.
And there there is a chance
that I'm wrong, right?
That the paperwork that gets filled out
actually really does get put into a data
file that can then be
used to, to, you know,
target certain customers that
follow up with certain customers.
And if that's the fact you explain it
to the guy and how it's going to benefit
them. And we're back to answer number one,
which worked, which is fine. Yeah know,
right and wrong,
right and wrong are interesting concepts
and people sometimes get wrapped around
right and wrong and they just think that
there's a right answer and there's a
answer and many times neither question
or neither answer is right or wrong or
both answers are right and wrong.
So you got to open your mind
on these things. You got to
open your mind. You know,
it was, as we talked about with
Jujitsu schools, should a judge,
should a Jujitsu school be
strict bow to your professor?
Everyone wear the same uniform?
I'm not allowed to ask people
to role or should it be, hey,
where whatever you want the instructor's
named Jocko and go in there and crews
and train heart. Which one is right? The
answers, they're both right. You can.
Both of those have benefits and some
people flourish in one kind of school and
some people flourish and and other kind
of school and you can't say one's right
or wrong.
Same thing.
I used to run in this a lot with
in the seal teams with tactics,
like should we enter the
room like this or like this?
And the answer is actually, well,
which is better in that scenario.
And sometimes this one's veterans,
sometimes that one's better.
And so if your mind can be more open,
you'll be able to use more options,
which is beneficial.
Yeah,
that's the narrow kind of
reminded me of one of my,
who was a friend of a friend and it was
actually my friend's friend's wife and
she was saying,
yeah,
she's kind of making light of the fact
that they force their kids to watch a
charger game or something
on this day or whatever.
And the kids don't like football
or the kid, the one kid don't like,
doesn't like football.
It doesn't like watching football
doesn't like this whole thing. She,
and she was like, oh no, it's an, it's
a tradition, you know, so you know,
we make them do it. It's the tradition,
all this stuff. I'm kind of thinking like,
okay, I mean that's cool that it's like
your tradition, but like no one likes it.
Like, so what is the
tradition doing? I mean,
I understand like if you have a tradition,
everyone likes it or the
tradition and it improves.
Like I don't know if the cohesion of
the family in or something like that and
you know, for all these beneficial reasons
and one way or another beneficiary,
but if you're doing it just
for the sake of, you know,
the tradition,
like this paperwork situation
and also what are you doing if
you're telling your kid like, no,
you'll watch the football game.
Yeah.
Especially now that everyone hates the
chargers because they left San Diego
sometime ago.
But if you tell your kid,
hey,
no,
it's a time for our family to get together
and you don't got to watch the game
but hang out, we're going to have some
hot dogs. Yeah. You know what I mean? And,
and we're just,
that's what it is.
It's not about staring at the screen
watching something that you don't like.
Yeah. It's about hanging out.
You know, grandma's coming
over, auntie's coming over,
we're going to cruise, we're going
to eat barbecued chicken, right? Yup.
That's different than, hey, you sit
down and watch the football game. Yeah.
But when kids reach a certain age,
they don't want to hang out with
you for a certain time period.
That's what started my whole argument
right there. It wasn't an argument,
but that's what started my little
discourse at a certain time period.
Your children are supposed to
rebel against you? Yeah,
somewhat. Cause they,
cause they have to convince themselves in
their mind that they're going to leave,
they're going to be on their
own and something in their
mind triggers that to be
like,
okay,
I need to separate myself from these
other humans that have been caring for me
since I was wearing diapers and now I
need to get that out of my head and figure
out how to survive on my own. So they do
that by rebelling against you and said,
I don't wash this stupid football game.
Yeah.
I want to go to my friend Mary's house.
We're going to do something
over there. Right. That's, yeah.
Do you think that there's
an element of like a pro,
you know how like when you're
a kid and you hit like 1312,
13 years old, you start to get this
like empowered feeling, you know,
cause you're like physically kind of
growing up and then your parents are kind
of,
you have the feeling of oppression,
not that your parents are the
pretzels things are totally,
that's exactly what I'm saying. I'm like
it's those like an actual rebellion.
Like you can oppress me no more.
Don't have to ride with you. You know,
I don't have to walk with you
in the mall. No, I'm out. Yeah.
And you're trying to do that cause you
realize subconsciously that these people
are not going to be here.
I need to learn how to fend for myself.
I need to get out of the nest, get out
of them, start flapping them wings.
But yeah, exactly right.
But the tradition, just for
the sake of the tradition,
because actually my whole argument with
the lady was that you was trying to,
not necessarily prove but try to find
out whether or not she even thought about
it. Like, why you [inaudible]
traditions that are important, right.
Within a family, within a culture.
But if you lose fact, if you lose,
if you don't understand the
meaning of the tradition, yeah.
Then it doesn't make sense to you. Yeah.
So then you don't care about it. Yeah.
But if you say, hey look, this is our
family and this is when we get together.
This is the only time it's her
tradition, so we're gonna do it. Yeah.
And that way we get to know each other
and that week we keep connected. You know,
we can help each other.
Cohesion, cohesion.
Next question Jocko.
As a leader,
at what point am I allowed
to go to others and say,
I need you because I recognize I'm not
capable of pushing toward forward on my
own.
Or should that be an instance where I
need to take a step back and apply more
discipline to my life and find a
way to push forward by myself. Okay.
You are allowed to say that to your team
member immediately that you need them.
Absolutely.
If you,
of course you need your team because
if you didn't need your team,
why would they be there?
If you can do everything yourself,
then you don't have a team, right?
You just do everything yourself.
So while you of course
should be working harder,
you should be applying
discipline as a leader.
It's your job to actually lead things
and to let other people support and make
things happen.
And there's nothing wrong with that.
And also you don't want to be stuck
in the weeds doing minute thing. So
if you're not capable, I think what
might be holding this individual back,
there's two things.
Number one is I feel like I should take
extreme ownership of everything. Yeah.
I feel like I should just
do everything myself.
That is not what extreme ownership is.
Extreme ownership isn't
doing everything yourself.
And also what can come into play is
your ego because you don't want to ask
people for help and
that's not a good sign.
There's nothing wrong with asking
people for help if you need it. In fact,
that's the humble thing to do.
Hey Echo,
I don't know how to quite
finish out this. Uh, you know,
this thing of this project and working
out. Can you give me a hand with us?
I don't know how to work a video recorder.
Can you show me how to do that, right?
Whatever. Um, so, so there's no problem
with that. You're allowed to ask. You can,
you can say that immediately.
In fact,
your team should feel that you are
counting on them and relying on them.
They should know that. And then
put your ego aside. Ask for help.
No problem.
That doesn't mean you're giving away.
That doesn't mean you're
not taking ownership.
not applying discipline.
It means you're working as a team
together to accomplish a mission. Again,
if a t if a, if a mission is so easily
that you can accomplish it yourself,
you don't need a team,
why do you have them?
If you can do it all yourself
just by applying discipline, cool.
You don't need anyone else if you're,
but your mission should be larger
than one human being can accomplish.
So that's why you have other people
on board to help you out. No problem.
You know, like, I always think when I
thought we made it out of that question,
go ahead. Nope. But you know,
like let's say it's like something that's
just a pain in the ass and you don't
really need help, but you just don't want
to do it by yourself. Oh, okay. I'm then,
yeah, the then you gotta just do
it yourself. Yourself. Yeah. Yeah.
So that's kind of where this is coming
from ultimately, because it's like,
I'm not saying that if you're the,
if you're,
if you have a position in a company
where you shouldn't be doing some sort of
task because it's not
financially efficient to have,
you know,
a person that's making $150,000 a year
doing a task that someone that's making
$10 an hour should be doing so.
So you shouldn't do that.
That's not what I'm advocating
and accompany won't,
won't be doing well if you're paying
people $150,000 a year that you can get
someone to do for $10 an hour.
I'm not saying that,
so don't get me wrong.
Yeah.
But that's why we have a team so that
you can focus on going forward and
whatever it is you need to be focused
on and somebody that's below you in the
chain of command,
that's a member of your team
that's getting paid $10 an
hour can do some of this
stuff that you need
them to do. Yeah. Yeah.
And the question actually is really
clear because it's because quote unquote,
because I recognize I'm not capable of
pushing, you know, it's kind of like,
it's obvious to you that you need
help. It's not that you're, you know,
raking leaves and I don't want to do
this all by myself, so hey, you know,
you tell your brother come help.
It's not that it's different.
Yeah. If you need to get
to the leaves raked and,
and you need them done by Monday so you
can get them in the bags so that the
dump truck can come and take the leaves
away and you can't physically get it
done. Then your, you said to your brother,
Hey, can you give me a hand on you?
You get these done tonight
before the sun goes down.
I'm not going be able to make it in
time. Can you give me a hand? Yeah.
Your brother says absolutely.
Oh yeah. Got Your back. Next question.
What's the best way to deal with feedback?
You don't agree with my manager?
Give my manager,
gives me feedback on my personality
that I don't agree with.
I'm only in the company five months and
he doesn't know enough about me to make
the comments he's making.
I find myself wanting a con wanting
to contest with what he's saying,
but I believe this will
ultimately end poorly for me.
It's frustrating for me to
listen to feedback from him
about my personality when
my friends and family
would disagree with him.
Okay.
Again,
this is one of those questions that I
think people that listen to podcast and
know what the answer is, what you do
when someone's giving you feedback,
as you listen to it and you
try and make adjustments,
get in their head and figure
out where this is coming from.
They're obviously saying
this for some reason,
and maybe the reason is because they
have a big ego or they don't understand
people very well, and that's
fine. And if you know that,
then you just learned
something about them.
But also you might not know yourself
as well as you think you do.
And,
and obviously if you can test with someone
saying you're going to look like you
can't take critique, so you're right,
that's not a good approach to take.
Furthermore,
what you're saying is that your friends
and family wouldn't agree with this guy.
Well, guess what? They're your
friends and family, right?
It's like the dude's mom that,
you know,
the dude's mom always thinks the dude's
handsome, right? Losing on handsome,
but his mom thinks he's handsome and he's,
you know,
your friends and family think, oh I, I
can't believe they'd say that about you.
Well that's your friends and family.
There's a reason why you have
friends because they like you, they,
whatever purse part of
your personality is,
is not cool. They're over
it. Or they can deal with it.
Well this, this boss, the
manager can't deal with it.
His know how to deal with it yet.
So like I said,
when someone gives you a critique,
you should actually listen to what
people have such a hard time with.
And you should actually listen and say,
okay, well maybe I'm too aggressive.
Maybe I'm too close minded. Whatever,
whatever critique point you're getting,
listen to them. Maybe someone's like, Hey,
I don't think you take critique very well.
And you're like,
what are you talking about? Of course I
take critique. Well you don't know what.
That's what, that's my point.
So, and the other thing, like
I said, isn't doing this.
The managers actually telling you
something about their personality and,
and their views,
their judgment.
So learn from that.
Learn what they're pretty,
they're teaching you
about their personality,
which is going to help you better
influence and nippy late and work with.
Work with that person in the future and
perhaps help make them into a better
leader and a better supporter of
what it is that you're trying to do.
So calm down, relax. One of the
best things you can do when someone,
when someone says to you, Hey, I think
you're screwing this up as I call it.
Hold on, let me, let me,
let me grab a notebook.
I just want to take notes and make sure
I understand where you're coming from so
I can, I can make some adjustments.
I'm always looking to get better.
That might be a little extreme,
but you know, yeah, no,
hold on a second. Let me
get my notebook. Yeah,
so I can take notes because
I want to get better.
I over did that just a little bit.
Tell him. Yeah, but not some people,
some new, they'll take notes,
taking notes like, oh, when I was,
when I was running the west coast
seal training, the, the good officers.
Like there'd be some officers when
when I'd be putting out word to them,
they'd be taking notes and I was eating,
when I first saw it,
it was kind of like
surprise me. Yeah. Um, okay.
This guy is just straight up taking
notes on what I'm telling you is a one on
one conversation, but he's, he's
sitting there like taking notes.
But if you said it with your
tone would be like, hold on.
All jock was going to say something.
Let me get out my notebook. Oh No. Yeah,
that's sarcastic. Yeah. But there's
also not just being sarcastic.
I was leaning towards more like the
Brown noser. Oh, that guy. Oh, Echo.
You're going to give you some feedback.
Hold on one second.
I want to get my notes out so I can make
sure I do exactly what you're telling
me to do.
Thanks buddy.
I see again with the tone
that was the middle way.
The middle ground I
think. Yeah. Who is it?
Sarah Armstrong I think pointed out on
Twitter something about tone and body
language in some psychological survey
makes up more than half of what is
actually being said. Yeah. And I heard
that too. Um, and I was like, hey,
that sounds cool. But I
mean, you know, maybe,
maybe not because if someone says
something that's pretty clear but then I,
it's kind of stuck with me and it's true.
I could literally say the same like
I dunno 10 words to you in all these
different tones and that would mean
10 different things. Oh for sure.
Like you can like
it's actually baffling in surprising
how much we can actually communicate.
Like if I, if I make a joke to
you like something you don't know,
my level of sarcasm, you don't know
necessarily, you have to know the person,
you know.
So there's all these things that that
have to be in place for you to effectively
be communicated to.
So like let's say you overhear
a conversation in the next room.
Like you could easily miss the whole
point of the conversation even though you
heard every word because you
didn't know if they're joking.
You didn't know if they're serious.
You didn't know if one guy's mad.
You know if one guy's getting
school district and they
can take the same exit or
they can say the same exact words,
but they're just saying different
things coming from different places.
You end up a lot of communication
problems with email where someone emails a
joke.
Yeah,
joking about something and then someone
takes it seriously and next thing you
know,
people are flying off the handle.
I always had that rule in my
seal platoons and tasking do.
You weren't allowed to joke on the
radio and the main reason for that rules
cause you,
you don't want other people outside your
organization to hear it and take it the
wrong way. Same thing, but
at the same thing with email.
Unless you know someone really, really
well, really, really well, you better.
It's better to keep the sarcastic comments
and just be straightforward and speak
plainly when you're an email, when you're
communicating with people, it's a lot.
It's a lot easier. And then even with
that probably has no escape from this.
Even with that,
you could easily come off as like
too rigid or Dang is this guy,
does this guy not like me? You know like
that's your second email. And he's like,
that's why communication is important.
That's why learning how to
write well is important.
That's why little words that you put
in matter into phrases, into sentences,
they matter. Make a difference.
Thus the invention of emojis.
Emojis. No, you're very into emojis and
I sometimes I I,
I must say that I think you communicate
very well with emojis because even
though you don't sometimes
use any words in a text to me,
I fully understand what you
mean by lightening bolt.
Lightning bolt, lightning bolt, rainbow,
rainbow, lightening bolt, thumbs up,
chocolate fires. Shaka fire. Very
clear, right? Yeah, no I yeah,
yeah I agree. Yeah I agree
with that. Shock. A fire.
I forgot about fire. You do
quite a bit of fire. Yeah,
the lightening bolt and fire a
youth and then the shotgun for sure.
And the room with you.
I use a rainbow a lot cause
they got to lighten up the mood.
It seems like a child thing. I don't
like emoticons. I don't like emojis.
But you're kind of like that in real
life too though. I know, but it's,
it seems like to me it's,
yeah, it's like a kid.
Maybe your little daughter would do it.
Well my daughter will send me
875 emojis from my wife's phone.
All of them see if she can fill up and
I sent back. Okay. Yeah, yeah. See,
but you're like that in real life too
though. That's the thing. Like if you,
like if you, you know that you're running
the risk of sounding too like, you know,
like stoic or whatever,
you know, like if you,
if you have to answer a question with
yes when, whatever the question is,
it's a yes or no question and you
answer yes affirmatively right it,
you'll put yes. Period. And that'll
come off as like God talk was like,
I don't know what this guy is serious
or something, you know, instead of yes.
Point yes.
Two exclamation points. Lightening Bolt,
fire rainbow or something like that.
That gives away a little bit more
like, you know, you're just like, yes.
It's as if you're just looking someone in
their eye going, yes, that's it. I know.
That's what I'm saying.
You're really like that in real life
most of the time. Right on. Anyway.
Lightening Bolt, fire. Yeah man.
Let's emojis in there. Don't over do
it. Double Shocker. Shocker. Yeah.
What's the highest level of a moot
Emoji approval? You can send me
three lightening bolts. Three fires,
three shockers, three rainbows.
For sure.
Three of everything you do go for.
It's like you shouldn't do
for four Don Murray, you know?
Depends on what I say though. So
like if there's, if it's a word,
the vowel in the word will,
they'll be like, that's,
that can be infinite or what do you like
if I put it, I don't know, you know,
like you'll tell me something exciting
and I'll put it on and off, but Dang,
instead of Dan g, I'll put d, lowercase a,
depending on the level of excitement, Ei,
EI, that can go infinitely by the way,
that can spend 20 text messages even over
20 days because that's how infinite it
can be. Then the first half
of the A's and lowercase,
the second half of the are
uppercase, the end, maybe 10 ends.
Geez. All capital. Then you
know, then, so it depends.
It just depends on it. Just like I said,
I think you communicate well. Yeah, that's
what I'm saying on a, on a serious note,
in regards to communication that
is effective, you know what I mean?
You can sense my level of excitement
as opposed to cool. Period.
No, you're, you're,
you were your quick fix.
Like,
anyway,
next question if you're
ready. All right. Sorry.
No, no. All good. Here is a
good mood. I guess the rainbow
does things dearest Jocko.
Speaking of lighthearted,
uh,
nice emotions dearest Jocko.
Oh,
okay. My bad, my bad, my bad. Jocko.
What is the difference between extreme
ownership versus the easy button?
Can you elaborate?
I just need a little more clarification
to connect the dots in my situation.
Okay. Again, so as a leader, yes,
of course you are supposed to
take ownership of everything.
Extreme ownership of everything.
That's what we talk about all the time.
But does this mean that you say,
I
will do this and I will do that and I
will do the other thing and I will do
everything that the team is
supposed to be doing? No,
that's not what I'm talking about.
Now ownership does mean
that you get things done.
You are responsible for making sure
things get done. That's what ownership is.
It as our team is in charge of something.
If our team is in charge of a project and,
and we don't get it done,
it's my fault. It's not anybody else's
fault. So that's, that's what it is.
It means you take responsibility
when things go wrong.
for problems and you get them fixed.
That's definitely ownership.
Now,
the easy button and when I talk about
the easy button in a negative way,
because that's what I'm doing here,
it's when your subordinates
come to you and say,
how should I do this? Or, or what's the
best way to execute this? Or can you,
can you tell me a good plan on how
we should make this happen? Or even,
hey,
there's bad news.
Can you come tell my people because
I don't really want to do it. Now.
If you say yes to those types
of things on a regular basis,
then what you're doing is you're actually,
you're actually stunting the growth of
your subordinate leader because instead
when you come to me and you say,
Hey Jocko, we've got this semester,
we've got a plan. How do you think
we should do it? If I say, okay,
we should come in from the
north, you should, you know,
set up an Overwatch position here.
You should move to the target from this
direction. You didn't learn anything.
You just took what I told
you. It's not. I say, well go,
come up with your best plan and
come back to me and brief me on it.
And so now you might be kind of bummed
out because you wanted, you didn't have,
want to have to do this extra work,
but now you've got to go
do a little extra work.
But now you're learning
and in two or three times,
you're not even come to ask me any more.
You're going to come with a plan.
And because we already did a cycle
cycle after cycle of you saying, Hey,
here's my plan and be saying,
hey,
make this adjustment and you come back
next time you say, here's my plan.
I said make this little adjustment.
And eventually, you know,
to make those adjustments on your own
and now you can do it by yourself.
And that's what we want.
I don't want to stunt the growth
of my subordinate leaders,
so I don't want to be an easy button.
Um,
so you're providing the easy button,
like that's what they're talking
about when they see easy button. Yeah.
If you didn't want to be that you don't
want to be an easy button for everybody
else. And I also, no one's going to
be able to take your job from you,
which is actually what you want.
You want.
I want to make every one
of my subordinates so good
that they can take my job
from me.
That means I can step up and look forward
and look out and they can do a better
job of handling what
they've got to handle.
And eventually when it's
my time to get promoted,
I got people to take my
place and we're all good. Um,
of course that doesn't mean leave them
blind or let them fail. Don't do that.
Give you want to give them rope,
but you don't give them enough
rope to hang themselves.
You give them enough rope that they may
be get a little not in the rope and it
gives a little bit sloppy and you,
and then you go over to me and say,
there's a lot here.
Let me help you get that untied.
And now you give them the rope again
so you don't eat. You know, in, in, uh,
in the military,
you don't let someone go do a mission
that's real where someone's gonna get
killed or mission failure because you
want it to not be the easy button. No,
you don't do that in the civilian sector.
You don't let someone lose a big client
or lose a bunch of money or make a
mistake that costs a bunch of capital
because you didn't want to be the easy
button. No, no ums. Now might you let
someone make a little mistake? Sure.
Little mistake that cost them
a little bit of money. Sure.
So they learned a lesson. Sure. Yeah,
but you don't let them fall on your face.
You don't let them hang or hang
themselves. So that's that.
Next question.
Dearest Jocko,
a question for you and the podcast.
Our Fire Department promotion process
has role playing scenarios and those role
playing scenarios. I lose points
because I'm not outwardly passionate,
quote unquote,
you know,
I would have to fake it to
succeed and I'm not a fake person.
Is this worth it to fake
it when seeking promotion.
It's not like I'm going to fake
it once they attain the promotion.
Okay, great. This is a, this
is a very cool question.
I like this question a lot and actually
on this guy sent me this question on
Facebook,
I responded very quickly
and simply my response was,
play the game. Yeah, so
fake. You play the game and,
and you know what he wrote
back? Got It. Good for him.
Because what everybody I think
thinks I'm going to say is that no,
you don't yourself. No,
you don't play the game.
You're not going to get up there and act
all passionate about stuff. You're you,
you're hardcore. No. Play the game
now you, because what you're doing,
you play the game.
You want to do good job and you're doing
your job and doing your job. To me,
any job requires some level of faking it.
Yeah. Now, does this mean
that you're a fake person? No.
It means that you're
trying to do a good job. I
think if every time that your boss
came in with a dumb idea and you,
your reaction was to say,
that's a dumb idea.
Is that going to get you anywhere or
every time a customer had an idiot, idiot,
idiotic complaint about something,
you were like, hey, you're an idiot.
Or every time your wife said,
you know,
is this chicken dry?
And you said it's dryer than a piece of
cardboard in the Sahara desert. Is that,
is that easy? You know, art, would
you, would you benefit from that?
How would that work out you?
The answers you would,
he would not work out well in any of
those cases. You have to play the game.
You have to play the game.
And I know,
I know that that's hard.
And I'll tell you what I did to
get myself over playing the game.
I turned it into a game in my head.
I was like,
I'm going to build a relationship
with this boss that I don't like.
I'm going to do it. Yeah. I'm going
to build the best relate. That's my,
I'm going to go,
I'm going to become this guy's bro.
Right when I was at
officer candidate school,
you got to do the most ridiculous rules.
They have these rules that you've got
to follow that were really annoying and
you know what I did?
I,
I executed the rules harder
and more stringently than,
than anybody thought was even remotely
necessary and had fun with it.
I played that game. I, you know,
if I've got a peer that may be, um,
competing with, or there's some tension,
I'm going to support them. I'm going to
play the game. That's what I'm saying.
You got to play the game. Now does this
make me a bad person or a fake person? No.
Why? Because you're doing this,
the reason you're playing the game,
the reason your act as acting this
way is for benevolent reasons,
right? This, this guy
at the fire department,
he's not trying to get promoted so that
he can usurp the powers and then take
over.
No,
he tried to get into a position where
he can better lead and serve and,
and step up and raise young leaders
underneath them that that's what you're
trying to do.
You're not trying to sneak into a
position you don't deserve and you're not
trying to build relationships so you can
take advantage of people for your own
benefit that that would be
a fake person in my opinion.
You're trying to move,
but if you're trying to move up in rank
so you can do better and you can take
care of the troops and you
can increase readiness,
there's nothing wrong with that.
And if you don't play the
game to us at some level,
you're not going to get promoted.
And guess what?
Then people that played the
game that might be less,
less qualified to do that job,
they're going to get the job
because you wouldn't play the game.
You're too stubborn.
Your ego is too big.
So you got to put that aside and
I'll tell you something else.
Learn from what you're being told.
If if you're showing no passion,
if you're showing like zero motion,
that's bad.
People will not connect with you.
And if they don't connect with you,
they don't follow you.
If they don't connect with you, you're
not building relationships with people.
If you don't have relationships with
people, you don't have a good team.
So show a little bit of passion.
Sometimes you gotta fake it. That's fine.
You're just a really unpassionate person.
Cool. Show a little bit of passion,
fake it a little bit,
learn it a little bit cause it's
actually going to be beneficial.
I would love for you to fake it
for a little while until you're,
you start caring. Like what are
you are not passionate about?
Are you not passionate about the job?
Are you not passionate about,
you're a firefighter about saving people's
lives are you're not passionate about
having a squared away department? Of
course you're passionate about that stuff.
Otherwise you wouldn't be, you wouldn't
be sending me a message saying, hey,
how do I get advanced? How
do I do? How do I do better?
You are passionate about
it and that's fine. It's
good. Um, I say it all the time. You know,
if you don't have any emotions
that you're a robot and robots,
people don't fall robots,
immune cell.
Sometimes you got to show a little bit
of that emotion and passion to connect
with people. And that's okay. Yeah. Don't
be scared, homey. Yeah. Don't be scared.
Yeah. Cause that's
really the thing, right,
is showing it of course you're passionate
about but showing it because different
people, they know
something. Brian, I dig it.
I don't want to always be like showing
how fired up I am all the time or
whatever in whatever scenario, whatever.
But you're right, that does help. Yeah.
Like when he was excited about it.
And there's a,
there's a dichotomy here because there's
some people that will show too much
emotion and there's some people
that will not show enough.
So you want to be somewhere bounced
in the middle. Yeah. Yeah. It's true.
And I dig it too when,
cause it does feel like faking it because
like in football that tradition is
like to be fired up on the sidelines.
Let's go, let's go, let's go. You know,
like that kind of,
but probably sometimes you don't have
the energy for that and sometimes you're
kind of just nervous and you want to
focus on what you got to do or whatever,
you know. But it's kind of part
of the game, you know? And,
and it does help the people around you
too. And he's like, okay, he's fired up.
Okay. Maybe I'm not fired up now, but he's
kind of getting me fired up, you know?
And it kind of like helps
the team. Yeah. But yeah,
sometimes it doesn't feel that comfortable
to do express outwardly. You know,
how passionate, but it helps.
Plus this fake like faking it.
That's like a framing thing too.
You know how like if you frame it like
you're faking it versus how you said
you're playing the game,
right.
You're playing the game because
you want to do a better job. Yeah.
Want to get promoted. You
want to, you want to get
promoted for the right reasons.
Yeah. There's nothing wrong with that.
Yeah. That's that. Yeah. That's good.
I think if you can kind of
bend and stretch yourself
in an uncomfortable way for
the benefit, you know, I, you
know, I think where people,
I think that term of faking it, no
one wants to be a fake person, right?
Yes. Which, which is why
you're correct in that.
The way that's framed is I'm being a
fake person and no one wants to be a fake
person. Yeah. At the same time,
you have to grow and you have to adjust.
And if you're going to be
in a leadership position,
you're Gunna do things that you don't,
that you wouldn't have planned.
I do that all the time. I mean, when
I was in the military, you know,
I worked with people that I, you
know, I've said this before I could,
where I work with people both below me,
the chain of command and up above me in
the chain of command that I despised.
They never knew it. They don't
know who they are right now. Dang.
But you know what? Remember that? What
does that make me a fake person? No,
it makes me a professional.
Makes me a professional at doing my
job because I wasn't gonna get let some
little personal emotion of mind or some,
oh that guys does this and I don't like
that, so I'm not going to like him.
And now we have an adversarial
relationship and now we've
got a problem. Yeah, no,
I'm playing the game. Play
the game. So where's the line?
What is a fake person? Genuinely,
well, I was going to say,
you asked me what the line is.
The line is if you go against what
your principles are, you know,
so if you've got fundamental principles
that they say, Oh, if you want this job,
but what we need to you to do is fill
out a report about Billy saying that he
did something wrong, that
you know he didn't do wrong.
Right? And then you go, no,
I'm not going to do that. That,
that, that's what, that's bad. Right?
That's not now you're not
just playing the game.
Now you're going against
your principles of being a,
an honest person about what's happening.
Yeah. That's really what it is. Right?
Like the honesty when you're a faker. So
like if someone's like, oh, I'm faking it,
or I'm being a fake person.
How you sit in a fake person,
like turning on some passion,
some manufactured passion for the
sake of the team and stuff like that.
That doesn't feel like you're
a fake person, fake person.
It's kind of like you'll sit like some,
I dunno for example,
someone's in the room and
you're like, hey, you're great.
That shirt looks great and you're doing a
great job. They leave and be like, fuck,
I suck so bad. The reason I'll tell you
the difference, the reason that someone,
the reason that you would consider
someone and be angry that someone's a fake
person is when they are doing it because
they're doing it for personal benefit.
Oh yeah. They're, they're
saying like if, if, if,
if you were my boss and I
come in and I say, hey echo,
I really like your new haircut.
It looks great.
I don't really think that
your haircut looks done,
but I'm going to say that
anyways and everyone knows that.
All I want to do is get that next
promotion. Yeah. That's being fake. Yeah.
Makes Sense. Being fake.
But if, if I'm saying, well,
cause what am I really doing?
What I'm doing is I'm, I'm,
I'm making an adaptation.
I'm growing.
I'm,
I'm doing something that I'm uncomfortable
with because I know it's gonna make
me a better leader.
That's what I should be doing is trying
to become a better leader. Now again, if,
if, if in this, whatever organization,
what you have to do is,
is do something that you don't agree with
and it's,
it's the wrong thing to do and you do
it anyways, we'll then, then that's,
that's, that's, that's almost
a totally different thing.
There's that. Then there's,
hey, I'm going to kiss ass
so that I get promoted.
It's all about me and that's probably
the what we think of the definition of a
fake person.
Yeah.
Okay.
Next question.
I saw a weakness in you
on your latest podcast.
You seem to overlook the fact that
some infant children were raised in
undisciplined environments
with undisciplined parents.
They grew up having modeled
these undisciplined examples.
I hate the fact that I have growth,
undisciplined behavior solving this
is a major priority in my life.
You have zero of what it,
of what this experience is like for me.
You seem blind to this struggle,
like a father who would ignore their child
struggle and offer only the words man
up.
So this is a good question and I see
where this guy's coming from for sure.
And I know that it can be very,
very frustrating to try
and become disciplined.
Yeah.
And I apologize that I haven't talked
about the fact of of what to do if you
come from an undisciplined family
or you have on disciplined parents.
I haven't really talked about
what to do in that situation,
but there's a reason that I
haven't talked about that before.
And that is because you don't get
disciplined from your parents.
You don't get disciplined from your
parents, from your grandparents,
from your older brothers and sisters.
You don't get disciplined
from an external source.
You have to get it from you.
That's what self discipline is.
You get it from yourself,
you get it from you. So
here's people from every
possible background,
from no parents to crazy parents too,
you know,
drug addicted parents to super squared
away parents and everywhere in between on
that spectrum that are completely
disciplined people more disciplined than
anyone I know.
It doesn't come from your parents,
you don't inherit it.
And there's another piece here.
It's called ownership,
right? It's called
ownership. And if you're,
if you want to blame other
people for the problem,
and I say this all the time, if you
don't take ownership of the problem,
the problem's not going to get salt.
So if you blame your parents for not
having raised you in a discipline
environment,
you're not going to solve that problem.
You're looking at your parents.
And if you would've done a better
job being more disciplined for me,
I would be more disciplined now.
So that means that means you can't do
anything. The fact of the matter is,
it's wrong. You actually can do
something and it doesn't matter what,
how your parents raised
you and brought you up.
You can have the discipline
you need to decide to do it.
So as long as you're blaming
other people, I mean,
even if you blame me
for not discussing it,
you blame me for having zero idea
what that experience is like.
You blame your parents for
not raising you this way.
As long as you're blaming other people,
as long as you're counting on other
people to give you discipline,
as long as you do that,
you will not have it.
So again, I, I'm sorry
I should've made that.
I should make that more clearly and
I'm trying to make it more clearly now.
And like my parents,
my parents are good people.
They had successful as,
as educators in public schools.
And my mom eventually became a,
went into school administration and
my dad taught in high school for 30
something years and they were good,
hardworking people. And I'll tell you,
they were no,
they were no extraordinary
preachers of discipline.
And I'll tell you, I, I in fact, I,
I never remember either one of them
ever using the term or referring to
discipline in any way. Um, you know,
and actually both my parents worked,
they both worked a lot.
My Dad was coaching sports and we'll do
an afterschool stuff. My mom, same thing,
like we were on our own a bunch.
Well my parents were gone in the morning.
We got ourselves to school when we got
home in the afternoon. They weren't home.
Uh,
you know,
so it wasn't like they were setting up
this rigid disciplined manner for me.
Right. Yeah. And um,
and you can see this with families,
many, many different families.
There's families that have kids that
the parents are very disciplined and the
kids are wild and out of control
sometimes it problematically, so, right.
Kids that come from really good families,
but they get addicted to drugs,
lack of discipline. Kids that come
from really good families, but they,
they spin out of control and,
and going the wrong direction.
And there's also the opposite,
which is pay.
The parents weren't around or the parents
were abusive or the parents were drug
addicts and all of a sudden the kid,
the kid comes out of that and
then is squared away is awesome.
And we saw that all the
time in the seal teams.
And I've said that before on
this program doesn't matter.
It doesn't matter where your background
is, it is what you decide to do. Yeah.
Um,
and I'll tell you another thing,
it's not even from the military,
like the military requires
discipline obviously,
but there's plenty of people in the
military that don't have it right. And,
and many poor,
many people lose their discipline when
they leave the mulch because it's not
being imposed on them anymore. So,
I mean, just go look around. I mean,
being in the military does not
make you a discipline person.
Being from a discipline family does
not make you a discipline person.
Being in a discipline group does
What makes you disciplined person
is choosing to be disciplined.
So yeah, I, I, and,
and also as far as telling
people to man up, um, which,
you know, when someone says, how
do I get up early every day, I say,
get up early every day.
How do I stop eating sugar?
Stop eating sugar if that's
the definition of man up.
But obviously is not just men that
need discipline in their life.
I don't think I use that term, but what
I do tell people is to get after it.
That's what I tell people to get after it.
I tell people to do the things that
they know they're supposed to do, right?
There's things that you know you're
supposed to do as a human being.
Things that you know are gonna
Improve Your Life. Do those things.
There's things that you know are going
to make you a worse person and make your
life worse.
Don't do those things.
Don't do the things that
are making you weaker.
Start doing the things that are going
to make you stronger and smarter and
faster and healthier and get to
make you a better human being.
And I'll say the same thing to this guy.
Yeah,
you want to be more disciplined. Get
after it. That's it, man. Get up early.
Do some kind of workout. Eat
good foods, clean your room,
make a list of things that you're
supposed to do in your life,
and then wake up in the morning and do
those things that you put on the list.
That's what discipline is
and no,
it is not easy, but you're not going
to get it from anyone else but you
and it's worth it. And it is the thing
that is going to bring you freedom.
That's the key word right there.
When you said it's worth it.
You know what,
I think this is what I think.
I think like in an environment
as like how he put it,
an undisciplined environment or aunt or
something like that where he grew up in
an undisciplined environment.
I don't,
obviously that's a very
vague expression, right?
Undisciplined environment. I mean that
can mean a lot of different things.
So a lot of times like when you're
brought up in a certain environment,
basically you're kind of
taught or, or not taught, like,
like the value of certain things.
So if you use like, I don't know,
working out or whatever. Right.
So I'm going to use myself as an,
as an example. My Dad was
an athlete, um, you know,
not a superior athlete,
but he was, you know, he,
he knew like working out was a part of
life and stuff like that. And you know,
in elementary school were doing sports and
stuff like that. You know, some people,
they don't do that at all.
So when they grow up into adulthood
that some people straight up have never
worked out before,
never been in a gym and you know,
so growing up they were never taught the
value of what working out does for you.
They never taught.
So they can't appreciate it.
They just simply don't know the value
share or they see people with, you know,
you know,
they're in shape or they can do these
things and they're very functioning,
whatever they see that of course,
but they don't have that value.
They don't feel that value. They
just never learned it. So it,
it can come off as like this
thing for other people, you know,
like well that's what other
people do kind of thing.
So they don't understand the value.
So back to the point in their mind,
this weird,
the connection is not made that it's
worth it because they don't know the value
of it really. But if you do know the
value of it and then you can decide, okay,
is this worth it,
is it worth it to wake up every day and
in quote unquote get after it for this
particular goal or this particular
set of goals. So that's what it is.
And I think sure the
undisciplined environment
can maybe provide that. But I think you're
right. I think that once you're like,
oh yeah that's worth it,
you know, help people,
they'll find reasons when it's worth it.
Even though they've never expect like,
you know, like a person who has a
heart attack or something, it's like,
and they have kids or young kids or
something, they have a heart attack,
maybe never worked out ever in their life.
They have a heart attack,
they almost died. They're like guess
what? I'm working out every single day.
I'm a vegetarian now.
You know like doing major,
major changes that they've
never even thought about making.
And they'll do it because they decided
it's worth it and they'll be discipline.
They'll find that discipline real quick,
no matter how they were trained as you
know, their environment and their cause.
Now I see that it's going to be
worth it. That's it. Yeah. And if,
if it's not worth it to use,
and that I think is what you develop,
the value of working out,
the value of you develop,
you can develop that from anywhere. That's
what I'm saying. That's essentially,
that's part of the early develop that
from any, any, you can develop that from,
from anywhere. Yeah. You can
get it from parents who can
get it from, yeah, exactly.
Right, exactly right. But the
discipline itself, just like I said,
that's going to come from you.
Your parents can teach it,
but guess who has to the, it's
still you. It's still you.
And you can go to the
military to specifically learn
discipline when you leave,
it's on you. Who's it? Yeah, exactly.
Right. And just like I said, like yeah,
I know people who are done
with the military and are
glad they're done with that.
They're glad with this waking up early.
They're next monster out of shape.
They're not doing anything productive.
It's, it's horrible to say,
but it happens. Happens with the
military. It happens with anything. Yeah.
It was when kids get out of
high school sports, you know,
and all of a sudden they don't want,
I don't have to do that anymore.
I don't have to listen to
coach. Yeah. Yeah. Crazy.
Don't listen to coach. Listen
to yourself yourself. Yeah.
Determine whether or not it's worth it.
And I'm telling you do,
you don't need to determine, I'm
telling you it's worth it. Oh yeah.
I'm telling you it is worth it.
And you know what?
You actually know it's worth it.
That's why you're asking this question.
You know it's worth it. You know
what's worth it to have discipline.
But you think there's an easier way.
You think that it's
something that people have.
You think that when Jockos alarm
clock goes off, it's like, oh,
just like my father taught me, I rise
and I shine. You know what I'm like, no,
I,
it's like the pillow feel
soft and comfortable and the
alarm clock is banging on
my head and I don't like it.
But you know what,
I know it's worth it to
get up and get after it.
I know it's worth it and you know it's
worth it. Here's the thing though,
we all know what's worse is
in in a way you're right,
but like really though
really I'm going to be open,
open and honest with you. I don't think
that that people know it's worth it.
I think they know it's worth it.
Like the kind of on paper,
they have a multiple choice question, is
it worth it? Yes or no? There'll be like,
yes. Obviously I know working out
is worth it. But here's the thing.
I don't if you don't know, if you don't
like like having good credit for example.
So I never got taught like
why really? My Mom said, yeah,
you should have good credit.
That's it.
That's the limit to my
education on credit. Right.
So of course they're below it
because they get, you know,
I fall for literally all the tricks if
self-inflicted and otherwise credit gets
jammed up. So, so I don't know. I
don't know the value. I don't know.
I've never experienced the
benefits of having good car.
I don't know the value of good credit.
So it really didn't mean much to me.
Really.
My credit was like junk and I didn't care
until I got denied for something then
I cared.
You know.
But just like if you're never into
working out until you're in a specific
situation where shows,
but like this guy that's
asking this question and glad
he's asking the question,
I'm, I'm not, I'm trying, I'm not
trying to come off all hard. Um,
but he realizes she realizes
the value of discipline.
Cause he's saying that he wants it.
Right.
He knows that it's going to
make his life better. Yeah. And,
and that's why I think he,
he's gotten jammed up in whatever way.
We don't know, cause I don't know,
maybe he's gotten unhealthy. Maybe he's,
you know, who knows, maybe he's
gotten his finances jammed up,
whatever the case may be. He knows that
discipline is better for them. Him,
he knows that. He does know this
isn't a guy that doesn't know yet.
Cause sure there's people that don't,
you know, when you're 16 years old,
you don't know the value of discipline.
You don't know that the, what you're,
the way you're acting right now,
it's gonna affect you in five years.
You don't know that you can set yourself
your whole life up to be pretty awesome.
Yeah.
You don't know that yet.
You're just like worried about where
you're going on a Friday night. Right.
So this guy knows and he wants it and
he's looking for where he can find it and
where he can find it is in the
mirror. Yeah. That's where it is,
you know, so do it brother. Good luck. Get
on the path and stay on the path. Yeah.
And that's going to be beneficial
when you do the harshly.
Maintaining that, like not knowing
the value is a big is a big thing.
It's kind of like, okay.
So back to my credit thing,
there is a point at the end where, okay,
so, um, you know, like, uh, I dunno,
10 years ago, whatever, I repaired
my credit, my credit was repaired,
I went through it was painstaking,
not fun stuff. Yeah. But I did it.
Got To credit repaired and now I know
the value because as an adult I'm
functioning. It's useful now, you know?
So now I know the value of having good
credit because I've been through all the
things that having good credit
brings you through, you know?
Now I'm thinking I'll never
go back to bed crying. Never.
It's worth it every single day.
I'm telling you that I agree
with what you're saying. Yeah.
I agree with what you're saying.
I'm saying that this guy knows the
value and that's why he wants it. Yeah.
It's like when you realize that you got
denied for something and you're like, oh,
vow credit has value.
I understand that something happened in
his life where he said discipline has
value.
I know that now.
But you did credit repair and
in what you said was, okay,
I need to go out and repair my credit.
You didn't say, Hey, you know what?
My mom didn't tell me about bad credit
and now I have bad credit. Yeah. Yeah. So
now, so now what am I supposed to do?
You know who repaired your credit,
who repaired your credit? Well it was
a combination of my wife and I but,
but who repaired your credit?
It yeah, we did this stuff.
You took responsibility for it and said,
okay, I'm gonna get my credit card. You,
you talked to your wife because she's
smarter than you. And she was like,
Hey I will, I will help this.
But it was you that said,
okay I got to get this
fixed and you got help.
But you knew to reach out for help,
but you're the one that ultimately
is responsible for it. Yeah,
you're right about that.
Like I didn't like I didn't blame my
parents and then continue having that
credit. Right. Like you
said, no I gotta get this,
this thing has credit, has
value, I need to fix it.
And you fixed it, you know, regardless
of where it came from regardless.
So w w w w you know, oh you
don't know how to work out. Cool.
Then you go hire a personal trainer
cause you know it's going to,
it's the right thing to do.
You know what I mean? Oh,
you don't know how to
repair your finances. Cool.
Go get a counselor that's going to
help you repair your finances. Oh,
you're addicted to drugs or alcohol.
Okay,
I'm going to go find a counselor or join
a group so I can get through that thing.
No one's going to hold your
hand and bring you into that.
Any of those situations,
you've got to do it yourself.
You've gotta have the discipline
to make it happen. Yeah.
Good.
Ah, number seven. Good morning.
Did you find that people in the
military mock those that emphasize the
importance of good leadership,
who take leading and our responsibilities
seriously? What does that mean?
Mocking like the front of you? Yeah.
Like what? People in the military making,
making fun of you because
you take leadership super
seriously. Oh yeah, yeah, yeah,
yeah, yeah. Like you're this way
scout. This is an interesting question,
so it makes me a little bit
nervous because my suspicion
is that this individual
might be going about being
a good leader the wrong way,
and if you go about it the wrong way,
people can take offense to it.
If you're the guy that goes around
telling everyone that you are a leader and
you're trying to be great leader,
people would take offense to that because
like you can't make that part of your
thing,
right.
People that talk about the importance of
good leadership are they come across as
implying that they are good leader
and and that can be offensive,
especially if you aren't quite as
good of a leader as you think you are.
She run around like you don't
understand how important leadership is.
Like just think about that
statement right there.
You don't understand the
importance of leadership. Echo.
I'll all of a sudden I'm basically telling
you like I'm a good leader and you're
not.
When the reality is just the way I'm
talking proves that I'm not a good leader
because I'm talking down to you. Yeah,
so we have a problem right there.
And also
if,
if you take leading and our
leading responsibilities,
what does that actually mean?
Does that mean that you can't
have any fun with your team?
Does that mean you can't laugh at
yourself when you've made a mistake?
Does that mean that you are trying so
hard to give off the impression that you
are a great leader,
that it appears to everyone else that
you aren't really who you act like and
that your character is,
is disingenuous.
Right?
If I'm,
if I'm constantly trying to put up
this front that I'm the great leader,
everyone starts looking at me thinking
that guy's not even, that's not,
that's not the real him. He's just
trying to rock around like, uh, like a,
he's not true. Right? You think about it,
you're trying to build trust and as a
leader we are trying to build trust.
We talked to dick winters talking
about honesty being the most,
one of the most important traits of a,
of a leader.
But if we're putting up
a facade and how we act,
that does not come across as honest
and that doesn't build trust. In fact,
they build the opposite.
And
also if,
if,
if you have to put up a leadership front,
hmm.
If you have to put up a leadership front.
In other words,
if sometimes you have to
act a certain way, fake it.
Going back to something earlier,
if you have to act and fake like a leader,
that means you might be,
you might be insecure about
your leadership capability
and you will come across
as insecure and people
can sense that insecurity.
So that can be very problematic.
Also,
if you're so into being a good leader,
that probably means that you
have issues giving up the reins.
That means that you are
probably micromanaging because
you want to be a leader.
Do you want to prove to everyone that
you're a good leader and so you start
micromanaging and no one wants
to follow a micromanager.
They don't want to do that.
And if you add
all these things together,
what do people end up doing?
They end up mocking.
You
may end up mocking the things
that you think are important,
like leadership itself.
They start to make fun of it.
[inaudible]
it's, Oh man, the, it's like the needle.
I think his name is needle
Meyer in animal house,
isn't it the right name?
I don't know. I kind of,
I'm doing a movie reference and you're
not in with me. This is messed up.
I can give you the John Belushi.
That's all you know. So there's,
it's like the leader, the the ROTC
guy. He's the guy that's like Mr leader
and everyone makes fun of him. Yeah,
he's trying to be a great leader.
He's trying to be the authoritative
figure. Everyone is making fun of him.
So you have to be careful in case
I would recommend you move to
the center a little bit more.
Meaning that on the one hand you have a
leader that isn't building relationship,
isn't building trust, expects people
to do as they're told and and treat,
treat that leader with respect to,
even though they haven't earned it,
that's not a good leader.
On the other hand,
you have leaders that are
too close with the troops,
has very personal relationships
to personal relationships
with the team and has
lost any semblance of authority over
the team. So there's your two extremes.
You want to be balanced in the middle.
You want to build relationships with the
people you want to build your team up.
And also forcing leadership on to people
does not work any more than forcing a
religion or a diet or a workout or
a political breathe belief system.
And can you make someone from a,
from a leadership perspective,
if you have a 40 over other people,
can you make someone bow down to your
program mechanically for a little while?
Yeah, you can. You can. But
if it's not from them,
if they're not part of it willfully,
it's not going to work
over time. So, you know,
don't beat people up verbally
with your leadership lessons.
Hmm.
Don't make it your external religion that
you are forcing on people internally.
Yes, of course. Obviously Ma, I
always thought about leadership.
I always thought about leadership,
but I wasn't barking it. And I don't,
I don't even think,
I don't even think
like my best. The people that
taught me the most about leadership,
they never said a word to
me about leadership. Right.
And I'm not saying that that's
the best course of action because,
because sometimes it is good to, you
know, pull someone aside and say, Hey,
this is the way you're acting right now
in front of your troops and that that's
not going to be effective.
Sometimes that is good. Yeah.
Especially once you've
built the relationship.
Because if I don't have a relationship
with you, echo, when I say, Hey,
I need to talk to you.
Hey,
the way you're treating your guys right
now isn't going to go over very well
with them. What's your reaction going
to be? You're going to be pissed.
You're gonna think of you don't know
my guys. I know them better than unit.
We're going to have a problem.
I D I. D I accomplished nothing.
My coaching and mentoring of you
was horrible cause we didn't have a
relationship.
So you're not listening.
And obviously of course when I
started coaching and mentoring,
that implies that I'm the greatest
leader of all time. That's my,
that's the implied statement
and you suck on great.
Which people reject that as well,
especially when you're not that
great of a leader in the first place.
So don't talk about it so much.
Just lead, be a good leader,
open up discussions,
take a wrap off,
come from the flank instead
of going straight on maneuver
tactically and tactfully get into
their heads and make better leaders by
actually leading.
Yeah.
Yes. Of like that lead, you know,
lead by example kind of thing.
It kind of makes you like the question
kind of how you said at the beginning,
it makes you wonder.
He says,
the question is do you find that
people in the military mock those that
emphasize the importance of good
leadership? You kind of think to yourself,
I wonder how this person is
emphasizing the importance of good.
Is he the guy at the party who, you
know, people were talking about,
I don't know that the food or something.
Then he just bust out leadership stuff.
You know that guy who's like
everything on like ROTC guy.
He's just pushing it everyday. You know,
leadership has everything leaves you.
If everything are bright.
We weren't even talking about that.
Leadership is everything kind of thing.
By the way,
this is coming from a person in me that
I literally talk about leadership at the
time. Yeah. And, and I
actually think that way. And I,
I get up on stage and in companies and
in front of military members and police
officers and, and I talk about leadership.
That's what I talk about all the time.
Yeah. And that's what, you
know what's interesting,
that's what makes about face by
Colonel David Hackworth. The,
one of the best things about that book is
it's not a leadership book. He doesn't,
he just talk.
He barely talks about,
he barely says a straightforward sentences
and use it. This is how you lead.
It's all from the flank.
And that's why it gets you so
well because it's from the flank.
Yeah. It's not a book about
leadership doesn't even say it. Right.
You know how many books get
published publish all the time.
You know that this is a leadership book.
I wrote a book with life.
How to lead and win. Yeah. Hackworth
did it better Hackworth like,
oh, this is about war.
Read it. Yeah. Yeah.
In a way a day. I think we've seen.
But obviously that's your job.
So I guess my point is that if you're,
if this is coming from someone who
talks about leadership all the time,
literally wrote a book about
leadership. Yeah. And I'm saying, Hey,
you might not want to talk about that.
That's my point. That's my point. Yeah.
Good point. Just just, just back off a
little bit. Yeah. So if you were like,
you know, you go on the road,
you do one a year, you know,
with your deals and then you know,
at dinner with your family,
you start going into your
leadership stuff with them.
That's what you shouldn't
hear. Yes, yes. But I'm,
what I'm saying is with your team,
with your platoon,
you don't sit there and say,
all right,
today we're going to talk
about leadership again. Yeah.
You don't quote unquote emphasize the
importance of good leadership. Right.
You demonstrate it. You just lead.
They're smarter than you think. They're,
you know what you're in to do and
you're kind of condescending. Yeah.
You help it cause you're treating
them like they don't know.
You want to talk about the importance
of leaders if they know what the
importance of leadership there
in the military. Yeah. In fact,
an example of their reaction
of how people take it.
When you start preaching to them, you
know how they take it, they mock you.
That's a lesson learned. That's a lesson
learned. If people are mocking you,
they're not taking you seriously. Yeah.
That means you're doing something wrong.
What you're doing wrong in this case
is your condescendingly talking to them
about the importance of leadership.
They know what the importance
of leadership is. Yeah.
They're in the military.
They know how bad it is to have a bad
platoon sergeant or a bad platoon,
a platoon commander. They know you
don't need to rub it in their face.
Yeah, I remember, I think I told you
the story about one of my friends,
I'm not gonna name the name cause I'm
certain, you know he's a navy seal.
We were at a party and he got,
he got drunk and he's sitting at the
table explaining to all of us how bad ass
navy seals are. Yeah. Like for
a long time too. This is the,
and he even said those words,
maybe you still just so bad ass,
like we're so bad at and this
is why and all this stuff.
And it's the exact same thing because
we know navy seals are bad ass,
but you sitting here telling us how bad
ass you and all navy seals are is going
to make us mock you a little bit. Going
to get mocked. Yeah. Even a little bit.
You're gonna get mocked a lot. You're
going to get mocked by other navy seals,
by the way. For sure. Doing
that stuff. Anyway, check. Well,
I'm glad that this guy
is asking the question.
I'm glad that the guy is
focused on leadership and I
hope that these points can
come across and be digested with no.
Um, you know, there's real easy to get
offended by what I'm saying, right.
If you're him, you like, well, you just
doesn't get it. You know what I mean?
It's real easy to say that.
Yeah. We used to do yo, Yo,
it's easy for him to say he doesn't
know what he's talking about.
I'm the one that's here. I'm trying to
get these guys to be better. You know,
I'm trying to get my book too, and
understand the importance of leadership.
I know, man. I know, and I respect that.
I liked the fact that you're have
that mindset, man. That's all true.
That's awesome. That's awesome.
Come from the flag a little bit.
Come from the flank, man. You're
not gonna. You're not gonna.
You're not gonna get that.
Get it done this way. Yeah.
Yeah.
It's Kinda like if you try to convince
everyone that you're the most humble
person in the world, you know, nobody
more humbling me. I'm the most humble.
I'm humbler than that guy.
I'm a humbling then you,
I'm home earlier than anyone
through that who've ever lived.
I'm just the most humble guy in the world.
Just doesn't work like that.
That doesn't work that well.
X question,
Jocko.
How do you lead a team of volunteers?
How to punish or discipline them?
Can't threaten to fire them
because they're all I have.
I know a leader does so much
more than threatened and punish,
but I need some guidance.
Try to motive,
try to motivate but feel
the need to do more things.
Trying to answer this one quickly once,
cause this is kind of a,
a question I've answered
before in a different form. Um,
do they understand why they're doing
what they're doing and do they understand
why it's important? Do they understand
how what they are doing will benefit them?
Do they also see you working hard
to try and make things happen?
So those are,
those are just the basic questions.
Let's just get those out there every time.
Every time someone's not doing
what you want them to do.
Do they understand why they're
doing what they're doing?
Do they understand why it's important to
the mission and do they understand how
being successful in the mission
and will benefit them? So,
so let's just get those out of the
way. Next. What can we do here?
Have you game a five the situation at
all? How do you like that gamified, right?
Have you gamified the situation?
Cause I realize that's a term
that's getting thrown around now,
but we would gamify stupid things all
the time in the seal teams to make them
fun. Right. How much brass can you pick
up? Let's see. I'll pick up more than you.
My squad will pick up more breasts and
you'll pick up all of the sudden we were
running around the range
trying to pick up brass.
One of the most miserable things that you
have to do in the seal teams is pickup
brass off the hot range and
the summertime. And you do
it for, for like two days.
Because once you get
done with all your work,
you've got to go pick up millions of
rounds of brass spread out all over the
Desert Inn in August in the
imperial valley. It's odd.
It's socks. But guess what?
We're going to do,
have a contest know.
So what are you going to
do to game a fight? Uh,
like what kind of cool competition around
some short term goal can you set up
that's going to be, it's going to make it
fun for them. Some kind of cool reward.
What about some kind of friendly bets
around achieving something like I bet if I
raise this much money,
you know,
I will go to work with a pair of
underwear on my head or you have to,
you know what I mean?
Whatever these stupid bets,
you know what we used to do
in the teams is we'd bet $1,
one of my old running mates, we,
we, we had something like critical,
I bet you $1.
Yeah.
That was like the biggest bet you could
make because it's just, it's pure pride.
So, you know, and then we'd,
we'd always have fun if you are
collecting or if you're giving the dollar
collecting the dollar was
just totally glorious.
Giving the dollar was shame and shame.
So yeah, like you could add like, okay,
when you give me this dollar a,
it has to be in front of everybody,
be you have to,
I don't know,
you have to do it well like
walking on your knees or something.
Something to real, kind of demeaning.
But we didn't even have to do all that.
Just give me and my resume if we
won or lost the bet and is like,
you know, and, and you wouldn't even ask
for the money. You just look at them.
And this buddy of mine,
he had of the most classic looks
when he'd give you the look,
when I lose a bet to me, he gave
me the look, I wanted to cry.
He lost more than that.
So maybe you make a bet for a
dollar and if that's not working,
okay now if that's not working,
if you can't game a five,
if you can't have fun with it,
maybe ask them while they're,
why they are there and figure out
their motivation is for being there
and how you can tie that into something
concrete.
And then also like you might have some
people at heart aren't really into this
and then lower your expectations of this
particular group of people and gaunt
recruits and people that
want to get after it.
Makes Sense.
Yeah.
Have some fun.
Fun goes along way.
Fun goes a long way.
Having fun doing things goes a long way.
And the, and that praise
thing too. You know,
when you said like add like a reward or
something for, because a lot of times,
especially volunteers were so,
you know, and we all feel this,
like even at work you can have like
a super fun job, but you'll get,
you'll people genital spe speaking tend
to get complacent in one way or another.
You know, when things are
routine or things are, you know,
not as exciting or
whatever. Um, and you know,
when you're volunteering and that happens,
it's kind of like you're not tied
there by a paycheck really, you know,
which is just, it's just a powerful
tie, you know, that people have to work.
It's like, yeah, I don't like my job, but
it pays the bills and paying the bills.
It's a big deal kind of thing.
So if you add that element of
excitement or fun or you know,
little personal payoff
in one way or another,
I think that helps a lot of
the time. Indeed. And that
tends to happen too. If the,
if the Li, I'm not saying this person
is doing this or not doing this,
but like if they become kind of complacent
and not recognizing how much they,
they, they appreciate the volunteers, you
know? Like if they're just like, oh yeah,
this is just business as usual,
you know, thanks for coming in.
That's kind of it kind of
thing. And they, you know,
then it just gets kind of kind of Blah,
you know,
like that there's not the payoff
that they used to have, you know?
But if you can kind of keep that going,
keep them in the game.
Next question.
Do I need to keep training Jujitsu?
If I hate it?
I mean, can I just live my life
the way I think it should be,
which is of health energy and become
becoming a force of nature as a doctor
without dreaming up,
have some invisible enemies on the
street that I've yet to come across in
preparing and spending my pittance of
wage of a wage on lessons that I hate in
every sorts of ways for
something that might be avoided.
Physical clash if I learnt to use wit
and saving my money to move into a good
neighborhood and I've been successful
in preventing physical clashes to occur.
I've learnt basic ways to escape the
amount I can run. I'm fairly strong.
Isn't that enough?
Okay. So yeah, bro
Do. Jesse was not the meaning of life.
All right. And you did. Who has a lot of,
I mean, I find Jujitsu very
enjoyable. I get a lot out of it.
Beyond physical training.
Beyond self defense.
Yeah.
I get a lot out of it and I apply it in
all different sorts of realms in my life.
But if you hate it
and,
and you've learned some basic ways
to defend yourself, escape them out,
maybe some basic guards type stuff then,
then okay.
I mean then step away.
I mean,
you shouldn't be going through life
doing something that you hate. I,
if I were you,
I'd still train occasionally,
even if it's just like once every
two or three weeks, once a month,
just to keep some of the ideas fresh.
And also also there's always
the possibility that will
click in your head and
you'll realize there's,
there's like a magical thing that
you could get out of the Jujitsu. Um,
and it's kind of like waking up,
waking up at four 30 in the morning.
That's what time I wake
up. And, and first of all,
I'm genetically predisposed to sleep
less than most people. And for instance,
we just had daylight savings
time and yeah, and so,
and I went to bed,
so I sat back my clock and it was,
it was like nine 40 at night, so it
went from 10 40 when I was going to bed,
I set back my clock and now it's nine
40 and I said, I'll call, you know,
I'll sleep extra hour.
We know what time I woke up,
like two 48 and then I laid in bed saying,
no,
sleep more, sleep more,
sleep more. I couldn't do it.
So I got out of bed at three 30 but
that's, that's me. And, and, and that's,
that's just me.
And it depends on what your schedule is.
It depends on what your
genetic makeup is for sleep.
And if you work the night shift,
then obviously you're working at four 30
in the morning or you're getting off at
war of work at four 30 in morning.
So this just doesn't work.
And I try and put that caveat on
pretty much everything that I say,
like my workouts to what I eat.
Um,
everyone's a little bit different
and I like what I like and,
and I do what I do and it works for me
and you can try it then if you come up
with something that's better,
I'll listen to you. Um,
and that's the same with Jujitsu,
man. If you hate it, then you know,
maybe it's not for you. And,
and, and you know what I,
what I truly think my true thought.
Is it beneficial for you? Yes it is.
D should you stop doing
everything that you don't like,
but just because you
don't like it? No. I mean,
there's some things that you
should press on. Should you get it?
Should everyone have a fundamental level
of knowledge of Jujitsu? It's very,
very beneficial.
But if you hate it and,
and you've kind of come to that
conclusion, then don't do it.
Yeah.
And, and, and I think also once
you give yourself that out,
once you give yourself the out and you're
not forcing yourself to do it anymore,
it might open up your mind to actually
enjoy it and try it and not be miserable
about it. Yes. Yeah. That's what
actually what I was going to say.
It's probably,
and I don't know easily this,
some people don't like it straight up. My
God, I accept that. I know. I know. But
that being said,
there is a possibility
that the environment that
this person worked,
that people train in.
Sometimes we'll make you not like it
and it's not necessarily the Jujitsu you
don't like. Sure. Not wound up that way.
You don't like to do anymore
because you were kind of, you know,
pushed in the wrong direction as far as
like what you do like and don't like.
So you could try a different school, try
different, try different school. Yeah.
Like I said earlier today,
some schools are really strict
and rigid and maybe that's,
but would be better for you. Some schools
are real wild and there's no control.
Maybe that, that be a better school
depending on what your personality is. Uh,
some people like that regimen and
environment. Yeah. Yeah, you could,
you could definitely try a different
school. Uh, but again, I think,
I think the mental hurdle to come over
is you've told yourself that you have to
do it and now tell yourself you don't
have to do if you don't want to,
but certain in,
and you say try different school.
It's the environment that you train in.
So the school is part of
the environment for sure.
But it's like trading partners.
It's like the,
which can wind up as the pressure you
put on yourself. It's like everything,
you know, the whole environment. So I know
that. And people are different people.
Some people, they want that pressure. They
want people yelling and you don't like,
remember I used to tell you
like when you start coaching,
either me just in training,
you know like you'll get fired up when
you see two people training and whatever
and you'll be like, do this,
do that. And you'll start code.
It's almost like you're like as a friend,
you're doing it just for fun
and you're like, okay, do this.
And you usually coach up the other guy
when I'm rolling with him and that other
guy,
oh he's getting coached by Jocko.
So he turns up the heat and I don't like
that because it's now it's like a thing,
you know, I don't like that at
all. But some people do like that.
Some people that get them
fired up, it gets them more
in the game, you know? So to,
I'm saying people are different.
So the possibility is that this guy
happens to be in the wrong environment for
Jujitsu first for hip, for Jiu
Jitsu. For himself. Yes, exactly.
So it was a possibility. And
just like you said, you know, he,
he could very well be putting
that pressure on himself.
Like you have to go and everyone's
saying how great it is and it's the best
thing.
And if you don't show up to practice,
you're whack and you're
lame or get on the texture.
If you get told all the time
it's the best thing in the world.
And then you show up
there and you get beat up,
which is what happens and now you're like,
how does everyone likes this?
This doesn't feel good to me. And you
just go in a negative mindset right away.
So you guys should be careful of that.
And that's not dimension.
When you even imply that
you don't necessarily like
it. Oh yeah, cause you suck.
Oh yeah, because you're this or you're
weak or you're whatever. You're a slacker.
Like basically all this negativity,
you know,
it's going to turn you off even more
so now. Yeah. You paid it now, which,
which there's the reality of it is some,
some things don't agree with some
people, right? That's, that's a reality.
Like there's some things in the
world that, that I don't, I know,
I just don't like them.
Like when we were driving to La,
you're playing some music.
Some of the music that you're playing is,
is popular music. I just don't
like it. I just don't like it.
And
there's other things
like that in the world.
I'm trying to think of things that I just,
just like other people like them. Yeah.
And I just don't like them. I just don't
Pokemon go. That's one thing. Yeah.
I mean, I don't, I've never
even thought about Pokemon go.
It seems like a cool idea.
You got, you look for things
on your phone. I mean, well,
I'm not, that's not the type of
thing that I'm talking about. Um,
you know, I guess dancing at the
club. No, I mean, I don't care about,
I'm trying to think of something that's,
um,
I guess music is the best is one
of the best examples for me is,
is, you know, hey, this certain types
of music, certain artists, yeah.
Like Lafe,
Lafe likes hair.
Lafe likes hair metal from the
90s he legit likes it. And, and I,
I like legit do not like it.
And the reason I used the reason that's
a good example is because that's not far
off from kind of the music that I do like.
I mean I like,
I like led Zeppelin, I love led
Zeppelin, right. Led Zeppelin's awesome.
And, and the step from led
Zeppelin to, to, to poison.
I mean you could, you could be in the
same record category in the store, right?
Rock and roll led Zeppelin. I love, yeah,
I poison kind of turns my stomach.
I hate it.
And so that's an example of some things
they just don't sit well with you and,
and maybe Jujitsu doesn't sit well
with this guy. Now I'm, like I said,
I think there's a lot of benefits to it.
I think you get a lot out of it.
Try a different environment. But if you
hate it, don't force yourself to do it.
Open. Open the escape, right.
Give yourself an out and that
allows you to feel more comfortable.
Cause when you feel trapped,
everyone feels like a cornered animal and
now you're just pissed off you. If you,
if you've been like, hey
these guys, everyone,
I hear everyone talking about Jujitsu so
I'm going to try it and now your first
day you don't like it,
but you're like,
I'm going to keep doing it
because everyone is saying
that's great and you just
ended up in a bad way.
So be careful with that one.
You're kinda trapped it with it, with
the junk parts of it. Yeah. That,
that kind of came about and yeah,
and you can't really escape it
then you're like rebel against it.
Yeah.
Remember when we were driving up to la?
I was playing carry by Europe.
That is actually technically
an eighties hair metal. Yeah.
That's an easy yeah, for sure. But
you were really mad. Yeah. Yeah. No,
I'm telling you that music doesn't
sit well with me for some reason.
You got little bitty going back to life,
like lay likes Metallica.
Lafe likes black sabbath lay flags tool.
He likes rocking bands too.
For some reason. There's some genetic
code in his head that poisons cool. Yeah.
Just lets it right in my and
gets the, and Holt. Yeah.
But then I guess on the other
end of the spectrum you'd get,
we get into music that leaf and light,
like life likes Pantera.
Pantera was a hard band. Now I go one
step further than Penn. Tara. Right.
Some of the music that I
listen to him, uh, which I
think leaves Lafe a little bit where he
wouldn't listen to some of the harder
music that I listen to. But pantyhose,
you know, brushing up against it. Hey,
do you listen to soft music? Come on.
What do you consider soft music? I Dunno.
Something about love songs. I don't
know. So you don't let something soft,
do you know what I'm saying?
I'd say White Buffalo,
White Buffalo is hard acoustic music.
But you know,
he's got some pretty mellow songs.
He got a song called love song number one.
What's it about though? Like is
he, is it like romantic, you know,
is he talked to you about
the girl or something like
that? I would say yes. Yeah,
he kinda did the count cause
it's, you know, how like
what, how can that not count?
No. Because you know how
like, like a Metallica for
example, they have unforgiven.
Right. So it sounds softer, but they're
still talking about hard stuff. Okay.
And then they have like interst hand man,
which is what I guess I'm just not,
no my answer to use. No. Like do you
like what about led Zeppelin by one sec,
you're still talking about like, these
are soft things, like, you know, okay.
So I'll play an Algebra. Remember?
Remember Algebra? And you're like,
what the off this and you're pissed.
You are mad at me personally.
Like you and you were like,
who is this? No, no, no. You
know what though? Actually
I played another song. Uh,
who was it? He was like Josh in or
something. And you're like, Hey,
this is pretty good. I was very surprised.
It was a soft song. Do you remember?
That's my musical. Tastes are varied.
Yeah. Different types of music. Yeah.
So I guess some types of
music that I don't like. Yeah.
I sometimes wonder with you,
like if you're the kind of,
you know how some people,
they just, just, I like
music. I'm not saying me,
I'm just saying certain people they
are into just a specific type of music.
That's it.
That's the whole reason for music in
their head is like this very specific
feeling. Like some people, um,
that I had know before they,
they only like house music. They don't
like anything other than the house.
Music is like, it's just the
old rather listen to nothing.
So I was wondering if you were like kind
of that kind of no where it's just all
different kinds of music. Yeah. Well at
least just not, maybe not all different.
Yeah. Okay. You're right. I listened
to a wide various types. Sure.
There you go. Not Algebra
though. I forget the song,
but it was who we can refer back
to it later some other time. Cool.
All right. Next question. How about that?
Dang. I kind of feel bad for the guy who
hates you. Do too. That's kind of crazy.
Yeah, it's a bummer, but it's, it's
not that rare. Yeah, it makes sense.
It totally makes sense. I was
actually talking with Dave real sure.
I know who that is.
I don't know him personally.
Well I was up with him up in San Francisco
area yesterday and we were talking
about how some people don't like Jujitsu
and you'd think even people that are
you would think would like to Jitsu people
that have jobs that Jujitsu would be
really beneficial for them to know.
They don't like Jujitsu. Yeah. And so,
and I was saying that I've introduced
a lot of people to Jujitsu,
a lot of people to Jujitsu.
Not many of them have actually stuck
with it for a long period of time and,
and so it's not that rare for
people to not like Jujitsu.
Yeah. And I, I dig, it's like not
sticking with it. Cause did you do that?
Takes work.
It's not like the easy thing that provides
discipline is a difference between
not like in Jujitsu and not
actually sticking with it.
Yes. This guy straight up.
I hate it. That's a little bit
more powerful statement. Yeah.
It's like definitely doesn't like people
who don't stick with it for the most
part, this is just a total guess on my
part or lazy and lack discipline. Yeah.
Like they,
they just,
they, they, they don't
like it enough on an,
on a kind of moment to moment basis to
get off the couch and go. That's kind of,
you know,
it's one of those situations.
Next question Jocko.
I have a question after reading your book,
which I thought was one of the best books
I've read since your last book. Nice.
I'm curious what,
what you did during your seal
team days to maintain your,
your schedule as I would
imagine in the teams,
your schedule changes at any minute to
include you being deployed or active
during your various missions at night.
So as in life,
how do you keep your balance of your
schedule when duty calls in your book,
you say keep your schedule,
but how did you work through this when
you would be on a mission that didn't
allow you to sleep at night?
Did you still,
did you still the following day upon
return, maintain your normal schedule,
appreciate your time and response.
Great.
Yeah.
Obviously the teams that you're scheduling
the teams can vary a lot and you have
to adopt to what makes sense. And
sometimes in the teams you're working 18,
20 hour days. Sometimes out in the field
you're going in the field for two, three,
four,
five days at a time.
Sometimes you're working for 24 hours
a day or you work for 36 hours straight
because you do planning in the blah,
blah, blah. So that can be wrong.
But sometimes you're doing dives,
you're doing two dives a day and that
takes a bunch of time and it takes a toll
on you. It's hard work I
guess you could say. Um,
sometimes we're running around all day
or all night running around the desert,
running around the
urban training facility.
And so the schedule is
changing all the time.
And it's the same thing with business.
The same thing with business.
Right now I travel on the flight
leaves early in the flight leaves.
He doesn't work all day or the dinner
with the clients or the interview or the
writing or the,
the recording of the podcast
or the changing time zones
and things just change.
And so what I do is yes,
I try and I try and keep the schedule
as much as I can and if I fall off the
schedule for whatever reason, I get
back off on it as quickly as possible.
And I think so. So yes,
you do the best you can.
I think the main thing you have
to watch out for is letting,
letting a change in schedule
or a problem in your schedule being
an excuse to fall off the path.
Right? That's what you have to watch
out for. Um, you know, we think, oh,
I'm in a new time zone or I've got jet
lag or I didn't sleep well or I need rest
from traveling or I did this the other
night and saw I'm going to sleep until
nine 30 tomorrow morning
and just call it good.
That's what you have to
watch out for now sometimes.
Do you need to work to ninth did you
sleep til nine 30 yeah. Sometimes you do.
Sometimes you stayed up for 36 hours.
You go to bed at three o'clock
in the morning, guess what?
You might need to sleep until
nine 30. That's cool. Good.
Do it. Get some sleep. Um,
but just be careful of using it as an
excuse to go way off the path and just get
yourself back on the path as soon
as possible. Yeah. Make sense?
Yes, sir. Yeah, that's all me right there.
Like one little thing on my schedule
throws off on this whole day is gone.
I'll do it tomorrow. He's
got to be careful that, uh,
speaking to schedule,
I think we're about good for questions.
There's one more thing that I wanted
to close out with and you know,
I get a lot of,
I get a lot of really great emails.
I will get a lot of great
messages through social media,
letters, written letters,
I get all those kinds of things
and I appreciate them all.
I don't always respond to all
of them because there's, I,
I physically cannot do it. Yeah.
And of course, you know, oh,
get someone to manage your social
media or whatever. I'm not doing that.
If you hear back from me,
you hear it from me,
not from somebody that I paid $10 an
hour to respond to my stuff and say,
cool, get after it. Like
no, uh, not doing that. But
you know, I get, I would get all
these things and I, I do read them.
So if you send it, I read it. And so I
appreciate the feedback and everything.
I got one though that I,
that was good.
I wanted to actually wanting to read
on here because I felt that it not only
said, hey, thanks for you know, the
podcast or whatever, thanks for the books,
whatever.
It actually gave some pretty
good methodology and really
an inset into a mindset
that I think will help people
doing what they're doing.
So here we go. Mr Willick just wanted
to share a quick story with you.
At 39 I had fallen into a 15 year
Rut of undisciplined alcoholism.
I was soft and heavy and wanted a change.
Earlier this year I had started working
out three to four times a week in my
basement. I was trying and failing
to get a handle on my alcohol abuse.
Every failure made the beast
seemed bigger and unbeatable.
It was like I didn't have
control over my body.
I finished your book on a Monday night
and decided that I would get up early the
next morning and workout. I got
up and worked out. Not much,
but I just wanted to do
something. Sit ups, pushups,
15 minutes on the bike,
worked out twice, Tuesday,
got up Wednesday and did it again.
Got To Thursday night on normal drinking
night and decided to try not drinking.
Made it through Friday.
Same thing.
Worked out morning and night, stayed
busy and stayed away from the drink.
Fought I should try and push it through
the weekend. Worked out Saturday morning.
It took the rest of the weekend,
often stayed dry.
Monday morning I got up
and started two days again,
made it through the week with 11 workouts.
By the second week, I felt better
than I had in my entire life.
I was astounded that normal people
walked around feeling this good.
I guess not systematically
poisoning your body will do that.
On the fifth week,
I got a project at work that was going
to require traveling for the next eight
weeks.
I was worried about overcoming
my triggers and road habits,
but normal traveling evening was dinner,
watch cable and drink eight beers.
To my surprise, the hotel
at a sweet gym. Cool.
I'll just keep doing what I'm doing.
Then at the site I found out that weren't,
we would start work at 6:00 AM.
Damn.
That means I have to get
up at four to workout.
I'm 12 weeks into my traveling.
Two a days,
usually getting 11 to 12 workouts a week.
They recently moved our start time to
7:00 AM so now I get an hour and a half in
the morning and evening.
I'm 16 weeks clean,
dropped 30 pounds or more.
I haven't been on a scale in three weeks.
34 waist jeans hanging off of me.
I sit up and pushed.
Upsets went from 10 to 40 to 50 kettlebell
swings went from 35 by 10 to 50 by 15
I started to learn how to run as,
I haven't done it in 20 years.
Now after a day off,
I can do two miles without stopping.
I do four to five miles on the treadmill
and nine miles on the bike besides the
sit ups, pushups,
kettlebells, core and weights.
I look forward to next year's
competitive shooting season.
I'm going to bring it at this point,
my cravings are gone and I actually
recoil from the smell of booze.
When I started this,
I thought it would be temporary.
Now it's going to be permanent.
No reason to waste time with it anymore.
Now when I questioned something, your
voice comes to me with the hard answer.
It's only black and
white with no gray area,
okay?
One day when I'm standing before the Lord,
Lord and hear his voice,
if it doesn't sound like yours,
I might be disappointed.
The book I read those months ago
was the way of the war. Your Kid,
I'm working on extreme ownership now.
Thank you for your service.
Thank you for producing a bad ass podcast
and thank you for influencing my life.
So
there you go.
And I, I say this to
people all the time. Okay?
Most important here is it isn't me,
it's you and sure you may have grabbed
some little foot hold from the podcast or
from one of the books, but it isn't
me. That changes you. It's you.
Yeah.
You set the small goals,
you achieve those goals,
then set some more and achieve
those and set some more goals.
Maybe a little bit bigger
but not that much bigger.
You pay attention to the progress.
This guy is 16 weeks deep,
30 pounds lighter, working
harder, stronger, faster,
more efficient,
competitive.
The individual that wrote that is
getting after it and changing his life.
And you can't too.
Just start,
just start small.
Start with changing tomorrow morning.
Just tomorrow morning.
Get that squared away.
Okay.
And then move on to the next day and
the next and move your life to a better
place.
One little step,
one little victory at a time.
Appreciate the letter.
And I think that's all
I've got for tonight.
So Echo speaking of people getting better,
stronger and faster
and actually supporting the podcast
if they want to do that. Sure.
Do you have any suggestions
for us? Sure, of course.
I can talk about the fact that origin
has a new key coming out.
Good one.
I don't know that the name
of the game. You know, geese
have names, you know, like,
okay, we'll origin does. Yup. Yup.
That's a cool name too by the way.
Axiom. But this one is called
I think discipline discipline,
I think it's called discipline
might be called discipline. Yeah.
Not The discipline does just discuss
discipline. I that could be called that.
Sure. You could check it
out. Origin main.com. Right.
Surprisingly aesthetically
great.
I would say it's,
I would say it's probably
is the term they use
like on brand on brand,
meaning it kind of fit fits
your brand. Okay, sure.
Let's say it does that. Yeah.
Yeah. It totally does it. Um,
it's like, yeah, it does.
It's not the kind of where,
you know how like some geese,
like you look at him,
you can tell there's like all these bells
and whistles as far as decorations go.
That's a good word. Decorations.
Yeah, yeah, yeah. So, but
he was looking for decking.
Right. Here's the thing though.
There are some, there are some, uh,
how should I say functional decorations
and now that's not actually a good word
for it anyway. It, it looks
cool. Put it that way.
It looks cool and it will basically um,
kind of lighter weight,
one for functionality
but awesome nonetheless.
Uh, look at it. I got a white
one. I know you got the black one.
How do you know I don't have both.
Yeah, I'm sure you do it both.
I'm still working on the black one
but that's the long story nonetheless.
It's a good one.
And
a lot like back when we first
started everyone would ask them that.
I don't want to say everyone, but a lot of
people. Yeah. You know, I don't like to,
it feels weird like yeah, a lot
of people, people, some people.
But the thing is a lot of people though,
cause like a lot of people ask,
should I get, I'm making the
disclaimer. It was a lot of people,
it wasn't the kind of like, Oh, you know,
my little brother asked me once
and then ask me again. It was.
It's a lot of people
maybe two times a week,
two times a week for two years. By
the way, that's a lot of people.
It's a decent amount of skin. The same
exact question. Anyway, they ask like, oh,
what can eat? Should I get? Or
whatever. Now there's like, yeah,
origin gies and then now
I'm saying get this one.
This is the one that's straight up.
I don't know that I'll wear any other key.
I'm not saying I won't.
I'm just saying I don't know that I,
yeah,
and actually I don't
know if you know this,
did you know that they're going to sell
this g and a certain number of them?
400 you're going to get a
copy of discipline equals
freedom field manual signed.
I signed it, so if you want a signed
copy, you know g and yeah, that'd be cool.
It's like a little little packages,
a little discipline package. Yeah.
If you end up
hating Jujitsu, what do
you do to hang up? Hang up,
hang up the hin. Hopefully you don't hate
Jujitsu like that one. A question today.
Yeah. Hopefully you love Jujitsu, most
likely you'll love Jujitsu. Good. Yeah,
hopefully. Yeah, if you're getting
the discipline equals freedom,
gay as a discipline equals freedom.
Get or just discipline.
Just be all the deaf geek. I Dunno. Well,
yeah, that's good. Deef disappointing.
Go through them. It's good. It's
embroidered as the American May. Yeah,
and it is made in America, like all
the words and stuff, but yes. Yeah,
that's a good one. Anyway,
look at Dalen get down.
If you're still looking for a GIG, get
down. Even if you're not looking for a,
you just look at this and pick worth.
He said on Twitter,
he's going to get the [inaudible].
You know he's not training
Jujitsu and then actually I have,
I didn't respond to Brandon,
but I'll respond right now.
Get the G and train Jujitsu.
It's the kind of where he's gonna.
He's gonna by the way.
He's going to get the GIG. It's
like, but then train Jujitsu or dude,
he's going to come on.
That's my bet.
I almost am challenging
him to prove me wrong.
That's how much anyway prove to everyone
that he could do a hundred burpees and
10 minutes. It was a challenge for her.
It's hard for him, but he did it. Yeah.
And that was, he's a reasonable
challenge on the mat. Yeah,
he's gonna you can't just get
the gains when you put it on.
And this goes for pretty much any like
legitimate gay when you put it on your
tray. And this is true, like you
ever, um, like we, we did it in Maine.
Like it happens all the time when you
had you put on the gay just to grab,
I grab it. You're like, oh,
it's time, you know, kind of
thing. Same exact thing. Yeah,
exactly. Right. Cool. And this
guy is no different. In fact,
it might even have that even
more that feeling. Yeah.
Yeah. Good nonetheless. Um,
yeah, so it comes from origin.
If you didn't already pick that part up.
Origin main.com.
There's a lot of Gisele in there.
Even if you want to get a another one
other than the you don't want to do.
I have all the patches that you know how
like like Naco Nolan and they'll give
you these patches and stuff like that.
I'm going to have all of them on Maggie.
All of them.
How many do you have?
About 12 cause I have like 90
I've got so many awesome patches from
fire departments, police departments,
military units all over the country.
Foreign. Yeah. I got a lot of stuff.
That would be a biggie. Yeah, you
got to put them on multiple. Jeez.
If you got the black and the white,
it wouldn't have enough room. Yeah.
Tan a lot of patches, bro. Yeah. Yeah.
And there's certain places
you can't really put them to,
so that even limits you more.
But I'm doing it.
I'm starting it and if I run out of
space, I'm getting another geek. Boom.
I'm going to keep it going. I do
kind of risk people saying, hey,
you're not law enforcement.
Why are you wearing that patch?
Like some of those patches to me
seem like you, you give me a NASA
one, like that's to shoot. Should
I be even wearing this patch?
We got friends at NASA,
I'm going to wear it and we'll say this
is from my friends at NASA. Great up.
Anyway. Anyway, back to origin, origin.
That's all American made stuff from
the cotton out of the ground. American
to the factory. American
factory in America, in Maine.
Make the material, make the
clothing, make the gies,
make the rash guards make do.
What else do they have? Some bags,
gym bags and whatnot. Accessories, I
believe they're called accessories. Yeah.
Like beanies and tee shirts.
All made in America. Yeah.
I think when I told Jordan Peterson that,
I think he liked it even though even
though he's not American. Yeah, yeah.
Still and and the supplements.
Yeah,
from origin labs yet those
are Jocko supplements.
So here's the thing,
I'm going to,
I'll go into the details later.
But Super Krill.
There is a legitimate difference between
Super Krill in regular Krill oil.
There is, and it's very beneficial.
I'm not going to say it right now,
but just know super
krill oil, Jocko, brand,
joint warfare, Jocko brand
for your joints, supplements,
boom. Jocko came out with it.
That's the stuff from the beginning.
That was the main supplements,
you know, joint stuff. Krill oil,
you're the number one reason,
not even the number.
And the only reason I started
taking it and I'm kind of mad.
I didn't take it before. Yeah. You were
behind and now you got your own one,
which is even better. Yeah, it's super,
it's super as a matter of paper. Yeah.
But it's not just a name though.
The joint warfare has, uh,
some magic in it. Sure.
In my opinion. Sure. And,
and in my shoulders opinion. Yeah.
Left shoulder both of my shoulders,
my back and my elbows. So yeah. Or
domain.com. That's the place to go.
Also, some legitimate fitness gear.
Everyone knows I'm into kettle bells now.
I get mine from on it. They're the
cool ones. Straight up. That's it.
I don't think I could go
back to regular kettlebells.
It's my opinion. The Werewolf
at the big foot, 90 pounds,
two pounds heavier than Jockos
heaviest kettle bell. Every rep,
I think Jordan Peterson was impressed
with that too by the way. He was.
That makes one of us
also.
Oh sorry.
[inaudible] dot com slash
Jocko that's the one good spot.
You know also good way to support
when you buy books that Jocko reviews,
I guess technically I kind
of had help review them
in a real kind of distant direct,
yes,
indirect way. Anyway, those books,
very compelling books when you get
them go through the website Jocko,
podcast.com little tab on the
top says books from podcasts.
Go through there by the
books through there.
That's a good way to support take you
to Amazon shop. Just the way you know,
prime one day shipping,
whatever you choose.
Just like anything else
but go through that.
It's a good way to support and do any
other shopping you have to do. Carry on.
Good way to support. Also subscribe
to the podcast on Itunes, stitcher,
Google play depending on what kind of
platform you prefer or
is available to you.
Cause iPhone I think doesn't
have stitcher, right? No.
My iPhone has stitcher.
Oh wait, no. Android doesn't
have a l s I don't know.
Apple. Yeah. I don't think you
could listen to it. I don't. Maybe,
I don't know either. I Dunno,
but you can get it man. Yeah.
Your podcast is out there.
You can subscribe to it. The
point is subscribed to it.
Yes. Yes. Subscribe to it on that one.
It's a good leave a review if you want.
If you're in the mood, leave review.
Also subscribe to it on Youtube.
The video version of this
podcast is a good one still,
and I still do get the
whole thing like, oh, echo,
you don't look like you sound.
And I remember it.
Change the way you talk. Yeah.
Yeah. Or change the way I look.
I don't give her no. Get skinny. Yeah.
Get less jacked. That is it.
It's kind of an intuitive thing.
Youtube comments like one out of every
20 youtube comments is Echos Jack.
Yeah,
that's flooded.
It kind of is because you wouldn't think
that you could determine what someone
looks like by what they sound like.
But it feels like you can,
I think a lot of times you can.
I don't know though,
actually now that you think about like
talk show hosts on radios. Yeah. Yeah.
You don't know what yeah, it's kind
of can't I guess it's uh, it's, it's,
it's harder to do than you think.
Yeah. If feels like you can't. Yeah.
If someone has like a d, I
dunno, like a deep voice.
You think they're huge or something
or you know, like something like that.
Not necessarily true. Yeah, not true
at all. Remember that Seinfeld One?
No, they're there. The guy who
was like, she, I think Elaine,
who's the girl in there?
[inaudible] she was like, oh,
he had a good looking voice or something.
Like he sounded like he was good
looking or something like that.
How'd it turn out at the,
I don't know. I forget.
I think he was telling that story.
You remember it? Yeah. The analogy,
I didn't remember it, but it reminded
me of that nonetheless. Anyway,
youtube subscribe to Youtube.
That's the point there.
Regardless of if you want to
know what I look like or not.
Doesn't even matter what I
look like. Really? Barely.
Maybe a little bit I guess maybe I see
because if I see you out in the wild,
it'll you know,
we can recognize each other if you
know what I look like beneficial.
There's times when people will recognize
you and your like say, Oh yeah,
this is Echo Charles.
Ian,
you can tell on their face like are you
sure that this is talking to you though?
Kind of encountered that for sure.
For real like I know for sure.
That's cool. I dig it but if you
want to avoid that kind of situation,
subscribe to Youtube, good way to
do it and could witness support.
Also Jack was a store.
It's called Jocko store Jocko
store.com we have tee shirts on there.
If you want these tee shirts.
I'm wearing my good tee shirt right now.
I haven't worn this one anytime.
The original.
That's really high quality
layers too by the way.
The good is backwards to look at in
the mirror. That message is for you.
If you think about the whole message of
good, I mean I know you said it, you know,
you know you were like good kind of thing,
but you were kind of
like you guys had the,
the luxury of you being there
to be able to explain it.
If someone's going through
like something hard, it's,
you can't just automatically just say
good. It kind of comes off kind of weird.
Yeah,
potentially.
That's why I put this backwards cause
it's like you tell yourself good.
You see what I'm saying? That's the layer.
That's the little insight to the layer.
I'm not going to go deep and I'm not
going to go into any of the other
explanations for the other layers,
but just know that they have layers
on all the clothing on Jacqueline,
store.com check it out. I'm not saying
to buy something. I'm saying go on there,
look on there. If you like something,
get something good way to support this.
A women's stuff on their t
shirts. Like I said, some patches,
rash guards for Jujitsu or
anything physical cycling,
anything requiring range of motion.
Maybe some compression situations.
Highest static value but not too high
because it's more about functionality.
That's my take on the whole deal. But
they do look good and they have layers.
Hoodies are in
being shipped out right now.
They're in heavy. Do you have
one? No, Dang girl. Sorry.
Well we are in California so you
know it's not that big of a deal.
You know you got your old one,
it's all good.
But yeah there's some hoodies on there.
Some warrior kid's rash guards are coming.
Boom cause people have been asking me
about that cause I wore one that was like
a test one and I wore one
when I was training with Dave,
Dave Burke and they're like oh where
you could rush card, you know, whatever.
But I was trying to narrow down kind
of the colors and stuff but they are
narrowed down and they shouldn't be
available within the next week and a half.
Where are those made?
Those are made all in America.
All in America where he keyed rash guards.
Also, there's another kind of cool,
fun one, but I want to talk
about Dell until later. Also,
good way to support yourself.
Psychological warfare,
if you didn't know what that is,
it's an album with tracks,
Jocko tracks and there are to aid you in
the event of you needing aid and you're
campaigning against weakness on your path,
on the path.
Okay, so here's the thing about the
path. It's not always going to be easy.
You know what I'm saying? I know what
you're saying. Yeah. Every day, man,
this is not a one day Gig.
This is in every day.
Every day is a Monday on the path.
Here's,
I will say this though. Okay, so, and you,
you read the letter for
the guy with drinking.
I guess I could relate to that deeply.
Deeply could relate to that and in a way,
and I don't want to go too deep into it,
but in a way that my situation was in a
way harder because the drinking wasn't
preventing me from working out.
It wasn't preventing me from
doing like a lot of stuff.
It was only preventing me from
doing like a handful of things,
but those things are really wanted to do,
but it was really preventing
me or it was put it this way,
it was making it super difficult and
then just the fact of like I'm drinking
every single day, you know kind of thing.
And the more you do, you know how you,
the more you get in the routine on
some with something, the harder,
the harder it is to just straight a break.
That routine,
especially when it provides the payoff
is like drinking does chemically, I mean,
you know like when you drink it
like an instantaneous exactly right.
The longterm payoff,
no longterm negative,
like not even proportionately
more beneficial to,
to to stop drinking. Like
you know when he said, wow,
this is how every day people
walk around feeling good. Really.
I felt that statement. Right. That's
so true. That's exactly what I thought.
I'm like Dang, no wonder. Tricky tricking
these feed Jocko doesn't drink. Right.
So no wonder Jack was doing
all this stuff and I could,
I could do all that stuff too.
That's how you feel.
I'm not saying I'm doing all this stuff.
Well, I'm just saying that's the feeling.
Psyche. I could dig it anyway.
Point is when you're on this path,
it's not always easy,
but psychological warfare is there to
get you through those difficult parts
parts that you admit or that
you can admit that you need.
Maybe a little little push, a little
help, little spot, waking up early,
procrastinating. That's a big one.
Skipping the workout, that kind of stuff.
Psychological warfare.
Okay,
so there's a track for every
little weakness he might encounter.
Skipping the Diet or, or, or slacking on
the Diet. That's a good one. Um, but yeah,
check that one out and uh, you know, see
what up. Good way to support yourself in.
You're on the path when you're on the
path and support the podcast as well.
Also,
you can get some Jocko white tea,
which tastes like victory and
will make you feel really good.
You get that on Amazon. The books
way, the warrior kid number one,
which we just covered. Obviously it
is not just a book for kids. Yeah.
Uncle Jake has something to
teach. All of us, myself included,
it's for adults and teenagers and anyone
else that wants to have a better life.
Can I add something about where the work?
Yeah.
Which, and a I'm on a cycle. I
just read it over and over again.
Like as just like a routine to
your daughter. Daughter. Yeah.
She's four and a half so she
can't quite read yet. Um,
but there's little things
in there that it's like,
this is really good that
these kids are getting this,
this message because it's stuff
that as an adult you're like, Dang,
I never really, even though you know
it, like, okay, and this is what it is.
When you're like,
how do you expect to be good at
something if you don't practice?
Like kids don't know that they
don't, they straight up don't. Yeah.
And guided practice, we kind of forget
that in a way. No, we absolutely do.
Yeah.
So yeah,
it's for sure there's a lot in that book
and sometimes I read that book and I,
and, and there's even more in there than
I even recognized. You know what I mean?
The lessons that are coming out
of my head, they're so important.
They're like beyond my own comprehension.
And I was just explaining the
book way of the Warrior Kid too,
which is going to come out. And I
was, I was just talking through a, uh,
with a guy yesterday. Like
what, what it's about.
And as I'm explaining
everything that it's about,
it's a lot of stuff and it's a lot
of really important lessons. Yes. Um,
but yeah, it starts with the
way of the warrior kid. Uh,
the second warrior could
book will be out April 28th,
2018 actually speaking of books,
there is extreme ownership.
A new edition, a new edition is
out. It's not a totally new book.
It's a new addition of it.
It's going to be available November 21st.
You can get it for preorder right
now on Amazon if you want it. Um,
it's got a new forward in it. So,
so Leif and I wrote a new forward,
it has some color pictures
in it. Um, also the,
the new cover is black. We changed
the color from white to black. Why?
Because block dope. Yes, because
it looks cooler way cooler. Also,
and this is interesting,
there's a new Q and a section in the back
of the book that is actually from this
podcast.
So I kind of rounded up the most
prominent leadership questions that, that,
that we've answered on this podcast and
wrote them up and kind of Ed had it,
added him a little bit to make
sure that they made sense without,
without everything we've talked about
today without the tone and the pacing of
what's being said. Excited,
edit them a little bit,
but they're there what they're,
what the answers were given on this
podcast and they're all from everyone's
questions. So everyone, uh,
appreciate the questions.
Everyone that listens to the podcast,
you helped us write this
next section of this book.
Echo Charles is in it
as the question asker.
So Echo Charles is in the book and
I'll hold it up if you're on youtube,
there's the new book right
there. Boom, discipline or sorry,
extreme ownership available November
21st also you can get the book discipline
equals freedom field manual.
It's a manual for getting after it.
So if you want to get after
it, get, get the field manual.
Discipline equals freedom, faults
and actions. They're both in there.
It's been great. Again, getting great
feedback. Appreciate everyone's feedback.
It's pretty straightforward book.
No fluff involved,
not,
not making you read a bunch of
words to get to my point.
Here's my point. Boom.
You can get it anywhere that they,
that they sell books
including obviously Amazon,
Barnes and noble. You can get it at
Walmart by the way. Target the publisher,
ship that out to everywhere
so you can pick it up.
It's a good book to give to people.
In my opinion.
It's, it's, it's not just
like giving someone a book,
you're giving them something
a little bit more than a book.
It's like something a little bit more
than a book. It's, I dunno if I can't,
I can't explain it too well
right now. Look at it. Yeah.
Yeah. You can look at it.
It's, it's not normal. I
would say it's not normal. Um,
if you want the audio
version of that book,
which a lot of people have been asking
about, the audio version is available.
It is not on audible and it
is not going to be on audible.
It is made and we put it together,
echo directed and produced the album that
also has tracks so it's an album with
tracks and it's available as MP3 anywhere
that you can get MP3 tracks for sale,
iTunes, Amazon, music,
music, Google play, wherever.
Whenever MP3 platform you utilize,
you can find it there and if you like
the leadership principles that we talk
about on this podcast and you want to
get them for your team or your business.
We have a leadership and
management consulting company.
It's called echelon front.
It's me. It's Lafe Babin.
It's JP Denelle. It's
Dave Burke. You can email
info@echelonfrontdotcomoryoucanjustcheckoutthewebsiteechelonfront.com
and
if you
have more questions or you have answers
to the questions that we covered that
are better than the answers that we gave
today and you want to share them with
us, that'd be cool. I want
to learn, you can find us.
We're actually on the interwebs,
on Twitter,
on Instagram, on Dash facey bowl. Aha.
Echo is an echo.
Charles and I am at Jocko
Willink and to close out,
I want to say thanks to our military
that's out there on the front lines.
I recently got reports of
Isis in Iraq sending kids to,
to surrender to coalition forces,
but they'd been laden with suicide bombs
and rigged to blow up and as these kids
would approach the areas set aside
for surrender to American forces,
they would,
the Americans would see the terror in
their eyes and realize that there was
something wrong.
And American military men,
especially explosive ordinance disposal
technicians would risk their lives time
and time again to go disarm these bombs,
risking their lives so that
these young children can live.
Who?
Who even does that?
Yeah.
I'll tell you who America's
servicemen and women.
Yeah,
they are the finest and we thank them
for their service and sacrifice and to
police and law enforcement,
firefighters or paramedics,
other first responders.
Thank you for doing your job.
Extremely difficult,
often thankless,
keeping us safe here on the home front
and to everyone else that is listening.
Remember this, if there's something
in your life that you want to change,
then change it.
You have control.
And if you don't think you have control,
then take control.
Get a grip on your life
and start getting after it.
So until next time,
this is echo and Jocko out.