This is Jocko podcast number
33 with Echo Charles and me,
Jocko Willink. Good
Evening Echo. Good evening.
People say
there is a line,
there's a line between good and evil,
right and wrong between light
and dark.
And that's a nice clean
way to think of things.
But the line can be hard to recognize.
It can get blurry,
it can get twisted by emotion
and passion and by one's own ego,
they in war,
that line is tested,
it's pressed,
it becomes even more blurry.
It gets crossed and violated
and sometimes abandoned.
Or we can see that throughout history
and we've talked about it here in the
Japanese slave camps in Rwanda,
it me lie,
those are a few examples,
but there are thousands of them,
okay?
And obscene the line.
And I've seen men approach the line
driven field with fury and with hate.
And that fury needs an outlet.
And if it gets a purchase,
it can become unstoppable.
But it can also be controlled,
okay?
Because there is a
counter to all that evil,
okay?
There is the man that steps up and says,
no,
no, not today, not here, not
now. We will not do that.
Okay.
And the dichotomy of leadership
and that they caught him.
He of war is so hard to balance.
Soldiers are trained and
to have asked to kill
and yet they are also trained to be
humane and fair and moral and good
[inaudible].
So how does a warrior reconcile
those opposing forces?
That dichotomy.
How does he know to balance
God damn faults rush through my mind
is I tried to decide what to do.
Women,
old men and kids,
obviously non combatants but
this is a free fire zone.
They are not supposed to be
civilians in this area. Yeah,
but dinks occasionally ignore those
warnings about free fire areas.
Maybe they're the point element for
Vietcong or Nva traveling behind them.
Maybe they're supposed to give the
warning if stopped. It's happened before.
In that case,
some of my men could come under fire
and be killed or wounded for six killed
that one dink last evening
and he had a Thompson,
there was a whole squad
of Kong in that group.
There was some incoming fire
when we made the Elz a dink,
try to cost cross the dyke last night.
These people look innocent enough.
They may be carrying supplies for the
Kong in the area, food and or Ammo.
It's a free fire zone. Everyone is
supposed to be considered enemy.
I'm responsible for my men. They'll get
killed if I make the wrong decision.
These dinks coming toward
us mean nothing to me.
My men mean everything.
What if the dinks aren't innocent?
My men depend on me to keep them alive.
I spoke softly to the men around me.
It's a lick on them.
When I give the order open fire,
I brought up the [inaudible]
to site in on the dinks.
SPAG was standing to my right,
his m 60 machine gun support it on
his hip by a sling around his neck and
shoulder.
He reached over and touched my arm.
His whispered voice reflected
the agony of doubt in his face.
No Sir, you can't kids, women.
He motioned toward the file
of people coming towards us.
I felt ashamed.
SPAG was right.
Wait one I whispered to the men around me,
I'll call for them to surrender.
I felt relieved capturing them.
What's the best solution?
If they were the point for a VC group,
I would just make sure none
of us was exposed to fire.
When we captured this point, the dinks,
we're almost to the intersection.
I stepped through the brush with some
of my men dung. Louis don't. Louis,
I warned they were only
10 to 20 meters from us.
They all glanced at us standing
with our weapons, trained on them.
We had them dead to rights.
They had no cover on no place to
run to a perfect capture situation.
Almost in mid.
They all moved with astonishing speed.
The two boys in the point split up. The
one ran past us heading down the trail,
pass the school house,
the other boy, the woman,
the old men started running back
towards the bridge. Stop. Stop.
Don't like Deloitte. I yelled to
no avail. I could not order them,
the men to run after them. It could be a
trap. Neither could I let them get away.
Why were they running in the split?
Second,
those thoughts ran across
my consciousness. I gave
the order to open fire
and irrevocable wave of
death swept in front of us.
After the initial burst of
gunfire, I yelled, cease fire.
The two women survive long enough to
cross the bridge and enter one of the
hooches.
Three of my men crossed over the bridge
and threw grenades and the hutches.
We heard lead looked over the bodies on
the trail since they were lying in the
open and we had no desire
to be caught exposed.
The men reported that some of the dead
had been carrying hand grenades in their
ammo and ammo packs.
I felt somewhat relieved.
Those supplies could have been for, could
not have been for anyone but the Kong
I received report from
the squad down the trail.
The firing had alerted them barely fast
enough to fire at the teenager running
toward them down the trail. Someone hit
him in the shoulder and knocked him down.
Surprisingly,
the boy had jumped up and run past the
squad to safety somewhere in the brush.
I had no pleasure in reporting to Delta
six that we had killed six dinks and one
wounded. I knew who you would ask how
many happened weapons we had captured.
I stared at the gray horizon for a long
time before answering that. The dinks,
we're not carrying weapons,
only supplies and grenades.
I felt low this putrid war.
I thought of so many ways I
could have done it differently,
so easy to think afterward.
After all,
now I knew there was no dink
squad behind on the trail.
This episode would be
the darkest of my career.
I called my men together for a march
up the slight hill to Delta six his
position forcing the dinks out of my mind.
Now that's from a book that
we're looking at tonight.
It's called the killing zone, my life
and the Vietnam War by Frederick downs.
Now Vietnam,
it was a hard war,
obviously a wretched
whore for many reasons,
and the mee Lai massacre
is almost the apex,
almost the pinnacle.
It almost seems like the essence
of the war in many respects.
At least it's viewed that way and
it did have a huge strategic impact.
It was devastating to the war effort
and something that should always be
remembered is that tactical
operations can have strategic impact.
Like Hackworth said,
the mee Lai massacre probably did more
to end the war and he snored departure
from Vietnam.
Then anything are communist enemy did
okay
in in a similar vein in the war I was in,
in the mistreatment of the prisoners
in Abu Ghraib prison in Iraq and the
photographs that showed that mistreatment
likely did more to fuel the insurgency
in that country than
anything al Qaeda did.
Okay.
Tactical actions can have strategic impact
and that actually happens in business
too.
One bad customer experience for a customer
that's got some reach and there can
really be a strategic impact and what
the front line troops do really does
matter and what the frontline troops
do is based on how they are led.
Clearly in me lie,
there was a total lack of leadership,
especially from the moral
and an ethical perspective,
but this was not the norm,
not by any stretch and,
and like I said,
it's viewed sometimes as
the representation of what
the Vietnam War was like,
but it's not an, and I said this
when we talked about me lie, yeah,
America has done monstrous
things in our history,
but we most certainly are not monstrous.
We are an amazingly benevolent nation,
especially now perhaps
even to our own detriment,
but that's why I wanted
to talk about this book,
the killing zone to show the challenges,
the Vietnam War and how American troops
handled those challenges and pressures
on a day to day basis and how they
sometimes cross that line if only for a
moment,
but then
most of the time brought themselves
back from the brink of darkness
into the light.
Now let's go back to the book here.
Okay.
Going to the beginning when Fred downs
young lieutenant in the army is flying
into Vietnam at 2130 hours.
The continental big bird with a golden
tail DCA dropped through the night sky
into the landing pattern over
the black landscape of Vietnam.
23 hours earlier,
165 of us had been crammed a board,
the commercial jet at the
airport near San Francisco.
I looked around the cabin at the
officer and enlisted at the officers and
enlisted men who'd come from all over the
United States to catch his flight from
San Francisco.
How would they return?
How would I return?
I had graduated six months earlier from
the U S Army to ocs program at Fort
Benning, Georgia, and now I would
seem to be leading men into combat.
I was 23 years old and I had
been trained to lead physically.
I thought I was ready.
Mentally.
I was as confident of myself
as any young officer could be,
but underneath my confidence
where the ever present questions,
worry and curiosity about
war and my role in it,
I was eagerly looking
forward to finding answers.
I would not have to wait long.
So we've talked about that before. When
you're stepping into a leadership role,
you're not going to get,
if there's a good chance,
you're not going to feel a hundred
percent confident. And that's okay.
So he gets to Vietnam,
he gets assigned to a fourth
division and he actually,
he hadn't heard of fourth division,
he hadn't seen it in the papers.
And he kind of is asking, hey, why, why,
why haven't I see that in the papers?
What are they doing?
And he said,
there's no reporters up there where
they're working. It's too rough for him.
And he's kind of saying, you know, I want
to get, I want to make sure I get it on.
And in some of the old timers are
telling them, one of them says,
you'll get a belly full of fighting up
there, son, if that's what you want.
So it's one of those,
be careful what you wish for scenarios.
And uh, I thought this was pretty,
pretty interesting. You know,
we talk about Hackworth and the hardcore
rock condos as the salute and reply.
The reply is no fucking slack.
So here's what they had here.
It was sop to solute in the fee and
the company area, but not in the field.
When enlisted man saluted, he
would say Golden Dragon, sir.
The officer would return the
salute with right of the line.
I asked about this. They told me that
in that the first, the 14th that's the,
that's the division.
He's with the first.
The 14th was an old infantry
regiment steeped in tradition.
During the boxer rebellion in China,
the unit had fought bravely.
Afterward they adopted the
symbol of a golden dragon.
The other part of the
solute came from some,
some battle in the civil war
right before large battle,
a staff officer asked a general where
to put the first to the 14th the general
had roared back, put them to the
right of the line where they belong.
The right of the line is where a leader
traditionally puts his best men in units.
This comes down through military history.
When a man fought with
the shield and sword,
the right arm or sword
arm was unprotected.
The best fighter was put the right to
protect the sword arm of the man on his
left.
Only the most trusted and best fighters
held the position to the right.
Legit.
So he's there in the, in
kind of in the, in the uh,
headquarters area for a little while
and then he gets his indoctrination and
then gets flown out.
He's flies out into the field into
where he's going to be operating out of.
He gets up there, and this is, this
is straight out of a movie right here.
Bug swarmed around my face.
I squatted and looked at the
men who looked right back at me.
It was my first view of American Gis who
had spent several days in the jungle.
I stood there and sparkling,
crisp, fatigues, brand new boots,
new rifle, clean shaven, fresh
haircut. I even smelled clean.
My helmet, camouflage cover didn't
have a mark on it, nor did I.
The two men opposite me were filthy.
They're fatigues or torn and they
had scratches all over their skin.
Two or three days of growth on their
beard and dark circles under their eyes.
They look tired and they smelled
the high heavens. So that's,
that's right out of a movie. The boot
lieutenant coming in to take over,
he's in his pressed Cam,
he's looking all squared away and these
guys look like they're living in hell.
And they introduce the,
the company commander and this guy
you're going to see throughout the book,
this guy captain cells was an
ROTC officer, 26 years old,
son of the son of a father
killed in Korea. So that's,
you know,
the guy's dad got killed in Korea and
he's there during the Vietnam War.
He's joining up and leading men at
a comedy is a company commander.
And if you remember from, from the
book platoon leader where you remember,
he didn't even meet the company commander.
So his direct boss didn't
even meet him for weeks.
He'd been in the field for weeks
before I even met him. And here's this,
this company commander obviously much
more squared away, walks him around,
introduces into, everybody's
given him a heads up, you know,
this is the way it's supposed to be.
And you know, he's getting told, look,
there's any me all around.
And you might've heard in
that intro piece that I read,
I was talking about Delta six and,
and here's a little piece about that.
He informed me that his
radio signal was delta six.
So that's the Delta company commanders,
Delta Six, Lieutenant Smart,
the first platoon leader
was delta one six.
The second platoon leader was Delta two
six six is where the commanders of the
unit. And this is a tradition
that holds true in the,
in the army and the Marine Corps today.
And it's pretty cool when you're,
when you're in the field,
you'd hear someone call for the six and,
and that means that we want to talk
to the guy that's in charge out there.
Their seconds, a command. We're
known as fives. For instance,
Delta one five was the first platoon
sergeant. And this is a, you know,
goes on to talk a little bit
more about captain cells,
who's asking him about his
family. He's getting to know
him and he's, you know, uh,
uh, down's had, I had a wife and
two little girls back in Illinois.
And so again,
you're getting,
the impression that sells is a guy that's
trying to get to know his people when
they learn about them, which
is, which is the way a leader,
what a leader should be doing.
Now these guys are out
and he's talking again.
This is, this is something straight
out of a straight out of a movie,
darkness quickly and Gulf to us.
My hooch.
May Ch watched an astonishment as I
pulled out mosquito netting and spread it
over my poncho liner and air mattress.
They were aghast that I carried so
much extra weight. No, I answered.
This is all the good stuff.
That amazement grew as I revealed three
changes of underwear and fatigue. Close.
Wait until the next day they scoffed
when the sun is sun and heavy pack will
drag me down.
The jungle would exact a toll for every
ounce I carried. We'll see. I answered.
Not a good answer. Lieutenant
Smart said. Yeah. You'll see.
You'll see that the only change of clothes
your carriers and be an extra pair of
socks,
you'll learn to live in one set of
jungle fatigues until they rot off you or
grip to badly to where that's that. That
actually reminds me when we were in, uh,
my, my first deployment to Iraq, we, uh,
we had three sets of cammies and just
warm rotated them in Ramadi that the op
tempo was so high and the conditions of
fighting we had to order new cammies.
We then within a couple
of weeks of being there,
guys had destroyed Caymus can run across
the street. They're getting, you know,
dragging people and they were
just ruining their, their cammies.
So that was another indicator in Ramadi
that we were in a totally different
scenario than I was on my
first deployment to Iraq.
Back to the book.
My first days on combat control,
combat patrol introduced me
to the vicissitudes of war,
10 foot deep Punji pits.
Wait a minute,
vines at collected around the feet and
legs until the combined strength stopped
you. And you had to say, wait a minute
while you untangled or cut yourself loose.
The Hot Sun beating down on us, on us as
we marched around with 70 pound packs,
the sweat pouring office,
the bugs,
so stick our faces that around our faces
that we sometimes inhaled them of and
the physical agony of forcing
tired muscles to keep going.
It was a search and destroy mission,
which meant we searched all the hooches
we found and then burn them down whether
a single farmers, hooch or a
whole village, all were burnt.
The few Vietnamese we found in
the area where women, children,
old men who had been left behind, when we
started to burn their particular hooch,
they would start wailing, crying,
and pulling in our clothes.
We didn't harm the people, but the
orders were to destroy all the dwellings.
So we did.
The first time I saw a Vietnamese family
go into hysterics when their hooch was
set on fire,
I was unsure of whether burning their
home would accomplish our mission.
The mission was to deny the enemy use
of the hooches to destroy any food we
found had to teach. The people a
lesson about supporting the enemy.
But I quickly got used to it and accepted
that this was one way to win the war.
And that's, you know, a
few. If you talk to anybody,
anybody knowledgeable about
true counterinsurgency,
this is not a great plan to go in and
basically abuse the populous. Now,
if you know that they're supporting
the, the insurgence, sure you want to,
you want to disrupt that.
But oftentimes they're not this,
they're not supporting the
insurgents because they want to,
they're there supporting the insurgents
because their fear for their lives.
That's the way it was in Iraq when,
when I was there.
So back to the book,
Sheldon brand took the opportunity
later that day to explain in the,
in this unit,
everyone called the enemy and
ultimately all outsiders dinks.
So that's their word that they use.
And I found this interesting. He says,
ultimately all outsiders, and you've
reverbed me and eve or lay from,
in the book we talk about Moose.
That's what we call it, the enemy,
we'd call it the enemy MOOC.
But what's interesting is here it says
all outsiders and that's exactly what we
do. If when we were getting
resistance from, you know,
up the chain of command
down the chain of command,
guess what we call them Moosh we'd say
all the boss is saying this or can't
believe that Mooc. So it became
the word that we use to every,
to all outsiders and that's,
that's the unit cohesion and there's
some dehumanization of the enemy there
obviously,
but the fact that you ended up using
the same slang word to describe anybody
that's against you is,
is is interesting.
Back to the book,
it turned out that the enemy started
calling us dinks first because it was an
insulting or demeaning term that
meant hairy man from the jungle.
We had just turned the word around
and started calling them dinks.
At least that was the story. I don't
know if that's true or not. I never,
never read it,
didn't do any research on that one.
I saw the face of the
enemy for the first time.
He'd been machine gun down
by one of our gun crews.
The powerful weapon and throwing a hail
of bullets into the brush where we had
spotted him.
When we got to his position,
I saw for the first time
the death of a soldier.
The machine gun crew had done a good job.
The young soldiers,
green combat uniform body
was riddled with bullets.
He was sprawled across his bicycle
with his face toward the sky. At last,
I had before me,
the enemy I had been trained to destroy.
He was a young man for whom the war
and life had ended. One evening,
a jet was returning to base and needed
a target to get rid of his unexpended
bomb load.
The captain called the forward
air controller and gave
them the coordinates of a
sniper 300 meters away who had been
pestering us off and on for three days.
As the jet pulled up after dropping
napalm on the snipers position,
we could hear the pop pop of
the sniper firing at the jet.
The men talked about the of that sniper.
As I watched the napalm burned itself out.
I wondered what would drive a man to
stand up to death and so remarkable a
manner.
Okay,
gain.
You're dealing with a hardened enemy.
You're getting napalm dropped on your
position and as you burned to death,
you're trying to shoot down a jet fighter.
Back to the book,
Sheldon brand was worth his weight in
gold to me in running that platoon,
he even introduced me to the
platoon motto. It's a lick.
A lick is a lick on a
young man's ass lieutenant.
You remember when you were a kid and
you did something wrong or something got
fucked up that you got the blame for the
old man would give you a licon with a
switch or a belt. Yeah, I sure
remember getting lickings well,
when something goes wrong, it's a lick
on you. You see anything that goes wrong,
I'll give you a lick and over
here you'll get plenty of licks.
My RTO was, or the other most
important man to the platoon.
His job was to carry the radio
and stick to me like a shadow.
The radio was our link with literally
everything outside our platoon from
supplies to survival without a
working radio. When a good Rto,
opportune leader and the platoon
were as good as lost in this war.
My RTO man, a skinny kid,
five feet, 11 inches tall,
was next to perfect for his job.
He loved to know what's going on.
And his job was a kin to the
central switchboard operators.
So that's the RTO. That's what that was
actually when I was an enlisted seal.
That's what I was. So I was a, I always
had that same attitude. When you're there,
when you're the Rto,
you always know what's going on cause the,
the officer's telling you,
you're right next to him.
You're listening to what he's saying.
So you always know what's going on.
And that was a real good education for me.
Hmm.
Grown my whole career.
Always be next to the,
to the guy that was
running in the platoon.
Talk a little bit about the troops here.
My squad leaders were first squad Delk,
a tall cowboy type from Wyoming,
second squad porter.
I light a slightly built black from east
Saint Louis, third squad, Jose, a skinny,
short, sparkly Puerto Rican
fourth squad, Gallagher,
a medium built redhead
from New England states.
And of course there was
the platoon medic doc,
but platoon makeup was whites,
blacks, Puerto Ricans, Mexicans,
Americans and an Indian
and a Japanese American.
All of them from 18 to 21
years old in a combat platoon.
We were evaluated by our peers on our
ability to help the platoon survive and
not on our racial backgrounds.
A combat platoon pulled together
and was tight with each other,
with no room for the soldier who
wouldn't do is share. So I, you know,
it's always good to just point that out.
These are just people for this,
a cross section of America and these,
these are pretty stereotypical,
right at cowboy from Wyoming.
It, you know, this is,
this is stereotypical stuff and that's,
that's one thing that the military,
so when I joined,
I grew up in New England,
right when I joined the navy and I got
to California and I went to the enlisted
man's Club on any B Corp Natto.
The gator gardens back in the day,
I was 18 years old,
19 years old. And I showed up, you know,
cause there's a club, it's a
club on base, right? And so I go,
oh, I'm going to go there.
People are saying, hey, we're
going to go to the club.
So I go, okay, well let's go
see what's going on there.
So I walk over to the club and
as I'm kind of standing outside,
I see two guys walk by with,
with jeans on,
with cowboy boots,
with big belt buckles and cowboy
hats and like a wrangler shirt.
And I was kind of thinking to myself, oh
that, that's there. Is there some kind of,
is it Halloween is the, these guys get
dressed up for something. And again,
this is pre internet
man. I mean, and, and,
and then I see a couple more guys go by
and it turned out it was country Western
night, but at the club, at the club.
But I had never seen a person in,
you know,
I come from a small town in,
in Connecticut and there's,
there's,
there's just no cowboys up there.
I mean,
interestingly there's farms and there's
people that raise cattle and there's
people that grow.
You don't have have farms,
but they don't have cowboy boots
and they don't wear cowboy hats.
And so it's just,
that's what I,
that's what I was thinking about when I
read this is just how you take all these
different people from all over the place.
They had no idea.
You have no idea what other people are
like. And again, this is pre internet.
You know, when I joined the navy, we
didn't get to Google. We didn't watch it.
Youtube videos because you,
you're exposed to the entire planet and,
and galaxy through youtube.
Yeah.
First Time you saw a
real cowboy. How it is.
I thought, I thought they were,
I thought they were dressed up.
Yeah, it's crazy. It is kinda crazy.
Okay.
And then, you know, I ended
up, I mean the, in, in tea,
you bruiser we had all kinds of guys from
Texas and there's all kinds of cowboys
down in Texas. Uh, but
like Graham and Chris,
Chris Kyle was like a legit whatever
Rodeo dude in Lafe later cowboy place and
absolute cowboy. Yeah, absolutely. I mean
there's all kinds of cowboys in there.
Yeah.
So all right.
Now we were going to advance a little
bit and it's the first time that that
Downes is actually in charge. Um,
he did a little turnover with the,
with the form of platoon commander.
He takes charge of a platoon and he's
doing security for the bridges for some
bridges that are out kind
of away from the main camp.
And they're out there to prevent landmines
and gathering Intel and kind of set
up a checkpoint. And, and
they're, they're, they're,
they're actually staying out there.
So they would,
they would set up by these bridges and
as they're getting set up for the first
time, I'm going to the book and
explosion, rip the air behind me,
followed immediately by a scream.
My body instinctively through my,
through itself, against the sandbags
is my mind shouted, mortar attack,
my eyes registered the scene of
men frozen in shocked Wunderman,
their eyes staring behind me.
Man was directly in front
of me and the track man,
we're off in the background
crouching where they,
where they were when
the explosions went off.
So they're actually out there with some
tracked vehicles quickly turning around
my eyes swept and awful catastrophe.
One of the claymores had
gone off shattering for over
the lives of the three men
in front of it. Jesus Christ was in a
mortar. No one of our claymores went off.
Get those men quick. No, no wait, there's
another claim or out there. What the fuck?
Set it off. What about the
other one? So imagine this, you,
you get to a position and you
want to put out claymore mines.
And if you don't know what
a claymore mine is, it's a,
it's a directional blasting mine that
you set off by command detonation.
So you have a little,
a little thing that you squeeze
and when you squeeze this thing,
it sends an electrical charge down
the wire into the claim or detonates a
blasting cap, the claim or explodes and
everything in front of it's going to die.
Well,
they had set up the claymores and then
they were going to put some barbed wire
out and as they were
putting the Barb wire out,
there was a storm,
electrical storm, you know,
thunderstorm and the static electricity
in the air actually set off the claymore
so it killed or it, it did some
serious damage back to the book.
Only a few seconds had passed.
Since the explosion,
one of my men and I dashed to the
other claim or frantically fumbling,
unscrewing the plug and
holding the bast and crap,
throwing it away from the claymore.
Then I rushed back to the radio.
Two men were applying first aid.
The other positions were covered
by the men assigned to them.
They had stayed in place during
the action. Good training.
I fought as I fumbled with my map.
It was folded into plastic radio bag.
All of us used to carry maps in Delta
six this is one six over one six this is
delta six over.
This is one six I need dust off.
There's been an accident
resulting in three peanuts over.
We tried to say nothing over the radio
that could be understood by the enemy.
Thus,
we used code words for certain things.
A koolaid was a dead soldier and
a peanut was a wounded soldier.
This is Delta six what
the hell happened over?
This is one six static
electricity in the air,
set off a claim while three trackman.
We're putting out barbed wire over.
This is Delta Sex. What's your position
over now? What would he ask me that for?
I was on the bridge heat assigned
to me. Let's see, we're here.
So I read writing up real easy,
just like all the training.
So he's looking at his maps, trying
to figure out where he is. Of course,
that was my first responsibility
where men had been hurt,
so maybe that accounted for what happened
next in spite of training. Lieutenant,
Lieutenant, you've got to get
a dust off out here quick.
This man's got a bad head wound.
Said one soldier,
as they brought the wounded over to me,
dirty black clouds of
lightning crashing around,
added the confusion as the wind
howled over from all directions,
huge range drops. Started to
spatter down. This is one six.
I'm at coordinates to nine
eight zero two eight over.
I read them out. This is Delta
six. Are you sure of that
over? This is one six. Uh,
let's see. Yeah, it's, that's
it. All right there. One, six.
You better check that again.
According to what you gave me.
You're in the south China Sea over.
Oh, did he sound mad? God Damn.
I've done this a million times.
The thought ran through my mind is a sweat
broke out. The wounded were groaning.
The storm was reaching
gigantic proportions and the
track sergeant was demanding
to know where that fuck that dust off was.
Concentrate Fred,
concentrate. I said to myself while
staring at the meaningless blob of colors,
worlds and numbers, so he's looking at his
map. It's just trying to figure it out.
Suddenly everything jelled and perfect
clarity. Delta six is one. Six.
You're right. My coordinates are
two eight eight zero two eight.
I need to dust off fast over one six.
This is Delta six.
I know where you are. I just wanted
to see if you could figure it out.
I already called the dust off.
So captain cells this, that's who he was
talking to. Captains cells. That's a,
that's Delta six,
the commander of the company.
And even in this pressure situation,
he's trying to make sure that the guy
is thinking he's in opportunity to think
for the first time under pressure.
And he already called the dust off,
but he's still putting the test to him
and seeing how he operates under that
kind of stress and pressure.
Another uh,
following situation there,
they're kind of sitting in this location
and they see a woman start to start to
approach where they had some,
some equipment and she was looked like
she was going to steal some stuff and you
know, was kind of no big deal. Okay,
she's gonna Steal. So whatever,
some ponchos or something,
well then they see her,
what she picks up as a case of
grenades and they're thinking,
wait a second,
now this is just got really bad because
if she was stealing a Poncho, okay,
no big deal.
But if she's stealing grenades,
that's stuff that's going to be used
to come back and kill them. But again,
because we have a guy with a,
with a conscience, you know,
a guy that sees where the line of darkness
is and he doesn't want to cross it.
So instead of just shooting her,
which she could have done,
he loads a magazine of tracer
rounds into his, into his weapon,
and he starts shooting them around her
kind of warning shots and then eventually
start shooting.
He's a good shot.
He starts shooting at the little rope
that holds the case that she's holding on
to. He starts shooting at that rope,
shoots out at like five or six times,
finally hits the rope, kind,
Kinda hits her hand. She drops it,
she runs off again,
just trying to show the discretion that
this guy's using as a real contrast to
the meal. I episode. Now.
Speaking of that,
the little later on they
roll up some prisoners.
One is an old man and one is a young man
and this old gray haired sergeant
starts going after him to,
they got these two prisoners.
They're captured and here's the sergeant,
so you're the fuckers that
Zap my buddies in the tank.
The old grey hair sergeant
snarled without warning,
he swung a heavy fist in the face
of the old man knocking him down.
The other fist swung into the face.
The younger man knocking
them down beside the old man.
The sergeant was screaming and bellowing
as he pummeled the two men on the sand.
They rolled into balls for protection,
but we're hampered by their tied hands.
I ran from the road yelling my two men
to pull the sergeant off the prisoners.
They grabbed him by his soldiers as he
fought them to get back to the Vietnamese.
He lashed out with his foot
at the prisoners, catching
one of them in the side.
What the hell are you doing, sergeant?
Those men are my prisoners. I exclaimed,
his face was red with fury.
As he yelled back at me,
you had no right to take
those stinking Kong prisoners.
He smelled of beer that he had drunk.
You should have killed those motherfuckers
like they killed that other tank crew.
Fuck, these men are tied up. We don't
know who they are. I yelled back,
I was saved by the
sound of lieutenant nut.
Can Knutson's voice breaking over
the argument? Calm down, sergeant,
go back to your tent.
So that was the other lieutenant was
the commander of the tanks. Again,
I'm pointing this out. He's
new in country. He sees
somebody beaten up a prisoner.
They had just lost a one of the tanks
to a mine earlier and obviously the gray
haired sergeants pissed and he
wants to take it out on these guys.
But you know,
calmer,
cooler heads prevailed in that situation.
Now speaking of minds
minds back to the book,
mind continue to be laid in the
road at irregular intervals.
It was a fact of life.
But the terror of an explosion never
failed to send a shiver through our guts.
No matter how many times we heard them,
whatever we were doing,
our heads would jerk around.
It was terrifying to hear the explosion.
See the ugly gray and black crowd
cloud is it ripped into the year.
See dark pieces of metal,
canvas machinery and human beings flying
in the blossom of death out from the
center of destruction
and this one big mine happens and he's
going to check it out. It hits truck,
hits a vehicle.
I approached the twisted wreck.
It was very disheartening
to see the smoking rec,
which had once been the
carrier of human beings.
There were with smoke drifting upward
from the HOLC. As we approach closer,
we saw parts of the driver's body mangled
beyond recognition in the cab and on
the ground.
That main portion of the driver was only
recognizable because we knew that was
what it was supposed to be.
My men ran toward the still living,
being huddled in the rice patty mewling
over and over that his leg was gone.
The scene of desolation brought about
the impact of the Vietnam War. To me.
There was no enemy to fire at.
There was no nothing to
retaliate against at a distance.
The traffic of vehicles
and Vietnamese watched.
Okay.
All that remained was the messy job of
cleaning up while thinking that this
could happen to us.
A small part of her mind tried to retain
it's sanity by reminding yourself over
and over that it would never happen to us.
It can happen to everyone else,
but it would not happen to me.
With that in mind,
we started scraping up what was left
preparing it for the plastic body bag.
Now
eventually they,
they go from guarding the bridges to
where they start doing patrols out in the
jungle and ambush is out in the jungle
and direct action missions out in the
jungle and at this point they're out
in the jungle and I'll go to the book.
My platoon and I had not
shaved for three or four days.
Delta six was a bear about
shaving combat patrol or not.
Just because we live like animals
didn't mean we had to look like them.
Who was his way of thinking?
Throwing my fatigue jacket across a Bush.
I grabbed my shaving gear and told
spag and visa nor to accompany me.
We would guard each other as we shaved.
So the company commanders coming out and
there unshaven and they're like, okay,
we gotta shave real quick.
But again,
you can see that captain cells
has a real influence. Any,
you can see that that discipline,
it carries over.
And when you let it slack and,
but then you go visit your troops
and they'd have to get back in line.
It brings him back to humanity. It
makes, it reminds them that thing.
Cause think about it,
that shaving is something you do
in the military every single day.
So when all of a sudden you're out
in the field, you start losing that,
you start slipping away
from that and things start.
Other things start slipping away as well.
Hmm.
They get into a,
they get into some firefights out there
and at one point he gets wounded and I'm
going to the book.
After homes had finished bandaging my arm,
I put on my fatigue jacket and
lit a cigarette. I felt good.
I'd only been in country a few months
and I had my second purple heart.
The first one had been from a wound
received an October to top it off.
I had been wounded twice in one day,
shot in the ear in the morning and hit
with a grenade, shrapnel in the afternoon.
Luck was with me.
All three wounds had been slight.
Now you can say luck when you get shot
in the ear and you are lucky for sure,
but that's,
that's a real,
that's a real eyeopener indicating that
you realize how close you were to dine
and I had guys get shot in the helmet
and and they didn't like it one bit
because that's real close.
Someone got real close to getting you
now going forward more. There's a,
there's a battle going on and the
companies out in the field and they're not
directly involved in the battle
so they get told, okay you,
we want you to go set up where the,
where we think the,
the VC is going to run to where
we think they're going to run.
You guys set up a blocking force
so that way when the VC runs into,
you ambush them and take them out.
So they're kind of
maneuvering to go set that up.
His platoon is maneuvering to set
that up and we'll go to the book.
After 15 minutes or so, we were
approximately halfway down the ridge.
The captain gave me a call.
Dragon six had decided it would be better
if I have to my platoon marching the
two elements in opposite directions
in order to cover a larger area.
I was dead set against this. My platoon
was below strength and dividing.
It would be asking to reinforce rifle
squads or defend hundreds of acres of
jungle against a foe of unknown size.
So dragon six is above
the company commander.
This is now the battalion commander.
And so now you're getting an order
from the battalion commander. So it's,
you know,
you're a young lieutenant
platoon commander and you're
getting told to do this
and he doesn't feel good about it back
to the book. But orders were orders,
especially from dragon six I pass back
the ward for Sheldon brand to come up.
I was pouring over my map and compass
when Sheldon brand reached me,
the battle was full,
the full blown it sound,
it sound provided background noises.
I briefed Shelly on the situation and
our orders, shit, I don't like it sir.
I know I don't either. But it's a lick.
You got your map and compass. Good.
So there's all kinds of reasons
why they don't like this idea.
Uh, obviously one that he already
stated was that, you know,
you take your platoon and you cut
them in half. That's, that's just,
you don't have the same fighting
capability at all. I think they had one,
one heavy machine gun and each squad.
So now you've got basically they're
down to two squads cause they were under
strength. So we're talking one
heavy machine gun. And by the way,
if somebody gets wounded,
you know,
you got your wound do guy and
if you're gonna carry that guy,
it takes two or three guys to carry
the guy. So that's four guys go on.
So you could very easily be outnumbered
outman and Outgun by the enemy.
So he doesn't like this idea.
On top of that, I will tell you,
he doesn't talk about it here. When
you split up in a situation like this,
it becomes very difficult to do command
and control and now you've got two
elements that are weak size and you're,
you're no longer able to
support each other. That's the,
that's the premise of cover move.
Covered.
Move means you want to be close enough
that you could support each other.
You don't want to split far apart where
you can't help each other if something
happens. Well that's what they're
getting told to do. They don't it and,
but they do it and maybe he should
have protested more, but he's getting,
he's getting orders from the battalion
commander and he says, okay, let's do it.
And of course,
within a couple of minutes of doing it,
they lose radio contact.
So now they can't,
they can't hear each other and
they're starting to march apart.
Finally they get radio, uh, they
get connected on the radio again,
they get columns again. And it sounds
like this one five this is one six.
Have you figured out where you are yet?
This is one five negative.
So Shelley with his squad is lost,
doesn't know where he is.
Okay. Now the lieutenant is
all set up though. They're,
they're in their position where they're
thinking the enemy might come by.
They're set up to attack them
and here we go. Back to the book,
Lieutenant Porter risks whispered
as he reached my side where he,
we hear noises to our front.
Men are moving across in
front of us in the jungle.
Hold on a second. Porter.
One five. This is one six.
The sound of the battle
should be on your right.
If you're going in the right
direction where the sound's over.
This is one five negative on the right.
The sounds are on the left over one five
did you just say the sounds are on your
left? I was squeezing the handset so
hard. My knuckles were white. Affirmative.
Affirmative.
Jesus Christ.
One five I Horsley whispered
intensely into the mouthpiece.
You're heading in our direction.
I could hear the sounds of men
moving through the jungle below us.
I whisper deporter get back down there
and tell the men to hold their fire.
That may not be dinks.
After all,
hurry porter and heard the conversation
with Shelley and quickly turned to are
to carry out my order.
He couldn't yell because the sounds
were coming from the dinks soldiers.
His yelled would put us in jeopardy.
As porter started toward the crew,
the machine gun crew, open
fire, the harshness of the guns,
multiple explosions ripped across my
thoughts as it sound echoed through the
handset I was holding next to my ear,
the sound of American
swearing and screaming,
rebounded from the jungle below and
from my handset cease fire. I screamed,
cease fire so he can actually hear
his guys getting shot by his own guys.
We have a blue on blue porter
and I were running the gun crew.
Both of us yelling,
cease fire, cease fire,
the sound of their gun blanketing the
screens in front of them abruptly.
The gun quit firing. I yelled into
the jungle. Shelly, is that you? Yes.
Yes. Stop firing. Don't fire.
I was answered by many voices.
I stood there and instant the horrible
realization that I had fired on my own.
Men's swept over me like a
wave from an ice cold. Hell,
the gun crew looked at me,
their faces filled with shock.
I ran leaping and falling down to the
brush line where my men were asking the
question to anybody hit for Christ's sake,
Gallagher yelled back as I burst into a
small clearing, one man, the point man.
So there you go.
Blue on blue.
Another reason why if you don't
have to separate your forces,
you don't. You don't separate your
forces and unless you have to,
and when you do what you do
with extreme caution, and we,
we've w I think every book we've,
we talk about blue on blue,
it happens in all these books.
It happens in my book and some
of these descriptions right here,
I recognize those 100% when he says the
horrible realization I had fired on my
own, bent, swept over me like a
wave from an ice cold. Hell yeah,
I totally recognize that. And the fact
that he says the gun crew looked at me,
their faces filled with shock when I,
when I explained to my guys in the
field like that was a blue on blue.
Their faces were just complete shock.
If you're in the military,
if you're in law enforcement,
be very careful when you
split your forces. It's,
it just multiplies the challenges.
Sometimes it is necessary,
but you got to keep control over it.
And now we go to where he's calling for
a evac for his, for his wounded guy.
Okay.
Delta six. This is one six over, this
is delta six over, this is one six.
I need a dust off for a peanut.
We run into a little action over.
This is Delta six. What do you mean
a little action? What's going on?
What happened over my knees felt
weak and my stomach was sour.
This is one six.
We had a little difficulty
with w with the terrain and uh,
I ambushed one five over what?
How the fuck did you do that one six
you mean your ambushed your own men?
What kind of outfit are
you running up there?
That's the most asinine
thing I've ever heard of.
You get your head out of your ass one
six and get that platoon straightened up.
You've got that over.
This is one six affirmative over.
Okay.
Ah, one six gimme your coordinates.
The dust offs. Honest way.
How bad is your peanuts over?
This is one six. Not too bad.
He'll lose a couple of toes, but
everybody else is okay over, all right.
One six settle down out.
Yeah.
He was more gentle with the
last transmission because
I'm sure he heard my voice
and showed the strain I was feeling,
whatever the reason,
I welcome the sound of his voice.
Perhaps he understood better
than I thought what had happened,
so he comes at him real hard. He realizes
that the guy feels horrible and me and,
and then he kind of backs
off and to settle down.
He also knows he's got
to stay in the game.
He's got to get him to stay in the game.
And there's a nightmare of a video on
youtube of then just actually it's from a
documentary,
but there was a really bad blue on blue
in the first Gulf war where a Apache
gunship led up, lit up. Uh, I think it was
a Bradley, some kind of APC, the one that,
it's a nightmare,
but you can hear the one guy that fired,
they're saying, hey, you got to
get back in position, you know,
hold the line basically. And he's
like, ah, I just killed my own guys.
I want to come. And they're,
they're saying negative.
And so that's basically what this,
what captains cells is doing here saying,
hey listen, okay I'm pissed.
But guess what? Calm down,
settle down, get your shit together.
And he sits out in and, and by the way,
for those folks that aren't military over,
when you say over at the end
of a transmission on the radio,
it means you expect a reply.
When you say out there is
no reply expected. So like
when we end this podcast,
I say out cause it's over there. Don't
say anything back to me. It's over.
I don't say over and and sometimes you'll
hear people say over and out in the
military that doesn't, you don't
say that. It doesn't make any sense.
So when you hear that in a movie, no,
that they know that they are cheesy,
that kind of like when you,
when they hang up the phone on the movie,
he goes [inaudible] and you
hear the dial tone. Yes.
That doesn't really happen either.
I trudged back back to the book.
I charge it back to my position one five
and his men following man handed me a
can of coffee.
I chain smoke my cigarettes and drink
coffee while the platoon expanded into a
larger perimeter,
I stood facing the mountain,
the battle still raging on
one five walked over to me,
still shaking from his experience.
He told me how he was sorry that he
had gotten to me in such a Dutch with a
captain and we discussed the operation
going over his mistake while we attempt
to figure out ways to keep it from
happening again, if we were ever split up,
Shelly and I had been through too much
together for me to blame him for what had
happened.
I told him so and we let it go at that.
We have been lucky besides,
I blamed myself for what had happened.
The responsibility for any units,
actions ultimately rests
with its commander.
The leader got the glory when things
worked out and he took the blame when they
didn't.
That went with the job.
When it came right down to it,
the men were my responsibility
and I had failed them today.
Okay.
Little bit of extreme ownership.
If you read the book extreme
ownership that Leif and I wrote,
the opening chapter,
that's what it's about,
blue on blue and doing exactly what
what lieutenant downs did. Right.
They're taking ownership of what the
mistakes were made in the battlefield
back to the book. There's a couple
of got well actually not yet there.
They link up with another with another
platoon and now they're having a
conversation.
Uh,
Downes is having a conversation
with another officer named Anderson.
A dink was lying next to us as we talked.
He had a black ace of spade stuck onto
his fist. Handerson what's that all about?
That's so the dinks no, what outfit
fucked them up over here. Look around.
Most of the dinks got those in
their hands. Sure enough, the dinks.
We're all holding an ace of spades.
That's a good idea.
But where'd you get all the aces? One of
the guys. Mom's works in a card store,
so he wrote home asking her to send her
a couple packs of nothing but an ace of
spades.
Why did we want to kill dinks after all,
we had mostly been law abiding citizens
back in a world and we were taught that
to take another man's life was wrong.
Somehow the perspective
got twisted in a war.
The government told us it was all right
and in fact a must to kill members of
another government's per people.
Then we had the law on our side.
It turned out that most of
us liked to kill other men.
Some of the guys which shooted a dink
as much as they would at a target.
Some of the men didn't like to kill a
dink up close. The close to the killing,
the more personal it became.
Others in the platoon
like to kill in clothes.
A few even like to torture the dinks
if they had a prisoner or cut the dead
bodies with knives and
a frenzy of aggression.
A few didn't like to kill it all and
wouldn't fire their weapons except to
protect their buddies.
Mostly.
We all saw it as a job in
rationalized it in our own way
over.
It all ran the streak of anger or fear
that for brief moments ruled us all.
My job is platoon leader was to
control the spectrum of emotions,
to guide the men towards survival.
I didn't believe in torturing or and
allowing a dink to die lingering death in
the jungle. We never took
prisoners. If we can help it.
Every day we spent in the jungle eroded
a little more of our humanity away.
Prisoners could escape to become
our enemy again. Hence no prisoners.
The philosophical arguments in favor of
man's ability to resist the slide into
barbarism,
sound,
noble and rational in a
classroom or at a cocktail party,
but when the enemy is bearing down on you,
bent on taking your life away from you,
it's not his country against your
country, not his army, against your army,
not his philosophy
against your philosophy.
It's the fact that that son of a bitch
is trying to kill you and you better kill
him first.
That's a reality right there.
Now going back to tactics a little bit,
back to the book, there was a spot about
midway down the mountain marked in blue.
That meant something bigger than a stream.
If I were an enemy commander,
that would be a perfect spot for a camp.
High mountains on three sides,
a good water supply, thick jungle growth
and escape path in any directions.
If he decided on that location,
the any we could commander would be
counting on attack from the valley up
towards his location.
He would have his back guarded but
not very heavily or so. I reasoned.
I just liked that because you can see
he's getting his mind in the mind to the
enemy. He's thinking about what he's
looking at the map. He sees the stream,
he sees valley, he sees good, good,
uh, covered positions from three sides.
He's thinking, okay, this is what the
enemy must be thinking right here.
Now the, the fighting continues
and as always, you know,
I'm burning through book.
I mean, this is, uh,
this is a 250 page book and
I'm reading, you know, what,
maybe 20 pages from it.
So there's so much action going on in,
in so many good lessons to learn.
Obviously I can't cover them all.
That's why you can buy this book
yourself as you should. But here we go.
I'm going to a point here where
they've been in a firefight.
They'd got three wounded.
One of the guys lost an arm,
one of them is unconscious
and they're getting a,
they have a helicopter to come in and
the helicopters lowered down a cable and
they're lifting the guys out to
get them to a med evac situation.
Back to the book, the signal was given
and the cable pulled him off the ground.
About halfway up he waved to all of us
just grinning like a Cheshire cat blood
dripped on us. It was a picture
I shall always hold in my mind.
A man dangling from a cable holding a
stick fastened to a tourniquet on the
stump of his leg, waving at his
comrades with the other hand,
a cigarette dangling from his lips.
One six is getting hairy up here. We're
starting to take fire. The pilot reported,
hold on just one more.
SPAG and I lifted the unconscious man
up while we slid the vest on to him.
Someone had to be the cable,
which I hooked onto the ring.
The unconscious man was winched upward,
dangling like a limp doll
at the end of a cable.
SPAG and I stood underneath
watching this final exodus.
As the crew man reached out to
grab the man, something went wrong.
The man had become unhooked and somehow
fell through 50 feet of sky towards us.
We jumped back as the man fell in a heap,
better feet,
the medic and I pulled the man over.
Fuck,
he stopped breathing.
He goes on to say the attrition rate
on our side was terrible on our morale.
Although we killed and
wounded many of the Nva,
we never knew how much it hurt them.
It seemed there was an unlimited number
to take their places, but on our side,
when we lost a man,
we all knew
and it wore heavily on our minds.
The constant marching and fighting
demanded two things of us,
strength and absolute reliability.
Now they're moving out on another
operation and there was one of the,
one of the soldiers named
Yoder Yoder was the point man.
He was experienced and full of good humor
due to his promotion to door gunner.
A good man to have on point any day.
He was aggressive and unafraid,
even though he was going in soon.
There was no question of putting
someone else in his place on point.
It was his turn and he would
not have in any other way.
So he's getting promoted to door gunners.
He's gonna get pulled out of the field,
is going to fly around in the helicopter.
You relatively safe compared
to being in the field.
He reminded me of a hillbilly with this
course, language, mannerisms and humor.
I was always asking him who he was
going to get that front tooth replaced,
that missing tooth made him look more
like a hillbilly than anything else.
He always laughed and said,
fuck sir,
I ain't about to let them fucking
army dentist work on me. She had no,
that would be a lick on me.
Yeah.
So they continue their patrol and they're
coming up on this kind of flat area
and Yoder crept forward in a crouch,
looked back at me and grinned.
I grin back and nodded my head.
Yoder stepped over a tree root holding
up part of the small gully bank.
Okay.
At that moment, all hell broke
loose as a chai come machine guns.
Strafed the point element.
Yoda was hitting the body and
fell forward into the gully.
The machine gun acted as a key
which triggered a complete ambush.
We walked into a classical u shaped ambush
with a machine gun being at the base
of the EU, so this is, we
used to call this a fire sac.
When you're get ambushed and you're
completely surrounded by the enemy and
that's where there,
that's where they are,
starts with this machine gun and
and Yoder and then just breaks out.
Okay,
explosions,
machine guns and rifle bullets rip through
the air and ricocheted off the ground
and trees around us. The
noise was overwhelming. Men
were screaming and yelling,
trying desperately to get covered or
screaming when they were hit or thought
they were hit,
which was almost as terrifying.
We still not seen any of the enemy
in the thick growth around us.
Most of us in the point play dead.
I lay trying to get my thinking
organized as to what to do.
So you're just taking massive, a ambush
and you're laying there thinking, well,
what am I going to do?
Okay.
I could hear Yoder crying on the other
side of the route where he had fallen.
He cried out for me to come and
get him lieutenant, I've been hit.
I've been hit bad. I'm dying. Please
come and get me. Please come and get me.
Okay.
I turned my head in his direction.
Twigs and bark from trees were falling
like snow all around us as the charitable
shrapnel and firepower rip
through the jungle around us.
I was terrified.
So they're,
they're pinned down and
okay,
he's actually ends up going to try
and help one of the other guys.
First,
a guy named bell,
then he gets to bell under
covering fire and he says,
bell was able, was able to help
me but couldn't see anything.
He limped and crawled.
I pushed and swore as we continuously
fell in our flight back up the hill.
As I pulled him up the hill, one of my
feet was shot up from, from underneath me.
I've been shot in the Hilo,
one of the bullets knocking off
a piece of my boot heel and then,
and the force had knocked me down.
I got a begin and felt a tremendous
blow to my hip, knocking me down.
He had again,
I thought finally I got bell behind.
A rock doc was there and
started working on him.
I lay on my back looking up at
the sky through the jungle canopy,
not believing I'd actually
made it down there and back.
Yoda was still down there and although
I had witnessed the bullets hitting him,
I didn't want to leave.
I had to be absolutely sure he was dead.
I would never forgive myself if I
pulled back and he was still alive.
I was ready to call artillery in
on our position if we were overrun,
and that's like the ultimate,
okay,
the ultimate game over move. We're
going to be overrun by the enemy. Okay,
here we go. I'm going to call, call
all ordinance on my position drop,
but luckily the fire subsides.
The one of the other platoons had come
to their help and now that other platoon
shows up and the enemy's pretty
much gone and it stopped shooting.
We all stood up.
A couple of my man and I ran down to
where three six his point with standing
over Yoder, I leaped over the edge
of the goalie and stop at younger.
His body kneeling down.
I turned his body over.
He died with his headline downhill.
His face was a dark blue from the blood,
which gravity had pulled into
the downhill portion of his body.
There wasn't much blood on his body,
but numerous bullet holes were cut into
his fatigues covering his stomach and
chest. His eyes were closed.
I looked at him for a moment.
My thoughts running back to our
many conversations in the past.
Once we had discussed whether we would
go to the aid of one of our fellow
soldiers if he was in trouble,
I told him I would always respond to
one of my men if they needed help.
He had replied it would be a lick on me.
I wondered if he had known that.
I tried to get to him.
He was the first man
under my command to die.
Yeah.
I looked up to see some
of my platoon in three,
six per tune standing over a dink body,
and the goalie, three six had an Indian,
his platoon and I had
an Indian in my platoon.
They drew their knives and slashed
the enemy's body and frustration.
This was the only dead dink.
The men could find one lousy dink
for all that pain and suffering.
At least we could take our hate
out on that son of a bitch.
They'd also taken one prisoner as well.
The the other platoon head
answer.
Now he starts thinking back
to the book. This is it.
I thought I'd been wounded four
times in battle. I had done my job,
captains cells had asked after my third
wound, if I wanted to be sent back,
anyone with three wounds was do that.
All it took was two wounds to get
you out of the field. Surely forward,
let me live with myself.
What was I trying to prove?
But I answered my own question.
The men depend on me.
It's my job to keep them alive by giving
them good leadership and looking after
them. They need me. Yeah,
but shit,
what did I own myself?
I had a wife and two
little girls who needed me.
The $10,000 in insurance money wouldn't
do them much good. Where did my duty lie?
I was still shaking. I couldn't go
through this again. Reluctantly.
Almost against my will. I started
walking toward the captain. Captain?
Yes. Fred. You asked once if I
wanted to go out of the field,
if I had been wounded a third time, he
turned and looked into my face. Yes.
Well, I think, I mean,
what do you think I was letting you and
my men down if I did I stammered. No,
I wouldn't. You've done your
job. I could get you a job.
Get you a good job with us too. That's
some intelligence back in the rear. I,
I think I want out.
I don't know if I can do this again.
Maybe I can't cut it.
That's nonsense.
You're a hell of a fine officer
and the men will understand,
but you think about it.
Okay. I will. Let me think.
A little bit of confidence returned at
his words. I handed Yoders things to him.
I wandered back to the pacs thinking I
should find Yoders pac bell had stood up
and was coming toward me. When he saw
the blind fold to dink in one motion,
he swung his fist into the dinks face.
He hit him again and again,
knocking the surprise, dig down in a
burst of fury. Bell started kicking him.
It was obvious.
Bell was going to kill him.
The other men and I stood
smoking and watching.
We were going to let bill kill the dink.
Bell had the right captain.
Sales yelled and ran over to us,
pushing me out of the way and pulling
bell off the Dick here. What's this?
What's going on? We are not
going to have this in my company.
This man's a prisoner lieutenant downs.
What are you doing? Just standing there.
I looked at him in surprise.
Bell was killing this motherfucker.
What's wrong with that? I
retorted. You know God damn well,
what's the matter with that lieutenant?
This man is defenseless and our prisoner.
Now let's get this
prisoner back to the LD Lz.
I wanted the dink dead,
but the captain was right.
So you can see there
obviously captain cells has a,
has a great head on his shoulders
and there's something else at play.
The other thing that's at play is that
by function of the way the battle went
down and by function of being one rank
above the platoon commanders that are in
the firefights,
guess what he is defacto.
He's detached, he's detached.
He didn't, I mean bells,
the guy was pinned down,
almost got killed, right?
He's the guy that's emotional and guests
who pulled him out risked his life,
lost Yoder. That was downs.
So these guys are emotional.
They're there. They want to kill
this guy. They captured him. He's VC,
let's kill him.
And captain cells is detached
because he wasn't in that firefight.
He wasn't directly there.
So he's able to maintain
enough mental detachment to,
to make a hard decision,
but also hold the line.
And this is something that, you know,
when we go through the meal, I'm massacre.
This could have happened
to over and over again,
just going to happen to 80 anywhere along
the way. Someone could have said, hey,
what are you doing right
there? Stop. We don't do that.
And that's exactly what sells does.
And I think another thing that's that's
important from a leadership perspective
is also,
well before I go to that point,
you notice that when he's
having a personal conversation
with lieutenant towns,
he calls him Fred.
But when he's screwing up and he
needs to kind of put him in his place,
he's lieutenant downs
on top of that from the
leadership perspective, from
captain sales perspective,
he's got to always remember that w w
what is happening that they are emotional
that they did just lose their
buddy that he's got. He can't just,
you know, be so on the
straight and narrow that goes,
oh I'm going to court martial you.
He could call it or he could court Marshal
Bell, right? Hey you abused a prisoner,
you're, you know, I'm
going to court martial you.
And he doesn't do that
because he understands their
perspective and that's why
you know, again, throughout this
book sells really impresses me as a,
as a very squared away, good solid
leader as does downs. I mean downs.
Obviously right here. He's emotional
and he's lost it. Uh, he's,
he's crossed the line, right? But all
it takes is sales. Just telling him,
get back over here, buddy.
You crossed the line,
come back and he says the captain
was right. So that's all it took.
Just a little snap just to get him to
detach a little bit from the emotions and,
and move,
move away from the darkness.
Back to the book,
I walked over to the bodies.
Yoders eyes were partially shut and
I leaned down to push them clothes.
Not that it did any good, but for some
reason I thought it was better that way.
I stood there with one hand on my aching
hip smoking and thinking Yoders face
was all muddy from the numerous times
he'd been dropped in the mud and it was a
trickle of blood at
the base of his throat.
This is the way it will always end.
I thought men being killed in the jungle,
other men dragging their bodies out,
putting them on choppers and the rest
of us going back to the fighting.
When they left on the chopper,
it was as if they had never been man's
beginning and man's and would always be
attended by only a few.
Those that bought them at birth
and those that bore him at death,
the only important thing
was what he did in between,
good or bad or indifferent.
He would touch those around
in some way and then be gone.
I wondered if a solute would be an order,
not necessarily in the military sense,
but a salute from one who had known
him and who would never forget him.
I decided it was and I raised my
hand to my forehead in a farewell.
Yeah.
Now the birds coming in to pick them up
as after he gives that final salute to
Yoder.
Smoke was popped and the large chopper
swung in towards us for is landing.
The doors were pushed back and I saw
the door gunner on the side facing me
looking around, anxiously searching for
the ominous, for the omnipresent enemy.
Good man.
I fought not trusting a goddamn thing,
even with an American infantry companies
surrounding the Lz and I love, I love,
just love that he's noticing
that this door gunners coming in,
the he coming in to pick them up and
instead of this guy cutting corners and be
like, oh, there's him fucking Trump
again. There's no rounds being fired.
I'm just gonna Relax. No, this guy's
in the game. Opens the door, doesn't,
what does he say? He says, uh,
not trusting a God damn thing.
Even with an American
infantry company on the LLC.
Many thoughts were Chris costing my mind
above everything else ran the fought
that I could not abandoned my men.
I felt the shame that I had asked
captain sales to pull me out of the field
earlier when I was still shaking.
What would demand think if they found
out I was doing such a thing worse?
What would I think of myself?
Yeah.
Now they continue to do operations
and eventually they get,
they get pulled out of the field on this
for the final time on a helicopter back
to the book,
the machine carried us away.
I looked over my men sprawled
along the sides of the chopper.
They'd removed the magazines from their
weapons before boarding and now we're
holding them close to their bodies.
The men were dirty and unshaven.
They're clothes in various stages
of disrepair. Jungle boots,
worn and torn with clouds and mud.
Between the cleats,
there were dark rings under their eyes
and their faces were drawn and tired.
Some of those phases were
new men set ultra places.
The faces that started the
operation in were racist.
We had experienced the worst of
life and the most challenging.
We had survived.
The platoon I took back was not
the platoon I had brought out.
Yeah.
Now they're on yet another
operation have to go back.
They get reset and they're
out on another operation.
Okay.
Doing a patrol and him going back to the
book about five meters past the gate,
the two men turned me and waved
me forward all clear, sir.
Let's go Rudo I pass through the gate.
My right hand grasp my m 16
my left held my cigarette.
I was humming the blue tail fly.
As I mentally ticked off the physicians
around the saddle where I would set my
men,
I noticed the time zero seven 45 hours,
my foot slipped backwards,
a fraction of an inch hitting
the trigger mechanism of a mine.
I never heard the explosion.
Black powder and dirt flew by me.
My eardrums ripped.
My body was flying through the air.
I threw my arms in front of me in
a reflex motion to balance myself.
My eyes registered the
horror of a brilliantly white
jagged bone sticking out of
the stump of arm above where
my left elbow had been. Ragged.
Bloody flesh surrounded
this splintered bone.
My mind cursed as utter helplessness in
disrepair and despair overwhelmed me on
another part of my bodily Cooley
calculated what had caused the explosion.
It had been a landmine, but what kind
would blow off my arm instead of my legs?
Of course it had to be a bouncing Betty
mine that flies up to out of the ground
after being tripped and explodes
to waist high. That would do it.
My [inaudible] had been in my right hand.
The rifle was shattered.
My hand was mangled. I stared in horror
at what remained of my right arm.
The flesh had been ripped away
exposing two bones in my wife forearm.
From risks to the elbow, the bones look
like two white, glistening, narrow rods,
buried and raw bloody meat
thinking. My God, my God,
my God, I felt told to feet of
my life as I landed on my feet,
five yards from where the mind it
explode. It exploded. After landing.
I staggered forward two or three steps
and then collapsed. My legs wouldn't work.
The mind had gone off about six inches
from my left hip, from the waist down.
My body was mutilated and torn where
large chunks of flesh, muscles,
blood vessels and nerves had been ripped
away by the hot, exploding shrapnel.
My buttocks were blown away.
The back of my legs were ripped
to the bone down to my heels.
I rolled over on my back being careful
to keep my stump and right arm out of the
dirt and sand.
My body was sending so many pain signals
to my brain that had overloaded like an
electrical circuit. It caused
me to feel a racing, humming,
numbness. I lifted my head
to view a scene from hell.
I watched a couple of men run
by me to the wounded point man.
They would only glance at me sideways as
I lay there holding my bloody stump in
the air.
They seem nervous.
Some of my men ran toward me.
Then turn suddenly away at the sight
of my torn body. They stood near me,
but hesitated to come too close as if
their movement through the air would make
it worse.
Spag asked me to turn sideways a little
bit so he could pull my gear off.
There were tears is not Adam.
His eyes as he worked
over me with a grunt,
he pulled the belt out from under me.
Is there anything I can do for you?
SPAG asked. Yes. Run over there and
pick up my arm and bring it back to me.
I don't want to leave it
in this stinking village.
I told Marlene to get my squad leaders
go take care of the other men doc,
they need you.
I looked up Marlene and my squad leaders
were standing in a rough line along my
right side. I asked who was hurt.
I was feeling weaker and weaker.
It was so god damn cold.
As my body fought for life,
my thoughts ran to my man and my platoon.
I felt I was cheating them by
leaving them when they needed me.
Most when I joined,
the platoon is their leader.
They had taught me the
ways to survive in combat.
A second lieutenant who is new and
country and they were old timers,
18 1920 but old to the
ways of combat and deaf.
As I gained experience and
confidence as a leader,
I became an old timer having
to make decisions that put
me in the position I was
in now wounded and maimed,
facing death.
My men were still up there looking at me.
Despair on their faces.
They're in vulnerable leader
had been brought down. Marley.
Yes, sir. I want you to your men to
get the dink. Who planted that mine.
I want him dead. Get Him. We will
want six. Don't you worry about that?
They looked at each other.
Then back at me.
The gray haze of the day was strong.
I pushed it back to look beyond my men.
It was colder now and harder to see.
I was thinking of my grandma downs and
her form of the woods and fields of
Indiana.
I love so much.
If only I could walk them one more time.
If I'm only 23 years old and I'm dying,
what a waste.
There are so many things I had
meant to do and say, but I hadn't
now I will never get the chance.
So
obviously,
although he thought he was gonna
die, he lived, he lost his arm. He,
uh, ended up with, uh, with severe wounds,
got discharged from the army. And you
know, it's one of the things in the story.
He had actually got picked up
for up for a pilot program.
So he's going to be a pilot in the army.
He was gonna stay in the army to become
a pilot and obviously that was gone
because he didn't have an arm anymore.
Uh,
luckily they were able to save his
other arm, but you know, severe wounds,
real long Rehab and
eventually he ends up
going back to college.
And here we go back to the book
in the fall of 1968 as I stopped at a
traffic light on my walk to class across
the campus of the University of Denver,
a man stepped up to me, said hi,
without waiting for my
reply to his greeting.
He pointed to the hook sticking out of
my left sleeve. Get that in Vietnam.
I said, yeah, up near Tam,
Ky and one core serves you right.
As the man walked away,
I stood rooted to confused with
her shame and anger to react.
10 years of past the hurt,
shame and anger still flood
over me with the memory.
But one thing I am certain,
none of the men I knew who served in
Vietnam deserve to die or be maimed either
physically or mentally.
I think it is necessary
now to give Vietnam to give
another view of Vietnam that
have the day to day life of
an infantry man on the ground.
I have always been asked
what I thought about Vietnam,
but never what it was
like to fight in Vietnam.
This is the way it was for us,
but platoon of Delta one six
in the afterward he talks
about why he wrote this book
in writing the killing zone.
I had two goals.
I wanted future young infantry lieutenants
and noncommissioned officers to learn
from my experiences both good and bad.
Some actions I took as a combat officer
had worked out well and some had not.
The time had come to deal with both.
Perhaps some would learn from my mistakes,
especially the lessons that combat,
especially the lesson that
combat does not go by the book.
I also wanted to show future generations
that the American soldier in Vietnam
was a good soldier.
In 1978 the anti war anti military feeling
in the United States was pervasive in
the newspapers, on television among
writers and movies and in colleges.
I had started college and
at the University of Denver
in the fall of 1968 while
I was still on active
duty in the military,
the students for a democratic society,
the weathermen and other antiwar groups
on campus targeted to anyone in the
military as fair game for
their anti war stance.
Such hostility was not pleasant
for me or other Vietnam veterans.
It was hard to be denigrated
for serving your country.
Many veterans have never admitted.
Many veterans never admitted they were
in the service for many years after
Vietnam,
angry at the antiwar faction.
I wanted to set the record straight by
proving that the men I served with had
fought and died with honor
and here are the men
that died and made the ultimate sacrifice
for freedom
and for their brothers in arms from
Delta Company. First Battalion. No,
the 14th Infantry Third Brigade,
Fourth Infantry Division,
PFC Donald Lawrence Glover,
Pfc Norman Charles Kissing
her Pfc Robert Wayne Seaton,
Spec for Gregory Timeless Thomas iding
Spec for Charles Irwin
Edwin. Dot. Kaufman,
Pfc James Garrett Miller.
Okay.
Spec for James Strong,
Yoder
PFC William Henry Whorf Spec
for Steven Richard Anderson,
Spec for Louis Charles Nelson,
Second Lieutenant William Dwight Ordway,
Pfc Paul James Miller,
Spec for Jose Cortez,
Pfc Charles Peter,
totally it
and second lieutenant John C.
Martin.
So
Fred downs.
Second Lieutenant asked us to
do two things in this book.
First,
learn from his experiences,
the mistakes, the lessons,
and that is what we do here.
We read and we study and
we think and we learn.
Then the second thing he asked is that
we remember the man who fought and died
with honor.
Then that's something that we need to
do and we should continue to do each and
every day.
Remember
in that is one
thing about this podcast
that is a
has a lot of meaning to me is the fact
that people are listening it and the
memory of these types of men and
the challenges that they faced,
it will be remembered.
They will be remembered
always.
So
once again,
the book is called the killing zone,
my life and the Vietnam War
by Frederick downs. It's,
it's a fantastic read. It's a
fantastic book. It's a fantastic,
okay
dedication and, and it's a, it
doesn't incredible job of honoring,
honoring these men that fought so hard
and are in a very unpopular war and
by the book and read it. You will, you
will absolutely get a lot out of it.
Echo Charles,
I believe we can move on to the
next sector of this podcast.
And again,
um,
if nothing else is delivered
through this podcast,
you know,
let's let it be these couple things,
these couple ideas of learning lessons
from other people's experiences in
remembering other people sacrifices.
That's definitely one of the driving
forces behind my wheel to do this podcast.
Okay?
And we're going to keep doing the
podcast echo. Get me out of here. Please.
Let me out of this situation over
there. I'm in that zone right now. Um,
I need to send up a red star
cluster. You know what that is? So,
so in the military, when you need
help, it's a red star cluster. It's a,
it's a flare.
You pop up and it means you couldn't
communicate with anybody and you need some
help. So there's my red star cluster. Do
you need to jump in and say, Hey Jocko,
speaking of the podcast, here's
how we can support it, you know,
so talk about that while I go get over
here and get myself under control before
I start smashing things.
Uh,
yeah,
if you want to send any reinforcements
to support Jocko and end our podcasts
here while supporting yourself
with supplementation, by the way,
good idea.
Go to on it.com/jocko so on.
It has like these supplements that
we take supplements for your joints,
Krill oil, boom, shroom
tech for a performance.
Hard stuff, you know, cross fit
Jujitsu if you're trying to go hard,
you know, hardcore in the paint.
Yeah, shroom tech boom. Um,
also if you do your shopping at Amazon,
which I think we all do, um,
good click through our website.
We have a little link there. Um, you
know, you can support it that way.
That's a super easy way. All you gotta do
this, remember to do it before you shop.
That is helpful. Yeah, very much so.
We also have a new tool
because can you, can you make them
remembering part a little bit easier?
Yes. So when you know, you figure, Hey,
I got to remember to go to the
website before I shop on Amazon.
Sometimes I'm in a hurry,
whatever, you know, maybe I'm
thinking about other stuff.
I'm not thinking about Jockos
podcast every single day. All Day.
I got to buy some, you know, some
cleaners, some duct tape, whatever.
Here's a way so you, it helps you remember
and or makes you not have to remember,
know this little tool called the
trooper tool. Oh, jock podcast.
Super tool. Thanks to Brady for the Allen
Brady. It's, it's a cool little thing.
It's like this small little thing is
pretty cool. He, you click on, there's,
there's a little link on both websites.
So you click on the thing,
it asks you if you want it,
you click yes,
puts a little icon there on your
browser and it basically direct to the,
to the affiliate Amazon
link automatically.
You don't gotta think it's dope.
That's a really easy way to
support the podcast. Yeah.
The,
the,
it doesn't cost you anything.
Yeah. It cost to Amazon something.
And it seems to me like Amazon can afford
to kick a little bit to the podcast
over here. Right? Yeah.
And it does serve its purpose because
you don't have something, you know,
like Amazon, they're, you know, they're
a good company, provides good stuff,
good service and all that. And they're
trying to get the word out and you know,
they'd be partner with people who,
who can get the word out. Yeah.
There's people that are going
to go, oh, you know what?
I want to support the podcast so I will
buy this instead of buying it through
some other website,
they're going to go to the store that's
going to support something that they
enjoy or something that they get value
out of, hopefully from this podcast.
So yeah, that's an awesome way to support.
We appreciate it and it makes it like,
it's kind of this little tool.
It's kind of cool because it kind of makes
it official. You know, like if you're,
I mean if you're one of the people that
listen to this and really talk with us
and stuff, it's a, it is a cool way to
kind of be more part of the it group,
I guess. It seems like it, when I
put mine up there I'm like, Hey,
you know I'm like a fish. I
don't know. It felt weird. Again,
Echo Charles is in the game. We
did that. So it was cool. Yeah,
it's a really cool tool. You
don't have to, it's safe.
It's not like you just put it on if
you don't want it on there anymore for
whatever reason.
Right click it right click and it,
cause she made a little video that
shows you go to the Jocko podcast,
youtube channel and Echo Charles made a
video of very high speed instructional
video on how to do this. Trying to
waste anybody's time. It's really easy.
You are not around with
the instructional video.
I think that was very
impressive. And, and by the way,
subscribe,
do me a favor troopers.
Subscribe to the Youtube Channel,
the Jocko podcast, youtube channel.
That way when Echo,
cause I'm been,
I've been to hacking on echo to make
little outtakes and other little
conversations and videos and
he's like, well you know, we,
we got some subscribers
but maybe you know,
if we had some more maybe I'd be more so
we need to motivate Echo Charles just a
little bit because so we
could get some outtake videos,
some other other interesting videos.
I wanted to do a little pre video today
of what it was like when we were getting
set up because we have a little ritual
that we go through when we're making some,
some beverages, you know, some, some
Alpha brainy and we have, you know,
so I was like, I'd be pretty cool if
you shot a little video. And he's like,
well you know, maybe one day, no,
I actually am imitating. So subscribe
to the, I don't think, if it doesn't,
I mean it's just, just go to, go to
the Jocko podcast channel on Youtube,
subscribe at youtube.com/chocolate pie.
And also what's cool about
that is when you do that,
then you get little emails that say,
it's not like you just
get an email and says,
hey Jocko podcasts just uploaded a new
video. I get those. And I'm always like,
oh yeah, cool. Now I can watch the
video and even that's option. Oh okay.
If you don't opt out. But yeah,
that's a good, I have, um,
remember that that one,
a cha children's book idea I had.
Yeah. You probably forget cause
you know, you need to remind me,
I got a lot of ideas that I had that
on video when we were talking anyway.
Oh yeah, that'd be funny. Yeah. So yeah,
I'm going to pull some of some
things you've got understand.
So I have a certain standards,
I'm talking not talking to you,
echo and talking to people
that are listening right
now. I mean you're here too.
So I guess I'm talking to you too,
but people got to understand that there's
a certain expectation in my mind of
what the podcast is and
what it's supposed to be.
So when something happens
that's not quite there,
I'm like, you know what, I
don't really, hey, you know,
I don't want to talk about that on the
podcast. But it's like, for instance,
before we hit record, we're
recording, but before we go,
before I opened the show, we're
talking about something, right?
We're always talking about something
and sometimes those conversations are 20
minutes, half an hour. We're
talking about real stuff,
we're talking about legit things. But we
haven't even introduced the podcast yet.
So that goes into scrap pile right now.
Some of the scrap metal material,
while it might not be in March,
marching step with what the podcast is,
it does perhaps have a, have a life
that it could live and it could,
it could guide people in a certain way
and it's stuff that people might be
interested in.
So that could be youtube download,
you know,
youtube just posted on there.
So that way people get a little taste
of other things around the podcast,
which I think people would dick. Yeah,
yeah, that makes sense. So like, you know,
if you free, you buy an Echo Charles,
free your mind. You're totally right.
I'm the thank you. Thank
you once for once. Yeah.
Yeah. Cause you know if you listened
to it on iTunes you're like,
why am I going to sit and watch? And
Josh would talk to each other. You know,
I listened to one and I got
to look at them too. You know,
a lot of people might not be interested
in that really. There's some moments,
you know what I do is I,
well I watched certain moments
of the podcast on Youtube.
Yeah. Like when I know I was
feeling intense about something,
I go and see what it, see what
that looks like. So like, okay,
what does that look like when I'm
feeling that? Does it look like,
does it look like from the outside,
what it feels like from the inside?
Because even today I was
getting pretty fired up. Like,
I mean you're talking about
heroes and young man, man,
18 1920 years old that said,
okay,
this unpopular war. I'll go fight
it. I'll go fight it. You know,
I'll go rest of my life, I'll go out
there in the jungle and live in, you know,
I was, I was, uh, out this week
in the field, right. Camping. I,
I kept putting it in quotes on Twitter.
I was putting in quotes because I was
like, I can't call this the field,
but you know, it wasn't the comfort
of a house, right. It was, it was,
and it was, you know, bugs and ants and,
and I'm like thinking to myself, you know,
this is nothing. And I
was thinking back to, uh,
to the forgotten Highlander and remember
the bugs were just eating those guys
alive and you know,
you just,
you just can't, you can't
compare. So these guys that,
that just stepped up
fought and I just wanna
I just wanna always, you know, that
kind of thing will get me fired up.
So when I go back to the videos
sometimes, like, oh man, what,
what was I looking like,
you know,
a little self assessment and I wonder if,
cause when I'm feeling that way, I'm like,
okay, you got to detach a little bit.
Cause you're starting to
get a little bit fired.
I'm gonna start breaking them and start
getting them like really emotional about
something. And so I got to, I
got a little red flag goes up,
I go to you going to back
off a little bit here.
We don't have to edit the
video and if I break down,
so I got to just back off and
sometimes I got to see you.
What does that look like? Does it look,
can you tell? Am I looking? You know,
so that's the kind of thing that I
like to go back and look at the youtube
videos and say, you know,
what does this, what does this
look like? Yeah, yeah, yeah.
There's some value. There was a lot of
value on youtube. We're probably not,
you know, capitalizing, I dunno,
whatever. For people who care.
And it's weird too because the interesting
thing about all this is you used the
word capitalized,
right?
In the fact of the matter is we aren't
really capitalizing on this at all.
And I keep getting told by a variety of
different people what to do to you to do
what? That right there to
capitalize. Just capitalize,
not for us to come and I know
everybody, you know, but what we,
what would you want to do is we want to
maximize the effort that we put in here.
Want to maximize it so that people
get the most out of it. That's,
that's what I know.
That's what you meant.
I know you didn't mean like let's run to
the cash machine because we're doing it
for the passion of doing it.
That's what I'm sitting here
for sitting here so I can tell.
So I can tell this story right here
about these guys and I know, you know,
I know,
I hear from all kinds of cops.
I hear from my seal buddies that are
still in, that are listening to it,
that are asking me, texting me questions
going, hey man, what's going on with us?
Hey, what would you have
done differently here? Hey,
those are my buddies that are in,
that are getting ready to
deploy overseas right now.
And I get texts and emails and Twitter
things from guys that were guys that are
active duty in the Marine
Corps and the army.
So I know that we're getting the
word out there and that's what,
that's where I'm sitting here for.
So you make a good point with,
you know, there's a lot of people who
don't watch the video. Of course. I mean,
I don't watch podcasts
videos, right? I mean, why?
The reason podcasts are so convenient
that you can be doing something else.
You don't have to dedicate, you have
to dedicate your all your senses to it.
You only have to dedicate two of them,
your ears and your brain because you
don't have to dedicate your eyes.
You don't have to dedicate your asked to
sit down and share and watch something.
You can walk around, you can
do yard work, you can drive,
you can do what you gotta do.
But I think the shorter little youtube
clips where you go, hey, check this out.
This is when Jocko and I were discussing
a kids book that echo was talking about,
or yeah, I'm going to post.
Yeah. Post that thing though.
And it's interesting cause a
lot of people apparently don't.
I mean don't are surprised that I looked
different than I sat on a pair I guess.
Oh yeah. They think you're a skinny
white hipster or that's what they think.
Maybe I am at heart. Maybe you
are at heart, you're just trapped.
Maybe you identify as a
skinny white hipster even
though you're a 227 a I don't,
I don't identify myself by
my physical characteristics.
It's what's in my heart and my mind. The
content of your character, like to say,
think the youtube. I just,
good idea. Yeah. We'll post
more. So I have a lot to men.
So many outtakes a lot.
You've done something really good
outtake videos in the past. Yeah. Yeah.
They're pretty, yeah, from when we were
filming commercials and stuff. Yeah,
those are good. All right.
Anything else? Jack?
Can you in chocolate store?
Did you talk about that? Yes.
Go to the store to buy
some Bryce and merchandise.
Somebody who hit me up on Twitter
the other day and they're like, hey,
you should set up a, we've got asked this
a bunch of times, set up a Patrick on,
is that what it's called?
Patriarchy. Patriarchy,
where you can donate to the podcast
certain amount. And I just said, hey man,
go buy a tee shirt. You know,
that supports us just as well.
And you get a t shirt and just that's a
good way to support the podcast by buy
some merchandise. Buy some gear. Yeah,
the chocolate store. That's a good one.
Tee shirts, coffee amongst stickers.
Those are kind of cool. Um,
one of my friends saw to
Jacqueline stickers in the
wild in the wild one day or
maybe one location here at San Diego.
Everyone in San Diego,
we know everyone in San Diego
doesn't count. I Dunno. Yeah.
Cleveland counts.
But yeah.
Awesome. Good. Yup.
So now we get to those
questions from the inner webs.
First Question Jocko is the minimal
amount of competent defensive ability
defense,
essentially the most overlooked essential
stabilizer of young male psyche.
So this question, this actually, this
actually came across the interwebs as a,
as a statement,
an opinion.
And I kind of rephrased it just a
little bit to make it into a question,
but it actually came across
someone and saying, look,
he believes this person believes
that the no one had a fight,
no competent defensive, defensive ability.
I call that knowing how to fight is,
and he thinks it's the most essential
stabilizer of a young male psyche.
I agree with this statement.
I think that, yeah,
I completely agree.
I think that learning how to fight and
knowing how to fight gives you real
confidence and security, not just
in the form of being secure, but as,
as in in opposition to insecurity.
Right.
Because when you know how to fight,
all of a sudden you don't have anything
to prove anymore. Yeah. And we,
this change is so I,
you know,
I wish I would have learned how
to fight and I'm watching. Sure.
We fought all the time. When I was a kid,
we fought, we didn't know how to fight.
So what do we have to prove
that we knew how to fight.
If we actually knew how to fight, we
wouldn't have to prove that all the time.
So I absolutely agree with us and that's
why I'm constantly trying to get people
to get into Jujitsu. You know, get
your kids in. Did you get your,
get your 13 year old boy, your 10
year old boy. Get him into Jujitsu.
Your girl too.
I mean your girl too because your
girl is gonna use it for defense. Um,
girls don't have the constant
tension of fighting that guys have.
It is part of who we are.
When I shake someone's hand,
I don't care what kind of mood I'm in.
I am thinking about taking them down.
I am thinking about what I'm
gonna do to him in a fight.
It doesn't matter if
I'm meeting Santa Claus,
I'm thinking about doing a double leg.
I'm thinking about what,
what his weight his, does he have
cauliflower ear? That's what I'm doing.
And guys do that, guys do that.
And it's real. And I mean,
especially in the environment
I grew up in the seal teams.
I mean everybody's got that constant
like test evaluates the evaluation,
you know?
So if you don't know how to fight,
there's only one way to figure
out where you are and that
is to fight know.
And so you end up doing stupid things,
stupid things to prove your,
your manhood.
And I hate to use that word,
but you end up doing stupid
things to prove your manhood.
So my recommendation is, well, I
totally agree with this statement.
I think it is a huge stabilizer of,
of your personality and,
and your psyche as a man. So teach,
get those kids to learn Jujitsu.
They're going to understand the things
you understand violence you respected
because you know where you've got
choked out. You know it's happened.
You know that is a horrible feeling.
It's a horrible feeling when another human
being can't control you 100% you know
what? Physically, it doesn't matter
how smart you are anymore. I'm sorry.
It doesn't matter. It doesn't matter. It
doesn't matter how smart you are anymore.
When you are getting completely
physically dominated by someone,
it doesn't matter that you're
smarter than them at that time.
There's nothing you can do about it.
What are you gonna Challenge them to a
spelling bee. It's not going to help you.
You're, you're under their control. And
that's a horrible, horrible feeling.
And so I think it's a, you know, and I
felt that, you know, when I was a kid,
you know, I got bullied just like
everybody, everybody gets bullied.
It's at a certain point, you
know, you show up to high
school, you're 13 years old.
I was 30 I was a young, whatever,
however that works when you are born.
That was born in September.
So I was a young,
scrawny kid and I didn't get
bullied to some crazy extent,
but you get picked on,
you get picked on,
you get in little scuffles and you
get thrown around by a kid that's,
that reached puberty when he
was nine and he's now, you know,
six feet to 20 and I'm showing up at
school 13 years old way and a buck 45
you're going to get, you're going to get
physically controlled and it's not fun.
And so I didn't know how to fight.
I was trying to figure it out.
And there was no,
no one knew how to fight back then unless
you were a boxer, maybe a wrestler. Um,
but yeah, so definitely this is a
huge piece. Helps you with I think,
I think kids that know how to fight
are going to get an a lost less street
fights.
They're going to do a lot less stupid
things to prove themselves because guess
what?
They already have the essential primal,
animalistic characteristic
of physical domination.
And that goes a long way.
Yeah.
And we talked about this before,
back to the the girls thing,
getting your girls into it.
You know how when you get into
any kind of physical situation,
even if you're in a crowd and
someone starts shoving someone else,
not even you and pull him,
you feel the force of somebody or
someone's just all like on you.
Or even if someone like, I don't know,
tackles you or something like that.
It's like this kind of
imposed physical situation.
And when you're into Jujitsu,
that's every day.
So you get used to that real quick and
in fact you get real comfortable with it.
But as a girl,
not trying to like
win fight, now you know,
I know what you did,
so I'm going to trade when
fights and beat up guys.
That's not really what it's for for girls.
It's more for knowing how to function,
knowing where to be, where not to
be. Because man, if you don't know,
you just simply don't know.
And also being totally right and
then also being inoculated to the,
the physical comedy when it
happens. So you can't win. I mean,
not looking to win fights.
There's go watch youtube. Yeah,
there's all kinds of videos of girls
and just working over guys and I mean in
street fights there's one particular
where this girl's just triangle.
Our mock just choke. Just
crushing this kid. Yeah. Well the,
I mean the truth is if you learned,
you did. If someone knows Jesus,
someone doesn't,
the the chance of the person knowing you
did to winning the fight is very, very,
very high. Even if you're a
girl, it's still applies to you.
Of course the girls that have physical
diff disadvantage because she's smaller,
weaker, whatever. But like I said,
Jujitsu is just this huge jump in,
you know,
ability as far as fights go and you know
something else from a pure self defense
perspective, if you, a lot of times,
let's say a girl's not able to physically,
let's say she's a hundred pounds and
she's a guy attacks or that's 200 pounds,
she might not be able to put him to sleep.
She might not be able to finish him,
but she may able to be able to survive.
Fend the guy off for a minute and 30
seconds instead of two seconds. Yup.
Instead of four seconds
instead of eight seconds.
So that's what it takes for someone
to hear, for someone to see.
So every second counts.
And if you know you did too,
I guarantee you it's,
it's really hard to subdue
somebody that knows some Jujitsu.
If you don't know anything,
you are going to have a hard time
getting control them. They're going to,
they're going to be,
and even if you're stronger than them,
you'll be able to get ahold of the, maybe
eventually if there are a lot smaller,
a lot weaker than you, but it's going
to be a fight. And a lot of, a lot of,
you know, you read a lot of stories
when in self defense situations,
if the girl puts up a decent fight,
the guy's not going to have any of it.
You know, he's going to realize
that he's not looking for that.
He's not looking for a fight,
he's looking for something else.
And so the fight begins, he backs off.
So yeah, absolutely. It applies for,
for girls as well. And there's just a
certain level of confidence, you know,
and I've seen that, you know, my
son's had a couple of little scuffles,
a couple that I've witnessed
to where, uh, you know,
he just was like not trying to,
not trying to have a problem until someone
just grabs him and is obviously going
to do, try and do something to them and
then that person's getting launched.
You know, like a perfect judo
cause you're going to, you know,
how hard is it to judo? Throw somebody
that doesn't know any judo, Jujitsu,
it's so easy. So you see a kid fly through
the air, hit the ground, you see my son,
you know,
just like there's no guard passing
because the person has even know what the
part is there. So it's just straight to
mountain. And then once you're in mount,
the person has no idea
what's happening and,
and they're completely controlled and
they're getting put to sleep. That's it.
It's as easy as that.
Yeah. And so funny how you,
this is kind of the part that I forget
actually every once in a while where,
how you brought up,
when you shake someone's hand, you're
always thinking about it or whatever.
So that's, that's the
thing too. That's why,
that's why it's almost like if you don't
know what you did to like or are for
real fighting's not many out there man.
There's not many.
But even we'll just say
if you don't know Jujitsu,
you might fall into this trap by thinking,
well you know, I might, you know,
you never know.
He's not on all the time or he might
not be ready for this or you know,
all surprise them with a like does punch
or something like this and they'll,
they won't give it its due credit.
But the thing is when you learned Jujitsu
Bruh, that's all you're thinking about.
You're like, Oh fuck, take this guy
right here. 100% of the time you,
you can be laying in your, in your
bed with your wife and she'll be like,
hey give me a hug. And you're like under
hook there. Yes, exactly. The whole time.
So you can't really to surprise the
guy who knows Jujitsu to surprise them.
It's super hard. Like you gotta
do from behind. I don't know.
Even if you think up for me, I like, you
know what to do from beginning, you know,
you gotta like I dunno hit
him or something really hard,
knock them out one punch or something
like that to knock somebody out.
So yeah, but that's so funny
cause that, that is how it is.
Even as like a, like a high
level guy, you're still like,
it's always on your mind.
Like it's like you're walking around
with this big powerful like gun or
something. Like you're like,
okay, who wants to get shot?
Not that you want to
shoot people specifically,
but it's like this radar that's like,
okay, who wants to get shot kind of thing.
Cause you're just rates ready. You
know, you're just ready to do the time.
And to me honestly, it's so
instinctive. You know, at this point,
part of every movement that you make is
thinking about that and your, you know,
you ever had somebody that doesn't know
what you did to like maybe you haven't
seen someone in awhile.
I've had that half what I've seen someone
for awhile and I mean 20 years so they
have no idea what Jujitsu is.
We've gone a completely different paths
in our lives and they like grab a hold
of you as if it was the old days and
you're going to have a tussle and it's
edible. It's just a, it's
just a four second, you know,
Spirit crushing maneuver of death and,
and you're happy to do it too,
you know,
cause as an adult like you know,
I think anywhere past 26 27 years old,
it's hard to get away with like getting
into a wrestling match in public or you
know, somewhere outside of
the math. That's interesting.
You might not have known
that, but I don't know.
I think I speak for more than
more people than just myself,
but there's a part of your
mind that kind of helps it.
It happens just with your
friend, you know, or something
like that. Just always on.
You're always hoping for for a
scrap. You know what? Ironically,
back to the part where,
where I was saying, um,
it's Kinda hard to surprise
that you did to guy. Ironically,
the easiest time to surprise
the Jujitsu guy is on the mat.
If you're another Jujitsu guy, what
do you do is you play like, oh,
we're just going light right now
and then you go hard. You know,
so you can't really surprise them in the,
like in public you gotta like you gotta
learn Jujitsu, go on the mat with them,
make them think you're not rolling.
Are they in surprise?
And you know,
I think that's part of it is you become
more aware when you're just talking.
What you've been talking about the
past couple of minutes is awareness.
And when you have Jujitsu
in your brain then,
and it's true with
boxing too, and Moy, Tai,
when you have that stuff in your brain,
then you can't help but be aware of what's
happening around you because it's in
there. It's like knowing that the
color of the table is Brown. Like you,
you know what that
person's body position is.
You're looking and seeing that
their stance is off balance.
You're seeing an under hook exposed,
you know, so you can't help,
you can't take it away.
So your awareness increases.
You also are aware of what problems can
occur really quickly. So if you start,
you know, if you're a girl
and you say, oh wait a second,
now I'm backed into a corner where I
can't get out, I don't like this feeling.
It becomes a,
it increases your awareness as a
human and makes you more aware of your
surroundings. So there's so many
benefits. It's kind of ridiculous.
You kind of have almost like one level
up from that or awareness that you're
talking about because like how
are you saying it's part of that.
Even if you don't know how to fight, it's
still kind of on your mind. You know,
like all guys have that
kind of of evaluates,
especially with the guys close to
your close to you, who you are,
what are the age, size,
whatever, whatever the scenario.
Even like if you're a scholar
and no one else's scholar,
then another scholar walk through
this evaluation, you know?
So that's how it is naturally
smart. This guy. Yeah. Well,
so as a guy, just naturally
you're going to have even more,
it's like you know what the
color of brown is or whatever,
but just instinctually you're
always looking for Bratton.
That's kind of what it's like.
So now you,
when you're doing these evaluations
that are going to happen anyway,
your Jujitsu mind is right there
at the front. Ready the whole time.
Yeah.
They thing to people.
But that's not to be confused with like
you're aggressive and want to fight.
That's the weird thing.
It's like you don't want to actually
fight with people because you don't feel
the need to like, oh, I got, I dunno.
That's where this whole
conversation started off.
And also now you not feel like
you need to prove anything.
But I literally am like, oh, there really
want to get in a fight with this guy.
I'm gonna get my knuckles.
You know,
I'm not going to rip my tee
shirt disguising it. Right.
Yeah. This is really, no,
I fight every single day.
I don't need,
I don't,
I don't care about this guy.
This is a two second thing where I've
got to scuff up my knee on the pavement
and he's probably gonna rip my shirt,
my shirt, and that's going to be a pain.
And then I got to deal with the cops.
If they show up, it's just a big pain.
Whereas if you don't fight
and you have that opportunity,
maybe you got the thing
inside you and will,
you don't know the payoff of the
fight, right? If you don't know or,
or if you're just insecurity over the
payoff of the fight and hopefully winning
is bigger than all the detriments that
you had to be. I used to tell him,
my platoon guys, when we were overseas
before the war started, they didn't know.
So guys were overseas. What
are you doing? You're drinking,
you're out in bars or just causing
problems or whatever. And I've, you know,
before we go on over here, hey guys,
if you feel like fighting tonight,
come find me.
Cause if you want to fight, come find me
and we'll, it'll be all be good. You know,
you, you know we'll, we'll fight and
it's all good. You won't get in trouble.
You won't get arrested. You
won't get hurt. It's all
good. You'll get in trouble.
You get in trouble for sure. You're not
getting in trouble with the law though.
You know what I mean? You're not
going to get that kind of trouble.
You didn't have a little trouble in your
situation and your in your positioning
is going to be troublesome.
So yeah,
it's better to fight amongst yourself
than to fight against the outsiders who
are going to sue you. Pull a knife out
and stab you in the throat, whatever.
Right. Don't do that. Stay out of the
street fights. Not Worth it, you know.
All right.
I agree with it too though.
When you said you agree that it is
the stabilizer in religion. It is.
Cause if you don't know, you don't
even know how much you don't know.
It's funny cause we get a lot of people
that have started training, Jujitsu move.
Yes. A have over. They'll come on
Twitter or on on the Facebook he and,
and say, you know, um, hey, you
started training Jujitsu. Oh my God,
I can't believe I need to train this all
the time. I can't believe I got control.
How they always say how humiliating
and sometimes they say humbling,
but sometimes I think even
when they say humbling,
they actually mean humiliating
because they you've,
that's the weird thing when you're
walking around on the earth without the
knowledge, you don't, you look at
other people, you think, you know what?
This guy knows Jujitsu. I heard this
guy knows just to, it doesn't matter.
I'm strong, I'm athletic. I'll just
hit him in the neck. Or even even,
you know what? I'm just strong
enough. He's not going to get my,
how's he going to get my arm over there?
That's not gonna work.
I'll just pull my arm back. And then you
get on the mat and you go, oh my Lord,
I have no control over this situation.
This guy has effortlessly making me
submit over and over and over again.
And that's when the reality hits
the reality hits, doesn't it?
On the first time you tap cause
on the first time you tap you go,
oh I'm going to, I'll just, I won't
do that single movement again.
I won't stick my head over there.
Okay.
So then you get your arm locked and then
you get your foot locked and then you
get your knee lock and then you get
[inaudible] and then you get a gay teen
again. Then you get rid of.
So you all, it's just a lose,
lose, lose, lose, lose, lose,
lose.
And then you go after.
Usually for me it's like three to five
times with somebody that's never changed
you. So before three to five times before
they realize like, oh I will never,
cause you knew when you tap,
a guy wants us never trained before and
he comes at you so hard, he and his mind,
he thinks all this time I'm going to
get them and they don't even come close.
They don't even realize. So yeah, get on
the mat man and learn. Learn the Jujitsu.
Nope,
please cover the over or please cover
overcoming the frustrations of beginning
Jujitsu. And this is coming
from a 54 year old by the way,
but not quitting. Good. Good
for him. That's awesome.
Glad you're picking up the Jujitsu at
54 years old. Uh, okay. So how do you,
the frustrations of beginning
Jj and it is absolutely,
if you have the wrong mindset,
it's viciously frustrating because of
everything we just talked about and you
think,
oh,
I'll just do this and let's go a little
bit harder and I just won't put my arm
there. I'll be able to win. You're not
going to win. You are going to lose.
You're going to lose over and over and
over again to people that are smaller
than you. Weaker than you.
Not as tough as you are.
Literally not as tough as you are.
Not as tough as you are. You know,
Jujitsu has a faction of,
of getting nerds,
for lack of a better word,
straighten nerds.
And no offense to the nerds out there,
but you know,
people that are not
physically active and in some,
for some reason they fall into Jujitsu
at some point and, and the, and they,
all of a sudden you've got a guy that's,
they're not tough, but they'll know,
they'll know the moves and
I'll finish you so that,
so those are the people you're going to
lose to. So, and it's a, it's a long,
long,
slow journey that takes a long time.
Now that being said,
if you train for a month and
someone's trained zero is,
that journey's not that long. You've been
that guy, you, you will beat that guy.
I mean, you know, again,
you take two people,
one of them knows Jujitsu for a
month and one of them doesn't. Yup.
That guy's going to win. I mean, you know,
basic weight, same weight, basic same,
you know, you can't have
somebody that's completely weak,
but in six months you're beaten.
Anybody that's,
I'm trained for 95% of it.
Maybe you're 99% of people that aren't
trained, but, but, but as far as like,
you think you show up and in six months
you're going to be beating a blue belt.
It's not happening.
A beating a purple belt is not happening.
You're not gonna,
you're not gonna catch a purple belt know
in, in your first two or three years.
Um, unless you got to somebody
that doesn't, of course,
like Glover, Jeff Glover,
he'll, he'll, he'll, that
people put him in all kinds of,
I mean, he does that in comedy. You
just saw that I've met at Morrison.
He lefts all kinds of crazy things happen.
So yeah. Can that happen? Of course.
But as far as legitimately
taking someone down, yeah,
it's not going to happen
to you. So, so that's all.
That's what I'm saying is a long,
slow journey. Especially too,
because everyone's on that bus.
We've talked about this before.
Everyone's on the bus getting better.
So that blue belt that started,
that you started six months behind or
a year behind. So he's a blue belt.
You're a year behind him.
He's not stopping getting better.
So as you start to pursue his game,
his game is evolving and
changing and improving student,
you're not going to get there.
And then on top of that,
when you do learn something new, it
takes time to incorporate into your game.
So if I taught you echo a new move
tonight as it, hey, here's a school,
here's this new setup for the arm lock,
and we drilled it 10 times and you went
now and started to apply that, gee,
it would make your game worse because
you'd be trying to apply a move that you
don't know 100% yet. Like you got
some good solid moves that you do.
And those are, you know,
those work really well.
So when you start incorporating this new
move, you don't need to know it. Well,
you don't get it all together. So you're
going to fail out it a hundred times.
It's not going to work a hundred times
before you get it. And by the way,
every time you tried it on me, I got on
top and then I smashed you in the night.
So you're, you're sacrificing.
And it's in every time.
So you're actually going backwards a
little bit before you can go forward.
So that's problematic and that's very,
very frustrating.
Occasionally you might learn something
that like really improves your game
dramatically, almost instantly.
That happens from time to
time. Some will say, Hey,
put your arm position here. Or Hey,
you know, whatever the case may be.
But generally when you incorporate
something new, it can take some time.
You're going to get injuries,
you're going to get little injuries,
you're going to get big injuries, you're
going to be sore, you're going to, so yes,
you will be frustrated.
So how do you counter all that?
You just got to embrace it.
You got to embrace all those things.
You got to enjoy all those things.
And I hate to be cliche,
but you got to enjoy the journey.
You got to enjoy getting tapped
out by somebody that smoking.
Be Amazed by that. Say, Dang, how did
that just happen? That is impressive.
Uh, you know, say hey, got a little
war scar on my face. I got, you know,
split the eye open. Okay, cool. Chicks
dig scars. You know what I mean?
Just going to go. Don't, don't,
don't look at all that stuff as negative.
Look at it as, you know, it's like,
don't rush to the end. Don't rush to the
end. Don't be in a rush to get there.
Take your time and enjoy the sites
that you're going to go for. Also,
I've said this before,
select your training partners carefully,
especially like you're 54 years old.
You don't want to be rolling with a 20
year old steroid freak that's going white
belt trying to kill you.
You want to be rolling with a cool mellow
purple belt that's wants to do Jujitsu
and train, um, and find
me. I would just say,
remember that Jujitsu should be fun.
It should be all those other things,
all those frustrating, all those
challenges, all those things,
all that humiliation and humid and
getting humbled, but she'd be a good time.
You should have fun. We were doing
Jujitsu. I know I do. Yeah, yeah.
Like a video game,
right?
You know how I was going to hit
town for a couple of days, man,
and I came back and had a little
injury that I figured figured out.
It took me a little while.
I got my jacked up finger and
it took me a little while,
a little while to get the right,
get the right apparatus to splint
it properly and protect it.
But it's,
but tonight I train and I was so happy.
I was so happy. Go and getting
on the mat, just saying yes.
Yeah,
that that is how we're all these,
all the junk parts that come with
it were quote unquote jumper.
You know like the bitterness.
Yeah. I got choked out. Aware.
That's all part of the game.
Seems obvious, right? Yeah.
It's all part of the game.
But be happy that that's the
game you're in. You know? I mean,
do you get some basic,
I mean if you don't do Jujitsu,
this would be kind of kind of an
insight. Basically all it is, you go,
if you go to a class, you go in,
you, you may or may not warm up.
You learn a move. Whether it be
a submission move or just a move.
You learn a move to move three moves,
sometimes four moves and then you to
Roland straight up. You guys are
fighting, no strikes. That's it.
You're finding no strikes. If
you whatever moves, you know,
go ahead and do them while in real
life against this guy. That's it.
If you don't know, if that's your
first day and you learn one, two,
three moves that first day, you better
try to do those moves. That's it.
So of course, you know, two, three
moves that you learned once. By the way,
and your role with someone who, even
if he's still a white belt or whatever,
he knows those moves and then you know,
three,
four more and he's practiced some in,
you know, in real time or whatever.
Of course he's going to get you,
you know, that's just how it works.
But keep in mind, the more
you go, the more you do, the
moves, more moves you learn,
the more you practice them in real life,
the better you get at them and you don't.
Let's go ahead and just apply this to
life as well because you just to such a
great metaphor for life,
whatever you're doing,
whatever goal you're trying to achieve,
if you're letting those frustrations,
we hit those obstacles. If you're letting
them control you and get you down,
that's the wrong attitude to
have. You know, look at it
as a learning opportunity.
Look at it as something that's good,
that's happening. Look at it as,
as a chance for you to try something new.
Look at it as the journey that you're
trying to achieve. And by the way,
anything that's easy to achieve
and you don't hit any obstacles,
well that's not worth
it, right? That's not,
is not going to get the full
satisfaction that you want out of that.
So in life as in Jujitsu,
don't get frustrated.
Embrace those challenges because those
are what is making this goal worthwhile.
You know, man, and I'm telling you when
you, let's say you well back to the, um,
avoiding frustrations specifically.
Um,
it does how you were
saying training partners,
that doesn't make a big difference
because sometimes every once in a while,
like I've,
I've heard of people where they,
their schedule doesn't allow them to
catch like the beginner class for example.
So they're like, hey, I have no choice.
I got to do this more
intermediate or advanced class.
So they're the only white belt
and the next, you know, guy,
even close to the Tim is
like advanced blue belt.
So that's going to be
a steep learning curve.
It's going to be tough because how are
you going to practice your moves in the
wild. You won't get to work
your offense. It's really,
but he was kind of the good thing
you get to work your defense.
So when you do get the opportunity to
exercise, like your offense, whether you,
you get another class or it just comes
but just takes longer or whatever,
but you know how good your defense
is going to be. Yeah. And I actually,
so from training with Dean
for so many years, you know,
he's just got some positions
that are brutal. Yeah. Brutal
positions. And you know,
for instance, his mount is, is
outstanding. He's when he gets the mount,
when anybody else that I've ever trained
with in my life as mountain with the
exception I guess of Hixon Gracie, I felt
like, oh well it's not dean. This is not,
you know, this isn't a horrible scenario.
Right. And not that I'm not that worried,
I'm not trying to degrade people I've
trained with, but that is a great,
Dean has an incredible amount and on top
of that Dean kind of knows my escapes.
So whereas if I roll with a random
other really good, you know,
worldclass black belt, they might not
know the particulars of my escape.
Dean actually does those and
he's good and he's good at it.
So you're right in that the more you train
with people that are better than you,
you're, your defense is going to be
very good. Cause like when you mount me,
I mean you've got a good solid
mountain, but I'm not, I'm
like, I'm like, okay cool.
I'm going to be out of this and
in a short period of time with,
with no real threats, keep telling
me and the re uh, you've had,
I mean, I'm sure it's the same way
if you've got dean mountain on you.
I mean my mouth,
because I don't have a great mouth.
My mouth is nothing compared to
deans. Nothing. Yeah, yeah. Fully.
Yeah, that's absolutely true.
And at the same time though,
so if you fall it,
and I don't want to say it's like a small
thing because it's pretty big chance
where if you enter a beginner class,
there's going to be a guy who's
just as much of a beginner is you.
And that's where you can
really flourish because you're,
you can practice moves your new moves,
which I mean, for lack of better term,
your junk moves, you know, junk
people. I will say this though,
whoever you roll with,
whether they're worse than you,
the same as you or better than you,
you're going to get a lot out of it.
Of course,
all three of them.
So you should roll with all
three of those types of people.
I have a tendency to want to usually
roll with guys that are, you know,
light good and,
and I should spend more than
I do. I mean, I definitely,
I trained with everybody that we got at
the gym. I'll turn him and everybody,
but I always prefer, of course, I
guess I shouldn't say of course,
because there are people that
are like white belt hunters
that want to go out there and be bullies.
I'm not like that.
I'd rather get bullied. Right. I
want to get, I want to feel the,
I want to get after it, you know? Uh,
but you definitely get benefit from
training with people that are better than
you. Worse than you, and the same as
you because you practice one of them.
You're practicing defense,
one of them.
You're practicing pure offense
and someone that's equal than you.
You got to start
practicing your setups and,
and your approaches and you got to
learn how to defend and do offense and
defense at the same time.
So it's all good, bro. Yeah.
That's basically the concept here.
Roll after it. Consider that scenario.
You roll with it and you're
talking from an ideal standpoint,
role with people better than you,
same as your worst in you or you know,
not as good as you. Um, for a
beginner, that's not really the option.
The worst than you guys. That's not
an option for a beginner. Like really,
and also there's no one
that's worse than them. Well,
as far as overcoming the
frustrations or whatever,
it is a good situation where you can
get in with guys just as beginner as you
and,
and it helped that they hang around and
listen after a certain amount of time.
Those guys who aren't as new or,
or I could,
I could see where it could
become frustrating if you
were the guy that you're
talking about earlier.
Let's say a guy that's,
you have to work late and you can only
go to the advanced class and all of a
sudden you think Jujitsu is just
getting crushed and destroyed.
They can't learn this really, I guess,
the distance to, to understand. But yeah,
that's, that's a good point. So keep in
mind that if you're in that situation,
it's okay. You're gonna, you're going to,
when you eventually get to roll with
people that are more your skill level,
you will be,
uh, you'll be that much better
off. Yeah. Yeah, for sure.
And, and watch the first
time you tap someone out with
the move that you learned.
Celebrate that. Did you, yeah,
that's a good, that's a good time.
Next question,
Jocko.
How do you balance the idea of checking
the ego well in an interview scenario
where you need to talk about yourself?
Okay. So good, good question.
I would say in that situation,
and that's something that it's not just
an interview situation where you're
going to need to do that. I mean, you're
dealing with your, your superiors,
you know, throughout the course of
your career, whatever that may be.
You're constantly interacting
with people and you of,
you're going to want to
make an impression. Uh,
so I think one of the best
ways to do this is instead of,
okay,
you speaking about why you're so awesome,
just state facts of let's
say accomplishments and let
them speak for themselves.
In other words, you know,
you wouldn't want to say, uh,
Yup, I am the best project manager
in the entire world. Right.
That's not,
that's sounds ego centric.
You know,
instead you'd say, uh, you know, I got
this a, we had a $38 million project,
got it done on time, under
budget, ahead of schedule.
And when I got done with that,
when they moved me to another project
that was off track and we got that one
back on schedule and back
on track as well. So that,
that's the kind of experience
that I've had and I,
and above to bring that here to this
company. Right. So you're not, you're not,
you know, there's a hint of, hey, this
is what I did. I can get some stuff done,
but you're not saying, listen, I'm better
than the people you currently have,
so you should hire me because I'm the
best cause you don't want to do that. Um,
and you know, so, so yeah, just
build, think about it, you know,
before you go in, how, what,
what experience that you have represents
the good qualities that you have.
So then you can say, if they say, you
know, how are you at meeting timelines?
You don't say I am perfect
and we're never late dope.
You just say you say you say, well
you know, as far as meeting timelines,
here's a bunch of projects
that I got completed on time.
The only one that I missed was one that
we had to roll back cause whatever that
we are actually showing a little bit
more humility. You're saying, hey,
here's what happened. You're being
logical about it and you'll speak to that.
I actually got a good question
that's similar to this one. Um,
about what's the best way to interview
people to see if they can be in a
leadership position.
And this is really hard.
This is really hard because it's
really hard to interviews and working.
I work with all kinds of
different companies and
everybody always has, you know,
hey, what's the best way
to interview? And Man,
I interviewed this guy
and he seems so great.
Or I interviewed this woman and
she seemed incredible and her,
her paper look great.
You know,
she looked great on paper and we
hired her and she's a disaster.
He's a disaster or whatever
the case may be. Because,
because there's people that are
very good interviewers, right?
I mean there's people that can interview
well they have the gift of Gab,
they can, they can bs their way through
anything and make themselves sound good.
So it can be really hard to identify if
someone's good is actually going to be
fit for a leadership position
or really any position.
So one of the things that I
was telling people to do is it,
when you go into these,
when you want to ask interview questions,
ask them scenario based questions and
say, okay, here's what's going on.
You've got these three people in your
department and one of the people has come
to you and said that they think there
might be something illegal going on in
with the other two. What actions
do you take? And you know,
have a scenario built out that you can
actually talk through and see where they
go and see what their mindset is and see
what they're going to develop as a plan.
And see how they would execute the plan.
So it's a great way of
figuring out how people think.
And then you know, even that's not a
guarantee because there's people that can,
can navigate those types of
answers as well. So, you know,
one thing you can do is hire people
on a little bit of a trial basis.
And that can be difficult
in some situations where
people are walking away from
one job to another job or they're not
going to do it on a 90 day trial basis.
But when you do have that opportunity,
it's a good thing to do as well. Um,
but hey,
so going back to the first question
about keeping your ego in check and an
interview,
like I said,
be confident but not cocky and let the
facts of your experience speak for your,
your abilities rather than
beating your own chest.
Yeah. So it's almost like, I mean,
correct me if I'm wrong here,
still you, you essentially, even
if you're talking yourself up,
you just, you simply state the
fact that you just state the fact,
don't say your opinion about it.
Just simply state the facts.
Here's what I did, you know,
we turned this project around, we
got it on, on track and on budget.
And that's the type of,
that's the type of experience that
I have in those situations. Right.
Just like how you're saying like even if
someone has got like an award to be the
best,
whatever salesman of the year,
the right tells me that you're the best
whatever of the year. And then, um,
like to say that in a
factual way would be,
I was recognized as the best guy in the
world instead of saying I'm the best guy
in the world who my award to to prove it,
you know?
So it's like you're seeing the fact
that you were recognized, you know,
not so much the fact that a way of
doing it stick to the facts. Right.
Just the facts. Just the facts. It's
good. Yeah. Sure. Next question.
Um,
how do you stay humble when you know
you have better skillsets than others?
You seem humble with all that
you've accomplished. Well,
this is just what like in general,
just holiday back, be humble.
How'd you stay humble when you know
you have better skill sets than, and
then he's saying that I seem humble with
all that I've accomplished, which is,
which is actually,
it's funny when I read that,
like it's not,
I'm sure that for the dude
is asking this question,
he's thinking I accomplished all this
stuff and it's not, I don't feel that way.
Like first of all, there's always
somebody that's better than you.
That's D. I guarantee it. There's
someone that's done more than you.
There's someone that's
had better experiences,
someone that's accomplished more and,
and if you are truly the
master of some thing,
whatever one thing
you're a true master of,
there's going to be people that are a
lot better at other things than you.
So you might be the master
of one particular thing,
but are you,
you have to respect the fact that people
are going to be masters at other things
or better than you'd think. I mean, so
if you're super strong, that's great.
Let's see. You run a marathon. If
you're super flexible, awesome.
How much can you dead lift if you're,
if you're smart, that's great.
You're smart academically,
let's check out your common sense and see
where all that at. You know, so, so you,
you,
you are going to be good at one thing,
but you're going to have failed in other
areas or have weaknesses in other areas.
And so
you just have to keep that in check.
And I'll tell you like,
I recognize why I've been successful,
you know, for one thing, been
surrounded with great people,
for others being lucky in
certain situations that
I've been in certain times.
And you know,
going back to Jujitsu a little bit,
it's a good example because just
because I can beat someone in Jujitsu,
it doesn't mean that I'm a
better person. Yeah, it does.
It doesn't mean that I'm a better person.
It what it means basically
is that I happen to get into
this random fringe sport
before they did and I spent more
time on the math and they did.
That's what it means.
It doesn't make me a better person.
And I'll tell you what it goes
with. You know, if you're,
if you feel like you're
smarter than someone,
it's probably because you've had the
opportunity to study a subject or you've
had a bunch of education on something or
you've, you've dove into some subjects.
So that might make you seem smarter.
Whereas if they applied themselves and
that particular because what they were
applying themselves to
something else. So yeah, stay,
you gotta stay humble with that.
And also when we talked about
those are when you fo [inaudible],
I am smarter than this person.
Well guess what? There's something,
there's still something that they're
better than you and what is it?
You might be smarter than him,
but guess what?
Maybe the guy we talked about earlier
where I'm smart as I can be, guess what?
This person can physically take me down
and dominate me and that's horrible.
Or they're better at whatever,
better athletically.
Or some people are really good
craftsman with their hands. I mean,
there's so many different
things you can be skilled at.
And if you start thinking that yourself,
that you're,
that you're better than other people,
you're going to have issues because in
the long run you want to stay humble.
Just stay alive because
life will humbly humble you.
Life is hard.
And if you're pushing hard and you're
driving hard and you're trying to achieve
a lot, you're not always going
to win. I don't care who you are.
You going to get humbled. It's
going to be hard. So many,
so many people that are successful,
they've got some hard luck stories along
the way of things that they had to push
through and overcome in order
to get there. They got humbled.
And if you're winning every single time,
then you're, you're not, your
goals aren't high enough.
So step those up. So, you
know, I appreciate the,
the kind of comment, but um, man,
it's not hard to be humble when you know,
you can,
you just take like maybe someone I
didn't, you know, people always think, oh,
oh, he's a navy seal or
whatever. Um, you know,
there's a lot of seals that are more
badass than me that done more deployments
that have gotten after it
more than me. And I know that,
that, that, that's awesome.
I mean, good, good for them. I, you know,
they got after it good. Um,
so I don't feel like, oh,
I did more than everybody.
No, there's no one like that.
There was no one like that.
Even even, uh, you know,
Mikey Thorton who will seal that won
a medal of honor, awesome guy of, uh,
you know, just to, just to, you know,
he's a, he's a hero, but if, you know,
when he gets interviewed,
I've watched a bunch of interviewed here,
heard him talk, he's like, you know,
he's like, oh, you know, you, you,
you got the medal of honors x,
not mine. It's my guys. You know,
it's the guys I was with. It
represents all. So there's a guy like,
who's going to be,
if there's anyone in the world needs to,
that could not be humble.
Maybe it's Mikey Thorton,
but guess what Mikey Thornton,
he's as humble as they
come, because you know what?
He also has been humbled by combat
cause he realized there's things that he
tried to do that he didn't get done.
There's blinds,
he tried to save that he couldn't save.
So you're Gunna,
there's no doubt if you're
living the right life,
you're going to be humbled by
it. And there's always, always,
always going to be somebody that's better
than you that's done. But then you,
so just stay humble. And by the way,
what does being cocky gets you anyways?
What does that turn you into? What
I talked about last time, what is,
what is overconfidence gets you, you
start cutting corners, you start to slack.
I mean it's just ridiculous. So you got
to stay humble. You've got to stay hungry.
If you, if you want to stay
in the game and believe me,
you want to stay in the game on
if you want to stay in the game.
Did he think that
like, and I can't, I mean,
I don't know if maybe this is where
this even the question is coming from,
but if,
you know,
when you're insecure and at
you like you're just like
everything's a competition.
Like, just in life, it's, it's like,
it goes beyond just what you're into.
It's just like, if someone's better
than me feel, it makes me mad.
It makes you uneasy or whatever.
It's like this insecurity kind of thing.
So when you do,
it's like if you look at everything
is just this big life compare.
Like I got to beat that guy
gotta be better than them.
So when you are better than them,
it's like you're still looking at it as
this competition. Like, Eh, you know,
like you're not on my level,
so you don't deserve to be treated.
It's kind of like maybe this good analogy,
maybe not,
but like in Jujitsu where if you roll
with a white belt, you don't go hard,
you don't get satisfaction or whatever.
So in the Jujitsu competition arena,
you're not giving them the respect.
You're not going all out like you would,
you know, you're not respecting
his arm bar. You know, if you are,
you're smashing him. No
satisfaction, you know, whatever.
It's in that specific competition setting.
But if you're just an insecure person
where you think that all life is like just
one big competition,
you've got to smash that person.
And if you're not worthy of my smashing,
it's like I don't even treat you like you
should be on the mats with the kind of
saying cool, but may, I mean,
do you think that maybe that's
where some of that comes from?
Like if you're having trouble,
like being humble,
it's kind of like I'm
better than you in life
driven from intercity insecurity,
but there's also a way, uh,
there's a dichotomy there too
because man, I like to win. Like,
like no doubt about it.
I like to win in the dichotomy of it is,
is that I also don't literally don't care.
Like if I get beat,
I'm like, okay, well what can
I do to get better? It's not,
I don't feel this despair because I lost.
Losing actually kind of motivates me more.
Yeah.
As opposed to getting angry.
And the worst thing that happens is people
decide they're not going to compete.
Right.
They're not going to compete in the game
of life because they didn't win or they
don't feel like they can win. So they
go, ah, you know what? I'm just gonna,
I'm just going to back off. I'm just
not going to participate in the game.
But getting the game
get in the game theme.
So maybe it comes from
not understanding what that
means when you win and stuff.
I guess.
I guess like let's say like the fight
back to the fighting situation where the
about, you know, being a secure part
of the males, balancing real psyche.
If you know that you've achieved these
skills, have these skills to when people,
you know who, who don't have your
skillset, you don't want to fight them.
So you're just like, whatever.
But let's say like you,
you have a better skillset yet you're
still blowing your horn about your
skillset. You know, you're not
humble about it. It's, it's
like he comes from maybe,
I don't know, something.
There's no doubt there can be
some insecurity that charges,
that makes people super
competitive beyond healthy,
competitive, just like in life, like
just in life, you know? No matter what,
which again, there's people that
are that way, myself included. And,
but again, the dichotomy is I don't think
you're like, no, no, I, I, I know I am.
Well, how can I in the know I am remember
echelon front, remember the logo? Yeah.
Right.
And I'm going to post this on Twitter
to Jocko made the original echelon front
logo Liz like long time ago. And you're
like, hey, you know, this is the logo,
something like this.
And then basically you,
but you didn't care that
it was junk. No, no. But I,
all I want to do is get you the idea.
You weren't competing with me,
but you drew and I drew.
But like,
like as someone who's competing
in everything in life,
like if you draw something and I
draw something and you're like,
I want to make mine better.
No, no, no, no. But well, uh,
see I wanted to win with the idea, not
with the skill, the idea of the war.
I wanted to win the war,
not the short term battle.
It's like who can draw this thing better?
That the war was who comes
up with a strategic victory,
which the icon and the symbol for
echelon front is the one that I drew.
I liked it.
So yes,
I didn't care that it looked
like junk cause I'm not,
I was did it what you should
post docs is pretty fun.
I did it on PowerPoint with like a, like
a Cran, it looks like a crayon cause I,
I didn't want to take as
much time with it. I know,
I knew that that thing would take you
15 minutes to make on your, what is it?
Ai Ill illustrator
that might have been
with don't be mad at me.
That's probably the first logo I've
ever actually made. Hmm. Maybe hey,
there you go. Cool.
Thanks for trusting me.
Next question.
What do you do when you have two extreme
ownership believers that have to go
against each other?
Ooh,
sounds like a big challenging question,
but it actually shouldn't be
because if you think about this,
if you truly think about this, this
should not be an issue and here's why.
Go against each other,
against each other.
So what are the goals are,
are these two people on the same team?
I'm assuming that they're on the same
team right there on the same team.
So if they're on the same
team and we want to win,
we have the same goals.
We want to win,
but we won't work together because if
the goal is to win and we both want to
win,
why would we be going against each other?
We are not taping,
taking actual extreme ownership because
if you and I were had opposing ideas,
but we had those same longterm goal,
I'm going to take ownership and say,
all right, echo, we got to come to terms
here. We're going to work this out.
We got to fix it. If you were
doing the same thing, you'd
be like, yeah, absolutely.
Let's sit down.
Let's figure this out.
Let's figure out what's going to
be the best. Let's take two mark.
Let's do a market says we're going to
figure out a real solution because we're
taking ownership of it.
So what's the little nugget that's
getting into the system here in screwing
things up?
It's Edd.
Go 100% and I will say this occasionally,
the idea of extreme ownership can
be very poorly and very incorrectly
interpreted as micromanagement
and Egomania meaning like,
I'm going to own this, I own
this. This is mine, right?
We're not, that's not what
extreme ownership is at all.
It's you. You've got to own
everything, but you don't,
you don't feel the intrinsic
need to do everything right
cause you own.
It's like owning the outcome and the
owning the progress and owning the steps
along the way and owning the
responsibility of mission achievement.
It doesn't mean that you
own each individual step
and you have to make it your
way. That's not extreme
ownership. That's micromanagement.
What you know,
it's so extreme ownership is about
leadership and decentralized command.
Then using indirect tactics to make
things happen in owning the outcome.
So that's,
that's why when you,
if you have two people that
were truly about like, Hey,
I'm gonna own this,
I'm going to do,
I'm going to have the
attitude of extreme ownership.
If you and I have the
attitude of extreme ownership,
we're not going to fight over anything
because we have the same long term goal
and if you come up with a better idea
of how to get there, I'm going to say,
oh, Echo, awesome job. That's a great way.
We're going to get to where we want to go.
We own that outcome.
We're going to make it happen.
Boom, I'm going to support you.
The only time it's going to be a problem
is if I have an ego and then you have
an ego.
When we both have an ego issue and
and usually one person with a big ego,
it that that inflames other
people's he egos because if I say,
hey, echo, I got a great plan for how to
do this. We need to execute it my way.
There's a little bit of ego coming out.
It doesn't matter because now your ego
was down, but I wasn't even really,
what do you mean you're away? Right?
Well, wait a second, just right there.
Now we've got a thing. Now we've got some
cop kind of issue going on. You know,
we're now, we're working against each
other instead of working together.
So that is, uh, that is
absolutely problematic.
And I guess to say,
to put this in a nutshell,
the Wifi, if you're using the
principle of extreme ownership,
the most important thing you to take
extreme ownership of is your own ego and
put that thing in check.
Yeah.
It seems like the extreme ownership
as far as owning it is more,
is essentially take responsibility,
like at all costs kind of thing.
For more like the, the bad stuff
that happened, the bad stuff.
Absolutely the best.
What'd you know?
But you're going to take
week because absolutely.
If you and I do something great together
and I was the leader, I don't go,
yes, that's right. I was the, I'm the,
you know, you say, Hey, first of all,
this was mostly on Echo. He did most
of the work. He did all the, you know,
that's what I'm going to say. I'm
not going to say no, this was mine.
But when something goes wrong,
obviously I don't say no.
It was echo's fault number. I say,
Hey, this was my fault. So, you know,
I should have done double check on the
audio before we started the podcast
because, uh, you know, we wanted to make
sure that thing was recording, right?
I don't say no. Echo dropped the ball.
Yeah, I don't do that on him. I said, hey,
you should have double checked.
So that's if you truly have to people
that have real ownership and they put
their egos in check, this is literally
not an issue. Right? So they, yeah,
this isn't even a question for that,
right?
Cause they don't go against each other.
They're going with each other.
And so what are the chances that you as
a person that's really put your ego in
check and you're exercising
extreme ownership,
what are the chances that you work with
another person that is exactly with the
same mindset taking ownership but no ego.
What,
what are the chances that
they're actually pretty slim?
This is not easy to do this.
It's simple. Not Easy, right?
So that means you have to be even more
proactive in helping adapt to their ego
scenario that's happening. And when Echo
says, hey, we need to do this my way,
I'll be like, hey, you know what? Echo,
let's take a look at it. Absolutely.
You've always come up with great plans.
Let's take a look at
what this one is here.
And all of a sudden I've disarmed you a
little bit. You're feeling good about it.
You're like, oh yeah, that's right. Jack
was going to listen to me cause that's,
that's great.
That's exactly what I want you to think.
It's exactly what I want you to think.
So you're going to have work to do.
You're going to have work to do
that. So that's what, that's what,
that's what it is. It's
a challenge. It's work.
But when you have the basic
principles, the, I shouldn't say basic,
when you have the fundamental principles,
they are going to work well for you.
And when they're not working well for you,
don't get mad at the other
person and blame their ego.
Look at your own ego because you can
adjust and adapt and maneuver and get that
person disarmed and you can flank
them and then you're going to win.
But that's so interesting that
all of this question is like that.
Like it seems like when, like when I
first read it, I was like, oh shoot,
that's a good question. You know, no one
there. And it is, but in a different way,
because this question is essentially
what it does. Is it like,
what do you call it?
Like a strainer or whatever.
Like it shifted it SIF see strains out.
The guy who's not doing extreme ownership,
see how it says if they're
both exercising it,
but if they're going against each other,
that means there's some extreme ownership
not being practiced. Somewhere in here,
we didn't know, but we're going
to, we can find out. You know,
who's going again to kind of thing.
If they're both going against each
other or maybe they both have it.
You know what? There's always gonna
be one person. Well, not always,
but there's usually me
one person that is got it.
Okay. That understands it and that's
going to be working in this guy.
He's just so good and so smooth.
It's so tactical and they're going to win.
And that other person that's like,
that's right. You know why we're winning.
Cause I got extreme
ownership going on and I,
I took ownership of this project and you
want the guy says they're good. Real.
The real leader is like, absolutely
man, you did a great job with that.
And meanwhile he knows he just made his
manipulated and flanked him and made it
happen to the best of the
best for the team. You know,
just keeping the train going.
That's good. Yeah. Interesting.
Okay. I think we got it. Last
question. Yeah. Just maybe one more,
maybe a jacket.
Can you talk about fear of
failure in how to overcome it?
Fear of failure.
So obviously fear of failure can,
can keep you from taking risk.
Yeah,
they can leave you just sitting there
paralyzed into not taking any action at
all.
And obviously that's bad,
but
I don't actually want you to
overcome the fear of failure.
I want,
I want you to be afraid of failure.
Fear of failure is good.
Fear of failure.
We'll keep you up at night.
Planning in rehearsing and
going over contingencies.
Fear of failure will
keep you training hard.
It'll stop you from cutting corners.
Fear,
fear of failure will keep you working
and thinking in striving and relentlessly
trying to be more prepared for battle.
So I want you to be afraid of failing.
I fear failure,
but more important.
I want you to be horrified.
I want you to be terrified of sitting
on your ass and doing nothing.
That is what I want you to be afraid of,
of waking up in six days or six
weeks or six years or 60 years,
okay?
In being no closer to your goal,
you've made no progress.
Yeah,
that is the horror.
That is the nightmare.
That is what you need
to be truly afraid of
being stagnant.
So
get up and go.
Take the risk. Take the
gamble, take the first step,
take action.
Don't let another day slip by.
And I think that's all
I've got for tonight.
And if you got something
out of the podcast tonight,
you want to hear some more,
well then maybe you should go ahead
and support the podcast and echo.
How can the troopers out there
best support the podcast? Well,
one of the or the initial way is to
support yourself at the same time and that
is to supplement
on it on it has the best
supplements. Uh, you know,
it's one thing to say they have the
best supplements because I like them,
but they have for real, have the
best supplement. Like the legit,
you read all this stuff about it,
it's straight up the best anyway.
You want 10% off there.
So support your wallet as well.
So you're supporting podcasts
yourself and your wallet.
10% off on it.com/josh. Yep. Solid.
Um, also if you want to passively support,
uh, you can do the Amazon click through.
That's you got to one of the websites doc,
podcast.com or chocolate or the chocolate
store is the Amazon link on the top.
Now we have international cause there,
um,
every once in a while like
who are overseas or you
know, international. But Hey,
what about this? Cause it's a, it's a long
story, but we have everywhere overseas,
it's Canada.
Basically I started the ones that
people have actually told me,
you know, like, Hey, we're here
in the UK, we want to, you know,
be done with the thing or
whatever. And yeah, so,
so I did those and so those are
up on both websites as well.
Thanks for hitting me up with that by
the way. Um, overseas support? Yes.
Yes, fully. So dope. And
also speaking of Amazon, the,
the new trooper tool, that's
pretty, it's a cool little tool.
Thanks again Brady for that one.
It genius and Jujitsu student by the way.
Nonetheless, like this tool,
you just click it. You got it.
There's a link to it on things called
the called the true chuck podcast trooper
tool. Chrome extension. That's what it's
called. Awesome. You Click on the thing,
you just like you clean thing
if you want and you click
on the thing,
it shows up as a little icon.
Jack was head and you can even hide that
if you don't want it on your browser or
whatever. You just hide it if you
don't want it there. But it looks,
I think it's kind of cool. It's
up there or whatever. Anyway,
it helps you go to aid,
makes you good at Amazon.
It helps it go through the affiliate
link so you don't have to go through the
website anymore. Does it automatically
for you? Don't think it. Say it.
Say some time. Uh, also, you know,
of course subscribed to
the iTunes and youtube.
I think we're going to pump
some more value in youtube,
but some outtakes on there. I think I like
that. I like where you're coming from.
Yeah. I subscribe to the Youtube, the
youtube channel. That would be cool.
So we know that you're out there and
you're going to receive these things that
echo was putting together.
Yeah. And then also the uh,
the Jocko podcast store.
Yeah. If you like shirts,
if you were sure it wasn't Jocko store
chocolate store.com Jocko store.com. Yup.
Some cool t shirts.
I still,
I their eyes delivered yet
to see one in the wild.
Not someone I know.
So I'm looking forward to seeing
that somewhere in the world,
somewhere on planet earth.
I am thoroughly enjoying the pictures
that people sent their awesome,
you know what's funny? The,
the, the Heather Gray, right?
Gray like that's the kind of shirt like
you know, a lot of lighter colored shirt,
they get real, um, like
dark. If you sweat in them.
There'll be like pictures where, I don't
even know why I think this is funny,
but it's interesting because the other
one is charcoal gray. That's a dark gray.
So they'll be like, yeah,
I got my disability to, and
they see the bottom line.
It looks like a stripe. I'm like, wait,
what? That's weird how the lighting is.
So there's a stripe on
the bottom of your shirt,
but it's not the charcoal gray
one. It's the, you know, they,
they were getting after it of getting
after it is very much so. Anyway.
I know why I thought that was funny,
but it's, it looks funny. Not Funny,
like I'm laughing at them,
but it's interesting how it looks
like a shirt then it's like an optical
illusion. Anyway. Chocolate store.com.
There's some other shirts on there if
you like them. Coffee mugs and stickers.
Awesome bumper stick.
Also,
if you like the podcast and you
want more of this information,
there's a book that I wrote
with my brother Leif Babin.
It's called extreme ownership.
You can order it through Amazon or
you can get anywhere books are sold.
It's available in hard cover,
digital and audio format and the audio
format and Lafe and I actually read so
get some of that.
If you want to talk to echo and I,
you can find us on the
interwebs at Twitter.
Echo is an echo.
Charles and I am at jockowillink.
We're also on the Facebooky
and some of that Instagram,
I got a snapchat thing,
I signed up for it or whatever,
but I haven't done anything with it
yet. Yeah, so I got to explore that.
But man,
the social media stuff takes time and,
and I can't, if you want me find
me on Twitter, that's the best way.
Ask Your questions on Twitter.
Hit me up on Twitter.
That's the most common thing that I use.
I do.
I do check Facebook. I mean I read
everything that has ever been sent to me.
I've read,
I might not have responded to it because
I can't literally can't respond to
every single thing that gets sent to me.
Uh,
which is what's nice about on Twitter. I
can just hit that. I like it, you know,
so that people know like, oh he
read it cool on Facebook. I read it,
but there's nothing to press to
say I read your thing. So, um,
maybe I should figure something
out like that. But anyways, it,
you're solid on Twitter,
you get back to people and stuff,
which is cool cause there's some
people you can tell it's not them,
it's like their,
their social media.
Me and I was just out where I just was,
there was very limited internet,
so I was able to get like
a tweet out in the morning,
a couple of weeks out in the morning. But
when I'd go to start responding, it was,
you know, three minutes to, to
look at the tweet from somebody.
So I'm backed up right
now for like five days,
four days behind or something like
that. Five days behind actually. Yeah.
Let's see. You mean? You're saying
that like that you're like backed up.
It means like your,
you know your engagement and that's good,
but even then I was reading and I do,
man, if you send me something on Twitter,
I'm going to see it. You want to read
it. I might not respond to it directly,
but I might have had a day
actually more than once too,
but I'm remembering a very specific
time a day where I wasn't going to go to
Jujitsu. I wasn't going to go. It was,
you know, today's the breath, dare what?
I Dunno, whatever. I wasn't going to
go. We call it, we call that weakness.
Maybe call it what you want.
Nonetheless,
when you see pictures of,
I saw,
I don't know that the name
of the specific person,
but I saw a picture first
day of Jujitsu and I'm like,
you know how you get that feeling when
like let's say you weren't at Jujitsu and
I took a picture of me on the Mat
saying I'm here without Jocko.
I'll do that every once in a while to
like my friends or I'm here without
Jacquelyn's. You kind of like,
you have this feeling like, Dang,
I wish I was there right now just to
whatever. I kinda got that feeling,
that weird competitiveness you
were talking about earlier.
I want to be there with you maybe,
maybe a little bit, oh by the way,
I don't know if you knew this,
you know like guys will be like,
Hey I want to come visit you at,
at the gym or went on. Right.
And to me it's a guy showed up when I was
out of town. Yeah. And that's, you know,
I I I say the days like I go on this
these days typically and whatever.
So it just hit me up, whether it be on
Twitter or whatever, if you're in town.
And he did. And cause he, the
reason that's significant,
one of the main reasons what I said
too, was he from Arizona? So Arizona,
his name is ab Ab. The man
showed up rolled money. Yeah.
So cause a lot of people in life,
I'm not saying just on Twitter,
I'm just seeing in life they always
will be like, Hey, oh you do? Yeah.
I'm going to combine,
you can show me or all roll or whatever.
And I would say a good 95 to
99% of the time they don't,
they don't come.
Yeah.
Well a lot of times they're hitting you
up from love plays her farther than the
way than, than Arizona. I'm even talking
about like before the podcast and stuff,
I'm saying like your friends, you know.
Oh, just, Oh, whatever, you know. Yeah.
I'm going to come check it
out. Sounds cool. You know,
and they never had this dude
rolled before. Ab Ab ab. Um,
was he uh, he's a uh, yeah,
he was like a three straight white
belt or something like that. Yeah.
Nice guy. You know, he's cool. What's
up baby man? Thanks for coming. Um,
yeah.
And,
and obviously just want to
give a shout out.
We talked about some soldiers today,
but I want to give a thanks.
All the police out there.
I hear a lot from police officers all
over the country and thanks to you guys
for doing your duty to keep us safe.
Same thing for the firefighters.
I've actually hearing a lot from five.
There's all kinds of firefighters and all
you guys are protecting us on the home
front,
obviously much appreciated and then
course the military folks out there,
especially those that are deployed
right now, taking the fight, hey
to the enemy,
be aggressive and crush him and
we'll see you when you get home.
And finally to all the 12 the
Jocko podcast troopers out there.
Thank you for the support across the
board with all of us. We appreciate it.
And what we really appreciate more than
anything is you out there in your life
taking ownership of your
world and getting after it.
So until next time,
this is echo and Jocko
out.