This is Jocko podcast number
103 with Echo Charles and me,
Jocko Willink. Good
Evening Echo. Good evening
whilst lying at Winchester young
as I was in the profession,
I was picked out amongst others to perform
a piece of duty that for many years
afterwards remain deeply impressed upon
my mind and gave me the first impression
of the stern duties of a soldier's life.
Okay.
A private of the 70th regiment had
deserted from that core and afterwards
enlisted into several other regiments.
Indeed,
I was told at the time that 16 different
times he had received the bounty and
then stolen off being
however caught at last,
he was brought to trial at Smith and
sentenced by General Court Martial to be
shot.
Okay.
As the execution would be a
good hint to us, a young ins.
There were four lads picked out of our
core to assist in this piece of duty.
Myself being one of the number chosen
besides these men for soldiers from
three other regiments were ordered on the
firing party making 16 at all.
The place of execution was ports down
hill and the different regiments assembled
must have composed a force of about
15,000 men having been assembled from the
isle of Wight, from
Chester, Chester, golf,
sport and other places.
Okay.
The site was very imposing and appeared
to make a deep impression on all their,
as for myself,
I felt that I would have
given a good round some had.
I possessed it to have been in any other
situation rather than one rather than
the one which I now found myself.
And when I looked into the
faces of my companions,
I saw by the pallor and anxiety,
anxiety depicted in each countenance,
the reflection of my own feelings.
Okay.
When all was ready, we were moved to the
front and the culprit was brought out.
Yeah.
He made a short speech to the parade
acknowledging the justice of his sentence
and that drinking and evil company
had brought the punishment upon him.
He behaved himself firmly and well
and did not seem to flinch at all.
After being blindfolded.
He does.
He was desired to kneel down behind a
coffin, which was placed on the ground.
And the drum major of the depot
giving us an expressive glance.
We immediately commenced to loading.
This was done in the deepest silence
and the next moment we were primed and
ready.
There was then a dreadful pause for a
few moments and the drum major again
looking towards us,
gave us the signal,
agreed upon before a flourish
of his cane and we leveled
and fired.
We had been previously strictly enjoined
to be steady and take good aim and the
poor fellow pierced by several
balls fell heavily upon his back
as he lay with his arms
pinion to his sides.
I observed that his hands waived for
a few moments like the fins on a fish.
When in the agonies of death,
the drum major also observed the
movement and making another signal.
Four of our Party immediately stepped
up to the posture a body and placing the
muscles of their pieces to the head
fired and put him out of his misery.
Okay.
The different regiments then fell back
by companies and the word being given to
march past in slow time when each
company came in line with the body,
the word was given to mark time and then
eyes left in order that we all might
observe.
The terrible example.
We then moved on words and marched from
the ground to our different quarters,
and that
is from a book called
recollections of Riflemen Harris,
who was an enlisted soldier for the
British army during the Napoleonic wars,
and that was his welcome to the army.
He'd been in for about three
weeks of service when he had to
okay,
stand and execute a fellow soldier
four
basically being drunk and disorderly,
not doing what he was supposed
to do. Brett, essentially,
he was being executed
for being a human being.
And that was the introduction to military
service for riflemen Harris Riflemen
Harris,
his full name was Benjamin Randall Harris.
He enlisted in 1803 he fought all
over Europe in the peninsular war,
which posed bourbon, Spain,
the Kingdom of Portugal,
and the British empire against Napoleon's
French empire and boat apart just
Spain.
And also the Duchy of Warsaw,
and this is a war
where they have daggers and swords and
Bay and nets and mounted cavalry charges.
They have cannons and they used
a lot of muzzle loading rifles,
which a skilled rifleman could load
and fire about three times per minute.
Hmm.
Accurate out to about 200 yards.
Very different from the
weapons that we have now,
which can fire three rounds in a second
and are very accurate out to 800 yards,
a thousand yards and some sniper
weapons way further than that,
but even though these
weapons are different from
the weapons we see in modern
warfare.
Okay.
As always,
in the end it is men.
Yeah.
It is. Human beings on the
battlefield, bleeding, sweating,
starving, suffering, killing
and being killed.
Let's find out a little
bit more about rifleman.
Harris.
Going back to the book,
my father was a shepherd and I was a
sheep boy from my earliest youth. Indeed.
As soon as almost I could run,
I began helping my father to look after
the sheep on the downs of Branford
endorsed it. Sure. Where I was born.
Whilst I continued to tend the flocks and
herds under my charge and occasionally
in the long winter nights I
learned the art of making shoes.
I grew a hardy little chap and was one
fine day in the year of 1802 drawn as a
soldier for the army of reserve.
Thus,
without troubling myself much about the
change which was about to take place in
the quiet of my routine days,
I was drafted into the 66 the regiment
of foot bid good bye to my shepherd
companions and was obliged to leave my
father without an assistant to collect
his flocks just as he was beginning
more than ever to require one nay.
Indeed,
I may say,
to want tending and looking after
himself for old age and infirmary.
We're coming on him.
His hair was growing white as the
sleep of our downs and his countenance
becoming as furrowed as the
plowed fields around. However,
has I had no choice in the matter.
It was quite as well that I
did not grieve over my fate.
My father tried hard to buy me off and
would have persuaded the sergeant of the
66 that I was of no use as a soldier
from having maimed my right hand by
breaking the fourth
finger when I was a child.
The sergeant however said I was just the
sort of little chat he wanted and off
he went carrying me amongst
a batch of recruits.
He'd collected a way with him.
Yeah.
Sheepherder Dad's getting
old army comes and gets you.
That's the way it works.
England 1802
now he travels around a little bit and
eventually ends up in Dublin and here we
go back to the bulk Walston Dublin I
one day saw core of the 95th rifles and
fell so in love with their smart dashing
and devil may care appearance that
nothing would serve me until I
was a rifleman myself. So on.
Arriving at Castle one day and falling
in with the recruiting party of that
regimen, I volunteered into the second
battalion, this recruiting party,
we're all Irishman and I had and had
been sent over from England to collect
amongst others,
men from the Irish militia and we're
just about to return to England.
I think they were as
reckless and devil may care.
A set of men I had ever been
beheld either before or since.
So these,
these riflemen I would say
from what I read about them,
they're,
they're almost like a special ops unit.
And one big difference is they're wearing,
instead of wearing red jackets like the,
the Brits would wear it
this time they wore green.
So they were a little bit different and
they had more accurate rifles and they
would fight, they would do what
they called skirmishing, which is,
is fundamentally cover move. They'd shoot
and they'd maneuver and they'd, they'd,
they'd act like little special
operations troops out there.
And of course it's interesting to me and
when I hear this guy talking about the
first time he saw someone that looked
a little bit like a special operations
troops, he said it. He actually
says, I fell in love with it.
You know, that's, that's very much how I
felt as I was growing up. The more I saw,
you know, the special ops,
he's, he actually didn't
even need to be special ops.
For me.
It was just someone in the military,
but then he was already in the military.
So now he's looking for the next thing.
What's the next thing going to be?
And here he ends up as,
as a rifleman.
So he's now a right from an,
he joins, he moves over to their
regimen and here we go back to the book.
The next day we marched for Ashford and
Kent where I joined the 95th rifles and
about six months after my joining for
companies of the second battalion were
ordered on the expedition to Denmark.
We embarked it deal and sailing for
hostile shores landed on a little place
called I think scarlet island.
The expedition consisted of about 30,000
men and at the moment of our getting on
shore,
the whole force set up one
simultaneous and tremendous cheer.
A sound I cannot describe.
It seemed so inspiring.
This indeed was the
first time of my hearing,
the style in which our men give
tongue when they get near the enemy.
Though afterwards, my years became
pretty well accustomed to such sounds.
As soon as we got on shore, the
rifles were pushed, pushed forward,
and he says the rifles,
he's talking about his guys,
the rifles were pushed forward as the
advance in chain order through some thick
woods of for and when we had cleared
these woods and approached Copenhagen,
centuries were posted on the roads and
openings leading toward the town in order
to intercept all comers
and prevent all supplies.
Such posts were occupied for about three
days and nights whilst the town was
being fired upon by our shipping.
I rather think this was the first time
of the con grieve rockets being brought
into play and they rushed through
the air and the dark. They appeared.
So like so many fiery serpents creating,
I should think,
terrible dismay among the besieged,
the con grieve rockets.
They basically look like
giant bottle rockets in a way.
[inaudible] they got at this time they
were getting their range out to 1500 2000
meters.
So it was a pretty crazy weapon and,
and I can tell you rockets in this day
and age have become fairly accurate,
but in those days they'd probably about
as accurate as a bottle rocket is.
My guests back to the book,
as the main army came up,
we advanced and got as near under the
walls of the place as we could without
being endangered by the
fire from our own shipping.
So what's happening right
there was covered move.
The shipping is bombarding and these
guys are advancing as close as they can
where they are not going
to get killed by their own,
by their own fire from the ships.
We now received orders
ourselves to commence firing
and the rattling of the guns,
I shall not easily forget.
I felt so much exhilarated that I could
hardly keep back and was checked by the
commander of the company who called me
by my name to keep my place about this
time,
my front rank man,
a tall fellow named Jack Johnson,
showed a disposition as though
the firing had an effect on him.
The reverse of what it had had on many
others of the company for he seemed
inclined to hang back and once
or twice turned round in my face,
I was a rear rank man and porting my
piece and the excitement of the moment I
score that if he did not keep his ground,
I would shoot him dead on the spot
so that he found it,
he would go on so that he found it would
be quite as dangerous for him to return
as to go on.
I feel sorry to record the
want of courage of this man,
but I do so with the less pain it gives
me the opportunity of saying that during
my many years of arduous service is the
only instance I remember of a British
soldier endeavoring to hold back when
his comrades were moving forward.
Indeed Johnson was never held again.
An estimation among the rifle core for
the story got wind that I had threatened
to shoot him for cowardice in the field
and Lieutenant Cox mentioned to the
kernel that he'd overheard my doing so
and such was the contempt the man was
held in by the rifles that he
was soon afterwards removed.
There you go. The first
time under fire, it's,
it's interesting how rifleman
Harris first time under fire,
he wants to get after it.
He is ready to charge and only one guy
out of their whole crew is looking like
he's going to hold back and they
talk about reputation here and that's
definitely something that is when you get
to the seal teams, as you're a new guy,
someone tells you, they'll say,
hey, your reputation is everything.
And it's totally true. And it's the
same in any military organization,
what your reputation is because,
because in the military,
you think ranks all
important, right? Yeah. But,
but the reality is there's something
that completely Trump's rank and that's
reputation. And if you're, I mean,
I always talk about the
fact that relationships are
more important than chain of
command,
but you're not going to have
a good relationship with
people if you don't have a
good reputation. It's not
happening. Yeah. So it makes sense.
The same thing back in 1803,
yeah.
Back to the book. Whilst in Denmark
we led a tolerably active life.
The rifles being continually on the alert
ordered hither today and countermanded
the next occasionally.
Also we had some pleasant adventures
among the Blue Wide Danish lasses for the
rifles were always terrible
fellows in that way.
Okay.
That doesn't need too much explanation.
They,
I'll say this as I always say,
I have to fast forward through this book.
I'm not reading the entire book,
even though the entire book is awesome
in this point. This point here,
they're embarking for pers,
uh, Portugal. We have another,
another campaign to go
on back to the book.
I wish I could picture the splendid
site of the shipping and the downs.
At the time we embarked with about 20,000
men. Those were times which are sold,
which the soldiers of our own more
peaceable days have little conception of.
So this book was written
before World War One and,
and really this was the,
the last big war is the boards that
he went through the Napoleonic wars.
So he's kind of,
he's kind of saying,
you don't even know what this is like
anymore. You don't know what it is.
Like you don't know what the, the, the,
the soldiers of our own more peaceable
days have little conception of what it's
like to embark 20,000 troops
to get ready and go get some,
hmm.
Back to the book.
We sailed majestically out of the
cove of Cork for hostile sure.
Where we were safely arrived and
disembarked at Monday go bay.
The rifles were first out of the vessels
for we were indeed always in front of
the advance and always in the rear in
retreat like the Kentish men of old,
we claimed the post of honor in the field.
I tried to figure out what that Kentish
man can't is obviously a place and and
the as far the best I could figure out
was that the people in Kent stood up
hardcore against the Norman invasion.
I think that's what that reference is too.
I'm sure somebody will correct
me and I hope somebody does.
Back to the bulk of being immediately
pushed forward up the country and advanced
the main body.
Many of us in this hot climate very
soon began to find out the misery of the
frightful load.
We were condemned to march and fight
under with a burning sun above our heads
and our feet sinking every
step into the hot sand.
The weight of the weight I myself toiled
under was tremendous and I often wonder
at the strength I possessed at this
period that which enabled me to endure it
for indeed.
I'm convinced that many of our infantry
sank and died under the weight of their
knapsacks alone.
For my own part being a
handicraft handicraft,
I marched under the weight sufficient
to impede the free motions of a donkey
for besides my well filled kit, there
was the great coat rolled on its top,
my blanket and camp cattle,
my haversack stuffed full of leather for
repairing the men's shoes together with
a hammer and other tools,
ship biscuit and beef for three days.
I also carried my canteen
filled with water,
my hatchet and rifle and 80 rounds
of ball cartridge in my pouch.
This last,
except the beef and biscuit being the
best thing I owned and which I always gave
the enemy the benefit of
when the opportunity offered.
It's interesting,
he knew how to work on shoes and so he
carries stuff to repair shoes in the
field. Mm Eight think about that.
That's just a lost art, isn't it?
But think about where you are in the field
when you have to March 15 miles a day
and you have no shoes. If there's
someone that can fix your shoes, that's,
that's a godsend. Yeah. Back
to the book the next day.
We again advanced and being in a state
of the utmost anxiety to come up along
the French, neither the heat of the
burning sun, long miles or heavy,
we're able to diminish our Arbor.
Indeed.
I often look back with wonder
at the light hearted style,
the agility and the reckless indifference
with which men who were so destined in
short time to fall,
hurry,
dawn words toward the field of strife
seemingly without a thought of anything
but the sheer love of meeting the
Foa and the excitement of battle.
He wrote this book
20 something years after this happened.
After this experience.
I want to say he wrote it
in 1930 something 1938 maybe
is when it came out and
you can see that the so,
so my point in saying that is that
looking back he knows because he's, he's,
he's going,
he's going to go through hell.
He's going to go through hardcore combat.
But even even knowing
how horrible combat is,
he still looks back in,
is,
is amazed at how they were ready to go.
Going back to the book. The 29th regiment
received so terrible a fire that I saw,
the right wing almost
annihilated and the colonel,
I think his name was Lennox
lay sprawling amongst the rest.
We had caught ourselves in it pretty
handsomely for there was no cover for us
and we were rather to near
the living skirmishers.
We're laying beside
heaps of their own dead,
but still we had her own till
the battalion regiments come up.
Fire and retire is a very good sound,
but the rifles were not
over fond of such notes.
We never performed that maneuver except
when it was made pretty plain to us that
it was quite necessary.
The 29th however,
had got their fairing hair at this time
and the shock of that fire seemed to
stagger the whole line
and make them recoil.
At the moment a little
confusion appeared in the ranks.
I thought Lord Hill was near at hand
and saw it and I observed him come
galloping up.
He put himself at the head of the
regimen and restored them to order.
In a moment. There's some leadership
just full on leadership and action.
So there's also fire and retire.
What that means is covered move.
So you have some people shooting
and some people falling back.
That's how they retreat and there they
use that whenever they have to retreat,
you'll hear that and in, I dunno if
I did this, made this clear enough,
but it's a bugle.
It's a bugle signal.
So the bugle would play some certain
number of notes or some pattern of notes
and p and everyone would know,
okay, that means firing, retire.
So now we're now we get that broad,
that broad.
Yeah,
the broad plan out to everyone at once,
which is instead of advancing,
which is what we were doing,
now we're going to,
we're going to retreat and as soon
as you get everyone that information,
now little elements can start to
make it happen. That's decentralized,
but you have to give good communications
in order for that to work.
And what you need to communicate is the
broad plan and that's what they get done
with a nice little bugle signal
back to the book pouring or regular
and sharp fire upon the enemy.
He galled them in return and remaining
with the 29th until he brought them to
the charge.
Quickly sent the foe in the right about,
it seemed to me that few men could
have conducted the business with more
coolness and quietude of manner under
such as storm of balls as he was exposed
to. Indeed. I have never
forgotten him from that day.
So yeah, it's important to
also recognize that you have a,
you have a group of men that are about
to fall apart and there's confusion.
And one guy,
I talk about this all the time,
one guy steps up,
takes ownership of the situation leads,
and it changes the entire outcome of
the battle. Think about that one person.
You got thousand men versus a thousand
men. One person makes the difference.
So if you're in a leadership position,
think about that.
Thinking about what you're doing,
are you leading? Are you stepping up?
Are you galloping up on a
horse and setting things right?
Do you need to be doing
back to the book?
At the time I was remarking these matters,
loading and firing as I
lay another circumstance,
divided my attention for a while and made
me forget even the gallant conduct of
General Hill,
a man near me uttered a scream of agony
and looking from the 29th who were on my
right to the left once
the screen should come,
I saw one of our sergeants named Frazier
sitting in a doubled up position and
swing backwards and forwards as though
he had got a terrible pain in his bowels.
He continued to make such complaint
that I arose and went to him for.
He was rather a crony of mine.
Oh Harris said he,
as I took him in my arms,
I shall die. I shall die.
The agony is so great
that I cannot bear it,
okay.
It was indeed dreadful to look upon him.
The froth came from his mouth and the
perspiration poured from his face.
Thank heaven.
He was soon out of pain
can laying him down.
I returned to my place.
Poor fellow.
He suffered more for a short time
that he was dying than any man.
I think I ever saw him in
the same circumstances.
I had the courtesy to return and
look at him after the battle.
The Musket ball I found had taken him
sideways and gone through both groins.
Okay.
Within about a half an hour after this,
I left sergeant Frazier and indeed for
the time how'd as completely forgotten
him as if he had died
a hundred years back.
The site of so much bloodshed around
will not suffer the mind to dwell long in
any particular casualty.
Even though it happened
to one's dearest friends.
There was no time either to
think for all was action with us.
Rifles just at this moment and the barrel
of my peace was so hot from continual
firing that I could hardly bear to touch
it and was obliged to grasp the stock
beneath the iron as I
continued to blaze away.
Okay.
Doesn't even have time to think about it.
Yeah.
James Ponton was another crony of mine,
a gallon fellow.
He had pushed himself in front of me
and was checked by one of our officers,
rap for his rashness.
Keep back, you Ponton.
The lieutenant said to him more than once,
but Pontin was to be restrained by Ponton
was not to be restrained by anything,
but a bullet went in action this time.
He got one which striking
him in the thigh, I suppose,
hit an artery for,
he died quickly.
The French man's balls were flying very
wickedly at that moment and I crept up
to Ponton and took shelter by lying
behind and making a rest from my rifle of
his dead body.
Okay.
It strikes me that I revenged his
death by the assistance of his carcass.
Okay.
At any rate,
I tried my best to hit his enemies hard.
There were two small buildings to our
front and the French having managed to get
into them,
annoyed as much from that quarter.
A small rise in the ground closed before
these houses also favored them and our
men were being handled very severely.
In consequence,
they became angry and
wouldn't stand it any longer.
One of the skirmishers jumping off,
rushed forward crying over boys over,
over.
When he instantly,
when instantly the whole line
responded to the cry over, over,
over.
They ran along the grass like wildfire,
then dash at the rise fixing their sword
bayonets as they ran the French light.
Bob's could not stand the sight but turned
about and fled and getting possession
of their ground.
We were soon inside the buildings.
After the battle was over,
I stepped across the other house.
I have mentioned in order to see what
was going on there for the one I remained
in was now pretty well filled with
the wounded, both French and English,
who had managed to get
there for a little shelter.
Two or three surgeons also had arrived
at this house and we're busily engaged in
giving their assistance to the wounded.
Now also here,
lying is thickly as in the building,
which I had left,
but what struck me the most,
but what struck me the most forcibly was
that from the circumstance of some wine
bots having been left in the apartment
and having their engagement been
perforated,
having in the engagement been perforated
by bullets and otherwise broken,
the red wine had escaped most plentiful
and ran down upon the earth and floor
where the wounded were lying so that
many of them were soaked in the wine with
which their blood was mingled.
Okay.
Aye. Aye. Aye.
I hate to even think about the medical
care that these guys are getting.
Yeah.
In any the Ma,
the medical care that that we
had in Iraq was unbelievable.
Not only from the speed that
you would get assistance,
but also the quality of care that you
would get on in the field from our own
medics and how quickly they would get
you to get to you and then get you taken
care of, I think get you evacuated
to a full medical facility. Yeah.
Yeah.
And that, that actually changed during
my time in the teams. For instance,
the biggest, the biggest change it
when, when I first gotten the teams,
it, the, what we were taught
was if someone gets shot,
you immediately give them an ivy,
meaning you know,
a bag of fluid because they're bleeding.
You got to replace that.
And now the,
they don't do that automatically because
your body has its own mechanisms.
When it loses blood to stop the bleeding,
it pulls back in the,
the arteries and veins and it constricts
them and clots the blood that's there.
And so, and when you give someone an ivy,
the body thinks I don't need to do that.
So it opens up the arteries, it opens up
the veins, it doesn't constrict anything.
It doesn't get clots slower.
So there's like one example
and that that's during my time.
So that's the last 25 years
that that change has taken
place. So now you go back,
you know, 102 hundred years,
it's totally different.
Totally different. And they'll talk
more about that. And the, the basic,
the basic plan was if you get shot in
the limb, you're losing the limb. Yeah.
That. That's basically what's
going on. Just amputations
Kinda and nowadays they do
an incredible job of saving,
saving limbs if they can be saved,
they saved them.
I mean they do an incredible job.
All right,
back to the book,
it was on the 15th of August when we
first came up with the French and their
skirmishers immediately
commenced operations by
raiding a shower of balls upon
us as we advanced, which we
returned without delay, and
I haven't said this yet,
but the reason they're saying balls
instead of round is because these guys are
shooting the balls,
the round balls of led and at this point
there was some rifling had started to
come about, but what they basically
just consider everything to be a ball,
a lead and that's why
they're not accurate.
That's why they're only accurate out to
200 meters because they're not rifled
like we have the tight rifling
spinning bullets today.
Back to the book, the first man
that was hit was Lieutenant Bunbury.
He fell pierce through the head with a
musket ball and died almost immediately.
Okay.
I fought.
I never heard such a tremendous noise
as the firing made on this occasion and
the men on both sides of me.
I could occasionally observe.
We're falling fast.
I do not pretend to give a description
of this or any other battle I have been
present at.
All I can do is tell the things which
happened immediately around me and that I
think is as much as a private
soldier can be expected to do.
Okay.
Soon afterwards,
the firing commenced and we had taken,
we had advanced pretty close upon the
enemy taking advantage of whatever cover I
could find.
I threw myself behind a small bank
where I lay so secure that although the
Frenchmans bullets fell
pretty thickly around,
I was enabled to knock several
over without being dislodged.
In fact,
I fired away every round I had in my pouch
waltzed laying in this spot at length
after a sharp contest.
We forced them to give
ground and following them up,
drove them from their position in the
heights and hung up their skirts until
they made another stand and
then the game began again.
Okay.
The rifles indeed fought well
this day and we lost many men.
They seemed in high spirits and delighted
at having driven the enemy before them.
Joseph coach and was by my side loading
and firing very industriously about this
period of the day.
First thing with heat and action,
he lifted his canteen to his
mouth. Here's to you, old boy,
he said is he took a pullet its contents.
Okay.
As he did so a bullet went through
the canteen and perforated his brain,
killing him in a moment,
okay.
Another man fell close to him,
almost immediately struck,
struck by a ball in the thigh,
okay.
I saw a man named Simmons struck full in
the face by around shot and he came to
the ground,
a headless trunk.
Okay.
When the role was called after the battle,
the females who missed their husbands
came along the front of the line to
inquire of the survivors,
whether they knew anything about them so
the wives could travel with the soldiers.
And again,
that just seems crazy to me right now.
But that's,
that's the way they did it
and not all of them. But if,
if they made that decision,
I guess as a family to stick together,
they'd get right on board the boats
and they'd, they'd March, they marched,
they cover it in this book, they'll get
there, they wouldn't carry the weight,
but they'd marched alongside and go from
place to place and when the battle is
about to take place, they'd hang
back and then you have the situation.
Once the battles over that I'm talking
about right now amongst other names,
I heard that if coach and called and a
female voice without being replied to the
name struck me and I observed the poor
woman who had called it, as she said,
stopping,
sobbing before us and apparently afraid
to make further inquiries about her
husband.
No Man had answered to his name or had
any given account to give of his fate.
I myself had observed him fall as
related before whilst drinking from his
canteen, but as I looked at the
poor sobbing creature before me,
I felt unable to tell her
of his death at length.
Captain Leach observed her
and called out to the company.
Does any man know what has
happened to coach and if so,
let him speak out at once upon this order,
I immediately related what I had seen
and told the manner of his death after a
while and this coat Mrs.
Coach and appeared anxious
to seek the spot where her
husband fell and in the hope of still
finding him alive asked me to accompany
her over the field.
She trusted not withstanding what I
had told her to find him yet alive.
Okay.
Do you think you could find it said
Captain Leech upon being referred to?
I told them I was sure I could.
As I had remarked,
many objects waltzed looking for cover
during the skirmishing go then said the
captain and show the poor woman this
spot as she seems so desirous of finding
the body.
Okay.
I accordingly took my way over the ground.
We had fought upon she following and
sobbing after me quickly reaching the spot
where her husband's body
lay pointed out to her.
Yeah,
she now discovered soon
all her hopes were in vain.
She embraced a stiffened corpse and after
rising and contemplating his disbelief,
disfigured face for some minutes with
hands clasped and tears streaming down her
cheeks, she took a prayer book
from her pocket and kneeling down,
repeated this service for
the dead over the body.
Poor woman,
I pitied her much,
but there was no remedy.
Okay.
Whole new dynamic right there.
Hmm.
Continuing on back to the book,
it was on the 21st of August that we
commenced fighting the battle of Ramiro.
The French came down upon us as a column
and the rifleman immediately commenced
a sharp fire upon them from whatever cover
they could get a shelter behind while
star Canon played upon them from our rear.
I saw a regular little lanes torn
through their ranks as they advanced,
which were
immediately closed up again
as they march steadily on.
Whenever we saw a round shot,
thus go through the mass,
we raised a shout of delight.
That's a savage image,
right there.
Ranks of men and there's cannon balls
that are cutting lines through cutting
lanes through them and you,
you'd probably talking 2030 people killed
each one and the ranks just close in
around them and that's what these guys
are seeing is this advanced takes place
there. Continue through that battle. They
get into a position for another battle.
Going back to the book,
as I looked about me whilst standing
and ranked and just thought,
and just before the commencement
commencement of the battle,
I thought it the most imposing site the
world could produce our lines glittering
with bright arms,
the stern features of the men as they
stood with their eyes fixed on alternately
upon the enemy,
the proud colors of England floating over
the heads of the different battalions
and the dark cannon on the rising ground
and all in readiness to commence the
awful work of deaf with a noise that
would defin the whole multitude.
Although the site had a singular and
terrible effect upon the feelings of a
youth who a few short months before had
been a solitary shepard upon the downs
of Dorsal pitcher and had
never contemplated any
other sort of life than the
peaceful occupation of watching the
innocent sheep as they fed upon the grassy
turf.
Talk about a dichotomy.
No fought in his mind other
than watching sheep eat grass.
I would think that that'd be kind
of a good little escape, you know,
from time to time to notice
those types of things. Yes,
I think you're right. And I
think that happens in, you know,
there's a movie called the thin red line
and that's portrayed very well in all
this chaos.
He'll take cover and he'll be face to
face with a flower or he'll notice a
burger, a bug. And that's definitely,
that's definitely something
that people notice.
I mean I noticed there's the sunset
no matter where you are in the world.
And actually the sunset and the deserts
have very beautiful thing and same with
the sunrise.
And so those are little things that you
notice even though you might not be in
the mindset to notice them,
you still notice them.
Back to the book,
the battle commencing immediately.
We were all soon so hard at work,
the rifles as usual or
pretty busy in this battle.
The French in great numbers came steadily
down upon us and we pelted away upon
them like a shower of led.
Inhale under any cover we
could find in lay firing.
One moment, jumping up and
running for it. The next and
when we could see before us,
we observe the cannon balls making a
lane through the enemy's columns as they
advanced as they were [inaudible]
and shouting like mad men.
Okay.
The battle soon became general,
the smoke thick into round and often I
was obliged to stop firing and dash at
aside from my face and try in vain to
get a sight of what was going on whilst
groans and shouts and annoys of candidate
and musketry appeared almost to shake
the very ground.
Yeah.
It seemed hell upon,
or if I thought a man named John Lowe
stood before me at this moment and he
turned around during a pause in our
exertions that he addressed me. Harris,
you humbug. He said you've
got plenty of money about you.
I know for you to always staying about
and picking up what you can find on the
field, but I think this will
be your last field day old boy.
A good many of us will catch it,
I suspect today.
Okay,
you're right.
Low.
I said I've got nine guineas in my pack
and if I am shocked today and you escape
yourself, it's quite at your
service. In the meantime,
however,
if you see any symptoms of my
wishing to flinch in this business,
I hope you will shoot
me with your own hand.
Yeah,
blow Pitsa the, so let's think about
that. That's, that's pretty awesome.
First of all, the attitude
of they're basically talking
smack to each other. Yeah.
Classic. Hey, I don't
think you're gonna make it.
I know you got a lot of money on you and
if you don't make it, what do you say?
Is that mine? Yes. If I die, come and
get it. I got nine guineas and my pack.
They're all years and then
this is classic by the way,
if you see me acting cowardly in
any way, you better shoot me. Yeah,
that's a legit
low as well as myself survived
this battle and after it was over,
whilst we sat down with our comrades
and rested amongst other matters,
talked over low,
told them of our conversation during
the heat of the day and the money I'd
collected and the rifles from that time
to time had a great respect from me.
It is indeed singular how a man loses
or gains cast with his comrades from the
behavior and how closely he is. He is
observed on the battlefield. Again,
talking about reputation.
Once again,
the officers to our commented
upon and closely observed.
Everyone's watching the officers.
The men are very proud of those who
are brave in the field and kind and
considerate to the
soldiers and under them.
An act of kindness done by an officer
has often during battle been the cause of
his life being saved, got a
little relationship going. Hmm.
Nay.
Whatever folks may say upon the matter.
I know from experience that in our army,
the men liked best to
be officer by gentlemen,
men who's education has rendered
them more kind in manners.
Then your course officer sprung from
obscure origin and who style is brutal and
overbearing.
So as I was reading through that,
I at first I, I kinda got a little
bit taken aback because I said, oh,
what are you trying to say if you haven't
been to college or a year that that's
what you need. You need to be from this
good upbringing. But that's not well that,
that might be what he's
saying at that time.
But the important part is
it's how you treat people.
It doesn't matter what background
you came from, you know, he,
he says men who's education has
rendered them more kind of manners.
And rather than someone that's from a,
an obscure origin,
what I'm telling you is it
doesn't matter where you're from.
And he would agree with this. Now if
he was here to talk with me, of course,
but it's not.
He's talking about the p the men like
to work for officers that aren't brutal
and overbearing. No one likes that.
Yeah, and you don't perform well.
You want to build the
relationship with your troops.
The kindness done by an officer as often
during the battle been the cause of his
life being saved.
That means guys are trying to win.
Yeah.
Back to the book and let me bear testimony
to the courage and endurance of the,
of that army under trials and hardships,
such as few armies in any
age I should think, endured.
I've seen officers and men hobbling
forward with tears in their eyes from the
misery of long miles,
empty stomachs and ragged backs without
even shoes or stockings on their
bleeding feet.
And it was not a little thing that
would bring a tear into the eyes of a
rifleman of the peninsula wars youths
who had not long been removed from their
parents' home and care officers and men
have borne hardships and privations such
as in are more peaceful days.
We have little conception of
okay,
and yet these men faint and weary with
toil would brighten up in a moment when
the word ran amongst us that
the enemy we're at hand.
Once again, he's ragging on you
haven't really been to war lately.
Peaceful days and
brutal
privations that these guys go through
and yet they're still ready to step up.
Back to the book.
It was just at the close of the battle.
The dreadful turmoil and noise of the
engagement had hardly subsided and I began
to look at the faces of the men close
around me to see who had escaped the
dangers of the hour.
I saw that the ranks of the
rifleman looked very thin.
It seemed to me that
one half had gone down.
Okay.
We had four companies with fifth and
we're commanded that day by major Travers.
He was a man much liked by the men of
the rifles and indeed deservedly beloved
by all who knew him.
He was a tight hand,
but a soldier likes that
better than a slovenly officer.
Pay attention to that one.
Don't be a Slovenly leader.
They the troops prefer the tight hand.
Back to the book.
I'd observed him more
than once during this day,
spring here and they're keeping the men
well up and apparently in the highest
spirits he could not have
enjoyed himself more.
I am sure if he had been at a horse
race or following a good pack of hounds.
The battle is just over. A flag of truce
came from, came over from the French.
We threw ourselves down when we
were standing. When the fire ceased,
a Frenchman Lake close beside me,
he was dying and called to me for water,
which I understood him to require
more from his manner that his words.
Yeah,
I need not say that I got up and gave
it to him whilst I did so down Gallup,
the major in front Justin,
the same good spirits he'd
been in all day plugging along,
avoiding with some little difficulty, the
dead and dying, which were strewn about.
Okay.
He was never a very good looking man,
being hard featured and thin,
a hatchet face man as we used to say,
but he was irregular Gooden,
a real English soldier,
and that's better than if he had been
the handsomest ladies man in the army.
Legit,
totally legit.
Back to the book of French, a French
soldier was lying beside me at this time.
He was badly wounded in
hearing him Moen as he lay.
After I had done looking at the cavalry,
I turned my attention
to him and getting up,
lifted his head and poured some water
into his mouth. He was dying fast,
but he thanked me in a foreign language,
which although I did not
exactly understand, I could
easily make out by the look.
He gave me Mullins of the rifles who
stepped up whilst I supported his head.
Dammed me for a fool,
for my pain's better.
Knock out his brain's Harris.
He said he's done os mischief enough.
I'll be bound for it today.
So right from the Harris is
still a pretty sympathetic dude.
Hmm.
Back to the book towards evening I posted
upon arising ground amongst a clump of
tall trees.
There seem to have been a sharp skirmish.
Here is three French men were lying dead
amongst the long grass upon the spot
where I was standing,
as I threw my rifle to my shoulder
and walked past them on my beat,
I observed they had been plundered and
there have her sacs having been torn off.
Some of the contents were scattered about
war is a sad blunter of the feelings.
I have often thought since those days
the contemplation of three ghastly bodies
in this lonely spot failed then in
making the slightest impression upon me,
the site had become even in the short
time I had been engaged in the trade,
but too familiar
and now they're another truce kind of
happens and he's observing the scene in
this churchyard. The scene in this
church yard was somewhat singular.
Two long tables had been procured from
some houses near and were placed end to
and amongst the graves and upon them we
laid the men who's limbs it was found
necessary to amputate
both French and English.
We're constantly lifted
on and off these tables.
As soon as the operation
was performed upon one lot,
they were carried off and in. In those
waiting behind, we're always stood up.
The surgeons with their sleeves turned
up and their hands and arms covered in
blood looking like
butchers in the shambles.
Okay?
I saw as I passed,
at least 20 legs lying on the ground.
Many of them being clothed in the long
black gators then worn by the infantry
line.
Okay.
The surgeons had plenty of work on hand
that day and not having the time to take
the clothes off the wounded.
They merely rip the seams and turn the
cough back proceeding with the operation
as fast as they could.
Okay.
Many of the wounded came straggling
into this church yard and search of
assistance by themselves.
I saw one man faint with Ross of blood
staggering along and turned to assist
him.
Okay.
He was severely wounded in the head.
His face being completely
encrusted with blood,
which had flowing during the night.
Now dried one eyeball was knocked out
of the socket and hung down upon his
cheek.
Okay.
But another man I observed who had been
brought in and propped up against a
grave mound,
he seemed very badly hurt.
The men who had carried him into
the church yard had placed his cap,
filled with the fragments of biscuit
close beside his head and he lay and the
and occasionally turned
his mouth towards it.
Got a hold of a piece of
biscuit and munched it.
Okay.
As I was about to leave the
church yard doctor Ridgeway,
one of the surgeons called me back
to assist with holding a man he was
endeavoring to operate upon.
Okay.
Come and help me with this man.
He said where I shall be all day
cutting a ball out of his shoulder.
Yeah.
The patient's name was doubter,
an Irishman.
He disliked the doctor's efforts and
writhed and twisted so much during the
operation that it was with difficulty.
Doctor Ridgeway could perform it.
Okay.
He found it necessary to cut very deep
and doubter made a terrible outcry at
every fresh incision. Oh,
doctor dear doctor said,
it's murdering me. You are
blood and hounds, I shall die.
I shall die for the love of the Lord.
Don't cut me all to pieces.
Doubter was not altogether wrong for
although he survived the operation,
he died shortly thereafter
from the effects of his wounds.
Okay.
Again,
you just got surgeons mixing blood
and not clean and not even cutting off
clothes or sterilizing.
I mean the,
the amount of people that must have lost
from the infections after the fact is
just
crazy
now.
They weren't fighting all the time and
at this point they are quartered in a
house in Spain.
And again,
Spain was divided at the time and there
was friendly and enemy span Spain.
And so they're quartered in a
house and there's a family there.
And here we go to the book,
the mistress of the house.
Seeing that I was the head
man occasionally came down
and sat beside me as I
worked, bringing her daughter, a very
handsome, dark eyed Spanish girl.
And as a matter of course I fell in love.
We soon became better acquainted and
the mother one evening having sat and
chatted to me,
serving me with wine and other good
things on my rising to leave the shop,
made a signal for me to follow her.
She had managed to pick up a little
English and I knew a few words.
It's Spanish language so that we could
pretty well comprehend each other's
meeting. And after leading
me into their sitting room,
she brought in her handsome daughter and
without more circumstance offered her
to me for a wife.
Okay.
The offer was attempting one,
but the conditions of the marriage
made it impossible for me to comply.
Since I was to change my
religion and dessert, my colors,
the old Dame proposed to conceal me
effectually when the army marched after
which I was to live like a gentlemen
with the handsome Maria for a wife.
Okay.
It was hard to refuse.
So tempting an offer with pretty
Maria endeavoring to back her mother's
proposal.
Okay.
Hi.
However,
made them understand that nothing would
tempt me to dessert and promising to try
and get my discharge. When I
returned to England, I protested.
I would then return and Mary Maria.
Okay.
Soon after this,
the army marched for Spain.
Okay.
The rifles paraded in the very street
where the shop I had so long worked at was
situated.
And I saw Maria at the window
as our Buechel struck up,
she waved her handkerchief.
I returned the salute.
Yeah.
And, and a half an hour
had forgotten all about her
so much for the soldiers. Love that.
I read that and I said, I have to
read this. This is to every 18,
1920 and 21 year old service member out
there that you meet the girl your dreams
and you've, you've do you think
you're gonna do some dumb stuff?
Don't do the dumb stuff.
Go back to your platoon and in a half
an hour you'll forget about her because
that's what happens.
Yeah.
Such so much for a soldiers.
Love [inaudible] back to the book.
Every man in the rifle seemed only
anxious to get a wrap at the French again.
Yeah,
on and on.
We toiled.
I love to remember the appearance of
that army as we moved along at this time.
It was a glorious sight to see
our color spread in these fields.
The men seemed invincible.
Nothing I fought could have beaten them.
Yeah.
Now he's talking about a guy named Cardo.
He was found to be most gallon officer
when we were engaged with the enemy in
the field.
He was killed whilst fighting bravely
in the peer knees and amongst other
jewelry he wore.
He had a ring on his finger wharf,
150 guineas as he laid dead on the field,
one of our rifle rifleman named or
observe the sparkling gem and immediately
resolved to make a prize
of it. The ring, however,
was so firmly fixed that or could not
draw it from the finger and whipping out
his knife,
cut the finger off at the joint after
the battle or offered the ring for sale
amongst the officers and on inquiry.
The manner in which he had obtained
it transpired or Wisconsin or wasn't
consequence tried by court marshal
and sent us to receive 500 lashes.
Okay.
Which sentence is carried into execution?
There's some significant corporal
punishment going on here with the,
with the lashes
and that's one of the cases mean what do
you know when you're executing someone
for being drunk and disorderly,
you're going to get some pretty severe
punishment for cutting the finger off of
one of your officers so
you can steal their ring.
Yeah.
Back to the book,
it was during the heat of the day.
We were rather hotly pressed by the enemy
after having advanced somewhat to near
their force,
give and take is all fair enough.
But we were getting more kicks
than half pence as the saying is.
And their balls stung a so sharply that
the officers gave the word to fire and
retire.
Doubtless many got a leaden
messenger as they did so,
which saved them the unpleasant necessity
of retracing their ground altogether.
Jock Gillespie and myself wheeled about
and obeyed the order just as we had
done.
So I saw Gillespie limp along as though
someone had bestowed a violent kick upon
his person. However, he
didn't give up at first,
but continued to load and fire and make
off with other skirmishers skirmishers
till we halted and made another stand for.
We never went further from them when
once engaged than we could possibly help.
I'm going to read that again.
Okay.
We continued to load and fire and make
off with other skirmishes till we halted
and made another stand for.
We never went further from them when
once engaged than we could possibly help.
And what that means is cover move. Hmm.
So if you are out on the battlefield
and you get too far away from the other
element where you can no longer support
them, you've made a big mistake.
So that's why they have doctrinal terms.
That mean I am in supporting distance.
I won't go further away from you then.
Then we're going where I can't help you.
Yeah.
Okay.
All right. Now speaking of lashings,
there's another situation here.
There was sort of a a ceremony where
they were gathering and standing in the
parade sort of in a,
in a town square and
somebody basically through,
I think like a brick at,
it's one of the soldiers from one of
the windows that was watching the other
regiment.
So there's one regimen standing on
the parade field handing out awards or
something.
The other regimens sitting up in the
various rooms around looking down and at
some point this this someone hawks
a brick down and it hits the kernel.
So
this Guy Liston was the guy that they,
they grab and they think it's this guy
list back to the book and was sentenced
to receive 800 lashes.
The whole brigade turned
out on the occasion and I
remembered that the drummers
of the Ninth Regiment where the infliction
of the lash list and list and receive
the whole sentence without a murmur.
This is the him talking about as he
goes on to talk about how this strict
discipline about it and how it kind of
fits in with the English mentality back
to the book.
They are strange set the English and so
determined an unconquerable that they
will have their way if they can think
about that. You got your soldiers there,
so it's a great quality
to have, right? You're,
you're determined and unconquerable
but what does that mean?
It means you're going to have your
way if you can and if you let them,
they're going to get after. It may be that
the way you don't expect. Yeah, indeed.
Back to the book,
it indeed it requires one
who has authority in his
face as well as add as back
to make respect and obey him.
They see too often in the instance of
sergeant majors that command does not suit
ignorant and course minded men and that
tyranny is too much used even in the
brief authority which they have.
So again,
he's going back to the fact that even
though you have to have these talking
about the dichotomy of leadership,
even though you have to have discipline,
you can't have tyranny
back to the book.
A soldier I am convinced is driven often
to insubordination by being worried by
these little minded men for the various,
the various trifles about which the
gentlemen never thinks of tormenting him.
So the this, the, the,
the little minded person that harps on
these little trifling things and that's
what actually creates insubordination
whereas the gentleman never thinks of
tormenting him with these little things
like these little things don't matter.
The, and then he goes on to balance
this dichotomy of leadership.
Back to the book of the moment.
The severity of the discipline of
our army has relaxed, in my opinion,
farewell to its efficiency.
But for men to be tormented about
trifles as I've seen it many times,
is often very injurous to the whole core.
So this is the perfect talking about the
balance of the dichotomy of leadership.
If you're to ultra strict, you're
guys are going to rebel against you.
And if you're not strict enough,
if you don't impose enough discipline,
they're going to not have any control.
So you got to balance these two
going forward. Back to the book. War is
a sad blunt or of the feelings of men.
He said that before and
he's saying it again.
We felt we felt eager to be added again.
Nay.
I am afraid we longed for blood as the
chair of our comrades sounded in our ears
and yet amidst all this softer feelings
occasionally filled the breasts of those
gallant fellows even whilst they were
thirsting for the site of the enemy.
Some of the men near me,
suddenly Rico recollected as they saw
the snow line physically on our pass path
that this was Christmas Eve.
The recollection soon spread amongst the
men and many talked of home and scenes
upon that night in the other days of old
England shedding tears as they spoke of
the roulette relatives and friends
never to be seen again by them.
As night approached,
we became less talkative.
The increasing weariness of our limbs
kept our tongues quieter and we were many
of us half asleep as we
walked when suddenly a shout
arose in the front that the
French were upon us.
Yeah,
so guys are missing home.
It's Christmas Eve.
Nice little dusting of snow on the ground
there. They have this skirmish with a
French there and now they're continuing
continuing the first march.
And if you remember the march that the,
that we talked about with Napoleon's
troops going into Russia and back,
these guys are under the
same basic conditions of if
you want to move the army,
the army's going to walk back to the
book of Sergeant of the night. So the,
so he's now on this also. He not only,
they are forced marching right now,
they're starting to retreat.
They're starting to do, they,
they're starting to take heavies
and they start uh, uh, uh,
retreat back to the book.
A sergeant of the 92nd highlanders just
about this time fell dead with fatigue
and no one stopped as we pass
to offer him any assistance.
Okay.
Knight came down upon us. So
those, think about that and this,
I highlighted that one,
but throughout this book he talks about
people just dying and he says they died
a fatigue. I don't even know what that
means actually. Maybe they're dehydrated.
I don't know.
But if you think about these guys who
are risking their lives for each other,
how exhausted are they that when someone
falls out during this first march,
the forced march,
they just leave them there
back to the book night came down upon
us without our having tasted food or
halted.
I speak for myself and those around me
all and all night long we continued this
dreadful march. Men began to look into
each other's faces and ask the questions,
ask the question, are we ever to be halted
again? And many of the week restore,
we're now seeing to stagger,
make a few desperate efforts and
then fall perhaps to rise no more.
Okay.
Most of us had devoured all we carried
in or have or sacks and each and and and
endeavored to catch up.
Anything we could snatch from
a hut or cottage in our route.
Many even at this period would have
straggled from the ranks and perished had
not. Crawford held them
together with a, from rain,
one such bold and stern commander in
the east during a memorable disaster and
that devoted army had
reached its refuge on broken.
Thus we staggered on night and day for
about four days before we discovered the
reason of this forced march.
Okay.
And they find out that they're
marching actually towards England.
They're trying to get away. And this
a guy that I talked about, Crawford,
he's pretty significant.
And here's a little talk about Crawford.
Crawford seem to sniff the sound of
battle from afar with Pq your feelings.
He halted us for a few minutes.
Occasionally when the distant clamor
became more distinct and his face turned
toward the sound and seem to
light up and become less stern,
it was then indeed that every poor fellow
clutched his weapon more firmly and
wished for a site of the enemy
before long they had their wish.
The enemy's calvary.
We're on our skirts that night.
And as we rushed out of a small village,
we turned to bay.
So even though they're retreating, they're
still having to fight. And this again,
this guy, Crawford, is
definitely a powerful leader.
Back to the book,
I remember one evening during the retreat,
he detected two men straying
away from the main body.
It was in the early stage of that
disastrous flight. And Crawford knew.
Yeah,
and Crawford knew well that he must do
his utmost to keep the division together.
He halted the brigade
with a voice of Thunder,
ordered a drum head court martial on
the instant and they were sentenced to a
hundred a piece.
Whilst a hasty trial was taking place,
Crawford dismounting from his horse stood
in the midst looking stern and angry
as a worried bulldog.
Yeah,
he did not like retreating at all.
That man.
They march a little bit further and then
back to the book ordering a square to
be formed. He spoke to the brigade as
well as I can remember in these words,
after having ordered the three before
named man of the 95th to be brought into
the square.
Although he said I should
obtain the goodwill,
neither of the officers nor the men
of the brigade here. By doing so,
I am resolved to punish these three
men according to the sentence awarded,
even though the French are at our heels,
begin with Daniel Howard's.
So these guys were looked like they were
going to dessert and they got caught
and he got a court martial on the spot
and going to give them a hundred lashes
or whatever the number was, and even
though they're running and retreating,
he's all right. We're going, we're
going to administer this punishment now,
even though it's not popular.
I got to do it back to the book.
This was indeed no time to be lax and
disciplined in the general knew it.
The men, as I said, where some of them
becoming careless and roughing and Lee
and their demeanor whilst others, again,
I saw with my,
with the tears falling down their cheeks
from the agony of their bleeding feet
and many were ill with dysentery and
from the effects of bad food they had got
ahold of and devoured on the road.
Our knapsacks too.
We're a bitter enemy in this
prolonged march. Many a man died.
I'm convinced who would have borne
up well to the end of the retreat,
but for the infernal load
we carried on our backs.
My own knapsack was my bitterest enemy.
I felt it pressed me to the earth almost
at times and more than once felt as if
I should die under its deadly
embrace. The knapsacks, in my opinion,
she have been abandoned at the very
commencement of the Retro Gate Movement as
it would've been better to
have lost them all together.
If by such loss we could have saved the
poor fellows who as it was dyed strapped
to them on the road.
There was some difficulty in finding a
place to tie how ends up as the light
brigade carried no Halbert's.
However they led them to a slender
ash tree, which grew near at hand.
Don't trouble yourselves about tying
me up. Set Howland's folding his arms.
I'll take my punishment like a man.
Yeah,
he did. So without a murmur
receiving the whole 300.
His wife who is present with us,
I remember was a strong hardy Irish woman.
So don't worry about tying be up. You
hit me 300 times. We add, uh, you know,
they do the whipping thing with the,
when you get your belt, do you remember?
Do you remember Irish? John, can you tall?
Pretty lanky and real good at Jujitsu
and he got his blue belt and he walked
through the whipping
hallway to get his belt,
but got the gauntlet.
He Wa he walked through the gauntlet.
He just walked and stopped at each person
and gave them the opportunity to give
them all they got. Yeah,
that was pretty legit.
He sounds like he sounds like he sounds
like my boy. Howland's right here.
More about Crawford right
here. This is classic. They're,
they're getting to a river.
They got across the river on their
retreat back to the book. Presently,
he spied an officer who to save himself
from being wet through I suppose and
wearing a damn pair of breaches for the
remainder of the day had mounted on the
back of one of his men,
the site of such a piece of a feminist.
He was enough to raise the color of the
general and in a very short time he was
plunging and splashing through the
water. After them both put him down, sir,
put him down.
I desire you to put that officer down
instantly and the soldier in an instant,
I dare say loft dropping his burden
like a hot potato into the stream,
continued his progress
through, returned back, sir,
said Crawford to the officer and go
through the water like the others.
I will not allow my officers to ride
upon the men's back through the rivers.
All must take their share of like here.
You can just go ahead and
note that down is how to lead.
That's just the,
that's a metaphorical and literal example.
Hey,
I'm going to ride on the back of my
enlisted man so that I can stay dry.
What a savage.
I think that that guy should have
guns will ashes back to the book.
General Crawford was indeed one of the
few men who is apparently created for the
command during such dreadful scenes as
we were familiar with in this retreat.
He seemed an iron man.
Nothing daunted him,
nothing turned him from his purpose.
War was his very element and toil and
danger seemed to call forth and increasing
determination to surmount them.
Okay.
Would you yet?
Now they are continuing
to March and again it's,
it's a story we've heard many times on
here and how harsh foot marches can be
and at this point, rifleman Harris, he's,
he doesn't think he's going to
make it. Hmm. And he's fading fast.
He's marching with a guy named Brooks.
They're kind of broken up into pairs to
try and stay together a little bit and
he's trying to maintain back to the book.
I remember Sir Dudley Hill
passing me on a mule this day.
He wore a Spanish straw
hat and had his cloak on.
He looked back when he had passed
and addressed me. Harris said, he,
I see you cannot keep up. He peered
very sorry for me for he knew me well,
you must do your best.
He said,
my man and keep up with us or you
will fall into the hands of the enemy.
As the day wore on,
I grew weaker and weaker and at last spite
all of my efforts I saw the main body
leave me hopelessly in the lurch.
Brooks himself was getting weaker too.
He saw it was of little use to urge me
on and at length assenting to my repeated
requests to be left behind.
He hurried on as well and he was
able without a word of farewell.
Okay.
I now soon sink down in the road and lay
beside another man who had also fallen,
was apparently dead and whom might
recognized as one of our sergeants named
Taylor.
Yeah.
Whilst we lay exhausted in the road,
the rear guard,
which was now endeavoring to drive on
the stragglers approached and a sergeant
of the rifles came up and
stopped and look at us.
He dressed himself to me
and ordered me to rise,
but I told them it was a useless for
him to trouble himself about me as I was
unable to move a step further.
Okay.
Whilst he was urging me
to endeavor to rise up,
the officer in command of the
rear guard also stepped up.
The name of this officer
was Lieutenant Cox.
He was a brave and good man and observing
at the sergeant was rough in his
language and manner towards me.
He silenced him and bade the
guard proceed and leave me.
Okay.
Let Him die quietly. Hicks, he said
to the sergeant, I know him well.
He's not Amanda lie here.
If he could get on.
Okay.
I'm sorry.
Harris Harris.
He said to see you reduced to this for
I fear there is no help to be had now.
Yeah.
He then moved on after
his men and me to my feet.
Yeah.
Lot different than never
leave a man behind.
You've actually got people just saying,
hey, you're not going to make it do.
I can see you're not going to make it.
I know you're a tough guy and if you're
not, if we're not walking right now,
there isn't.
We've got nothing for you
on now.
He lays there for awhile and he actually,
once he rests for awhile,
he regains a little bit of strength,
eventually crawls to a house,
gets in the house and gets a little
bit of food, gets a little bit of a,
I would love to say water
but isn't get water.
He gets food and wine
and he recovers somewhat.
He pretty much recovers. Um,
sleeps for awhile. Wakes up,
recovers and now he can
now he can walk again.
And what do you think would happen now?
Like in a case as similar to
this as possible? You know,
but just now we're at, I can't make
it. What do you do? Carry him? Yeah.
I mean you'd try and carry him. Of
course. Other guys. Got It. Yeah.
And I mean it's horrible to think of
these situations where if we have to move
these all these men and to sit there,
if we start, let's, let's weigh this.
You'd have to weigh this.
If we try and carry all over wounded out,
none of us are going to live.
Right. So that, that's what the,
that's the situation that
they're likely facing. Hey,
you're either gonna get Outta
here yourself and people
don't understand how hard
it is to carry it down,
man. It's, it's a very, very
difficult to carry it down, man.
Especially across terrain.
Then you know,
sometime in wrestling practice you pick
up and you pick up your partner and you
do a couple laps. Right. And Yeah, you
know, it's all good. You're honest,
nice smooth surface. The guys cooperating,
cooperating is not just dead weight.
It's, yeah, when you start carrying bodies
around, it's really, really difficult.
Yeah. So you don't, it's
not a one-to-one either.
So if one guy's down you can't,
it's not just one person carries that guy.
It actually has to be two or sometimes
three when you have gear on. Yeah.
And we have methods of carrying guys. I
mean, well I can carry you a little while,
right? Yeah. But after a
little while, you know,
be that 500 meters,
a thousand meters,
you're not going to be your, and also
your combat ineffective. You can't,
you can't utilize your weapon properly.
Not for, not for any length of time.
So you know,
in a situation like this that the decision
that these leaders are making is, hey,
guess what, if we don't just keep
walking, we're going to get overrun,
the French are going to catch us and
we're all going to die. So Harris,
he got nothing for you.
So in countries like now we'll say if
there was a circumstance like that where
we're going to lose more guys,
if we bring this guy with us or one big
luxury that we have now is we have f air
support. Yeah. So, oh, the enemy
wants to keep coming at us.
Cool. We'll sit here and call,
drop bombs on them all day.
Situations like that have happened
over and over again in the modern wars.
And when in the eight,
Iraq and Afghanistan were small
elements are out there in the field.
They're about to get overrun and
the aircraft and air, air, fire, uh,
air power comes in and completely saves
the day and keeps the enemy at bay for
extended periods of time.
So we have, uh, an option,
another option,
but in the,
I guess ultimately it'd be a hypothetical
then the case hypothetically, we then,
then you got to put someone in that
situation and see what they're gonna do.
And that's a decision you've got to make
as well as a leader and an on the spot.
I mean,
you,
you'd be weighing all these micro
micro facets that are happening.
How far away are the bad guys?
How many of them are there?
Do I have reinforcements coming? Is
there any terrain I can take is or what,
you know, what can I do? How
many people are down? Yeah.
You have to weigh all these things out
and make a decision and it's going to be
a hard decision for sure.
So you don't put like the, the,
the concept or should I say,
um,
like the action of at least trying to
bring the guy with you ahead of like other
guys lives.
So you need a circumstance like
this where you hypothetically,
you don't have any content,
you don't have any support,
you don't have any other options.
It's either other guys die or the
where we leave this guy behind.
The fact that you tried to bring the guy
doesn't Trump like the lives of other
guys
where if the decision is to be made where
it's understood like other guys would
have died if we didn't leave this
guy here, that would be okay.
It's not going to be okay and you're
going to have to live with one horrible,
right thought or the other. Right, right.
The the thing that's powerful about,
we're not going to leave
everything anyone behind.
The thing that's powerful
about that is if that's your,
if that's your default mode, your default
mode is to fight. And that's what,
that's, that's what we train. That's when
I say we, I mean like America trains,
we're not going to leave you behind.
And so when that's your goto attitude,
that's your go to attitude and
all the thoughts about, hey,
we'll weigh it out and all of a sudden
there's like, no, we're going to fight.
We're going to kill
everyone and we're going to,
we're going to do everything we can to,
to bring everyone back. That's what we do.
And that is a powerful thing. Yeah, man,
these are savage times. These
are savage times. Savage Time's
going. So like I said,
he does recover though.
Luckily before the French get to him,
he recovers enough to get out,
start walking again,
and he talks a little
bit how he was clinging.
I mean he was clinging to
survival back to the book.
It is however, indeed astonishing
how a man clings to life.
I am certain that had I
laid down at this period,
I should have found my last
bill on the spot I sank upon.
Suddenly I heard a shout in the front,
which was prolonged in a sort of hub hub.
Even the stragglers whom I saw dotting
the road in front of me seemed to have
caught something like hope.
And as the poor fellows now reached
the top of the hill we're sending,
I heard an occasional exclamation of joy.
The first note of the sort
I'd heard from any days.
Yeah.
When I reached the top of the hill,
the thing spoke for itself.
They're far away in our front.
The English shipping lay in.
Okay.
It's a view had indeed
acted like a restorative,
uh,
to our force and the men at the prospect
of the termination of such a march had
plucked up spirit for a last effort.
Okay.
Fellows who like myself seemed hardly
have strengthened their legs to creep up
the ascent seem now to have picked
up a fresh pair to get down with
okay.
Such as hope to us pour mortals.
So they obviously
see the uh,
see the ships and that inspires them and
they start moving a little bit faster.
Back to the book,
there was I recollect a man of the name
of Belle of the rifles who had been
during this day holding a
sort of creeping race with me.
We had passed and repassed each
other as our strength served.
Bell was a rather discontented
fellow at the best of times,
but during this retreat he had
given full scope. Two is ill temper,
cursing the hour he was born and wishing
his mother had strangled him when he
came into the world in order to have
saved him from his present toil.
Okay.
He had not now spoken for some time and
the site of the English shipping had
apparently a very
beneficial effect upon him.
Okay.
He burst into tears as he stood
and looked at it. Harris. He said,
if it pleases God to let
me reach those ships,
I swear never to utter a bad
or discontented word again,
appreciation.
And he did make it to the
ships and Harris Rifleman.
Harris made it to the ships and
okay,
they got embarked on those ships
and they sailed back to England.
Okay.
For a few days and then get off the
English shore and then finally back to the
book.
One fine morning received orders to
disembark and our poor bare feet once more
touched English ground.
Yeah.
The inhabitants flock down to
the beach to see us as we did so.
And they must have been a good deal.
Surprised at the spectacle we presented.
Okay.
Our beards were long and ragged,
almost all were without
shoes and stockings.
Many had their clothes and accoutrements
in fragments with their heads.
Swathed in old rags and our weapons were
covered with rust whilst not a few had
now from toil and fatigue
become quite blind.
Okay,
let not the reader,
however think that now we,
we were to be despised as soldiers,
long marches,
inclement weather and want to
food had done their work upon us,
but we were perhaps better than we are
appeared as the sequel showed under the
gallon.
Crawford,
we had made some tremendous marches and
even Gal Dar enemies so severely making
good our retreat.
Yeah.
But our comrades and adversity who had
retired by the other road under general
more turn to bay there and show the enemy
that the English soldier is not to be
beaten even under the most
adverse circumstances,
the field of death and slaughter,
the march,
the BIVOUAC and the retreat are no
bad places in which to judge men.
I have had some opportunities of
judging them in all these situations.
And I should say that the British are
amongst the most splendid soldiers in the
world. Give them fair play
and they are unconquerable.
Yeah.
For my own part,
I can only say that I enjoyed life more
whilst on active service than I have
ever done since.
Yeah.
And as I sit at work in my
shop in Richmond Street,
so Ho I look back upon that portion
of my time spent in the fields of the
peninsula as the only
part worthy of remembrance
it is at such times that scene's long
past come back upon my mind as if they had
taken place.
But yesterday
I remember even the appearance of
some regiments engaged and comrades,
long molder to dust.
I see again performing the acts of heroes,
acts,
heroes,
and I think it's
okay.
Safe to call riflemen Benjamin
Randall Harris I hero as well.
Yeah.
And at the same time,
yeah,
I think it's important
to remember that these,
Yep. These men, these heroes,
they're not superheroes
like we see today in movies.
They don't wear a cape.
They don't have any super human strength.
They have no special powers.
What they do have is they have will.
Yeah.
The will to fight the will to drive
on the will to live the will to win.
And I think
that's the superpower.
They knew. It never ceases to amaze
me. These aren't normal people.
Riflemen Harris was normal guy.
My costs,
but when called upon to March,
they march and when called upon to fight,
they fight and when called
upon to rise up and overcome,
they do just that they
rise up and overcome.
Yeah.
And that shows us
that we can do the same
thing in the Fallon,
in the challenges that we face.
We can do the same thing.
Yeah.
Briars
and overcome.
And I think that's all
I've got for tonight.
So Echo
perhaps if you could let people
know how they can support themselves
and maybe if they want to support
this podcast as well. It's crazy.
Huh?
These marches, right? Brutal.
Yeah. And this is, uh, I dunno,
maybe no. From what I can remember,
the, the worst one that when you,
especially how they talk about
it with no shoes to shoes,
their shoes probably just fall off
within the first, you know, a little bit.
And then they're walking with no
shoes or barely any shoes or whatever.
Crying straight up just from the
march, by the way. Yeah. Not the,
not the war or anything like
that where the marches yet
just as big of an enemy.
He said his pack was his biggest enemy.
He had literally though the kind of
work guys are strapped, killing them,
killing them,
killing them.
So we,
we just got back from Utah
obviously and um, you know,
after every we're doing that training
where we brief debrief reco down,
exercise B and then, you
know, we've walked back and
forth. Right. Okay. So, okay,
so echo,
I'll just tell people these people
have no idea what you're talking about,
which is fine. Echo, we just
got echelon front, did a
FTX field training exercise with
the company we were in Utah.
We brought echo out so that he
could get some footage and whatnot.
And so then, so that's what we're
talking about. So we're in the field,
we're doing basically urban
combat with a group of,
let's call them regular people,
business people that are
learning leadership through
experiential environments.
It's an interesting one is a good one.
It's like the,
it's like a con,
you know how if you don't communicate
with someone effectively, right,
things fall apart.
I know exactly what you're going to
say is drawn out situation in life.
But this is like a condense
version of that. Yes.
So if you don't communicate with
someone during an Ftx, it do, you know,
within like 30 seconds that
something just went wrong.
And now we're getting shot in the
face with a, with air soft rifles.
It's just fun.
It's really fun to watch from
the outside cause do you see it?
And I've been to another one too.
Um, and yeah, you see it. It's right.
And it's interesting how in the beginning
it's like, it's almost impossible.
Like he don't,
right.
And immediately communication breaks
down immediately and then towards the end
you start to see people
communicating, getting it. You know,
like when you kind of got to
overcommunicate. Yeah, for sure.
But the more you do that, the
more effective it is. You know,
it's so crazy to watch. It is an, I don't
know if you remember Dave saying this,
Dave told them,
he said,
Jocko just told you the mistakes
that you're going to make.
You told you what you're going
to do and you're going to do it.
And then sure enough,
every single one of them,
the funniest was the one
individual that said,
they came up with a plan
for something and we said,
you know your risk and get a blue, a
blue on blue there. Yeah. And she said,
she said, listen, I
understand what you're saying,
but it's not like we're going to walk
in there and start shooting each other.
That's not going to happen.
And, and sure enough,
that very girl was in a
stressful situation and they
entered a building from two
different sides at the same time. And
sure enough, she, she dusted one of her,
one of her teammates and it was,
you know,
it's one of those things I
said, hey, remember what you
said yesterday? She said,
Oh yeah,
I remember.
And I had the luxury of seeing it from
the outside. You can feel it though.
Oh yeah. But you're in a different
situation position than me.
Anyway, the point is, um, so
the terrain there was, um,
where the field and where you,
where you actually do the,
the field training part of it is like,
well what would you say 100 yards away
from the pre where you do the brief and
debrief has about 400 yards. Yeah. Yeah.
So it's, it's a little bit of three,
300 yards out.
If you're doing it again in the animal,
we're going brief exercise,
debrief,
brief exit, you know, kind
of all day. Really. So,
and this was a situation where there,
it was a hill and rocky, you know,
so I'm walking right and I have my
camera the whole time and it's not,
it's lighter than my other accountant,
but you know, it's something. Um,
and so I'm walking back and forth all day,
all day,
where my feet are starting to get
kind of tired, more tired than normal.
And I'm thinking every but every single
time. Now, every single time I'm thinking,
this is nothing compared to what
you guys was going to do. Nothing.
How nothing it was.
I didn't,
that didn't even go into my mind at all
in any way, shape or form. You don't,
what's interesting about
that is while I'm walking,
this was like after lunchtime,
I'm thinking,
I'm seeing you guys and
everyone's Cruzee and,
and I'm thinking is everyone tried to act
like this isn't like Kinda kinda tired.
Literally didn't think of it until
you said this to me right now.
The biggest I was, I was wholly
acting like, fuck, this is nothing.
And I wasn't going to mention it.
I was going to brought,
that's how I handle a lot of stuff.
That's good. And it helps him.
But the fact is true.
You do actually better when you
pretend that it doesn't bother. Yes.
I remember that night and day
and night and night and day.
So we started acting all tired and
accepting it and showing everyone. Yeah,
it's true. But nonetheless,
the fact is it wasn't nothing.
It wasn't nothing. I
felt it and you know, um,
so it's funny, I'm looking at
you guys something like, Hey,
I wonder if these guys are, you know, um,
but no one said anything. Nobody said,
Dang, these tracks are
getting long, 300 meters bro.
But nonetheless,
so every time I feel anything like that
I think of like you guys first and you
guys are doing it in like crazy heat
to gear and like all this stuff.
And I think that this kind of
guys, these gang guys, yeah.
Riflemen Harris Riflemen Harris
feet all tore up starving,
starving, starving, no
sleep, no water, no water.
And people are trying to kill you.
Oh yeah. So that's the point, man.
If these guys can rise and overcome that,
what figure your personal potential.
Yeah. Right. Yeah, take of it.
I think of what more you could do.
Yeah. That bothers you a little bit.
I just saw the look and
bothersome you guys.
That looks like I made
some dope videos though.
I'm about to make a huge
excuse right now too,
which I don't even know if it's an excuse,
but it's a factor where these like hard,
actual hard times kind of call on you to,
to exercise this kind of will,
you know?
And I think a lot of times
we're not like hard times,
don't call on us like this anyway.
I mean hard times do you know?
But you know what though?
You know what though it,
you should put,
I mean technically and potentially you
should be able to exercise as much.
We'll as it takes really now when
you consider kind of the limit,
because these are the lemmings are the
limits. This is interesting. This is the,
this is one of the stories where the
guy's like, I'm done. Yeah. He said, okay,
I'm done. Guys are saying, Hey, if you
stay here, you're going to die. He's like,
yeah, I cannot move anymore. Then
when you think about, you know what,
what point are you at when you
cannot save your own life by walking,
you can't walk, can't take another
step. And he came back from that.
Yeah.
And they told a really good
job in illustrating it.
Cause you were talking about it where,
cause you mentioned the no shoes
thing a few times. Yeah he did.
But again, I bet if, yeah, yeah, he's,
he does a great job,
but you can't even begin to,
can't even begin to really get the point
across because the way it is as the
leader, I was talking to a guy the other
day that went to buds and didn't make it
through.
Yeah.
And I known him for awhile
and I just said like,
hey man, you know, you're
a good dude. You know what,
why did you, why did you quit? And
he said, you know, it just sucked.
And I was like, okay, but didn't, you know
it was going to suck? And he said, yeah,
I knew it was going to suck.
But at the same time, you know,
I watched it on TV and I thought to
myself, okay, yeah, that's going to suck.
He said. So I, I thought I
understood how it was going to suck,
but I didn't understand how it was gonna
sound. And there was there, I said,
this really sucks and he quit.
And again, a good dude, that debt.
I'm kind of, you know,
thinking myself, why?
I'm trying to figure out why people
quit. Yeah. And that was what he said.
He said much like we're saying like as
much as you could imagine and you say to
yourself, all man, never.
Yeah, but I think I can cook.
I could make that one more step.
You don't know.
You don't know until you've
been dehydrated. Having
people trying to shoot you,
cleaning up your buddies,
brains off your jacket for weeks,
months on end, you're dehydrated
and now you have no shoes,
no stockings.
And your march or doing a forced march
on this road for this may march for days
without stopping. What
even is that Tang? Yeah.
Yeah. That's it. I mean,
this kind of, that's not to
mention like no medical care.
No. Like no one's coming
to save you. You know,
it's really jacked up
is thinking about this.
Think if you have an ingrown
toenail. Right, right.
Like a little thing that is Bob,
it actually bothers you in
actual life. Yeah. Thank.
If you had that here or you have a, or
you have, say you got a sprained ankle.
Yeah, a bad sprained ankle. I sprained
my ankle really bad before. Sure.
You can't walk on it.
Well now you don't have a choice.
You either walk on it or you die.
I think about the little things that are,
that caused you an inconvenience right
now and think about what an inconvenience
that is in this situation.
Think about you get a little infection
in your fingers, your fingers year.
You ever had one of those little
stupid like where your fingernail is,
get a little infection there.
Think about that and that you don't have
no medicine. You don't have any way of,
yeah, that's the things you're going to
turn into in giant infection. You Die.
It's the little,
little tiny things that annoy you are
will kill you back in the day check.
So what we have to do is
prepare for these hard times.
Do you have any advice on how we could
help prepare ourselves for these hard
times on top of
references,
seeing these scenarios?
I referenced your guys' scenario.
Like basically everything that you guys
guys tell me and talk about like how
it's super hot,
you don't sleep as much.
I'm not talking about them talking about
like Ian Ramadi, like all these stuff.
I kind of imagine that helps. Totally
helps. That's good because it,
it helps me to think about rifleman
Harris. Yeah, for sure. You too.
Speaking to help. Speaking
of help, help being yourself.
All right,
so you're just in the way,
this is kind of a dichotomy here cause
you know like when your joints get sore,
I'm talking about Krill oil.
Joining her for a real quick
that you can be spelled in dream luxury.
Yeah.
You recommend Harris who would've
had Kerlan Jobe warfare. Who knows?
Maybe it wouldn't have stopped that
day. That time. This is pre luxury.
Yeah. Supreme luxury where now it's
like, hey my joints, I'm getting older.
My joints kind of hurt. I kept,
I can't work out at the gym,
you know,
at my leisure as good.
Let me take some joint warfare, you know,
improve my comfort while I work out.
Function for sure function.
But Comfort has has a lot to do with it.
Working out with sore joints is way
less comfortable than not sore joints.
Yeah. I'm going to say though, there's
exercises that you cannot do when you,
when your joints aren't
ready to rock and roll. Yeah.
So you can push yourself harder and be
better prepared for the hard times if
you're working correctly, if your
joints are working correctly. Yeah.
That's the dichotomy.
And there also is no
like concession.
There's no,
there's no reason to say, hey, my joints
being less healthy is a good, is fine,
is good. That's a good thing. You
know. So you have a choice. Shouldn't,
should I maintain or improve this joint,
my joint health,
the health of my body including,
but not limited to joints or should I not?
The decision should never
be, I'm not, never be,
I think this was my opinion anyway.
So the point is,
so jock, Lizzie them supplements
joint. So it's for your joints to me,
best kind of supplements as,
as someone who with a level head.
Now as far as supplements goes.
So I think the joint for your joints,
um,
you know,
bones,
maybe stuff that's going to base
structure, structural, structural support.
Because again, and I
said, I said this before,
like if you're like going for
super cool protein powder,
a lot of people that say, Hey,
what's a good protein daughter?
Here's the thing you don't stake.
Like how much protein do you like
not get to need supplemental protein.
You know, people want that
cause it could even convenience.
That's why people like those very,
very few.
I'm going to make one that's going to
be both convenient and tasty and good.
Alright, there you go nonetheless. That's
cool. I'm not saying that's a bad thing.
I'm saying as far as like the
importance of focusing on a supplement,
the most benefit.
Okay,
so your sound lamenting your convenience
then really for sure not supplementing
protein, you're supplementing
convenience. Nothing wrong with that.
Nothing wrong with that. We've
got a lot to do. I understand.
But as far as like the,
what do you call it,
the hierarchy of suppler Jordan B.
Peterson supplements or the house.
It's hierarchy of supplements,
like the Krill oil,
Omega threes,
like these kinds of things that
help you directly. That's the,
that's the main ones.
Anyway,
so your point in all this is Josh
also supplements, legit supplements,
Super Krill oil.
Jocko super is what's called Krill oil,
free joints and joint warfare.
Where do you get them? Or Gin
main dotcom kit. Thank you, Bro.
I'm telling you it. I feel like
you're drawing this out way too much.
Just if I was doing this and be
like, hey, if you want to have good,
healthy joints,
get some krill oil,
Krill and get some joint
warfare from origin main.com m.
A. I. N. E. Yeah, but and
then we'd be good. We'd been
moving on the next thing. Yeah,
no, I dig it and I got the
hierarchy. Here's the thing though.
Dominance. No, this makes
sense. This is relevant
because you're not doing it on a proof
point because it needs to be proven. No,
because back out of your element
again, again, when I was,
we'll say 23 and I'm going to
take some phosphorous something.
Yeah,
so what if someone listening or group
people listening who have that same
mindset because not
because I knew both things,
I would just just didn't know. Okay,
so I'm going to say no. We know. Yeah.
Well that's good.
If there's someone that doesn't know that,
maybe they turned this off like
eight minutes ago, maybe, maybe not,
or maybe they're more educated
now and maybe boom there.
Now they're looking into
the joint situation. That's
what I think is happening.
That's my opinion. Hey,
that's my prediction.
I'm sure Twitter will let us know any way.
The origin main.com on the top click labs.
Actually three in the front page.
I keep forgetting this phrase on
the front page. Boom. Supergirl,
Supergirl and joint warfare kid on it.
There's also some Geezer in rash guards.
People been asking me years now
what? Gee, should I get? I started.
You did to with gee, should I
get, we know now we know. No,
100% all made in America from the cotton,
from the fields of the cotton planted
harvested process about seeds.
Did do.
Yeah. That's an exciting thing. I'm just
saying if you're into that kind of thing,
but nonetheless, you know,
Pete makes it in Maine,
formulates the fabric. Boom. Geese.
Other stuff too. By the way. Clothing,
he has more of like a stylish kind
of twist on his clothing. Yeah.
In fact I was, who was it? Oh Dave Burke.
Yeah, we're in Utah. Had the origin,
the Hoodie and the Hoodie has like,
I don't know if you know this kid's stuff,
but like there's certain cuts of like
goodies and stuff and even though it's
like my daughter's XL. Yeah. Yeah. I
see it goes beyond that. No brother.
Yes it does. Anyway, Mike,
you know it's noticeable for people
who want to notice it nonetheless.
Notice that I'm going to dance
group did what? He was like, Dang,
that's a good like that's a good hoodie
and it's just a pullover. Come on Dave.
Hey, it's something, it's not
nothing pumpkin. Nonetheless,
it's all made in America and there is a
little stylish twist if you're there to
notice,
if you care to notice has some
fashion style baked in there.
If you don't notice you to notice
cause he you, you ever wore the,
you wear the Hoodie, right?
Functional warm to kept me warm.
I'm not used to 19 degrees
like it was in Utah.
I don't think I've ever been in 19
I was but I had that Hoodie on help.
You guys had these biggest cortex check.
It's
nonetheless all the stuff on origin
main.com is made in America from cs of the
cotton all the way till the
final garment you wearing.
Yup. Yup. Good one. Check
out this stuff on there.
Good way to support also
in your fitness routines.
If you want to expand out of
like just basic hey bench squat,
burpees, dead lifts. What else? Basic.
Once you pull up to if you want to expand,
do some like cool,
interesting stuff on it.
Dot Com slash Jocko go there.
They've got some cool fitness
gear, kettle bells, which are,
they got all the kettlebells including
the artistic ones. Those are cool.
I think those are all the ones that
have just artistic ones. Check it,
makes it funner.
Put a little twist on it and do,
you can mix up your workout
as far as creativity,
which keeps it fun for some people,
not Jocko. Some people though,
if you vary the workout
like new movements,
new functional movements, if you will, um,
you're more likely to stick with it.
Stay on the path and
make the path enjoyable.
Sometimes don't just neglect the
enjoyability of your workout.
If you want on it.com/jack of really
good fitness gear on there. Um, you know,
check it out, see what you like
and uh, get something. Also,
when you are buying the book,
recollections of Riflemen Harris,
I'm going to make it easy for you. We have
made it easy for equal in the website.
Jocko podcast.com on the top
menu says books from episodes.
Boom is a list of all
the books by episode.
Click through there to get
it takes an atmos on and um,
both good way to support and they want
to do some other shopping while you're on
there. Like what? Lawn mowers? Golf clubs,
golf clubs, podcast equipment. Recently,
a lot of people have been hitting me up
saying, Hey, I'm going to start a podcast.
What's the equipment, you know, I
should get, they asked me that too.
Yeah, no wonder I just talk.
Yes. You press record. Yes.
And I got the equipment so I had that
knowledge and excited about that. Are We?
So having knowledge is better than not
having the knowledge in whatever regard.
Nonetheless, if you're gonna buy a podcast
equipment, carry on, do that stuff.
But yeah, click through this.
Good, good way to support.
Also subscribe to the podcast.
If you haven't already on stitcher iTunes,
obviously Google play.
Spotify confirmed.
It seems weird that I didn't know
that for sure. Dude. Real weird.
Here's the thing.
So many things that weird.
We need to talk about it for a minute.
I guess I can. You know what?
You're right. It's just me
expressing myself. Look,
all you got to know. Spotify confirmed
troopers out there confirmed it to me.
And that's really the good
thing about people interacting.
Yes it is. You learn a lot about
yourself and your own situation.
You know things that you don't know
cause they're detached and they have
different expertise by the way.
In a lot of ways. Most ways.
Anyway, subscribe. If you haven't
already. Also subscribe on Youtube.
This excerpts on there.
If you don't want to listen to or if
you don't want to necessarily watch the
whole episode video
version of this podcast,
you can just get little
excerpts taking share,
watch or even come back to.
That's a big one.
We've put out so much that it's too much.
People can't absorb it all the first
time round. Yeah. Wait, what do you mean?
Like the whole episode
you mean? No, no, no.
What was on episode 63 people when
people don't remember that thing,
they may be so you just like Jujitsu,
you go listen and you learn it again and
now you'd now it's more recognizable.
Yeah. So it's like drilling
a little bit. Yeah.
It's like you're going to come back. I'm
going to drill somewhere. Yeah. And some,
you know how like certain things
just apply to you more like if your,
your advice on, I dunno,
college, that's easy.
One to remember about how to approach
college, right. Crush college or whatever.
It's gonna apply to me more if
I'm actually in college, you know,
versus just apply that to other things
in life would you can easily do for sure,
but that's going to apply to
me directly. We'll say, oh,
you know more than maybe the next guy.
So that kind of stuff where
that one I want to remember. Okay,
I'm going to come back to that one.
If I can constantly remind myself of
the things that directly apply to me,
you can be more,
it's going to be more beneficial rather
than just linking to all the podcasts
and hoping you remember each one.
Nonetheless, point there is that it.
That's a good reason to subscribe to
the Youtube Channel. So if you, in fact,
if the excerpts or some
excerpts resonate with you,
you got them there at your
fingertips and you can share. Also,
Jack was a store it called Jocko store
Jocko store.com that's the URL there
there.
That's where you can get if
you want shirts because you
don't even know what you
are Alizea anymore. Of
course they do. You think so?
I think that's common language. No,
actually no, I think you're right.
Just call it the website. Website. Yeah.
The website website, URL stand for to see,
well I don't even know. Here's the
thing I knew that I forgot. No,
I'm actually not a tech
guy. Yeah, but you knew it.
I knew what it meant. I don't
know what it stands for. I Dunno.
Universal home. Ask your brother. I know
where it's probably not even universal.
J Charles.
Nonetheless it's Jocko.
The website is Jocko store.com.
I'm not that creative but easy to
remember and that's where he can get the
shirts. Hoodies, rash guards,
compression rash guards if you will.
We're very selective cities where
you maintain range of motion.
Jujitsu specifically in my opinion,
uh,
what he's on their hoodies, all the
hoodies. They're the same design but the,
there are the heavy ones.
People have been asking me like,
are these the heavy ones are,
where's the heavy hoodies
ones we saw like the,
the non heavy ones, we'll
call them. I've got therapy.
The first kind of
iteration. Exactly. Well,
those were all sold out.
They sold out last year.
And so I did another iteration
with your for the heaviest there.
They're the heaviest one.
Actually I think there might be
some industrial heavier one. Maybe.
No, because I think that was
then he, I dunno, I forget.
Nonetheless. These are
the heavy ones. Confirm,
double confirm. I'm also so
women's stuff on there. Uh,
I think I'm going to add a few
things before Christmas on the store.
So if you want,
keep your eyes on that.
That's a good way to support. If you want
something, get something, check them out.
Also,
psychological warfare.
If you didn't know what that is
until it's an album with tracks,
Jocko talking on these tracks,
basically you listen to them when you are,
you know,
on the path we'll say on the path
and you get moments of weakness,
days of weakness, you know,
those, you're not feeling like it.
You know how you always talk about like,
it doesn't matter if you feel like you're
not, you just do it. Okay, let's do it.
Okay. So, uh, and I respect that and
that's where we all want to want to be.
We all want to be there,
but for some of us it's not
like that 100% of the time.
Sometimes when you really
don't feel like it.
Sometimes when I really don't
feel like it, I just don't do it,
man.
Sometimes I gotta be honest.
We'll put on psychological warfare and
you'll do it. Yes, like a spot, you know,
especially a spa. This is where it's
like a no brainer. Like really easy.
When you, you're like contemplating
when you're like, he's,
I could just do this tomorrow. Right.
And you start making deals with yourself.
Do you ever do that? Deals with
myself. The weak part of it.
It's like you don't so straight up
Jocko Jocko like I don't feel like it,
I feel like it,
whatever gain,
I get pissed at myself at yourself.
If I start leaning towards like, oh,
maybe I just won't do anything.
No. Oh really? Really how
it is. That's how, okay,
cool. We're going to go smash. You know?
It's real funny. That doesn't surprise.
I've witnessed that with
you. Like we'll be like,
ah,
I don't know if we can kind of do that.
Then you get this sort of look this kind
of way about you kind of like, wait,
did I just say that echoes going on
vacation and he's going to be gone for a
couple of weeks and I've been
real busy with all kinds of stuff.
And we were talking about if we'd be
able to actually get all these podcasts
done and I didn't think we could do
it. And so I said, hey, echo, you know,
we're just gonna have to take, you know,
no, no podcast for a few weeks. And then,
um, then I said, actually, I, like
a day went by and I said, I said,
echo a text that said, uh, actually
we're going to do it in your corn,
all the podcasts.
I'm going to prep for them all.
We're going to have an all nighter
and we'll just get it done.
Bring some red bull and get some
great some Jocko white tea. Yeah.
Well what was interesting about that is
when you said that you had this kind of
tone of like Dang, like term it
like, Whoa, we got to take a break.
We've got to take a break after two
years by the way, every single week,
by the way,
we got to take a break.
That's what you said. Yeah. And right
when you, and I was like, cool. I dig it.
I mean I'm not saying good, I'm
saying cool. I I totally understand.
And you know what?
That makes sense.
Hbo Big Company takes huge breaks.
Everybody takes huge breaks.
Everybody takes parent and
you're over here two years in,
no breaks, no breaks,
no matter what. Okay.
So they'll come a time when we are
forced to for some reason. Yeah.
That's kind of part of the point
bro. So I'm like, cool, I dig it.
I totally understand Jocko.
And when I said that,
that's when your face kind of shifted,
like kind of you went into your own world.
Did I just say that? Like, it's almost
like you sorta got mad. Real subtle,
but it was there and I was like,
oh, we're not taking a break.
I know docker is going to come back
nonetheless. And I'm sure that I'm like,
okay, so I dig it. But back
to psychological warfare.
If you
need a spot or even want a spot
with those times that you're like,
maybe I'll skip the workout,
maybe I'll slip in the dive minute.
Just listen to any track.
And the track is labeled, you know,
where if you can skip on the diet,
it's like just sugarcoated. Like wait,
what is it? Sure. But it's something,
something's sugarcoated, lies.
Sure. Recording. It's just so, yeah.
So he listened to that. And then what's
good is it's not some inspirational, Eh,
you can do it. It's not that. It's
like it's pragmatic here to do that.
Here's the thing though, you, but just
by nature, your tone of voice kind of,
kind of like by happenstance
inserts that concept in it.
So it's kind of a double double thing as
it turns out. But primarily it's just,
it's a pragmatic thing. Think about,
think about this logical stuff.
And then at the end of the truck
he kind of conclude that, oh yeah,
it's going to get after
it. Yeah, exactly right.
That's what psychological warfare
is. It is on iTunes, Amazon music,
Google play, wherever you can
get MP, three s mp3s, true
story. Anyway, to support.
Also,
you get Jocko white tea and if you're
having trouble dead lifting less than a
thousand pounds,
if you get Jocko white tea,
that would be solved immediately and your,
your dead lift will then be 8,000
pounds, including uh, Jordan B.
Peterson who can now dead
lift a thousand pounds.
He broke through his 7,000 pounds.
Yup.
Cat barrier barrier books.
I got some books way the
warrior kid number one. Um,
don't let your kid be a wimpy kid.
Why would you do that?
Or why would you let your neighbors could
be a wimpy kid? Why would you do that?
Get them on the path way the warrior kid
path stronger, faster, smarter,
better. It gets some extreme ownership.
The new edition is out and thanks to
you all because we added questions.
Your questions from this
podcast into an appendix inside.
Not every question, but uh,
a bunch of them. Oh, good
amount. So they're in there.
There's also a new Ford and some new color
pictures. Color pictures. Interesting.
Yeah. Cause I don't like color pictures.
I said no dichotomy. They said,
well this is more premium. I said,
no, black and white is between users.
So anyways, if you want to see
what I looked like in color
then you can get the book. But the w
two to offset that, I said okay fine.
You want to put color pictures in there,
make the whole book black.
So that's what they did. Make the
whole book black and that was that end.
Speaking of black also.
Yeah,
the discipline equals freedom field
manual is available worldwide.
And I told you about that tagline that
the publisher wanted to have like the um,
this book is a superb differ for the
holiday season. And I told them no,
the tag line is,
there's no better gift than disappointed.
Yeah.
That's the truth. You
know, it's actually true.
If you could give someone
the gift of discipline,
would you not be giving them
the best gift in life? Yes.
Now you can actually give them the
gift of discipline equals freedom field
manual so you can do that.
Now this is important because people
keep asking me the field manual audio
version, discipline equals freedom
field manual is it is also on iTunes,
Amazon music, Google play, other MP3
platforms. It's available right now.
It is not on audible. Audible
is not with tracks. No,
we wanted an album with tracks.
It's why we did it this way for something
on top of the books and the podcast.
If you need leadership
training and execution at your
business or with your team,
you can contact our leadership consultant
company. To me it's JP Denelle,
Leif Babin,
Dave Burke,
info traditional on front.com and if
you have questions for us or you have
answers for us.
A couple of questions I asked today,
you can communicate with us
on the interwebs, on Twitter,
on Instagram and on Duffy.
Echo is that Echo Charles and I am at
Jocko Willink and to the service men and
women out there right
now holding the line,
slogging through the mud and the
heat and the danger and the fear.
Thank you for defending us
and our freedoms and to the
police, law enforcement,
firefighters, paramedics
are there. First responders.
Thanks for living the life that you live,
which allows us to live the life we live.
And to everyone else that's listening,
just remember that you
might not be wearing a cape,
you might not have any magic powers,
but you have the ultimate
power and that is human will.
The power to march,
to fight,
to overcome
and to get after it.
So until next time,
this is echo n Jocko out.