This is Jocko podcast number
one 20 with Echo Charles and me,
Jocko Willink. Good
Evening Echo. Good evening.
So it's been a while
since Q. And. A. Yeah.
So we have some Q and a
from the interwebs. Yeah,
go first question Jocko.
More than once on the podcast,
you've mentioned how the teams were so
competitive that no one wanted to admit
when they were cold.
Being too too cold puts you at a
tactical disadvantage in hindsight,
was that a failure to control your
ego so your ego doesn't control you?
I didn't ask this question.
Out of idle curiosity.
A lot of folks that an active duty,
listen to the podcast and I'm concerned
they might put themselves their
teammates and their mission in jeopardy
because of their egos won't let them
admit they're too hot or
too cold. All right, so
good question.
Good point.
And there's definitely a big difference
between between being uncomfortably
cold,
right?
Like on like you're just uncomfortably
cold or uncomfortably hot or we thirsty
or hungry or whatever.
And being in an actual state where
you're putting the mission in jeopardy
because you're too cold or
hot or thirsty or whatever.
So I just needed to say this.
In the teams you are 95%
of the time you are cold,
too cold, too hot, too wet, too
thirsty, too miserable, something.
There's no time.
When you're in the field,
you put on a hundred pounds
worth of gear worth of gear.
You're uncomfortable from the word
go from the word go and you're cold.
You know, you come in over the
beach, you're in wet cammies.
It doesn't matter who will come out with
great technology and we've got a dry
suit or this, we got a wet suit that
no, you're, you're miserable. It's not.
You're going to be cold.
You're gonna be uncomfortable.
You ride in a Zodiac
first, you, you ride in a,
in a big ribbon,
which is like a 10 meter boat and
you have your Zodiacs on that boat,
so you're in that boat,
you're getting sprayed with water,
you're getting bounced up and down.
You do that for three hours and then you
launch your little boats into the water.
Well there, while you're doing that,
you fall in the water, you slip,
you get sprayed more, you're
covered in water. By the way,
the water is not warm and then you got to,
cause you're going to
travel then 15 knots,
so you've got to fear facing
a 15 not headwind for another
two hours in a Zodiac,
and then you're going to get in the
water and swim. It would be deeply,
you're going to be cold.
That's just the way it is and you
can't complain about that. So,
and you don't complain about it in the
teams, you just keep your mouth shut.
That's what you do. Keep your mouth
shut. Now the big distinction here is,
this is correct.
If you're going to get hypothermia or
you're going to get a heat stroke or
you're going to go down from dehydration,
then yeah, you got to speak up and be,
you know you to say, Hey, guess what?
I got an issue here. I'm, I'm starting.
You know, I'm starting to get dizzy or
starting to get light headed or whatever.
Yeah.
If you cross the line to where it goes
from discomfort to actual problem,
then you definitely need to speak up.
Um,
and it does happen. It happens a
lot actually. You know, when we,
when we do our land warfare training
in the desert in the summertime,
it's 120 degree heat. Got Your, you're
going to take heat casualties. You know,
when I was running training,
we used to just have premeditated heat
casualty evacuation cause we knew someone
was going to go down.
That's just the way it's going to happen
because you got 40 guys that are all
turning and burning and
they're all running on three
or four hours of sleep and
then they're going out in the field and
they just got back from the field and
there's no time to rehydrate.
You know, the, okay there's time,
but some guys might forget to
rehydrate and next thing you know,
you've got a guy going down.
So the stuff does happen and yeah,
you got to let your team know what's going
on. I've the, the closest call I had,
I was on a long patrol training patrol
in the Ozark mountains of Arkansas.
It was summertime, it was hot.
We were planning to pump water.
Meaning you bring a little
water filtration system into
the field and you get to
a stream and you can feel
your canteens and it's great.
And it seems like you have water
forever cause their streams, well we,
the way the patrol went,
we started off in pairs and then we linked
up with fire team and they need like
a couple of squad and you
look up with a platoon.
Well while we were in the squad
linkup we for whatever reason,
the course that I was on,
I didn't hit water.
We had a couple of streams that were
supposed to be there and they weren't
because they're intermittent streams.
So sometimes dreams are running year
round and the time of year it was,
the streams weren't running. So the
first one I was like okay, I'll be okay.
Gotcha. So you go up over a mountain,
come back down the other side,
get to this where the stream is marked,
intermittent stream is marked on a map.
Guess what? No stream. So now, and
then by that time I was out of water.
So now coming the next day
I said to myself, you know,
if there's not water on this next stream,
I'm going to,
I'm going to have issues and there
wasn't water for the next day.
So yeah,
that's,
but I started to feel the
dehydration coming on me.
That's why I hate being thirsty. I, Hey,
I always carry as much water as I can.
You,
you gotta be paranoid about being thirsty
and once you start going down from a
dehydration, it's really a bad
situation. You went the whole day. No,
it was two days. Yeah. I'm now, I had
water going in, but I didn't really feel,
I didn't have a ton of water. I should
have had it. I should've had one. Oh,
I should have maybe two more liters
of water as a, as a just in case,
but I didn't think need
got to carry. Yeah. Yeah.
Cause you know you've got to carry it.
Now you're heavier,
now you're sweating more.
So there's a little balance.
You've got to figure it out there.
But yeah, can it be a problem?
Yes, I have seen it become a problem
where we're guys, ego's too big,
they don't want to admit it for
sure. So yes, this is a good warning.
Don't your ego get you in real trouble
and that's going to hurt your platoon
even more.
So don't let that happen.
Don't let your ego prevent you from
telling the truth about what's happening.
And this happens in,
this can happen in the business world too,
where, Oh, you know what? Oh,
I don't really know how to
operate this piece of equipment,
but I'm not gonna say anything. I'm
just going to try and do it. Well,
that's how someone gets hurt.
So again, that's an ego problem.
When you have an issue,
when you know you can't do something
or you've never done something before,
step up and,
and raise your hand.
Now of course you should have done the
research. You should just, you know,
you should have figured some stuff out on
your own, but if you failed to do that,
don't dig the hole deeper. Raise
your hand. Say what the problem was.
There you go. Good
question. Yeah, makes sense.
Cause that especially the thirst thing,
like the dehydration thing a yeah.
You don't want to be the guy saying,
oh I'm thirsty. But here's the thing.
I think nowadays though, like teams
and coaches, here's the thing,
in football case they'll pop Warner
football. They'd be like, yeah, no water.
You know we have a water break,
you drink water at the water break,
otherwise you're practicing,
you know kind of thing.
It's like a toughen you up thing. But
man, that can jam your health up. Yeah.
But let's face it. I mean it would be
pretty rare if you gave people the,
if you're doing a practice, what, how
long has the practice last? Two hours.
Two hours. Okay Bro, you can make it
two hours if you're properly hydrated.
Now if a person is not properly hydrated
going into the practice, sure that can,
that can be a problem when if someone
is properly hydrated going into this
situation, it should not be a
problem. And I'll tell you what,
if you are in the military
and you're going in the field,
man pre hydrate like crazy.
That used to save me so much from caring
so much water and just drink so much
water. Now I'll tell you
where the problem comes in.
You're in a helicopter ride for an hour
and a half that you got to Piss so bad.
It's awful. Well you know
what, bring a little,
bring a little plastic bottle with
you so you can piss him the bottle.
That's the way less of an issue I think.
Like finding a place to drink
versus fee for sure. But yeah,
if you pre hydrate properly,
no matter how hard you're working,
you can go like 12 hours without any
water, which is pretty legit for you.
You know,
kind of an average seal mission.
12 hours get you probably have plenty
of time. Yeah. Yeah. But I mean,
I'm talking pop Warner here so you know,
we're not talking about,
but here's the weird thing, like when
you went to high school, College,
they'd have water right there, right
there on the sideline, and they, you know,
they're really aware of, hey, you need
good, you need lots of drink more water.
You don't think that was also the time.
Yeah. That's actually the point. The era,
the era when we were kids,
no one ever,
ever one single time in my old,
from the time I was zero until
I was 18 no one ever said to me,
hey, make sure you drink water.
Never, never heard anyone
say that. It was like, oh,
you're thirsty. Drink a coke. Well,
you know, it's just the way it. Yup.
So that changed for you in that
time period. When I got to,
when I got to seal training, when I got
a buds, that's when they were saying, oh,
you got to stay hydrated. Yeah.
I thought it was kind of a joke.
I thought they were kidding
at first. Like, what are
you talking about? Hydrogen?
Me Drink water. What do
you, what do you mean?
Why would you call it
something else hydrated?
We're Thursday this naive will,
you should,
cause you can go down from like heat
this for, there's heat exhaustion,
heat stroke, heat exhaustion. Yet there's
all kinds of heat injuries you can get.
Yeah. And you get heat stroke by, you can
straight up die. Oh yeah. So that's not,
you know, it's not a matter of
like, oh yeah, tough it out. Right.
You can't tough it out. You're shutting
down kind of thing. That's for sure. So,
you know, that is important. It's sort
of the heat thing. And I guess that is,
you know,
going back to this question,
that is probably why we would
see he casualties in training.
Because guys do not want to say
anything. They're like, man,
I'm not gonna say anything. I'm not
going to get an IUD and look even worse.
Cause that's what happens.
You get stuck with an ivy.
Now you're laying in the field.
Everyone else, by the way,
it continues on doing another
tip kilometer hump to a
target and you're sitting
there laid up in the ambulance like
a little baby. No one wants that,
but pre high if you pre hydrate properly,
you won't be in that situation. Yeah,
but if you are going to get
that situation, you need
to say something. Yeah.
We're talking about your life essentially
and more important and we're talking
about the mission.
Yeah. Yeah. I'm still thinking about the
pot. We're in a situation, but yeah, man,
I dig it and you are correct.
I can't help but agree with you.
100% net question Jocko.
Dear Jocko,
my chosen community has lost and
continues to lose members due to suicide.
One reason is that they
don't ask for help.
I think one reason they don't ask for
help is that they're afraid of being or
being seen as weak.
I'm aware that this takes strength
and discipline to be able to purse,
perceive when you need
help and to ask for it.
I don't know how to convey that to them.
Could you address how one
can gather support from their
team without losing face?
So there's an obvious reason why I paired
these two questions together because
they're both very, very similar.
And it's the same thing.
And if we don't,
if a member of your team won't come
forward and admit they have an issue,
then the issue is not
going to get addressed.
And this is the same exact thing that you
have to explain to your team. Like, Hey,
if you start going down because you're
dehydrated or your start getting d, uh,
getting frostbite and you need to get
warmed up, you need to say something.
If you don't say something that's
going to hurt the whole team,
that's what's bad. So, so
I think that's important.
I think that's important to make sure
everyone understands that this part of
being a good operator is
knowing your limitations.
And when you reach your limitations,
raising your hand and saying, Hey,
this is a problem. And
believe me, there's,
there's guys that might complain about
little things and they're eventually
going to be labeled as a
little complainer, right?
And they don't really have issues.
So there's a fine line, right?
There's a fine line. But
for this one, you know,
for someone that's having some
kind of mental stress, well again,
we got to recognize what's going on.
We've got to recognize that it's
impacting us negatively at work.
So that means you got to raise your hand.
If it's having a negative impact
on the way you're performing,
then you got to raise your hand.
And I think it's important to explain
to people that this is something that
something that happens
to can happen to anybody.
And it's not a negative thing. It's
just a reality. It's, it's kind of like,
it reminds me of being afraid.
Right? And if, if, if you're,
let's say you got a new guy that's never
done anything before and he doesn't
know that he's going to be
afraid going on an operation,
then he's going to wonder why his stomach
is upset or why he's second guessing
themselves or why he can't sleep.
Like, Oh, you can't sleep. Guess what?
That's normal. You're going on a
hardcore combat operation tomorrow.
The fact that you can't
sleep as completely normal,
the fact that you feel sick to
your stomach is completely normal.
The fact that you're, you're, you're
shaking, those things are normal.
Like you're going to feel those. That's
okay. It's not that big of a deal.
And those things are, are just
fear. That's what they are.
And if you know what they are and you
know that fear is okay and it's acceptable
and it's actually kind of
good, right? Because if,
if you're not feeling any fear whatsoever
all, then you know you've got some,
well you should be feeling afraid. You
should be, should feel fear that should,
that should propel you. It
should get you on edge. Those,
all those things are actually
happening for a reason.
So there's nothing wrong with that.
And I think that's the same thing that
you got explained to people with stress.
Like,
Oh okay that you can have too much fear.
You keep someone at that heightened
state for an extended period of time.
Well that's called combat stress
and it's real and it can happen.
It can happen to anyone.
And you know,
how many books have we talked about on
this podcast where you can see stress,
combat stress taking
its toll on people and
and when it does, you know we've
talked about it many times. P if you,
if you get to that point you need a
break and and Dick winters from band of
brothers, you know, he would give gloves,
guys breaks without them even knowing that
he was giving them a break and saying,
Oh hey echo,
you've got to go back and do a little
logistics run for four days and just make
sure we have more supplies coming our way.
Get you off the front line,
get you a breather. So that way, again,
the same metaphor I've used before is
if you have an engine in the red and you
keep running it, what's going to happen?
The engine, it's going to burn out.
It's not going to be usable.
If you have someone that's psychologically
stressed and they're in the red and
you keep running them in the red,
guess what?
Eventually you're not
going to be usable anymore.
So you need to give them a break,
get them off the line.
Because if you do take an engine,
if your engine like check engine light
comes on and you go and get it maintained,
get it fixed, the engine still
good. If you keep running it,
the engine will be destroyed.
So you've got to do that with your people
and you've got to make sure everybody
knows. And I think that's a real simple
metaphor to use with people as well. Say,
look,
we're running hard and we're going to
put some stress on the engine and if you
don't keep the engine maintained,
the engines is going to break and
you won't be any good to the team.
You won't be in good for the mission.
So if you start feeling
your engine light go on,
you got to let someone know so we can
give you the proper maintenance and that's
it. Jody Mitic talked about that
too. Jody was saying, Hey, you know,
basically if you get injured,
if you break your ankle,
they don't just expect you just
to keep going. No like, okay,
you need to get back and you needed to
rehab while the same thing had happened
to your brain.
Your brain gets a break in it.
You don't just keep driving or it's
going to fracture and fall apart.
What do you do? You, you take a break,
you get downtime and you get recovered
and then you'll be ready to rock and roll
again. So two really good questions
to start it off. You know, again,
especially for folks out there on the
battlefield and then it's not just for
people on the battlefield
because it happens with any,
any group of people that are
in a stressful environment.
I mean obviously cops get put into a
really stressful environment all the time.
Well, if you need to take a breather,
you need to say something before you,
before you burn out the engine. Yeah.
Same thing with business world, right?
People in the business world
get extremely stressed out.
Well you probably need a break at some
point. Make sure you work that in there.
Don't like, uh, like police have like a,
like a mandatory program or a
mandatory situation where you know,
you go through,
I think we'll like when they shoot
someone or something like that,
like mandatory. You have to go to
like some kind of like counseling.
Most of them do now. Yeah. Yeah. So that,
that makes sense too because even if,
let's say you don't necessarily
need it or whatever, right?
You'd go through a shooting situation,
you got to go mandatory and
then I got to go through.
But it's good that everyone kind of
does it because it seems like, oh,
it takes away the negative, the stigma,
you know, like kind of like, oh,
I'm the only guy, you know, I'm the
only guy that apparently feels this way.
I'm looking around. No one else is going
to counseling and now I'm the only guy,
I must be the weak guy, so I don't,
I'm going to know. And they do that.
They've done that somewhat
in the military of, Hey,
when you come home from deployment,
everyone's going to go talk to uh,
talk to what does it a psychotherapy
therapist or psychologist.
They kind of do that. I know they did
that in the seal teams where they'd be,
everyone would go,
they didn't do while I was in,
they give you like a piece
of paper to fill out,
which everyone just kind of gun deck,
you know,
it just pencil whip. I don't
know what, just like, you know,
fill it out except for Tony. You know
what Tony wrote on the, the head of his,
what he wrote.
This is a cry for help.
That was pretty funny.
But in the west that was,
he filled out like a whole fake
one about just a funny one.
Yeah.
But it makes sense though because of that,
because that's kind of the,
yeah, that's really smart way to do
thing. It's the smart way to do things.
Let's give everyone a, let's give
everyone a baseline sort of, okay. Check.
Here you go. Yeah. And that
way no one's, no one has to go.
No one has to take raise
their hand first. Right? Yeah.
You're all going to talk to somebody.
I think it's a smart thing to do.
Yeah. Cause it's kind of the thing, right?
It kind of goes along with
the earlier question too.
Like if it's a water break and hey guys,
water break, everyone's drinking water.
So now it's like you don't
have to feel like, Ooh,
the one plus
who like me to use water. Oh you
know, kind of thing. Oh yeah. Yeah.
This exact same thing.
Yeah. Hey Man. So yeah, if you've got an
issue, man, speak up. Let everyone know.
You know, that way you can do your job,
you can do it longer, you can do a better,
your goal is to do the,
is to be the best possible.
That you be the best possible capability
so that you can go out and do your job
the best if you're,
if you got issues,
you got to say something so that you can
keep doing your job for the team. Yeah.
It's like, I'm like, don't
look at yourself as being weak.
Look at yourself is trying to optimize
your strength, kind of, you know?
Maybe just flip over the way you look,
look at it and whatever. There it is.
Next question.
Do you think martial arts tournaments
are the most effective way for preparing
for physical confrontation?
I just competed in my first,
my second do just the tournament as a
three straight white belt in one match.
I completely lost focus and control of
my mind because I believe I was taken
aback by the strength and wildness
of my opponent. Amen, man. I dig it.
Hundred percent I barely,
I can barely even remember how my,
how the match unfolded.
I've given this match significant thought
and I concluded that I need to compete
more. I'm very calm. I'm very
comfortable with everyone in my academy.
I trust the desert role with
without question. They're
like family. Now. The Guy,
the guy in the tournament
was a total stranger.
He was unknown and therefore elicited
fear. I allowed myself to be,
to be crippled by fear.
Is there any other way to overcome
this beyond competing in tournaments?
Thank you.
All right.
You know,
competing is definitely part of it and
it's interesting [inaudible] he's asking
if this is the most effective way to
prepare for a physical confrontation.
It is a very good way to PR to help you
prepare for a physical confrontation and
the bottom line is competing.
One of the things that competing,
one of the things that that's true with
competing and it's true with anything is
that the more familiar you
are with the unfamiliar,
the more familiar it will be calm.
Yeah,
I know that sounds pretty obvious,
but the more familiar you
are with the unfamiliar,
the more familiar it will become.
So you get to become familiar with things
that are unfamiliar and you learn how
to handle things that you
weren't expecting in the teams.
We always talked about that your
first free fall jump when you're,
when you're learning how to skydive with
the freefall rig and they're your first
jump, seems like it's, it's like three
seconds long. Even though it's a minute,
even though it's a minute because you're
just, you're all amped up and you,
all you see is your altimeter
and the more you jump,
the more you see until that minute.
I mean,
have you ever had tried to hold
your breath for a minute? Yes.
That's like a long time, right? But
and that's,
that's the amount of time that can take
up a free fall can be a nice long minute
where you're observing all
these different things.
But when he first started doing it,
it doesn't seem very long.
I'm sure if we had Andy,
you know Andy Stumpf on here,
his one minute free fall
price seems like a really,
really long time because he's
got thousands of of jumps.
And so this is the same thing.
The more you train for chaos,
the more custom you're going
to become to the chaos.
Now what's great is in this particular
case he's talking about this guy's just
wild and crazy and hey,
if you survive it that first time will,
the next time someone goes wild
and crazy, you're like, okay,
well here's what I needed to do.
Need to put this in check. I need to,
I need to hold on,
I need to make sure I don't give any
positions but I'm not going to get crazy.
I'm just going to absorb some.
You go through that mental drill and the
more you go through that mental drove a
battle, you better you will
get at it. And this is true,
this is true with anything.
And, and that's why, you know,
when I was running in seal training,
we put the we, we would make it.
So we hit people with the most random
hospital things because that's what
prepares you for random possible
things is random possible things.
That's what you want to deal with. It's
kind of weird, you know, in Jujitsu,
Dean Dean used to talk about this
and now you can hear John, Donna,
her talking about it as well.
And if,
if you have never been in
a certain situation before,
you're not ready for it. And when, okay,
so there's a, there's a position in,
in Jujitsu called 50 50 right,
that's what it's called now.
We used to call it cocker Reiko because
that's the position that dean was in
when he beat a guy named Cocker Rinko
for the ADCC world championships.
And
Dean Dean calls that position 90 10
because he's been in it so much that even
though it's a neutral position,
meaning we both have the same
advantages and disadvantages.
When deans in that position,
he's been in it so much that he's got
a 90% chance he's got a 90% chance of
success because he's been there 10
times, 20 times, 30 times more than you.
And I heard John Dawn, her talking
about the same thing the other day.
He's getting Pete, you know, his,
his Jujitsu fighters right now are
doing things to guys that are these,
they're, they're putting people in
positions that the person's not used to.
So if you're not used to it,
guess what? You're an advantage.
Even though I might have trained,
even though,
let's say I'm a Jiu Jitsu black belt
and I've been training for 20 years,
if I've never been in this
particular position before,
it's I might as well be a
white belt in that positioning.
You can see that happening.
You can see that happening in Jujitsu.
That's why when somebody comes
up with a new new type of moves,
that move can be effective for
a little while. Like let's say,
let's say you came up with a new move.
You might catch me in that new
move one time and then I go, oh,
I know what he did, but if, but
now if instead of just a new move,
you had a whole new area that
I had to learn all. Yeah.
Then I had had to learn
a whole new deal around.
It's the same thing with Eddie Bravo
and 10th planet. You know, like they,
they were doing things like, oh, I've
never been in this position before.
Now what do I do?
And they were catching guys like that.
And then the more people figured
out that part of that system, okay,
well then you get better at it and
we get to a neutral ground again.
But anytime you can,
so in training,
anytime you can get to be put yourself
in a situation that you haven't been
before, it's going to be beneficial
to you. Now what does it,
how does this translate to real
physical confrontations, right?
How do you train for that? Well, how often
are you putting on gloves and Jujitsu?
How often are you having
somebody punched you in the face?
How often are you having somebody
come up and push you around that?
How often are you having people do things
that people have been doing a street
fight,
right?
That people are going to do in a street
fight that they wouldn't normally do in
a Jujitsu match, right? For
instance, in a street fight,
does anyone ever start on the niece,
right?
They don't start on the nose.
They don't.
So you don't start on the knees and
street fight. You don't say, Hey,
you want to fight me?
And then you,
then you get down on your knees
and so does the other guy.
Now we figure out what happens.
No street fights don't start on the knees.
So you're almost, and people
ask me, this is actually,
somebody asked me the other day,
w w what should I do when starting from
the knees? What's a good take down?
I'm like, oh, pull guard. Because
why are you on your knees? Yeah.
The best thing to do if your
opponent is on their knees,
stand up and kick them in the face,
right?
Because you're not going to be, if you're,
why would you be on your knees? Yeah.
So don't practice that.
So how do you prepare for,
the best way to prepare for these
combat situations is, is uh,
is Jujitsu tournament a good way?
Yes, it is. A good way. Is Boxing,
is boxing a good way?
Is it good to do a smokers?
So you figured out what
it's like when somebody,
some you want to talk about
with someone going wild.
Wait til you get someone that's untrained
in boxing. Come throne, the throne,
you know,
windmill haymakers at you 38 in a row.
Now they're going to be exhausted
after that first 32 seconds. But,
but you will,
I would have had to have withstand and
not get punched in the head. You know,
cause if you get punched in
the head by a while, hey maker,
I don't care who you are.
If they connect with your chin,
there's a possibility you might go down.
So you need to be careful of that. So,
so don't just think, oh just Jujitsu.
Hey go out, train some boxing,
train some boy tie and go and
spark. And if you can do a smoker's
cause it's smokers. Pretty easy to do.
In other words, you don't need
to, you don't need to, uh,
do like a full preparation
camp and all that. Yeah,
it's an unofficial event.
So you go do a smokers and you're going
to experience somebody going wild on you,
throwing haymakers at you, throwing
crazy kicks at you. Do that,
do all these things to get ready for
those physical confrontations. And then,
then you also on top of that,
you read and you look at youtube videos.
Go Watch Youtube.
I've talked about this before.
Go watch youtube videos of street fights
because you get to see what people,
what kind of things people do,
which,
which can be very effective,
right? You need to watch,
learn to watch out for soccer punches.
You need to learn to watch out,
watch your back and watch you sneaking
up on you and be aware of your
surroundings and put your back
against the wall. You know,
there's all these little things that
you can do to make sure that you're not
going to get sucker punched, but you've
got to pay attention to those things,
you know? Yeah. That was that
wildness that he talks about.
That is a huge thing.
It's like a whole nother factor where,
especially in exactly
how he said he's real,
he's real familiar with his
training partners. So men, you know,
the amount of cruising and kind of
relax and even during the role there's
probably a significant amount of it
almost to the point where it seems like
anyway where he kind of maybe
expect that or you know,
even subconsciously kind of he,
he understands that that's
kind of part of the deal.
You go against a complete
stranger and he gets wild.
Then it's like Whoa, this is
like, it's kind of overwhelming.
And also even at the three
stripe white belt level. Yeah.
This other guy, he may,
he's got his little game,
he's got his game that he plays and
there's a chance that as a three stripe
white belt, you haven't learned that
part of the game. So it just feels crazy.
Yeah. And that whole, you know, when
you compete for the first, second time,
you know, just a at the earlier, see
that's the thing is the more you train,
the less holes there are. Right. The last
holes you are there are in your game.
And so if you're a three straight white
belt, you might not have good, uh,
guard replacement. Yeah. Right.
Like you really haven't learned how to
replace the guard from cross side. Well,
if this guy happens to be a guy that
holds really well across the side and
that's where he works his game
from, man, you're in big trouble,
you're in big trouble.
And it all seems so unpredictable too at
those earlier stages because you don't
know where your holes are. I mean, you,
you might know some, but you don't know,
you know,
you haven't seen enough of the game and
you haven't been in enough situations
where you, you can kind of stay
calm and you know, all this stuff.
So to your point where you say you got
to be familiar with the unfamiliar kind
of thing, remember when
[inaudible] started just
baseball bat choking everyone.
Yeah. Yeah. These little weird setups.
And he would let people pass as
guard and he, they'd be thinking, oh,
I'm about to score some points on that and
boom, they're getting tapped out. Yeah.
It was so foreign that, okay, so he went,
the two real real famous ones at the
time when he exploded on the scene with
these was he was Clark and Zack
Max through there's two matches.
And one of them,
Zach Maxwell had mounted in arm bar.
No, hasn't been the arm bar. Meanwhile,
baseball choke is in not,
but who cares because
really that rule not rule,
but that situation of kind of applies.
If you have someone in the arm bar,
I don't care, he choked me up to break
your arm, but he's going for the arm,
but he can't lean back because
baseball that chokes in and he's like,
he got a tap, you've got a
straight up tat. And then, uh,
I think he was Clark where he could've
been the other way around. But either way,
Clark has a smile. I was better
at these matches, weren't
we? I know I was. Yeah. No,
I wasn't. I was there, I saw
the videos. But um, yeah,
the kind of where Clark was like,
I know this joke,
I'm in Maui or I'm in this good position.
I know that this choke doesn't work.
It simply doesn't work cause I have the
advocate and he gets choked unconscious
cause he doesn't tap.
Sure it might hurt.
And that is the case for a lot of jokes
where it's like sure this her, no, no,
no don't, no, a good one doesn't
even hurt. Yeah. It's just a joke.
It just in the, so what we're talking
about there is a guy named measured,
what's machines last name? Age.
Yeah, that's right. And he,
he came onto the scene we'll say with,
well this is what's interesting about
this is the baseball bat choke is not a
new choke. Yeah. It's not a domain
that people were unfamiliar with.
It's just that he was doing it really,
really well with really good
setups that people, that's what,
that's the part that people weren't
expecting. It was a really good setup.
They really going to set up so people
weren't expecting and so he let people
pass their guard or his guard,
but he had the token,
they'd get across side and
get mounted or whatever.
Go for arm locks and they're tapping.
Yeah. Because they weren't expecting it.
Yeah. And even if those, you know,
I mean Zach Maxwell and Clark Gracie,
but just phenomenal competitors.
Blackbelt Jujitsu,
I mean been training their whole lives.
Both of them got caught
by that by, yeah. The,
the,
the legitimacy of like,
the way that whole thing went
down was just so astounding. Like,
just like how you said like Clark Clark
has been winning stuff from day one and
then, yeah. And yeah, it was just crazy.
But it just shows, you know where you can,
you can be that good. You get just that
one teeny tiny window of unfamiliarity.
Yeah. They guy creeps in there and he's
familiar, but he'll just have his way.
And then what was interesting is as people
started knowing that that's what he's
going to go for it, but
he'd still get it. Yeah.
And actually he and I trained with him
before for know a few times or whatever
and he didn't do that to me. And I
was like, hey, you know, like Wah,
I didn't have to him, why didn't he
do it to me? But I was, do people,
you know like does everyone asks you
to teach them or what did he's like,
you know what people don't w I don't even
really talk about anymore because I've
become so well known for
that move that it becomes,
it became less a part of my life. He said,
I was like, well, it can happen to where,
okay, now once you go, okay, it
goes through a phase of, hey,
I wasn't expecting that and it
worked because I wasn't expecting it.
Then it goes like, hey, I was
expecting it but it still worked.
But then it gets to a point where people
are just going, I'm not gonna do it.
You're like, Oh, if he grabbed my collar,
I need to go in a totally different
direction. I need to not do anything,
I need to back out, whatever. And
then it becomes where, like you said,
it's an now it's loses
some of its effectiveness
because everyone is expecting
that to be the move that you do.
That's what happened with Dean
Paul a hundred percent sure.
Like where there'd be like,
I don't care what position that I'm in,
I don't care what position I have to
give up and just do not get into that leg
lock position and you can tell when
someone is bachelors. I was like,
I get it, I get it. But you
know man that is how it goes.
But the chaos thing,
I think he should compete more.
Yes I should compete more for sure.
But what I'm saying is compete in
Jujitsu for sure, but do some smokers,
do some more Thai, do some wrestling
matches, do some samba. You know,
get out there,
do some different competitions.
And then on top of all of that man
do some scenario based training.
You know,
do some self defense based training at
the academy where somebody pulls out the,
the, the, the knife, the
fake knife, whatever.
Would it would they call the fake knife
and like let's make sure we know how to
deal with that. Let's make sure we
not to deal with a baseball bat.
Like what are you going to do? What
are you gonna do? Cause Baseball Bat,
you know what to do with baseball back
close the distance, you know, hey that's,
that's,
that's not even really a game changer.
As long as you know what you're doing,
knife goes the distance with a knife,
now you're getting stabbed this problem.
Yeah. So you got to make distance. Yeah.
It again, men that just, that
familiarity, like once you go through it,
that's like almost night and day in
and of itself. Once you've seen it,
if you've never seen it visited,
if you seen it in once,
like first step is night and day.
So that's good that he went through this.
Really. Yeah. Yeah. And what's
the other good? Psychologically?
Nobody recognized psychological.
He recognized that he lost his mind.
What he said. He said, uh, I fear. Yeah,
I got fear. What was it in one match?
I completely lost focus and
control of my mind. So once you,
that's what you just said.
When you get that you experienced that,
that's a good thing to experience
because then you learn to recognize that
you're losing control and you're losing
your mind and you're going to, when you,
when you realize that it allows you to
start monitoring it if you've never been,
because there's people,
we'll let her listen to this right now
that have never lost their mind before.
They've never been overwhelmed by
something and just not knowing what to do.
Never been frozen.
You ever been frozen with fear frozen
with fear if never felt your fight or
flight thing engaged and when it
happens you won't know what it is. Yeah.
You want to know what it is so that
way when it happens you can go, okay,
I know what's happening right here.
I'm going to make this,
I'm going to make this decision yet.
And now you're saying
when you train boxing or
boxing? Yeah, yeah and MMA. So
when you get hit in the face,
and we talked about this before,
then you haven't really been hit
in the face before. Like that's a,
it'll throw you off. Oh, put
really Miley, it'll throw you off.
So especially, yeah, you're right.
Because when you see someone get punched
in the face and a movie and it seems
like it's doesn't really phase
him that much and they keep going,
if that's what you expect is going to
happen when you get punched in the face,
that's the wrong idea.
Because what's going to re if you've
never been punched in the face before,
when you get punched, it's
a little shocker. Yeah.
And there's pain and your eyes get blurry
and you're, you get a little flash.
I mean,
there's a lot of things that go on when
you get punched in the face once you get
used to where you're like, yeah, you can
move right through it. Exactly. Yeah.
But if you're not used to it, it's
a problem. Yeah, fully. And it's,
that's another one.
It's night and day when a guide has been
hit in the face a bunch of times and is
used to it.
And a guy who's not used to it because
you know how like you can hit a guy in a
face or get hit in the face
and there'll be like, I'm done.
Like I didn't really
expect this encounter,
this experience you don't want to get.
And then other guys,
they'll give him the face, break
their nose, break their jaw,
all this stuff in there, keep
fighting, you know, it's like Dang.
So that night and the situation,
if you're not used to it,
which is essentially the same thing
you went through, this guy went wild.
He wasn't ready for this overwhelming
experience and he lost his mind turning to
him. Yeah. So you get him the face.
Like I remember Greg punching me in my
face so hard where I don't know if he was
mad or,
or just just
Greg James fires it off.
He punched me right between the eyes,
thought he broke my face and it was the
kind of where it was a timing thing too
where I came in,
I was shooting in and right before
a level change to whatever he,
it just connected and I was like boom.
And I remember thinking,
cause I just kept going and
I remember thinking, Dang,
I'm glad I was kind of used to getting
hit in the face because that would kind
of at the very least paused me for a
long time. Like didn't he would've,
but when you imagine just that kind of
chaos and sensation that'll just stop
you. But once you're
used to it, you're good.
And this is a good point to bring up
with just with any kind of training like
leadership training,
right?
When you have leaders that haven't
been put in certain situations before,
that's why Ashland Front,
we do like role playing exercises with
people and you put people in situations
the first time you put them in
situations like dealing with a hostile
subordinate that doesn't want to do the
plan the first time they'd get put in
that scenario. They just Lou,
they just fall apart. No,
I told you to do it and here's,
I'm like, okay, let's replay that.
By the third time you're doing it,
are already handling the job,
handling the scenario infinitely better.
Infinitely better than they
did the first time. Yeah.
So it's the same with everything in life.
Like the exposure to it and the
rehearsal of it gives you such a massive
advantage that to not
rehearse and to not train is,
it's actually sad and that's actually
the national front's a great example
because that's why we're
in business because people,
people don't even know that they
should be doing this, you know, and,
and to go to a company that
has 50 100150200 leaders
that are leading teams and
they have no leadership training and
therefore we're all surprised when the
leader doesn't get the teams to do
what they're supposed to do. Well, who,
who taught him how to lead because
you just don't show, he just not,
you just don't show up to
work knowing how to lead. No,
you actually get trained to lead all these
unfamiliar micro scenarios happening.
That's, that's one of
the, I got the muster.
We'd do these little drills at the
muster and you could see people are,
are overwhelmed with the knowledge
that they gain from two or three little
scenarios that we put in front of them.
And these are common stairs
that happened all the time.
But when you watch seasoned business
leaders trying to handle a scenario that
they haven't seen before,
now they might've seen it before,
but they never actually had to
deal with it the first time.
They try and deal with it, they
fall apart. Yeah. And it's real.
I would say it takes like 10
seconds before you go, okay,
let's just stop because you've
already got this guy mad at you.
Well let's try this again because we
haven't been sued the situation before.
They never been punched in
the face before. Yeah. And
that's the problem. Yeah.
Don't let it happen. Get punched in
the face a few times to be, yeah,
you can do this. It's kind of like, I
remember when we were kids, there's this,
there's this gut, you know, like
Wrigley's chewing gum, the little packs,
four or five of them, small
little thing. And you know,
you grab one and this one kind of
sticky. Now you can say, hey, you know,
do you want one offer,
one of your friends.
So it was my brother and
he did the long story,
but he was crying from
something else who said,
and he was like crying and oh by the
way, you know, he offers me some gum.
I grabbed the gum.
It's one of those miles trap and it slaps
you and then kind of hurts when you're
a little kid anyway, and it snaps
a fan. I'm like, Dang, I never,
you know,
I see he's laughing.
He was crying from something else and
then he's laughing, cheered him up,
whatever, double leg it was up there for,
well actually, which would have made
the double lake even better nonetheless.
I had never seen that before.
Now someone offers me Wrigley's gum.
I'm aware I'm ready for that mouse trap.
Maybe the muster at may be not,
but you're grabbing by the
side of the program or the
site. Exactly right. Listen,
learn. Yeah, exactly. Right.
I don't have to take it into
her that I won't lose my mind.
Life is no different.
Next question.
I'm a chef in a large operation kitchen.
I'm second in command overseeing a large
kitchen staff, part of a five person
management team overseeing
the entire account.
Recently during my last review I was
given some advice by my boss and his boss.
I'm unsure about my last two annual
reviews have gone very well and I'm on the
rise in the company.
However,
they said if it was important
for me to get or heat.
However they said it was important for
me to give up some of my kitchen dog
mentality
and work to showcase my artistic side
and embrace more of a star role in the
spotlight, get out of the kitchen
a bit more, gain more exposure.
Specifically with our
high profile clients.
While they appreciate their sentiment
and respect their big management skills.
Their style isn't one I strive to emulate
or feel would work for me and the way
I operate, I have always approached my
work is more of a craft than an art.
And I've always like being a trench,
dug with my team,
my team responds to it and I get results
for the business and I feel the results
should speak for themselves. It is
propelled my career rapidly thus far.
So why would I want to change
and be something I'm not?
Should I heed their advice or stick to
what I do best and keep getting asked.
Great on my terms
was just funny how,
how that last statement
is framed, right? Yeah.
Should I stick to what I do best and
keep getting after it as if to say,
if you say no,
you should not stick to what you do best
and you should not get after it. Right.
That's, that's the frame
there. And actually this guy,
I answered the question real tersely.
I think this came through Facebook
messages that, you know, I said, uh,
sounds like you found a comfortable zone
for yourself and you want to stay in
their little cold butter and
responds. And he's like, ah,
I knew it because as we know in a
comfort zone there was no growth in the
comfort zone. So it's interesting
this guy is actually getting some,
some good solid and straight forward
advice from up the chain of command.
Uh,
plus I think if they have him as more of
a personality than the restaurant will
do better and they're trying to build
their reputation and your reputation at
the same time. And that seems
pretty reasonable to me. Right?
And I'm not real familiar
with the restaurant business,
but I'm familiar enough to know if you've
got a good reputation with the staff
that works at the restaurant.
It brings in more people,
like there's no doubt about
it, the, the relationship,
just like any other business,
the relationships that you build
with the customers strengthens them,
strengthens that relationship and makes
them want to come back for more. Right?
That's the way it works. And so
for them to say to you, hey man,
hey, you know you're a good cook. We
get that, but we need a little bit more.
We want a little bit more chef. We
need somebody that has, yeah, chef.
Sorry. You're, yeah, yeah.
Sorry. You're a good chef. Well,
actually what I think I might've
actually purposely said that like, hey,
you're doing a good job
in the kitchen as a cook.
We don't need someone that's
just cooking the food.
We need a chef with a reputation
with a personality. Right.
There's a difference there,
right? Yes sir. So it was
called out for reason. Gotcha.
He's happy. And you can see
like kitchen dog. Yeah. He's
proud of that, right? Yeah.
And I get that, man. I get that. I
get that. Like you're one of the boys,
you're back in the, in
the grind. Well let me,
let me ask you this or let
me make this statement.
Guess what you have to do as a seal, as
a CEO leader, guess what you have to do?
You have to build relationships.
You have to make your
commanding officer trust you.
You have to build
relationships with the army.
You have to build relationships with
the Marine Corps. You have to end.
In order to do that,
you have to like raise your hand.
You have to call a little bit of attention
to yourself and raise your hand and
say, Hey, this is who I am. You
have to take, this is who I am. You.
You have to actually have to step into
the spotlight a little bit so that you
can let people know who you are.
Because if people don't know who you are,
how do you have a relationship with him?
And if you don't have relationship with
people, how can they trust you? So, so
that's part of it, right? That's part
of what they're asking you to do. Now,
in all seriousness, if, if you
really don't want to do it,
well then you can keep being the guy
that's in the back. And guess what?
You're going to be mad in six months
when some other chef gets hired for a
different shift and all of a sudden he's
out making friends with everyone and he
gets promoted. And why does he get
promoted? Well, look what the guy's doing,
but he's not as good as,
he's not as good as a cook as I am.
Guess what?
They don't really care.
Being making the food is only
part of what they want you to do.
Just like being a seal. Doing, doing
missions is only part of what they,
what you need to do to do the mission.
You can't just be tactically sound.
You've got to have the relationships
built so you can work in the battlespace
that's owned by a conventional commander.
You got to have the
relationship that you can get.
Your mission's approved up the chain of
command on the special operations side.
How do you do that? You build,
you go out, you talk to people,
you get out of your comfort zone.
It's a weird thing, you know,
I'm kind of, I'm kind of
antisocial, right? Like
if you don't know me,
we're not going to have a conversation.
You know? Like we're not having
a car. Like it's not, I'm not,
I'm not walking up and talking
to you if I don't know you.
I'm not walking up and saying hi to you.
It's not happening.
It's not my personality. If
you say hi to me, I'll say hi.
I'm not disrespectful,
I'm not rude,
but I'm not looking to have a bunch of
conversations with people and so that's
known to me,
but that's not okay for the
business side of my life, which is,
hey, I got to talk to people, got
to build relationships. Got It.
To had to know my commanding officer had
to know the commodore, had to know the,
the,
the conventional battalion commander
had to know the brigade commander had to
build relationships.
Could I just talk about war
with the brigade commander?
Well I could,
but what's more powerful that I talk
about war and I talk about where I'm from
or where he's from or what,
you know, other things. Yes.
Cause I want to build a
relationship with a why?
Because I'm trying to
build trust. What? Why?
Because I want him to allow me to go out
there and do things in his battle space.
So that's what they're asking you.
They're asking you to step
out of your comfort zone.
It doesn't need to become
your primary focus. No.
Should you try and step out of the
comfort zone if you want to grow,
if you want to have more opportunity,
I would give it a try.
I would give it a try. If
not, you know, like I said,
if you hate it and you feel like you're
not being true to your true self,
that's okay.
Maybe your true self is meant to be the
one that's back not getting promoted.
Yeah. They need somebody
to do that. It's not you.
It might be somebody else.
Yeah.
Another one of those tough questions
where people, you know, hit me with like,
should I just be,
shall be loyal to myself because the
obvious answer that everyone wants to hear
is like, yeah, dude, two
most important things. You've
got to be loyal to yourself.
That's the most important thing.
Okay. If that's what your priority is,
then that's the most important
thing. But guess what? Who Does? Uh,
who can take care of the other
kitchen dogs that respect you so much?
Who can take better care of them than
you can? Because if you get promoted,
if you don't get promoted and,
and Johnny Glamour boy gets
promoted because he likes
to go out and Schmooze the
clients and now he gets
promoted and you're,
and now who's going to take care of the
kitchen dogs on his, on his time, right?
Not Him. He doesn't care. He's got,
he got promoted not for
taking care of his guys.
He got promoted because he smooths the
clients. Play the game a little bit.
It's weird menu explaining that and
it's like, yeah, makes complete sense.
I'm thinking of it in terms
of like being a, I dunno,
I guess it applies to any relationship
you have. So, so like let's say, okay,
you have a wife, right? You're,
you're buried, whatever.
And so your wife wants to go to,
hypothetically wife wants to
go to, I dunno, Vermont, right?
And you're like, hey, I
don't like Vermont, you know,
go to Vermont to whatever.
But your wife say,
Hey,
I want you to come because I like spending
time with you and in all this stuff.
And as a husband, like, hey, I
like spending time with Youtube,
why can't we do something that I
specifically like to do whatever.
And it has to do so a lot of times with
like maybe your wife's friends or the
enlarged. So I don't want to
hang with the only hang you,
but I want to hang with them.
And the went from to hang with you
with the friends and all this stuff or
whatever. But a lot of the time, my case,
it might've been me just sticking
in my little comfort zone, you know,
like the people that I like
to hang out with there,
there's like set stuff that I know
they're into and I know that they like to
talk about it and all this stuff.
And I'm essentially rejecting
being open to new or other stuff.
You know, that's, you know, this kind
of like a situation. But in a way,
I'm kind of doing what this,
what this guy is implying,
where it's like I'm gonna say true to
myself and my interest in all this stuff.
I love my wife hundred percent
that has nothing to do with it.
Vermont has nothing to do with
me and my wife, you know, but
why shouldn't I step outside of
my comfort zone and you know,
tried to accommodate
her wishes in this way.
It's not a make or break a relationship
or nothing like that. But if I do that,
if I just exercise the ability to be open,
I become more valuable of a husband,
more valuable.
I offer more value in the
relationship and as a person.
So same exact thing when
you're explaining this,
when this guy's explaining where he's
awesome as a chef in the back doing the,
you know, doing his deal, doing what
he does best, awesome. But they,
and these guys see it, his severe, see
it obviously, where they're like, hey,
we want you to do this more stuff.
Even cause you're awesome in men.
Imagine if you had this,
this more stuff.
You know how valuable
you would be as a Xyz,
whatever the position is in this case
as the ship and to reject that is
essentially to say, you know what, I,
I don't want to be more valuable as a
chef or I don't want to be more valuable
as a husband.
I prefer to stick with my current value.
I don't want to upgrade.
There you go.
I refuse to upgrade some
staying true to myself.
Just saying anyway.
I mean,
can you cross the line and get to a
point where you make yourself sick cause
you've done. Yeah. Then you've gone too
far. That's the dichotomy of leadership.
Like, yeah, if you become just a
disgusting Sycophant, then guess
what? That's not good. Yeah,
so I'm not talking about that.
Yeah.
Well not talking about leaving your
values and abandoning your values,
that's not what I'm talking about.
I'm talking about playing the game a
little bit. There's a big difference.
Step outside of the comfort zone. Play
the game a little bit. At the very least,
do it with an open mind. See how
you like it. What if you were like,
you got real good at that. You know
how like public speaking for example,
where I'm no exception,
a lot of people didn't like
public speaking even though
they might have a lot to
say or whatever. You know like
some people like their their spot,
but to I don't want to get up on stage
and nothing like that. That's dumb.
I'm going to, I'm not a star, I don't want
the limelight on me and all this stuff.
Then they do it one time and they,
and they offer like just so much value
doing it and then they get used to it and
then all of a sudden they stay
kind of like it. You know?
It could be one of those
deals. Could, could be.
You never know until you try it.
Next question.
Two of my bosses have told me,
I don't like Jocko.
Interesting,
interesting concept.
Without giving any value, valid
reasons. Their ego is in the way.
How do I flank them to
help them see the path?
My belief is that they're
afraid of the truth and they,
they're afraid of the truth. They see in
extreme ownership. Okay. So, uh, yeah,
I mean, clearly ego could be a
problem here as a leader, you know,
who wants to constantly be compared
to some other leader, right?
You know, if you were teaching to
Jujitsu class tickets, like, Whoa,
the way that you, the way that
Dean teaches this, you know,
that that would make you mad afterwards.
So that could be part of the problem. Oh,
that's dead.
That's definitely,
that's way up there on the
list of possible things.
Could be the military flavor,
right? Some people don't like the military
flavor of thing, so that's, that's okay.
It's,
it's
can turn some people off. They don't
want to hear about it. That's fine. Uh,
the reality is he,
here's,
but here's the reality of the situation.
Okay.
What is there to not like about
the things that I talk about?
Right? So let's say, you know what,
I don't like people taking ownership.
I want everyone to make excuses and
blame each other, right? It doesn't,
it doesn't even make sense.
You know, instead of we,
I don't want to hear
about this cover move.
I want everyone to ignore each other
and get worry about themselves. Right.
Like that, that makes no
sense whatsoever. You know,
if keeping things simple,
I don't want it, hey look,
I don't want to keep things simple.
I want everything to be so complicated,
but no one knows what's going on. Right?
Like these things that they make. No,
there's no human being,
no one in a leadership position that
would want everyone or that would,
that would go against what
these simple principles. So
how do you fix it then? Right. What's
the problem? Uh, one, here's a couple of,
and actually this was a Twitter thing and
a bunch of people gave great responses
on Twitter after I kind of
highlighted it. Uh, one,
one of them and my, my actual responses
like, hey, just don't, you know,
stop using my name. You know, stop
saying, well [inaudible] was it?
Cause you can't even imagine how annoying
that must be. Right? Well, Jack was in,
you know, when you're in a
leadership position, you know,
it's like that's going to really
great on somebody. So, so,
so throw that out the window.
Don't pit it as me,
Jocko against what your bosses
are saying. No, don't do that.
You've set up an adversarial relationship
with them and you've set up or an
advert adversary relationship with me.
And I've never even met these people
before. I don't even know who they are,
even know what business they're in.
But what you've done by constantly harping
on it as you've pissed them off and
now they're saying, dude, quit
talking about Daca. We don't care.
Because also the way that he's in
just the way he's being offensive in
approaching these things means that he
has a little more listening and growing
to do. Because if you really want
to approach your boss or you know,
he asked about flanking as possible, the
way you find someone isn't going, hey,
the wedge Alcoa's says you should
do this. Like, no, that's not good.
So let the principals work in another,
another person pointed out, you know,
um, hey, don't, hey,
stop trying to impose your things on them.
Like take extreme ownership. How's that
sound? You step up and start leading.
You do your thing, you
perform well. Quit talking.
Quit trying to force these things down
people's throats and give them space.
Give them room and then they'll
recognize that you're doing a good job.
If you label it with something
that you know they don't like,
well then they're going not going
to like it. No matter what you do,
no matter what you do,
that's going to be problematic.
Don't bludgeon them with with will. You
know I've, this is blah, blah, blah. No,
don't do that. Take Let.
Bring your ego in check.
How's that sound for your
ego in check a little bit.
Make the ideas that you're
talking about their ideas.
Get them to talk about
ownership, you know, get them.
Maybe they call it something else
other than extreme ownership.
Maybe they call it, you know,
a personal accountability.
Okay, awesome. That's great.
Yeah, I really liked that. I really
like what you've come up with, boss.
I'm in with.
Oh well now they're in the game and they
don't realize that you're talking about
the same thing. That's fine. Don't
they? Don't ever have to realize that.
They don't ever have to realize that.
So I mean there's some people are
some people that don't like it.
Even to the teams. There's people that
like, they didn't like me, didn't matter.
It didn't matter where, what the
principal was, didn't make no, that's,
it's like no, like, hey,
just, just, just don't,
don't attach my name to it and go
and do be a good leader. How's that?
So those are some things I think
if you live, live the principles,
act on the principles.
No one's going to be mad at you for taking
ownership and responsibility of what
you're doing. Unless you say, Ooh,
you look how I took ownership of that.
Well then you might paint yourself
into a corner where they ain't stupid,
where they end up not
accepting what you're doing.
And they'll get mad at you for
stepping on their toes out of court.
And it is also as you do this, as you take
ownership, don't rub their noses in it.
You give them credit. How
hard is that? You know,
you've come up with a solution
to a problem. Say, Hey, no,
actually I got this idea from something
I saw you doing really. Right.
That's how you, that's how you flank them.
Hey, I took ownership of this problem.
Who? Oh, really? Oh, you just go, oh, here
we go. Extreme or, no, don't say that.
Don't say that. You know?
It's like, Hey boss,
I wanted to make sure this got done
correctly. I was watching the way you did,
blah, blah, blah, blah, and you
go from there. Give them the idea.
You it makes sense it,
yeah.
I W I wonder how the boss got introduced
to the concept of Jocko for him to
eventually
hate and not like in this situation
it probably was like, you know,
multiple repetitions of
way. Yeah. Like, yeah.
You and didn't pick up the vibe.
Yeah. Which is like, hey you,
I'm dealing with someone with a big ego
and they're not going to take well to me
talking about this other guy's
leadership style, do you,
you don't want to be compared to some
other leader if you're in a leadership
position. Yeah man also is kind of the
same thing but a little bit different.
The, that thinking about
that type of scenario, men,
that's the worst.
That's like as a boss,
I would think that that'd be
really bad cause, okay, so
here, here's the situation.
So I make videos sometimes.
Right.
And so let's say I am,
and actually this is an actual thing
that actually happened where, okay,
so I made this video for this. We'll
see client and kind of take, okay.
You know, they look at it
and it's typical, you know,
they'll have some input,
maybe some information they want to add
or take or change or whatever. And then,
um, this guy said, oh yeah,
I'm not sure about this part. I showed
it to my wife and she said, you know, x,
Y, Z and x, y. And I'm thinking,
okay, I get it. Like, okay,
you showed it to people that I understand,
but I was like, wait, wait, wait.
So this is the video made for
you and your deal kind of thing.
And you went and showed your wife and
then now she has some kind of input.
She's not part of this deal.
You know,
now you're like citing your wife's
critique and like all this stuff and it
doesn't make sense by the way, as far as
what we've discussed and all this stuff.
Right. So the, so the wife is now,
I kind of have this kind
of disdain for the wife.
I don't know the way if at all by the way.
So I'm like,
I'm just not feeling the wife anymore.
Ego got in the way a little bit and it's,
and it's natural is what I'm saying
where it's Kinda like I thought we were
doing this video kind of together and
I'll just do this for you and you give me
the input and when now you
involve your wife in it,
who threw the whole thing off?
Cause she's not even part of
this little thing right now.
Really hard to put your ego in check.
It's really hard to put your ego in
check and actually listened to what the
critique points are. It's he, it's
hard for anyone to do that, you know?
And so when it happens,
you have to go, okay,
that's my ego and you need to put it
aside. Yeah. So consider the situation.
If the guy would have just said,
don't say I showed it to my wife
and she said this, don't say,
if he would've said, well I was thinking
about this, which is, what do I said?
You know, in their whatever else
finger about this, what does they,
it woulda got delivered way better.
Way Easier. Same thing with here,
your situation. If someone's saying,
I don't know, let's say for example,
it's a fireman, there's a farm and
you know the, the bosses saying, Hey,
we should do this and do that.
And then this guy had just out of the
blue said so well Jocko says is like,
who the hell is jobs?
I don't remember hiring Jocko who did it,
who is this guy and what's
he talking about? Cool.
But Jocko has no say in this
department. It's me, it's
you. It's the team. You know,
the team that we've worked with kind of
thing. And that's kind of the feeling.
So yeah, man, don't say
Jock, lead chocolate.
I don't need the credit.
Not all.
Next question Jocko.
Please explain how working harder for
an incompetent superior helps oneself.
I feel like screw them in
whatever lightning bolt of
luck they were struck by it
again in their position.
Is that kind of like screw them and the
horse they wrote in on kind of thing? No,
he's saying screw them.
They were there.
They're in their position as superior
because they got lucky. Yeah, yeah.
I didn't get all that. Yeah. And you know,
here's the answer that I was like, okay,
so what are you gonna do then?
What are you gonna do?
Then you're going to sit around and wait
for your own bolt of lightning of luck
to hit you. Is that what you're
going to do? I don't recommend that.
Instead,
I recommend that you step up and yes,
you do work harder and you do the
best possible job that you can do.
And you take some pride in what
you're doing and how you're doing it,
and you do it better than they could,
not to rub their nose into it,
not to prove that you can do a better,
but out of professionalism.
That's why you do it. Now,
one outcome that can come from that
is they get credit for your work
and it makes y'all mad.
No,
that's actually good because if they
get credit for your work, guess what?
Work's going well,
they're going to get promoted,
okay.
And they get the recognition.
Okay, that's fine.
Okay,
but, but they know where
the actual credit goes,
even if they don't give it to you.
Okay?
Even if they don't give it to you,
they know it.
Even if they're the
type of person you'd go,
that doesn't even realize
that you're like, Oh wow,
I did all that work and he's
taken all the credit for it.
They didn't even know that I made this
happen or he doesn't even know that he,
that I made this happen.
They know. They know.
So as long as you can keep your ego
in check and you can let them have the
credit, eventually they get
promoted, the team's doing well,
you'll look good, you'll get
promoted. You're life is easy,
you're gaining experience,
you've got a good reputation.
Like everything is going in your
direction. And, and by the way,
when that incompetent
person does get promoted,
who do they usually recommend
that fills their spot?
You cause you're the one that got
them promoted. They're stoked on that.
Now you become a superstar.
That's great.
Eventually they're going to get found out.
By the way,
like someone in competency can't be hidden
forever and eventually someone says,
wait a second, you didn't even
know how to do this. That was,
that was echo Charles that was doing
this this whole time. Yeah. Okay. Okay,
well we're going to promote echo.
You're out of here. That that'll happen.
And when that happens,
we in competency gets found out,
then you will get the recognition
you deserve because people said, oh,
that wasn't Jocko doing all this stuff.
This was echo. They go, oh Jocko,
you're done. So that, so
that's something had happened.
Or another outcome that can happen is
that they give you the credit that that
you're do,
which is great and you still get
promoted and you may get promoted above,
which is fine too. Oh and or they
might get promoted, which is fine.
Stop worrying about it.
So those two things,
if you do a good job, eventually
something good is going to come out of it.
Whether it's they get,
whether it's you both get promoted,
whether it's they get promoted above you,
whether it's you get promoted above that,
it doesn't matter all those outcomes.
Or maybe it's just the team continues to
do well and your job is stress free and
you continue to perform.
And, and the, the, the,
the division that you're in grows and
you get a chance to promote because
everyone's getting promoted. It's
like all good, all good stuff.
Or you can be angry.
And you can be frustrated and you can
blame your own bad luck and you can not
work hard and you can not do a good job
and you can be recognized as a slacker
and you can get blamed by the incompetent
competent boss when things do fall
short, because that's what the incompetent
boss does. He doesn't step up and say,
go ownership of it. He says, no, you
know what? I would've done a better job,
but echo was slacking. That's
the problem. Now Aco gets fired.
Okay.
And,
and guess what?
Someone we hire someone else to come
in and they start doing a good job.
That boss still going to look good.
I still get promoted.
Just that you lost your
job and by the way,
you lost her job with a bad reputation.
Now you can't even get a
recommendation for a new job.
So you lose. That's what's
going to happen. Yeah.
So step up, do your best.
It'll pay off in the long run.
Yeah. It's funny how like
it's one of those things
where if you can just flip the
switch and see that. Just that one
little thing, and it's funny though too,
the way.
That's the way these questions are framed.
You know what they want to hear
is like, no, you know what?
If you've got an incompetent
boss, you don't help him
out. You Bet I'm Berg. Yeah,
that's what you do. That's what
people want to hear. But it's,
it's the easy answer and it's not the
smart answer and it's a short term answer,
not a long term answer. You make your boss
look great. How's that? That's my goal.
I want to make my boss look great.
You know there,
there was a little tell in the,
in the question too,
I'm no expert obviously, but
lightning bolt of lock La. Yeah.
So you know the whole deal, and this
is even, you can be an normal person.
They recognize this like
people who are bitter.
I'm not saying the asker of this
question has been, I'm not saying that,
I'm saying this is the external scenario,
but you know how if you get a bitter
person who's just been in life,
maybe not doing as well in life
as they had hoped or whatever,
you'll probability wise you'll probably
encounter them from time to time.
No more saying how the guy
who is successful is lucky.
They're lucky, big headache given to
them like all this, all this other stuff.
Me, I'm not lucky with whatever, but
it's always the sixth successful guys.
Lucky always.
Yeah.
They attribute other people's
success to luck to look for sure.
So the lightning bolt
of luck in screw them,
you know kind of thing. Just that
is indicative. I'm not saying it is,
I'm not saying it is or isn't as
far as this particular person,
but it tends to be like
that. And again, like that,
just that switch if you can like turn
on the switch and just look at it.
Just how you said, yeah, it's not
intuitive.
I get it man.
Because it's like I was in that situation
where like literally I was doing the
work.
So think about this.
You just said you're in this situation.
Almost everybody has been in this
situation and here's the difference.
If you don't flip that switch
and you're in this situation,
your whole wife goes down in the other
direction. Yeah, that's a real problem.
That's why you meet people. You know, this
is a a thing I think about a lot. You,
you don't know you, you know people in
your life, they're bad asses, but they,
but they're not going anywhere. Like,
like you look at it and you go, man,
this guy is smarter than me and,
and by better athlete than me
and a better speaker than me,
but they're not going anywhere.
And you know why?
It's because at some point in their life,
instead of saying, Oh wow, that guy's,
that guy's lucky. That's what they do at
some point their life instead of saying,
hey, that person worked to get in that
situation and I should do the same.
Instead of saying that, they
say, oh, that person got lucky.
That's why they're there.
And I'm down here. Yeah.
You can't make the upward climb if
you don't say, you know what? Hey,
that person might be a little luck there.
But guess what?
They're obviously working hard.
They're obviously doing something right
because I'm down here and there up there.
How do I get up there?
Yeah.
The answer to get up there
as not by tearing them down.
The answer to get up there is
by working hard. Yeah. Make them
good that the line you said,
um,
what, and so what are you
going to do about it? And yeah,
what are they going to do?
But that's the switch right there.
Cause I mean you deal with it with kids
obviously they have some young kids and
you know, same thing like oh this is how
it is or this happened or, or whatever,
spilt milk out and whatever.
And you know, the kid's crying.
It's all this stuff's like, okay, so
what are you going to do about it?
So you can cry.
You totally can.
And you can complain about how junk that
is that the mill that spill to your toy
broke or whatever the situation.
Yeah, cause that's all true.
It's absolutely true and
good. You can cry, whatever,
but if that's what you're going
to do about it, then okay,
then that's what it's going to be
and that's all it's going to be.
You're going to continue to cry and
you'll probably continue to cry next time.
It happens too. Or you clean up the milk,
you fix your toy, whatever, you know,
whatever. What are you going to do about
it? That's the whole thing. You know?
What are you gonna do about it? It's
interesting too. There's like a,
just a known,
the right answer seems really obvious
when we talk about it right now,
but not many people see that right answer.
No.
Most people want to just be mad at their
boss and be frustrated and undermine
them and not work hard so that they don't
get any shine on them. It's like, okay,
great. That's you putting yourself
in that barrel to, yeah, don't do it.
It's crazy, man. Actually, I
shouldn't say it's crazy. It's,
it makes sense. I mean, I
felt that before 100% yeah.
Oh for sure. For sure. Next question.
Can you be default aggressive
and relaxed in Jujitsu?
Okay.
Yeah.
This seems like two opposing things
that you can't do at the same time,
but the actual fact is yes,
you can and you should.
So you want your maneuvers
to be aggressive,
but you don't want to be using a bunch
of strength to execute the maneuvers,
right?
You want to aggressively escape your
opponent's position before your opponent
gets settled. Therefore, you don't have
to use strength. You can use relax it.
You can relax, you can,
you can be proactive.
Same thing with defending
a a submission attempt.
You want to sub defend that submission
attempt aggressively before the
submission attempt gets settled in.
You want to move aggressively.
Again,
I'm not talking about
strength and spasming,
I'm talking about moving aggressively
before your opponent moves and get ahead
of them on their Ooda loop. When you
get ahead of them on their Ooda loop,
they're going to have issues
with you and so yeah, absolutely.
You can be default aggressive and at
the same time you can be relaxed and you
should.
That should be your goal.
Do you sometimes have to use strength
in Jujitsu? Yes you do. Yes you do.
Sometimes you got a power out
or something. Why did you,
the reason you had to
power out of something,
it's because you were too late because
you weren't moving aggressively enough.
You want to move in quickly enough
and so then you've got to power out of
something kind. Call those hands,
claw that guillotine off your neck.
Do you know what I'm saying? You want
to get a gauge on what some of them,
they're clawing your fingers
away from their neck. Yes.
Yeah. So when that happens,
that person was late and and now they're
clawing. They're resorting to strength.
There were resorting to panic, clawing
at your fingers. Sometimes it doesn't.
It usually doesn't even matter. They
can claw. It doesn't matter. You good?
I like that sense of panic that I
feel when they're clawing. Yeah,
I'm sure you do. You really like it a
lot. So that's what, that's what it is.
And by the way, this is true in
life as well, right? Like if,
if you are maneuvering correctly,
correctly as a leader,
you don't have to get aggressive at
people because they're doing what they're
supposed to be doing. You don't have
to be, you shouldn't have to yell.
If you have to yell as a boss, guess
what? Your, your intent wasn't followed.
Your plan wasn't understood.
There's so many mistakes that you made.
If you're yelling as a leader,
do you never have the oh yeah.
So sometimes you can yell cause you've
got gotta make sure you can get that
emotional point across.
Sometimes you've got to make sure that
someone really like someone doesn't seem
to realize that the mistake that they
made is severe enough that it warrants a
yelling and therefore it doesn't matter
to them because their dad yelled at them
their whole life. What? So
if you're not yelling, they
don't get it. So can you can,
can you run into that cake
problem? Occasionally,
occasionally. Very occasionally.
Very.
Very rarely should you run
into that situation because
if you're doing the right
job,
being default aggressive as a leader,
you should be in situations where you
never have to yell because your people,
because your people understand what it
is that they're supposed to be doing.
They understand why they're to be doing
it. They understand what the plan is,
they understand what the contingencies
ward, they understand what the,
what the intent that you had was.
They understand this way that this
fits strategically into the situation.
They understand all those things and
if they understand all those things,
then they're going to do the right thing.
And if they don't,
if they understand all those things
and they still do something that that
doesn't make sense, we'll meet. Maybe
they do deserve, get yelled at. But again,
all the first person that I
check is myself and say, well,
I obviously I to make this clear enough.
Hmm. So yes, relax harder.
So yelling is to leading as using
strength is to Jujitsu somewhat.
You got to do it every once in a while.
Every once in a while. Or if you lay,
maybe you lacked on your
technique earlier, you got
to kind of make up a little,
but think about this, you hurt
your stamina. Strength. Right.
And when I yell at you because something
went wrong and you're my subordinate
when I yell at you,
I pay a little price for that too.
Cause I better be important and I better
really think about it cause I didn't do
anything to build our relationship in a
positive manner by yelling at you. Right.
Didn't do anything.
Yeah.
Just like you didn't improve your
Jujitsu technique or knowledge in east or
really you, I guess you improved
your situation for a moment. Right?
Cause you escaped,
but now you're more tired.
Just like if I yelled at you to do
something and you did it cause you real,
you know, you were like, okay, well fine.
I want to get yelled at anymore so I'm
just gonna do this thing that he told me
to do that it's temporary.
The temporary fix.
It's a temporary fix. Yeah. You
know how like JP will say, um,
aggressive, it isn't, or do you felt
aggressive isn't towards people.
It's towards making things happen. So
like so when do you do it? The same thing.
So it's like I don't aggressively like
it's and it in a way you kind of can
narrow it down to the timing thing.
It's like it's like it's either taking
action or hesitating kind of thing.
So you just don't really hesitate.
You can lay back if that's part of
the strategy and stuff like that.
You can relax when it's
part of the strategy,
but it's about making things happen.
Like what are you trying to
make things happen timing wise.
So you know how like you have to think.
Tim Ferriss asked what is the disrespect?
Remember he asked me that, what's the
disrespect? Oh it's a Jujitsu move.
I'll go past your do that you made,
but you made up the terminology as well.
So the disrespect is basically when a
guy pulls guard or you're in a guard
scenario, it's actually not
even the guard scenario yet.
It's like you essentially treat that
person like they don't even have a guard.
The guard doesn't even exist. That's how
little respect you have for the garden.
And then you just pass.
But when you kind of think about it,
when I think about it,
when you've done it to me,
the times you have it is literally that.
So before I can establish any kind
of position to establish guard,
you're just just, yeah, you're a
pass it, you're done. You know,
you don't even consider the guard.
You know what's weird is,
is where people get confused on
this though, is they think, Oh sir,
you're saying move faster. Yeah,
right. That's the weird thing. It is.
It's not. It's a, I'm sure I'll
think of this at a later time,
but it's not about moving faster.
It's moving more aggressively.
Right?
It's not faster.
It's like being proactive and being
aggressive and shutting down the situation
before it,
before it even becomes the situation that
you'd know what's going to become. Yup.
So if you take, like you said, like,
like if you take a taking action
and hesitation, you take those two.
It's basically you're narrowing the
hesitation down to zero, if possible.
Literally what it is. Yeah, just take
action. And again, you can relax,
you can wait, but it's not
hesitation waiting. It's waiting.
It's like one more like being patient
or waiting for a very specific reason.
You can do all those things,
but there's no hesitation.
That's what I think that is.
And then obviously it's going to vary
from case to hear over and over and over
again in combat leadership philosophies
like doing something now is better than
waiting, doing, doing something,
doing something that's pretty good right
now is infinitely better than doing
something that's great in two days.
Yeah. Good plan. No better than a great,
really aggressive. Make something
happen like that is so important.
Can you overdo it?
Yes you can.
Can you make stupid decisions
because you rushed it. Yes you can.
Is there a dichotomy in this?
Absolutely. There is due. That's,
there's a dichotomy and every part of
it, so, and every type of leadership.
There's a dichotomy in Jujitsu,
right?
There's a doctor because if
I just rushed to a situation,
well that might be the situation
that you want to be to rush to.
You gave me the opening, the trap,
the trap. So it's like, you know,
when you're helping your friend
move and then you get like three,
four other friends, you
know, and everyone's waiting
around to be like, okay,
where do we start? Okay, where do
we put, you know, where do we start?
Who starting first kind of thing.
The default aggressive guy.
He's just going to start moving
stuff. And that seemed like, okay,
that's like a little lighthearted
scenario, but by that's real.
That's when I would run into it.
You don't want to,
there's a bunch of people and we're
all capable of making the decision.
It kind of paralyzes everyone
because this is so true.
That scenario that you're talking about,
it happens over and over and
over again in the business world.
It happens over and over
again on the battlefield.
What happens on the training field
where there's a bunch of people,
no one's taking leadership positions.
Yeah.
Like you're all it takes is
someone to say, Hey, we're
moving this over here. Yeah.
They put all this to get all this
stuff off the truck right now. Boom.
All right guys. We're like, okay,
cool. Well we'll make it happen. Yeah.
Like you're a oil rig scenario.
The main exact same thing. Yeah.
And if your default aggressive
meaning that's your default,
that's the, that's your zero,
you'd hear that hundred percent.
Then you're just handling business your
whole life till you take it too far and
you're trying to run stuff that other
people might have a better vision of what
to do. Like if I might be, I,
if I'm only moving for the first time
ever on our moving team and I come in,
I'm like hey guess what?
Hey we're going to start getting this
the heavy stuff and you're like hey
actually that's not a good idea.
Yeah we should do this.
We should get this stuff
in here, the truck first or
whatever. Right. Cause you've
been doing it longer so even though
it's got to be your default mode again,
there's a dichotomy you can push it too
far. Yeah. Got to keep your eyes open.
That's the question.
Let's do one more Jocko.
How do self awareness,
self assessment and self improvement
begin and how do they continue over time?
Well,
they're all tied together and
it starts with being self aware,
with being able to detach.
Because if you,
if you cannot detach from yourself
then you can't see yourself.
Yeah.
And so people ask,
how do you detach from yourself?
How do you learn to do that in a good
drill for this is try to imagine the way
other people see you and what
other people are thinking of you
in one place where this happens,
and it definitely happened to me is
when I started getting put in charge of
things, I started thinking about
other people's perspectives.
What are they seeing?
Yeah.
If you're in charge,
then what are your subordinates see you
do? What are your subordinates here?
You say,
what kind of representation
are they receiving?
And if you work for someone else,
it's the same questions.
What does the boss see me do?
What does the boss here me say?
What kind of representation
am I making of myself?
To my boss?
And then you start thinking about what
are your friends and family think?
What do they see?
What do they hear?
And so the question becomes how
well do you represent yourself?
What shortfalls do you have?
Now when you first start looking,
it's like you're looking
at an overgrown lawn.
There are some big obvious problems.
So you do a broad,
just kind of general cut of the grass.
You fix some of the big easy
problems that are obvious.
Once you've done that,
once you've gotten rid of some
of those big obvious problems,
you notice some more detailed
problems. See? Then you handle them.
And once you've got those handled, you
see even smaller and more detailed issue.
So you start trying to fix them.
Okay?
And that's what you do with yourself.
You continually detach and then you look
and then you refine and then you detach
and then you look and then you refine
and then you detach and then you look and
then you refine.
That's what you do.
Yeah.
That's how you get better.
And that process doesn't stop.
It can't stop because
if you stop refining,
then
yeah,
then the weeds grow back in.
The next thing you know,
you can't see yourself anymore
there when you can't see yourself anymore.
When you stop looking at user yourself,
then you accept,
yeah,
you accept anything
that's wrong.
Don't accept the faults. Don't give
yourself the benefit of the doubt.
You've got to be your own harshest critic.
It hold the line
and don't let
go.
Yeah,
and I think that's all
I've got for tonight.
So
Echo Charles,
speaking of improving ourselves,
sure.
Have any recommendations as to how we
might be able to prove ourselves a little
bit. Sure. Improve and maintain,
improve, maintain improvement. Well,
something like that I
would recommend. Okay.
Let's start with the workout,
right?
We're keyed out is established and known,
well known by the way to be one of the
only things that you can do that all
affect every other part of
your life in a good way.
It's also one of those things that,
well, more health, if you lose that,
you lose everything.
It's one of those things for why do some
of us not regarded in that way 100% of
the time? Why is, why do people
not have time to exercise?
Lack of discipline. We, yeah, possibly.
It might be that short term payoff thing.
You,
it's natural to seek short term path.
It's natural.
I think that's it because again,
you lose your health,
you lose everything straight up.
So why wouldn't health be
first on the priority list?
I don't have time to exercise.
No, you have time to exercise.
You might not have time to the
rest of the stuff in life. Really.
That's how it should
be, right? Nonetheless,
when you're exercising your
joints degenerate, the,
don't worry about that even because
chocolate supplements, Jocko supplements,
Jocko,
Super Krill oil.
This is Omega threes for your joints for
a lot of other stuff too, by the way.
Praying skin, skin tone, that's
like a supplemental thing,
but it is good for it nonetheless.
That's a fact.
And another one called Jocko
joint warfare. So your joints,
when you start to lose the
functionality of your joints,
not only does it make workouts,
less desirable,
less fun, effective, less fun,
less everything it can,
it can jam up your health physically.
You can be less capable.
So you want to maintain your joints.
I didn't know this, but now that I do,
I'm never looking back. Jocko
Supergirl, take that and joint warfare,
maintain the joints.
Maintain joint health every single day.
Get the subscription so you don't run out.
That's what I say straight up.
Like there's a panic mode if you run out.
Yeah,
and you don't want that panic mode.
You don't even need that panic mode.
You didn't need that in your life even.
So why even bother?
So get the subscription. Do the recurring
one every month, every two months,
however often you take them depending,
you know how, how nuts you want to get.
Also,
Jocko has a supplement.
This is for your brain
and your body all in one.
You don't have to take the pre workout
and the cognitive enhancing a nootropic.
You don't have to do that.
And where you take to just the ones called
discipline tastes good to lemon, lime
forced multiplier, what we call it.
Boom. That's a good way. Take that.
That'll help you.
That'll take help you to stay on task.
Find all the words that you're looking
for to use, you know, you don't want,
what do you call that anyway? Not Brain
fog. Brain farts. Such a lame word.
Not late. It's not a lame
word. It's a lame word when
I say it. Absent mindedness,
absent mindedness, you know it
kind of combats all that stuff.
Present mindedness is the opposite of
apps technically. Technically. Yeah.
Nonetheless. Promote that and you're
all good. It's called discipline.
Get all these ad or domain.com
the company's origin.
I say origin Maine. I just did. That's
the company. I say its origin Maine,
but it's really called origin.
It's in Maine and the website is
origin main.com also on origin.
Me, Giza in rash guards for your Jujitsu
journey. Important journey, by the way.
I would say 90 I would
say every 100% of one,
not 100% almost a hundred
percent of people who started
Jujitsu, we'll say, okay,
it's valuable whether
they stick with it or not.
You cannot deny the value of Jujitsu.
Even with the,
is that one of the questions earlier?
Boom. You inoculate yourself,
you know all these things and it,
it's weird how it affects the rest
of your life. Jujitsu's good. Yeah.
For your whole life. Yeah. None the less.
When you start, you could ask what? Gee,
should I get? Guess what origin you
get an origin g made in America.
The fabric's made in America that cotton
to make the fabric is made in America.
Grown in America.
See,
we're going all the way down to
grown you straight up from dirt,
from the dirt to the her shirt to
the guitar top to all that stuff.
They also got hoodies.
Pizza,
me some new sweat suit situation.
Oh,
joggers got him on right now she's
straight up. Most comfortable.
What does comfortable clothes,
this goes for all clothing I've ever had.
Just to Anna,
that saint alive most comfortable and for
a straight up. Is She straight up? Yeah.
How did this happen? Um, is it because
it's made in America? Maybe, maybe not,
but it does speak a lot for the quality
of origin in and of itself. And oh wait,
it's comfortable because it was made
in America. That's the question. Is it?
Or isn't it? I don't know. But it is
comfortable. 100% the most common,
most comfortable.
That's,
I know it is because you are
one that deals high and comfort.
I know my comfort levels.
Yes.
I mean comfort kind of sore a hundred
percent and this one graded off the charts
check, but he'd lay down, he'd take a
break. So I export stuff, you know, in,
in, in video editing and special effects,
you get an export. So three d stuff,
export and takes a long time. Three d
studio Max, that's what it's called.
It takes a long time. So while it
exports, you start using your computer,
doing other things, it kind of,
you know, he can jam, you'll up,
it will slow down your computer, whatever.
So, you know, I'd take a little break.
I'm gonna lay down on the
couch and called my origin.
Whole sweatsuit on gets off and I lay
down on the couch and I'm like this for
some, for some reason I'm the most
comfortable I've ever been in my,
I'll talk to Pete. You need
like a, uh, a signature series
series. Yeah, I have it
on right now. That's it.
You know you've got to do
is rename it, embroidered it
right on the side. Boom. Eq,
doctrinals cruising and comfort. Oh, big
time day. And here's the thing. Sure.
I say that and I know comfort is kind
of a subjective thing maybe. Well,
okay, I challenge anyone to, if you have
the origin sweat suit or if you get one,
get on it, lay down on your couch.
Temperature would have to be just right.
Cause if it's hot and you have a sweat
suit on and not to be as comfortable,
but keep that in mind.
I challenge you to do that report back.
If it's not the most comfortable
letting me know we're 100%
you get a taste of real American
made comfort too. By the way, also,
if you're into Jujitsu or if you're not
introduced to those in Jujitsu immersion
camp on August 26 this year it
goes to September 2nd one week,
two sessions in that one week I'm going
to cause doing going and so is Dave
Burke the real top gun?
Big Burke. Yes. We'll data,
you know why he's going.
He sounded like a good deal.
Good deal. Good deal. It does not do non
good deal things. Yeah. And good deal.
Not in the sense where it's
like a good deal like um,
you know like I'm going to get over.
It's like a good deal.
Like it's like it's good. It's a win,
win, win, win, win. It's linked. The best,
best case scenario kind of thing.
That's what a good deal Dave is all about.
That's just him. That's how he is. How he
rolls. Unless other people will be there.
What would it be there?
Hopefully JP in life. Yeah.
Well they've just got his uh,
strike another stripe on the white belts.
White belts. Yeah. So He's getting shit.
He might very well be there as you think
of your blue belt by then maybe. Sure.
At this pace keeps trying to hard. Yeah.
And well he has prior knowledge as well,
so yeah. He never know. Yeah. Yeah.
So did you see immerse yourself and
you're just the best way to learn?
In my opinion,
Marne too.
And a lot even if you've never gotten go
cause last time I even went on the side
with beginner beginners, like one
day, zero days experience, boom.
We go through through some stuff
from, and I'm not saying, look cool,
I'm such a good teacher. I'm not saying
that at all. But after like that session,
they were ready to go start rolling.
Humblebrag to say I know this because
that's what they said that not all of
them, but some of them
said that. Nonetheless.
I'm saying there's a lot of
value that you did see value.
If you've never done before, ever.
Clia or gin main.com check it out.
See if it's for you.
It's for you,
but you want to make sure and
check on that one. It's a good one.
Also, Jack was a store.
It's called Jocko store.
Go to a chocolate store.com so chocolate
store is where you can get shirts,
tee shirts just equals freedom.
Get after it.
Shirt with Jacola's big head on it.
This is good.
Just for those days that you know
you're powering through some adversity,
whatever. Got Chocolate. They were
right on your shirt. All good.
Rash guards, hoodies, patches,
beanies or either on there or they're
like literally on the way the wheels are
in motion. Man, I can't stop
it. Can't stop it right now.
I'm a lot of cool stuff on the stickers.
Some details on there. It's good. Anyway,
you don't have to get something
but gone there. Check it out.
If you'd like something,
get something really good way to support.
Also for workout gear equipment.
You want to introduce some variety
in movements in your workout.
Good place to go.
Kettlebells, battle ropes,
maces go to on it.com/jocko I want said,
well actually more than once said
that Jacqueline's workouts are boring.
They're not. I get it. They're not
boring. I re retract that statement.
They're not boring,
but if you run the risk of
your workouts being boring,
just get some new equipment.
Actually it's good because you don't,
when you get new career,
like getting even like something as simple
as a jump rope, right? When you get it,
it kind of rejuvenate a little
party. You want to, you know,
it's like when you get a new key, you
want to go to practice more. You know,
you buy some new running shoes,
he's like you,
you're kind of compelled to go running,
so you're basically still
a five year olds, whatever.
We kind of all are in a way and if you
go to [inaudible] dot com get you some
new fitness gear, it'll introduce
a little variety to your workout,
different gear, different
movement, different workout.
Keep you on the path even more and
make it interesting. Made Fun, man.
I think that's my opinion
anyway on it.com/jocko good
spot. Good way to support.
Also when you're buying any of the
books that we review on this podcast,
don't worry,
I organized them on our website,
[inaudible] dot com and the book
section just clicked through there.
Gets books through there and if you're
doing any other shop, behave, carry on,
do your shopping. Good way to swear
it. Also subscribed to the podcast.
If you haven't already on iTunes,
stitcher,
Google play and any podcast
app that you might use.
A lot of new apps. By the way, doing
podcasts. Yeah, so Skype. Good way.
Good way to support.
Also we have a youtube channel.
If you are interested in the
video version of this podcast,
subscribe to Youtube Channel.
This some serps on there along with the
video version and enhanced excerpts.
There's good deliver the
message with some, I don't know,
some cool music or something.
Anyway,
shareable stuff like so you
don't have to share a two,
three hour podcasts with someone and
then you know when you get something in
your message or inbox or
whatever and it's two hours long,
you're not watching it straight up.
In fact,
I would say even right when you pes press
play before you even get to like five
seconds and you check, see how long it
is. I think that's a normal protocol.
That is a normal protocol. You see two
hours, you're clicking right out of there.
It depends what it is and depending
on what it is and it depends.
It's not too often that you just got
a two hour block throne, you know,
sit in the sit in, sitting aside randomly,
randomly, somebody sent me a video.
I'll watch it right now.
That's not happening. Yeah.
Typically doesn't happen like that,
but three minutes,
four minutes to hang with that. Yeah.
And you made sure it with your, uh,
you know your friend. Um, yeah.
So subscribe, Youtube Channel,
good way to support also psychological
warfare. If you didn't know what that is,
is what it is.
It's an album with tracks on this album,
not music tracks.
It's chocolate tracks and these tracks.
Each track is designated engineered,
if you will,
to help you.
Me This to help me is what it is.
But it will help you
get past little moments,
a weakness that you might encounter.
I'm not saying everyone's
going to encounter it.
It won't probably will encounter it,
but that's not the point here.
The point is if you do encounter it,
you got something to help you.
You got Jocko to help you.
That's a good deal.
You want to skip the workout
or something like this.
You don't feel like working out.
That's really what it is.
You don't feel like working out. The
comfort of not working out is, is,
is distracting you is what it is.
But it seems more appealing than
the discomfort of working out.
So what it is,
and then he listened to a track.
There's certain track for that chocolate
explains to you why you shouldn't miss
a workout. Boom. Power
through the workout, your
good. And for every little weakness that
you might come across as a track for it.
It's all good. Just check
it out and think like, Dang,
is that one of my weaknesses?
Boom. Get it. You're good to go.
100% success rate in my
experience. Cool. Also, uh,
you can get Jocko white tea,
which I'm not agreeing to say anything
else about it cause I don't have to
because this is a drink that guarantees
an 8,000 pound dead lift. And so what,
what molds but more else can I say,
regardless of age,
everyone should know.
And you should be careful with that
because my eight year old daughter,
she drank some Jocko white tea,
8,000 pounds,
the get something. All right.
Books where the warrior kid,
you probably already read the first way
of the warrior kid book. If you haven't,
you can get that right now.
Uh,
you can also get where the warrior
kid to which you have not read yet.
It's called the marks mission.
You haven't ready yet cause it comes
out April 24th, it has more lessons,
life lessons,
how to be a better human being.
How's that for a good subtitle? How to
be a better human being. By the way,
my nephew, my actual nephew,
sure he likes the book to better.
He liked book one. He likes book
to better judge for yourself.
Preorder it now wherever books are sold
so that it will be at your door on April
24th when it comes out. And on top
of that, when you buy this book,
you're helping another kid see this
book, if that. Does that make sense?
Like when you buy this book, someone
else is gonna see it. It's gonna,
it's gonna elevate it and other
people are going to see it.
We're trying to spread the word.
So the more we sell out of the gate,
the more kids are going to hear
about this book and the first book.
So get a copy for your kids, your
neighbor, kids, your classroom at school,
the library.
Get as many copies as you can because
we're going to help out a lot of kids get
their lives on the path with this book.
Okay?
If you don't believe me, check out to
Aiden. He's a warrior kid. 12 years old.
Own Business.
You can get his soap,
Jocko soap from Irish oaks
ranch.com so you can stay clean,
which is important.
Also,
don't forget about discipline
equals freedom field manual.
The manual for getting after it,
which is what you should do.
It's what we should all do.
How do you do it though?
That's the question and the answer
is in the field manual. This one,
it goes freedom field manual. If you want
the audio version, it's not on audible.
It's on Amazon music.
Google play all their MP three platforms.
Also extreme ownership.
Combat leadership applied to
the battlefield to business
and to life. Number One,
New York Times best seller, number
one, Wall Street Journal Bestseller,
Amazon bestseller number one.
Why?
Because it works.
Okay,
read it and right now you can also
order the follow on book two extreme
ownership.
It's called the dichotomy of leadership.
You heard me talk a little
bit about dichotomy today
and in this book Lafe and I
go into the granular principles and
examples from the battlefield and from
business that will make you a
better leader and a better person.
All those little scenarios
we've talked about today,
if you read them and understand them,
you'll be ready for you when you
get punched in the face with them.
So preorder that book now or
you're going to have to wait.
That's what happens.
If you don't preorder,
the book comes out and you don't
get your copy. Could you hesitated,
don't hesitate.
That book comes out September 25th and
if you need intrusive leadership training
with your team, then you need echelon
front. My leadership consultant company,
it's me, Leif, Babin, JP Denelle,
Dave Burke in Foa national on front.com
or you can just visit the website
echelon front.com we solve problems
through leadership. That's all.
And of course there's the muster,
which is our leadership seminar
would only doing two years,
two of these this year,
one in Washington DC,
May 17th and 18th one in San Francisco,
October 17th and 18th these events are
well on their way to being sold out.
That's all there is to it. There's not
gonna be any other monsters this year.
Come to one of these.
We will be there.
We will not be hiding backstage. We will
be out front with you. Join us there,
registered extreme ownership.com also
there is roll call zero zero one happening
September 21st in Dallas,
Texas.
This is for current military
while enforcement, firefighters,
paramedics and other first responders.
We appreciate what it is that you all do
every day and we want to help you do it
even better.
So one day leadership seminar about
leading in a dynamic environment.
You can sign up for
that@extremeownership.com as well.
And until we do see you at the muster,
at the roll call,
if there's some reason that you want
to continue this conversation with us,
you can find us on the
interwebs at Twitter,
on Instagram,
and inside DFH people hot this,
you will find echo who is at echo,
Charles and I am at Jocko Willink.
And thanks to all the military folks
that are out there tonight at some
forgotten barricade,
waiting and ready for whatever comes
in to the police and law enforcement,
firefighters, EMT and Auger first
responders who are here on the home front.
Also waiting in also
ready for whatever comes.
Thanks to all of you and to everyone
else that is out there listening,
but not just listening,
more important, watching,
watching yourself,
observing yourself,
looking to see what you can do better
and where you can be better so that you
can become better.
Keep yourself in check,
hold the line
and get after it.
So until next time,
this is echo and Jocko out.