This is Jocko podcast number
93 with Echo Charles and me,
Jocko Willink. Good
Evening Echo. Good evening.
I was lucky and blessed to have had
the honor to serve in the United States
military during the time of war.
I fought alongside us army soldiers,
sailors,
and marines on violent battlefields,
and I saw with my own eyes,
my generation of warriors uphold the
proud tradition of the American fighting
man.
America's military has a
storied history of bravery,
ingenuity,
and grit,
but it's most important.
Tradition is the tradition of victory.
Yeah,
America's military wins wars.
It is as simple as that.
If our nation deems it morally right,
an existentially necessary,
then our military is unstoppable,
of course,
and rightfully so.
The credit for victory is often
given to the men on the front lines
to those that are taking the fight to
our nation's enemies in close combat.
That credit,
he's well deserved.
But it is not the only credit
that needs to be bestowed
because it is a simple fact that many
of the most critical victories in
America's history, we're one not
only on distant bloody battlefields,
but we're also one right here at home
in factories,
fields and farms.
You see, our ability
to produce, to design,
grow,
build,
and manufacturer has been just important
to our nation's victories as our
ability to fight.
And throughout history,
when Americans march to war,
we marched wearing boots
made by American hands
and we wore uniforms that were cut
and sewn in factories like this one,
our body armor,
helmets and weapons have been the
products of American work ethic,
skill and determination.
The best planes,
ships and vehicles in the world.
Okay,
that carry us to war and then
support us on the battlefield.
They only exist because
Americans built them.
Without the American worker,
there can be no American soldier.
So let us never forget
that the freedom we cherish
so dearly is a gift,
not only from our American
service men and women,
but it is also a gift
from the American worker.
The American worker who toils in fields,
in factories,
in ship yards and on job sites.
The American worker who gets
up day after day after day,
not only to build and create products,
but also to build our economy for
strongest economy in the world,
which gives us unmatched influence.
Yeah.
And gives our great nation the ability
to make the world a better place.
With that knowledge,
I could not be prouder to stand here
today and be apart of this opening.
I could not be prouder to be a
part of this company or a gin
which like America itself,
we'll succeed because of the
power of the American worker.
Okay.
It will succeed because of
the power of American grit
in origin.
USA will succeed because of the
unmatched power of the American dream.
And I would like to thank all of you,
especially America's workforce
for making this dream possible.
And
that is a speech
that I gave today in a
town called Farmington,
Maine and I was at the opening
of the new origin USA factory.
Now,
as I've been saying,
we are now in league with origin
USA and tonight I have with me
our new partner
and our new friend Pete Roberts,
who as you will see,
has shown some pretty incredible
fortitude in the business world and who I
believe is just getting warmed up.
So Mr Pete Roberts,
founder of origin USA,
black belt in Jujitsu by the way,
and also black belt in
making things happen.
Welcome to the show man
audit to be everything you just said, man.
Just captures everything I feel
in my heart and mind for sure.
When you're in that speech
live was phenomenal.
You know, it was awesome walking
around the factory and meeting people,
meeting the workers here. I
mean just, we came in and Jill,
she was, she was, it's a week of vacation.
What she doing? She's in here working,
she's working and you know, just,
and, and I wasn't even really,
didn't really know what I
was going to say. But after
coming up here, meeting her,
seeing the rest of the people grinding
to make this happen, um, yeah,
I realized that I realized
exactly what I was gonna say.
I was going to talk about the fact
that literally metal and a battlefield,
you're, you're, you're,
you're propelled there by American
workers and that's what this,
that's what this represents.
And uh, you know,
we'll get into how all this kind of came
together in this kind of perfect storm.
Yeah. We'll get there, but we'll
get there in a little while. Okay.
Because first we got to know a little
about a bit about you and your crazy ass,
which I say with all you know,
in the most complimentary possible way.
So tell us about just growing up,
like,
get me from like birth to high school.
What was that all about?
Absolutely.
So it all started in Sparta back,
man.
I'm for real. It's real spartan blood
for real. Yeah. No, my, my uh, what's,
what's your, what's your, because Robert's
isn't no Angelakis I'm Greek. Yeah.
Moms and ended in July.
She's great.
So she's clearly Greek cause
I miss clearly she's Greek
and she made that bottle
of off today.
No,
I thought she might pull out a spartan
sword at some point in like attack me
instead. She's pulled out a big
thing of baklava and sugarcoated it.
You just don't care. Did you feel guilty
about eating? Um, no. I wanted more. Yeah.
How do you came over here?
Like where's all the pocket?
I'm like, it's gone. And I
looked over, there's six pieces
left. I had four of them.
That's awesome. No, I'm a, I'm
a half breed. Just half Spartan,
so no, uh, yeah man.
I mean like the rest of America.
You know my,
my grandparents immigrated from Sparta,
Greece and the early 19 hundreds.
Great.
Graham lived to 105 legit credit.
Yes.
Yes. My, my semen on Jocko white tea.
Do you see as some of the shoe stuff
going on through it? She actually, she,
I know she didn't need to be, she had
the Mediterranean Diet. Nice. Hey,
when my son got to meet her, but she
lived for a long time, but awesome. Yeah.
So from a young age,
I got to see the American dream
from my mom's side of the family,
you know, and when we were kids, uh,
I was born down in Massachusetts,
Gloucester and, uh, moved up
here when I was a young kid.
My mom wants me to get myself and my
three siblings out of Massachusetts and
into the woods just cause she saw some
shifts happening. She didn't like.
So she brought us up here and
said,
make a go of it basically. And what,
what business or whatever, what to date,
what did your Oh, why
saw, I got to see my,
my family built some pretty, pretty
cool businesses down in Massachusetts.
So being an entrepreneur was
something I always admired,
uh,
but didn't realize I
wanted to do that until a
little later in life. Um,
but my, my, my family down there, uh,
my grandfather had a sub shop,
you know, supercell for those you,
I dunno,
there's,
that's the one of those things where
they call it different things across
America. A sub in New England is
the same thing as a subway sandwich.
Uh, also in New England, you call it
a grinder. Do you call it a grinder?
A grinder would be,
I think technically,
oh no, that's not a hot sandwich.
That's Hoagie. Oh yeah. Hoagies boy.
Yeah, that's another one. Uh, poor,
poor boy, another word for it.
So sub, sub. So granddad
owned a sub shop, a few,
a few subs. Very successful with
the sandwich making. Nice. Uh,
I got to see that in my
cousin's built a big multi,
multimillion dollar company and I,
and I had the watch this from a way cause
I moved up to here to Maine when I was
eight years old.
So I wasn't cultured in that
at all in the business world.
I didn't have anybody to teach me about
business and I just got to see it in and
not be directly part of it,
which I always wanted to be,
you know. Um, but I always looked
up to them and, and, and whatnot.
And both from business perspective
in athletics, you know,
they were very good athletics
and my family and, and my
uncles, cousins and stuff.
So
I looked from afar up here in Maine and
the woods and an old farm house down a
dirt road with no neighbors. Cows in a
field or, yeah, that's where I grew up.
And then high school, you, you said you
were, I know you're athletic. What do you,
how, how tall are you? Six.
Three and shrinking six,
three and shrink and man, those
and what's your Max, what's your,
what are you walking
around that right now?
Right now I can tell you
exactly to 53.0 [inaudible] yes.
But you played, what'd you
play? I uh, in, in high school,
three sport athlete in College Football,
a division one for a couple of years.
I'm not the best experience of my life
learning experience, but not the best.
What? Well, why wasn't it the
best experience in your life? Uh,
you know, I was, I was real good at
football. I was not passionate about it.
Um, but I still worked my ass off because
that's the thing. You were kind of,
even though you were this big Jock,
I was,
you are also an artistic
guy, right? Artsy fartsy.
I was at artsy fartsy kid. I got along
with everybody, the jocks, athletes,
all the artsy kids, you
know, I liked everybody.
I could appreciate everybody's
talents where you like drawing,
painting or we doing everything
above painting, painting, sculpting,
everything. Just doing everything
and tackling people. Yeah.
Getting tackled,
play tight end.
It's where you more passionate about art
than you were about football for sure.
For sure.
And so you're playing football,
like it wasn't just one of those
things where you're like, Hey,
I'm good at it and I'm
getting a scholarship,
so I'm just gonna keep
doing what I'm doing. Yeah.
So back in 1997 pair can,
the jury is back in the
day. Yeah, no, it was,
uh, back in the day, some
will remember hockey fans,
Mainz hockey team was phenomenal and
they had to Korea kids on there and they
were that that team took gifts.
And what happens when you get gifts
and people find out sanctions.
So I went into college and
they had like 10 scholarships.
So I didn't actually have a scholarship
until my second year of college.
Kind of had to prove myself
and I worked my ass off.
And then I f I fell into the politics
of college football and I saw the ugly
side of the politics of college football.
And uh,
and what are you talking about?
Cause I'm the only guy sitting at the
table that he didn't apparently play
college football is busy in the
teams after it. What does it mean?
What does that consist of?
Like you're trying to get to be in this
certain position starting or is that
what we're talking about? Let's say
like, okay. Yeah. So I was supposed to,
I was supposed to start my
I red shirted my freshman,
I was supposed to start tight end,
got into a bar brawl,
right. And during the summer and couldn't
play the first few games. And it was me.
And what, uh, one of
my friends and we were,
were both freshmen and he
was a big kid, local kid. Uh,
he ended up playing in the NFL
and we were kind of like fighting for
the first spot on the depth chart and a
depth chart if for those of you who don't
know is like kind of where you stand,
right.
You know,
and you see your name on there and you
see everyone else's name and you want to
be the top guy. Right. So break that
out for every position. Oh yeah.
Oh yeah. Every position check.
Yeah. So little pressure to perform.
And I stayed after my freshman. I put
on 27 pounds of like hard earned muscle,
no illegal substances,
squats,
Mcdonald's and squats.
Maybe like Pete,
go eat some food at
Mcdonald's. What did you, what,
what'd you go from what
weight to what weight?
And I think I came into college
at Lake too. It was like
200 in like two 25 and you
went to no less 10 maybe.
Oh Dang high school. And then uh,
yeah. And then just earned it,
earned it in the gym. I remember my tight
end coach coming up to me and saying,
Hey, you know Steve, Steve was his name.
He's like, he's out. And he's like,
you're going to be starting this first
game. And I'm like, Shit. I mean I stayed,
I stayed like work my ass off,
you know,
stay during breaks and everything
and I was a good athlete.
And what's cool is that you're actually
going as hard as you can you ask
something, you weren't even that
passionate. No, but I committed to him.
He just wanted to win. Yes.
Yeah, no, I do it. Okay.
You look at yourself in that depth chart,
even if you don't necessarily
like what you're doing,
you make the commitment and you drive.
And I didn't want to be number two,
you know, so it's super
competitive. College sports.
So anyways, my tight end
coach, like you're starting
the first game. I'm like, yes,
call all my family. Call on my
friends, tell them what's up,
make sure everyone has tickets, Yada,
Yada, Yada. Like a day before the game,
the coach comes to me and says, Pete,
I gotta talk to you. And I said,
okay. He's like, I just got in a huge
argument where the head coach and you
will not be starting in the football game.
I said, okay, why? He goes,
basically told me politics.
My friend still a friend of mine,
local kid,
he came in on a full ride,
big kid,
had probably a better frame to build on.
And basically what the, even though
maybe I, you know, it's college,
we have different gifts. The head
coach shut it down and said, nope,
he's not starting. My coach
was like, he should start.
He's performing better. You know,
he's strong in the weight room,
hang clean and 300 pounds.
The kids ready to go.
He should be starting to get a huge
fight. Almost got fired. The coach at my,
my Ted and coach,
I'm Scott fired.
He said you'll be playing
a lot in the game though.
But yeah, he'll be starting. And
guess how much playing time I saw?
None. Zero. Who?
So that was the first game of the season
you said? Yeah. And so then what happens?
You grind out the rest of the season.
Yeah man. How's your attitude?
I
worked my ass off to her. You kept
grind to earn. Did you ever start?
Here's the shitty thing. I'd
already sounded pretty sure.
It's pretty shitty. Dude.
Here's the shitty thing and I couldn't,
I'm telling you I had football,
PTSD after this.
I didn't watch football for 10 years.
They put it on television. I'd walk
out of the room, I just hang out,
do something else. They'd be watching the
games. My son loves football. My find,
my family loves football.
Couldn't do it. I had like a,
just a version to the sport
to make a long story short.
Good. Cause it's been 45 minutes.
We haven't even made it past shut.
How long has it been? Has It my, my uh,
my scholarship. The money, like, like some
of the money hits your account. Right?
And like shit didn't kick in for like
my food and everything and my, my coach,
the head coach who is a narcissistic guy,
loved coming to the weight room
and just like waving his hair.
I don't one of those guys, you
know one of those guys. Yeah,
call it from what grave and that
he's like, I'll take care of it.
That's fine. Everything's happening. Okay.
Week later coach still this, this isn't,
you know, I'm, I'm on it. I'm on it.
I'm talking with EAD. It's everything's
good. We cleaner going coach.
It's still like, man, I'm stressing. You
know, like I'm going to have to get a job.
Like what's up with this? He goes, I need
to talk to you, my office and said, okay.
I sit down in his office,
your scholarship money
is not going to kick in.
Really.
I over gave
title nine had kicked in
and he overcame it.
Now is he being truthful with me or did
he find a new recruit that was better
that he pushed me out. Who
knows? I don't know why.
Cause the kid behind me, I ended up
starting full back the next year. Right.
So maybe I got pushed out.
Maybe he over gave.
Fact of the matter is
that bastard lied to me.
It didn't fall through with his word.
And that will never happen again.
I will never surround myself with those
types of people in that lesson I carry
to this day, I think about
it a lot. It's one of those
moments in your life that kind of
changes your life. I said, you know,
I'm tell you something, I worked my
balls off for you in this program.
I'm ready and this is what I get
that excuse
out out of the office.
I grabbed my cleats and that it of my
buddy Chad Rogers and walked out the door
and didn't look back. And
that was that. So with that,
that was your sophomore year? Yeah,
that would have been my red shirt.
It was right after my wrist.
Yeah, sophomore year. Yeah. Yeah.
So what are you studying at this time?
Studying a new media,
which was really new cause he
remembered the Internet hidden like 97,
98 became hot. Right. Really
there's a date on that link.
You can call it 97. That's when it
became hot. Yeah, for sure. I think so.
Yeah, for sure. 90 said,
can you guys word for it?
That's what it was like the Internet.
Everybody need,
everybody has the aol.com Yay.
Netscape Nikki here.
But you, you could really surf the
web and websites and stuff. Yeah.
And website development and flat.
This flashy came out, macro media,
all this stuff. So anyways, I was
into that. I I uh, discovered the,
the computer thing
fell in love with design on the computer.
And although I was a sculpture major,
I used to weld up crazy looking shit.
I I actually zippered to cope post
dude I did for like my final project.
You want to know what I did?
I built this big frigging zipper on
this like canvas and I erected it and I
zippered up the gold coast.
I'm talking to like the
real zipper real different,
you know like the thing that like the
thing you hold the dude, it was this big.
I sit my, my, my, my art teacher.
They allowed you to do that.
I didn't have a choice. I just went
out and did it. Savage style. Yeah.
And what's that like street art.
I don't even know.
It was weird. I think I got some of that
frustration out for sure. Bring it up.
I have never made that
anybody that my, my my wait,
did you get graded on it? Yeah. Dude.
So how did you not tell anybody?
Because what happened was is I erected
it in the practice field and my teacher,
she walked over with me to look at
it and she looked at me and she goes,
a plus B. You did it listen like
you did in the end. It's like, Hey,
come look at this. She goes,
she looked at me, she goes,
you're saying what
she,
she didn't think it was
possible, bro. When you said
like I zippered my goal. Plus,
I'm sitting here thinking, what is
this some slang term that I don't know.
Does that mean zip hang, hanging toilet
paper off of it? Like what does this mean?
Zipper Nene zippering as what it be. I
wish I had a photo of it. I wish she did.
We didn't have digital cameras back then.
Yeah, but that teacher was cool. She was,
I don't remember her name,
but she was Korean and you left it up
for the practice guys. When they shut up,
pull it down. Uh, she, she actually told,
pulled me aside one time and she was like,
you drive this class,
how what you do and how you act.
Every one is going to follow.
Basically she was,
she was pretty cool but that is was a
gentle vengeance giving you props for that
shipper. Done zipper it, nothing's
happening. The goalpost man,
I think it was called 35 feet,
30 feet,
probably more than like the full goal
Polo. That depends on the practice field.
We helped you very fully zippered.
I am not even kidding.
I put that I put in in a,
and I,
and I built it out of like wood laminated
band saw like all the lugs and I had
to fit together perfectly in that
whole zipper part. Had the zip,
it was functional national giant.
That's good.
I told my teacher I was new, she's like
impossible to make it function. Oh, okay.
Let's see. Yeah. Like I said, it's
fortitude that I mentioned that earlier.
So, and at this time, what are you,
what's going on personally?
Personal Life, don't you?
With your high school sweetheart
at this was, yeah. Yeah. So I,
my wife Amanda, my bride, uh,
we got together and we were 16,
15,
16 through,
through a difficult situation.
We became friends and we've
been together ever since.
They were drawn together
by a difficult situation.
And you stayed together through college?
Absolutely.
And she wasn't looking at you like,
like, I need to get away from this guy.
He said, you know, she,
she's very understanding apparently.
Yeah. Yeah. You know, the corny line,
like you complete me. Like
she, I tell people like she,
if my glass is a little full,
she just dumps them out and
if it's running a little
dry, she puts it back in. So,
and she always has,
you know what I mean?
So she's brutally honest and
you know, just by my soulmate.
No, that's awesome that you
guys were, uh, you know, I,
I knew that, but it's kind of cool
that you guys together all that time
now back to your,
your major and now,
now you're not playing football and
now you're sitting there in college,
you're studying new media,
which no one knows anything about.
I didn't even know anything about it.
And we actually hired the professors,
my class really,
we committee of students and we
hire the frequent professors and so,
and so then you're learning how to do
what? Build websites, stuff like this.
You're learning things like, uh, it's
what all like the first software hit.
You had like this Maya and you
could do three d animation.
They built like toy story in
my or something you had like
flash Macromedia.
I remember the flash websites,
all the animation and stuff like
that. So we, I learned about that.
So how did you make the jump from
that to going into business in that
arena? I was good at it and
I was passionate about it.
And what happened is my sophomore year
after I got done playing football,
I went right to a marketing agency,
sold myself on the spot and got hired
on the spot and I became their lead web
developer. And you're like
19 I was 19 with blonde hair.
Nice.
Yup.
They were like, who is this kid for?
The record is when I was 19 I had blonde
hair too, the day. The similarities.
That's cool. Well a lot of
Hawaiians have blonde hair, so,
so 19 with blonde hair. Yeah, man.
I walked in and I just sold myself.
Okay,
so then how did that morph
into your own business? Yeah,
so I wasn't in a cush job. I take it
if you're the lead at 19 years old,
cush job at 200 bucks a week,
buddy raking,
which I needed was pretty legit for you
though, right? Yeah, because it was either
that or the y Ymca, you know,
and I did work at the y, but uh,
yeah,
I mean it was,
I cut my teeth at this ad agency where
I learned from this really good graphic
design of Brad who started
his career doing pay stop.
So paste up is like when
you're designing an ad,
you actually have to take an exam.
So all the little tools
you use when you're in like
Photoshop and other programs,
those are real tools,
real life tools. So he,
he takes like that knife and he cut
around the picture and then they put that
and then like the typography.
So I cut my teeth under a real designer.
Not many people get that anymore.
So I learned from a master of design.
And how long did you stay at that?
At that agency?
I was there till I was 19
2021 three years I think.
And then I, then I moved back and
I started my own company here.
And that was just
inspirado what, what, what, what
made you say, you know what?
Because you must have seen a pathway at
the agency to take over or not even take
over,
but just to move up the chain of command
and get paid more than 200 bucks a week
and all that.
I did what your brain clicked
where you're like, you know what?
I'm not working for the man. Yeah,
absolutely. I'll tell you that. I got
to go back to give you that though.
Raking blueberries
and throwing hay.
[inaudible] manual labor.
Throw Hay for a day and get a $10 bill.
You're going to work very hard not to
do that. Raking blueberries in Maine,
which is a staple of us Mainers.
Hmm. That's tough work. Your bed,
Dover in the sun and the blueberry fields.
It guess what you do for your first week.
You earn your rake,
so what does that mean?
Does a different job that they do,
the rake picking or something.
You've got a buy that you've got to
buy the right rate. You're in debt,
you're either rake and
you have to work it off.
How much you think that rate Costa,
I'm doing the math. I'm like,
[inaudible] tells me, it's like,
this is tough, but I like it.
So when I, when I walked into my
interview at this marketing agency,
this kind of a pompous,
you know, kid, I said,
he said, what do you want to do longterm,
mark? I said, starting up my own business.
I'm going to own my own business.
He goes, you don't want to do that.
You do not want to own your own business.
You know,
you don't know what it takes to survive
in a world of business. And I said,
okay,
proceed.
Then I learned and sucked the knowledge.
I could, all the knowledge I could.
I just sucked it sucked and
sucked it. And then, uh,
I moved home and started
and what city was added?
I started, well, I started the
business out of my college apartment.
It was about as big as this table. I was
the man. No, I had a little a Mac. The um,
the black one, Wall Street. How would that
one, there was a man called Wall Street.
It had like a, it was black and
had like rubber on the sides.
You know what I mean? So you
were the man yeah. That you had.
I think that thing caused me some issues
because it was very tough to have kids.
I sat that thing on my lap for hours on
end and I'm telling you something with
radiation, man. I had to practice a
lot to have kids. Practice was good,
but it got a little tough when it's like
we can't have kids. So, but uh, yeah man,
I started the business out of my
college apartment, my first insight,
new media marketing agency,
a new media company and just started
hammering and I was fearless going after
accounts and clients,
you know.
And two years later I
find myself in Park City,
Utah sitting in the front of the
president of Rossignol, quicksilver,
selling them an idea like bill gates.
I didn't exist yet.
And telling them what I could do and
then they gave me the money to do it and
then we did it. And uh,
the rest is history.
So ever until the recession, so
everything was rocking. And so did you,
so you are in your college apartment,
but then where'd you end up?
I ended up here in my hometown.
And you had space,
you got an office in all nine yards?
Yeah.
Well I started in a barn and
it was me and another guy,
my first hire and then we
moved into kind of like a,
like a double wide trailer house.
You know, we call it a double wide.
Did have a skirt? Yeah. Y'All. Yeah. Okay.
Let me ask you again. All vinyl skirt.
You kidding me? Who doesn't have a white
skirt? Got It. Got to keep it real.
So we went there and then we
moved into a basement in town.
This is like the perfect
progression, right? Yeah.
And then we hired a few more and
then we moved into a beautiful,
we had built out a
studio where man it was,
we actually designed it. And because
you were making legit money now we were,
how many employees are we talking about?
I think maybe seven or something.
10 something like that. And now
you're 22 yeah, if that, yeah. Yeah,
probably 20 to 22 getting after 22
years old. Yup. Six employees. Yeah.
Costumed designed office space.
Everything you want to hear something,
I don't even know if I should say this.
You ready for this?
You may have to edit this out.
Alright.
I handled two governors
campaigns in Maine, 22 years old.
They wanted like the best design,
the best marketing.
So they came to these young
ins and we had this one guy,
uh, Les Otten should maybe
you not say the name you,
it was a national news. It's hard not
to. You can cut it out. Understood.
Really National News,
national news.
Really Nice Guy Right
after Obama's first term.
So les came and he wanted us to handle
this campaign and so he wanted a logo
that was circular, like
Obama's logo. And so we did a,
I designed myself a circular logo,
which green and blue,
very similar feel,
not even close to the same,
but it was around and who had
done around logo at that time.
Next thing I know this
thing ends up on CNN,
all the national news stations and they
have like the two logos have Obama's
logo and lessons,
logo I Scott,
influx of emails and phone calls.
People like rip it.
Cause remember how that first term for
old palm, remember how hot that was?
Remember people negative when they were
negative on you because they were like,
we ripped it off. And I
was like, really? Really?
So it was round.
Don't make around logo,
especially after the first
Obama don't use circles,
don't use the circles. So, uh,
anyways, it was, it was,
it was an interesting time.
There's a little bit of
stress. Did he catch heat for
it? Obviously, I guess. Yeah.
Yeah, because no one really
cared. They, you know,
no one even knew they were like some,
he wasn't like,
oh my addict HSE made it up and I
thought it was great. No. Well He,
you know what they, you know,
kind of a little bit, he did that,
but he had an advice advisor that said
this is the right direction and whatnot.
So it was,
it was interesting times.
So what was the heat to the
heat was like national media,
like ripping you down,
people dig down who designed it,
like the company that designed
it and just like daring you off.
They found your yearbook
picture or whatever it was.
That was like Obama was like
15 days of like holy shit.
Like are we gonna we gonna survive
this as a company, you know?
And we did. Yeah. Yeah.
And so you,
you survived that and,
and I guess your lesson is like from that,
that you can survive things you're
going to like, it's interesting,
I just caught that you said 15
days because guess what, 15 days,
no one cared anymore. Is that
pretty much pretty much, yeah. Yeah.
I see that a lot in the news. You know,
people, some will come on to all this,
people freak out about something
and I'm like, yeah, wait,
I'll wait a week for four days.
No one cares anymore.
There's like some other meteor that
hit the satellite thing or whatever.
Yeah. So you know, it was,
it was interesting, you know,
we were young, you know, and naive,
you know. I mean, I think all
entrepreneurs start out naive honestly.
And from a leadership perspective,
you're in a leadership position
for the first time and,
and you have a team of six
people, you're the man. Yup.
And I'm trusting you seem you say
that with a little hesitation. Yeah.
I trust that people
will do the right thing.
Are The people that are working for
you your age? A little younger? Just,
just all the sides are the same age,
year or two difference. All young.
So now you said recession.
What happens there?
Well we were,
we were kind of like booming as a company
building some incredible that we would
do interactive touch screen
kiosks and all this really,
really cool shit that nobody was doing it.
The recession hit.
We lost 65% of our business overnight.
I mean,
what's the first thing you
cut and recession advertising.
You're not supposed to,
but you do the wrong move, but it's the
move that everyone makes. Yeah, man,
I probably make the same move. Where
can we cut costs ad spend, right.
Stop that.
Anyways,
the recession hit and we had built
this company from like the ground up,
just funneled the money back into the
company, built, built, built by equipment,
Bill this, do all this
stuff. I'm like, Oh shit.
First time I thought about like
these guys bought houses here.
Have families are starting.
Families moved away.
How long had the run been at this point?
This had been,
this is a five year olds and that's a
good question. When does the recession?
Eight or nine this is six.
Seven year run. Okay. So yeah,
these guys had established their lives,
they established their families up here.
They, you were the,
for the form of income.
You're how they're paying their mortgage.
Absolutely. And I felt that, you know,
I don't know if that's a weakness,
but I'm sensitive to that man. I,
that's why promise somebody something
like this company is your future.
I mean this company is your future.
I will stop taking a paycheck and
that's not the right thing to do.
You got to always pay yourself.
Right.
I will stop taking a pay check
to make sure you get yours.
That's what I did.
And what I also did is I took out a
line of credit was the first money I had
taken out from the bank ever.
And I use that money to keep things going
to try to get through the recession.
And I didn't want to lay anybody off.
What I had them do was I had them start
designing in house. Cause by the way,
the next thing that you do
after you cut advertising,
the biggest cost to just about any
business there is as your people people.
So that's the next thing that gets cut.
But you're saying you're not
going to do that. And I'm,
and I'm young and learning about
business as I go, you know,
so no, I'm not going to do it now they,
some of them bought houses and stuff,
you know, like I'm not taking
away their livelihood, you know,
I'll find a way to just get
through. Right. You know, and I,
and I believe I had the fortitude
to get through, you know, but,
and there's the, but they
didn't. And here's why.
Because
I had them start working on his house
in house projects and I was training
Jujitsu at the time and so I was going
to develop a platform so that an academy
could build a website based
off of a templated system
for their Jiu Jitsu school
and it was going to be bad ass.
And we had done this for like
Rossignol Indiana Star we had,
we were like one of the first companies
to build online tools to build things.
Make sense?
There's a night early 2000 so when you
go on and you look at some product and
you want to, there's a little
customization that can be done to it.
You guys did design things to move the
mouse around and yeah, there's a bunch of,
there was none of them.
Zero.
And so we started building
this thing and you're be,
you're building this thing but you're
not being paid for it yet because
eventually we're going to sell it.
So you're just,
that's what's your in house project.
Exactly.
Now did Jujitsu take a little bit
more of my time than it should have?
You know,
these things happen.
Did I think about it more than
anything else in the world? I did.
And just real quick, how'd
you get into Jujitsu? Well,
after football I stopped playing football
and I was like, man, I, I need to fight.
Like I need to add, you know, I
always had this desire to fight.
Maybe all men have,
I don't know,
but I felt like many extra
extra like I need to fight.
So I'm like taekwondo.
So I started fighting in taekwondo
and achieved that in about two years.
It was like, okay, now what?
And then I found Jujitsu and I got
choked out by 150 pound kid and I was 285
pounds and I was like,
that's a convincer,
couldn't figure it out. I came at
him with every bit of Athleticism,
could choke me out almost cold.
I had what just happened
and I bought into it.
So when he, ah, anyways, I,
I was passionate about Jujitsu and I want,
I had this perfect plan to build this
system and they started getting salty
about it.
Now is that because they felt like there
was an income is because they weren't
getting paid by the project getting
a commission or something like that?
What were they going to salty about?
They all got salaries.
So what were they getting salty about?
The fact that they were working
on my pet projects, those words,
my pet projects,
they were also salty.
I had two very young kids and my wife
in the office that the kids were in the
office and they were, you know, playing
with their stuff and doing what kids do.
Kids, they're being kids. My company,
my office, my kids. Okay.
They found that a problem.
So out of them. Yeah.
What was your relationship,
cause this, this,
I'm just assuming right now that you've
got a bunch of people that are working
for you that are around
the same age as you. Yep.
And so I'm guessing that you were kind
of broken out with me. We're Super Bros,
super burros, super immature, super bros.
Immature kids, right?
Talented, immature kids.
I mean you're talking about like, Hey,
let's shut it down and go snowboarding.
We've got two inches of POW
POW on Sugarloaf, you know,
and we need to hit that.
That's what we do. We just shut
it down, grab the stope wheel.
Rossignol would send us like
$10,000 in product. We just,
we just go out and we'd just rip,
rip on the mountain. Hey Man,
just get the work done. You know, all you
need to, yeah man. No worries. Just do,
just make sure the work's done.
Yup. Very loose. Super Burros.
Yes. Hitting the power
to, we call it powder.
So yeah,
man,
the relationship was not a boss,
worker,
employee relationship. It was
a creative, I always wanted to,
we had a foosball table in the,
in the, you know, give me a break.
I mean this is a creative
agency. Yup, Yup, Yup.
But when shit hits the fan, the
fingers go to one person. This guy,
right. So, all right, I'm ready to
sustain this thing and make it happen.
They weren't.
So one day I'm in my wife's office and
the whole crew gets up and hands me a
paper and it's a thick
paper and they're like,
we'll see you on Monday to talk about
this because they thought they weren't
expendable. Okay. So they're
giving you an ultimatum. Ultimatum.
I was like, I turned white
for a second. I was like,
okay. When they walked out, were
you, did you anticipate this at all?
No.
No idea.
I will never be caught off guard like that
again. Yeah. That one's going to stick.
Now are going to leave a mark. This is
a mutiny, you know, straight up. New.
Straight up mute. Yep. Okay.
My wife is an emotional being.
We sat down and we read this,
this paper,
and it was a list of demands,
a list of demands about profit sharing,
how the company was making all this money
and it wasn't being filtered down to
the employees and
okay.
About my kids and how they cannot come
into the office anymore because they make
noise,
a whole list of demands.
They can't concentrate when they're
playing foosball. Yeah. Eddie and yeah.
Amongst other things.
Young, stupid kids. Yeah.
And I was one of them.
Yeah, because I was naive.
So we started looking at this
thing and I was just like, wow.
It's like getting punched in the face.
And my wife went zing
and she spun up and shoo.
She's French Canadian and she's, she's,
you know. Yeah. Anyway, she spun up,
I said, okay. Does she speak
French when she's angry? No. Okay.
I wish that would be kind of hot.
If she did, I'd be like, Babe,
can you speak French? Just make her mad
so she could yell at you and yeah, no.
So,
so what we did is we just,
we sat there and looked at each other
and we're like, what? What? And I said,
do they have any idea?
We just took out a line of credit to
support this place to get through the
recession. They have any
idea, we don't have any work.
So what do we do?
RECON,
we opened up their computers,
logged in and started looking for all the
interaction between the staff and wow,
what they thought of me.
I was sad. I was like,
wow, this is sad. Maybe you
feel like shit, what they think.
I mean they thought I was
like some type of miser, like,
like squirreling away cash and
resources because I, because I was,
I
kept a straight face and hat how happy
personality and they had no idea how much
in the whole we were.
Yeah.
And I can imagine that you're trying to
actually protect them from the stress
and business. Yes. And in doing that,
you didn't communicate to them
what was actually happening,
which meant that they created what
was happening in their own minds,
which was obviously Raj shit.
Them creating what they think reality is
in their minds when they don't know all
the facts.
There's so many times in business when
I talk to businesses and businesses are
going through transitions or there's
something happening and you know, they'll,
they'll be asking like, well do you think
we should tell you know the employees,
what's happening? And I'm like,
well you have two choices.
You can tell them what's happening or
they're going to make up a story to make
up a story and it's not going to be good.
They're going to think
worst case scenario.
And so the open communications that is
what is how you prevent this kind of
thing.
And obviously you're 22 years old.
That's pretty awesome that you were in
a position you earning and obviously you
can look back now and it's pretty
simple to see what the solutions were.
One of them, you were, you were
broken out with these guys too much.
And this is a fine line, you know,
because you know, in a seal platoon,
I had Bros,
all lifetime brothers that were,
you know,
three or four ranks below me.
But they were professional and they
understood the line between and they
understood and they
respected the position. And,
and then there's other guys that
were, you know, that same rank,
lower rank that I could not,
I couldn't give that kind of closeness to.
And so that's one of those things that,
you know,
w w we talk about a lot with companies
is it's different for the different
people in your company,
right?
So I'm not saying you can't bro out with
people and also that doesn't mean you
don't have awesome relationships with
your people because that's what you want.
You want to have awesome relationships
with the people that are working for you
because they're going to do that much
more for you and you can do that much more
for them and it becomes a functional
winning team because everyone cares about
each other. Exactly.
There's a dichotomy there.
Are we being there? The lines, are
we super burros? What does that,
what is that line? That line is the
thing that you need to figure out.
What makes it really hard
with the relationship pieces
that it's different for
different people.
And I had some guys that was an e
five and a seal platoon and I was the
lieutenant and they were my total bros.
And there's another guy that's in e
five and I got to keep a little distance
just to make sure that they,
they stay professional. Right?
And so this is,
this is challenging stuff and great
lessons learned for anyone running a
business, especially young people.
But it's not just young people.
Cause I see seasoned CEOs
asking these same questions,
learn this shit in college.
I'm so sorry. You know,
like being an entrepreneur,
businessman or woman,
whatever it's learned.
You know,
you may have a gift of something
or accounting, you may,
maybe a good salesperson are
good at marketing or something.
Nobody's born with a gift of being an
entrepreneur. You know, it's built, it's
crafted over time and you have to fail
and fall flat on your face and get
punched in the face to
figure it out. Yeah. So,
but what's good is unfortunately there's
those like those lessons that your
parents tried to teach you
but you didn't listen to.
And a commando so stupid if
you're even aware of them.
And that's what's good about like
someone that's hearing what you're saying
right now.
They might not recognize it before.
And this is a chapter in extreme
ownership, right? Dichotomy of leadership.
And you gotta be,
you can't be so close to your people.
That one's more important
that we go through this.
But the awareness of it is it gives people
a percentage chance of maybe instead
of falling flat on their face,
maybe they just stumble and they're able
to recover. Right? So this is, you know,
classic. I fell flat. Yes,
dude, it hurt too. Okay.
So what happens?
So I was,
I was sad man at first.
Then I got angry and then
I got to even, no, no,
I basically what it was is w we are not
expendable heed these words and these
demands and we'll talk to
you Monday morning. Okay?
So what happens? We do a little
recon, get into the computers,
see the communication between all of them.
What they thought about me,
what they thought about my wife, what
they thought was going on with a company.
Half an hour later I'm in my
vehicle and divide and conquer.
You're not going to tell me.
Cause in that paper said,
do not come and see us individually.
Do not seek us out.
Do not try to separate one of us and have
a conversation and that's exactly what
I did.
By the way,
from the employee standpoint,
this is a horrible move.
They are making dupes as bad of a mistake
as you were making as a leader because
what they should have, any one of them
could have done is said, Pete, Bro,
I got to talk to you, man. Let me
tell you what's going on. Yeah,
this is what we're thinking. We don't
know what's going on with a company.
You guys working on these random
projects that are like your projects,
we should be working for other companies.
Can you tell us what in God's name
is going on so we can move forward?
That's what one of those,
nobody was that mature and you could
have brought them into a room and said,
hey guys, I apologize for not telling
you, but let me tell you what,
what income we have on in the
next six months. Nothing. Nothing.
So this is what we're going to do.
Try and survive you to give them the plan.
They would understand why you were doing
what you're doing it right and it would
have been good.
So both sides of the chain of command
there are actually making a grievous
mistake,
bad mistakes. My and I learned
from that that that was, I mean I,
I'm a transparent person as it is.
You can ask me anything you
want and I will answer it.
I was just a dumb kid though.
I didn't want to show weakness to
them is what I was thinking. Right.
Because I didn't want them to feel like
they needed to go find another job.
I didn't want him to think that start
talking like all the companies going to
shut down.
I was making my own stories.
I didn't trust they would make the
right decision if I told them this.
So I just carried on to try to
push through and you're right.
It was a mistake to not share it with
them because it would have been, I was,
we were bleeding as a company,
but they were,
the blood I was trying to keep in it
would have been easier just to let them
decide what they wanted
to do after in hindsight,
telling them where we were as a company,
how the recession had affected us,
but I didn't. Yeah, and so
I divided and conquered.
Meaning I got in my car,
drive to the first one's house,
knock on the door,
John,
we're going to talk or you have no job.
John's still with me right now.
He works for origin. I was
pissed. I was so pissed.
I was crying a little bit.
I was pissed at you were been so pissed.
Like you're just like you cried. Yes.
Negative next question.
Really. I don't know that even when you
were a kid it'll be, I mean, I'm like,
Oh yes. I guess I guess I'm
talking about being a seven.
I'm talking like 20 what am I,
2124 something like that.
I was in the teams at that point where
not crying. Okay. It's not happening.
This isn't one time to
echo.
I'm having a conversation with you.
Have you read it?
So pissed you like started
crying?
Honestly,
crying is not like anger does
not lead to tears in my eyes.
For me crying is weakness.
Leaving the body.
I sad. Okay. I get it.
But being angry, that's, that's okay.
But you know everyone's a little
bit as a kid. Yeah, yeah. No,
I was a kid because the kid talk,
please remember I didn't have,
I didn't have a mentor either.
Like when I was a kid I didn't have, I
had, I had one mentor, my friend, my,
my buddy's father.
Cause it was a single single mom.
Who was it just we are as kids be a
lot of the time we raised ourselves,
I didn't have a mentor and having a father
figure around all the time to see how
to, so I just, I worked off
of pure drive an emotion.
Yeah. Yeah. And again, I'm not trying to
be a jerk. No, I'm having fun with it.
But you're so pissed.
So pissed.
You've got freaking tears in your eyes
and you go to John and you fucking,
you want this job or not
because if you say no,
you're not talking to me. You do not
have a job and you've got a new house.
Okay, so he had, he's in the
car. Okay. One down, one down,
one in the game. Still in
one of the game. Got It.
As I drove to the other's houses,
they either didn't answer the door
and hid or answered the door and said,
I can't talk to you and closed it.
Okay. These our kids, you know like this
kid does, these are kids, which is a good,
is a message to everybody. Yeah. When
you don't want to talk to somebody,
you're not solving anything.
You know what I mean? Yes.
Now I'm not saying that there's sometimes
where I'm so mad at you that I'm like,
Pete, come back tomorrow Bro. Cause right
now it ain't going to go good. Yeah.
I'm so mad I could cry or something like
that. It sounds really sensitive, man.
What'd you actually do that and
that is a week, but that is that.
The point is though,
seriously, if there's,
if there's a problem and you're
not going to talk about it,
you're going to sound like that kid
right there. That answers where I can't,
I can't talk to you right now.
We can shuts the door.
That's not a way to get anything solved.
Are there times where you need a little
bit of distance because people are hot
headed? Yes, that happens.
As long as you know you're going to
see you both know that it's solvable.
You know, like I feel like with
respect to business and stuff like,
like if you're working with a client,
you may like bang heads with a client and
be like, all right, listen, we need to,
we need to shut this down and
discuss it like in 48 hours.
That's learned over time.
Not when you're a kid.
You just want to get after like Ah,
forget even your approach was
super hardcore and this is again,
you know people a little bit
aggressive. Yeah. People,
people want to hear me say like, that's
right. You go in there and you say,
you either talk to me now where you don't
have a job that was already bleeding
though. So was that the right choice?
I don't know. But the, the, the,
the approach for me
would be like, um, hey,
let me explain to you what's going on
and then you can think more about your
decision because right now I'm telling
you what you've decided and what you've
presented to me is so far off base that
if this is what you want to make your
decision based on,
I'm telling you what I'm going to have
to do is let you go because I haven't
told you yet,
but we don't have any money and I'm
paying you out of my own pocket.
So if you don't like that and you don't
want me to pay you out of my own pocket
or anymore,
I'm actually good with that.
But if you want to have a job and you
want to try and make this thing work,
let's have a conversation.
And that's close to exactly
what I would say now. Yeah,
exactly.
100% the reason I'm making this point,
because I had a guy hit me up
on social media the other day,
he asked a legit question and, and
he pre preface the question, he says,
I'm a very direct guy like you,
meaning he's direct like me.
And he says,
and I give feedback and it makes
people mad at rubs them the wrong way.
And I'm just, you know, I wrote back,
I go, look man, I'm direct on Twitter,
which is 140 characters and I'm
answering 720 questions in rapid fire.
And, and so yeah, I'm direct. When
someone says, well, what is your, you,
what is your average daily
diet consist of? Steak. Next
part. You know what I mean?
But with direct,
you're not an asshole.
But it's also like I'm having fun.
That's the fun part of,
you know, interacting with
people through social media.
That's not how I'm treating another
human being face to face in a real
relationship. When we're trying to
build something, then I'm using tact.
I'm using maneuvering, um, quorum,
manipulating the situation.
I'm setting things up. I'm being
the most tactful person. In fact,
not only am I not going
to rub them the wrong way,
I'm going to rub them in a very nice way.
So they feel good about the
conversation that we had.
Disarm them and have a real conversation.
The point is, is that you know,
you're you, you were like, you
said what my little quote was,
is what you would say. Now back
then, you're young, you're bleeding.
I'm bleeding. You're pissed
off. Yeah. And you say,
you know what wife nagging
at me about finances. Yeah.
You know how that all builds to young
kids don't sleep through the night
it gets, it gets tricky and
you're trying to maintain this
so,
so just Fyi that what you just said.
Yeah.
You, you just said you know how
it is. And to be honest with you,
I don't know how that is
because I was in the military.
I got a paycheck every two
weeks. Yeah. I had kids,
I had health insurance taken care of,
I had a house taking care of it. It's,
it's a huge, it's, it's, it's, it's
actually a feeling. I don't know.
Um, so I, yeah, don't know that
feeling. I want to, I can only imagine.
I can only imagine what I
would be thinking if I was
in your shoes at 22 years
old with a wife, two screaming
kids, and I don't have any money.
So yeah, check. Okay. And yet some,
I will tell you about that feeling. It's
a feeling I'm never going to go back to
as we,
as I divided and conquered
it did not go my way.
So meaning that the people were saying
they can't talk or they hid,
can't talk to you. They went,
they left their having their homes,
whatever.
So I made a decision what to do when I
told him, talk to my wife. She's like,
what are we going to do?
I said, well, I said,
they all think they're expendable
except they're not because there's not a
person in this world.
Okay.
That is so good. Oh, they
can't be recognized, right?
Yeah. Okay. Got It. Got It.
They think they're not expendable.
There's not a person's world
that is so good at their job.
They can't be replaced. Hmm. Did you hear
that echo? Yes, sir. Just just say it.
Almost none, but yeah,
you're right. You're right.
There's a lot of talented
people in the world.
So what did I do?
Hefty trash bags.
Get some,
I went up to that studio and I scraped
their desks individually into trash bags
and it felt good.
I didn't even mean to say that like,
but it felt good. Yeah. I
literally just scraped it,
tied it up, went to the next, my
wife just pushed it all into the bag.
This is good therapy. Yup.
Yup. We dragged all the shot.
I didn't care what was in the bag.
I don't care what they had on their desks.
My property,
your shit in the trash bags.
Didn't organize nothing.
Just scraped.
Dragged him down the stairs gently because
I'm getting a feeling this was not as,
you're not dragged them down the stairs.
We were in this,
this like studio,
you know,
third floor studio that we had
built out for us. Beautiful. Right?
That Monday morning the art director
who I cut my teeth with came down,
he lived in Bangor,
Maine.
We say Bangor came down and we were
sitting there and it was glass like the
glass and it's like you could
see through it being inside,
but from the outside you can't,
they all got out of the same vehicle,
kind of giggling and
chuckling like they own me,
they own this company and they walked
in the door and there we were sitting
there with a trash bags and they went from
Giddy
to guilty to sadness and
their faces turned white.
There's your shit.
Take it.
Yeah.
And that was it. Done. That was tough.
I said a few words
but I was not going to be
held hostage to this situation
in business.
I,
I say you've got like 40
years of being a maker.
I did a speech recently
at an innovation for,
I wrote a speech for an innovation expo.
It was zero to 20 year learning 20 to
60 you're doing and 60 to 80 hopefully
you're enjoying the fruits of your labor.
Anything good in life takes 10 years.
So my first 10 years had passed but I
still had 30 to go and so I knew I wasn't
done.
Yeah.
But the pain of the situation and the
in the experience I grew exponentially
overnight.
Yeah.
We had salvaged, a small part of
the company, which was a s was this,
we called it web were right.
It was like online software.
Like everything is now like the cloud,
but there was no cloud,
there was this system,
I was able to salvage that
and because it had like a,
a cool little customer base of some high
end customers and they paid monthly,
it was just like reoccurring
payments. Right. Just to use it. Yeah.
And so I found a buyer for it and
the negotiation took a long time
and in that long time we had no income,
no money.
And so what did I do? I started
selling shit, dirt bikes,
four wheelers,
snowmobiles,
every nonessential item I owned got sold,
trying to maintain, keeping my
home right, which we had built,
my wife and I in the forest,
which was our dream home,
just a tiny little 1500
square foot timber frame,
borrowing money from family
and
and in our parents and them
knowing the situation we're in.
So them actually just like
giving us food or whatever.
That whole time I had the maintain like
the super composure to try and sell this
thing at all.
This shit happening in the background
and I think it was like eight months and
I finally sold it $200,000 I think it
was,
which
was cheap for what we had built.
Extremely cheap,
but I was in a position
where we had nothing left,
had freaking nothing left.
You know,
it was super,
super challenging and I could have
easily easily turned to substance abuse,
which I didn't.
I've never been into substances.
I could have easily just fell off
the deep end and felt like a failure,
which I knew I wasn't.
My wife wanted me to go find a job. She's
like, that's what I was about to say.
I can't normal normal day you go get a
nine to five. I actually, I can't do this.
I can't do this Pete.
I can't do this
during that eight month stint, you've
got to figure it out. Myself paid.
I will find a way to make this work
and I believe everything happens for a
reason.
It happened for a reason and I just
kept that in the back of my head
and I pushed and pushed and pushed forward
and it wasn't freaking easy like it
was super, super hard like on us,
but she stood by me
unwavering.
She stood by me.
Never once did she want to leave,
did she
not believe in me
or not trust me,
which is what I needed.
And like I said earlier about filling
the class back up, it was empty.
It was bone frigging dry,
bone dry,
and she just put a little bit back in
and we kept moving and kept chugging.
Now during that time period where
you're looking to sell the old company,
are you hatching plans or is you gotta
be 100% focused on just so Moscow and my
creativity dove to the
bottom of the ocean done.
I was, I don't, I've never
experienced depression,
you know, but I, I I get it.
I felt a little bit like a failure.
Um,
I felt a little bit like a failure,
but I knew I wasn't.
So every time I had a negative thought,
I would just push through it.
I just pushed her the thought and what
got me through a lot of that was training
Jujitsu where I could expel my
energy and use my creativity,
which I thought I had lost in Jujitsu.
It's a very creative sport
art and that kind of kept me,
I guess it kept those endorphins flowing
so I could maintain some stability.
But tactically your focus is
sell scata gotta make sales,
make it look good.
Look,
let's show them the numbers that
are coming in for our few clients.
And a lot of projections could be,
Yep, that's all you're doing. Yup.
That's all you're doing. And you're,
you're thinking when you sell that thing,
you're going to have enough
and you'll figure it out later.
But you're not worried about it right
now. Exactly. So you make the sale.
I make the sale for the first year.
We get a monthly check.
No, it's like five grand a month
or something. Not the full amount,
just like five grand a month.
So during that time I decided to just
take 12 months and figure out what comes
next.
And in that 12 months I traveled
around the country training,
Jujitsu and filming a
thing we call Bjj weekly
because that's what I
was passionate about.
And so we traveled around
and film technique and train
and all this stuff and it
was like an excuse to train
Jujitsu. That's it. This newsletter.
And
after that 12 months and traveling around,
it just struck me what I wanted to do.
Years earlier,
I had designed this logo for a GE
brand off the cough came to me.
I get my ideas in the morning.
One morning I sat down and just boom,
done five minutes.
You know, sometimes you can have a
client come in. We used use doing,
I'd spent a hundred hours on
the Friggen logo. You know,
people don't realize how much locos costs
and sometimes you just nail it like 10
minutes done, finished it just
like getting hit by lightning,
just boom, done. That's what
happened with this origin thing.
Okay.
I wanted to start a brand because what
I had done and what I had learned and
over that year of driving
round and training and
reconnecting with myself and my
family was that I loved
building brands and products.
I loved taking something from nothing,
like a drawing in making it into something
and I had an aversion to the screen.
Okay.
In that space,
because of the new media thing,
I was always on a screen and
I, I just, I told him, man, I,
I need to like do something physically,
like have something physical and you'd
have a physical thing to do because I was
an art major and I'm an artist and I
zip up goalposts. I needed thing to do.
So in Jujitsu I had seen that the,
the uniform like hadn't changed.
I Dunno,
they'd been wearing Kimonos for a thousand
years, but you know, judo, you know,
hundreds of years did you to a hundred
years in Brazil, same thing. Same,
same damn thing. A hundred percent
cotton uniform. This is what you wear.
And I was like, why?
Why do you wear the hat?
You got under Armour with like wicking
stuff and you've got air helmets instead
of leather helmets.
And you know,
just all these innovations in
other sports in Jujitsu had shit.
We had nothing like wearing a bunch of
just straight cotton balls and no sweaty
soaked in g that stretches and stinks bad.
It's socked in. So to
start, I was like, okay,
I gotta start, I gotta start.
Meaning you, you now the vision,
you see that gies haven't progressed, you
know that they can be made better. Yup.
You, you don't actually
eat. And so you say, okay,
I want to make the best guy in the
world. That's the vision. Yes it is.
And you have to start somewhere.
You got to start somewhere.
So I didn't know anything about textiles,
but I knew about design and
I knew about the human body.
And you know how the human body
worked in, in, in, in college sports,
you learn about that a lot, you know,
mechanics, mechanics of the body,
they retrain, knew how to run in
college. Like they, you all run the same,
you do exercises. So you're all
striking, striking with your foot.
You all run the same.
And so I designed like a g pants
and it was like the cowboy cut.
Cause I knew that in Jujitsu
when you're like you're,
you're squatting a lot and on your knees
and the material pulled up your up your
leg but pulled down your butt.
So you're like got plumbers crack,
which sucks. So I designed like, so
the kneepads came up to your hip,
so when you squatted it
would pull from your hips,
right instead of a cross to
the top of your leg. And did,
did some cool innovations like that. And
then I was like, all right, time to go.
So we launched [inaudible] we, we, we,
we imported the ski from Pakistan.
One G I was in the basement of my house
and I was like, we're going to start
this brand. So I hit the basement socked.
Here comes a g,
we shot a photo,
we saw some photos off of it and I
launched it through Bjj weekly and boom,
40 grand. I was like, wow.
Which you didn't have any gies no,
none,
no keys.
But I wanted to prove that we could do
something different and I trust that I
could make it happen
knowing having the keys.
I was like 200 yeas sold.
I've got something here.
I've got something good here.
And I knew a new adventure was
going to start and my wife's spun up
in a positive way. No. Oh.
She just like, what are you doing?
I'm like, I'm starting a key brand.
And she like got sick. Like I know she
might had an anxiety attack at first.
Like the [inaudible] you can't do
this again. You can't, you, you know,
you can't start another company.
You know? It's like just,
and I use this word lightly
being around a war hero,
like you know,
Warrior here,
I promise you that PTSD of business,
right?
That's a real thing. Like she, she,
she had like PTSD of business because
of what we had gone through and selling
everything and the feeling you get
that you keep, you keep this feeling.
For me, I used it for drive
for her. She used it for,
I don't ever want to feel that again.
That makes me like ill for me it was
like I'm never going to feel that again.
I'm going to make sure I never feel
that again and I'm going to do something
about it.
So I did it anyways.
Started a company origin and
that's when it began.
2011 10 or 2000.
So how do you start it?
You got one,
Ge has sold 40 grand worth of one
guy that you didn't have. Right.
What do you do next?
Did you know at this point you
wanted to make them in America?
Had you figured that part
out yet? No. No. I, I, I,
let me take that back.
I figured you make them an American.
I want to be to make them in America.
And so I started like calling all
the factories and in Maine like,
hey, you know, you guys, so stuff.
Yeah. Cool. Can you sew this? No.
Okay. So it was people, I don't know.
Maine has traditionally had
a lot of industry up here.
Manufacturing big time. Especially when
we, when we were kids. Yes. Uh, you know,
big brands up here that build a
lot, you know, all kinds of stuff.
Bashu 10 minutes away,
sold out Dexter Shoe,
Hayden Shoe,
Lou Hayden,
he owns San Antonio shoe passed away
and huge companies Llb new balance 20
minutes away.
So rich heritage and manufacturing,
but apparel in Maine,
a little different that we made shoes
and we a wool fabric and stuff like that.
But apparel wasn't,
wasn't the norm.
So what I did is we are in that
basement and we're like, okay,
and I just got to make this
note that, yeah, the, all those,
a lot of those companies
that you're talking about
that had built all this stuff
for, for all those years, a lot
of them had left. Yeah. So that,
that's the political situation,
except all of them had left ll bean.
They still make some stuff here.
The rest left gone. So bounce,
still make some stuff here to write a new
balance stuff. Oh yeah. For sure. Yeah.
New Balance is awesome. Uh, so
yeah,
I was like, okay, we're going to make
a belt. That's what we're gonna do.
We're gonna make a belt. A
jujitsu belt. Yeah. Yeah. So
there was this guy and Lewiston
who ran this company and uh,
I called him up. I'm like, I need some
sewing machines. And he's like, okay,
well why don't you stop by in Lewiston,
Maine,
one of the manufacturing hubs of main
at one time walked in and he's like,
what do you need? I was like,
oh, this is what I want to make.
It's a belt for martial arts.
It's like, okay. And I said,
I just need some machine,
a machine to do that. And like I got
500 bucks cash I can spend on it.
Um, can you give me
something to practice with?
And so he sold me a machine,
showed me how to thread the Bobbin,
showed me where it went, pulled through
the needle and I'm like, okay, okay.
We filmed it so we knew how to do it.
So we're like filming him doing this.
They're like,
okay.
So we took the sewing machine and then
I put it in my basement next to the desk
and I'm like, yeah, it's sewing machine.
And my wife was just like
shaking your head. Luckily,
luckily we had sold a preorder, so we had
sold $40,000 in keys that didn't exist.
So she had gotten off
my back a little bit.
So that machinery sat there and as we
looked at trying to like make this key,
and I didn't say, oh, we're going to make
a Gig in America. I just said, right,
we're going to make,
you were going to change the GE.
We're going to change
the GE first. So we, um,
we started the import game.
Everybody else is doing it.
Everybody's telling me
manufacturing's dead.
I did a few phone calls pretty
much everybody's like, yeah,
you can't really do that. And
so I was like, okay, you know,
and the whole time I'm thinking like
something's not right here that I can't do
this. And I just couldn't
put my finger on what it was.
So I imported, you know, in 2011 and uh,
may we started in 2011 and into 2012
did a few batches to the whole who
you limited edition batch thing. Geez.
But we promoted it with
the innovations we had.
It was still shit. You know when it
comes right down to it, what the g was?
Yeah man, it was still shit. It's
still using old textiles have exist.
So you design the,
well you said you imported one from
Pakistan and then what'd you do?
Like cut it up and redesign it or some
or did you send the design to them and
they can get of soy? I designed
like a everything in illustrator,
like a tech pack. Like I want this
here, I want the knee pads here.
They got to fall here,
the belt loops because I don't want to
untie them all this stuff in and then
they send it. Yeah. Done. Yeah.
Okay. Finish. So you know,
you know in Pakistan,
um,
they are like the
manufacturing for martial arts.
It's like the manufacturing hub in
this little city called [inaudible].
They're actually like a, almost like
migrant workers has a ton of factories,
Jujitsu factories. But the workers
are the same. All the same guys in,
they're all the same guys. They meditate
or whatever. Rotate around. Yeah. They,
we got a contract over here.
We're gonna make, yeah. That's
going to make her, Geez,
good bunch of guys show up there. They
work for pennies and pennies. Yup. Yup.
So we did the important thing
and we started to grow rapidly.
We started to make
money and at that point,
my other business,
I was making kind of that monthly income
and then I got kind of like a chunk of
money, like a hundred grand.
I was like, all right, cool.
I can like take a deep breath
and really push this thing.
And so I pushed it and we
started selling more and more.
Then I came out with this really cool
backpack called the [inaudible] backpack,
jal backpack, technical backpack. And
we sold a ton of them, thousand of them.
And then we came out with this
product for grip training.
We weren't patenting anything, we were
just, I was like boom. Cause that's,
I did like once I got on a roll,
it's like design this, design this.
And we were just selling,
selling, selling.
And during this time I was
also competing, you know, cause
a male
no more each Jujitsu and you want to test
yourself against the best in the world.
So I was training hard. I'd
ended up winning the, the, um,
let me,
let me digress for a sec.
I had seen another company release a
product for grip training that looked
exactly like ours.
What was the product though?
It's called, don't know.
Ring a hang. So it's you,
it's like the g and then color.
It was cool.
It was awesome.
And I was like,
those bastards ripped us off.
And I wasn't thinking my manufacturer
or anything of why I'm psyched man,
another company ripped us off. I
should have patented that, you know,
Blah Blah Blah.
Okay.
So I was competing.
I ended up going to Canada.
I won the world pro trials as a brown
belt at the time when the world pro trials
and the black belt division,
cause they, you know, they,
they put the divisions
together as you know,
for that was in 2012 now they, I think
they separated them now again, but,
so I got to go over to Abu Dhabi and
compete in the world pro and as a brown
belt in that black belt division.
I'm sitting there before my match and
I'm supposed to fight, uh, Shawn Gee,
how Barrow in the quarter finals
of the open division three.
And I,
I,
I'm going to say this,
it was bad seating.
Like the seating of the
brackets was not good. Okay. Um,
like I had in my bracket,
a guy from Brazil,
JT Torres,
a shine g and maybe under a golf ball.
And so JT didn't want to fight,
so he,
so I fought the other kid from Brazil and
he was much smaller and I was athletic
and good and I,
I ended up winning and then JT just
kind of like didn't want to fight.
So then he coached me again, Shawn
and we had a war. It was good man.
I had last couple of second
span. It was very close. Um,
[inaudible] multiple time
world champion for us.
One of the best of all time
and Jujitsu. Yeah. Big Time.
Awesome guy too. Awesome. Awesome
guy. So, but the seating was bad.
Like Lovato wasn't in it. Like there was
a couple of other guys. I don't know,
just it,
my division could have been tougher and
I would've gotten my ass kicked a lot
earlier. Okay. So,
but we had a war and it was awesome and
maybe I would have won if I had worked
harder or maybe I would won
if
that girl from Poland didn't walk by me
right before the match with an origin
Gian in a different logo on the back.
And what was on your cut of Biggie?
Like the gay that you designed. Yeah.
And you see a girl from Poland who's
competitive competing. She walks by. Yeah,
it was, it was actually, uh, it was
uh, it was uh, the, the pants. Yeah,
it was a pants or there's a logo different
low on the back. But our whole thing,
you're designed. Yeah. Look,
have a different logo. Yup.
I knew it was my manufacturer
and then everything clicked.
They ripped off the
Iranian hand grip trainers.
Okay.
But what am I to do?
Because I'm locked into these guys now,
so I had to strategize.
So I went out and lost
in the quarter finals,
got on an airplane,
worst freaking flight up my life.
Cause I'm an Adhd kid and I can't be
stuck in a freaking seat for 14 hours.
That sucks.
And on the ride back I was talking to JT
who had become good friends with and he
was kind of like in a
tricky position in life.
He was still with his instructor and
Maryland and just didn't know kind of what
to do. He wasn't progressing and
he's, he was telling me like, man,
I gotta I've got to get,
like I have to do a full workout before
I can actually train with the guys
because he was so good. He just
wasn't getting it, you know?
And you know, the Mecca of
Jujitsu, you know, is California
ultimately so far as to say San Diego,
San Diego,
that's where he went to San Diego.
That's where he went.
So he was figuring his whole thing out.
So cal for sure. Soquel yeah, yeah.
He was fingering his whole thing out.
And Al's I'm thinking about is like this,
I'm like, man, how I think
I'm gonna build a factory,
I'm more on the airplane as that.
He's looking at me like, oh yeah,
I want to build a factory, screw
this shit. This is bullshit. I said,
I'm not competing anymore.
I'm done.
And all she wanted to do is
win the world championship.
So we kinda like helped each other a
little bit in that plane ride back.
Like Kinda, you know,
bouncing ideas off each other.
Decompression,
decompression.
So I got back and I skyped my manufacturer
and I was like
over Skype. I'm like, this is bullshit.
You freaking,
I didn't say that.
So you fucking ripped off our intellectual
property and sold it to other brands
and he said, businesses business. Dang,
you ever have a defining moment in your
life where you just turn on and you're
like, Yup, done.
I knew at that moment and
what we're going to do. Like
it was clear,
it became clear and I knew the challenge
in front of me and I knew it was insane
and I knew it couldn't be done
and I was like, it's happening.
Props. So, so, uh,
I got to tell you a little bit
of what happened right after,
right after that I went out to the world
championships to compete because I had
already signed up
and that was going to be my year.
We were there and there
was this brand there
and I walked up and I walked by an a,
I did a double take. I was like, what?
And I looked for the right
and there's our Monday,
I'll technical backpack right there.
But with brand and their logo on it.
Okay.
I went up to the guy and
I was like, dude, I said,
got any original ideas and everybody,
there's a badass except for
this guy who doesn't do Jujutsu,
who does nothing,
right.
Just some chubby dude who wants to
capitalize on the success of combat sports
and Jujitsu's growth in California
and I'm not going to name the company.
And I was like, that is
a week. I said, bullshit.
I said, get some original
frigging ideas. I went down,
walked down and myself and uh,
the Deco,
our business partner and his wife and my
wife were down there and I told my wife
in spin,
did she ever,
she went up there and she
flipped out on the guy.
If Amanda bringing it,
she bringing it five
to 103 pounds of fury,
French Canadian re fury.
Done. It was awesome.
We flew back and the
picture was already clear.
This was just like added motivation,
just added motivation.
I called one of my buddies,
Tim,
and and John was already working
for me from my last business,
the sole survivor,
sole survivor moved back to Farmington.
What we did is we grab that,
like that tape you put around trees
and you want to flag trees to cut main,
you've got to flag the trees to cut.
And we Kinda, I'm like, all right John,
I have seven acres of property,
which is okay, listen,
seven acres is not a lot of
property in Maine, right?
You can buy property in Maine for $500
an acre in some places, private sale.
So let's just make that clear.
Seven acres is not a lot,
but we have seven acres of land in
the woods and so I like flagged out,
I'm like,
we're going to build a factory here.
We just flagged it out like this.
And this is based on the architectural
design that your engineered put new for
your factory. Yeah. Right.
I think a factory should be about this
big. Yeah, this looks like a factory.
His eyes so awesome.
And he brought his chains are over
and they're just like, all right,
let's just do it. And we just, rat rat,
rat rat just started cutting trees.
My father in law came over with a chipper.
We chipped it out.
Okay. We stumped it.
Would pull the stumps out.
We're pretty resourceful
up in here in May.
He ever had a Yankee ingenuity that term
for sure.
That happens.
So what do we do?
We cleared it.
We did a little bit of earthwork.
I got on the Compact and compact
at all the sand and poured a slab.
Had had some, some guy, some company,
a Sar out a bunch of eastern
white pine and had my buddy build,
build a barn,
factory barn.
And we just spent, I don't
know, eight 16 eight hour,
how many hours you slept and
zero hours around the clock.
We just built this thing from the
ground up myself, my brother, friends,
family that would just,
we did it. We built it.
Sure that we stuck a sewing machine.
So when you see that $200 were like,
what are we doing? That's where it began.
And, and we, you know, the thing is,
is like if you listen,
I'm, I'm all for planning.
Aye.
Yeah.
I like to plan the, what's going to
happen in that. I like to, like you say,
execute it.
I like to execute that plan,
but do it and I like to
lead the plan and I'm,
I'm shitty when it comes to like,
I'm always making sure everybody's
living up to their expectations.
Like as part of the plan, if they bought
into it, you better fully bought into it.
There's no room for like slacking.
Like if I'm working till midnight,
you're work until midnight,
right? You're not leaving.
So that's what we did. And I'm a
pusher to you, like a push, push, push.
I like to see how much I can get out of
somebody to push them to their potential
and see where their breaking point
is so I can learn about the person,
but also get the best out of them.
So we did it.
We built a factory and uh,
yeah,
that's where it started. So then comes
what, what's next? Sewing machines. Yeah.
And sewing machines and some,
as you started looking for
staff that knew how sell, yeah,
exactly.
So we didn't have any lights yet.
We had one sewing machine and we just
like, okay, this is how we're going.
This is how you,
so,
and I found this old timer bill who
came down and he's like explaining the
different types.
He's been in the business for 40 years
fixing sewing machines and he's just like,
you know when his accent, he's like, oh,
you got the single needle machine and a
double needle when you've got a locking
stitch in a chain stitch and you know
all this stuff. And I'm just like, whoa.
And so I just absorbed,
he became completely
absorbed in that right?
Learning about sewing machines. I learned
how to, how to run them, how to fix them,
what they were good for, the
different types of feeding, you know,
all everything about sewing
machines. I was like, cool.
I know about sewing machines
now we need some fabric.
So I started looking for fabric.
Guess what?
They don't make fabric.
Yeah.
In the United States,
they don't make fabric
that we needed in Mexico.
They don't make fabric in Canada.
Shit,
they don't make fabric for Jujitsu ease.
And I was like,
what are we going to do?
What would you do?
You just built a factory and you
have all these sewing machines in,
what would you do?
So you,
so your only option at this point is got
to order the material from the order,
the material from overseas. You got it.
That's what you're going to do. Right.
I was like screw that.
And so I started looking for like
weaving and so I just, you know,
it was looking for weaving
like hey, hey, hey you guys,
we've can you use a fire forest? Yeah.
A hundred thousand yards, you know,
12 bucks a yard. No. So
I'm just looking, looking,
looking, looking, and did
you ever order any material?
I did. Okay. Because you had to sell
gies. I mean you had to make some money.
You got to investment into this
thing now. Right. And I did, I had,
I didn't pick it. Take a paycheck for
like the first two years of business.
I didn't take a paycheck,
maybe three.
I didn't pay myself once every dime.
I just dumped back in,
dumped back in dumped back in
weaving was impossible. Right.
You're not in a freaking we material.
So I did,
I imported material for
that first year and we,
we figured out how to make a g
and it was a pain in the ass.
And that first week,
well we finished the week and I called
to deco and I said we made five pairs of
pants this week
and he's like,
really high production dude. I
was just like, what am I doing?
And I kind of start telling that story.
You like legit, we're questioning.
Oh I spiraled down like,
oh my God, you didn't,
you thought you were going to make 200
g's in a week and he or de Pants and
weekend you make five,
five, five pairs of pants.
I was just mind boggling,
mind boggling.
And Jill was my first teacher.
She's still with us today.
The one you were talking
about earlier. Yeah, dude,
I did not know what to do.
I was truly at a loss for,
I didn't have anybody do.
They teach me about how to manufacturer,
like how you should set this up because
the knowledge had disappeared out of the
state. It was gone. The folks
that used to do that stuff,
either they've passed or there
they've moved on, they're snowbirds,
they moved to Florida,
whatever, they weren't around.
So I had a lot of late nights
by myself in my basement
with a glass of whiskey.
I started to have that feeling come
back of that like failure feeling and
I didn't know what to do as like
what did I get myself into, you
know, like what, what are you doing?
Like how do you,
what am I doing?
And then I figured like
I cannot
basically like I can't do
this alone type of situation.
And in a conversation with my
father in law's like Joe, man,
I need to talk to somebody who's like
been there and done that and like done,
built something from nothing.
And he's like pds. Like,
I've got a friend that he did some work
for in his bulldozer by and finalize a
heavy macra repair machinery mechanic.
And so we made a phone call to this
guy, John, I'll leave his last name out.
And John said, yeah, I'll
meet with Pete. He said,
here's the date and time.
Meet me at my Lake House.
So I showed up at his Lake House and I
sat down and he shook my hand and he said,
let me tell you something,
you're not fucking special.
Now I'm already Pete down.
Just I'm using his words and
you're not fucking special.
Your ideas aren't special
and nobody gives a shit.
How's that? Okay. Motivational
speaker getting after it.
You nobody gives a shit. Yup. I said
reality check. Yeah. I was like,
Oh shit. He goes, what's your problem?
I said, man, Aye. Aye. We need money
to like, he was like, no you don't.
I said, no, we need, we need, we
need money to, to like do this,
to like learn how to do this and
build this and like make this happen.
I need money.
The capital.
He goes,
Pete w were you in the back of your mind
thinking you had good capital investor
right here is a big gala,
the lake house,
and maybe this guy's going
to throw to tgs at, you know,
nope,
I wasn't there for financial,
uh, financial, uh, I wasn't looking,
but that was the solution that you saw.
You didn't come from him. You just
thought, I need money for this thing,
only solution.
I need money.
And as he kind of like beat me down
and this guy ran like a 50 [inaudible],
I think they're $100 million company now.
At that point it was $50 million and he
was kind of retired and doing his thing
and giving his time to me for free to
help another kid from industry main
succeed.
He basically educated me in two hours,
educated me and I walked away from
that meeting like with a plan,
a plan of action. What
was like, what was the,
the big takeaways he told me I need to
basically find out who I was and do a
personality profile.
Uh,
and he goes, you're
probably what he say. N,
I, N, f, j, something like
that. He like guessed it.
Um, or an I an Ega. I'm not
even exactly sure what it was.
So I did my personality profile to find
out my strengths and weaknesses and it
was spot on. I was like, Holy
Shit, this is added like crazy.
And uh,
then he told me,
you're not all in,
you don't really want to win at this.
I was like, no, I do. Then go all
in. How much do you believe in it?
Because there's a million
frigging people like you.
He said there's a million people like
you and a million great ideas and less
than 1% are willing to go and
chase it and go all in and do it.
Are you one of those
people and if you are,
solve the money problem and
solve the rest of the problems.
The next day I was at the bank signing
my home away with my wife by my side.
She was stoked for a $200,000 loan.
That was tougher.
Her two things as you were saying them,
there's a big difference.
You put them together,
which is when you put them together,
it makes sense. But chasing your goals,
chasing your dream and being
all in does not in the same,
not the same things. Now, now if you're
all in and did, you have to chase it. You,
you don't even know what else
to do besides chase it. Right.
But I think some people, they, they chase
it, but they're running like half speed.
Yep. And I was a half speed. Yeah, it's
awesome. You gotta be uncomfortable.
That's basically what I took away from
that. And he's the one that told me,
he said, Pete, how old are you? I said,
I'm 30 what's your problem?
I said,
I'm going to get John on the podcast
at some point. I'm stuck. Yeah. I said,
I was stuck.
He goes,
you got three more chances. He's like,
I'm 60 you got three more chances.
He's like, if you believe in it. And he's
the one that told me everything in life.
Everything great takes 10 years to build,
go build it and be committed because
it's got to take 10 years to build it.
But if you believe in it,
you have to go all in and if
you got to put up your house,
put up your house,
you'll work your way out of it eventually.
So that's what I did.
I followed his advice and I went all in.
He also told me, the moment
you stop growing, you die.
He said, if you stop
growing, you will die.
The moment you want to do something
different than what you're doing,
the moment your mind wanders to
wanting to be somewhere else,
your business also dies
and you need to recognize that.
And that first meeting with him was just,
it just changed my,
changed my game and when I
signed my name on that loan,
when I signed my home to the
bank to receive that check,
I was laser focused.
It's like being in the woods on an early
morning hunt when it's dark and the sun
is coming up in the and the and the and
the leaves go right as the sun hits the
leaves,
it's the trees
and you're waiting right for the deer,
for whatever you're hunting.
That's what I felt like about business.
The same feeling you get from that.
I felt laser focused and it's like
everything just opened up like my mind
opened, like the synopsis connected
and I was at like a new Pr,
a nuance.
I was noo.
That's what I mean by like you can't
hear when was born an entrepreneur.
You're not born an entrepreneur.
You need to get punched in the face.
And John Punched me right in the nose.
It was awesome.
So the next step is
you order some material, but that's
not your longterm plan. Right? And,
and the next thing you do is you go,
we got to make this material more skills.
We've got to make the material.
I had called every use textile
company in the United States,
every use textile company to
try and find this machinery.
We had to weave our own fabric.
It wasn't a sustainable model
without waiving our own fabric.
They're all like, it's just
not going to happen. I'm like,
what is it to get set up million dollars,
right?
750 grand.
This is to buy a brand new loses the by
Lou, the operational experience in there.
And they're going to send you from the
factory after they build this loom,
they'll send you a guy that's going to
help you run it all set up is that we
just need $1 million. Yeah, exactly.
It's just not going to
happen. So I was like, okay,
in business it's like boxing.
Like it's like Jujitsu.
It's all about the angles. You know when
people get so stuck on like one angle,
they could only see that one angle and I
just had to like I the step to the side
and I had to see this angle.
I knew Maine had a heritage and weaving.
I knew there was weaving here at one
point and so I went back to that same old
timer in Lewiston,
Maine who had sold me my first sewing
machine and I sat in his office and I
said, no, where there aren't any looms.
It's like, what do you mean?
I'm like a weaving loom,
like to weave fabric. He
goes, get in my truck.
I get in his truck,
we drive up one street and get
out and this is massive building.
It's like,
uh,
I think total square footage was
like 1.5 million square feet low,
mostly abandoned a few businesses in
the front that they've refurbished
and there's a museum there
and in walks in and he introduces me
to this woman Rachel, and he says,
Rachel, this is Pete.
He's looking for a loom.
And she goes, well, follow me.
She made me sign a release.
We went up the stairs and into this
old mill five and the floorboards,
the windows were all broken.
The sawtooth building,
you know the saw tooth mill buildings
and windows were all broken and the wood
was all punky and like,
like all bent up and splintered.
You had like watch where you're walking
and there's this big green nasty thing
sitting in the middle of the floor right
there in this whole place. And
we walk over to it. She's like,
I need to get rid of this.
And I'm like, this is a whom
he, she's like, Yup. I said, Holy Shit.
Where's the rest of them?
They shipped them overseas.
Company in India bought us,
bought about automile and they shipped
everything overseas and she goes,
I kept this one. I kept it here because
I wanted to put it in the museum,
so we didn't lose our heritage day.
I said, can I buy it? And she
said, Yep. I said, how much?
She had 3000 bucks. I
said, okay, done men,
and this is it. Like I just want
to point this out. The the, the,
the floor is all broken.
The windows are broken and the
loom is like rusty, right? Oh Dude,
this is not like this. This
thing is disaster. When's
the last time it was used?
How many years ago? Oh, eighties it was,
it's an 83 it's like a 1983 I don't
know when the last time it was used,
but it hadn't been, had any
love for a long, long time.
Most of the parts were stripped off of it.
It was like a frame,
just like an infrastructure.
I said, okay, I'll buy it.
I'm going to buy this loom.
Yeah.
So you've got to be a little bit naive
to be in business and think you can
accomplish anything. That's the
bottom line. And I was pretty,
pretty driven and naive to think
that we could weave fabric,
but I believe that we could.
So she sold me it and then I called my
father in law and I said, I got a loom,
it's on the third floor of
this old mill in Lewiston,
Maine and we need to get it out.
And I got a quote on moving in and it
was $25,000 to move it. And I'm like,
we're gonna move it. And he's like, okay.
So I've got a bunch of friends.
We went up there,
took nine guys,
eight hours to move it from the middle
of the floor to the edge of the building.
And we
had another friend who had a crane and
we ended up getting it out and onto a
trailer and put it in the factory.
And then we were like,
why are we do dear?
And it was awesome.
It was awesome.
So that's where it started.
Uh,
you know, it's, I always believe like
if it was done, it can
be done. Like if it, if,
if you know,
in Maine we have this thing,
like main at one point was 90% field.
How to become 90% fields, you
know, a hundred years ago.
Hands and daylight,
hands in daylight, right.
How were these mill buildings built?
Hands and daylight. That's it.
These people they got
after it. I mean, why?
Because if you don't, you die.
That's it. You're going to die.
So you've got to farm,
you've got to know how to build a house.
You got to know how to start a fire.
Like that culture of New
England is still rich,
you know, it's still passed down.
We burn wood. Everybody Burns.
Would we build our own shit, you know,
houses, everything. That's what we do.
Why is everybody saying
we can't manufacture? We
can't. We've, we can't cut.
And so that's bullshit. If
they did it, we can do it.
Cause they did it with a lot less.
I found a guy, Lenny,
when that mill shut down,
he had a contract to go over to um,
Pakistan,
Pakistan of all places
to teach them how to run the
looms that were purchased
in a month later was nine 11 and
he didn't go and he stayed here,
thank God because he's the last,
he's like the last one left that can
actually get this thing going and make it
work again.
I asked [inaudible] how many
people know what you know?
He said a whole bunch. I said,
well, what's a whole bunch?
She's like five.
So he,
Lenny passes knowledge on US weaving
pattern making for textiles and all this
stuff.
And that's a whole nother
story maybe for different time.
But we started weaving fabric
and we became vertically
integrated and we started
making the product from raw cotton from
what did it feel like the first time
that thing created? Created
like fabric. You must've dude.
He was freaked out. We were
just like, he's just like, uh,
we had the, we had like the pack, like we
had to make Pearl we've, and so we did,
we made pro,
we would like took the up pro we've apart
that was like from the imported fabric
is like we just picked it apart and
Lenny looked at it and figuring out what
size threat, you know, yarns
and the weight and everything.
So we just recreated it and he
turned it on for the first time.
You know how long it took to clean
that thing, 40 man hours to clean it.
Like it just, it need cleaning
before we did anything cleaning,
then we had the buy it,
all the parts are out of a machine
and just to get it going again.
He turned it off for the
first time and it was like,
well,
and I looked at John, my employee,
John and Lenny and I said,
Holy Shit.
And then,
and there comes and it's just, and there's
a pearl. We've coming off the loom,
man, it was so exciting. I was
like, nobody's ever done this.
Nobody's ever done this.
And it was,
I was super proud. I was like, we're,
we're fricking doing it. We are doing it.
And then we announced it to the world.
We thought we still got a
lot of work to do, but, uh,
now we announced it to the Jujitsu world.
That's it, man. That was it.
How do I even want to tell you
the challenges after weaving?
I do color this though. Sold,
like I was telling you before,
when, when I was in this SQL
teams in the early nineties, yeah,
we didn't have the custom gear,
right?
You couldn't buy this stuff
on the Internet from these
tactical companies. Right?
So we made stuff and we had,
we had parachute riggers,
which are the people that pack parachutes,
but in a parachute loft you've got a nice
medium duty and sometimes a heavy duty
sewing machine. And so we would
make our own gear and, and us guys,
like we would kind of get into it a
little bit and I, you know, I had us,
a lot of seals would have
their own, um, you know,
sewing machines and you know,
you'd make gear and some
people would be good at it.
Some people get really good at it.
And I was not one of those people and it,
because,
you know,
there's these little threads and you
got to get these things working right.
The fifth bullet through the,
because all this stuff. Yeah. And so,
and every time I'd like to start
sewing it would just fall apart.
Or like a bird's nest and just mayhem.
And when I see like the loom,
yeah.
With it looks like stress you out.
1 billion is coming through
these little things and,
and therefore wing through.
And then you look on the other
side and all that craziness.
There's like these hundreds of thousands,
it looks like little pins that are
moving and things that are pulling apart.
It's crazy. And then it comes up you
other side and you see this pattern. Yeah.
And He makes me, it actually does
stress. Yeah, I see it. I go, man, I,
I can't be in here for two logs.
I'm freaking out.
Just thinking if I get too close
to these things, oh yeah. My,
my presence will cause disturbances in
the forest and things will go wrong.
I'm not allowed to be in there for very
long. I like, I'm not, I'm, I've got to,
I've got an issue, you know, a
subliminal issue with threads.
And so I keep, I even today I said keeping
a little distance from the machines.
I don't want to foul him up. You guys have
the magic, like stayed away from that.
But yet to see that and, and to even
imagine it like, you know, again,
as a novice person working with
a sewing machine as a young kid,
the how hard it was for me to do it. And
then like I was watching Julietta Wham,
wham, Wham, just hammering, you're
just, it's like such a good craft,
such good skill to have and,
and just to see the loom and all those
different parts, you're saying yourself.
Well for one thing like good luck, like
somebody wants to do what we're doing.
Go. Yeah, do it. You have fun
with that one. Not Happening.
But by the way we bought the
last loom switch. You're screwed.
Yeah, absolutely. And the last
bit of knowledge with six,
which exists. Yeah man.
And so then you know,
you,
you take and you start weaving it and
now you starting to sell gies and how's
business going now?
Now you're able to put on something
made in the USA 100% and that's from the
dirt to the shirt. Yeah. Code
Rod rod already dirt to shirt.
Right.
I mean because field to finish because
the cotton is coming from Tennessee Delta
region, Tennessee spun in the
Carolinas and shipped up to us.
That's like the,
that's old school fricken right.
It is the way it's supposed to work.
Hats, old school making shit. You know.
I mean
I talked today a little bit at
our grand opening about like
Mainers
generations of folks that put their
hands on something right there makers,
they need to make something in.
They're trying to cross train
these people to type on a computer,
you know,
do mundane office type of tasks,
filing papers,
answering the phone and call centers.
These people want to make shit.
We're known in Maine for being some of
the best crafts people in the world.
The products that come from Maine or
some of the best products in the world.
And to be part of
resurrecting that heritage is,
it's incredible, you know, and it
is our ultimate mission, you know,
to resurrect our heritage in manufacturing
and build old world level quality the
products and stand behind it,
stitch every, stitch, every,
every yarn in the,
and that's what we're all about.
And that's what origins stands for with
a little bit more modern look and feel.
But sourcing and manufacturing
100% in the u s and I,
we won't compromise on that at ever.
Like other companies do when
they get greedy and they say,
well,
it's time to look at the numbers.
It's time to increase the margins and we
got to import some of this stuff. Nope,
we're not. We're just not doing
it. It's just not happening.
I was in at bath iron
works for the awesome,
the Christening of the
USS Michael Mont store,
obviously named after Michael Monster War.
And it was awesome for me. You know, I,
I enlisted in the navy from that down
in Portland and to come back 26 years
later and see what you're talking about,
what I knew existed in
New England in Maine and,
and seeing the pride that these,
you know,
ship builders,
the iron workers that did the pride that
they took in that ship named after a
saint of a human being.
And you know,
that's one of the things that I tied to
origin cause I knew what you were doing
up here. Yeah. And um, you know,
to kind of get to how we
ended up joining forces.
It's funny because you know, you
were just some guy, you know,
some crazy guy up in Maine
in my opinion that I'd,
well I'd seen a couple of your videos
and I've seen it. I see a dude, you know,
you have the video that shows you pulling
this freaking loom out of this factory.
And I'm just thinking to myself,
this guy is insane and I think
I like him and I had actually,
the funny thing is for my gym
in San Diego, victory MMA,
I wanted to make Jujitsu gies in
America and so I was like, okay, this,
I looked around,
I find one guy that's doing it,
it's you w w like three or four years ago,
we went back and forth
on email and you know,
nothing ever came of
it because I was busy.
You were busy and just nothing happened,
but I always just remember, hey,
you know what? This guy up in
Maine, he's, he's, he's doing what?
He's doing it the right way.
And what happened was the weight we
actually got connected was I was on a
Facebook live just talking
to people and someone says,
what kind of, Gee should I get? And
I just rattled off. I go, hey man,
if you're going to,
if you need a g,
you're starting Jujitsu or you're good
at Jujitsu or you just want a good gee,
I go get a Guinea from origin
origin main.com. I go get
a gift from there. I go,
this crazy guy up there,
he a Lou,
I can't say it without laughing
because it's so pretty. I'm like,
he took a loom out of uh,
out of a broken factory and he refurbish
that thing with his team and they built,
you know, they're doing it, they're
building it. So if you need a key,
I said I'd try and talk
to this guy cause I had,
I had reached out to you a couple
of times of, through various,
even since the time I
asked for, for uh, Jeez,
I'd said sent you an email or
something. And I said, you know,
I'm trying to talk to him. If anybody
knows this guy, his name is Pete.
I go tell him I said,
what's up?
And this awesome woman that
listens to the podcast,
her name is Sarah Armstrong, and
she's super squared away, you know,
a professional with a, with a
big company. And she, you know,
she had communicated me with
the various things over the,
over the past year that I've been
doing the podcast and whatnot, and for,
she said, Oh, I'll take that for action.
And she contacted, she contacted you,
called me. And what'd she say?
She just said, uh, you basically,
she's like, have you heard of this guy?
Jockowillink and dude,
I'm sorry.
I had my head up my ass for the last five
years trying to build this factory no
factor. And I was like, you're like, who?
Oh, and then so you know, what do I do?
I dig. I'm like, Holy Shit. I'm like,
this guy is making some waves.
This is awesome. And so,
uh,
I did a little recon and then
I reached out to after that.
And what's awesome is I had no idea
what we were going to do. Yeah.
Um,
you know,
we went back and forth couple of times
on email and then finally you're like,
hey man, let's, let's just go to Skype,
right. Let's do Skype. Because we'd been,
I today, you know, when you want
to do something, you're like,
I want to do somebody want to do.
I'm like, well, let's pick, you know,
figure it out. Send me an
email about this. You're like,
how about we do a Skype call?
So I have my meetings,
like scheduled, I'm working all day. Sure.
And I blocked two hours.
I'm like, you know what,
this is probably going to take awhile
to get this conversation going on about
two hours or we're just going to get on
Skype and make this happen or figure out
what we can do.
So we ended up talking
on Skype for four hours,
talking, laughing,
talking, laughing, yelling.
After I got off, my wife goes, it
sounded like you were talking to you.
That's not good.
She was a little scared and uh,
and it was just, you know, it was,
it was awesome for me. It was,
you know, the things that I
believe in as, as an American,
as a person, as a new
Englander, it was like a,
you had the thing that I didn't
have, right? Like w you know,
for instance, we're, we're, we're
making things, we're building things,
but we don't have vertical integration.
We don't, we didn't, we weren't,
we weren't doing it the way
I want to get it done and so,
you know what I'm saying?
Hey like join forces.
Absolutely.
And from my perspective,
of course I was like this
dude is for real. I was like,
I would already told my wife.
I was like, man, this guy,
he's on another level and we,
we had been like looking for somebody,
I remember talking with the Deco
and the psych in too. It's like Ah,
you've got all these world champs and
then you have like the flavor of the month
guys with like a fancy
Jujitsu stuff and we just,
it just was never part of our plan
to sponsor Jujitsu world champions.
Right. Because what we were trying to
build is like much bigger than that.
It's like, man, we've been talking
for like a year. Like we need to,
we need to find somebody
or partner somebody with
somebody that like represents
origin through and
through in multiple ways.
This is impossible. You, we
will not find this person.
It's not possible.
And then
you're, you're, you were, we were
talking to earlier today, this was,
this was classic because
I didn't remember this.
So for those of you that know
anything about negotiation,
whether you're negotiating
a car purchase or whatever,
one of the things,
one of the tactics of negotiation
is you don't give a number first.
So if I want, if, if echo wants
to buy these sunglasses, he says,
how much are these?
I don't say they're 10 bucks.
Cause what if he was willing to pay 20
right? So, so, you know, if, if he says,
how much of these I go, well, you know,
what are you willing to pay for him?
And then he should say, well, you know,
I don't know. What are they worth to you?
And so Pete and I had the textbook.
It was, it was more than that though,
because it was,
it was the strategies is like,
what are you gonna do while you've got to,
you've got to devalue or show value
me. So going back and forth, well,
well, yeah, well, yeah, yeah. But you
know, it's like, you know, back and forth,
battle, battle battle. And
then I caved. They did.
So we were trying to figure out the
value of whatever, if something and,
and I'm like, well, Geez, you know what?
Like, you know, just give me, I mean,
what if you had to, what would you, what
would you say a number of eve of that?
And, and he's, you know, he's gives
me x and I didn't remember doing this,
but he told me that. And then I
remembered as he says, you know,
the value's probably x and I
went to your weekend spoken.
We both started laughing because
we've been playing the game was like,
actually that is what,
like both,
I think both of us realized we were just
let, let's just get it, let's do this.
But actually, you know, I'm
busy. You're busy. Yeah.
And so we,
and we actually,
we both definitely got
along. We, we, I mean,
I think both of us felt really
solid about the other person,
but we didn't quite figure out how to,
we couldn't figure out how to
make this work. Yeah. You know,
he's got something that he's put
years of blood, sweat and tears into.
I've got something that I've been doing.
My life has been to get to here and so
we just couldn't quite figure out, wow,
this was going to work.
So we just, you know,
we kept in touch a little
bit of conversation over
the next couple months and
then I knew I was going
to Maine. You, you,
you can I gotta ask you
something now? Yeah. Do you,
you knew you were coming to Maine. I knew
you were coming to Maine. Neither of us.
Like we didn't text back and forth until
the last minute because I knew the date
you were coming to Maine. Uh Huh. Did you,
were you planning on a meeting when
you came to Maine the whole time are
definitely knew we needed to meet.
Yeah.
He's like, you were icing me, be on ice.
I thought I was putting you on ice.
We were both on ice. Yeah.
So that was an oil is it?
That was like the meeting. Who Will,
awesome. When we met up in Portland, uh,
we had dinner. We actually both
brought our wives and I and I,
my wife is always too busy to do
anything business wise with money.
So she was super stoked to even be
around and meet a man and everything.
And you know,
you,
we sat there are wives don't even know
what they were doing because you and I
were just in the zone and,
and at the end of the night we figured
out and we shook hands on it and I knew
right there we were good. We, we, we
crafted the deal. That was awesome. Yeah,
it was awesome for both of us.
It was awesome for everything that
both of us want to achieve. And it did.
He turned into not even both of us started
to us. Exactly. And that was awesome.
And I think one of the best,
like lessons learned from,
from me,
what is just an incredible opportunity.
That's how I see opportunity in crafting
a deal is making sure that you're both
getting what you want in your both a
little bit uncomfortable so that you
continue to
feel a little bit of the struggle to
make sure you can take it over the goal
line. Right. You're too comfortable,
you'll become complacent,
bite off a little more than you can chew
and you're going to be chewing for much
longer. So that's, that's something
that was important. It was awesome.
Yeah. Ed. So just so everyone knows,
I mean know I've been saying it like
we're partners, you know, we're,
we're partners with,
with the podcast in what,
what echo and I had been doing for the
last couple of years and what origin been
has been doing for the last five
years? Seven years. Four, five,
five years. Six years. Yeah. Six years.
And at the end of the night when we
got done eating our steaks in Portland,
Maine, uh, we shook hands
and, and this whole,
you know, you've described
it as like a perfect storm,
which is what it feels like
to me. Hey Man, I was born
in Gloucester. There you go.
It is the perfect score. Go. You got,
we are the perfect storm. Yeah. Um, and,
and so that's what's going
on is that you don't,
now we've got this and
we joined forces and,
uh, that we, we both compliment
each others, you know, in,
in terms of our business,
we compliment each other's weaknesses
in terms of our personalities.
We compliment each other's
weaknesses and WWE were,
and the best part about it is the
whole time that we're doing it,
we're actually laughing our asses off
at each other and having a great time,
which is, which is what it's all
about. So that's where we're at.
That's why we're here, by the way. That's
why we're here. By the way, in Farmington,
Maine, in the origin
factory, 20,000 square feet,
we're going to end up with how
many employees in here in a year?
How many employees were going to
have in here? Oh, probably in a year.
I don't know. 30, 40, 50.
I mean, somewhere in there,
you know, between 30 and 50.
That's in a year by,
remember this is a start.
We're starting.
And so in five years we're going
to have a lot of people. Oh yeah,
we're and people ask, what are you
going to make? Everything. And I say,
we're gonna make everything.
Everything that I use in my life,
I want it made here in America,
from the shorts to the hats,
everything.
And that's what we're going to do.
Beanies,
uh, probably pants, pants. You know
what? I was at a store the other day,
uh, you know, like a hardware store,
but with a big one where they sell
work clothes. And I said to myself,
you know, let's just, cause obviously
I'm thinking about this all the time now,
you know, it's hard, hard to look at
work clothes and you say, of course,
American workers, they would want
to wear American made clothes.
Were these clothes made?
They're not made here.
And then I made American and they're
not made by American hands. Um,
so I think we're going to be in a take
no prisoners scenario and we're going to
Jay after it went on.
I just kind of take no prisoners.
We're going to chase the big dogs.
He'd look out, listen and
look out. And that's not,
that's not like an ego thing. That's
the truth. Yeah. Listen and look out.
Yeah. And like I said
today, when, when you,
when you rekindle the fire
now of manufacturing and the,
you rekindle, I mean, just talking
to talking to the employees here,
this is what they want to do.
100% and this is what they
made to do. That's right.
And like you said,
they want to take these things and
build them with their hands who got it.
And that Opportunity's been taken away
in the last 25 years and we're bringing
it back and that is awesome. Appreciate
that. Glad to have you as part of it.
Awesome.
That's what we did. Echo
Charles Right now, my brother,
speaking of what we do.
Sure.
Why don't you do what you do.
I have a question or you ask a question.
Do you find it
poetic that the origin
logo is that circle?
Remember when you were getting shit
from the politician? It's funny. No,
never thought about that. Now you
have an origin logo. That's a circle.
Okay.
It is a bill. That kinda in and of
itself is like a circle. It's actually,
it is a wave. It's a, it's
actually like a rip curl wave.
Is that what that logo is?
The is the flow.
Did you Jitsu flow? The surf flow? The
store. It's a wave is what that is.
And that's what breaking symbolic is.
What they'd call it. I'll just say ironic,
but that's not ironic cause symbolic.
Symbolic. Symbolic. So yeah.
Oh no one even remembers that. I don't
even remember who that politician was.
It doesn't even matter. Nope. They're
going to know what that origins dry
in the industry or we call that
layers. True Story. Anyway,
speaking of layers. Got
It. And support by the way,
support this podcast and yourself.
Yeah.
Origin main.com. Speak of the
devil. That's how you could support.
Yeah. So good to know.
What do we got geese.
So that's the thing from the beginning.
People ask what's the key to get?
We know, we don't know. It's hard to
100% now. Hundred percent. You know,
he had like a hierarchy. You
know, he only has one genome,
but you have multiple selections though.
Yeah. So they do absolutely. Boom. Edward,
we're about to like blow
up our manufacturing.
Um, and this new factory
again, grand opening today.
Lots of product coming right
on the east side of stuff.
Ramping things up over the next,
what time frame we've started ramping,
uh, over the next four to
six, four to eight weeks.
Let's say we're going to be
hiring another 16 people.
We put another loom in the factory.
So there's just three looms now and
we're going to be weaving Ninjas.
Like, like super real. It's like I,
I mean I didn't want to elaborate. You
just come, come to Maine and see, yeah.
Anytime in the factory. Come
check it out. I like it.
When are the shorts coming
out that I'm wearing? Oh boy.
Cause they're straight up.
My best short now
we're going to make it happen.
Well Hey, I get that all the
time. Hey, when is the, you
know, Xyz coming out. Hey,
so now it's on you a little
bit, you know. But yeah,
these are straight up
the best shorts though.
It's not actually that hard for you
because people say when's that next? Oh,
you're talking about the,
the the gear side. Yeah,
the merchandising side.
And I do believe that it might be a little
bit more work on pizza and compare it
to on my end a little bit. But
Hey, I don't know from a, from a,
if you go from like the level
that you're currently cruising at,
maybe you both have to travel the same
distance it relative to the work done,
relatively speaking. I think you're right.
And yeah, but not just geese, right? No,
no. We bunch of, you know,
apparel, everything is, you know,
like our t shirts or knit.
Like we have a partner that knits,
knits all the fabric like six hours
away or something. Everything's,
everything's sourced and made here.
We make all our own compression
apparel like cotton.
So sublimate dye sublimation, everything
you say. Compression apparel. Yeah.
I still call it a rash guard. It's
a rash guard. I know. I'm just,
because I know it's not just a rash guard.
This rash guard is for surfing. Right.
But, but, but like the, like, like the,
we still call it in the Jujitsu
community, don't we still say? Yeah,
I got a new rash guard. Oh yeah. Well he's
still saying that. I'm just making sure,
cause I wasn't like hearing
someone at the gym saying like,
did you check out this new compression
on the weight room? They do say that.
Right. I see. Like in
football. Football, yeah.
Like you'll see some company that's
advertising compression gear. Yeah, yeah,
yeah, yeah, exactly. And I'm like, Oh,
you mean a rash guard trying be on me.
You got to remember like every textile
is different than what you're used to.
Like,
like the warp wit we use are our textile
for the rash card or tights or whatever
else is different.
And you just called him tights?
I did because spats,
I have no idea what a SPAC is
going to say out in California.
It's definitely called spats,
spats.
And I don't even know where
that word comes from. Spat.
I knew spats is when you tape your ankles,
you spank your leg.
I bet you,
I bet you wait,
did this spats go down your leg
like tights and it around your foot?
Just tape over it.
He just take,
but instead of your ankles
under your socks or whatever,
if you take over everything
over your shoe, over everything,
trainer stopped doing cause it's, so
why don't we call him compression pedal?
Cause I'm gonna be,
I'm gonna be, you know,
earlier we got kind of like wrapped around
or we got sidetracked about me being
sensitive about something or
not being sensitive tights.
You're not down for 10 a dude. Right?
We're not wearing tights, not happening.
Pants come. Compression pants. That
sounds good. Compression shirt.
See their ego compression
shirt, compression and rash
pants, rash guard pants.
That doesn't make sense either. Does
it, even though they do prevent rashes
or did you get to met burn these?
You know why people,
you know why a lot of people
wear compression pants
and compression shirts in
Jujitsu, the prevention
of the disease, the funk,
right? They don't want
the hing horn, right?
They don't want that to hit one reward.
They don't want, you know, whatever.
Various Bursa and so people wear that
and the people that I know that where it,
they seem to believe in it. Oh yeah.
Just the level of, it's not like, uh,
like the,
what's the sun protection bringing
pf last 50 or UPF UPF yet UPF 50.
There's no anti ring warm
percentage rating. Right, right.
There's the general end time.
My crew will Beall. Right.
Like certification and that keeps
it from growing in the material.
What I'm saying is if you were like a
compression shirt and compression pants,
sure.
Then you're not rubbing your skin against
some savage that came into the gym or
have ringworm, so you have less percentage
with him too. But yeah, we're rolling.
Put a triangle on his ringworm on
his or something like this. Yeah,
you don't need that,
so you don't want it.
That's a good reason to wear compression
gear ration card across the board and
the rash guards are there now.
They're not like the rash guard.
You're used to the ones you put on and
then they on talk and then you talk about
it in the on talking and talking man.
They're designed to stay tucked in so
you put them on and the way the fibers
flex and bend with your body.
It's not your mothers or
grandmothers rash garden.
So when, when you say tucked in because
you don't really tuck in a rash guard,
right? Or do you? You're talking
about under the Ghia. Okay.
Oh yeah. That's, that's a whole
new world right there. Yeah.
Some places make you wear rash
guard under your G. Oh, okay. Yeah.
I think it's good to have
a rash guard in here.
I know a lot of people think that it's
not traditional. I mean I misread dish.
Yeah. In that one. I liked the barrier.
I liked the, I liked the key or
the, I liked the barrier, um,
between the, the, the fabric and the skin.
I like to compression because
you compress your muscle,
you get more use your straight
performance performance.
Yup. Got It. Absolutely.
The key slides a little bit better on a
rash guard than it does your skin once
it's all sweated up and sticky.
So that's why he use it. And um,
I Harry Creek too. Nobody wants
a chest hair space. That's right.
They don't want that. You know, would
be happy if we all wore rash guards.
She's our black belt at our gym,
female and she is still a girl.
So things like chest hairs. Yeah.
She's not happy about those. Those,
she begs me to where you don't something
under my gate. She's so far failed.
Failed on my grown man. But um, you know,
the other thing is you,
we didn't talk about origin
main.com is supplements. Absolutely.
So on the body and in your body.
There you go. That's it. There you go.
We're going to put everything you need
on your body and everything you need in
your body. Krill oil.
Yes. Really that's the,
that's the one now it's Krill
oil and then a super critical,
one of the things that you know,
you'll be happy to know that Pete and I,
we like to make things happen and you
know obviously I'm a big fan of Krill oil
for instance.
So you know what I was,
I used to be a fan of white tea.
[inaudible] a big fan and I drank it a
lot and eventually I said you know what,
I need this Jocko white tea.
And so I had a similar thing happened
with Carrillo. I want to have krill oil.
Good Carrillo so you know what
we're making good krill oil. Yeah,
actually we like to call it Jocko super.
So Jocko super grill, we're,
we're making that awesome quality.
On top of that we got a little,
again,
littleG , we need joint
maintenance, right?
We need joint man is when we are active.
When we're training Jiu Jitsu,
when were Jack and big steel?
We are tendons and everything
and get a little bit sore. Sore.
We might not admit to it in public,
just like we wouldn't admit to
crying on a public situation.
Ever uncomfortable with my masculine
has to be because I'm over here. Whoa.
Now don't cry and cry.
My wife says Pete,
the only time you cry is babies and belts.
When someone gets promoted and someone
has a kid. What about weddings? No, no,
no funerals and weddings.
No. So we got another,
another thing we're coming out with.
It's a Jocko joint warfare for your
joints go to war against the pain.
Inflammation in each generation.
Yeah.
And I've been kicking it for since we,
since we originally formulated.
Yep. And I got the samples.
I went on it hardcore and
it's Flagella legit the board
about that.
I have like bad back
from sports and stuff.
Herniated disc,
bulging disc didn't get surgery.
Severe Arthritis.
I can train seven days a week if
I want it to. As a matter of fact,
we have our mission immersion campus
week train every day, every day.
That's it. Joint Warfare,
it keeping it real.
So that stuff we,
it's being manufactured.
We had been on the samples for
one a month and a half. Um,
and now it's been being manufactured
in America check and very close by.
Right. By a partner. Right. And, and
so it's gonna be on the website now,
preorder it. And that way we can
get to get a feel for how much,
cause we've got a bunch coming.
We need to figure out how much of
a bunch is that actually means.
So kind of like with Jocko white tea,
I didn't do that. I just said, oh,
the Jocko white tea for sale.
It was gone.
Then I ordered some more and then that
was going on and people were really
getting angry because when you,
you know,
when you have Jocko white tea and then
you don't have it, all of a sudden,
you know, things start going
sideways. Yeah, absolutely.
So you got to get that back straight up.
So anyways,
you can check those things out.
Origin main.com there'll be there joint
warfare. You like that, don't you? I do.
Yeah. There's a, there's a layer on
there. Yeah. That's deep, deep layers.
Oh yeah. The one person that's going
to get this layer is dean lister.
Yup. Yup, Yup. Trebuchet.
I'll leave it at that. Well,
you know Trump agenda, a lot of
moving parts and a trebuchet. Yeah.
I gotta keep him grease that.
Got to keep that joints. Sure.
Also speaking to jacking steel
kettle bells.
So when we came here,
we're in Maine right now.
If people haven't gathered
that already up in camp. No.
Like big weight room. Kinda. There's
a little fitness center there. Yeah.
First night we get here,
one of the guys, they came,
I brought my Onnit kettle bell
or who wasn't gonna need to
John. John. Yeah, it was John. Yeah.
Nice honey. Kettle Bell. The gorilla.
The ones I just ordered logit their ship.
They're on the way tracking. Anyway. Um,
yeah, that's the good ones. You do kettle
bells. I don't stop lifting though.
That's where I stopped. I did.
I stopped lifting two massive,
well kettlebell massive,
I don't even bring this up because we
talked about this prerecording a so you a
two 53 right now as we talked about,
you use the way to 85 and I asked this
question and this is a good question that
everybody should kind
of hear the answer to.
Could the 250,250 pound Pete beat the
285 pound Pete in a grappling match and
your answer was 100% the smaller guy wins.
Why is that?
I mean lots of reasons.
You're more flexible,
more flexible and better positioning.
Better escapes cause
there's less mass burning,
less oxygen because you have
less muscle mass. And for me,
I would wear the 285
version of myself out.
So it's I,
I stopped and I love lifting weights.
I love lifting weights,
but for me,
Jujitsu fulfills the void because it is
resistance. Yeah, you're always working.
I never feel out of shape.
Well unless I have too many whoopie pies,
but she do anything to work out
besides Jiu Jitsu. Do you run?
Do you sprint? No Day. Just
cause you choose who I do.
Dean lister tells me that when Dean
lister doesn't want to work out,
doesn't want to do any, you know,
sprints. He's like, no, I get,
I get it from Jujitsu Jocko.
That's what my best thing.
So now you're supporting his argument.
Now going to now,
now got to deal with that.
We'll be Robert sued.
You know we will talk about some day
how Jujitsu makes you unathletic.
Oh really? That's a whole
nother talk. Interesting.
And I have facts on why
it makes you on athletic,
what it keeps you. It keeps your
body together, your core together,
your muscles strong.
So what does it do to make you unathletic?
It's slow movement.
You slow,
you start when you started you to your
body slows down, your mind slows down,
your muscle slowed down.
Whenever you had for fast twitch turns
a slow twitch because you're pulling and
tugging and you're moving slow.
I used to be able to dunk a basketball
every dunk so you can't touch the rim.
Now I think we need to,
I will go ahead and defend the Jujitsu
over here on my side of the table because
if you continue to do cleans
and you continue to squat,
yeah. And you can do, you do
sprints and mobility drills and uh,
agility drills. You can keep that
athleticism. I think you're right.
I know you're right jack.
That's what I did when I competed.
I had a strength and conditioning
coach, sprint lift, push, pull.
So I guess big picture is one of those
deals where it kind of confirms the idea
that you don't have to be
athletic to do good in Jujitsu,
generally speaking. But if you want to
do some kind of athletic competition,
including, but not limited to Jiu Jitsu,
it helps to be athletic. Jackson's deal.
Yeah. I'm kind of glad that you kind of
hit them with that because when I said I
stopped doing like legs and stuff like
that, I got a lot of crap for it by hand.
I, I, I did a lot of squats
and college football,
college football. Hell
yeah. I, I'm scared of them.
I like hack squats, hack
squats. Man for sure.
He got bad knees or something bad
back. Bad back. You did my back. Yeah.
But last time I squatted and I
hit the floor. Right. Of course.
Bad back,
bad back from years of major
s and personal question,
does your ego not allow you to get in
there and do 185 pounds for some higher
reps? Nope. I do that 100% but you
still don't like it? I do hack squats.
I still don't write on, I still
don't like it, but I mean it's
steel is great. Yeah. That's the
bottom line. It is great. Yeah.
I just get it. Jujitsu, man.
I pushed. I do. You know,
every time I step on the mats at six 10
minute rounds and I've trained to the
break, so I'm doing 12 minute
rounds. I make sure to get six. Yeah.
And I,
and I get it as,
as things free up and my son wants
to lift as he started the summer,
I'll get in with him and we'll,
we'll press some iron. Yeah.
Yeah. That sounded pretty, pretty
fired up. You want to go there,
press a buyer in a big kettle bells
don't get you that be, I mean,
I'm sure under certain circumstances
they will, but athletic. Yeah,
like a hang clean. Clean them
right here. I'm sorry. The jumpers.
And the other big thing is when
you like for a kettlebell snatch,
it's a swinging motion and when it gets
to the top you have to stop it, right?
Because otherwise you're going
to rip your shoulder out.
So you have to use all this, whatever
that kind of muscle, what is it,
echo centric or something.
What it concentric.
Whenever you've got to do to stop it
at the top, you got to stop it sorts.
It's using all these muscles to make that
thing happen. That's cool. Yeah, I mean,
yeah, yeah, yeah. It's
cool. It'll get fun.
Like when you start getting like the
balance and then the is the momentum,
you got to create momentum. Then
you've got a balance. A moment.
It's like all this stuff is fun.
College. They said that the true,
a true test of how strong somebody is.
I hang clean.
Yeah. And they said you could bench a
lot, you could squat on. Yeah, there's,
there's a lot of people,
there's a lot of things that you could
say that like for instance, you know,
what's a good one? Overhead squat spot.
If you've got a guy that can do massive
way big weight and or, or medium weight,
high reps over and squat this word yet,
but on a hang clean you got to
use your speed also. It's speed,
it's explosive. So you could
just go straight to the
snatch, right? Yeah. Right.
But then again, the snatch, you
need the balance at the top.
That's coordination and then
all these other things. So,
and it depends on what you mean by
strong too. So you know how like I guess,
you know,
in,
in certain circles they call strength
power and strength and power are two
different things. And it's like,
okay, so what are you talking about?
So I dig it and I agree actually.
But this is also 20 years ago. Yeah,
exactly right. You get another point to
consider. That's a really good change.
You think they agree? You said hang clean,
right? Hang clean. That's a real metric.
Yeah. The solid metric. Yeah,
for sure. Dead lift. Another
solid metric, by the way.
Yeah. Raw strength. That's
what, yeah, yeah, yeah.
Cause consider a member by like when
you're a kid or maybe old school kind of
philosophy. It's like, hey, you know, you
get the old timer and he was like, whoa.
Stronger you and you're like real
strong. We're sir. Okay. Pick that up.
You know what I mean? Okay. You can't
pick it up. You're weak. You can't,
you're strong.
And he comes and picks it up
and then the step two is
pick it up over your head.
You've got to dead lift the
deadlift. Yeah. Oh yeah. No,
just kidding. Yeah. Let's not do this.
Yay. That's good. But don't get too
nuts with that though. Who is that?
I was just talking to somebody. There
were lots of dead lifts. It was Ed. Yeah.
He was like, Hey, you know my
back and stuff. I was like,
I don't get crazy with dead lifts.
No.
But you can talk to plenty
of people that say, Oh,
I had a bad back and I dead lifted
and now it's healed. Right, right.
Plenty of [inaudible] would say that
absolutely crazy with them because they
give you good gesture straight,
like your your backs and
bad a lot of times anyway,
even just anywhere in your core is because
when you have like some core or your
back or something, when you do
stuff, you adjust to that. Use it.
And it's a dead lift. Yeah,
because you don't use it anymore.
So now when you do something,
you're grabbing the cranberry
juice from this side.
You're going to put it over here.
You gotta like floor and you're like,
how did I do that?
Cranberry juice.
Sugar in a bottle broke. But you shouldn't
be. That's your body's way of telling.
You don't want that. Cool. Hey Man, I dig
it. Maybe you're grabbing it from here,
put it in the trashcan or something
like this. You know? I'm just saying.
That's why though. So you go
dead lift, not heavy, not crazy.
Just like your buddies like,
like you need lifting.
It's like your buddy just
getting used to it. So boom.
You used to picking stuff up and I
want to try it. Do it. I like it.
Try the kettle bells too. And if you
want the cool ones and when I say cool,
it's like you look at them and they're
cool, like irrefutably cool on it.
That's the ones the gorilla
want to actually don't do
the gorilla on this first.
Do the chimp one first
straight to zombies.
We were just super strong,
doesn't have the same categories and I
forget what they're all called Zombie.
When I look at the legend versus the
gorilla ones or the primate ones too.
To the zombies. I wanted
the ones that look crazy and
evil. Yeah, that's no biggie.
I think we both, we all collectively
know why you want the zombies.
Technically it's so, but that brings
up a good point in my opinion.
All the different categories, primal
bills, that's the champ, the, you know,
all the things, different zombies,
all zombies, legends, Werewolf,
cyclops, cyclops, like all the
legends. So boom, pick your category.
But that's the cool ones. I recommend.
What else? Check them out. Hey man,
jump ropes off kind of.
Actually, it's Kinda good.
You go in there and they have all kinds
of workout stuff like stuff, you know,
haul brag. You know how when you
get into a workout, maybe not you,
you're not like this, but like I got
into the kettle bells and it became fun.
You know, you know how like, um,
if something becomes fun for me,
I stopped doing it and do something
that sucks, but well, Dang this
psychologically challenging,
but they got all kind and they
have like the Macy's and you know,
all the workout stuff or whatever.
Anyway,
that's a go down on it.com/jocko check
out that stuff and man get after it.
Even if you're getting bored,
man,
you've got some interesting stuff to
work out with. Highly recommend. Awesome.
Also, if you like these books,
Pete didn't write a book.
Wait to have you written a book before and
I wouldn't be surprised.
I wrote along ass paper when I
couldn't sleep over the last year,
but total book. So yeah, little
bit different. But anyway.
A lot of times Jocko, we'll review books
on this podcast. People like to get them.
If you're one of those people out there,
go the website,
chocolate podcast.com section
books from the podcast.
Click through there to get the books.
That's a good way to support it.
Takes you to Amazon or if you're
doing any of the other shopping,
do it through their big support.
Small actions. My action.
Big Reaction. Nice. Also,
subscribe to the podcast.
Google play. We still feel the need
to say that. Yeah, because what?
Some people aren't subscribed
in the event, you know it's it.
I guess it's just our guests,
my guests. There's probably
hype type pot. This is speaking as
my hypothesis is what I'm saying.
There's probably a marginal group
who's like, Hey, who's Jocko?
I heard him on Joe Rogan, or I
don't know. I seen him on whatever,
and then I call him and listen to
the podcast. I was like, okay, cool.
Well listen to let me listen to another
one. Okay, cool. Maybe I'm not down.
You know, he's kind of weird or just
whatever they don't understand. Like, oh,
I can subscribe to this, but I can just
get it'll, it'll tell me when it's coming.
Right. Cause a lot of people don't
listen to podcasts. Yeah. I know.
I got a question for you about that.
Have you thought about, cause you,
this is number 90.
Have you thought about breaking the
podcasts into categories to speak to your
audience because you cover such a broad
audience? Um, when you say breaking them,
you just another section like
cutty had him up. No, no, no.
The full podcast where
you're covering books,
where you're talking about business,
where you're interviewing somebody,
breaking them up that way.
Yeah. They are a cent tech.
There's not a linear, right. You
don't have to listen from you. Right.
I recommend when someone
says, Hey, you know,
I just heard your
podcast. I heard, I heard,
I just isn't that podcast you just put
out, I want to listen to the rest of them.
Should I go backwards? Should
I go forward? And I tell
people start at one and,
and, and most of the people that I
talked to that are into the podcast,
they're like, that's the
right advice. Tell people,
start at one. If I said Jocko,
I want to listen to your real
business related podcasts,
I couldn't, could I do that or
know what we are going to do?
And I have this in the background going
into something that I've been trying to
get done for a while is we're gonna
kind of archive where you're going to be
able to maybe figure out,
oh I want to listen to business.
Boom and here's a podcast,
a section.
Now whether or not we'd like chop them
up and put them into one group, um,
not yet. Not yet. Not yet.
Yeah. I mean it, you're, yeah,
it's not organized we'll say,
but you know,
it's one of those things you've
got to manually look, you know,
cause it'll say what it's
about. In fact, the Puck,
it's straight up by timestamp
talking about, you know,
that you can kind of do it that way. But
no, not organized. Like if, if you're,
and it makes sense though,
because if we're talking about a book
and people like what Love World War II
love pull most 10 podcasts in world war
two and they can just get after it and
then maybe, you know, just an
idea. Good Idea Pete House.
Big Time. But yeah, subscribe. That's
a good one. If you haven't already.
How about that? If you haven't
already subscribed, that's
a good one. Also, youtube,
subscribe to Allen
Nouns a little bit more.
Like make sense to be
like, hey, subscribe to,
and the big thing that you might not know
is if you're not subscribed to youtube,
there could be things that
are not in the podcast. Yeah.
So let's say you liked the podcasts,
you're listening to it and you go, yeah,
well I've heard all the podcasts. I don't
need to get youtube. You're wrong. Yeah.
Because there could be things
released into the youtube.
I have not been released, for instance,
deleted scenes, deleted scene,
which is us talking some off the record
about things like people that have
certain, you know, what issues,
uh, nothing, bro. Lack of
squatting issues. Brassy.
Yeah. And I said I had stopped
squatting because of blockchain.
The technically the story goes, I stop
squatting because my wife said, hey,
your legs are like real
big and it looks weird.
That's funny cause my wife said
you're starting to get an old man but
cold the same thing me,
I don't know dude. Dang. Just
like it though. I'm squatting.
You need to get all the songs but
like kettle bell swings. Bull.
Yeah. That's what they
say. They say that the,
the regular or the Russian kettlebell
swings posterior chain a new day.
I learned that either way.
Yeah, the deleted scenes.
That's what he was giving me shit about,
cause I stopped squatting.
Actually I didn't stop squatting.
I stop squatting like hardcore legs.
You know what I'm saying? He stops
crying. He said the point is,
is you stopped squatting
deleted scenes or on their
uh, excerpts to, you know,
like let's say you were like,
Hey, I liked that part and people
still email me about that by the way.
What are like, Hey, what was that
part? Or what episode was that?
From that part where it, whatever.
So instead of having to scour,
share that excerpts,
easy to find. So yeah,
that's a good and subscribe to
youtube also. Jocko is a store,
it's called Jocko store Jocko store.com.
Guess what's on there?
Everything.
Potentially everything.
But as of right now, there's some
shirts on their women's stuff,
on their patches on there. You know, you
put them on your hat, interchangeable,
velcro patches if you
will. Rash guards. Awesome.
So now they have two options,
Huh?
Jocko rash guards get after
it to trooper darkness.
Rash guards and origin rash guards. Yeah.
Just like that. The selection just vast.
Yeah. And eventually they're going
to be right. And this will be, we'll,
it'll all be kind of melt together
as one big vast place to just go.
And these going to be a melting
pot of Awesomeness, right? Yes,
indeed. Indeed. Yeah. All that. So,
and some hoodies on there.
Yeah.
I think we should consult. No.
[inaudible] I'm going to tell you,
I already know what he's gonna
say. He's from Hawaii. What,
you want a lightweight Hoodie? No, he, he,
so he made hoodies and I'm from New
England. That's all. It's like, oh,
you make a Hoodie,
you can wear it in like a full fledge
Arctic storm and you're going to have a
heavyweight cotton hoodie. So his, his
hoodies are, are, are light. They're,
they're cool for so cal.
Yeah, they're good for Hawaii.
If you even have hoodies in Hawaii,
they're like a fall Hoodie I guess.
And even that's like,
my guess. I don't know.
That's why I'm saying we should consult.
I mean his,
his like his consultation things
when I consult him like, Hey, it's,
it's like mixed in with a scolding.
So, you know, I get the scolding first,
then the info like maybe
I want to make a really, really bad
ass flat locked Hoodie or to do it.
What is a flat, what does that, wait
a sec. That seemed Hoodie. Well,
how could we possibly do that?
[inaudible] where are we
going to get someone that
knows how to make flat locked?
Awesome. Badass hoodies. Hm. Oh wait,
we're sitting. Get him a factory
where we can make it happen.
The big one. There you go.
That's good stuff also. Hmm.
Psychological warfare. Previously,
a few minutes ago we talked about
joint warfare for joint degeneration.
In summation, all that stuff.
Overall, real generous.
Generally supplementation for your body.
Yeah.
Sometimes you need supplementation for
your mind. Your mind. Yes. Full on.
So in your campaign against weakness,
psychological weakness,
you know you're trying to get up
every day, right? Stick to the Diet.
Can that help me with eating
multiple whoopie pies?
Yes. Yes, yes. Actually, there
isn't a specific tab for this.
I'm definitely interested in that because
that's been my one struggle as a human.
What is a whoopie pie?
I will be pies.
Like cake and whipped cream.
Right?
Like a fig Newton commercial
cause kick some ass.
Fig Newton is like if you put
those two next to each other,
they're in different planets. Exactly.
The plants. Newton's were healthy though.
Allegedly. They're actually just a
big giant blocks of sugar, sugar cane,
which is pretty much what it will be.
Bias, which is why my homie over here,
you've got a kid. I'm a single
parent family, four kids.
We were fighting over the food in the
house too. I've never broken out of that.
And the Whoopie Pie, we need
a break. We can, we can worse,
we can introduce you to attract called
sugarcoated lives. Really? Yeah.
Yeah. I get very
interested in that. We'll,
we'll get you on the
[inaudible] week there. Yeah.
And you'd think it'd be like Jocko
yelling at you, like don't, whatever.
But it's a pragmatic explanation of what
your mind is doing right now and what
it shouldn't be doing and what it should
be doing and psychological warfare that
can help you with that. Basically.
You mentioned that it's an album,
it's an oh yeah, yeah. It's an
album with tracks on iTunes,
Jocko tracks, iTunes, Amazon
music, like all these things. Yeah.
MP three and you know what you, you're
probably sitting here thinking like, okay,
that's a neat little idea that,
you know,
echo came up with and made Jack
would do this and Oh, cool.
That album number one spoken
word album on iTunes for,
I don't know, I lost 38 straight
weeks to kidding me. Number one.
That's bad ass. No big deal. You
know, Shit. Yeah, it's awesome.
And I will say that when echo is like,
dude, you just got, you know, just, just,
you know, these things that I'm asking
you about, what you kind of just like,
you know, hammering and I'll just record
it. But it's basically like, okay,
so I used to have this
thing, you stew, not anymore.
Had this thing where you don't,
when you're like, okay, I'm,
I'm working out this
day, this day, you know,
I'm just through this day and when it
comes time to workout and I have a gym at
my house now, so I'm like, ah, maybe I'll,
I'll do it. I meant to do it at noon.
I'm going to do it tonight.
I want,
I don't feel like doing it wrong and
do it tonight. And then, you know,
accountability.
Nobody's watching.
You can do what you want when I
feel like it a little bit marching,
some coffee mate, whatever. It's right
outside, you know, can I totally get it?
And that, that, that night
turns into hail, do it tomorrow.
So you basically turn a
workout day into a rest days.
You turn on your motivation to get
it done. Yeah, and it's, again,
it's not like a motivational
thing. It's like, okay, this is,
it's Jocko saying it so, okay, there's
that, but it's like, it's saying, okay,
this is what's going on right now.
This is what you're thinking right now.
This is what you shouldn't
be thinking right now.
This is what you should be thinking right
now. Okay. There you go. Cool. Gotcha.
It's when you're like,
oh,
the thing that I find about them is
because it is me talking. I find it there.
They're very,
very tight arguments.
Yeah. You'll get done listening
and you go, you know what, man?
I still find a little hole
in his argument. You know?
I think there's one sugarcoat who's
one will be buys it and not going to be
happy. I know you're like, you know what?
This is a big deal and I'm
sitting there will be biocide.
Know you might be the ultimate test
case. Yeah. I will be the ultimate.
I don't care. I don't
care who's around me, Ben.
If I get this craving for sugar, we
were traveling the other day. What?
I get sweet tea. Oh
Dang. Why sugar, sugar,
sugar. But keep in mind I'm going to ruin,
you know your mom is, I
know I can't, you know,
you're like, hey, you want to try these
things and I, I know what it is. And,
and you said, man, you got to try this
sparkle ball. My Mom's coming back though,
bro. I know it's sweet, right? And
you go, Oh yeah, yeah it is. And I go,
you never had spartan balaclava yeah,
I was like, you know, could, you know,
no big deal. And, and you know, we've
been lately been saying like, you know,
a discipline won't allow it.
That's between pizza. When we,
when we maybe see each other
maybe a path that we shouldn't
be taking, we're going off the path and
onto the path of weakness. You know,
how might be like, Hey Echo, you
know, that's cool and everything,
but the discipline won't allow that. Oh
man, that's awesome. You know yesterday,
you know you're dangling this custom
homemade lavar and my mom's there and your
mom's there actually like,
and I know I can see her.
She looks like she arrived from Greece
three days ago to make the buck of off.
I'm like, okay, I'll have one. Right.
So I had one yesterday and then the
discipline wouldn't allow anymore today I
had nine of them.
I think I have three of them today.
I have three of them sugarcoated lies.
Balaclavas get some.
My Mom's is going to get
called to make baklava origin.
Ballclub are pretty serious maple syrup.
But yeah. But keep in mind
though, with these tracks,
you got to be on that path though. It's
not like you're like, hey, I eat too much.
Let me listen to this track.
It's not that. It's the, okay,
my plan is to straight up clean up
my whole shit like by my plan is.
So you've already found a bit of
motivation. Yes. Yeah. You're motivated.
You're on the path or already,
but it's on the weakness moments,
the moments of weakness. You're like,
okay, I'm gonna, I'm gonna arrest today.
I'm going to, you know, whatever. Is
that kind of, I do. We all do. We all do.
That's, that's probably why a lot of
people get that album with tracks.
You ration what I used to do. No, no.
What I would do is this. I'd be like,
especially when I was
training for competition,
I'm going to eat this whoopie pie. I
would eat it and that would run two miles.
Yeah. I was being earned it
frigging right. Yeah. I do that too,
like it.
Normally I try and pre empt
weakness with hardcore exercise,
which by the way often mitigates.
It takes like a like, oh,
I want to have a mint
chocolate chip milkshake. Cool.
I can have a mint
chocolate chip milkshake.
As soon as I do 30 clean
and jerks at the bar down,
I can do that and that's cool, but then
by the time you get done, you're like,
you know what?
I'm going to want that thing.
I infuse my brain with
discipline from the bar.
They went from the bar into my hands
and into my brain and so that's a great
idea. Yeah. Even in the simplest
one is burry burpees like, okay,
you know what,
I can have this if I do a hundred
burpees that takes less than 10 minutes.
We had this thing the other
day and I talked about it.
My freezer in my house
broke and so we had,
I have an RV and our frozen food was in
the RV refrigerator and I wanted some
ice cream and then I was like, ah,
you know it's all the way up. Get it.
And I said to myself, God, wow, lazy
loser. You don't even deserve ice cream.
I didn't have it cause I said,
you're a pathetic,
if you're actually questioning whether
it's worth it, Geico to be our call,
you don't need this at all in any way,
shape or form.
If you were thinking it wasn't
worth 27 steps to get to the RV,
grabbed the mint chocolate chip
Bryers ice cream, bring it back down,
scoop it into a bowl,
let it melt a little bit and then
just sit there and get after it.
So good. You're like a little melt
to the ice cream. Just a little mail.
I don't like it if I ever
had to turn gains bowl. No.
Have you ever heard that term
gains ball? Uh, it's, it's you,
you basically take ice cream
and you put milk in it. Oh,
stirred around Gainesville.
That's what I do. But let's,
let's all detach right now and consider
what we're talking about right now.
The pleasures of gains bowl.
The problem is chocolate chip ice cream.
I would walk barefoot and two
feet of snow to that frigging RV.
Look at this guy.
No,
he was that compliment that or is that a
negative or positive? No, yours is worse.
It's weird because you
have a better result,
but your discord or your path is
where, cause he was like, Hey,
I'm going to be weak. I have discipline
that week to week. That was him that day.
But you could,
that's rationalize because at the end,
you know the means and the end situation
thing is I actually embarrassed myself.
Yeah. Yeah. That's what it was.
I just hated myself. And I said,
I can't believe I'm even questioning the
fact if I would take 27 steps to my arm,
get the ice cream, the fact that I'm
even thinking that way, I should,
I should Hayes myself.
This is ridiculous and pathetic
and just stop. And so yeah,
I didn't get the ice cream that night,
but the mint chocolate
chip ice cream for sure is,
is a real thing. And it's
even, it's my favorite flavor
is my flavors. Although when I was in
Montana, who's tracks those tracks?
Moose tracks, that's the other, that's
the other. I'm not going to, you know,
I am going to stand and I thought,
and I dig it, but it's just,
it's very surprising that
the way
you can close the Moose track with
a scoop of mint chocolate chip.
I've never done that. That sounds
deranged. It's like it would push me over.
He says, Jesus, a cheese and wine
grapes. Oh Jeez. Just clothes.
It's just a finishing touch is what we
should do. Is that what we should do now?
One of my buddies in the trees
or is it is a awesome guy.
Bad ass wrestler.
Wrestled was a champion wrestler in
college and it was on the Olympic team.
Uh, didn't compete for variety of
reasons that I won't talk about. Uh,
but he was friends with Dan
Severn. You remember Danny
saw? Yeah. Early UFC and so,
and so. I don't know why this just
came to my mind. Oh, I know why I did.
So he would say they knew each other,
they were friends and whenever
he'd see Danny Severn,
Danny [inaudible] was a heavyweight and
this buddy of mine was cutting weight,
you know, and when he was a
big guy, he was like whatever,
like 200 pounds be to
cut to one you whenever.
And he would call Dan Severn pot liquor.
Meaning like meaning like you're, you're
just, you're a guy that's over there.
You're eating everything and when you
get done eating, you're licking the pot.
Right.
I picture you with a smile.
You got straight up palm liquor cause
you get to the end of that bowl,
you're like,
oh I'm getting the,
the rest of this mint chocolate chip
ice cream is getting into my belly now.
My kids have followed the path of my
wife and they'll come up to me when I'm
eating junk food and they'd
be like, Dad, you got moves
that and they'll just grab of that
fat on my guts. You don't need that.
Oh they're brutal. Dang.
Kind of the psychological
warfare situation. Yeah it is.
I'm surprised you're
not sometimes 84 pounds.
I should be scarred mentally actually.
Whoa.
What do we say?
That's the freedom part.
But the thing is he got to be
on the path. So like, yeah.
You know how say discipline
equals freedom, right?
So you know you grab the ice cream.
Yeah,
I had to pull that one for
the first time I was at,
I was a little like family
get together and there was,
it was a birthday party for a friend
of the family, blah, blah blah.
And there was a grandmother there.
So a grandmother of one of these kids.
I had a birthday party,
blah blah blah. So,
and she's a German woman and you know,
she kind of knows what's going
on a little bit with the game.
What with what's going on with everything.
And so I'm sitting there and there's
like a um, you know, straight up,
this is rough. You know the ice cream
cakes as you can get a mic check.
Do I know we have ice cream cake is a
mint chocolate chip ice cream cake talking
to a fat kid. So I'm like, if
we're talking to a pot liquor, so,
so I'm like, okay, you know what,
we're going to get some of that mint
chocolate chip ice cream. It's got those,
what?
I don't even know what it is.
Those little black Crum things that Oreo
or something like something like that
on there too. We're talking, this is a
situation that needs to be, you know, we,
we need to get in on this thing real
quick and he's a little bit melted so it's
soft. So anyways, I'm cutting a piece
of the cake and not a big piece,
not a small piece, but you know, like
a medium piece. Getting it on my plate,
stick my fork in it. And this woman is
German woman who's super cool. She's like,
I thought you were about the
discipline. And I was like, Dang.
And she called me out and uh, I
looked at her, I said, you know what?
I have the discipline and that allows
me to have freedom sometimes to eat mint
chocolate chip ice cream cakes,
which I'm about to do. Thank you.
That's it. Just say this is the
freedom park. But like I said,
you gotta be on the path. You gotta be
in the game. You can't just be like,
this is the freedom part every
single day. No, it doesn't work.
That doesn't work that way. Um, also
Jocko white tea, you can get that.
You know what it does if you're
gonna start dead lifting again, you,
you should get drink a little bit more
Jocko white tea because it will increase
your dead lift to 8,000 pounds.
And this is proven,
proven across the board. I'm
on it. Uh, everyone, uh, books,
I got some books.
If you want to get them extreme ownership
book about leadership book about
combat leadership,
you can get that,
you can get it for yourself and you can
get it for your team and you can get it
for above and below you
in the chain of command.
It's gonna make your life easier
when everyone is on board.
If you got kids or you know,
kids, you can pick them up.
A book called the way of the warrior
kid and what that's gonna do is going to
lay out a path,
actually a yeah,
that a kid who doesn't have a path,
most kids don't have a path.
The book will give them the path and
the path leads them to being stronger,
smarter and better.
So my daughter read it,
she loved it. That is awesome. And she is
an individual and she speaks
her mind. And I was like,
Chloe, no, really? What each
thing, she goes, I love that book.
And she came up and she wanted you to
sign it and she wanted me to get her
coffee back at home today or shite fails.
We get it tomorrow or something.
I'll be back tomorrow. Awesome.
Uh, that's, yeah, I appreciate it.
And Yeah, straight up, like when
you ask kids, how did you like it,
which I always ask kids how they like it
and cause you know, kids, like you said,
kids are going to tell you the truth. And
so, so far I have not had a kid go, eh,
marginal March and hold,
you know, marginal.
You kind of missed the mark, but you
know, we'll entertaining, but you know,
whatever, they should make that
shit into a movie or something. Oh,
they're going to make it into a movie.
Um, also another book coming out,
October 17th,
discipline equals freedom field manual.
That will also show you the
path it's going to show you the,
it's going to show you one path.
The path of discipline grabbed that book
if you need help of your business.
Uh,
I have a business called echelon front
with my brother Leif Babin and he was,
we worked together in the
seal teams battle of Ramadi.
We took the lessons that we learned,
we wrote that book extreme ownership and
the reason we wrote that book extreme
ownership was because we had people that
we were consulting asking us to write
down the lessons learned, so there it
is. If you want us to come work with you,
it's Leif Babin, me,
JP Denelle, Dave Burke,
you know who they are,
email us info@echelonfront.com also the
muster September 14th and 15th in San
Diego,
California.
We could throw out the like game changer,
which definitely has been said about it,
but I'm going to say this,
it's not this fantasy game changer thing.
It's actual pragmatic tactics and
strategies that you can use as a leader,
as a follower in business and in life.
Come to the muster in San Diego,
September 14th and 15th
you can register for the,
for the muster@extremeownership.com
also until the muster.
If you want to communicate with us,
you can do that.
We can all be found on some thing
that we talked about earlier tonight.
The interwebs. Sure. Twitter,
Instagram and batch. Facey ball. Ha.
Echo is at echocharles.
Pete is
at origin. We talk in Instagram.
Are we talking Twitter?
Instagram. Where are you
at? Origin USA. Twitter.
Where are you at at origin? B.
J J as in Brazilian Jujitsu.
Awesome.
I am at Jocko Willink.
If you want to hit us up you can hit
us there. Echo any clothing, clothing,
clothing, clothing, thoughts. We've got a
lot of closing thoughts, closing thoughts?
Nope, that's it. Pete the man.
Great to finally meet you in person
and I appreciate that. Thank you guys.
Uh, man, I'm honored to be at
the table with you both and uh,
just mad respect for everything
you guys do. Like quiet.
Just glad to be here with you
and experience this. Also,
I want to thank my wife,
Amanda for putting up with my crazy shit
and midnight ideas and allowing me the
flexibility to live this life,
which is important in a relationship.
And my kids, uh, Keegan and Chloe,
uh,
who are the ones I work for every day,
day in and day out,
that family
good things come in.
Yeah.
Well for me,
you know,
I wish I would have met you 20 years
ago and for whatever reason I didn't,
I wish I would have met you 10
years ago for whatever reason.
I didn't met you six months ago.
And just looking at what you've
done, I'm telling you, and if,
if I haven't made it
perfectly clear today,
what you've done to this
point already is incredible.
I don't,
I don't even,
it's the possibilities of you pulling
off what you've already pulled off is
incredible. And what's, what's cool
is it's like when, uh, when, uh,
when a space shuttle takes off,
the hardest part of the journey is that
first part getting breaking away from
gravity of Earth and
what you've already done,
you've cleared the gravity earth and now
you're on track and it's, it's, you know,
just nothing but respect for what you did.
I know that you have used your
hands to make this happen,
your mind to make this happen. And I just
respect everything you've done so far.
Talking to the team here and
the attitude that they have,
everybody has that attitude.
And,
and just for me to come in and be
a part of that is just outstanding.
I look forward to being
a part of this team.
I look forward to getting to know
the team when I can come up here,
which is hard.
But to see the people on this team is,
is,
is phenomenal and I can't wait to see
where it goes. So thanks for coming on.
And uh, this is guaranteed
to not be the last time. Uh,
and of course to the military
folks overseas right now.
Thanks for allowing us
to make this podcast.
We could not make this podcast without
your service and sacrifice to the police
and all law enforcement to firefighters,
BMTs and other first responders.
Again,
you allow us to make this podcast
and we are thankful for it.
And finally,
and of course to the
working class of America,
thanks for doing what
you do day after day,
working, sweating, bleeding,
building calluses
while you build our great country.
Thank you for holding the line
than thank you for getting after it.
So until next time,
this is Pete Roberts and Deco and Jocko
out.