Juggle.
What if I don't have time to explain
the why to my troops for a decision I'm
making during an operation
US army first lieutenant.
So awesome.
Thanks for your service.
US Army first lieutenant gets some and I,
I talk about troops and people
in general never wanting a path,
a plan to be imposed upon them.
And so that's,
that's what this question
is kind of based around.
Cause I'm going to saying look,
you know,
you don't want to just force people
to do some plan. You want to say, Hey,
what do you think you
should do? And Hey, here's,
here's what we're doing and
here's why we're doing it.
This is why it's important that gets
people to take ownership of it and
therefore they do a better job.
So he must have heard me say
that and now he's saying, look,
sometimes I ain't got time to,
to be explaining the why when
we're getting this going on.
And that's why this idea of explaining
the why is true 99% of the time in an
administrative situation,
in a situation where things are under
control and we've got time to think about
what's happening, that's when you can go
and say, Hey, what's your, what's your,
you know, what do you think? How
do you think we should do this?
This is why I want to accomplish this.
This is the commanders and 10
you can do it and all that stuff.
And that makes sense.
Again,
in a administrative situation when there's
chaos and when there's May Hamot and
when there's uncertainty,
actually the opposite is true.
You actually want your
troops to you. They,
they want,
they want to see and hear
clear directives from you.
They want to know what they should
do in no one certain terms. And it's,
you can think of situations where if
you've seen, let's say a car accident,
right? And you see people
that are kind of frazzled.
If someone steps up into that situation,
no one's doing anything that
they're supposed to be doing.
If someone steps up and says you
to start dragging that person over.
There you go. Call nine one one they
actually teach that. You know when you,
when you're learning about how
to handle a traumatic situations,
somebody needs to step up, step
back, take charge of the situation.
Everybody wants that to happen.
And that's true in a combat scenario.
Again,
this is different from when
we're in the rear and we're,
we're formulating a plan and we're
safely going over whatever ideas we have.
And that's when you want to get impact,
input and feedback and
you let your subordinate
leadership come up with a plan.
That's all good. But that's
not true during a, like I said,
during a pressure situation, when
there's a critical scenario unfolding,
people want to be led.
Now when you lead them
in those situations,
you can still give orders
by Commander's intent.
You can still just give intent.
So an example of that,
and I actually wrote my example down,
you can say like Delta one six we need
high ground on the other side of that
road, make it happen. So then the
delta one, six commander goes, okay,
I need high on the other side of the road.
There's a good building.
It looks like that's when
we can take, hey, you know,
t squad come with me and they go over and
take down the building. I gave them a,
uh, still gave him commander's intent. I
gave him very clear commander's intent.
I didn't really tell him why. I didn't
say, Hey, what do you think would be best?
Do you think it's a good idea
to get high ground? No. I said,
go get high ground on the other side of
the street. That's what I told him to do,
so I'm going to let them figure it out.
They understand what the intent is.
You could say something a
little bit more specific.
You could give them an actual, an
actual directive. You could say,
Charlie wants six gag,
take two squads,
assault building 34 on the
other side of the road.
Get high ground on the rooftop.
Go now where you have something
that's more specific. Again,
it's not commander's intent.
It's directly I'm telling you what to do.
And a lot of times people
are gonna want that.
They're going to want to hear exactly
what to do in these pressors situations.
So depending on the level of experience
that your subordinate leadership has,
depends on maybe how specific you're
going to get with just given commander's
intent versus giving
something very specific to do.
Both of those are the right answers.
If you have a good really good leader
underneath you and you can just give them
the intent and even let them come
up with a plan, cool. Go with that.
If you've got somebody that
needs a little more guidance,
give them a little bit
more specific guidance.
Now obviously, one part of that
is you've got to have trust.
You got to have trust with the,
with the subordinate leadership
with that you're working with,
whether that's you working with your
whole platoon and you just got to trust
your, your squad leaders and
your, your fire team leaders.
But you got to build that trust through,
through training and
through hard training,
through coaching them and mentoring.
And again,
I hate using the word coaching
and mentoring because that
always gives an air of
superiority and I'm not going to want
to come off across as superior to other
people. Why do I not want to come
off as superior to other people?
Well, number one, because it unifies
our team more. And number two,
cause I'm not superior to other people,
right?
I'm another person and my subordinates,
even though they might not have as
much time in rank or experiences me,
they still might have great ideas
and I respect that. So this isn't a,
hey,
I don't want to use coach
or mentor because I'm
manipulating them and I want to
make sure that they,
that they listened to me because I'm
being a certain way with them. No, no.
I legitimately respect what they're
saying. That's the difference here.
So, but that's my goal is to build trust.
And the other way that you build trust,
and I've said this before, is
by giving trust. You know, hey,
I trust that you can do this. Hey Echo,
you're going to go take down the building.
I trust your plan and come up with it,
make it happen. Boom, you could do it.
You trust me more when I trust you, you
trust me. And that's what we want to do.
Now when the operation is over and now
you're in a post operational debrief,
then you can discuss why you gave a
certain order or you can get feedback from
them on why they executed it a certain
way and you can get the questions going
back and forth and through that little
question and answer period that takes
place during or post operational debrief.
We get to know each other more.
We build more trust and we
become better as a team.
So that's the way it works.
You don't always have time to explain
why pressure situations you lead.