Jocko. I had had a few rough months,
some setbacks at work that hurt me
financially, which is stressed out.
My family, I'm late on some payments,
I'm falling further behind at work.
I don't want to tap out, but I
just don't know where to start.
Well, you know what, that's,
that's just kind of the
way that life works.
Sometimes it's, it's Murphy's law.
When things go wrong,
they always seem to happen at once and
they just compound on top of each other
and it's, it's pretty easy sometimes to,
to feel beaten when you're faced with
all those issues and all those problems
and they all hit you at the same time. But
let me tell you that that
doesn't mean give up.
In fact, it means the opposite.
Okay?
It means it's time for you to fight harder
to dig in means it's time for you to
go on the war path.
And that starts with one of the
fundamental laws of combat leadership,
prioritize and execute. What's
the biggest problem? Well,
what's causing the most
stress? Family. Okay.
Sit them down. Explain where you are at.
Be Blunt,
be up front and then give them the simple
plan of how you're going to get things
back on track. Don't sugarcoat it,
okay?
You give it to them straight.
Next you've got some,
some late payments.
Call those creditors up.
Explain to them what's going
on. Set up some kind of a of a,
of a minimum payment plan so you can start
making some progress and get them off
your back and then you got your job
right. You're falling behind at
work, okay? Talk to your boss.
Face it. Tell him that you're
going to step up your game.
Tell him you're going to be at work
early. You're going to be at work late.
You're going to be at work during lunch.
You're going to be wherever you need to
be whenever he needs you to be there.
Tell him you're going to get after it
and tell them that you are 100% committed
to supporting him and the
company and the mission
and then you get started
and I'm going to tell you
right now, it won't be easy.
It will be hard because life
is hard. That's what life is
in these challenges, these
challenges that you face,
they're going to do their
best to take you down.
Do not let them stand up. Dig in,
line up those problems and
confront them. Face them.
Fight them.
Yeah.
Do not let them bring you down. In fact,
in fact,
let loose challenges raise you up.
Let them elevate you.
Let their demands and their
trials make you stronger.
But the adversity you faced today
turn you into a better person tomorrow.
So, so in the future,
you look back at these
struggles and you say to them,
thank you.
You made me better.