This is Jocko podcast number
one 62 with Echo Charles and me,
Jocko Willink.
Good evening.
Good evening on the 22nd of April,
2008 to Marine battalions,
the first battalion,
Ninth Marines,
the walking dead from Vietnam fame and
the Second Battalion Eighth Marines.
We're switching out pain. Ramadi, Iraq,
one battalion going home in a few
days and the other just starting,
it's a seven month tour
to marines,
Corporal Jonathan Yale and
Lance Corporal Jordan herder,
22 and 20 years old,
respectively.
One from each battalion.
They were assuming the watch together
at the entrance gate to an outpost that
contained a makeshift
barracks housing 50 marines.
The same broken down,
Ram shackled building was
also home to 100 Iraqi police.
Yeah,
they were my men in this fight
against the terrorists in Ramadi.
Yale was a dirt poor mixed race kid from
Virginia with a wife and a daughter and
a mother and a sister who lived with
them and he supported them as well.
On $13,000 a year
herder was a middle class
white kid from long island.
The two of them were from two completely
different worlds in our country.
Not good,
not bad,
just different.
Had they not joined the marine corps,
they would never have known each other.
They would never have even understood
that multiple America's exist
simultaneously.
Depending on your education level,
your family's income status may be,
but they were marines.
They were combat marines and because
of this bond they were brothers.
As close as if they were
born to the same woman,
the mission orders they received from
the sergeant there, squad leader.
I am sure when something like this,
okay,
you two clowns stand this post and let
know on authorized personnel or vehicles
pass you clear on that.
I'm also sure that Yale and hurt her
then rolled their eyes and said in unison
something like, yeah, sergeant, we
got it. We know what we're doing.
Well,
just enough attitude that made the
point without saying the words.
No kidding sweetheart.
We know what we're doing.
They then relieved the two other marines
on watch who turns out we're probably
the two luckiest marines on earth that day
and they assumed their post at the
entry control point at joint security
station. Nasser in the Sophia
district of Ramadi, Iraq,
a few minutes later, a large blue
truck turned down the alleyway.
The alleyway was no more than a hundred
yards in length and spread its way
through the serpentine of
Juror Concrete Jersey walls.
The truck stop just short of where
the two were posted and detonated,
killing them both catastrophic Lee,
if you know what combat is like,
you know what I'm talking about
when I say catastrophic Lee,
24 brick masonry houses were
damaged or destroyed by the blast.
A Moscow hundred yards away collapsed.
The truck's engine came
to rest 200 meters away,
knocking most of a building
down before it stopped.
Our EOD guys are explosive.
Guys reckoned the blast was made of
at least 2000 pounds of explosives.
Two died.
And because these two young infantry men
didn't have it in their DNA to run from
danger,
150 men,
50 us marines and a
hundred Iraqis were saved.
When I read the situation report about
the incident and a few hours after it
happened,
I called the regimental commander and
I asked him for details of what had
happened.
It seemed different to me.
Unfortunately, marines dying or being
seriously wounded is common in combat.
We expect marines and for that
matter, soldiers, sailors,
airmen and coast guardsmen regardless
of rank or mos to do their duty,
to stand their ground and
do their duty and to die
if that's what the mission requires.
The regimental commander had just returned
from the site and he agreed with me,
but reported that there were no
American witnesses to the event,
just Iraqi police.
I figured if there was any
chance of finding out what
actually happened and then
to recognize and decorate these two young
marines and acknowledged their bravery,
I'd have to do it myself because I
understood that the bureaucrats back in
Washington would never accept Iraqi
statements for what had taken place.
If getting these marines properly
awarded had any chance at all,
it had to come under my
signature as a general officer,
so I traveled to Ramadi the next day and
spoke individually to half dozen Iraqi
police,
all of whom told the same story.
They said the blue truck turned down
into the alley and immediately sped up as
it made its way through the serpent,
Teen Jersey walls.
They all said they knew
immediately what was going on.
Yeah.
Particularly as the marines began to fire.
Okay.
The Iraqi police all began firing as well.
Then to a man,
they ran for safety.
Just prior to the explosion.
They all survived.
Many more injured,
some seriously injured.
One of the Iraqi said to me that they
had all run from the danger like any
normal man would to save his own life.
What he didn't know until then,
what he learned that very day
was that Americans are not normal
with tears welling up. He
said, sir, in the name of God,
no sane man would have stood
there and done what they done.
No sane man.
They saved all of us.
What we didn't know at the time and
what I didn't know at the time and only
learned a couple of days later after
I wrote a summary of this bravery and
submitted it and submitted them both
Yale and hurt her for the Navy crosses,
which is the number two award for
marines and sailors in combat.
What I didn't know was that one of our
security cameras that we had at the
location that was damaged initially
in the blast had caught everything.
It had happened exactly as the
Iraqis had described it to me.
Okay.
It took exactly seconds by
that recording from when the truck
entered the alley until it exploded
six seconds
and you can watch,
and I did watch many,
many times on this recording the
last six seconds of their young lives
when it first started.
I suppose it took a second or so for the
Marines to separately come to the same
conclusion about what was going on.
They had no time to talk it over.
Only enough time to take half an instant
and think about what the sergeant had
told them to do.
Only a few minutes before,
let no unauthorized
personnel or vehicles pass.
At that point in the recording,
the two marines had about
five seconds left to live.
Okay.
It took maybe another two seconds for
the two jar heads to raise their weapons,
take game and open fire on the truck.
By this time,
the truck was halfway through the
barriers and gaining speed the whole time.
Hear the recording shows a
number of Iraqi policemen,
some of whom had fired their [inaudible]
now scattering like the normal and
rational men. They were some
running right past the marines.
The two marines had about
three seconds left to live
for about two seconds more.
The recording shows the
marines weapons firing nonstop.
The truck's windshield exploded into
shards of glass as their rounds took it
apart and undoubtedly tore into the body
of this terrorists that was trying to
kill their brothers.
Yeah.
On aware of the danger at
the time the other marine,
since Iraqi soldiers in the barracks
could take comfort in the fact that two
marines were on watch and
would die before they ran.
The recording shows the truck careening
to a stop immediately in front of the
two marines
in all of this instantaneous violence.
Yale and herder never hesitated.
Yeah.
They never stepped back.
They never even started to step back.
They never even shifted their weight.
Yeah.
With their feet spread
shoulder width apart.
They leaned into the danger
firing as fast as they could.
They only had one second left to live.
Then the truck explodes,
the camera goes blank.
And the two young men
go to their God,
six seconds,
not enough time to think about
their families, their country,
their flag
born about their lives or their deaths,
but more than enough time for two
very brave young men to do their duty
into eternity.
That is the kind of people who are
on watch all over the world tonight
for you.
Okay.
And
that was a speech
that was given by Marine Corps
general,
General Kelly,
and he gave the speech to
gold star families.
These are families who have lost
a service member killed in action,
and he gave that speech on February 21st,
okay.
And General Kelly was obviously
a speaking from the heart.
Not only was he the commanding
general in charge of those marines,
but he also understands loss
on a very personal level
because on November 9th,
2010 general Kelly's oldest son,
First Lieutenant Robert Michael Kelly
was killed in action by a landmine while
he was on patrol leading a platoon of
marines in Afghanistan.
And that story of those two marines is
yet a nother example
of the dedication and the
devotion of the marines.
And we know full well that
there is example after
example after example from all
our branches of service.
Examples
of sacrifice
and do,
you can think about those six seconds,
six seconds.
We throw those away all the time.
We can waste hours and days.
We can even waste weeks
as if we have an endless supply.
Okay,
but we don't.
If you were given six seconds to live,
what would fill your mind?
Would you be okay with that?
Would you nod your head and think,
okay,
it's time.
Would you be filled with regret
in those last moments? Would you
think about what you should done it,
which you should have said
who you should have been,
and in
the end
would you realize that there's no reason
ever to waste six seconds of your life?
That is one lesson
we can take away from
General Kelly's speech.
Yeah.
Six seconds can be an Aternity.
Another lesson we can take away from
this speech and from its author knowing
that General Kelly had lost his son,
is that we have to move forward.
We have to move on.
And this isn't to say don't feel anything
cause that's wrong.
And that is not what we are doing.
I mean,
who can fathom the pain that General
Kelly felt at the loss of his eldest son
as his eldest son pursued a career that
was no doubt inspired by the general
himself,
but he moved on.
He drove on.
I was talking to a friend of mine
can,
we were talking about survivor's guilt,
which is something that
we all feel on some level
when we're in the military.
And sometimes I think people feel as
if there's something wrong with them.
Okay.
Or they feel like they're weak because
they let their emotions get ahold of them
sometimes.
And I could see my friend stealing that
and I told him about an
interview that I did.
Yeah.
With Colonel Tom Fife on this podcast,
the,
he was an army officer that
had served in World War II,
Korea and Vietnam. He had gotten
a purple heart in all three wars.
Yeah.
And I explained to my friend that as
Colonel Fife and I were discussing the men
that he lost in Vietnam.
Okay.
Colonel Phife got choked up.
Yeah.
Despite the fact that 51 years had
passed since he lost those men.
Yeah.
51 years.
But he's still got emotional.
Why is that? It's because we care about
our men because we care about each other.
And it's because while we hear
that time heals all wounds,
time does not remove the scars.
They are going to be there
and they're going to hurt.
And that's okay.
And that's normal.
It's normal to feel the pain and
it's normal to feel the guilt.
And I think that's one of the hardest
things for vets that I talked to
is that they don't think
that this is normal,
but I am telling you it is normal.
Every vet that I've talked to,
yeah.
From World War Two Vietnam,
the guys that have served in Iraq
and Afghanistan, everyone feels it.
It's part of the deal.
It's part of the job.
Yeah.
It's part of the aftermath of war.
It's always existed
and if you're feeling that,
then you should know
that you are not alone.
What else did we learn from this speech?
Well,
another thing opens up a whole,
Oh, a whole box. A whole
Pandora's box of lessons learned.
We're talking about urban combat
and how fast things can unfold.
Their urban combat is
exceptionally stressful. The,
the space time continuum in
urban combat is very compressed.
The threats are 360 degrees. The enemy
can be, they can be 500 meters away,
but they can also be five meters away
in one of the ways that we can mitigate
that stress and thereby mitigate
casualties and thereby mitigate
the guilt that we all carry.
Okay.
Is by knowing and understanding that form
of combat to the best of our ability.
And as always,
history has much to teach us
and I want to go now to a direct source.
The leadership from Charlie one five
Charlie Company,
First Battalion Fifth Marines,
Charlie one five fought in
the battle of waste city,
a brutal battle that took place during
the Tet offensive Vietnam 1968 the battle
lasted from January 30th to March 4th
and included 11 Arvin battalions for US
Army Battalions, three U S Marine Corps
battalions support from the air force
and they were fighting against a
strength of about 10 enemy battalions.
It was a massive battle and way
was a built up city.
It had a population of
almost 150,000 people.
It had typical urban terrain and also
some unique terrain like the citadel,
which was a massive walled
portion of the city.
By the time it was over,
the enemy had lost thousands of
men killed. The South Vietnamese
had lost 452 men in America suffered 216
men killed in action and 1,584 wounded
in action
and here are some quotes
from the interview
from the digital journalists with a
guy by the name of John Olsen and army
combat photographer who is
in way during this battle.
He said,
I was in a way for five days.
I had been in Vietnam for
one year at this time.
I'd seen a lot of battles and I
thought I was pretty experienced,
but I'd never seen anything like way.
Okay.
There was tremendous bravery,
a lot of dead.
There was a situation in way where
we had marines in a courtyard.
They had been moving from house to
house and transitioning here across this
courtyard,
they had rocketed.
A lot of them were wounded.
There was no radio contact.
We were pinned down and
in pretty bad shape.
We had an element that eventually came
to into leave us and he'd had a priest
and he gave last rites to the dead
and he was a very generous priest.
He offered to give the last rights
to any of us that wanted them dead,
wounded or not scratched at that point
in context, it was such a horrific
battle with such horrific images.
Way was different.
There were tremendous casualties
and no way to treat them,
no way to get them taken out.
There were reports and
as shown in this image,
there was a marine who was badly wounded
so badly he couldn't be treated than he
was zipped up in a body bag
while he was still alive.
That's what way was like,
okay,
I was in way for five days and we
were under heavy fire all the time.
One of my favorite quotes was a journalist
to asking a marine how many times he
had been wounded in way
and he said, today, sir.
Yeah,
so it was a brutal battle and there was
just
incredible heroism and sacrificed and of
course there were many lessons learned
and while the lessons focus on urban
combat and they focus on the battle wastes
city,
I think as you hear some
of these lessons learned,
you'll see they apply broadly
to leadership as a whole.
And as we know, if we understand
the way we can see it in all things.
So let's go to this document.
Lessons learned, Charlie,
one five operation away city 31 January,
1968 to five March,
okay.
Even under the best of circumstances,
street fighting is a bloody business.
This was in the end,
the ultimate lesson learned by the
United States Marine Corps personnel who
participated in this historical battle
considered by many to be the bloodiest of
the Vietnam war.
The Marine forces involved in operation
way city lost 142 marines killed in
action during the month long battle,
including the initial fierce
clashes involving primarily
fighting throughout the
southern sections of the city.
In the climactic full scale battles
inside the citadel, fortress itself,
hundreds more marines were wounded and
had to be medivaced on both sides of the
river.
Enemy casualties estimates
range well into the thousands.
Although operation waste city will long
be remembered as an overwhelming victory
over the best conventional forces
the enemy could throw at us.
And although the fifth marines overcame
very unfavorable odds and ultimately
triumph in the finest traditions
of Marines in combat, in truth,
this battle was a very close thing.
Okay?
At the squad platoon and company levels,
casualty rates were very severe,
as high as 75% or more in some units,
okay?
This was especially true during the
first day of day or two of each unit's
initial experience in
full scale urban combat.
There's an important piece right there,
specially heavy casualties during the
first day or two of a unit going into
combat. What does that mean? That means
then that first day and two day or two,
you are learning a ton.
And that also means that if you can find
out and figure out how to simulate that
combat before you enter
into those situations,
you'll be able to overcome or at least
mitigate some of those initial shock,
uh, things that happen that shock your
system and you're not ready for them.
And you know, I talk about this with,
with doing Jujitsu, for instance,
for females,
right?
If you're a female that wants
to learn self defense and you,
you know,
you started training Jujitsu.
If you don't train Jujitsu and some
guy grabs a hold of you, you're a,
you're in shock. You're not
used to it, you haven't, you,
you have to contend with that.
Something that you're unaccustomed to.
If you train Jujitsu, guess what? You
have guys grabbing you every single day.
They're grabbing you, they're grinding
on you, they're trying to move you.
You're used to that. You don't have to
overcome that. Same thing with combat.
The closer you can get to simulating
what you're going to face in combat,
the better you're going to do in combat.
And you don't have to learn these
horrible lessens your first entry.
And you know, you and I have talked
about this too. If you get, if,
if let's say I learned a new move
in Jujitsu and I did it to you,
you'd,
I'd catch you and then I show it to you
and now all of a sudden I can't barely
catch you anymore. Right?
That's all it took.
All it takes is you
knowing and understanding.
And it's the same thing when we
talk with businesses and we do,
we do roleplaying exercises as a leader.
And how do you talk?
How do you tell someone that they
need to improve their performance?
You do a couple of role plays and you
get good at their objections that they're
going to give you are the reactions
that they're going to have.
You can get better if you
wait until the real thing.
You're not doing yourself any favors.
Yeah. Yeah. It's kind of like an ambush,
right? Like an ambush is so effective,
but if you know that push is coming,
it's not even effective at all. Yeah. And
once you've been ambushed, like imagine,
I mean it, it happens all the
time. Any, anytime you exp,
you know and understand
what's going to happen,
you're infinitely more equipped
to handle that thing. Yeah.
As opposed to I have no idea
what's happening and I'm
going to go and figure it
out on the floor.
Yeah.
So experience is the best,
but guess what?
Experience is expensive.
It takes a lot of time.
So what you have to do is you have
to train. That's what you have to do.
What if the only time you,
what if you wanted to get good at street
fighting and the only time that you got
to practice was when he got
in a street fight. Yeah.
Even if you literally went out every
day and got in the street fights,
two things would happen. Number one,
you'll get arrested, but number two,
you get all the first street fight.
You might pick the wrong person and die.
Yes, that is true, right? Yeah.
So what you want to do is you want to
get into a training environment. Yes.
And then you want to get yourself skilled.
Yeah. Same thing with the military.
Same thing with fighting. Same thing
with shooting. Same thing with business.
Anything that you're,
it's another
thing I see like business people, there's
business people that have been through,
let's say they've been through an
acquisition, an acquisition before.
They know what to expect.
They're anticipating what's going on and
it makes them that better at foreseeing
what's gonna happen in mitigating
the risk to it. Yeah. How do you,
if you can't go through the acquisition,
well what do you do? Read about him,
you know, interview people, learn
about, figure out what to expect,
but hire someone on your team that has
been through an acquisition before so you
get, can capitalize on
their experience. Yeah,
it's crazy. I guess when you think about
it. Not Crazy, but it's interesting.
So you know like sports teams for example,
like a, um, well, uh, I guess football,
say football for an example.
You practice for like five or six days,
just practice, practice, practice and two,
sometimes more hours every single day,
you know, maybe a day off maybe.
And then, yeah, for one game.
So it's like there's training,
then there's performance kind of thing
and they go kind of hand in hand.
Like you got to perform in
training and then you know,
the game or whatever that you learned
stuffed in. They get them too. But it's,
it's interesting where one game
is predicated on so much training,
so much training, but then when
you go to work, it's like you,
you kind of expect to have gone or they
expect you or whatever the expectation
is that you went through
your training or Eddie,
and then they'll add sprinkles
of training. Like a work.
Just normal when you go to work.
Yeah.
So every once in a while you'll have
what gear. Quite honestly, that's,
that's one of the reasons I salon Ashlyn
font is doing well because people are
realizing that if you want your
leaders to know how to lead,
you actually have to train them out of
lead and that you can actually do that.
Yeah.
So that's one of the reasons that it's
you Ashkelon front is in such high demand
because
we can actually train your leaders to
handle these situations that they're
coming up against. And when you do
that, you have this massive advantage.
And we see the companies that
we work with, they, they, their,
their performance just improves immensely
because their leaders are working
together and learning how to lead. And the
most powerful thing you can have. Yeah,
it's, it's weird cause I, you know,
I'm kind of behind the scenes guy with
echelon front and I see like, you know,
any video that it's been done, I probably
seen it, you know, and I'm around,
you know, all the time. So essentially
I'm getting the course too, you know?
And it's interesting where
I think probably in a lot
of cases I probably am more
trained in it than most people.
Even most people,
companies that you work with or
whatever because I'm kind of getting it
secondhand and listening because it
applies to everyday life, you know,
like this whole deal.
It's not just work isn't in fact for me,
I mean yeah it applies
to my quote unquote work.
But it applies to like family
stuff, you know, life stuff.
And the big thing, this is the big
thing. This is a big difference. You
know the material,
you but you because your position,
you'd use it on your family but you
don't use it in a work environment.
And therefore you get to learn the
technique but you don't get to roll.
You don't get to spar. Not In
hard. And here's the thing,
when we work with companies, it's not
like, oh, here's this information,
and then they go apply it perfectly.
No, they come back and say, hey,
this didn't work. I went and talked to guy
and he said this, it's like, okay, cool.
Here's how you've got to overcome that.
So there's the,
you got to get the initial information.
Yes, but you still have to apply it.
Even if you train a group for
combat as much as you possibly can,
they're still going to have a certain
delta that they're going to need to rise
to when the real free occurs.
And so we see that with companies.
We see that with individual leaders
that are part of companies where they're
there and I show up sometimes,
you know,
there's some people out there that are
just straight up in the game and they're
in the game before I even show up.
Like it's the icing on the cake.
And even people that have read
extreme ownership 10 times,
they've read dichotomy
of leadership 12 times.
They've listened to every single podcast
and they'll still ask questions about
things because they haven't
quite put it together,
split like they haven't mapped it
perfectly on their situation. Right.
And just like I said, like it takes,
it takes like, okay, how you say,
I don't really get to spar. I D I do
get to spar, but they're real easy,
super easy sparring partners. What do I
got? I got you. I got my wife, you know,
I'm like, you know, this is coming easy.
Splunk partner technically. Yeah, for the,
for this stuff it is.
I mean technically you're the easiest
sparring partner because you're just like,
you're doing the same thing, you know?
So it's like there's no friction. I mean,
very little friction maybe on some level,
but I miss songs.
But the, the, you know, these people at
work when they apply it, well you know,
when you have, whether it be a
corporate job or what or whatever,
anytime where you have bigger teams,
different personalities, you know,
you care about people in different levels.
It's like it takes way more,
it takes more effort and more time on
the mat for people to get proficient to
where you look at a situation, you go,
oh, here's what this, here's the problem,
going to hear this guys. He goes, get a
little out of control a minute, massages,
ego a little bit,
and we'll let them have some more control
and that'll make him feel better and
they'll do a better job like it.
It takes a little bit of experience to
get to that point. And, and you know,
a lot of times,
like I said,
when we go and work with a company that
this fully in the game and they'll be
batting,
there'll be nailing nine out of 10 things
and then there'll be one more thing
that they need a little adjustment on.
And they make that adjustment
and they call. Yeah. You know,
and everything makes sense.
So training is how you get good.
Don't waste your time getting beat up
in street fights in order to learn.
It doesn't make sense.
All right. Moving on.
The ultimate success of this operation
could have been significantly improved in
our opinion by several factors,
including one improved less
restrictive rules of engagement,
including situational flexibility
down to the platoon level.
This is something we hear about all
the time. Here's the deal. What that,
what that really means
is decentralized command.
You need to trust your troops. You need
to explain to them what is important,
what is not rules of engagement to
tell someone you cannot do this.
What I'm saying,
if I say Echo,
you cannot shoot at this type of building.
If I tell you that what I'm telling
you is I don't trust you to make a good
decision based on the information I
give you. If I was to say, Hey, listen,
some of these buildings
that are marked with a star,
those buildings are historical buildings
that will cause the civilian populace
to um, you know, get angry at
us. So don't shoot at them.
If I say that to you and I say, tell
me, explain to you why it's important,
and then I say, hey, look, then
again, remember you're in the field.
You need to protect your men and you say
God and now you go on the field and if
you're a good leader and you trust me
and I trust you and I've explained the
commander's intent well and you
understand the strategic impact of,
of disobeying or of, of going
outside the rules of him that that,
or not the rules,
but the direction that I've given you,
then you understand that that's great
and you'll make a good decision because
what that decision might entail is
you're getting shot at from one of these
buildings and now you
have to take it down.
If I don't trust you to make
that decision, what do I do?
I put strict rules of engagement on you
and now you can't do something and that
is, that is not decentralized
command and it's not generally good.
Do you have to put some broad rules
in place? Yes, you absolutely do,
but you have to make sure that the people
on the ground understand that those
rules can be bent if they have to,
when they have to have the
authority and the leeway to do that
next to improved communication.
Of intelligence information to all levels
of command. Of course, communicate.
Communication is one of those
things. And again, I, I feel,
I always feel when we go
to work with a company,
it's one of the first things I have to
ask is what are your methodologies of
communication through your company?
How do you communicate
with your frontline troops?
How do you communicate with
your mid level managers?
How do your mid level managers and your
frontline troops communicate with you?
Because sometimes the front line
troops might see something out on the
battlefield, but you don't see because
you're up in the ivory tower. Yeah.
And how do they communicate that back
to you? Do you have a methodology?
Oftentimes communication
is ineffective or it's,
they don't have procedures around it.
They have protocol on how
to communicate that's bad.
So communication up and down
the chain of command. Simple,
clear and concise.
And that's the way it's gotta be.
Three acquisition of improved intelligent
data in particular concerning the
disposition and size of enemy forces.
That's cool.
That's a little bit of,
uh,
a universal fantasy for military
people that we want great intelligence.
We want to know who the enemy is.
If we knew who the enemy has power jobs,
so that's a,
that's a universal fantasy and we should
always strive to achieve that fantasy,
but it's very difficult to get to.
But then they go to this reconnaissance
and small unit probes to fix enemy
positions are critical. What? What that
means is when you want intelligence,
go get it.
Go find it.
Gather the Intel yourself as much as you
can for improved supporting fire plan,
access to artillery,
naval gunfire,
direct fire from armored vehicles and air
support should be judiciously employed.
Doh deployed. So what does
that mean? We need to cover?
We need cover from big guns covering move
five significantly increased training
for urban conflict,
street fighting practice and preparation.
I think we just covered that.
Training is always paramount.
Six deployment of available
chemical weapons in this case,
tear gas for offensive operations
during early stages of the operation.
These guys use tear
gas and it worked well.
The North Vietnamese army had didn't
have gas masks and they didn't like it.
Of course, you know, there's people
when you, when you say chemical weapons,
what do we think of? We think
a mustard gas. There's other,
there's nerve agents and nerve gas.
That's where people generally think
of when you think of chemical weapons,
but chemical weapons are also tear gas
and tear gas can be very effective.
There's also some people that can
just BTF through threw tear gas. Yeah.
Uh,
continuing seven,
improved dissemination of operational
plan details down to the fire team level.
Fire team leaders,
these fire team leaders.
If the fire team leaders,
and you're talking about someone that's
in charge of four guys or six guys or
something like that.
Really small little element.
If those people understand what
you're trying to accomplish as a team,
that means they can execute at
their level and make things happen.
They can move the ball
in the right direction.
If they don't know where they're supposed
to be going. They can't help you. Yeah,
they can help you.
So broad guidance needs to be given,
needs to be updated. People
need to understand, hey,
we're trying to move forward
trying to take this area.
We're trying to move across this line.
Everyone needs to understand that if
they don't understand that they're there.
Actually no good to you.
If you've got a fire team leader out
on the flank somewhere that has no idea
that you're trying to move forward
or move east or west or north,
that person is just sitting there
waiting for you to tell him what to do.
They're almost worthless. So, and,
and this also means if you're a fire
team leader and you don't know if you're
supposed to be going north,
east, south, west, whatever,
you should be raising your hand
and saying, Hey, what are we doing?
Tell me what we're doing.
Continuing on the other side of the scale,
small unit experience,
individual marine determination,
the buddy system,
the quick learning capacity of
marines under combat conditions,
the combined leadership officer's staff
Nco as an NCO pose of one five at all
levels.
And the ultimate ability to coordinate
fire support and execute street fighting
tactics under heavy fire
were factors that one,
this pivotal battle
despite incredible odds,
high casualty rates and the resulting
turnover of officers and NC.
So you, it comes down to your
individual marines and your,
your frontline leadership
that make these things happen,
which no doubt the military or
the u s military is awesome in a,
in their front line leadership
and the frontline troops,
they make so many things
happen. The, even in many cases,
despite poor leadership, you just, you
just have great frontline leadership.
I mean I would see that a lot.
You know,
you'd get a platoon that had kind of
a marginal and if not maybe even a bad
platoon commander, but you just get some
guys in that platoon that are awesome.
The platoon would be awesome as long
as the leader was humble enough to take
guidance. If the, if the leader
wasn't humble enough to take guidance,
they would fail because he would just
drag everyone in his terrible ways down.
If he, if he had the common
sense to say, you know what,
I'm going to listen to these guys.
I'm going to let them kind of run with it.
Platoon would do fine.
Continuing on,
certainly using 20,
20 perspective of hindsight,
this battle could have been decided and
even more timely and decisive fashion,
reducing friendly casualty rates in
the process by paying attention to the
fundamentals of Planning
Marine Operations.
Proper prior planning prevents Piss poor
performance and they actually edited
out pis because they're squared away.
Marines.
Yeah, got to come up with a good
plan and had they done that better?
This is the typical situation.
Hindsight's always 2020 and I,
I always avoid becoming a arm chair
postgame critic in the military.
I mean I'll criticize someone like
a fighter in the UFC or whatever,
but when it comes to military operations,
uh,
it's real easy to sit back and
throw darts and say, well, you know,
I would have done this. You weren't
there. You didn't see it. I didn't see it.
I wasn't in this situation. I have all
the now they didn't have those facts.
So I'm always very cautious
about Huc and darts into the past
and you deal with like that can situation
you. It's, and you kind of use it.
You actually do you use this as,
you know when you say you can sit back
and be at a tactical genius or whatever?
Yeah.
I don't know.
If I make a video you can like sit
back and be like look at these like 10
mistakes or 10 things or whatever.
Meanwhile there's like a thousand
elements so 990 elements have had to be
created well in in work and all this
stuff and then you can just be like,
yeah those, cause essentially those
are created for you. You know,
you don't have to create those things.
All you have to do is poke holes in
the 10 yeah and I can focus instead of
having to focus on a thousand things,
I can take a broader look and see the 10
things that you screwed up or one thing.
None of nine Mikey slick.
Probably this one
maybe too.
All right.
The following details regarding the
lessons learned from operation wasted.
You're offered from the former
members of Charlie company,
First Battalion Fifth Marine Regiment,
First Marine Division who served in
combat during operation way city and who
were directly involved in the battle with
Nva forces inside the citadel fortress
from 13 February, February,
1968 through five March,
1968 situation terrain.
There is an infinite variety of possible
landscapes that may be confronted by a
Marine force given the mission of
attacking an enemy force in urban terrain,
infinite variety of possible landscapes.
What does that remind me of?
That reminds me of life itself.
When the Tet offensive
broke out on 31 January,
1968 and conventional NVA forces overran
major sections of the largest cities in
south Vietnam.
Marine forces were literally knee
deep and Rice patties in jungle mud.
Since first establishing a beachhead
in 1965 marines had been assigned the
mission of conducting a
counterinsurgency or rural conflict,
fighting for the most part,
a guerilla army.
The Tet offensive changed all of that.
And for the first time since the height
of the Korean War in 1954 marines found
themselves with a mission
that involved urban combat.
Okay.
So you have to be able to,
you should never turn your back
on something. I had a fighter,
I was training for a fight and
okay.
I was like, Hey, let's
do some groundwork. No,
the with you on the bottom. And
the dude was strong. He wasn't a,
it wasn't a good wrestler. Well let
me rephrase that. A decent wrestler,
but not by any stretch,
you know, not a call that,
not a competitive call address or
anything like that, but solid, strong,
very strong. I said, hey man,
let's put you on the bottom.
And the response was,
I'm not going to be on the bottom.
Yeah.
Gotcha.
Hey, well even if you don't think
you're going to be on the bottom,
let's train for the unlikely event
that you happen to end up on the bottom
because it's a fight and anything
happened. I don't need to,
I'm not going to be on the bottom. Yeah.
So we can sell where the story's going.
He went to his fight and fought and was
on the bottom. Basically the whole fight,
it was a three round fight,
was on the bottom almost the whole time.
So it was oral via and why?
Because you can't,
you can't neglect one.
Part of the possibilities that can unfold.
And even even for us,
when we would get ready to deploy to Iraq,
we're going to Iraq.
We're literally going to a desert and
going to be in the middle of the desert
and we would still do dive operations.
We'd still do maritime operations while
we were getting ready to deploy. Why?
Because we don't know what's gonna Happen.
We don't know whether it would
next war is going to break out.
So just don't neglect anything.
And I'll tell you what else.
If you're good at a variety of things,
you will be better at everything. So if
all we knew how to do is enter rooms,
what happens when, when that, when we,
when we enter a building and
instead of being a bunch of rooms,
it's a giant warehouse or no,
it needs to be cleared.
Like we've gotta think about these things.
But the more flexible you are,
the more capabilities you have
that that's what I'm looking for.
The more capabilities you have,
the more flexibility you have.
So learn different skill sets.
Don't neglect things.
Continuing on preparing to remove an enemy
battalion that is captured a 40 story
skyscraper or a college campus
as much different than, oh,
he's a much different mission than
getting the enemy squad out of a house,
school or church in a small town. But
common factor in all of these variations,
however, is that in all cases in urban
combat structures dominate the terrain.
Studying and assessing
terrain is a fundamental issue
for marine commanders when
planning mission,
this,
this idea of terrain is so important.
The way,
the advantage that terrain gives you is,
I don't know what to compare it
to in other, in anything else.
If you understand terrain,
okay,
you can dominate.
It's like trying to do Jujitsu and not
understanding arm position like where
that you need under hooks.
If you know,
if you're going against people
don't understand on our hooks,
you will destroy them.
If you go in against someone that doesn't
understand where to position their
hands, where to position their
arms, you will destroy them.
If you're going to get someone that
doesn't understand how to utilize the
terrain, you will, you will destroy them.
If you don't know how to utilize
the terrain, you will get destroyed.
And by the way, that doesn't matter
if you're in the city, you're in,
in rural environment as
a matter where you are.
Studying and terrain is a fundamental
issue for marine commanders
when planning missions.
This is even more critical and planning
house to house combat operations,
building materials very worldwide and
their ability to provide small arms cover
to a very high degree for the use
of reconnaissance and intelligence.
We recommend conducting a
serious assessment of each
building or structure that
is within your units area of operations
because tactics involved and taking each
objective, building structure, et
Cetera, maybe different. In each case,
a small wood frame house may offer to the
illusion of cover from small arms fire,
but little else in some places,
walls are paper thin.
Even houses that use some form of plaster
concrete construction can prove to be
unexpectedly porous and at
the worst possible times.
This is something to
consider all the time.
Things are not always what they see that
that's, that's what's important there.
Things are not always what they seem you,
you think you're hiding behind
a wall and now you're safe.
No bullets will go right through it.
Yeah.
Continuing. No. The basic
layout of a structure as much
as possible before entry.
This is something that I would say our
standard operating procedures in the u s
military now are so good that we don't
really need to know that did the layout
of a structure.
Hmm,
we're gonna go in and be able to
handle whatever the structure,
however the structure is laid out.
That's what we do.
If you don't train to enter rooms
regularly and you don't train to enter
buildings and you don't train to be able
to contend with all these varieties of
things that you could face, you won't
be able to, if you try and say, okay,
we need to know what the building looks
like inside before we go in there.
That's a horrible, horrible idea. It's
not going to happen. And by the way,
when you go in there,
the first thing you're going to come
across as a barricade where you can't go
down the hallway and you got to go
through these other rooms that you weren't
expecting.
Hmm.
Continuing approach,
each structure with an entry plan and a
surge plan and make sure each member of
the fire team in squad as well versed in
these plans. What I say instead of that,
it's not plans.
These are standard operating procedures.
So you develop standard operating
procedures so you know what to do when you
enter a building.
And so does everyone on the team
established voice codes and commands and
communicate regularly with each other?
Yes.
Consider entryways existing doors and
windows to be extremely dangerous,
likely locations for Woobie traps
and to be avoided if at all possible,
wherever possible, blow entry holes
using Satchel charges are rockets.
Once the entry plan is
finalized and understood,
it must be executed with
fierce determination.
Be prepared for anything
and be ready to improvise.
Be Systematic and check everything.
Basement, sewer access addicts, rooftops,
trash cans thoroughly before establishing
that the objective is secure.
So what I, one of the most important
things I take away from that is that the,
the existing entryways,
you got to consider them dangerous.
W W how do we translate that into life?
What that means is these well
established patterns are exactly that.
And it, I'm not saying you can't ever
use a pattern that someone else used,
but you at least at a minimum,
have to be aware of the fact
that when you're doing something,
when you're using a path that
someone else has already gone down,
it's a known path.
And so you can't expect to be able to
surprise your competitor when you're doing
something that's always been
done the same way. Gotcha. Yeah.
So think of how you can approach things
in a different manner and if in fact
that manner might be better.
Sometimes you look at things
from a different angle and you,
you realize that the reason that everyone
does it this way is because that's the
best possible way and to make some huge,
Herculean effort to try and do
something like, to just to be different.
Sometimes that's the wrong answer.
I get that. But considerate. Yeah.
Yeah.
Lot of times those,
and like certain industries are like
this up in an email, but they're,
they're so used to doing it a certain
way because that's sort of like what they
learned then. It's all for sure.
It's almost like as an industry,
they don't think of like what,
why they're doing it that way.
Well, yeah, that's why,
that's why there's been so many
disruptors right in the last few years.
I mean, you can look at any
of these disruptors, uh,
companies that are come out
of nowhere that, you know,
you can look at the ride
sharing applications.
If you were a taxi driver,
you were thinking, okay,
how can we get more dispatchers? How
can I hire more cars? These, you know,
these ride sharing people said, oh,
we're not going to own any cars. Yeah,
that's great. Same with Airbnb, right?
We're not going to build a hotel.
We're going to use a random people's
houses and puts you in there.
That's looking at it from a
completely different angle. Yeah.
Seeing a problem and coming up with
a completely different solution.
If you looked at a city and said, oh
wow, there's no rooms in that city.
There's no hotel rooms in that city. Where
am I going to put in? Everyone? Okay,
well let's do what everyone else does.
We'll build a building and we'll put rooms
in there and we'll staff the building
and we'll put a restaurant. That's
what you do. That's what's been done.
Guess what? Someone else looked
at that and said, you know,
there's nowhere to stay in that city,
but some people might have empty
rooms in their house. Let's,
let's see if we can access
those rooms. Boom. There you go.
Yeah. I wonder how it was where the guy,
one of the guys was like, hey shoot,
I can't find a hotel room
when I go to San Francisco.
And then the friend was like,
Hey, just come stay with me. Yup.
And then when he stayed with them, he
was like, you know, next time you come,
if you, if he can't find a hotel room,
you can always stay with me when I call.
Yeah. Hey, I'm not the only way I'm
coming up here. I'm coming up on and
you know, um, my company's paying me to
come up here so I can get them, you know,
they'll give me money for the room,
so maybe I could just pay you and
you go, oh cool. We're kind of,
we're kind of getting a little,
it helps us kick it back to the company.
Cool. And then the next thing you know,
hey, I bet other cities have, I know
a guy down the road, he has a room,
it doesn't really use.
So if you have any coworkers and Ellen,
if you know anybody, you know that
guy too. Simple as that. Yeah.
Simple as that. But it's looking
at it from a different angle.
Yeah.
So look at things from a different
angle then what you come up, you know,
fierce determination first determination
is always good. Yeah, that makes sense.
Is there a dichotomy to fierce
determination? Yes. The redness.
Can you have someone that's too fiercely
determined? Fiercely determined,
yes you can. Yes, you can.
They don't know when to stop.
Yeah.
Next.
The other aspect of urban terrain or
the spaces between buildings, streets,
alleys and other pathways are normal
routes for humans and therefore must be
sussed.
Must be,
must be suspected to be under observation
and possible enemy firing lanes
whenever possible. Take the most
difficult route from house to house. Hmm.
Same thing we just talked about.
Look for a different path.
Establish and the,
and there's obviously there's a dichotomy
to that because if you're constantly
just taking the hard road all the time,
you might not make any progress,
which is also bad.
Established an advance,
a plan of what to do in
the event noncombatants are
found in urban zones and for
marking buildings that had been cleared.
It's kind of crazy that they knew would
have an idea of how they're going to
mark buildings that were cleared.
Continuing.
Make absolutely sure that your marines
are aware that while inside a building
being secured, they are at risk
from both within and without.
Always assume that every room of every
floor in each and every house contains
enemy.
Soldiers always move very quickly when
moving in front of windows or doors.
Always nowhere.
Enemy positions may be in buildings that
are adjacent to yours as an all marine
operations.
Watching your buddies back,
watch your buddies back and run as fast
as possible when traversing open ground.
Can't let your guard down.
Where do you let your guard down?
Me? Yeah. We can't tell you it's,
it's probably a pretty broad area.
100% of my life probably.
Yeah.
Is there any time where you feel
like, Hey, I need to get my guard up.
This is probably an easier
question for you. Yeah.
You're not just running around hyper
paranoid check. I am. Yeah. Yeah.
Know what in life you mean? Or
in Jujitsu? What like everything?
Yeah. Like I would say, I dunno it
put it this way, my guards always up,
but it's only kind of up,
I think you know it's like a 25% and
it kind of fluctuates from moment
to home and they fluctuate.
It's up from like zero to three stays
at 25 sometimes it goes up to like 30
sometimes certain scenarios
here check multiple stories.
Structures present an even greater
challenge than single story buildings in
medium size village or town or
small city that is dominated by one,
two and three story buildings be very
particular about the taller buildings
which are naturally used by the
enemy as high ground if possible,
make entry to taller multilevel buildings
via the roof and work systematically
and thoroughly downward.
Always look for the high ground.
So does that sort of the thing,
you know,
cause the high ground kind of seems
simple straight forward or whatever,
but is there like a,
a blueprint,
like a simple blueprint for like,
I remember you told me a story where
your son was talking with like a neighbor
or something who had, I don't know
if he went to Vietnam or something.
Like he was in, he was in the
military, whatever. And you get,
and they played like
laser tag or something.
His son like whooped him because he
knew the like some something. Well yeah,
my son knew some fundamental tactics.
It was when he was younger,
so he wasn't really up to speed yet.
He was like seven or six.
But you know, not up to us.
We started, you know, he was,
he was already through I think,
I think it was through level
seven of my tactical course. Um,
yeah, he's probably around level
seven. What tactical chorus.
I have like some tactical
lessons sat I run, you know,
what do you mean that you run
like as a father or as a what?
Like echelon front has a
tactical course. They move? No,
I had a tactical concepts that I teach
and you teach because you didn't teach me
nothing. Right. 25% cruising mode. Yeah.
Cause you know that's just
the standard right now.
If you know there's certain things you
have to learn in order to be tacked to be
proficient. And I, my son had learned,
like I had gone through seven of the
courses to understand the tactical things
and there was a friend of
my wife's friend came over.
He yes,
he was a prior marine or actually
he was active duty marine and yes,
my son challenged him to a laser
tag tag competition. And yes,
my son was victorious
three times in a row.
And in the room he just did
simple fundamental tactics.
And it wasn't even team sport.
It was a one on one. Yeah.
So how do you defeat someone one on one?
Well you maneuver very quickly.
You don't fire from the besaint
same position multiple times.
You get the high ground
because you'd like,
he knew if you get onto my garage roof,
which had access with a ladder,
you're going to be able to defend that
position very thoroughly and the person
that's below you because all you have
to do when you're on the garage roof is
doc and your hidden,
it's a parapet roof, eh.
Sorry. Are you have to use a deck up
there? Yeah, there's one access point.
How are you going to beat me?
You don't have grenades with the late,
you'll have laser grenades and then
he's drive the high ground. Yeah.
I'm seven years old or six years old.
I have the high ground,
I have a laser weapon. You're trying to
attack me. You're going to die. Yeah.
And then the next round when you're
trying to get up on that thing,
I'm not there anymore. I'm in the alleyway
up the alleyway up behind the fence.
Higher.
Still higher still.
So the high ground is kind
of like the Golden Golden
Room. Hmm. Yeah. Interesting.
You know, when the first time I found
out that the high ground is the,
is the spot to be where when I
watched the movie called the Rock,
they're washed out in the Sean Connery
and Nicholas Cage where the navy seals
come up. You know, they got to go to
Alcatraz, they come up through the,
wherever the journey or something like
this. Yeah. And they get, you know, boom.
They're sort of surprised by the, the, I
think they're marines. Yeah. The terror.
They're mercenaries at this point.
But nonetheless,
or patriots depends exactly what,
uh, yeah. And he was like, Hey,
your guys just surrounded, uh, from an
elevated position. It's kind of like,
this is a no brainer, you know, this kind
of thing. I guess that's a thing. Yeah.
And it is a thing, you know, and
they, and they killed them all. Yeah.
Except for Nicholas
Cage. He didn't die. Hmm.
That's, that's chemical agent,
by the way. Right. Vx Gas.
That's what I was going to say. Yeah.
But you, you'd know that was a real,
or are you good?
Let's be since fries.
He didn't just dive deep right into that.
I was gonna,
but you know those little
pearl, the little pearl balls
are kind of interesting.
Back to the book,
the mission assigned to Marine
forces during operation wasted,
he was to remove enemy forces that had
captured major sections of the ancient
imperial capital of way
during the surprise,
Nva offensive that was quickly dubbed
the Tet offensive due to the historic
listen closely due to the historic aspect
of many of the buildings in way the
usage of heavy weapons was significantly
restricted during the initial days of
fighting on both sides of the river
as friendly casualties mounted and as
initial estimates of the size
of the enemy force. In a way,
city area was significantly increased.
Fire restrictions were ultimately lifted,
so they didn't want to damage
these historical buildings,
and so they said, hey,
don't don't use 50 cal,
don't use whatever,
whatever weapons they
said they couldn't use,
and then eventually when the
casualties got so bad, they said, okay,
go ahead and do what you gotta do.
I say,
rip the bandaid off, right?
If you're going to go, you go.
If you're going to go,
go, don't play around,
that's a good lesson. America
learns over and over and over again.
If you're going to go to war,
go to when you're number one
priority over everything else.
That should be to win, and by the
way, if they would have done that,
I guarantee the city would have been
in better shape at the end because the
enemy's going to drag this thing
out and it's going to take longer.
You're going to have to end up destroying
every single building that's there.
Yeah,
makes sense.
They continue.
In our respectful opinion,
our ability to successfully complete the
mission was initially severely impacted
by the rules of engagement.
Again,
this is a lack of trust up
and down the chain of command.
If I have to impose strict rules
of engagement on my people,
I haven't trained them well enough. I
don't trust them. They don't trust me.
They don't understand the strategic
mission and we have a real problem.
Hmm.
Continuing.
Although it is understood that mission
and rules of engagement are not the
exclusive responsibility of marine
leadership at the platoon company,
battalion or even regimental level.
It is strongly recommended that every
effort is made at every level in the chain
of command to ensure that balance has
been achieved between the demands of the
mission and the effect of the rules of
engagement on the ability of the command
to perform the mission successfully.
Yes,
you do have to have balance,
but what you really should have is trust
and understanding of the situation so
that people don't need to
be constrained by rules.
If I have, if I, if my leaders
understand what I want them to do
and they understand the constraints and
they understand the mission and they
understand the impact,
they don't need any rules at all.
They just need to get told to go.
Yeah.
I think about like certain laws where
if this is going to be the law of the
land,
that this law applies to everybody.
Same thing with rules of
engagement where they got it,
cause they kinda got to apply to
everyone. Right. In a certain way.
So that's why they wind up
being so strict or they can, um,
and I'm thinking about laws to where
there's certain groups or individuals that
it's like, man, that La kind of shitting
and apply it to me because I know better.
You know like where like you
don't like the guy who's like,
okay unquiet as this
red light, right, this,
this or this stoplight where the crossroad
of that stop light is a dirt road.
And on both, if you turn in the
dirt road, either direction,
there's a gate that's always
closed. It's only Click, oh,
it's for like Cain trucks and stuff. Or
it was, I don't know what it is now, but,
and the cane truck guys have the
key to the gate. This big long get,
you can't even turn in there, but
there's still a stoplight, right?
So it's never read because it
only turns green when the kitten,
but every once in a while it'd be red
and the gate will be closed, you know,
and all that sort of happens. And here's
the thing, you can see the gates quote,
no truck is coming. Even if a truck was
coming, like they got to stop that open,
they get whatever.
Should you stay at that red stoplight
or can you just blow through the light?
You would think any responsible adult
should have the authority or whatever to
see that and just go through the light.
But the rules got applied to everybody.
That's the thing.
It has to apply to everyone.
And what about the new driver who's like,
they can discern quite as well where a
safe red light running situation versus a
not so safe red light running situation.
And then there's a spectrum, you know,
so when these rules get put in place,
they got to apply to everybody at
the lowest common denominator person.
And unfortunately these highest co hired
denominational people got apply to them
too because you know, you can't
just go down the line and be like,
okay this rule applies to you,
but kind of kind of, you know,
just maybe 30% this rule applies
to him hundred percent of course,
and him to you 1% cause you're this
elite dude so you can, you know,
you have ultimate flicks, you
know, it's hard to do that,
especially when you do it
like a bunch of people.
So that's why that can be a pain in the
ass sometimes. You see what I'm saying?
Three apparently that's been
bothering you for quite some time.
How long have you lived
in America for mainland?
Like think about like the court
system or like, you know, yeah,
no rules get put in place for
sure because people don't trust
the subordinates that have
to follow the rule. Right?
You tell your kid you're not allowed
to go in the yard because the pools out
there, right. What
you're really saying is,
I don't trust that you're not going to
go in the pool or I don't trust that
you're that you can swim well enough.
If you're a good leader, you'll be like,
okay, we got it. We need to work on this.
You can do understand the dangers and
that's a little bit of a weird thing to
talk about because drum and
a pool for a little kid,
you obviously have to err
towards the side of safety.
That's probably not the best example,
but if you tell your kid no
one's allowed to come to, okay,
I'm going on a trip Friday night,
no one come over to the house.
Those are the rules.
You know?
If my kids actually understood
what I really meant is like, hey,
if you want to have a couple kids
over, that's cool. Don't get crazy.
Don't eat my food. Weird to stay away
from the milk. No Weirdos, no. You know,
if they understood all that,
which actually that's what
my kids were like, Hey,
I've got a couple kids coming
over. It's all good. You know?
If they broke the trust,
then things might be different than
I have to go and implement rules.
Yeah. But on top of that year, you're
talking about like your kids or like,
you know,
in the military if you're dealing with
like one unit or one little group of
people,
but if the rules of engagement or in
your case like the rule of people coming
over, what if, what if it
didn't just apply to your kids?
What if it applied to the whole
block or the whole town or whatever.
So it's like, just to keep everyone safe.
We've got to sell. This is the standard,
which is why we don't
want communism. Yes, yes.
They just make tunnels that are
and blanket over every, well,
that's how laws are even here. Sure. The
gun laws consider the gun lots for sure.
Like, Hey, we need background check, but
the gold rules got apply to everyone.
You know, you can't
discriminate kind of thing. They
have to apply to everybody. So
it's like, man, well yeah, that's,
the gun rules are a perfect example
because they don't trust the people.
Everyone. Yeah. Certain people you know.
Oh, everyone just can't have a gun.
You have to get her background check.
Okay, fair enough. Why? But then it goes,
then it continues. See
that's, that's where,
that's where you run into products where
there's so much debate about gun laws
because pretty much everyone
says, hey, I get it.
You should probably get some kind of a
background check before you get a firearm.
Everyone goes, hm, okay. I
don't want somebody that's been,
I don't want somebody that's a felon or
a violent criminal to be able to get a
gun. Cool. I agree with that. The
problem is where does it stop? Yeah.
And, and then the problem on
top of that is because of the,
where does it stop?
Because of the slippery slope thing.
The people that don't want any gun
laws, they just said, we don't want any,
like every single, you know,
while we think we should,
that the background checks should
be an extra three days, no work.
And meanwhile,
on the other side,
people are saying every single thing that
they can do to restrict firearms from
being had by anybody.
They try and move it there.
So both sides or just take an extreme
position and no one will actually have a
normal logical conversation
about what's going on.
It's just, and even when you
do minute yelling and screaming
from the polar polarized positions.
Yeah, and I, and a lot of times,
even if you're in that in the moment,
like you can step back and see that when
that happens, when people are just like,
hey,
you're just defending your position just
to just kind of blindly or whatever,
you can see that happen.
I'm not saying like it's so terrible.
I don't think it's natural.
I get it.
But even if you can have like
an un Un civilized discussion,
it's still hard because
it's based on people. Yeah.
Because it could be good
because like for me,
I should absolutely be ha be able
to have whatever guns I want.
Yeah. Right. That's, that's the way I
feel. I feel that I should be able to,
and I sh yes,
you can check my background.
You can see if I am a felon
or a violent criminal.
You can see that I'm not okay.
You should be able to,
I should be able to get
whatever guns I want and,
but there's some people
that think, hey, you know,
but as strongly as I feel about that,
as strong as I feel like I should be
able to what? Get whatever guns I want.
If someone says,
oh well then you agree that everyone
should be able to get every gun they want
to know.
Actually I don't agree with that.
I think that there's some
people that don't need guns.
I can say that. I can say that without,
without thinking, without saying,
oh well Jocko believes in gun
control for everyone. It's like, no,
I just said what I believed.
So the rules are about trust and you
have to figure out where the trust lies
with everyone,
by the way.
And you have to figure out what the
minimum amount of trust is that you can
overlay on people everywhere.
That's where,
that's why governing of
giant country so hard. Yeah.
And depending on where you live too,
because depending on where you live,
you have different needs.
You have different, like
there's some people that live,
the culture is different,
but depending on where you live,
like if you live in a state where there's
predatory animals and you live out in
the bush somewhere, you're
damn right. You need guns.
If you live in a state where there's
predatory animals that are human beings
that will break in your
house and kill you,
I guess what you also need to be
able to protect your family. Yeah,
that's good to go. You know, uh,
somebody asked me the other day is
like, is, is uh, it's actually Tim,
it was actually Tim Ferriss.
He was asking me if pepper spray
is good home defense. I'm like,
pepper sprays, good home defense against
a person that isn't carrying a weapon.
I said, but if someone's breaking into
your house or coming to attack you,
are they not going to have a weapon?
Do,
are they following some kind of a rules
of engagement? Were there I am. Hey,
I'm going on a basic B and e tonight.
I'm only going to bring, um, you know,
I'm only gonna bring my, my, my
pillow to hit people with like, no,
they're breaking in your house to kill
you or they're breaking in your house too
to assault your family or whatever.
The breaking into your house too.
They shouldn't be breaking into your house
and they're probably going to be able
to defend themselves because
they don't want to get caught.
So what do they do to defend themselves?
They got a knife and they got out whatever
they gotta go nine. So pepper spray.
Great. The problem with pepper
sprays, you, you don't, you don't,
they're not following the rules of
engagement. The rules of engagement. Yeah.
That's a good question too.
But like pepper spray,
why would you use like think of a real
scenario where you would use pepper spray
as a, as a human girl? I get it.
Cause you have valuable goods
regardless of where you go. Yeah.
You can be at the post stuff.
He's still got those valuable goods
that predators might want as a girl.
But let's say, okay, I'm Tim Ferriss
or I'm, you know, me or whatever.
Why when would I use the
prepper pepper spray?
Realistic that I'm sure there's only one
10 was just asking that because it's a
legitimate question because
if someone says, look,
I'm not really comfortable with guns,
but if someone wants comes into my house,
I want to build to defend myself, I'm
going to get pepper spray. And the the,
the real quick answers like, yeah, okay,
cool. Yep. Better than it makes you go,
oh that kind of makes sense.
Right. At least you got something.
The reality is the person's coming in
your house, it's pepper spray is great.
As long as they don't have a knife,
as long as they don't have a gun,
in which case the pepper spray is doing
you no good cause you pepper spray me
and I have a knife. I'm going to
grab a hold of you. I'm going to,
I'm going to cut your head off.
That's what's going to happen
in a situation that you,
you got to use the pepper spray.
So like if someone's like burglarizing
you and you turn it on the light and they
scatter, you don't need the pepper
spray for that kind of situation.
You know pepper spray is for
someone who like, well yeah,
but you don't know that they're
going to scatter. But yeah,
just like you don't know if they
have a gun or not. Yes. Yeah, yeah.
And if you're prowling
around in someone's house,
you're going to be in a serious situation.
Yeah. I think he should be. Yeah.
Are you're going to be in
a real bad situation. Yeah.
So that's what rules are and rules
of engagement. So going back,
we're trying to bring this back.
Rules of engagement. That's exactly,
that's exactly why rules of engagement
can be tricky, but they shouldn't be.
If you train your people well,
if the people understand
what the strategic mission,
if they understand what the parameters,
you put the parameters on in there and
they're loose enough that people can
maneuver inside those parameters.
Then occasionally they got to call you up
and say, Hey, I had to break the rules.
And you say, Oh, what happened?
And they explained it, then
you go, okay, good call.
Yeah, yeah. People need to understand that
continuing on urban combat is nearly
always conducted at very close quarters.
It is not uncommon to have opposing
forces fighting from positions a few dozen
meters apart.
Most of the fighting is done from a
distance between 50 and 500 meters due to
this close in nature.
It is critical to know where the enemy
is and how they are deployed. Again,
this is a fantasy like knowing where
the enemy is and how they're deployed is
really hard to do even when you have,
even when you have overhead coverage
looking in the city, I'll tell,
I'll give you an example.
I was watching my guys out on a mission.
I was watching on a a UAV feed,
so we're watching,
we're watching and looking for enemy and
all of a sudden we see weird activity.
There's a vehicle,
the vehicle stops,
the vehicle kind of moves a little
bit stops. Again, guys get out,
they look around,
open up the trunk and now
we're totally focused like, oh,
these guys are getting ready to attack.
Open up the trunk and as they're
starting to pull stuff out of the trunk,
My guys get hit from a different spot
that we weren't looking cause you can't
see everything, especially in a city
because think of it with buildings.
As soon as you go off angle a little bit,
you can't see the street anymore because
it's down in the building. So we're,
we actually are totally focused on
this one thing and maneuvering the,
the air asset to look at
these people in a car and as,
as there as we're monitoring these guys,
these suspected enemy personnel,
all of a sudden my guys get shot at from
somewhere else and we completely miss
it.
And we continue to watch these guys and
they pull out a jack and attire and they
lift up the car and they changed the
tire and they leave. They're just normal.
But it looked very suspect.
So to think that you're ever going to
know where the enemy is and how they're
deployed is very, very challenging.
At best you do the best.
It doesn't mean you don't try.
You definitely try, but you,
you don't get all that information.
You just don't get it. Those Uavs,
how high are those? Depends
on the UAV. So like w can you,
can they see him?
Like can people see them or are they,
it depends on the UAV and like I'm,
I don't know what the
classification of all that is. Saw.
I'm not talking about it good.
I don't know what the,
I just know that they go
to different heights. I'll,
I'll leave it at that because on the
Internet you can see those, you know,
those videos. Every once in
a while they'll just have
them. Then it's like, Dang,
those guys don't even see that.
Or you know,
I don't know if they do or donor good
optics to look real good optics. I mean,
just imagine, you know, the optics that
we have in the civilian sector. Yeah.
Even those are good enough to
be pretty amazing. Yes sir. So,
uh,
talking about knowing where the enemy
has this lesson was learned the hard way
during the initial stages of
the battle inside the citadel.
During the first two major clashes between
marine and Nva forces on the morning
of 13, February, 1968,
the enemy surprised us and wreaked
significant damages very quickly.
This was because we weren't exactly sure
where they were. Although the, the Arvin,
which is the,
uh,
the South Vietnamese army had been in
several major battles inside the citadel.
I don't recall receiving any intelligence
attribute ID attributed to them
regarding the enemy's exact location.
Further to my knowledge,
no marine recon unit was sent to check
out the situation before attacking on the
morning of the 13th.
So that's rough.
And I'll tell you one
thing that from my mind,
where's the enemy?
The enemy is everywhere.
And you have to approach things
as if the enemy can be anywhere.
And the only way you can know that they're
not where they're not everywhere is
when you take something down and you
secure it. That's when you know not there,
then you move on.
We recommend that all intelligence assets,
recon units and surveillance devices that
can be made available are deployed in
a significant effort to fix the exact
location of enemy soldiers and units.
Again, this is, you can see where this
is coming out of this. For these guys,
they must have been completely outflanked
all the time where they were thinking,
where is the enemy?
We need to know where the enemy is and
it's a really hard to know that the enemy
can combatant who knows where
his enemy is. Hiding experiences,
experiences a decided advantage in
surprise and the deployment of firepower.
Of course. Now again, this
doesn't, like I'm saying,
it's hard to have definitely
doesn't mean you mitigate.
It doesn't mean you don't put up Uav so
you can see maneuver doesn't mean you
don't gather intelligence,
doesn't mean people shouldn't report
back in and explain where they think the
enemy is.
We at least have an estimate
continuing week combat
urban combat tactics.
The tragedy of urban conflict is that
the battlefield for each firefight is a
neighborhood.
Each objective taken is someone's home
or a school or church or some other
structure that has value and foe and
more or less significant meaning to its
inhabitants.
Considering the possibilities,
it is not difficult to imagine tank
battles across mall parking, lots,
mortar fire hitting a church, a hospital,
a community center, heavy small arms,
fire fights between homes and
artillery barrage on a school yard.
While these images may be grist
for the mills of Hollywood,
when we think about them in,
in relevance to our homes and
our neighborhood and churches,
the tragedy is somehow increased.
However,
it is our collective belief that the
life of one Marine is more precious than
ten one hundred homes,
schools, churches, shrines,
shopping malls,
or any other building known demand.
Okay.
Therefore,
all efforts should be made using any and
all weapons tree available to stun the
enemy and support marine advances through
the use of supporting arms and without
regard to damage to buildings.
So clearly the whole idea
that this started off with
of the rules of engagement,
that we're restricting heavy fire power
because the historical nature of the
city,
a,
if you don't want historical
buildings destroyed, don't have a war.
And if you think we should save a building
and that's going to cost the life of
one of our brothers not happening.
Hmm.
Continuing at the same time,
the use of heavy weapon tree in urban
combat isn't assuredly two edged sword as
are many assets in modern warfare.
Rubble can be nearly as effective as
a building for protecting enemy firing
positions.
Further artillery and other
flat trajectory weapons
may be somewhat restricted
by the height of buildings and their
distance from each other. In many cases,
mortars,
although smaller in caliber were superior
because of their higher trajectory.
So interestingly,
indirect fire,
indirect fire taking the indirect
approach is often better than the flat
trajectory. I'm going to shoot
through your front door. No,
we're going to lob in some rounds on you.
So,
so we think about that when
we're dealing with people.
Punching him in the face is not as good
as coming from an indirect position
where they don't quite see
where it's coming from,
but it still gives them
a little crack and the,
it's even to the point where he says the,
um,
even though they're smaller in caliber,
so even though somebody does something
that you want to straighten him out on
when you hit him in the face,
we know what the reaction is.
They get defensive and all the things.
When we come from a, from a flank,
indirect fire, it's smaller. Caliber is
not even as, it's doesn't hate his heart.
Yeah. But it's more effective.
Yeah. Just more effective
indirect fire all day long, continuing
supporting arms, supporting arms,
the most effective or most
effective prior to danger,
close to minimize the potential
of friendly casualties
and maximize preperatory
fires to support the infantry's
attack during operation wasted.
Even the most effective indirect fire
during danger close was from an eight inch
gun. We recommend that the supporting
access of fire be perpendicular as well as
parallel. Finally in the event as
in the case of operation waste city,
that due to political considerations that
proper preperatory fires would not be
allowed, that a variety of fires
such as smoke delayed fuses,
high angle can be incorporated with the
infantry's attack combined arms training
for urban combat is critical.
It's cover and move.
That's what supporting arms do.
They lay down cover so you can maneuver.
Other advantage of preperatory
fire include the destruction
of the camouflage of
enemy positions,
the psychological shock factor against
enemy troops and the fact that heavy
weapons can create new avenues of
attack and Egress for armored vehicles.
Pretty straight forward.
One of the most effective aspects of
supporting arms during the battle of way
where the killer teams that evolved the
m 48 tank and the end an Antos and the
Antos is like, uh, it's, it's actually
a pretty crazy looking machine.
It's got 160 106 millimeter like cannons
on it and it's got six of them and
they're kind of like sticking out.
Then it's a light armored vehicles and
it's like a tank anti-tank vehicle,
but I'm Antos would pair up and
maneuver together as a team.
This would allow either the tank or
the Antos to maneuver into a good fire
position where while the other covered
covering cover move,
thank you.
Further,
the devastating fire power put out by
the 90 millimeter tank cannon and the six
one oh six is of the autos turned out
to be extremely beneficial because their
capabilities to deliver
pinpoint of firepower.
Armored vehicles can provide many
benefits to the infantry engaged in urban
combat as they provide some
cover from and small arms fire.
However,
armored vehicles can also become rocket
magnets producing casualties for an
infantry troops in close proximity.
The enemy's going to see that target.
Yeah,
and they're going to
like it. Yeah, and you,
there's advantages to having that power,
but there's also disadvantaged,
so you have to always weigh
those things out. As a leader,
you have to pay attention to those things.
As a leader,
you have to think of every
advantage that you have.
There's going to be some negative to it.
There's going to be some disadvantage
when you bring an advantage to the table.
There's going to be some
disadvantage in Jujitsu, right?
If we're going to be super flexible,
you're not that strong.
Every gonna be Super Superstrong
are not that flexible.
Your cardio doesn't last very long.
Right?
So there's going to be advantages and
disadvantages that come with each asset
that you have. Yeah. So you have to
figure you're going to go for full ox.
That's cool. You're giving up position.
Yeah. There's all kinds of things.
You have to weigh those out and as
leader you have to look at, don't get,
don't get wrapped around the positives
of something. Right. Just the positives.
There's not just positives
for for really anything. Yeah.
There's nothing that's just
straight positives across
the board, I guess. Right?
Yeah. I'm sure we could think of
something, and I'm sure you could
continue with, other than instances
of harassment and interdiction fires,
buildings that are hit by heavy
weapons should be attacked immediately.
This is good.
Buildings that are hit by heavy
weapon should be attacked immediately.
Don't hesitate. You catch people off
guard. Don't hesitate. Don't hesitate.
This happens. This happens in,
in everything we, we get a good,
a good position or something,
an advantageous happens and we hesitated
instead of taking the advantage of it,
we got, Oh God got to here. Yeah.
And then, then we, then we let it go.
It happens in business too. We get to
a situation all we finally get the,
we finally get our competitor to make a
mistake or we get an advantage position
and we celebrate instead of
just finishing the job. Yeah.
Which is a big bad thing to do.
Yeah.
Okay.
Remember that when calling in fire
missions, you were can request splash,
so you're friendly troops have time to
take cover immediately prior to impact,
these cats were calling and
bombs right on top of them a lot.
Hmm.
In daytime operations,
that use of covering smoke
is often helpful when marines
must attack across open
areas.
Yeah.
As was learned during operation way city.
Even with proper support of heavy weapons,
which was ultimately
provided to the marines.
We faced hardcore north Vietnamese
army troops who fought from prepared
positions, move to secondary
positions, fought again,
and finally very reluctantly died
and the capture of each room,
each for each rooftop,
each building, each street.
It was ultimately the marine
riflemen who won the battle.
Okay.
As a leader,
as a leader,
do you always have to remember that line
right there in the capture of each room,
each for each roof top,
each building, each street.
It was ultimately the marine rifleman
who won the battle. As a leader,
if you think that all you need to do
is make a good decision and then you're
going to win, you're wrong. Yeah.
The folks on the front line have to
truly understand what is happening and
they're the ones are going to carry the
day and you could come up with the best
battle plan ever. You could come up with
the best strategic business plan ever,
and if you don't have folks that are
engaged and willing and are going to take
the fight to the enemy and are
going to win that, that foothold,
they're going to enter that room.
They're going to go out and sell into
whatever industry you're trying to get
into. If you don't have people
that you trust, that are trained,
that are ready,
that are prepared if you don't have them,
best paddle battle plan in
the world isn't going to work.
Hmm.
Is Critical for infantry units,
snow,
both the capabilities as well as
the limitations of supporting arms
know your limitations,
right. This is, again,
there's positives and there's negatives.
Another aspect of supporting arms,
limitations to do with helicopter support.
Urban terrain is not very forgiving to
helicopters that may be forced to make an
emergency.
Landing helicopter pilots might be
reluctant to fly over urban terrain.
No.
These things.
One very tragic aspect of using supporting
arms in urban combat is that the
likelihood of civilian casualties is very
high and at least two situations that
we are aware of.
The NVA used civilians as screens for
their infantry troops and fire missions
were of necessity called
in on those positions.
So
no
expect pretty discussed these things.
Let your troops understand,
put them in role plays scenarios where
they have to make a decision on what's
happening.
It's better to think through it 20 times
and make 20 mistakes while we're doing
some kind of a role play scenario than
it is to have to be making that decision
for the first time. When you're on
the battlefield and you can't discuss,
you can't debrief. Yeah. Not to mention
the stress that's going to kind of,
yeah, yeah. Absolutely.
Use of chemical weapons during one fives
battle inside the citadel fortress,
which was kicked off on 13 February,
1968 the battalion progressed a total of
four blocks along our avenue of attack
and had secured a total of 16 city blocks
within our assigned area of operations.
After nearly two weeks of heavy street
fighting and after suffering nearly 50%
casualties at the hands
of a well prepared,
determined force of Nva soldiers of
force that finally estimated that was
finally estimated to be nearly 11,000
strong in her waist in the waist city area
of operations.
On February 25th,
1968 marines from Charlie company shot
off three e eight gas launchers caring
about 40 cs gas grenades toward
the enemy's last known position.
The next morning one five took control
of the remaining 12 city blocks and about
three hours without a single casualty
because the NBA was not equipped to deal
with tear gas attack and
was forced to withdraw.
Okay,
so we're going from
50% casualties to zero.
Hmm.
Taking a different approach utilizing
weapons that no one was used to utilizing
the enemy who's had never had not
seen they even have gas masks,
they just had to get out of there
and that he ate gas lock launcher.
It's like a suitcase looking thing and
it's got eight tubes that have eight
rounds at each in them and it
fires him like five seconds apart.
So we're talking a lot of gas.
Hmm.
Especially they shot off three of them.
You don't want none of that.
Yeah.
No
one can never be certain that the use
of chemical weapons would have made a
difference in the initial
stages of the battle,
but many of the veterans of that battle
have often wondered what might've
happened if the [inaudible]
had been deployed in the
early stages of the battle.
We recommend the judicious use of
chemical weapons such as tear gas,
etc. For combat operations.
Okay.
Administration planning and preparation.
The inherent complexities of urban combat
are such that special attention needs
to be paid toward planning and
preparations. Training, training,
training practice makes perfect
a coordinated marina tack on an enemy
held position at a town or city can be
equated to an intricate
opera or Broadway production,
although the stakes are a bit higher.
Okay.
Entry techniques,
room search and clearing techniques.
Voice commands indicating movement
or progress, fire discipline,
the use of grenades, rockets,
supporting fires, communications.
All of these must be rehearsed and
improved until they are second nature.
Second Nature.
I was talking to you the other day,
you were saying something about
my guillotine choke. Yeah.
That it was there quickly. Yes. Yeah,
and I was saying it's second.
It's,
I should have said it's second nature
because what I did tell you is sometimes I
become aware like we'll be rolling
and all of a sudden I'll be like, oh,
I've got a guillotine right now.
Yeah. I didn't even does this way.
It just showed up there with zero
fought whatsoever. Yeah, yeah.
That's how you need to be.
Yeah.
If I have to think about
putting a guillotine on someone,
then that means they have time to
think about defending the right. Yeah.
If I didn't even think about it and
it just happened to Sorta, yeah,
and not to split hairs. It's less
about the gay teens specifically.
It's just about your like what do you
call it? Head control, you know? You know,
you get that Chin Strap, oh, it's that
we're, that just arrives and then sure.
It will become a good team for sure.
We're a cobra or one of these other
treacherous moves that you'd like to
implement it from time to time.
Yeah. But yeah, it's like your head.
Well,
I feel like,
I feel like it's second nature
for my head to just land in there.
That's what it feels like
for sure. But obviously it's
you, it's your thing. Oh no,
but that's the way we want to trade.
That's the way we're going to train it.
And I would say,
I'll add to this,
that what we want to train is
we want to train for chaos.
We want to train from mayhem.
We want to train for the enemy
to do things we're not expecting.
That's what we want to train for.
Because when you train for
things at the enemy's not you,
that you're not expecting the enemy, do
you actually get good at reacting to it?
You know, you can get good at
scrambling in Jiu Jitsu. Yeah.
You can get good at ending up in
positions that are beneficial through no
conscious thought. But because
you've scrambled enough that now you
just know what you're looking for.
These little,
these little things are gonna happen.
I'm gonna get the under hook.
I'm gonna get my hips in the right spot.
I'm gonna move my hand over here. Yeah,
that's what we want to do.
Yeah. Yeah. Like the old,
almost cliched saying to like get
comfortable being uncomfortable.
The thing you know, it's like, yeah,
you train yourself to be uncomfortable
or to be trained in being uncomfortable.
You can just deal better.
But I'm trying to get something,
I'm trying to reach a different
point here. My point is this,
if I,
let's say,
let's say here's,
there's a through z situations I can
put you in and they're all different.
If I train you for a and B all the time,
when I throwed Fmu, you're, you're lost.
If I throw Q at You, you're, you're lost.
If I train you,
so I get you good at a B.
But then I start training you at Dsr
drone, u, N, F I start throwing you at m.
You will start to realize that
even in these disparate scenarios,
there are some commonalities and there
are some base positions that you can go
to that will allow you the time
to assess and make decisions.
You can,
you can get good at chaos.
That's what I'm saying. You
can get good at chaos. Yeah,
yeah. You can get good
at it. You can say, oh,
when I see things happening that I don't
understand, here's what I need to do.
I need to find a good covered position.
Hopefully elevated
where I can look around.
I need to figure out where my troops are.
I need to do it very quickly.
I need to identify a prominent terrain
feature that I can move all of us to in a
rapid manner so that I can get
controlled situation right there. Now,
with those things that I just said,
hey,
I'm going to get in a position where I
can look around, I'm going to look for,
I'm going to try and figure out where
my people are going to look for a
prominent terrain feature that
I can utilize as a stronghold.
Guess what I just solved for just about
any scenario that unfolds that I don't
understand.
I have a plan.
I have a plan that I can actually
implement against any situation.
Think about that, so, oh,
if I get a contact front,
I have a plan or we started
getting cog shot up from the front.
I weren't in an open ground. I have a
plan. It's a standard operating procedure.
Oh, I start getting shot at from the
front and we're in enclosed terrain.
I have a plant.
There's a specific immediate action drill.
We're going to perform a, wait
a second. I'm getting shot at.
I'm not sure where it is.
I hear screaming.
I know that we're getting hit from
multiple locations. What do I need to do?
I have an immediate action for that too.
I'm going to find cover.
I'm going to look around.
I'm going to and figure out where my
troops are and to look for a prominent
terrain feature that we can
move towards. Yeah. There.
Now all of a sudden the chaos
isn't really chaos. Right now.
All of a sudden I have a plan and I can
actually apply that plan to almost any
scenario.
Yeah.
So the more that you train people for
things that they don't expect and don't
understand, the better they will get
it. Dealing with those things. Yeah.
And that's very positive.
Yeah.
Moving on
further,
all plans must be communicated
and rehearsed at each
level of command from the
fire team to the company and above.
It sounds like these guys did not have
good decentralized command in terms of
actually knowing what
the overall plan was.
Cause it sounds like the
fire teams were there,
even a platoon and fire team levels
were a little bit lost at points in
particular platoon commanders,
platoon sergeants and squad leaders and
fire team leaders must be aware of each
man's assignment. This should include
who goes into a structure first,
who covers cover and move
nowadays.
Cause we've done it in the U s military,
we've done so much urban
combat in the last,
what has it been 17 years.
Every military unit in the u s military,
they can take down a structure and
they do it well and they do it off of
standard operating procedures, not off
of a specific plan of who goes where.
Okay.
Continue on hand and arm signals as well
as vocal commands should be established
and practiced
and the last section is
called command and control
in full scale urban conflict,
especially in situations where enemy
dispositions are not well known.
Initial contact with the enemy can be a
unexpected to be at very close range and
see massively devastating
command and control.
The basic marines connection
to his leadership can
disappear in the blink of an
eye during operation way.
City Charlie one five lost all of its
officers except for two sergeants became
platoon commanders.
Pfcs were squad leaders
in urban combat.
It would not be at all surprising to
find Pfcs as platoon commanders given the
potentially high casualty rates.
The critical factor for Unit survival in
these situations is that units ability
to immediately determine the enemy's
position and to return a high volume of
sustained fire on those positions.
Allowing maneuverability
despite the situation with
the chain of command who two
critical things there cover and move
as one and decentralized command is to,
that's what they're talking about.
You need to be able to put down high
a heavy volume of sustained fire on
positions so that you can maneuver and,
and at the same time you need to be able
to do that regardless of the situation
with the chain of command.
Decentralized Command.
Hm.
During the first day of one fives
involvement in operation waste,
city Alpha company lost its CEO.
It's Xo and much of the
company CP Group of necessity.
Alpha was pulled back to the
battalion rear for reorganization.
The loss of a few leaders effectively
eliminated an entire company.
This also delayed the battalion's attack,
blunting our initiatives.
You've got to have a plan.
If people go down who's taken over,
that's gotta be,
that's gotta be ready.
The individual marine who is under heavy
enemy fire from very close range who
may now be caught off from his team
and or squad leader needs to have been
thoroughly informed of communications
codes, lines of departures,
lines of stoppage,
friendly unit dispositions,
and the ability to call and supporting
fires and conduct contingency plans.
What does that mean? That means the troops
need to understand what is happening
in short in urban conflict situations.
Command and control needs to be understood
at every level down to the basic
marine. Based on our experiences
during operation way,
city expect the unexpected,
expect chaos and plan
for all possibilities.
And it's signed Scott Nelson,
first lieutenant commanding
officer Charlie one five Nick War,
Second Lieutenant Platoon Commander
Charlie one five Travis Curd,
second lieutenant artillery.
Forward Observer attached to
Charlie one five and John Mullen,
Staff Sergeant Platoon
Sergeant Charlie one five
nick war is his name. W a R. R. Hmm.
Pretty stoked to be born with that
war was, he's in the Marine Corps.
What's your name? My
name is actually or yeah.
So, uh, yeah. And,
and to hear from these guys and,
and this is this,
this document which is now,
well it's 50 years old,
and there's still lessons learned in
this that apply to really apply to
everything, apply to life,
a blighted urban combat,
apply to business, apply to leadership. So
there you have it.
And of course when we see the way
broadly we can recognize it more,
we can see it in more things and it makes
us more effective leaders regardless
of the battlefield that we're on.
So read and appreciate the
lessons of the past and echo.
Speaking of the way,
I know,
I know Jujitsu is sort of beneficial,
sort of helpful in allowing
us to understand the way
more clearly and perhaps
even more broadly,
I don't know if you have any
recommendations of how we could sort of
get in the game and stay in the game.
It's funny you mentioned Jitsu is like
a way to recognize things like it's so
it's such a metaphor even to use the word
metaphor seems like it's like detailed
like it is life in so many ways.
Like all,
even this thing that I'm listening
to you read, I'm like, oh yeah.
Did you do every single one? I just
don't want to bore everyone with, okay.
More Jujitsu stuff
on the judo podcasts that we did,
I was talking about the fact that I,
I have to give credit some credit to
Jujitsu for sort of revealing to me the
thread that tied all these things
together was JP was in town. Sure.
And we were rolling Jujitsu
yesterday and I was thinking as like,
well actually when we were done, I was
thinking, man, when we were in Ramadi
12 years ago,
I was a black belt in Jujitsu.
Like I like, it was beneficial for me
then to a bit of black belt in Jujitsu.
Not because I wasn't going out
and grappling against the enemy,
but I had already started to
connect some of these dots.
Yeah. And it's very, very helpful in life.
It's also helpful because it is a physical
representation that you can feel and
you can see. Yeah. It's
not a theory. Yeah.
There's theory behind it, but it's
not a theory. It's happening to you.
And therefore when it happens to you,
you have something physical,
something concrete, something that you
actually experienced on a physical level.
And if you,
and that allows you to understand
it metaphorically better.
Yeah.
Like when you get caught,
when someone's trying to choke you
and then Bolton, they arm lock you,
you've just got flanked. Yes.
That just happened to you.
It's not metaphorical. You,
you truly understand what it
feels like to get flanked.
Yes. If I explain to you, hey, when
I'm telling you this thing over here,
and then I come at you from another
angle, you understand it. You're, you're,
you're just starting to grasp,
grasp of the concept,
but it didn't happen to you.
But when I'm trying to choke you and
you go for the defense and then boom,
you get arm locked and you didn't see
it coming at all, you feel a flank,
you feel the effectiveness of
it in real time, in real time.
And that's why it's very beneficial
to train some of that Jujitsu feel
experience,
the laws of combat field.
Yeah. You, you'll have a better
comprehension of them. Yeah.
And that's like a profound level too.
Like that's like a,
that's good.
If you can keep that in mind and then
you can go on the other side of the
spectrum where it's like,
it's you just fighting with your
friends with no consequence. You know,
where I think a lot of the time, what does
that mean? Like if mean if you go, hey,
let's go train right now what we're
going to do when you say, let's go train.
Sure, we might go over some toe. Oh, we're
fighting. But without real consequence,
we don't lose friendship. We don't get
injured. Uh, we don't get, you know,
rest of all that stuff that, but we
get to like fight, you know, I don't,
that's also good. Yeah. So in, here's
the thing, like, here's a thing,
like some people in,
I think we,
most people like we'd like fighting,
but we don't want to like fight people.
Like, I don't want to fight everyone,
you know? Well, because then you
can get arrested. Well, sure.
Most people,
like I said,
we don't want just fight because there's
all kinds of different reasons or
whatever. But when you can, just,
when you have the opportunity to,
to fight someone with no consequence,
just to see how it would go. You know,
like if he's, you know, these
huge, huge men, you know,
the guys who were like seven feet tall,
400 pound,
just huge and strong
man and stuff like that.
You don't want to necessarily fight them,
but you're like, I wonder, I wonder,
I lucked. That would be like roll
with them to fight with that guy.
You know when you do Jujitsu,
you get that,
you get that opportunity straight
up and you want to, you want to try,
if I eat this, I wonder how
many people out there wondering,
I wonder would it be to fight
Jocko to say I would beat him up.
Not to say I wouldn't,
but I wonder how it would be that it's a
lot of people show up at the gym and Oh,
and that's exactly why.
And that's one point.
The funny thing is it doesn't matter if
they're white belts or black belts. Yeah.
They still like, yeah. See what up,
see how that experience is, you know,
they usually smiling. Yeah, fully. And
really when it comes down to it, I mean,
unless you're trying to hurt someone,
you know,
and there's a bunch of different ways
to hurt someone if you want to hurt them
because they don't like gum
or you think they should,
you know they deserve it or all
this stuff. It's not about that.
It can be about that for sure.
But that's not ultimately what it is.
It's more about like I wonder,
I wonder how it beat a fight that person.
And then when you start to learn
more and more and more, you just,
you really just enjoy that activity.
Like quite get to fight like
right now if I wanted to,
if you had the time or whatever, I mean
you, we could go, we could go right now.
Yeah. And it'd be like in a good
safe way to wrap this up then.
But you see what I'm saying? No, that's
the way to do it anyway. Okay. All right.
Back to the path. That's
the path. Inappropriate part
of the path. By the way,
you wouldn't be you without Jujitsu?
I wouldn't,
you wouldn't even be like happening.
Especially if you knew
I wouldn't be happy at all.
Yeah. Especially if I knew.
But on top of that,
I wouldn't have connected things that I,
that Jujitsu connected for me.
Yeah. There's something else.
I would not be who I am.
I'm going to straight up say yes. I would
not be who I am without Jujitsu. Yeah.
And you wouldn't be who? You would not
be on this podcast without Jujitsu. No,
I couldn't even talk to you.
I believe it's a stretch anyway.
It's a stretch anyway,
but when I'll do too,
I'll be at least there.
So without that would be talking
about TV shows and I'd be like,
I'd be like muting your
microphone or something. Let's
see. So did you get to, hey,
it's a lifesaver. Get you into
all kinds of different things,
but even if you're trying
to stay on the path, okay,
I'm dragging it. I dig it, man.
But it's important when you're,
when you're trying to get on the path,
stay on the path,
be beat on the path.
It's only fitting for real. It's
only fitting. Okay. Let's say, okay,
let's say you have weapons training suite.
Let's say you can drive a car really
well. Cool. You can hunt, you can,
you're capable, you can, you
know all this stuff, right?
But if you're stripped
away of like your tools,
oh then one man on man. Yeah.
Just don't have the Jujitsu.
Yeah. And this is more of just a
real general way to look at it.
So it's like you ever
watch men in black one?
I can't really remember too much about it.
This might not even be the movie,
but it's, it's a movie with one of the,
it's like this big rope creature, right?
And then they find out it's just a suit.
And in the inside there's just this
little worm type person thing, you know,
they're kind of, you know, oh, so
you're saying if I didn't do Jujitsu,
I would just be like a little worm,
big strong guy or whatever.
But then like if all your
tools were taken away,
what are you left with kind of thing.
Isn't it weird when you, when you
meet people that are that like they don't,
they're like big.
Yeah. Maybe even their strong,
maybe even their aggressive. Yeah,
but they, they don't have, they don't
have a skill. They don't have the skill.
Right. That's kind of a bummer.
That's essentially, here's this,
here's the situation that people
might be listening and think, okay,
well let's say you're in the situation
where you don't have the skill.
You have two options.
Option one is the easy path,
which is I'm just never going to get
that skill. Never to go near Jujitsu.
I'm never going to get in a confrontation
with anybody because I don't want to
be proven to myself that
I'm a warm inside of a suit
or you can take the hard path,
which is,
even though I'm 37 years old,
I'm bummed that I missed out on the
bar. You know, I took me awhile,
but you know what? I'm going
to go figure this out. Yeah.
I'm going to go at least learn some of it.
I'm going to at least learn some of it.
I would take that even though I
know it's hard because people,
you know when you're, when you get older
you don't want to try something new.
Even though it's proven that learning
something new is completely beneficial for
your mental and physical health.
Yeah.
And ice and yeah,
it's not all like
pleasurable roses and stuff.
I don't know. Did you know there's
some, there's some struggle in there,
but tell me about it. There's
there, there's dean lister. I was,
I was in turtle position.
Dean lister is shoulders healing back up.
I was internal position mount and side
control for 22 minutes the other day.
And that's a struggle.
And also he was pushing my
face into the mat and saying,
what color is the mat?
See?
Like as you see what I'm saying, well
what does that fun? The answer's no, no.
That's high level struggle because
the typical person you go into,
that's not gonna happen to you.
So that's,
that's like the struggle that's going
to get someone that has a personal
vendetta on your existence that
Dean has on mine. Yeah. Yeah.
I think it was a CD called kill Jocko
does indeed. Factually. Nonetheless.
All right. There's going to be
some struggle in there. You get it,
but you jump in there just like
everything. When you learn golf,
there's gonna be a struggle. No, you're
going to miss that hole sometimes,
but I know it's a
different kind of struggle,
but on a fundamental level it's
all the same struggle here.
Nonetheless,
you're going to need a g and when you
get your g you're going to go to origin
main.com get an origin gets.
It's the best kind of made in America
from the cotton grown in America loomed or
we've woven for woven in America,
assembled, sewn, stitched,
presented,
enjoyed in utilize,
utilize in America in America actually
can be utilized where for but none the
less, I mean in America and they
are factually, no, not my opinion.
Sounds like an opinion,
but it's factually there.
Factually the best firm in the world.
What's cool is
the geese are awesome,
but there's a problem.
It's a problem. The problem is you
can't wear a geek to the store,
to the restaurant. No, not really. And yet
you were the origin pants and you think,
man, I wouldn't mind, you
know, if they had a pocket I
would roll out. Right. Yeah.
Especially if you get the black
ones, you know, like it's not,
it's not crazy to think,
hey,
maybe I'll just kind of roll out to the
store or maybe go take my wife out for
dinner.
No,
but that's okay because guess what
we got now denim or jeans dig it.
Yeah. Yeah. So those are common. Yeah.
Not quite out yet, but I got mine.
Yeah. I don't have mine
and texting Pete, Bruh.
I don't want to buy and eat a pizza
and he's busy, man. He does a lot.
And I don't want to,
I don't want to,
my personal interests start to create
roadblocks or speed bumps and get this
whole thing, but I do want those
jeans though. That's a thing.
So I got to balance that.
A little dichotomy,
my personal interest in the
interest of Pete and his discourse.
Nonetheless, I will
have them. We will have,
when did they come out then
in the process of coming out?
Right now you have the material.
We are cutting the material now.
We're so in the material. Yeah.
It's interesting cause I don't really get
excited about James or I don't get it,
like new genes coming
out or the new iPhone.
I don't get excited
about that kind of stuff.
But for some reason I'm
kinda excited about,
tell you why I'm a little bit
excited about it because of this.
Jeans are American, right?
Genes represent America.
Let's face it, if you wanted to
draw a stereotypical American human,
they'd be wearing a pair of jeans. Here's
the problem. Jeans were made in America.
Jeans were invented in America.
Genes became famous in America.
And then we sold our soul
and put them overseas.
Let them get manufactured overseas,
something that shouldn't have happened.
And so to bring it back to America,
does that feel good?
Indeed? Yes, it does. It makes
sense. I dig it. So, yeah,
bring back in the soul. Um, other clothes,
their tee shirts and stuff from origin.
If you can get, even if you don't want
jeans, you could get joggers right now.
Quick supplements to joint warfare,
Krill oil discipline, discipline,
go discipline go.
So when I work,
sometimes I have to work for two,
three straight hours
without any interruptions.
Gotcha. Yeah. Yeah. You
see what I'm saying?
So I would be drinking discipline and all
of a sudden I'm an hour and 40 minutes
in. And guess what? I got to hit the
head. Well, the restroom break. Yeah.
So that's why we made discipline goal.
Just Morgan is just a, uh, a pill.
Is that what it's called? A capsule and
it's got the, uh, got the goodness in it.
And we also have coming the
discipline going to can you had drink?
Yeah. That's like if you had it yet. Yes.
That's the one where like we were,
it was that,
did that give you one in New York
when we were in, did the New York,
I had one before that they sent
me. So yes. Good. I got it.
I got more coming today.
Hopefully will be here, but um,
yeah, so that'd be common.
Of course we got Moeloek,
which apparently doctor Luke hates
mint chocolate chip passionately.
And so when I heard him
going off the other day,
like why would you want anything that
tastes like toothpaste, toothpaste?
So we have a little disagreement.
We'll have to settle that one on the mat,
but he's just going with peanut butter
vanilla grill or something. Good.
And don't forget about the war.
Your kid milk. No kidding. Yeah,
it tastes like strawberry.
Nestle's strawberry quick.
That's what it tastes like.
Can I say that? Is that legal? Yes.
Okay. Okay. Whether it's legal or not,
I can say I did say it and
it's tastes exactly like that.
I'm using that exactly like
it's strawberry, Nestle's Quik,
but it has no sugar.
It's got awesome protein and it
will make your kid into the next,
you're about to say something
illegal right now. The next
squared away athlete. There you go.
Smart. Yes. I was going to name names,
but I'm not going to name names, but
so that's what works in main.com. Yeah,
that's a good officer.
They're all my people,
all my people up at origin that are
working every day, someone cutting,
stitching,
moving,
shipping and make pretty much
getting after it big time. Also,
we have a store, it's called
Jocko store, you know,
stuff a little bit more formulated
for representing the path itself.
Um, you know, a little bit skewed,
but some good stuff on there.
Some new stuff on there too by
the way. Oh really? Yeah, they uh,
the traveler travel mugs.
Okay. Kind of new. Good. Uh,
I'm putting it hoodie up there,
but black on black. I like that.
It's subtle heavy. Okay. Is
it heavy? Is it legit? Heavy,
legit, heavy, legit. Like it's
the head. Is it the heaviest,
heaviest one in existence?
I'm sorry to say no,
but is there one that
you've ever made? Yes. It's,
I want noticeably heavier to them than
the original black on black. All right.
You got it.
Two of them nonetheless.
Good stuff on their rash guards on
there too for Jujitsu for did you did to
representing the path big time on now.
And also
you can do other stuff with rash
guards as well. But, um, yeah,
some good stuff on there. If you want
to represent support, stay on the path.
That's where you go, Jocko. store.com.
Here's the thing about getting new
stuff too, and this is, this is,
this is where six year old echo brain
comes out and there's a straight up,
but it's still apply. It's still didn't,
if this dawns on me from time to time,
especially when it hits me, when
you get like a new thing, right?
I've talked about this before. When you
get a new rash guard, six years old bra,
you don't even act he life.
You know? And I think,
I think you think the same thing.
I think you feel the same way.
You won't necessarily admit it,
especially not to me, but I think you,
I think you feel the same way. Okay? If
you got a new thing of something that,
that excites me to get new and um,
you keep doing what you're doing.
I'll think of something over here. We'll,
we'll think surfboard, think whatever.
Nonetheless. There you go. So if you
get a new, a rash guard, a new gooey,
um, even new socks, sometimes
new shoes, new socks,
1843,
I get the socks from audit from it,
I get fired up nonetheless. You get
something new, get a rash guard.
This is get after it.
If you don't have one already,
you will be looking forward to
going to Jujitsu that much more.
And that's the good thing about like
these things that represents the pounds.
It's a hundred percent
correct. Try it. Try.
Actually I would say for anyone who has
like, you know, a shirt or whatever,
they felt it. Oh that's what I,
that's what I predict. No, I,
I understand what you're saying and
it actually is true when people,
when you get the,
you know,
that's the classic classic
scene from literature.
Sure. When is the, I think it's like
the dawning of the uniform of the,
of the warrior and they do it in movies
to the collage. They, you know, the,
the heroes putting his boots on and
then he's putting his web gear on.
And even just when people
see the superheroes secret
thing opens up and all of
his gears in there, it is
all fired up. Like the vet,
the old fet das go into that
chest in his or like in,
in Mike and the dragons.
You know when he's opening,
opening up the chest filled with war gear.
You know everyone got a little fired up.
Yeah cause they understand exactly right.
There we go. Same deal anyway Jocko,
store.com you want to
represent on the path,
get fired up about stuff.
There you go.
She's something like grab
something also Jocko white tea.
We're still doing that.
I'm still doing that big time
because I was never a tea person.
And W I mean I'm saying that's,
that's saying something because I was
never a tea person. But guess what?
Look at me.
Tea person that will kind of,
I only drink this tea but
you know I'm into it. Jocko.
White tea person. Big Time.
How's that deadlift? Huge. 8,100 pounds.
Actually I've been sticking with it.
Hey subscribe to the podcast.
If you haven't iTunes,
Google, play, stitcher, leave
reviews. So I can read them.
Yeah, if you will. If you want. If
you don't want them, don't what?
Also worry or kid podcasts,
subscribe to that.
While I was on a podcast yesterday and
they asked me to say subscribe to their
podcast and I said, I don't even ask
people to subscribe to my podcast.
And I was like, well actually I
got to do and now I just did. Yeah,
maybe it's actually you and I had this
discussion many times. I was like,
why do we need to cause you, you like
when people need to do to subscribe.
Maybe they haven't subscribed.
I mean, we're 162 podcast deep.
That's gotta be four or
500 hours of listening.
You don't think someone hit subscribe yet.
Well I,
I agree with you fully so we can,
can we cut this out now? Yeah.
You wrote this by the way, but yeah,
of course we can. Well this is,
this is a carryover carryover.
Oh yes.
Look,
it's us doing what we talked about before
earlier today about doing things like,
because that's just how you know,
you gotta think. Got To think,
why do we want to waste five seconds
of someone's time telling him?
It just sounds kind of like,
what is it like what do you call it?
Redundant or something. It's kind
of like, um, do you think everyone,
who do you think anyone ever got to this
0.3 hours deep into the podcast and you
are, I said and subscribing and they
reached down to, they're like, oh my gosh.
Yeah. Oh shoot, I can do that. Hey,
let me tell you what you might forget.
You might forget to subscribe
to the warrior kid podcast
because it's not coming
out quite as consistently at this time,
but it is a great podcast for you
or for your kids to listen to,
to get them on the path. Yeah,
they can also, if you have kids,
that's a good one. Oh, if you have
kids is definitely a good one.
If you don't have kids,
it's not a bad one. Yeah,
you can learn some real fundamental.
Those are lessons that you kind of forget.
That's what I think. I also get
to war kids soap, Irish oaks,
ranch.com got young aid and warrior kid
making soap. Yeah, just
having his own business. Yeah.
Throw him some support.
Whatever. Irish oaks,
ranch.com real soap too by the way.
This like Ooh,
kit on the line and put my
flavor in there and sell it.
You can do that. Oh I didn't
know you could do that. How that,
do you even know that I,
you know,
get all kinds of weird
knowledge on the left.
Don't forget about youtube and
that's where you can see echoes,
legit videos and when you
get done watching the video,
make sure you hit some.
Nonetheless, we do have a youtube
channel. That's the point.
That is the point because you know if
you liked the video version or you didn't
know there was a video version, you can
leave comments there too. I read them,
I read youtube comments even though
Joe Rogan tells me not to. Yeah,
cause you do.
That's a slippery slope
because if a comment comes
and it like it say what's the
worst can comment is the kind that's
true or kind of true that like just like
are you were saying like it won't hit you.
It's not a hard punch.
It's a little indirect fire.
It's an indirect fire but more effective
like you know in your neck or something.
It's like that. It has to be
a little bit true. I actually,
I think I've told you this before,
but I was one night I was reading youtube
comments to my oldest daughter about
me cause they were, and I forget it
was, it wasn't our podcast, it was,
it was a different podcast,
a podcast that maybe people weren't as
much on board with the programs they had.
It's a lot of really colorful to see.
Yeah.
So I think just you,
Joe Rogan saying to you like,
don't read them and this is why he
doesn't like that. He just, you know,
he doesn't say it like, Hey,
hey Jocko. Don't know what
I'm saying. Like he's like,
oh you can't read the youtube comments
man. He'll say it like that. Yes.
And that's what I mean.
So you just knowing that allows
you to go in and know like, okay,
you can read them and you just got
to know that that's accessible.
Most of them now in Jordan
Peterson like says he reads it,
but like they impact him. Yes. He
just, no, he didn't mean it. No, no.
Joe Rogan need to tell him that. You
got to tell them, hey, that's like,
that's not a normal comment
section is what I'm saying.
It's not like on Instagram where
it's like, hey, you know, it's like,
it's just different. The dynamic, Bruh. I
used to make these videos, you know this,
but I used to make these videos like
parodies of like Darth Vader goes on dates
and then I made this one. You put
those on my channel, on our channel,
on your channel. People still watch
it. I mean they're funny. And Jeff Gla,
but I made this one a
bikini light saber battle.
Gloria and them,
they're just fighting with light sabers
at the beach or whatever and well,
you know, you know people watch him. But
man, I look at the comments on that, man.
It's like people, I think someone
wanted me to die. He said,
whoever made this should die, like
literally said that. I was like,
what was the hating about it? What were
they hitting about it? It was dumb. Oh,
okay. Which it is by the way.
Yeah, it's like two girls.
They're mad at something and then they
fight lightsaber and then like she wanted
the girl kills the other one and then
like Spiderman comes out is basically all
the props that I had at my house. I was
like, let me make a video, you know?
And so it was like, you
know, it was dumb for sure,
but probably you don't have to
say that Ken comments like that,
I got to die now because it's dumb.
Anyway, the point is, yeah, you gotta,
you gotta kind of know that that's
not a normal comments. Youtube there.
I get it. I get good entertainment
out of it. It's pretty fun.
Also got psychological warfare. That's on
iTunes, Google play, MP three platforms.
And that is a album with tracks about how
to overcome various stages of weakness
that you might occur that
might occur during your day.
That's all we're going to say about that
one. That's good. That's very concise.
It's Jocko though, by the way, on the
track. So that's something also on it.
On it.com/jocko this is where I
get all my kettle bells and socks.
Like I mentioned.
It seems odd like why you just get socks
from on it because they're freaking
dope. You ever watch the, he ever look
at the socks on on it or a freaking good?
Yeah, really good. You want to flex on?
The guys had her, I got all of them.
So weird flex but okay.
No.
When you want to flex at the, uh,
at the people at the Tsa I keep,
I keep wanting to use
the term flex second.
That's modern way because my kids
use it and I keep wanting to use it.
Keep trying men. Yeah. I think
you're doing pretty good. But no,
I haven't really
appropriately used it yet.
Will you used weird flex but
okay on to me. Not about me.
Like you were, you were saying
about someone else? Uh, no,
because Casey had a video that was
called that it was called weird flux,
but okay. And that's when I
realized it was a thing that,
that that's an actual thing.
Weird flex, but okay. No,
you told me it was a thing that
I don't use it, I want to use it,
but it's sort of a humble brag, right?
No, like weird flex. It's, yeah.
It's like you're bragging about
something kind of weird to brag about,
but cool man, dude, do what you do
kind of thing. Oh, that's what the,
that's what Casey's video was weird
flecks of what okay. Was about,
he was in,
he's in a movie and he was kind of like
flexing that he was in a movie and he
was like, but okay. Yeah, here's all
fired up. Yeah. It'd be more like, Hey,
like I can turn my eyelids inside out.
Okay.
All right. We are flags because
flex was a little stronger.
You see what I'm saying?
Nonetheless on it.
This is where you get your fitness stuff,
probably you,
you know how were we all have
home gyms? Most of us. Yeah.
And you know you want a day,
you want some more kettle bells.
You want some jump ropes,
battle ropes, like stuff,
more good stuff to keep you on the path,
keep you in shape.
That's where you go on it. Dot. If
you want to get your mind in shape,
your brain in shape,
then you should read.
If you want to read some
books that I wrote, then cool.
You can read Mikey and the dragons.
Best Children's book ever for children
under the age of six voted by me and you
and our children and our children.
Actually, someone asked my daughter,
my middle daughter the other day,
what's your favorite book of Your Dad's?
And she said, Mikey and the dragons.
Interesting. My daughter didn't,
we didn't have any kind of official
like, oh, what's the best one?
But the one that she always reaches for
pushes for is where the warrior kid to
months mission. She likes
marks mission. So there's that.
So there's Mike in the dragons. There's
way the warrior could to Mark's mission.
There's way the court warrior kid one,
we're just called way of the warrior
kid soon to be way the warrior kid three
writing is complete.
John Bozak is knee deep in the art right
now and that will be coming out in the
spring. I'm going to get it on Amazon
for preorder as early as I possibly can.
So we don't have another
scenario like we had with Mikey,
the dragons where we bought,
you all bought a lot of them
and I didn't have them on hand.
Let's say I did give him everybody,
everybody by Christmas.
So look for that one way the warrior
kid three will be coming out.
And then of course we got discipline
equal freedom field manual,
which is awesome to
see that impact people.
And it's also a good gift
to give to people that maybe
need a little help. Yeah,
just kinda steer me the right direction.
Extreme ownership and the
dichotomy of leadership.
Those are the leadership books that I
wrote with my brother Leif Babin and
they will help you with your organization
and in Your Business and in your life
lead.
And when also we got to echelon front,
which is my leadership consultancy.
It's me,
it's Leif Babin JP to know Dave Burke,
Flynn Cochran at Mike's Rally.
Mike by Emma.
There's a picture of that echoes into
the picture on the website.
Yeah man. But he's not,
he's not one of the
leadership instructors.
He is one of the leadership
instructor filmers.
Right? Uh Hey man, I'm on the
website. So that's really all.
So what we do is we solve
problems through leadership,
go national in front.com for that.
We also have the monster coming up 2019
it's going to be May 23rd and 24th in
Chicago,
September 19th and 20th in Denver
and December 4th and fifth in Sydney,
Australia.
Check out a treme,
ownership.com they all have sold out
and this will solve a sell out as well.
And when you go to that your going
to get granular explanations,
multiple angles on how to work and apply
this stuff and if you can't come to
muster, guess what, you
can go somewhere else.
You can go to eff online.com
this is what we put together.
It took us about nine months
to film put together design.
It's me and the rest of the Ashkelon
Front team training leadership through
technology and it's available for,
we originally designed it for enterprise
for companies that we work with that
have 48,000 employees and we can't travel
the globe and train them all so we put
this stuff online and it's also available
now direct to consumer [inaudible] dot
com and also we have EFO Overwatch.
Yeah overwatch.com where we are connecting
proven leaders from combat aviation
and from special operations and we're
plugging them into companies that need
leadership to win at their mission.
So giddy go to f overwatch.com if you
need that and if you want to pass on
lessons learned to us,
we are kicking it on the interwebs,
on Twitter,
on Instagram and on Facebook.
Echo is adequate.
Charles and I am at jockowillink and
of course thanks to all of our military
personnel around the world
who stand their ground to protect us
and also thank you to our police and
law enforcement, the firefighters,
the paramedics and EMT,
the correctional officers,
the folks on patrol in all the first
responders who stand their ground here at
home to protect us.
Okay.
And everyone else.
I always say that time is short,
but most of us have more
than six seconds.
The six seconds that
Corporal Jonathan Yale
and Lance Corporal Jordan Herger had
to make the ultimate decision and the
ultimate sacrifice.
They could have had more time
had they run away,
but they sacrificed it all.
Okay?
They gave up their time,
but we,
we still have time to
time they gave to us.
Okay.
So don't waste it.
Not six minutes of it,
not six seconds of it,
not one second of it.
None of it get out there
every second of every day.
Get after it.
You're no till next time.
This is echo and Jocko
out.