This is Jocko podcast number
one 75 with Echo Charles and me,
Jocko Willink. Good
Evening Echo. Good evening.
23 October,
1942 eighth army personal
message from the army commander.
When I assumed command of the eighth army,
I said that the mandate was to destroy
Rommel and his army and that it would be
done as soon as we are ready.
We are ready now.
The battle which is about to begin,
we'll be one of the
decisive battles of history.
It will be the turning point of the war.
The eyes of the whole world will be
on us watching anxiously which way the
battle will swing.
Okay.
We can give them their answer at once.
It will swing our way.
We have FirstClass equipment,
good tanks,
good anti tank guns,
plenty of artillery and
plenty of ammunition and we
are backed up by the finest
air striking force in the world.
All that is necessary
is that each one of us,
every officer in man should enter this
battle with the determination to see it
through,
to fight and to kill and finally to win.
Yeah.
If we all do this,
there can be only one result.
Okay.
Together we will hit the enemy
for six right out of North Africa.
Okay.
The sooner we win this battle, which
will be the turning point of the war,
the sooner we shall all get
back home to our families.
Therefore,
let every officer and man enter the
battle with a stout heart and the
determination to do his duty as
long as he has breath in his body.
Yeah.
And let no man surrender so long
as he is on wounded and can fight.
Let us all pray that the Lord Mighty
in battle will give us victory.
B L Montgomery,
Lieutenant General Eighth Army,
and that
is it.
Note written on the eve
of the battle of Al Ameen,
which ended up being the turning
point of the war in North Africa.
Okay.
In general,
Bernard Montgomery,
commonly referred to as Monte
defeated the Desert Fox Rommel,
one of the most respected
generals in all of history really.
And Monte was a actually a controversial
figure and I think he got more
controversial, the more famous he
got. He fought in world war one.
Okay.
He was a soldier. He was gravely wounded
by a sniper in the battle of, he prays,
he was shot in the lung.
He was in such bad shape that
they actually dug a grave for him.
But somehow he pulled through,
he recovered,
he served the rest of the
war as a staff officer.
And he was actually very critical of the,
of the tactics and of the strategy and
have the willingness of the leadership to
accept such horrific and
heinous levels of casualties.
So he was critical of that. And
after the war was over, he served,
he stayed in the army, he served
in Palestine, he served in India.
And then in 1939 of course there was more
war and he was in command of the third
division.
He went to France and he was actually
pretty worried about going to France.
He didn't feel super confident about it.
And he returned home with the rest of
the British forces that were driven off
the content continent
from Dunkirk.
And you know,
they're,
they were able to refit to be able to
go out and reengage and he headed to
Africa next. And the eighth army
was pretty beat down at that point.
When he showed up though,
he turned around their morale and made
them believe that they could win and won
the first major land victory of the
war in the second battle of El Alamein.
From there he helped the invasion of
Sicily and Italy and then he commanded all
forces, all ground forces on d day.
He commanded all the ground forces.
So that was obviously a massive operation.
He planned and led
operation market garden,
which was the invasion of low countries.
And we've covered some of those battles
on this podcast because it was not good.
It didn't go well and he was
kind of a guy pushing that.
But he was able to redeem himself from
that during the battle of the bulge,
which we've also covered on this podcast.
So you know,
he had some ups and downs,
but mostly ups.
So what was the controversy or what's
this kind of tainted image of him?
First of all,
some people saw him as being arrogant
and some of the people that saw him
as being arrogant. We're Americans,
Americans like patent. And
Bradley and I mean, let's face it,
if you're talking about for sure patent,
we're not talking about
a guy with a small ego.
So you can imagine that when you have
a clash of Egos that can be, you know,
when you can get some
professional jealousy and whatnot.
Even Sir Winston Churchill
said that Monte was,
and this is a good quote in defeat
on beatable in victory, unbearable.
So there's another,
an anecdote about him where he was asked
to name three great generals and he
said the other two would be Alexander
the great and Napoleon meaning he's just
on top of the list.
So he may have had,
it may have been a little
bit egotistical and, and,
and I think from what I've read about him,
he lacked,
lacked tact
and later on in life he was kind of
contract. He was controversial as well.
He was very critical of
American tactics in Vietnam.
He said that America had no clear cut
objective in Vietnam, which, you know,
I'm critical of the tactics in Vietnam.
I think it's pretty safe to say that
there should've been more clear cut
objective that that obviously made some
of our military leadership in America
angry. I don't know if I would
argue against those statements. He,
he oddly enough,
spoke positively about the Chinese
communist government when he was older.
He, he publicly supported
apartheid in South Africa.
So these are more things that people
sort of sort of tainted his image.
But besides all that,
he is still known as a,
as a,
as a tactician.
And there's plenty of support
from his troops and his men that,
that loved him and were
ready to follow him anywhere.
And there's some people that
say even that he acted arrogant.
It was almost like a show that he put
on to kind of unify as troops that this
was Monte, this was the great guy.
And we're just, we're, we got,
look what Monte did, you know,
so there's that. He wrote a lot.
He spoke, he wrote, well,
he's got some great some documents
that he put out and I one on one.
He's got a ton that you put out. One
of them I'm going to read. It's a very,
it's a very interesting piece in,
and so he wrote this after Germany had
surrendered and the British occupation
forces were in place in Germany.
So you've got the Brits there in
Germany occupying the country.
You've got the German civilians
who had been defeated in war.
And here we go to this message
that he wrote, 10 June,
1945 Germany,
personal message from the commander in
chief to the population of the British
area in Germany.
You have wondered,
no doubt why our soldiers do not smile
when you wave your hands or say good
morning in the streets or
play with the children.
It is because our soldiers
are obeying orders.
You do not like it,
nor do our soldiers.
We are naturally friendly and people,
but the orders were necessary.
And I will tell you why.
In the last war of 1914
which your rulers began,
your army was defeated,
your generals surrendered,
and the peace treaty of Versailles,
your rulers admitted that the guilt
of beginning the war was Germany's,
but the surrender was made in France.
The war never came to your country.
Your cities were not damaged like the
cities of French, France and Belgium,
and your armies marched
home in good order.
Okay.
Then your rulers began to spread the
story that your armies were never really
defeated and later they denied the
war guilt clauses of the peace treaty.
They told you that Germany was
neither guilty nor defeated,
and because the war had
not come to your country,
many of you believed it and you cheered
when your rulers began another war
again, after years of waste
and slaughter and misery,
your armies have been defeated
this time.
The allies were determined that
you should learn your lesson.
Not only that you have been defeated,
which you must know by now,
but that you your nation.
We're again guilty of beginning the war
for if that is not made clear
to you and your children,
you may again allow yourselves to be
deceived by your rulers and led into
another war.
During the war,
your rulers would not let you know
what the world was thinking of you.
Yeah.
Many of you seem to think that
when our soldiers arrived,
you could be friends with them at
once as if nothing much had happened,
but too much has happened for that.
Our soldiers have seen their comrades
shot down their homes and ruins their
wives and children hungry.
They've seen terrible things in many
countries where your rulers took the war.
Okay?
For those things, you will say, you are
not responsible. It was your rulers,
but they were done by the German nation.
Every nation is responsible for its
rulers and while they were successful,
you cheered and laughed.
That is why our soldiers
do not smile at you. This,
we have ordered this.
We have done to save yourselves,
to save your children,
to save the world from another war.
It will not always be so for we are
Christian forgiving people and we like to
smile and be friendly.
Our object is to destroy
the evil of the Nazi system.
It is too soon to be sure
that this has been done.
You are to read this to your children.
If they are old enough and
see that they understand,
tell them why it is that the
British soldier does not smile.
Bl Montgomery Field Marshal
commander in chief British area.
So obviously that message was produced
in German and in English and spread out
amongst the population.
I thought that was a pretty awesome
outlook and he also spoke and wrote a fair
amount about leadership
and I think when you look at
his writing in his speeches,
you can see some of his,
some of his peculiarities, some of his
personality shines through sometimes.
And I want to take a look at some of that.
Some of the things that he wrote.
And the first piece is
called military leadership.
And it's actually from a speech that he
gave at the University of St Andrews 15
November, 1945 it's like a
transcript or maybe it's as notes,
I'm not sure which,
but it's,
it's written as if he was reading it.
So
here we go. Let's go to this
book. Military leadership.
I've come here to take to talk
to you about military leadership.
A subject such as this must in normal
times seems somewhat remote from this
quiet gray walled city by the sea.
Today I have to try and equate
the definition of military
leadership as I see it
to the lessons of the past and
to the experience of the present.
I proposed to limit myself in
this talk to higher leadership,
the command of armies or a group of
armies and not to consider the quality of
leadership at lower levels.
What I say about higher leadership
may well have certain application to
leadership of a brigade or a company
or a section of men. There are,
however,
certain differences in leadership at
lower levels and I do not propose to take
up your time by discussing these today.
Now you'll see as he goes into this,
he covers these talking about that all
the time. I'm not sure even why he,
he did that,
but he talks about the the the entire
chain of command throughout this speech.
Military leadership is a subject which
has always interested me and during this
war I have had some opportunity
to put my ideas to the test.
I have found that if you
aspire to lead soldiers,
you must take a close study of human
nature for that as the raw material with
which a commander has to achieve his end.
If you neglect human factor as a leader,
you will fail.
The personal relationship between the
commander and his soldiers is and always
has been one of the most potent single
factors in making for success in war.
If a commander has the complete
confidence and trust of his men,
there is nothing.
He cannot do nothing.
If a commander loses the
confidence of his men,
he cannot succeed.
Yeah.
That's a bold statement right there.
That's a bold statement right there and
something that I talk about all the time
and there's two. There's,
there's two words that I use
interchangeably. I should,
I should use them more interchangeably.
More often.
I talk about relationships a lot and the
word that I should use intermixed with
that 50% of the time is trust.
Cause to me trusting relationships,
it's kind of the same thing.
If you don't have trust,
you don't have a relationship. Yeah.
If you don't have a relationship,
then you don't have trust. But they
do have different meanings, right?
So it's important to me to establish that.
And the reason that I bring that up
is because if you're in a leadership
position and you're breaking the
trust that you have with your men,
that is going to be a real problem.
Yeah. So you could say, well,
you don't have a good
relationship with them,
but you could not have a good relationship
with someone and they could still
trust you.
You could not have a good relationship
with someone and you hadn't broken their
trust.
It's going to be hard if you break your,
their trust to have a
good relationship with.
But the key factor here is
trust and confidence of the men.
Back to the book.
Now,
let us consider on what a man's power to
lead others is based is necessary first
to define what is meant by leadership.
And this is where this
gets a little interesting.
I suggest to you as the
definition of the word leadership,
the will to dominate together
with the character, which,
which inspires confidence.
The measure of a man's ability to lead,
I think is twofold.
So the first part of the definition of
leadership and his mind is the will to
dominate. Hmm. Which is we're just,
we just stuck and you're going to see
where he kind of counters that and he
talks about,
he talks about decentralized command.
He talks about everything that
that I believe in. But you know,
I don't talk about, hey, as a leader,
it's first and foremost that you have
to will to dominate other humans. Right?
That's not, in fact, I think that's
a kind of a negative quality.
But that being said,
if you have someone that
doesn't mind not winning,
not dominating, well then guess what?
They're not going to put forth any effort.
They're not going to make things
happen like force of will.
I talk about that all the time.
You, you, you have to import.
You have to have the force of
will to make things happen.
Sometimes you just have
to make things happen.
They're not going to happen by themselves.
Anything that's anything that's
going to come that's good in life.
It's not going to happen by itself is
just not going to wake up and it's there.
Like, like an Easter egg
that's not happening. Oh No.
You've got to go out and you
gotta make it happen. Yeah. Okay.
Maybe you get an Easter egg when
you're six years old lawyer.
Once you're 26 years old,
there's no Easter eggs coming to you.
You got to make them okay.
Yeah. Back to the book.
First, it lies in his will to dominate
the men and events which surround him,
the will to drive himself and his men
to the limit of their powers for a
specific purpose and the refusal to
allow anything to divert him from his aim
again, you're going to see where that
sounds so strong. It sounds unbalanced,
right? It sounds, it sounds like he's
outside the dichotomy of leadership.
He's going too far in one direction
is being extreme like nothing.
You're going to refuse to allow
anything to divert you. Oh, okay.
So does that mean that mean
you get everyone killed?
That's what they did in World
War One and he didn't like that.
But you're going to see where he balances
out these statements later. Second,
it lies in the strength of his character,
whether good or evil,
to inspire others to place their complete
trust and confidence in him and his
ability to lead them with success and
to infuse his men for the task in hand.
This ability of a man to
inspire confidence in others
and to create enthusiasm
is a spiritual quality,
but it is not,
but it is well to remember that this
quality need not necessarily be for good.
The evil leader has equally the ability
to inspire confidence in others and in
history.
The evil leader has often at
any rate temporarily prevailed
and he counters that at the end too.
There have been many with different,
with different types of characters,
character who have inspired
men to follow them.
I proposed to choose three great captains
of the past and examine briefly why
these men were leaders and how they lead
their men and how as leaders that they
succeeded or fails. So he's going
to go into a little case study,
a couple of pages here.
I will first consider Moses.
He was already old when he was called to
lead the children of Israel out of the
land of Egypt.
His task was an immense one.
He had first to inspire his people to
cast off the yoke of the Egyptians.
This was no easy matter.
Israel had been living for about 400
years as slaves of the Egyptians.
They had lived in the Nile delta,
a bad climate and one which tends
to SAP up energy and initiative,
but they lived where food was plenteous.
While all around were deserts,
which could barely support life.
Moses must've had to overcome the most
tremendous initial inertia to persuade
Israel to launch out into those
deserts with all the risks of famine,
disease and the necessity to fight his
power to inspire and dominate his fellow
men must have been of a very
high. Now see, that's where I dis,
I don't look at that as domination
of your fellow man. You're, I look,
I see the inspiring part, but
I'm not looking at it. Hey,
we are looking to dominate.
I see his angle, right?
I see. I see what he's, I see
where he's coming from, but,
and maybe that word, you know, words
change words, Murph morph over time.
Maybe that word dominate that he's using.
Maybe.
Maybe it had less of a
sting to it then you know,
50 years ago possibly hadn't a listing.
70 years of words change
words change over time,
but that's what he's saying.
But things were kind of
hardcore to right back then.
You know how like long time ago
they're just things in general.
We're a little bit more blunt.
Yeah. So maybe the Times, Moses,
I'm sure they were pretty blunt and even
this time. Yeah. I don't know though.
I'm not,
I'm not 100% sure.
I'm not 100% sure if he means the
word dominate the way we think of it,
the way I think of it,
apparently not.
I mean it seems like there's a
little bit more to it, I guess.
Well when he counted and
you'll hear him counter.
I guess that's what maybe makes me think,
maybe he means it a little bit less severe
maybe because he starts to talk about
the, the balance of this dichotomy,
because let's face it, hey, okay.
Let me ask you this question here.
This one is gonna make it real easy.
If I was a type of person that was like a,
I'm looking to dominate you,
come with me into the desert where
we're going to have to live with,
as we're going away from the Nile River
and we're going out to this barren area
where there's not a lot of food and I'm
going to have a domineering personality
and I'm gonna be all over you every day.
How enticing is that? Not Very. Not Very.
Now, if I was inspiring and
I said, listen, Echo, we're
going to get out there.
We're going to train, we're going to
come back. We're gonna get our revenge.
It's going to take some time, but
we're gonna make it. You're like that.
That's different, right? Yeah. Yeah.
So yeah.
You know what?
Now that I'm thinking about it would
dominate like what's the root word of
dominant? You know what it could be. Yeah.
I should have studied the etymology before
we got on this podcast. I apologize.
You know what? It could
be though. Picture,
when you have a good leader that dominates
the room, right? Right, right. Yeah.
That's a positive thing, right? So this
guy just get you. Oh yeah. You know,
Echo came in for the meeting. He just
dominated the world. He did great. Right?
That's a positive thing. So maybe
he means it that way. Unfortunately,
he talks about dominating the wail of,
right?
He talks about dominating the
men and events that surround him.
I don't know. Actually. It doesn't
talk about dominating the will,
so maybe that's what they mean.
Maybe he means just like
this dominating presence.
All right.
Going back to the book without a doubt.
Moses realized that when
he led Israel out of Egypt,
they were useless as a fighting people.
They had been slaves for some 400 years.
He therefore set to work to train them
for the task and to forge the weapon
which would conquer Canaan.
It's interesting,
he talks about the training
of armies as forging weapons,
like you're forging this weapon.
I think that's a pretty cool analogy.
I believe that Moses intentionally kept
Israel for 40 years in the desert for
two generations in order to breed
and train a fighting race capable of
undertaking the task of
conquest which lay at hand.
And in that 40 years he taught them
gradually how to fight and conquer.
He took meticulous care
over there training and it
is most interesting to note
his refusal ever to risk
any failures into action.
This is interesting and he brings
us up quite a bit. So Moses,
Moses didn't take any risk of where
he was, thought he might fail.
We read of him soon after leaving Egypt,
asking if he might lead Israel through
the country of another people on being
refused permission.
He marches round by another way,
but later when the same situation arises,
when Israel is better trained to fight,
he leads his people straight through the
middle of that country and destroys his
enemy utterly.
He was a good judge of what Israel was
capable of doing and what Israel was not
capable of doing.
And as a result,
he had an unbroken record
of military successes.
He had the wisdom and the insight into
human nature to realize that the best way
for a leader to gain confidence of his
soldiers is to give them victories.
If a commander gives his soldiers
victories, they will follow him anywhere.
But Moses was not permitted to see
the few fruits of his own work.
He sinned by claiming as his own powers,
which did not belong to him.
And for this sin of presumption,
he was forced to hand over to Joshua the
final conquest of Canaan for which he
had so well trained
the children of Israel.
So there he wraps up on on Moses,
eh?
I think that, and he kind of refers
back to this point later in the,
in this book is the fact that you
got to be, you know, you gotta,
you gotta push for victory, right? You
got to push for victory and this is,
it's almost like risk aversion,
right?
Which I'm not a fan of and
you can't be risk averse,
but you got to be calculated
back to the book.
And then the next section he
is going to talk about chrome.
Well he just refers to him as Carl Unwell.
Oliver Cromwell,
Cromwell who wasn't an English
statesmen but he was a soldier.
This is like in the 1600 1620s
he was a hardcore puritan
and he organized military forces in the,
when the civil war broke out,
1642 he was the deputy
commander of the new model army.
He defeated the main royalist
in 1645 and then he commanded campaigns
in Ireland and Scotland and the 1650s
he was,
he was kind of a over the top,
I guess you might say in some ways he eat,
I mean beyond that he, he mass and
him, there was an Irish massacre,
you know, and that spiraled into
a war for hundreds of years.
And,
and ultimately as a politician,
once he kind of got done with a war
part, he became a politician. He end,
he really didn't do a great job.
So that's just some kind of
highlights of Oliver Cromwell.
But here we go back to the book I next
proposed to consider Cromwells another
leader who went to wage war only
when he was over middle age.
He was over 40 when the
civil war broke out.
He started the civil war in command of
a troop of 60 men and then commanded of
that troop.
He fought at edge hill there in spite
of the parliamentary superiority and men
and guns and a free fervently held
cause he saw the failure of his own side
disease,
the victory.
And s and he saw them escape defeat only
because of the folly of their opponents.
This gave him much cause for thought
superiority in men and equipment was
clearly valueless unless something further
was added.
This is a part that I kind of got
fired up for what was needed also.
So besides guns,
good superiority in magnet
superiority equipment.
What was needed also was the leader
who would forge the weapon out of the
enthusiastic material available and
would then lead it with vigor and
determination determination to achieve
his military. And so once again,
we're talking about what leader can
take this glut leader can forge a weapon
from men
he saw to the nature of the weapon
required and how it could be forged.
So he started to understand the the men
as a weapon and how you could forge this
weapon properly.
And he set himself to task to the
task of building a force after his own
principles based on a high
fighting spirit spirit,
good discipline,
and a sound knowledge of tactics.
It was to be a force which would of
have complete confidence in him as their
commander. So this guy saw this
situation where they almost got crushed.
The parliamentary forces were so
disorganized that they couldn't even take
advantage of it and he saw,
okay,
this is my opportunity and
those are great lessons.
I love it when you learned the lesson
that you didn't really have to pay for.
It happens sometimes.
It happens in MMA sometimes where you guy
wins a fight because something you get
lucky in the end and you
get to know we've got the w,
but we also got to learn a great,
a great lesson that happened
in combat all the time.
You come back off an operation
and you're like, man,
if we would have gotten hit
at this particular moment,
we had security was down.
We were not paying attention.
We didn't have this Flint covered.
And by the grace of God,
we didn't get contacted from that area.
But we can't let that happen again.
So sometimes you learn a lesson even
though you didn't have to pay for it.
And that's what it sounds like
happened here. The back of the book,
he said about his task full.
We are told of a furious zeal,
a fire in his belly which compelled to
him which compelled to others to follow
him. He had complete confidence in
his ability to gain success in war.
He saw the way in which he had to train
his men to fight and the few essential
oils which would ensure success provided
his men had the right fighting spirit.
Edge Hill was fought in October,
1642 with chrome,
well as a captain of a
troupe of horse 60 strong.
By January,
1644 he was a lieutenant general second
in command of Manchester's army of the
eastern counties,
the leading cavalry commander on the
parliamentary side and the one outstanding
commander in the parliamentary army.
So he made a rapid transition.
Now he gets into this.
Cromwell was not a likable man.
He was quick tempered,
believed in rigid discipline and constant
training and he drove his men hard,
but he believed with a blinding certainty
in the righteousness of his cause.
He enthused his soldiers
with its righteousness and
he was convinced of his own
ability to succeed,
to achieve success in battle.
This is one of those
things where you know,
when you hear that people that Monte
was a little bit like lack of tact,
is one of those things where I think,
well, did he read this? You know,
did he read about chrome will and
study crumble and say, well look,
no one likes chrome. Well, that's
okay. You can still be a good leader.
You don't have to be liked. In
fact, Lafe we'll tell the story.
There was a guy that was,
was Leif was teaching a class,
two young seals, and there was a seal
officer that would come in and say,
you shouldn't be liked if you're in charge
and laughs. You know, we'd sit in the
back of the room and think to himself,
this is not good, because that's
not true. It's not true. Now,
it's probably true that what the
guy was trying to say is, listen,
you're not always going
to be popular for you to,
your goal should not be to be like,
which I agree with,
but to say, look, you're going
to be hated by your troops.
That's just the way it is. That's
wrong. If you're hated by your troops,
you're probably doing something wrong.
Yeah.
And to say that if you're essentially the
what the guy that leaves talking about,
if he's saying, if you're liked by your
troops, you're doing something wrong,
kind of living. Yeah, that's
true too. What it feels like. So,
so I understand that thought as well.
Like,
Hey, everyone loves me. I must be doing
a good job. It's like, no, actually,
if everyone just thinks you're their
buddy, that's a problem. So that this,
this may have been what this officer
was trying to teach to the, uh,
to the young officers that that life
was in charge of instructing. Yeah.
I'm sure he tried to, was trying
to say the right thing. Yeah.
But perhaps he wasn't articulating it.
Yeah.
100% in the most clear way with
a guy cause just to sell, hey,
you're not going to be liked
where you're an officer. Not True,
not true and not good.
If I have,
if I look at a seal platoon and the
seal platoon doesn't like their officer,
that's not a positive sign. That does
not mean that guy's a good leader.
Now it's also not a good sign. If all
the soup tune, everyone loves him.
That doesn't mean it's good, good platoon
either. Yeah. So you can be loved,
but you're not doing a good job. You can
be hated and you can beat a good job,
but you're probably not gonna be able
to pull off doing a good job when guys
don't like you. They're not going to
put forth any real effort to yeah.
To make you look good is basically
what they're doing. Yeah. Yeah.
And at the end of the day,
it obviously seems like it's just not
that cut and dry like that, you know?
No. Back to the book. And
he did achieve success.
He had no failures.
And if a commander has a righteous
cause and gives his soldiers success,
he will gain the complete
confidence of his men.
And then there is nothing he can not do,
but the power.
Okay.
Which his prowess in the
field had one for him,
led chrom well to seize the
reins of government for himself,
he became impatient with
the inefficiency methods.
Inefficiency of the
parliamentary government of
those days and he compared it
unfavorably with his own ability as a
soldier to give immediate decision and to
see it take shape at once.
Inaction.
So you took over the government and
he wanted things to move real quick,
but unfortunately,
but as in battle, he had been sure
of the correct course of action.
So in the political field,
he was on many occasions,
uncertain and perplexed during the
period in which he ruled England,
he tried out five different systems
of government and all failed.
And at the end he was governing alone
and much more absolutely than ever.
Charles had attempted to rule internally.
He tax the people more highly,
any disregarded parliament,
more brazenly than Charles never done.
And he interfered with the
personal liberty. More Toronto stay
in Ireland. Also, his harsh and
cruel policy left a lasting hatred,
which the centuries have not quenched,
but his rule was not wholly unproductive.
He made the fighting starts.
So he did accomplish one thing.
He made the fighting services the finest
in the world and he gained for England
a voice in the affairs of Europe such
as England, had never had before,
so he was not a good governmental leader.
Yeah,
many of his triumphs abroad were transient
in ups and unsubstantial and much
that he attempted at home
disappeared when he died,
but he's worked for the navy and it's
initial steps toward the creation of an
empire, planted a foundation
from which much has grown, so
he had a good impact on the military,
but as governmental governmental leading
abilities aren't all that strong.
The third great captain I suppose to I
proposed to consider is Napoleon a leader
driven by selfish and evil ambition.
It's interesting and not like the
other two in pursuit of a great ideal,
unlike the other two,
he was a soldier by profession,
trained from his youth and
the profession of arms.
Even as a very young boy in a military
academy, he was clearly a leader.
He wished to dominate and he did
dominate his fellow men. There it is.
That one sounds a little stronger.
That's all.
A little bit more like what
I think of dominate. Again,
unlike the other two,
he rose at a very early age to
a high and independent command.
At the age of 26 he took command of the
army of Italy and army inferior numbers
and equipment to its opponents and
semi muteness from lat lack of pay,
yet within a year with this inferior
weapon which he reforged to his liking,
he fought brilliantly,
brilliantly successful campaign in the
northern Italy and imposed piece on his
enemy.
I liked that imposed piece on his enemies.
From the moment of his arrival with
his army. He dominated his troops,
both generals and soldiers and inspired
them with confidence in his ability to
give them success of that ability.
He himself had never any doubt and in
his own self confidence lay much of his
power to inspire confidence in others
behind this dominating self confidence.
However,
les napoleons ability to see in any
military problem the few essential oils on
which success would depend.
He had the great power to simplify any
problem and to see what details were
important and which were unimportant.
There you go.
That's prioritize and execute. And it's
simple both in one big rule, right?
You got to know what's important.
You got to prioritize the importance
things and you've got to keep everything
simple. I got a, I got an
email from Sarah Armstrong.
Sure.
Talking about podcasts,
one 74 trying to be a five.
Oh.
[inaudible] trying to be a
five. Oh, in all categories.
And she basically emailed
me and said, hey, heads up.
I used to try and be a five Oh,
in every category.
Even in categories that didn't matter.
So that's,
you know, give heads up.
And I was like, well,
yeah, I mean I've talked
about, I've talked about that.
I talk about it with clients all the time,
but I talk about on the podcast
as well when they've specifically,
I talked about it saying,
I don't know if you remember this example.
I said a black belt in Jujitsu.
Like they don't care where you're grabbing
their sleeve and you're getting all
crazy. They don't care. That doesn't
matter if you're a white belt,
someone grabs your sleeves, you're
freaking out. I mean if you're,
if you're a black belt, like
okay, if you're a good leader
and there's some, some,
some issue that guys are complaining
about snow factor, you don't care.
And then there's some issues that come
up and you go, okay, that's important.
I need to address that.
So this is what he had the ability to
do is figure out what is essential and
what is not. Yeah. Yeah. And that's,
that can be kind of a tricky one.
Cause you know, some, some things
are super small, super small,
but at the end of the day that
might be kind of important. Yes.
You know like you can sort of predict,
you're like, hey, that's small. Sure.
For sure. Hey, I could see that continuing
and growing, you know, for sure.
And sometimes all you have to do is
monitor it to make sure it doesn't grow.
Yeah. Sometimes you have to
put it in check for sure.
Sometimes you have to destroy
something, remove it, Jill. It
sometimes you can't worry about
it because it's not important.
So you've got to figure which one
of those out. Like if your employee,
say you're a boss,
your employee comes in one minute late,
let's say comes in on time
every single time like,
but right out he cast to get there at
six you get there at six on the dot every
single day.
And then like one week on Monday comes
in at six oh one is that a big problem?
One day? No, it's not a problem. You,
you might want to throw
a little something right.
It's something little something.
It's not nothing. Yeah,
there's a little something.
That's what you know,
you might even want to say something
like along this I was private. I'd say
see what happens when you cut it so
close every day. You're already a little,
your missed it by a minute bro. Exactly
right. That's it. You just throw a little,
a little yeah, just let them
know you're watching. Yeah.
Just like how you said like some
things there. Kini but am I going get,
am I going to give a due to written
counseling cause there were women at late.
No.
Cause now the guy's looking for different
jobs and work cause he doesn't want to
work for you.
Spazz out on him.
But at the same time he's at
six oh one he's like cool.
So the next day he comes in at
six o'clock we'll say next day.
Then the next Monday comes in at six oh
two oh two no, it's just one more minute.
All right, got to put it in check.
Yes sir. You just a little something.
Same like some things they seem small
but you can take a broader view and be
like, hey this is kind of
important. Yeah. This is,
it goes back to the troop shaving in
the Soviet troops stopping shaving.
This is it. This is the slippery slope
of a lack of discipline slip. Yeah.
But I can tell you this,
if you're focused only
on these little things,
you might miss the big picture, which
was Sarah's point. Yes. And I responded,
I said Hey,
I totally agreed with her,
talked about some of the black
belt thing and then the boss thing.
And then I was like, and by the way,
cause this is something I've talked about,
the floor in my garage
gym is not to clean.
It does.
It gets a 2.0 on cleanliness.
Five out of five maybe even gets a one.
I think one may have maybe get
some [inaudible] not bad. However,
however it gets like a 1.5
because it's not, it's, it's not.
It doesn't have actual dirt on it.
It's just God speaking.
It's just got a chalk and sweat stains,
dried up utility button,
you and I said it would take 20 minutes
to a half an hour each day to keep that
thing at a 5.0 inspection ready level
because once you got to get in there and
space basically got a power wash, that
thing daily, that's where you're at.
So I'm not power washing that
thing daily. Why don't, why is it,
why is it not clean? Not
Important. Do I, I have,
I actually have a vacuum
in my garage that I
hit it with. Sometimes I hit
it every two, three days.
That's a lot different than breaking
out then. Then pulling the mats out,
power washing them in the alley,
and then bringing them back in.
That's a, that's not even half an hour.
That's like a, that's a serious evolution,
you know,
that's a serious evolution.
So is it worth being a 5.0 in
Matt cleanliness garage gym?
The answer is no. The answer
is no. It's not worth it.
You need to lower that
on the priority scale.
Now do I have big chunks of dirt
and dog hair piled up and debris?
No,
it's completely debris free,
but there are some sweat stains on it.
It has been there.
The remnants of getting after it. Right,
which is kind of conducive Kenzie way.
It is the way it is to the standard.
Then generally speaking,
not just an application to your garage,
gym floor to like everything.
It's like little things.
I mean just the basic little
little framework to establish
depends on the thing.
Yeah. So but what is it? So you can go,
let's say you go fundamentally then,
so what is it like if it, if it
gets in the way, even if this much,
this little millimeter gets in
the way of the overall objective,
then it's relevant. Important. Well, no.
Then we just have to frame
it so that we're not,
when we frame it as a waste of time,
like how much effort are you going
to put into that is no, if it's not,
if it doesn't get in the way, if
it, no, no. If it gets in the way,
then I'm putting too much time. If, if
it gets in the way of my strategic goal,
it's to bump into too much time into,
okay.
If solving this particular problem
to know it. Yes, yes. Okay. Okay.
But a amend the existing of a
small little problem. If it's,
if it's get gets in the way, so like gets
in the way, then it's a problem. Yeah.
Like I'm
like the guy coming in late. Right.
And let's see, all my garage floor,
there was chunks of rocks underneath
the mats and they made it uneven.
Yeah.
And it was like slightly hazardous for
me to be moving around on it and it
interrupted and my weight's rolled
around. That'd be a problem. Yes.
It's effecting my strategic goal.
Yes. Those mats are getting picked up.
The rocks are getting moved. The floors
getting leveled in. Then we're good to go.
Yeah.
On the,
on this levelness my maths
get a five o perfectly flat.
They're good to go there.
Do not interfere at all,
but they got some getting after it.
Stains on them. Yep. There it is.
Okay.
Going back to the book,
having grasp the essentials of the problem
and having inspired his soldiers with
confidence in himself and with high
morale. He knew he could not fail.
Napoleon, however, was always as
much a politician as a soldier.
He had a great love of intriguing,
of diplomatic bargaining and his contempt
for his fellow men and his passion to
dominate them and events led
him to aspire to greater things.
From the time he became first council
political rather than military factors
influenced his decisions and his failure
to reconcile his political aspirations
with what was militarily possible.
Finally led him to the disasters of
Moscow and the peninsula from which no
recovery was possible.
He started playing that political game,
started making his military decisions
based on what he wanted to happen
politically. Now, what did these
three men, Moses, Cromwell,
and Napoleon have in common without which
they would have not achieved success?
The most outstanding similarity was
that they dominated their fellow men.
They were all supremely confident that
they could and would do what they set out
to do. It was quite simple
to them, quite easy,
and success was absolutely certain.
This certainty gave them each the power
to inspire others to follow blindly and
to the limit of their strength and this
inspiration and power to enthuse others
in measurably increase the power of their
forces to achieve whatever was asked
to them. That's called the confidence
right there and that's what that is.
Pure confidence,
isn't it?
Isn't it interesting when you see
someone that's ultra confident and no,
they're not even overflowing into ego,
but they're just really,
really confident and,
and Pete people fall, people will, will
be like, okay, I'm on board this, this,
this person's in the game. They believe
it. I'm Balombo. I believe it too.
You know,
I've seen situations where people are
so confident that people are following
them even though they're
wrong. Hmm. You know, you get,
you would get that occasionally with a,
with a seal platoon,
you get some experience guy that was super
confident and he will actually wasn't
that good or didn't really understand
tactics too well and need to knows what
we're doing. Yeah. You know,
so I've done this a million
times. It's all, by the way,
that's a red flag when somebody,
when somebody counts on their number of
times or their experience that the way
we've always done it, I've done this
a million times. That's a red flag.
The reason that they're using those
statements is because they don't have an
actual answer. So one of the
new guys says, Hey, hey boss.
I'm not really sure why we, why
are we assaulting, you know,
through the target from this area over
here. Wouldn't it make more sense to do?
And he goes, Oh look, I've done this
a million times zero, we're doing it.
He just thinks your cell phone so
you don't have an actual answer.
You don't have an answer as to why.
You're just,
you're just throwing that out there
as the easiest thing for you to do.
So if you ever find yourself saying,
because this is how we've always done it,
or look,
I've been doing this for 28 years,
you don't have a good answer.
You're all that could work against
you to be honest with you. Hey,
I've been doing this for 28 years and
then like that day and the person figures
out like a way better way to
do it. He'd be like, Dang Bro,
you've been wasting your
time for 28 years. Yeah,
it could definitely work out bad.
It could work out bad because
you're not listening to anyone else.
You're not taking input.
And then you end up making a bad decision
from what did these men get their supreme
confidence in their ability to achieve
their purpose in battle.
I think they got it from their ability to
see their problem in its simplest form.
Amen.
I totally agree with that.
To see the few essential is necessary to
the successful solution to the problem,
and to see how those few
essentials could be achieved.
This is why I'm always talking
about qualities of leadership.
The ability to simplify. I'm sure you've
heard me say this a thousand times.
If you have the ability
to simplify things,
that's a great asset to have and not
everyone has it or not everyone has the
same level of it. Some people are
good at it, some people not so much.
Some people just straight up
complicate things. Oh yeah.
Once they grasp the
essentials of the problem,
they never lost sight of them and never
allowed a massive detail to submerge
what was essential to success.
Boom.
Don't get caught up in the little details
of things that don't let those things
drown out what the real situation is
for all military problems
are in essence simple.
But the ability to simplify and to
select out of the massive detail,
those things and only those things that
are important is not always so easy.
So got to keep things simple.
Each of these men had the
power to dominate other men
spirits to inspire their
enthusiasm and to convince them of their
own ability to achieve what was asked
of them.
This moving of men spirits,
this power to enthuse could only be
done and was only done by their personal
contact with their men.
All my three examples weren't close
and frequent contact with their troops.
They were well known,
familiarly known to them and took
frequent opportunities of talking to their
men. So again, this is
where that the thing I,
I spoke of earlier where
it's like he kinda,
he kinda comes back on a,
you got to be this dominating
person that he's talking about.
You got to get out there
and talk to your troops.
You gotta be really truly
personally known to them.
Napoleon and Kronwall certainly
in very possibly Moses too,
were known to their men by nicknames
and use this familiarity to help their
purpose. At the same time, each
of these leaders knew, well,
what the soldier was thinking
and what he wanted most.
And they made always careful
study of the human factor.
Now it's interesting because,
okay,
no Monte, he's known as Monte.
Everybody called him Monte. Yeah.
And that's his nickname. Yeah. And that
little breeds a little familiarity. Yeah.
And like I stole naming a unit,
renaming a unit when you took it over.
I stole that from David Hackworth. Yeah.
I wonder if Krom I wonder if Monty stall
this nickname idea and kind of gave
himself that nickname. Right?
Hackworth took it from Monte. Well,
no Hackworth. Well actually
I guess Hackworth, everyone
just called hack, hack. Hey,
everyone called me Jocko. Yeah. Like
everyone, it's funny, someone said,
everyone in the chain of command,
the people below me in the chain of
command call me Jocko and the people above
me, the chain of command call me
Jack. Ever call me Jocko. Yeah.
So that was Kinda cool, but that was just
like coincidence. I don't even know why.
Yeah.
But
Hackworth, he didn't really, I don't
think Hackworth gave himself a nickname.
Yeah. And let's face it, the
Hackworth other than Hackworth and as,
as General Mooka Yama told us he
had the best nickname of all time,
Mr Infantry.
That is the coolest nickname ever.
He's hack considered a nickname if
it's short for your, I think it is.
Yeah. Yeah, yeah. There are certain names
that have an official shortening of it.
You know, like Richard and Rick
or you know Jonathan and John.
Robert and Bob. Bob. Yes, exactly. Bill
and William and bill on that. Okay,
so quit hack is not an official
unofficial, so it's sorta it,
it goes into the realm of actual nickname,
not just shortening of the name. Yeah.
Yeah. But I think I, we
can research this all,
it's not coming to me
off the top of my head,
but I'm pretty sure everyone
called hack. Hack. Yeah.
Like up and down the chain of command.
Yeah.
Although his soldiers back in
the day probably called him, sir.
That's more normal for Vietnam. Dang.
How do you engineer it? Nickname no.
For Yourself. You can't do that. You
can't give your nickname to yourself. No.
But you can actually, there has to be a
way to sort of engineer the environment.
You could say, Hey, I'm hack.
How's it going? Yeah. But the
isn't that, I mean if the,
it would have to be established
before that. If you just start,
like if I just start saying,
Hey, I'm dragon. No worries. You,
if you checked into a military unit or
you and no one knew you and you're like,
Hey, what's up? Um, um, dragging
boy. Yeah, that would be
no, that wouldn't work. No,
but if you said, hey, my name is,
you know, frag mob or whatever,
if you just made up, you know your
nickname, all guys calling me that. Yeah.
I wouldn't, one time I hooked a grenade
and it rolled back and you know,
those places would have games.
Not true though. You know,
like doesn't mean problem.
If look,
if you hook the grenade in a thing and
someone called you fragment from then,
then on, then boom, someone gave you that
nickname, but you can hook a grenade.
It does whatever it is that it doesn't
be like I should be called. You know,
he can't really do that.
No nickname herself. No.
So even if you introduce yourself, if no
one knows you introduced yourself. Okay,
I'm dragging boy, but I just gave
that name to myself today and, but,
and they sure they'll call you dragging
boy. But if one person finds out, oh,
you just gave yourself, then they're going
to get your different nurse. Oh yeah.
Oh, you're somebody else. Yes sir. Real.
So how do you do it though? You don't.
You just gotta let it.
That's what I think is important.
What's important here is that
the familiarity isn't a lie.
The familiarity is real. Yes. That's
the difference. You know how you do it.
It's not just, it's not 100% you,
it's more allowing nicknames to BC.
You know how like you know some people,
their name,
I don't know for just for
example, hypothetical example,
like let's say it's like,
Hey, my name is Jonathan,
and then you know,
in a casual conversation with, Hey John,
what's up done. And then there'll be like,
hey, it's like no disrespect
or nothing, but it's Jonathan.
Like they preferred the whole thing maybe
to pull John's more of an official one.
But like if Hackworth would've said,
hey, it's, it's Hackworth not hack,
then he probably wouldn't have
had the name hack. That's true.
So when someone busts out a nickname for
you, you just got to let it fly. Well,
I'll tell you in the teams when
they bust out a nickname for you,
if you protested, it's going
to stick even. There you go.
So you could essentially in theory,
fake protests. Exactly right.
They'd see right through that
call that fine
Jag ass, you've got to be quick. You've
got to be sneaky with it, I guess.
All right. Okay. Back to the book. If
a leader neglects the human factor,
he will fail.
No Man can lead others if he does not
know what they are thinking and feeling.
So again,
we got Monty here who kind of talks
like he's all aloof and everything,
but he knows you got to know your people
and you've got to understand people.
And then he goes on a little shift
here. No leader, however great can, can,
can long continue unless he wins.
Victories without victories in battle,
all else is useless to what
then is success in battle
do is great.
Study of Marlboro.
Mr Winston Churchill says,
very truly,
and so here's a little quote from Winston
Churchill, and this is interesting.
He's talking about the Duke
of Marlborough who was, uh,
another guy in the 16 hundreds that
fought in the war of Spanish succession.
This guy never lost a battle
apparently. And, and interesting,
he was the Duke of Marlborough,
but his actual name was John Churchill.
And he is actually, I want
to say the great, great,
maybe great grandfather
of Winston Churchill.
So this is Winston Churchill's bloodline.
Sure.
And this is what Winston Churchill
says about his great, great,
however many great grandfathers.
And I think that's right.
The success of a commander does not
arise from following rules or models.
It doesn't come from
following rules or models.
It consist in an absolutely new
comprehension of the dominant facts of the
situation at a time and
all the forces at work,
every great operation of war is unique.
What is wanted is a profound
appreciation of the actual event.
There is no sure road to
disaster then to imitate,
imitate the plans of bygone heroes
and to fit them to novel situations.
So there you go.
This ability to co two
absolutely comprehend this
new situation and to not try
and force,
not try and force a rule or a model to
to work for you in a certain situation.
Back to the book.
This indeed is true
for no war foreign war.
No two situations are ever the same
and each situation must be tackled as a
wholly new problem to which there
will likely be a wholly new answer.
You need only to look at the beginning
of this war and to and to the trust put
in ImageNow line here in deed.
Was there a failure to appreciate the
new and change technique which had risen
and one which rendered such fortifications
in themselves wholly useless
to win victories.
Certain qualities are necessary and I
will mention for which were possessed in
greater or less by all the
great captains of history.
These are the knowledge of
the technique of making war.
So that's interesting because
Churchill just said, look,
it's not using this previous knowledge.
You gotta be able to apply it.
But at the same time,
guess what?
You got to have the knowledge
of the technique of making
war next to the ability
to see clearly the few essentials
that are important to success. Next,
courage and mental robustness.
And lastly,
a well balanced judgment.
Okay.
He kind of goes through these
in a bit more detail now.
The manner in which war is
waged varies from age to age.
And with the advent of each new weapon,
it is a constantly changing,
constantly evolving thing.
He who aspires to high command in war
must thoroughly understand the main
principles which will dictate the manner
in which the battle of the of his age
will be fought.
He also must be constantly on the
watch for new ideas or weapons,
which will affect those principles.
The speed of change in military
science during time of pieces,
often slow and many of consequently
allowed themselves to be lulled into false
sense of security, which has been
rudely shattered on the outbreak of war.
So guess what? You got to have an open
mind and you got to pay attention.
The knowledge of how to make war also
implies the ability to train troops.
Every great commander has himself had to
forge his weapon for the task in front
of him. Moses led the people of
Israel for 40 years in the desert,
teaching them how to fight and he
forged the weapon to conquer Canaan.
So also chrom,
well and Napoleon,
they forged their own weapon
for this specific task in hand,
improvising and inventing as they went
along so as to develop new tactics to
deal with the new problems with
which in their day they were faced.
So you've got to study war, you've got
to understand how to train your troops.
Continuing on.
No Man can be a great military leader
unless he has the ability to cut through
overlying difficulties and to see clearly
the few essential in any problem which
with which he is faced in any problem.
There are never more than a few essentials
which are vital to that problem.
Yeah,
that's a pretty bold statement
and it's also pretty true. Yeah.
You get these big problems.
Guess what?
There's only a few things
that are truly essential. Now,
as you solve the first
couple essential ones,
there's going to be the next essential
problem. This is prioritize and execute.
Yeah, and it's kind of
simple to read. Simple. Yes,
like they're both wrapped
together in this thought.
These must be grasp out of the massive
details and must never be lost sight of.
If in battle commander loses sight
of the few essentials that matter,
he will suffer defeat.
So when you're getting
distracted by these other things,
you're going to end up losing.
But to see the essentials,
clearly he must not himself
get too immersed in detail.
Every great commanders had a chief of
staff who's main task with the mastery of
detail,
thus leaving his master free to tackle
essentials of the problem together with
those details and only though
those details which were
vital, that problem, boom,
that's it. You cannot get in the
weeds. You cannot micromanage.
You cannot look at a plan all day and
expect that you're gonna see something
that your troops didn't see who are doing
the planning. You need to step back.
You need to elevate yourself
for though they're as much detail in
which the for though is there is much
detail with which a commander cannot
and must not bothered himself,
is interesting to note that every great
commander has always concerned himself
with certain of the
details of his problems.
Napoleon and Wellington are
two good cases in point.
No Man can rise to a high command
who is not the quality of courage.
The highest form of personal courage
is required rather in the leader at the
lower level who has to plunge into
the turmoil of the battlefield.
So yeah, if you're in the frontline
troops, you need even more courage.
The leader at the higher levels has to
develop his quality of courage into a
mental robustness,
which can withstand the mental stress and
strain with which he will be assailed.
Okay?
He must at all times.
He must be able at all times to take a
dispassionate view of the good and bad
fortune, which will a sale him. Ah,
read that one again.
He must be able at all times to take a
dispassionate view of the good and bad
fortune, which will a sale. So a
get bad things are gonna happen.
Good things are gonna happen.
Don't get all excited when some you get
all excited, you gotta be dispassionate.
You got to detach. You can't let
your emotions start getting crazy.
You have to detach.
He must not allow himself to be distracted
by events or to be led astray from
his main purpose.
By some glittering prize.
He must at all times maintain an unbiased
view of the situation and in battle,
he must be able to judge the true value
of the mass of good and bad tidings,
which will flow upon him.
Okay,
man. Stayed attached. Stay levelheaded,
go too bad. Does that kind of like
one, like, you know how you get the,
the husband or the boyfriend or
whatever that like, you know,
he does something bad.
I Dunno.
Flirts with a girl or something like
that girl, that girlfriends all mad.
And then so the guy goes and
bias or like, oh, necklace,
you know to say sorry. It's
Kinda like that, right.
Where don't get all caught up in
the glittery stuff because you know,
no, that's not what this is like.
This echoes saving up to buy a
house. Yeah. In any saving up.
And he's like, okay, I saved,
you know, 800 bucks last month.
I'm a save 1200 bucks this month.
I'm gonna save 900 bucks this month.
And all of a sudden you see a,
a new car with rims in,
in with has rim and you can
get it, you can lease it.
Uh, yeah. And all you need
to lease it is, you know,
$4,000 and you're like,
you know what,
I'm going to go get data as the shiny
new thing. They just took you
off of your main goal. Yes.
That has nothing to do with flirting.
Girlfriend buy a necklace as
well. I think yours is a
better example. For sure.
I big so here's wasn't even an example
if you missed the point. Okay. Yeah.
Uh, I'm trying to think of where
it would be. Oh yeah. I mean,
so if we're going to talk like a girl
that was saving for a house. Yeah.
And then she's all cool
necklace, that would have been
a good example. Yeah. Look,
the flirting girl with the distraction
from the boyfriend. No, that's, that's,
here's how I would try to connect the
dots on that one. But you know, the girl,
her mission is to evaluate whether or not
this is the good boyfriend straight up
and then saw the boyfriend.
He does some stuff that's fundamentally
bad cheats on her, I dunno, whatever.
And then, you know, so she's
sort of on that mission.
She's sort of making the evaluation.
Then boom,
she gets distracted by the
sparkly necklace. Boom. She
goes back to them, blah,
blah, blah. See what I'm saying? It's
still, oh no, not quite. Not Quite.
I mean, I good, good effort, good effort.
Moving on.
Every battle resolves itself into a tussle
between the wills of the two opposing
commanders.
Unless he's mentally Robusto,
commander will not be able to
force his will on his opponent.
It is well for a commander to remember
that no battle was ever lost until the
commander thought it's so
hmm.
No battle is ever lost until
the commander fought it. So
a commander must have a
well balanced judgment.
They're too little balance
of the dichotomies here,
both from the battle situation and in
his dealings with his subordinates.
This is straight up dichotomy of
leadership. He must be okay now.
He must see the battle situation as
constantly shifting interplay of forces,
and he must instinctively know when to
be rash and when to be cautious. Boom.
Gotta be balanced.
He must weigh up the situation both at
the moment and as it may develop in the
future.
And he must so fight his battle that
the enemy's reactions cannot upset his
plan. And Novo, he's trying to
force his will on his opponent.
A commander must know when discretion
is the better part of valor.
His desire to dominate his opponent must
not outweigh his judgment of the actual
possibilities of the situation.
Yes,
you got to be aggressive,
but you can't be foolhardy.
That's what we're saying here.
This is the dichotomy of leadership.
His judgment and must always be
well balanced and if it is so,
and if he has good information
on which to base it,
he can so forced the battle his way,
that the enemy will be forced to conform.
He will in fact have rested the initiative
from the enemy in his dealings with
his subordinates.
He will also require good jet judgment
and sound knowledge of human nature.
He must choose subordinates well those
with whom he is infrequent contact,
his senior generals must know personally.
He must know personally and well.
He must be able to judge when
to drive and when to persuade,
when to be stern and when to give praise
for all men are different and each
requires handling it a different way.
So right there he just talked
about the dichotomy. Leadership,
right when to drive and winter persuade
when to be stern when it be give praise
God a balance. Those dichotomies. The
three leaders whom I have concerned,
considered succeeded so long
as they kept in their mind.
They're clear military purpose and
we're not deflected from it by any other
considerations,
but there is always the danger
that other and especially political
considerations will be forced,
will force the hand of the soldier
and leading to some action,
which is militarily unwise.
Many battles have been fought for
political and not for military reasons,
and these have been the graveyard
of many a soldier's reputation.
The soldier is the servant
of the statesmen and is
therefore bound to be subject
to political pressure.
He must be strong enough to resist such
pressure whenever it conflicts with his
clear military purpose.
Few statesmen will force
the hand of the soldier.
If the soldier very bluntly says, okay,
five, fight as you wish me to fight,
I shall lose the battle. If I fight
in my own way and in my own time,
I shall win the battle. So there
you go. That's what you gotta do.
You gotta call it like you see it,
but the soldier,
it must be prepared to be very blunt and
he must be prepared to stake his whole
reputation on successive given
adequate resources and a free hand.
And he also must be prepared to be very
firm and to refuse to be forced to do
something which he considers
is not capable of being done.
So there you have it.
If you don't think something can be done,
it's your moral obligation to say no.
And of course you have to weigh that
with the fact that if you don't do it,
someone mouth's might and they
might cause even more damage.
So you have to weigh that.
That conundrum
back to the book in history,
the military leader is frequently been
tempted and as frequently succumb to the
temptation to aspire to
political leadership.
The whole training and experience of the
soldier makes him less rather than more
fitted to be a politician. So this
is, this is an interesting contrast.
The soldier is trained to take direct
action down certain well defined blinds
and as in his hand,
a military machine which
responds immediately and
with precision to his touch.
The politician is trained in subtlety,
in debate,
in weighing up the conflicting interests
of his supporters and usually has to
compromise the governmental machine
much less precise and exact than the
military and is not as rapid an action
even in highly skilled political hands.
Okay.
Now in worf commander compromises
on essentials he fails.
Furthermore,
the time factor forces the commander in
the field to adopt the best expedient in
the time available,
which is usually short.
The politician on the other hand is seldom
forced to give an immediate decision.
Rather he delays in order to find out
the right to an accurate answer and he
avoids any temporary expedient one seizes
time by the forelock and adopts the
best expedient,
the other procrastinates in order to
ensure that what he does is exactly right.
Now I think you could.
I think this gets taken to the extreme
in both cases cause you actually,
even as a military leader, you want to
weigh in, make sure you're, you want to,
you want to wait long enough to make
sure you're making a good decision.
And I think in the political world they
go to the extreme of they're just going
to never make a decision,
never going to make a change.
Therefore, leader who is primarily a
soldier, when he metals with politics,
it loses his clear and simple military
purpose. He no longer sees the essentials.
He is at sea in a political world.
We read that chrom well in politics was
muddled and perplexed working slowly in
deviously to a policy which
he did not clearly see
and again that he was
confused and distracted.
So though he kept the political power
and his own hands during his lifetime,
much of what he built fell to pieces.
The moment he died. So Awesome Napoleon,
as long as his military purpose was upper,
most in his mind he succeeded.
But when had political
considerations dominated as policy,
the desire to impose his will on Europe
led him to undertake military operations,
which it was beyond his power to achieve
the qualities required by a soldier and
by a politician are in fact almost at
opposite poles and only a few men in
history of possessed both kinds of
qualities.
There have not been many soldiers who
have made good politik politicians nor
many politicians who have
made great soldiers. Now,
the only thing I'll say is that being
in the military is very political and
you've even in this time I, I'm not
gonna make any distinction that, oh,
it's more political now.
It's not the old moon may old books about
World War II was all kinds of politics,
politics, politics going on inside
the chain of command. So Adam,
I'm not sure why he,
he sees that great distinction
between, you know, there being no,
like there's no political things,
no political games being played in
the military. There certainly is.
Certainly is. And there always has
been. And there always will be.
It's a group of people and then group
people are going to do the little
political maneuvers. I, we'll
look out for themselves.
They're going to try and make
this happen. You know, that's,
that's they're going to have an agenda.
You got to learn how to
negotiate those politics,
whether you're in the military and
whether you're in the civilian sector.
It doesn't matter before we
leave the past. It is I think,
interesting to note that great military
leaders have on the whole been few.
Yeah,
there've been many generals of good
average ability but few who were really
great in the study of those who are great.
It is interesting to note two things.
First, a required a war
to produce them. Second,
that a number of them prove
their greatness after a
very short apprenticeship.
This suggests that the art of war,
at any rate in the past though less so
now is a relatively simple art and that
the qualities which
make a great commander,
our inherent rather than
acquired, interesting. He's a
little bit more saying, hey,
you kind of born with it.
The character and more especially
the will to dominate and lead.
His fellow man is given to few,
but given that power to lead,
the ability to gain success in war can
be acquired so you can get better at it.
A man may cultivate the qualities of
a great leader provided that he has
inherited him in sufficient degree,
the character and the will to dominate.
But unless he has those
inherent characteristics,
he will never become a great leader.
However long he studies the
art or the craft of war.
Okay.
Here's one of the phenomena of military
history that events in variably produce
the man age has little
or nothing to do with it.
The opportunity may come
sooner to som later to others.
Napoleon was 27 when he
conquered northern Italy.
Wolf was 34 when he captured
a Quebec at the younger end.
At the other end of the
scale of Marlborough was 52
when he first rose to high
and independent command,
an Abercrombie conducted as short but
brilliant campaign in Egypt at the age of
68 at the end of a long lifetime
in the careers of great generals.
There's always been this aspect of chance.
Opportunity comes at different ages
and in different circumstances.
Some have been luckier than others.
Some perhaps never had the
opportunity to prove their ability.
Yeah,
so that's where he wraps up so much
for the lessons of history today.
The problems of military leadership are
much the same as they always have been.
I proposed to tell you now some of the
things that have guided me in leading
armies,
which had been entrusted to my command,
I would say first that a leader must
very clearly know what he wants himself.
He must see his objective clearly
and must go all out for it.
Okay?
He must let everyone else know what he
wants and what are the basic fundamentals
of his policy.
He must in fact give from
guidance and a clear lead.
It will be necessary for him to create
what I call atmosphere and in that
atmosphere, his subordinate commanders
and troops will live and work to do this.
He will have to take a very firm grip
on his military machine from the top.
Only in this way will his force
acquire balance and cohesion.
And so develop its full fighting.
Potential history has many examples of a
lack of grip being taken by a commander
with the result that he failed to develop.
The power of which is forced with Cape
was capable and so met disasters we've
done. This is Monte. You
got to take that from grip
and again it's very strange because
he comes off so strong like that,
but here we go.
He's going to counter it right here.
Having laid down the basic fundamentals
of his policy, a commander must complete,
must place complete trust in his
subordinates and less give them freedom to
carry out that policy within the
framework which he is laid down.
So this is decentralized command.
He must be prepared to decentralize and
to trust his subordinates to use their
own initiative on all matters of detail.
Everyone listen to that.
Don't worry about the details.
The commander of selfless stand back
from the detail so we can see clearly the
essentials of his problem and make sure
that the correct action is being taken
on those essentials.
If ever a commander allows himself
to become too greatly immersed in the
unimportant details of any problem,
he will fail to see the
essential clearly detached stake.
A step back,
elevate yourself.
It is obvious that he must be a good
judge of men and a good chooser of
subordinates. He must also have
the drive to get things done.
No commander will long remain in the
first rank unless he achieves success.
The biggest single factor for
making success in war is morale.
High Morale is based on discipline,
self respect,
and the confidence of the soldier
in his commanders and his weapons.
It is a pearl, a very great
price, and without it,
no success in battle will be achieved.
A high morale is in fact a measure
of the confidence of troops of their
commander. That's an
interesting point, right?
How do you have high morale?
It's a measurement of how
confident the troops are.
Hmm. So when the, when,
when the troops are confident or the or
the employees are confident in the boss,
morale is high. When they're
not confident, morale is low.
And by the way, with low
morale, you're not winning.
Continuing on.
There is no book of rules which will help
a commander to gain the complete trust
and confidence of his men.
Each commander will adopt his own
methods and say the ones best to his own
personality.
Suffice it to say that he must be known,
must be known personally to
them and that success in battle,
we'll produce quick results.
All soldiers will follow.
A successful general no commander,
however,
will gain the confidence of his troops
unless he is known and well known to them.
They must often see him and if possible,
hear him speak.
A commander should take every opportunity
of talking to his officers and men.
It will repay him according to his worth.
Got To get out there
and talk to the troops.
There are other factors also, which have
a big effect on morale. The home front
and the battle on the front
nowadays are as as never before,
very closely linked. So you've
got to got to keep that morale up.
You gotta make sure everything's
going good on the home front and see.
Imagine what it's linked like now. I
mean, this is what he's talking about.
World War Two, World War II. Hey,
we're very closely linked because I can
write a letter that's going to get to my
wife nine weeks from now.
Right now we got brothers
on Facebook live nightly,
continue on just to success
as a great stimulus to morale,
so nothing lowers morale.
So quickly is failure.
Therefore there must be no failures.
Great and lasting harm can be done to
morale by undertaking operations for which
the troops concerned are not ready or or
trained in which they are likely to end
in failure.
I have therefore made it a rule to limit
the scope of any operation to what can
be achieved successfully.
So again,
this sounds super risk averse and that's,
that's that is,
hey,
I'm not going to do anything that I
don't know we can achieve it. Then again,
how often do you want to be rolling the
dice? W W why not say, you know what?
Well let's give it another month.
Let's train a little bit more.
What do we have to do this right now?
You know,
and I certainly think that there's times
when you have to take risk and you're
going to do some things that maybe you
don't know if you can get away with.
And there can be times where you're
forced into that position as well.
Like you're being attacked and hey,
we can,
I'm not sure if a flank is going to work,
but we can either sit here and get
attacked and get flanked by them.
Or we can go and flank ourselves like,
let's, let's go make this happen.
So I think we need to make
sure we don't take that route,
that comment to the extreme
because that can be a bit much,
but consider it,
consider it deeply.
And I think probably the reason why this,
this is probably one of
those points where, you know,
he said in the beginning of this,
he made the premise that, um,
that hey, this is, uh, this is,
this is for army command, right?
Or at least divisional
command we're talking to,
you're in charge of 10,000 people or so.
What he's saying maybe, but I guess
it becomes more acceptable of a rule.
You don't want to risk 10,000 you don't
want to risk an entire army or to entire
division on something that you may
or may not be successful at, right?
Maybe we need to reassess if we're
not sure we can make this happen.
Maybe we need to reassess if
we're going to go forward or not.
Hmm.
Another thing that today has a big effect
on morale is the standard of medical
care which soldiers can expect.
So you got that
and then we get to a commander must
make a very close study of human nature.
The raw material with which
he has to deal are men,
and it is important to remember
that all men are different.
What a commander makes of the human
material at his disposal will depend
entirely on himself.
I have found that every division,
which has fought under my command,
has added different characteristics.
Each division was good at
a different type of battle,
and it is a vital that the commanders
should gauge what type of battle is best
at and make sure that each division
is at the right point when required.
Okay.
So even in the quote,
uniformity of the military,
the half differences,
they're human beings and those,
those differences are
reflected through whole units.
The difference between divisions is based
partly on the individual individuality
of the commander of the division and
partly on the type of men of whom the
division is composed.
I found for instance,
that some divisions were outstandingly
good at the breakthrough attack,
but we're not so good at the
deliberate set piece affair.
Some divisions we're best at night,
some by day four, a solid killing match.
Certain types of men were
better than others and so on.
Each division develops an
individuality of its own,
which I consider a high commander
must study.
I was in the airport and I ran into a
dude from South Africa who is in the game
kind of big time,
and he was talking about,
he says, yes, I can't
do it on their accident,
but he was saying that he had,
he worked construction,
he was a construction guy and he had
a crew and he gave his crew a name.
I should have asked him what the
name of the crew was, but I didn't.
But I'm sure they gave him, he gave
him some kind of name and he was like,
he was just so pumped. And he goes,
yeah, I read it in Hackworth too.
And then I, I did it cause
you did it. And he goes,
it really worked mate.
It was all fired up.
Could you can change the
personality of something.
You can change the personality
of a unit like that can do it.
It works.
Okay.
In the same way,
all generals differ and must be selected
for the job in hand. No two jobs,
no two problems are ever the same.
And the character of the job must be
matched to that of the commander selected
to undertake it.
One of the most important functions of a
commander in war does to make sure that
he has the right man in the right
place to tackle the job in hand.
So think about that.
When you're in charge of a team,
when you're in charge of a business,
one of the most important things that
you do is put the right people in the
right job.
Some people are sensitive to that,
you know? So when I'm like, Hey,
hey bill, I'm not giving you this
op, I'm giving it to echo in.
Bill gets mad and frustrated and he's the
things to echo doesn't deserve it. Man.
We got to have a good enough relationship
and trust that when I say, Hey, bill,
this ops not for you, I'm giving it
to echo. And he goes, okay, cool.
Let me know what's coming down the pike.
Let me know what I can get ready for it.
Let me know how I can support.
Yeah, yeah, that. Remember you remember
the movie Major League Charlie Sheen?
Come on. But yeah, I remember the movie.
I don't think I ever sat through that
whole movie. Oh actually, you know what?
I think I asked you that before.
I think you said the same thing.
So there's this part where case Charlie
Sheen, right? He got his glasses.
He, Oh yeah, that's what we
were talking about last time.
So last time as far as major league goes,
the movie major league.
So Charlie Sheen, he had all this
crazy power and speed in his fastball,
but no control, no control. Then they
find out whatever, he can't see that good.
They give him some glasses.
Boomi, he brings it all together.
They start waiting on this stuff,
right.
So He's starting the other guy who was
starting before him, his name's Harris,
older guy, but you know the basically
the more concern, like he's consistent.
He's not like legit like Charlie
Sheen, but he's consistent, you know.
So there are about to
play the fast forward,
there are about to play the gang keys,
right.
And the big or the is that
called the world series?
It's like this big deal. And you
know, so the general manager,
Lou Calls Charlie Sheen,
what was his name in the movie?
Charlie Sheen doesn't matter.
It doesn't matter. Anyway,
it calls Charlie Sheen to the back
of the bus and he's like, Hey,
I'm going to start Harris
against the Yankees.
He just has a better reputation
against them and you know, more,
more experience or whatever. And then
Charlie Sheen was like, oh yeah, you know,
whatever's best for the team.
And he left and that was sort of it.
So he was good with it. Now the movie
goes on and he's not good with it.
He expressed himself like he was good
with it and he said the right things,
but later on it goes on like goats
drinking by himself or something.
And then he winds up hooking up
with like one of his teammates life.
And that was all, but that's a whole
nother story though. We don't get along.
We don't actually care about any of this,
but definitely old grandma.
That part [inaudible] that's his
name. Wild thing. Rick One. They go.
Same deal though,
right?
You got to get the right guys
and of course nailed it. You
nailed it. You even silly. Uh, Harris,
you know he does. Okay. You know,
and then they bring out Rick Vaughn to
fit the clothes out the game or whatever
and you win. So there
you go. Boom. All right.
Wayne went back to the
book back through the book.
If a commander thinks that all men are
the same and he treats the mass of human
material accordingly,
he will fail.
Okay.
The soldiers of today have different
standards and require more enlightened
handling. This then the soldiers of bygone
days. This is again where he starts to,
you realize that this guy, even though
he tries to come across all hard,
he's actually very thoughtful about
understanding humans back to the book.
They will no longer follow blindly and
unquestionably to an unknown end today.
Therefore,
a commander must ensure that his troops
always know what they are being asked to
do and how that fits in
with the larger plan.
Okay.
I have always been,
in other words,
they got to know why they're
doing what they're doing.
I have always insisted
that before a battle,
the essentials of the plant are known
right through the chain of command and
finally down to the rank and file.
The troops must know how a commander is
going to fight the battle and what part
they are going to play in it.
This must be explained to them by
word of mouth for that counselor.
Far More than the written word.
Yeah,
and then when the battle has been won
and the troops see that the battle has
gone,
as the commander said it would,
their confidence in the high
command will be very great.
This confidence is beyond price.
Yeah.
The problem with that statement is it
puts pressure on you to stick to a plan.
Did you get a flight that,
that make you think, oh,
I'm just going to stick with it because
I want everyone to think that it went
the way I want. I wanted it to go,
no, don't just stick with a plan.
If it's not working,
it's not working.
Shift a commander must watch
carefully his own morale.
Okay.
A battle is a contest between the
will of two opposing commanders.
The one who's heart fails.
When the issue hangs in,
the balance will lose the battle.
Okay.
A commander,
in fact,
must throughout radiate confidence
in his plan and operations,
even though inwardly he may
not be too sure of the outcome.
That's the one of those other things,
you know, people talk about transparency,
right? Transparency. Oh, guess
what? And it's like, oh yeah,
there's a book. There's all kinds of
book about transparency. Yeah. Like go,
you got to be fully transparent
with everyone. No, actually,
sometimes if I'm a little more nervous
about what we're doing and I started to
show that everyone's going to be nervous
about what we're doing. Yeah, man.
And had seen, yeah, they can up.
And sometimes too where like,
like how you mentioned before, like some
people can't take the truth, you know,
like,
so like
if there's certain shifts going to be
made or certain like rules going to be
implemented or whatever,
you know, like, hey, we're,
we're going to move,
we're going to demote this,
or we're going to move this person out
of this department because he's just, he,
he's ear, he stinks. Or something. Like
he has boo and he's irritating everybody,
you know, kind of thing.
Okay. And he'll be,
he'll just do just as good at work
down here in the basement where he's by
himself. Exactly. Right. You
know, and it's like, hey, hey,
we're going to shift you over here.
And he's gonna be like, oh, cool.
Like why though? Like I'm done to
do it. But why? DB transparent?
Maybe, maybe not, but you run
the good thing.
It would be like, hey man. Hey Bro,
let me ask you something.
If I had a booger hanging
out my nose, would you want,
would you would if you had a
booger hanging out of your nose,
what'd you want me to tell you? Everyone
says, yeah, of course. Cool. You stink.
That's good. Yeah. What about
Stinky gies on the mat, right.
Somebody's got to let them know,
bro, you gotta wash that thing.
You might need a new geek. You know some
people, they have this old ratty geat.
The smell is embedded in those things.
I had keys like that was like,
you wash it and then you
wash it and you take it out.
You put it on for four minutes and you go,
Oh yeah,
I've got to throw this thing away.
This thing stinks, Huh? Yeah.
That's true. That that would be a better
way to do it. That you can't say, hey,
why don't you move to the beginner class?
Go drill over there. Go work with
the grappling dummy over there.
It's like,
oh, that's not cool. You need to tell
a brother, hey man, you stinking.
You need a wash. Your Geek
washed Yogi immediately. Yeah,
so this is, this is one of those things
where if you, if you need to talk to them,
right? Even in that situation, you do need
to tell the truth. You know, you do new.
Say, hey listen man, I don't
know what's up with your hygiene
needs some work.
All right,
so what if the company is taking this
massive financial hit and layoffs are
coming straight up. You lay
off one guy, he left two guys.
Do you be transparent? Like, hey
guys, we're taking a massive hit.
We're laying off a bunch of people. Well,
yeah, not in that case. You have to say,
hey listen,
this is what's going on and this is
where we're at and we're going to do our
best and the best way we can do this is
by buckling down hard and working hard.
But right now it's
going to be tight going.
It's going to go through a tight quarter
right now we had to let go to guys.
We're going to try and maintain what we
got, but I can't promise you anything,
right? You gotta be yes, yes,
I'm going to be truthful.
So maybe it is better to be transparent.
Most of the time it is.
Most of the time it is what we do.
Well it's in this situation,
what we're talking about is if you lack
confidence in what you're doing and you
start to reveal that to yeah,
got you, then that's not good.
And you know there's, there's time.
Now let's say, let's say Echo.
Let's say I didn't think
you were cognitively capable
of doing a job at the next
level.
I might not necessarily tell you that
because that's something that you can't
necessarily change. You can't go home,
take a shower and get smarter. Right?
It doesn't,
it doesn't work that way.
You can't put on deodorant and now
you're smarter. That doesn't work.
Be smelling bad is not a,
is not necessarily a bad problem cause
it's something that can be fixed.
But if you, if you aren't smart
enough, well then we have a,
we have a situation you can't really,
I mean you can study,
you can work but you're not
going to get smarter. Right.
So it might not be a great idea for me
to say, well you know I I decided not to.
You know, you're not getting promoted
promoted Billy. Cause you're, you're dumb.
Yeah he's just a hot tomorrow. Here's
the deal man. Just straight up.
You're not that smart. Right. Sure.
So I couldn't put you in charge of
anything cause cause you're not smart.
Now that's different than me saying,
hey listen man,
six months ago if I was like,
you need to start paying attention
because what you're doing right now,
if you're going to move up,
you got to really know you get,
it's going to take you some extra study.
And look I'm not the sharpest
tool in the shed and I,
I know I have to work hard at making
this stuff happen. Do you look at your,
do you look at your manuals at all?
Have you been studying your manual?
So you need to like dig into your
manuals and really know this stuff.
If you're think you're going
to get promoted, you're
not going to get promoted.
And unless you know this stuff
like the back of your hand,
you need to get in the game.
So if we've already been through the
whole thing and you actually got out the
manuals and you tried and you didn't
make anything happen while you guys what,
hey man, there's just not that many
opportunities at this next one.
And by the way,
I think there's another kind of course
of career course that I have thinking for
you. You know, so let's talk about
that. You know what I'm saying? Yeah,
definitely some that,
some that requires large biceps I think
is going to be your area of expertise.
Thanks.
Check
going back to the book in order that he
may keep clear of unimportant details
and thus have time for the quiet thought
and reflection of higher commander must
work through a chief of staff and thus
avoid having to deal separately with the
heads of all branches.
So far as I'm aware of the British
army is the only army which was,
which does not adopt the chief of
staff system. In my own experience,
it is quite possible to,
is quite impossible to exercise high
command successfully in war without it.
I've adopted the chief of staff system
myself throughout this war and could not
have succeeded otherwise.
So you've got to have someone that's
going to handle things for you.
A little things you know,
I was talking about the um,
the senior enlisted guy in a platoon
chief or an a task unit or in a platoon or
a company,
an army company.
The senior enlisted guy I always said
was the action arm of the commander.
So when you need something done,
I don't have time to go do it myself.
And if I go do it myself when
I've lost the bigger picture,
but if I have something critical,
you've got the senior enlisted individual
that has the most tactical experience,
has the most, uh, 40 the most
respects. When you say, Hey, chief,
that building over there hasn't been
cleared yet. I don't know what's going on.
Go clear that thing.
And he'll say,
Roger that or the platoon sergeant
or the company first sergeant.
Those guys should have the experience
and the technical expertise and then be
utilized as the action arm
that can make things happen.
Now that's not exactly what
a chief of staff of is.
It's actually quite different,
but it's similar in the fact that
you can't get sucked into the weeds.
And if you,
if you're the commander of a,
of a division and you're in the
weeds all the time, you don't have,
you can't see what's happening. And it's
the same thing in a business. If the,
if the CEO of the business is
running the business daily,
he's not looking up and out.
He's looking down and in and that's
not going to allow him to make foresee
what's coming down the pipe in the future.
And that's pretty much what it says here.
No officer whose daily life is spent at
the consideration of details or who has
not.
Time for quiet thought and reflection can
make a sound plan of battle or conduct
large scale operations.
The wise commander is the one who uses
a chief of staff who sees it very few
papers or letters himself and who sees
that the majority of reports that are
made to him,
our verbal and short,
only in this way, giving himself plenty
of time for quiet font reflection.
Will he be,
will he keep himself mentally fresh and
capable of producing the sound plan of
operations which will defeat his enemy
for the plan of operations must always be
made by the commander and he must not be.
I must not be forced upon
him by his staff. Bias, bias,
circumstances or by the enemy.
That's pretty important.
Why are you allowing the circumstances
or the enemy to dictate how you're going
to do things?
That's not a good call.
A commander must decide how he will
fight the battle before it begins.
He must decide how he will
use the military effort at
his disposal to force the
battle to swing the way he wishes
it to go. To be able to do this,
his dispositions must be so balanced
that he can ignore enemy reactions and
continue with his own plan
until he is certain of success.
He has got to strive to read the mind of
his opponent to anticipate heavy enemy
reactions to his own moves and to
take quick steps to prevent any enemy
interference with his own plan.
Again,
this is a little bit sketchy to me
cause now we're talking about, hey,
I'm just driving forward with my plan no
matter what. I don't like that attitude.
I want to be flexible.
I'm going to try and stick to my plan,
but I'm going to be flexible.
This, this is one where you know,
man, I don't even know this is,
this is one of those things where
sometimes I would get guys that
would there be a little change.
They come up with a plan.
They'd spent all this time planning for
a mission and there'd be little change.
Maybe they getting ready to go out.
Some imagery comes in and it shows
something little bit different.
Or maybe they get some Intel.
It's a little bit different and
they decide they're going to,
they've already planned.
They've already rehearsed,
they already know what they're doing.
Everyone's kind of walked through and
they decide they're going to change their
whole plan because of some little
thing. And I would say, man,
don't change your whole plan. I get
you want to make a little adjustment.
Do you want to take a little fire team
and have them make an adjustment to take
a squad, make them do something
that's, that's okay. Don't,
don't try and rearrange your whole plan.
You've already rehearsed.
You have to unrehearsed. You know how hard
that is if the unprogrammed your team,
that is really hard to do.
So sometimes, and I used to,
this is actually one of those things that
slowly I don't really talk about very
often because,
but I used to used to be in the the
combat leadership brief I used to give,
it used to say don't fall for
6% advantage over the enemy.
And what I meant by that was,
and I used to draw a target up on the,
on the dry erase board and I'd say, okay,
you're going to take down this target.
So you come up with a plan, how do you
only want to do it? And I was just,
we set up an l and basic
maneuver, okay, cool,
you're getting ready
to go out and do this.
And you find out that there
was an outhouse over the
berm over here and there's
a chance two o'clock in the morning
that the guy could be in that outhouse.
What do you want to do? And some guys
would completely change their whole plan,
completely changed their whole plan.
Meanwhile,
we're launching in two minutes
or eight minutes or 20 minutes.
They've planned this, they've rehearsed
it. Everyone knows what their job was.
The whole team came up with a
plan together. I mean it's like a,
it's really in their brains and now they
see this little detail because there's
a chance that at three o'clock in the
morning when you hit this target that the,
the guy that you're looking
for is in the outhouse,
so we're going to change our whole plan
to make up for this tiny percentage
chance that this guy's even in
the outhouse. Not a good call.
Can you break off a fire team that's
going to maneuver to a position where they
can at least keep an eye on that on house?
That's fine,
but don't change your whole damn plan
based on this little 6% chance that the
enemy might do something you
didn't expect or know the enemy.
That's something is very
unlikely of happening.
It's not that you didn't expect it,
things that you don't expect.
That's why you have contingency plans
which is like, hey, when we fly in,
if we see any other outbuildings
that we missed on the imagery,
we have a fire team designated to go and
get eyes on those things from the high
ground. Oh, okay. Cool. That's
a contingency plan that works.
Going back to the commander here,
he has gone always to be a very clear
thinker and must aim to be always one move
ahead of his opponent. I actually
prefer it to be about five booths
to do this.
He must simplify the,
whenever a problem arises he must think
out the few points which will form the
framework of the solution.
The few things that will really matter
so long as the solution to the problem is
based on those few things
that really matter.
The solution will be on the right lines,
solid,
solid.
You have like this,
just this pathway and as long in the path
at the end of the pathway is what you
want to achieve. As long as you're
doing things that are on the pathway,
you're going,
you're getting there.
When you start doing things that are
off the pathway, we've got a problem.
Sometimes you've got to look at
your, your subordinates and say, hey,
it's not even on the path in the direction
that we're heading because it doesn't
seem like a domain. A commander
must at all times. Exercise,
personal command.
That is to say he must give,
must see and give full verbal orders or
instructions to his subordinate generals
on how the battle is to be fought.
Operational Command in the field
must be direct and personal.
No written order can ever be the
equivalent of a direct verbal command.
Interesting. And I've, my standard is,
I do both. I do both. I say, Hey,
echo, here's what we're doing. Hey,
do you understand this? Do
you have any questions? Cool.
And I send you a message that says,
Hey, echo, this is what we talked about.
This is what you're doing and
making sure you understand if I can,
I'm going to do both. If you want
to do one. Yes, verbal is better.
Most of the time
a commander must therefore understand
how to give verbal orders to his
subordinates. No two generals are the
same. Each require different treatment.
Each will react differently.
By exercising personal commander
commander can exert a far greater and more
exact influenced on the battle and the
confidence which will grow up between the
commander and his generals
will be of great value.
The whole chain of command can VUSs and
only thus be built into a United team
whose strength is based on mutual
confidence and understanding.
Yeah,
relationships. That's all relationships
is what he's talking about right there.
When the whole army is built into one
great team United in working all out for a
common purpose,
the result is terrific.
Success in war is due to good teamwork
by all members of the fighting forces and
to the correct use, which is made of
all members by the team of the team,
by the commander and his staff.
But failure in war is always
due to one of two causes.
Okay.
To faulty command or to bad
staff work and sometimes do both.
Okay.
I can think of no instance where the
failure has been due to a failure of the
fighting man. The British fighting man
will always do. What is asked of him,
but you must make sure
that he understands what he is asked
to do and also that it is within his
capacity to do it.
Okay.
If your team is not doing what
it is you want them to do,
the first person you
should check is yourself.
If you're giving people complex
orders that they don't understand,
there's no possible way they
can execute those plans.
And here's how he closes this out.
Finally,
I do not believe that today a commander
can inspire great armies or single units
or even individual men and lead them to
achieve great victories unless he has a
proper sense of religious truth.
Yeah,
and he must be prepared to acknowledge
it and to lead his troops in the light of
that truth.
He must always keep his finger on
the spiritual pulse of his army
and he must be very sure
that the spiritual purpose
which inspires them is right
and true and it's clearly
expounded to one and all.
Unless he does this,
he can expect no lasting success.
So what you got to believe in,
what you're doing.
Okay.
For all leadership, I believe, is
based on the spiritual quality,
the power to inspire others to follow.
And this spiritual quality may
be for good or may be for evil.
In many cases, this quality has
been devoted toward personal ends.
Yeah.
And was partly or wholly evil.
And whenever this was.
So in the end it failed
for leadership,
which is evil.
While it may temporarily succeed,
always carries within it the
seeds of its own destruction.
That's it. That's it. That's a solid
one. Leadership, which is evil,
while it may temporarily succeed,
always carries within it the
seeds of its own destruction.
And that is a theory
that I fully believe it.
Yeah.
And I mean,
I believe in it on that level,
on that
hi consequence level.
Yeah.
But I also believe it on a,
on a much less dramatic level.
And this is something that
you deal with every day.
Okay.
Yeah. And that's this, the leader
that is looking out for himself,
the leader that puts
himself above his team,
that leaders eventually going to fail.
Okay.
Even though they may temporarily succeed.
Same thing.
They may temporarily succeed,
but eventually they are going to fail.
That's what's going to happen.
And I will tell you something else that
is true and that is the opposite is the
of that. And that is if you are doing
the right things for the right things,
for the right reasons,
then you may temporarily fail.
But you will have the seeds for victory,
the seeds for victory. And the reason
that I say seeds is very specific.
There's a reason why I'm saying that is
because seeds are not guaranteed to grow,
right?
Just because you have good intention
doesn't mean that you're going to win.
It doesn't mean that you're
going to achieve victory.
It means we have the seeds for victory
because once you plant those seeds,
you have to water them and you have to
nourish them and you have to protect them
from birds and from
squirrels and from vermin.
And you have to work.
You have to plant those seeds and then
you have to make those seeds grow.
And if you do that
and you continue to do that,
then
you move forward and you're
doing it for the right reasons.
In the end you are going to win.
And you know that that middle section
of this Monte went pretty deep talking
about morale and he has a whole nother
section here that I've got on Robin.
I think we're gonna save that for
another podcast since we're all ready.
Two hours, dude. Until then,
Echo Charles.
If we want to keep our morale high,
if we want to nourish the seeds
and we want to protect them,
sure. And we want to do the right
things for the right reason.
Always so that we can win.
Yes.
Dominate or we are we doing dominate,
kind of looking at them and
they were looking to dominate,
possibly looking to dominate. When
I'm looking at dominate men. No,
but you gotta you gotta be able to,
we'll probably come,
we'll revisit that word. Yeah. Full.
We'll do the full study
of that word and dig deep.
At a minimum it means, hey,
we're going to dominate.
It's got dominates the room in a
positive way. Yeah. At the extreme.
It's like this guy just
has a dominant personality.
Prom is how often do you see with a person
with a dominant personality that rubs
everyone the wrong way all the time.
Dominant like Domini or yeah,
this guy's got to dominate and no one,
no one wants them on the team cause
you can't get a word in edge wise.
That's why I questioned
the use of this word.
Now that being said,
and I can see this,
I can see this,
just because someone has the will to
dominate and it's strong doesn't mean that
they sit there and rub everyone the
wrong way because if they really had the
will to dominate,
what they would do is back off and allow
others to step up and allow others to
have their say and allow others to
try and lead and to actually lead.
If they were really
going to play the game,
they might have the
strongest will to dominate,
but they don't act that way because they
realize that that's counterproductive
to actually dominating. Yeah. You
look like you're confused. I mean,
yeah. I mean, I don't know. So check
it out, confused. But I think that if
I feel like there's just,
there's a more general broad
use or meaning for that
word. That's what I think.
So I think you're right.
That being said,
it could also be if you have
somebody that has a strong,
incredibly powerful will to dominate,
but they realize that that is abrasive
and it is not the best way to actually
win in a situation,
they will modulate and they will tamper
that will to dominate so that it best
serves the accomplishment of the
mission and therefore best serves their
domination. Yeah, and I dig it. You know,
it just does feel at this by this point
right now it feels like that might be
kind of a reach. It's like that, um,
thing that I talked
about at the muster of,
of what is,
what is leadership and,
and I talk about how like
leadership is winning at all costs.
And there's been some people that say,
woof,
winning at all costs seems like
a bad attitude, but the whole,
cause you put a clip like that for an
advertisement for the muster in a little
muster clip. Sure. You put me going,
leadership is winning at all costs.
Right.
And there was some of that combination
commented on our, on the echelon front,
extreme ownership,
Facebook private group that you know,
I don't know if I like,
this is a seems a little bit,
that doesn't seem like a good attitude
and you know, I replied that, hey,
you have to hear the whole thing.
That's only, that's only a few seconds.
Because when it goes on to say
is if you really want to win,
then you'll compromise.
Then you'll make exceptions.
Then you build relationships and you'll
take a back step and you'll put your,
you will subordinate your ego.
That was the biggest thing.
That's the biggest myth.
We will subordinate your ego because
you will put the mission above your own
personal will to dominate.
You'll,
you'll subordinate your will to dominate
so that you can actually win in the
long term. In the long game. Yeah.
And it's important to
remember if you heard it here,
the whole speech or would it, or the
whole segment will say is that yeah, you
talk like a lot about,
um,
where like dislike battles and then
there's the overall victory and like this,
all this stuff and then sure, there's
the dramatic parts when you're like,
nothing's going to get in my way.
But yeah,
like you sacrifice so much where,
okay,
so when you say we need all costs, it kind
of, this is what it sounds like. You've,
you just hear that line,
nothing's going to get him mind.
It sounds like even at the cost of
lighting, half of my men or something,
I ended up not only that,
but in a corporate world,
it's like I'll just step
on anyone I need to write.
I'll send bad product out to the consumers
and I don't care if they get hurt her,
but I don't care if it's, I don't care,
whatever, I'm just going to win. I'm here.
Yeah. Like that. Yeah. That's, that's what
people think. So in that guy's defense,
it sounds like that. But again,
the whole speech, it really,
I mean really the one of the main,
actually the takeaway, if not anything,
is like winning. What is winning? Like
w you know, if I lose half of my men,
it did you really win? I
think you actually say that
exact thing. He's like, no,
that's not,
it's not a victory.
But also how can you carry on with your
mission and your mission and capable.
Now I'm actually putting, I'm
actually putting that, I'm going to,
I'm going to write that down,
capture that,
and I'm going to Redo it for ETF
online. What? That part? Yeah.
You know, so that way people can
understand what winning at all costs.
What it means when I'm talking about,
yeah. So we'll put that on e f on line.
If anybody wants to check that out.
If you don't know what that is,
you,
if online is a interactive leadership
training from my company Echelon Front
where we traveled the
world teaching companies,
businesses, organizations about
leadership in the course of doing that,
we eventually got to a point where a,
we couldn't serve us all the people
that wanted our service and B,
some of the companies
that we could service,
we couldn't service all their employees
because they have 50,000 employees and
they want to have everyone get
trained to by echelon front.
So talking to Lafe during a board
meeting or you surf meaning?
Yes. So Lafe and I were
surfing, I said a brother,
we need to figure out a way
to scale this stuff and we,
you know, I said, let's, let's
look at doing something online.
And Lafe was initially like, which makes
sense by the way. Yeah, for sure. No,
and I, I, I wanted to explore it. I
wasn't like all in out of the gate,
but I was feeling pretty good about it
because I'd seen some stuff Lafe really
hadn't seen anything. You
know, he basically seen,
well you used to get trained online
in the navy for some just the most
ridiculous sort of, uh, things.
They'd send you some online training
course about if you get a Dui, this is,
you know, check this box if you think
you're going to be in trouble, you know,
they're just really not the best training.
And that's kind of what life had in mind.
But eventually we to take
a look at it and once we
looked at it, it's like, oh
man, there's the capabilities.
Unbelievable to do interactive
training and all that stuff.
So we invested in it,
we did it and now we've got this thing
and we're using it primarily we were
using it primarily for our,
for our enterprise clients.
So we're national in front of is working
with a company and they go, well,
what are we going to do with
our other 14,000 employees?
How are we going to train them?
Well here you go now. Now,
that's where they're doing their training
through that great feedback and you
know the, the decision was,
well you know there's not,
everyone is in a big company and so maybe
some of the smaller companies or just
individuals cause cause
sometimes you know,
look at some of those people come to the
muster and they're paying their own way
to come to the monster
obviously and their,
their companies not supporting
it but they want to improve.
So that's why they're there at the muster.
Well it's the same thing
with the half online.
Something sometimes you might just do it
on your own because you want to become
a better leader and why not get the
experience of the echelon front team, the,
the principles in practice you
get to try them. So that's,
that's what it is. So anyways,
where we add modules every month,
like new training and so I'm going to put
the what is leadership and the winning
at all costs thing on there so people can
listen to what that's really about and
what it really means.
Yeah.
That broader views
important in my opinion.
Also what's important in my opinion,
is the ghee you get for Jujitsu
when you're doing, you did to us.
Here's the thing, when you started
just doing, you put on a key,
you don't have any basis for comparison.
You're not gonna understand
how important that is.
Do you want to put it on a straight
jacket when you take a drive around the
block? No. Correct.
Sometimes you have to her,
but you didn't do and that's what it'll
feel like if you buy one of these other
gies. Yeah, sometimes. Anyway,
so the g you get his origin,
you get an origin g many
selections on there. Yeah.
To fit who you are and also
there's genes on there.
Yes, it is. Yeah.
Did I say origin jeans made
America American Denim,
American denim and they
don't have are alive. Well,
you need to order a pair then. Oh,
all right. Maybe I'll get some. Okay.
There you go. Yeah, they're alive. They
are awesome. Highest quality possible.
Every detail go.
If you want to find out
what cause the genes there.
Right now the price point is 124 bucks.
That's a lot of money for a pair of jeans.
I understand that if you buy two pairs
is 99 bucks each. Here's the deal.
If you want to know why
they cost that much,
going on to origin Bjj,
um,
Facebook and watch [inaudible]
video where he breaks down
the details in the genes.
You can see the whole thing.
Why every little detail is
covered. Denim pockets, belt,
every little thing is done perfectly
to the next level and so they're more
expensive.
They're also more expensive cause
we're just kicking it off once we get,
once we keep building him we'll
get more efficient. So yeah,
eventually the price is gonna come down
if you can't afford it right now. I man,
that's cool. That's cool. I get it.
Do genes have the whole
situation of the first at dish?
Well they are technically right now you
can get first. The first judicious. Yeah,
but that would be like a
first batch of them first.
The rashes is live right now.
Yeah, go first. A dish. Right.
You ever seen those like designer jeans
that cost like $300 how they're made.
This is where if you see people that
are scraping them with rocks and stuff,
cause I've seen this, it's worse than
that. So they get like regular jeans,
whatever, and it's a certain color and
it just denim from wherever and they,
you know, this factory in, I
forget where, but you know,
a factory in a factory in China
treat. Yeah. I think it's China,
Pakistan or in India. And
there's uh, uh, you know,
these little kids that are nine years
old exposed to chemicals. Yeah, yeah,
yeah. I saw the one I saw on a little
bit. It was more team than that,
but nonetheless,
they were like super,
like they're like $300 jeans or
to fish or something like this.
And they go and the way they're
made, I'm like, Bro, how is it,
how is that even worth $300?
Like they,
they cut the jeans like normal and
it's like denim, you know, whatever.
And then they do them and they put like
this steam on them and then they send it
to the next person,
the next station in the factory.
The next station has this like it's
almost like a, like a fishing line on a,
what do you call like a wheel,
like a tomato look abused or whatever.
That's exactly right.
So it goes and it spins on the genes
and it makes it look a certain level of
abuse or whether to, what do
you call it? Distress, distress.
And then it goes to the
next little station and the,
and this person at this station is just
doing every single one. Same thing,
put up a book,
next station.
The next station has like a little
another thing to help it kind of do it.
Then the next session folded.
And so I watched that thing with Pete
and my point and I'm like, Oh man,
that makes sense. This all makes
sense. Like this is deep, you know,
there's good made me want
to get one obviously.
But I thought back to that
factory and I'm thinking, man,
how is that worth like $300
or whatever for that thing.
It was such a throwaway process like
when you, when you see it and feel it.
So I dig it man. It d and they are made
in America by the way. Yeah, for sure.
They're made in America
than made in Maine.
There the cottons from
America has died in America.
It's woven in America and yeah,
the price point is,
is more expensive than what you're
going to pay. And Hey, you know,
I don't want you to go out and spend
your last dollar on this pair of origin
jeans.
No Man.
But if you want to help
out and you want the bay,
they all have the best possible genes
you get. If you want them, then cool.
That'd be cool.
Yup.
But don't need to freak out.
I'm not freaking out on my end.
We're trying to make good,
we're trying to make good quality
products and our real mission is longterm
mission to bring manufacturing back
to America. You know, we want these,
we want to get these jeans down to
a price point. How do we do that?
Increase the volume, make more of
them. There'll be economies of scale.
We'll be able to lower the prices
for sure. Absolutely. You know what?
We talked to some gene people,
Denim people, they, they,
they wanted us to charge $300 for these
jeans. Yeah. Cause they're like, well,
you know, these are, wait,
what did they say? They were
premium. Yeah. Premium jeans.
But there was another word
too. Anyways, you know there's,
there's people that pay that kind of
money for jeans. I'm not one of them.
Yeah, no, you know, I don't know.
But anyways, yeah, either way.
Well the good news about the whole
situation, including made in America,
they do have other stuff. So an eighth
man, I haven't talked about these shorts.
So, and I don't know if you
notice what I wear all the time,
but the only thing I wear is the
shorts only one straight up. I mean,
unless it's like, you know, to
train or something like this.
But like just around is
only the origin shorts,
shark sharks or whatever.
Yeah.
I have like six pairs of them
and it's like the same thing.
So I'm sure it's like, you know,
if you go through your routine,
like people at the store,
they're like proud Skype.
Where's the same shorts every day,
but well one of them has a green logo,
the other one has a black logo.
Either way.
These are literally the best shorts
in the like ever made that I've put on
straight up. Yes. So I can get
those Charlie. There you go.
Custom made in the mirror. He Oh, big
time. And I'm so that's for real though.
Well you also said that
about their dark chocolate.
Well those are the most
comfortable for sure.
And and well, let's show you
were, and I tried on Joggers,
I told me about it. Yeah. Ridiculous.
Then the whole idea. So sounds ridiculous.
You don't have a Jogger, uh, what do you
call physique? Yeah. What do you need to,
what's the geography?
I like skinny.
I don't know that I can put my finger
on what exactly a geography is,
but I can tell you that I don't, you don't
have it. Yes sir. I confirmed that. Yes.
So don't worry about the joggers. If
you're Jocko button. If for anyone else,
those joggers are factually
in the most comfortable.
A jogger sweat situation close
in exists currently.
Currently they've got some
supplements to a joint warfare.
Krill oil discipline discipline.
Go.
We were on a Skype or a or a yeah,
this business Skype call today
and Jason Gardner was on and he,
you know,
you can you have a little video?
My little video, I don't know which one.
Jake. No little video like Skype, Skype.
You know what Skype is? It's video
comp. Video teleconferencing. Yes.
What you mean Jason Gardeners like,
like pulls out his bottle of discipline
going opens it up and like takes one in.
Yo, Jason's super animated, you know,
and he gets this big smile on his face
because he took a couple hits in the
discipline go anyways, so we got that.
Good. If you need to get in the zone.
We also have milk, mint,
milk, peanut butter, milk,
vanilla, gorilla, the darkness,
chocolate and now live strawberry,
strawberry, slayer, moldy,
strawberry slayer. Oh boy. All right,
so let me tell you,
get that strawberry is just straight up.
Get that strawberry.
That thing is a dessert.
Dang. Okay. So we like,
I don't know how well
it's, it's the, the kids,
the warrior could moke which
some strawberries. Awesome.
The chocolate's good to strawberries.
Awesome.
And I didn't think I just was telling
Bryan like, no, hey man, I don't care.
Just put a bigger scoop in and whatever.
Just re duplicated. But you know,
he's like, no, it's kind of more
protein. It's adults, blah blah blah.
And somehow he made it.
It's actually,
it's actually better or at least as good.
It might be so good dude.
It's so good. It's ridiculous.
It's a straight up desert.
It tastes like a milkshake straight up.
If you mix it with milk,
which is what I mix it with.
It tastes like a Straw Berry milkshake.
It tastes better than a
strawberry milkshake. So if
he's so good, it's ridiculous.
You go blind taste tests, you've got all
the protein that you need. Here you go.
And then you have um, blind taste
test, right? You've got to imagine,
cause you know the difference. I get
it. So you have a, a cop, you know, war.
You could milk strawberry adult. We'll
just, we'll just say milk strawberry.
Right. Which one are you going to
choose? Which one are you, you, you,
you, I think I'm going to
go for the adult. I thought
you were gonna throw a, uh,
a Haagen daas strawberry shake.
And here's the deal.
I'm not picking the Haagen. Daas is too
much. It's too much. It's too much. Yeah.
That's kind of why I didn't say it.
And it's not even,
it's not even too much in a good way.
It's too much in a bad way. It's like,
it's like you don't want to drink it.
The strawberry Mulkey you're like
just pounding it. Yeah. Three. Her,
she feeling good about things.
Interesting. All right, well
I'm gonna try it, Ellen,
because I have no,
actually, wait d I think he,
he should have put some in the
mail. It just, it just came out.
I have not tried it yet, but I will
report back 100% Jocko. White Tea as well.
Yes. Don't forget about that. Yeah.
It'll get you 20,000 pound dead lift,
which is no big deal to some people.
To me, it's kind of a big deal.
And this organic by the way.
So you know,
percent organic certified check also.
Yes, we have a store. Jocko has a store.
So I made a video is fun about, it was
nothing like super in depth, but you know,
he got all our friends training partners
are people call you got Noah Noah
Oliver. No one's got good arm locks.
Yeah, he's actually been like,
I mean on top of Greg Macintyre.
He,
he's been kind of my main training partner
recently. The past few months. Yeah.
The main one. Yeah. So him.
Yes. No Oliver. Greg Mcintyre.
Greg tray is in there.
We got nay Dene,
nay Dene Belgium may dean,
um,
Tim Ford.
Did I say Greg Mack attack?
He's all up in there. Yeah. Oh, you
got Dave Burke. Good deal. Good deal.
Days in there. Jamie's in there.
Jamie. Yeah. Um, and then the kids.
Can we say whose kids there?
There's some kids in there.
We'll just say there's some
kids in there. Yes, they're not.
My kids are not echo kids, but they
don't make kids do their warrior kids.
We know. What, don't worry kids a
hundred thousand percent. Yeah. So yeah,
the deans in their teams there anyway,
the point is they're just our friend.
He was just this cool, fun video
Jocko story. You want to do,
you want something get or if you like
something to get something nonetheless
Jocko, store.com this is where you can
get the shirts that say discipline equals
freedom if you want to represent
in the wild on the path.
How is this? When I was um,
this was a while ago, so my, my,
I had an extra shirt later on.
It was a size medium
for the that you wear.
See what's funny is I need,
you can say that,
I know you're going to say Sunday that
anyway, I'm taking pictures for this.
You know,
you've got to take pictures for the
products for the store and for whatever
reason, the size medium, that's the
best looking size I guess for pictures.
I Dunno nonetheless take the picture of
him, but I have it laying around, right?
So my wife is like,
oh this is extra shirt and you know,
can I give it to like one of my
friends or whatever and I wasn't,
I had no use for the shirt at this point.
And I said no because I don't know if
their friend is like going to represent,
you know,
I don't know if the friend is on the path.
What if the friend's not on the path
and they're wearing that shirt that's,
you know, it's different. There's
more to it. That's what it feels like.
You see what I'm saying?
It's true story nonetheless.
When you are on the path and you
want to represent in the wild,
you just go to Jocko store.com
I was at the Joe Rogan show.
Sure. The four 24 20 and San
Diego with Peter Attia. Yeah.
And we were with a bunch of other dudes
and Peter was reminding me that on
Twitter somebody had said,
hey Jocko,
I wasn't in the seal teams but I
want to show support to the seals.
Is it cool if I were like a navy seal?
Trident on my hat for tee shirt.
And my response was,
I was in the seal teams for 20 years
and I don't wear a seal team hat or tee
shirt. Wait, so does that
mean yes or no? That means no.
Hell No. Right? Because, okay,
so coincidentally me and good deal,
Dave Burke,
we're talking about the exact same thing.
So I forget how we ended up talking about
it, but I was like, Hey, what's the,
what's the,
cause he gave me his uniform,
I was doing something with it
for video wise. So I don't know,
for whatever reason we ended up talking
about what like what can, you were like,
what can not wear, what's off limits on
this thing? And he told me it was like,
you know,
some stuff in me but I don't know.
So he had to sort of explain it to me
and that's essentially the scenario he
painted. He was like, you
know how like the navy seals,
like they have the trident.
Like you can't just put on
a train it, you know, like,
like if you're not that you bring the,
tried it here,
but let's say for
whatever reason you read,
I can't just grab it and then like kind
of put it on even as like for fun. No,
it's like Beth that's kind of off
limits, you know, you can't say.
And then so you made the
comparison to Jujitsu belt too.
Like if I grabbed your
black belt and put it on,
granted you're kind of my
friend. I could never, let's say,
let's say I wasn't listening, I
wasn't even a white belt. Let's say.
I was like even like a purple belt and
my instructor who I wasn't necessarily
personal friends with, but that
was happening to be my instructor.
I can't put that belt on.
What if you use it?
What if you forgot your belt?
He was injured and he was on the sidelines
and he's like, oh, just wear mine.
Would you wear it?
Never do that. But what's funny is Dave
Burke brought that exact scenario up.
Different colors though. So he got good
question. When someone was like, Hey,
just where mine, it's a blue
belt. He said he's in, uh,
the guy he was training with,
I think it was a blue belt that he
was training with. He was like, Hey,
I have an extra one. You don't have a
belt, you need a belt to to, you know,
the train and stuff like that.
Gives him his blue belt.
Dave Burke said out of respect for
the guys, like, you know, suggestion,
he wore it but he did not feel
good about it at all. And I think,
I think that's kind of the
deal where if some higher belts
I used to give guys,
like in the,
if they started trading I'd give them
a piece of one inch, two tubular.
Nylon Green. Yeah. Which is
just like to tie their belt.
Do you remember any Cameron using
ABC. Okay. Right. Okay. Yeah.
Camp Good Jiu Jitsu by the way,
the wrestler and strong wrong. Yes.
So he came to mind is the guy that,
you know,
Cameron came to my house and
tamed the beast. You know the,
you know what that is with
Kettlebell tame the beast.
You get the 48 kilogram Kettlebell, which
you don't have one that big? Yes I do.
I'll have a nice, so I have
one, but before I had those,
he ordered one and he was like in
between houses at the time. So he,
so he ordered a, had it sent
to my house. He gets it.
He comes to my house first time he's
ever picked up a 48 kilogram hundred and
six pound kettle bell. And there's
a thing called taming the beast,
which is you do a press
with that kettle bell,
you do a pistol with that kettle bell and
then you do a pull up with that kettle
bell. And the first time
he ever did it, he did it.
He did it right in front of them. Did
it all right. Like no warmup. Just,
just did it.
Yeah. And that's quite a lot cause he's
not a large get like I'm bigger than him.
He's like what?
[inaudible] 95 yeah,
maybe one nine. Yeah, I, yeah, I might
give him like one nonetheless. Yeah,
that's saying a lot.
No,
that's the point I bring him up is because
the first time he ever trained Geek
because I trained with
them before and I was like,
oh this guy's probably at the time,
this was years ago, I was like,
you was probably, I was a
purple belt. So I was like,
this guy is probably like a purple
belt too. So you know, whatever.
I trained with him one day he comes
in in the Geek, so I'm like, Oh shit.
You know that little parties like
kind of like, oh yeah, like you know,
let me confirm.
We don't want to,
but he has a piece of
that green that Darlene,
and here's the thing,
he doesn't just stand out because
it's like it's Kinda dark or whatever.
But you see new guy come,
you know, cause he's Sorta,
you know how when you come and train for
the first time and g and some classes,
kind of like most of those people, they
kind of [inaudible]. Exactly right.
But this guy is a new guy. I knew who he
was. So I was like looking at, I'm like,
okay, that's obviously a military
piece of equipment. It's not a belt.
It was funny, the looks on
everyone's face, they'll like this,
like you're kind of looking at each other
as the whole world gone crazy.
It's really funny. But that's how
rigid the belt situation is though.
That's why you can't just grab a
guy's belt. And as I know people,
not specific people, but it would
stand to reason, put it that way.
It would stand to reason that even as
a joke, if I grabbed like, you know,
it's funny as a joke, I've been like
here just where mine, like some people,
you know, I've just been like giving
people my black belt. Like, Oh, you know,
like a, like a blue belt or a
boy here, you just were mine.
And that give it to me like, like
awkwardly awkwardly, make them do it.
That's how the dynamics of that, you know,
before I really knew Jeff Glover, yeah,
he came down here and did a seminar and
he's like, Hey, I don't have a belt.
And I was like, yeah, you can use mine.
And I was really, I was actually worried.
Yeah, we had one belt. I've
only had one belt my whole time,
like one black belt and I was
worried. I was like, Dang. I mean,
not that I thought he was going to
like steal it, but I just was afraid.
Oh you know,
you know he'll,
he'll put in his bag and next thing you
know it's in Santa Barbara and the next
thing you know, I'll never see my
belt again. My special belt. Yeah.
I was there for that day when he did
it because we wasn't here though.
I wasn't here. That was more, I like
what's here and I had to go. Yeah.
And so I didn't get to,
but he hung it back up.
Jeffy Glover took care of it.
I took a picture of him that day.
Oh really rough to see
if he was where my belt,
he is wearing your belt and the picture
and he's doing this and that picture
ended up being used for a bunch of
different stuff. That's kind of cool.
Then my belt made it
kind of famous with Jeff.
He if you notice like the belt is a
little bit long. It's fun. Oh yeah.
Cause I'm thicker than he is.
Yeah we'll you have like a what you
know the belt comes with three. Yeah.
And he's probably, he's Ne one for sure
cause you have 55 yup. There it is.
So don't do that.
Don't
seal team two who is just an incredibly
well respected guy in the day he had,
I think he had two sons and he was
giving them like a, like a hat,
like a seal team,
two hat or something that had to try done
on it or he had an old one that he was
going to giving to his son's like hey
I'm not going to wear this and it's too
old. And he made them cut the Triton
off of it. If they wanted to wear it.
I was like yes I dig it. And there's
all those kinds of things, you know,
like if even on a super
lower level, like, you know,
if you made it through some little thing,
like I don't know,
like one of these spartan
races or something that you
only get this shirt or hat
if you did it, you know. And even
then there's a little, I mean it's,
it's way more loose for sure.
But you know,
like your wife puts it on or
something and you're like,
people like don't do that. That,
yeah, man. I know my daughter,
I know my daughter present in that state.
A state wrestling championships.
Those kids up there, they're buying
those shirts and sweatshirts.
I got to read about what if you came home
and your wife had, you're trading on,
why would my wife had lunches because
she's trying to represent, well,
I'll just take it from her.
No,
actually there's a thing where there's
a thing where like a seal will give his
wife like a little necklace when
I tried it on it. Okay. You know,
that's sort of their why. So she
doesn't take his going to be, no,
I don't think she'd be trying to take
his, but I think it's just, you know,
little appreciation. Yeah,
fully. But no, but no,
my wife knows what's up. You know?
My wife does not one of those. Yeah,
I know she doesn't make sense. So
that's kind of how it is. Right.
When the shirts from Jocko store
kind of, I mean, not to that level,
but I put it this way.
If I see someone wearing representing,
I know that they're representing,
I know they're on the pathway.
They're not just some guy who person
or whatever. That's not in the past.
It doesn't seem like that.
Oh, they're definitely in the
game. Yeah, for sure. Yeah,
they're definitely in the game. That's
what it feels like. Well, there you go.
Also subscribe to the podcast
if you haven't already. I know.
Seems obvious,
but apparently it's not as obvious
from what I gather. Nonetheless,
subscribe if you haven't already, and
by the way, if you get a piece of gear,
it supports the podcast. Is that
important? We'll, is it important?
Depends on what you mean
by important. So yes. Yeah.
I mean it's important to let people
know that the one additional bonus of
representing is you're actually
helping out the podcast support.
We're going to get a new table by the
way, which has been a 100 yeah, this one.
It wiggles a lot. It's
ridiculous. Echo Charles is table.
This is one of those things where like
an apt punishment would be you had to
bring this to your house and use it
as your dining room table for a year.
Oh my gosh. No. Yeah, yeah.
This is a good day. Why?
You know the picture looked
nice. Check. All right,
so we're going to get a new table.
If you buy a tee shirt,
we can get a new table that's not
going to fall down and all that.
But we appreciate that support too.
And when you're subscribing to podcasts,
I got the warrior could podcast, the
warrior could podcast is aimed at kids,
but I promise you that Uncle
Jake has lessons for everyone.
And also we have a kid,
a warrior kid named Aiden,
and he's making soap here in California.
Irish oaks ranch.com if you
want to get some, some soap,
some Jocko soaps so that you can
stay clean and they're going to,
he has a new one to trooper chill persona
has a rope on it, so put in a row.
He's a five 50 corn by the way.
Too late for sure. For sure. Yeah.
Yeah. That's some good stuff,
by the way. Also, youtube,
we do have a youtube channel.
If you're interested in the
video version of this podcast,
if you want to see what this table looks
like, week table looks okay. Actually,
I see it in that. Nonetheless, you
can see how wiggly all the books.
Nonetheless, if you're interested in
the video version of this podcast,
that's where you can find it.
Also, some excerpts on there.
If you don't want to watch
the whole podcasts at once,
you know some excerpts on that little
lessons that you may have found important,
you can kind of revisit. Those.
Also got psychological warfare.
Everyone that asks for an alarm
clock with my voice on it,
telling them to wake up or whatever.
That's good.
The psychological warfare soundtrack,
the psychological warfare album
on iTunes or Google play or MP,
three platforms and there's a bunch of
things on there for me telling you the
right thing to do and why you should
do the right thing. So check that.
Also check out flip side canvas.
My brother Dakota Meyer is making art.
That's the right word.
Yes it is.
He's making art and putting
art on canvases and vinyl
posters that you can hang
up and you can remind yourself
the discipline equals freedom.
You can remind yourself that
all your excuses are lies. Yeah.
Well that, that's really good
because a lot of people were,
and we have posters for sure on you know
the store, but this is a little bit,
it's like one to maybe like
three or four levels better way.
Then you know a poster.
The poster is buzzer.
Qubit like of course you hate me to
Jim. What I, this is likes level. Yeah.
It's like a leveler.
Flip side, calm flipside,
canvas.com and also support Dakota
Meyer for crying out loud to yeah,
big time.
Also on it on it.com/jocko this
is where you can get fitness gear,
kettle bells. I recently posted a picture
of my newest Kettlebell storm trooper,
which it took us on a picture,
a good picture on it,
posted it as like a picture on their
thing. You made it big, huge time.
Made my day big 10. What
time did that guy, no,
but you know, nonetheless it
happened. Um, but yeah, you can get,
you know kettlebells on there,
some ropes and battle ropes.
They got some good like
immunity supplements too.
That's the one I actually have been
religiously taking this shroom tech immune
check. You got to take Talon
so she, if you're doing travel,
but nonetheless a of good good stuff
on there.
On [inaudible] dot com slash jock have
a little book coming out called way of
the warrior kid three
where there's a will.
It is available for preorder right now.
If you want to help me
and you want the book,
please preorder it so that
I know how many to print.
I failed miserably when it came to Mikey
and the dragons, Mike and the dragons.
I didn't make enough. I ended up having
a scramble to make more. I apologize.
We got them to everyone by Christmas,
but it was uh, it was not smooth.
It was a little bit of a nightmare.
So total failure on my part this time way,
the warrior kid three where
there's a will check out that book,
preorder it.
Now it's coming out May 28th by the way.
So we're almost there,
but I can make more quickly,
quickly enough to have them ready
for you if you preordered. Anyways,
also they way the warrior
kid and Mark's mission,
those are the first two books in
that series. Mike in the dragons.
Best book ever for little
kids in the history of ever.
That's confirmed by the way.
And the field manual,
the discipline equals
freedom field manual.
That's a book about how to get after it,
no matter where you are in your life.
It's a great place to start boarding,
keep you up to start on the
path or to keep you on the path.
The audio version of that is on
iTunes, Amazon music, Google play,
extreme ownership. First Book I
wrote with my brother Leif Babin,
the dichotomy of leadership.
His second book I wrote with my brother,
late Babin Ashkelon front.
That's our leadership consultancy.
We solve problems through leadership.
That's what we do.
Go to echelon front.com the
muster May 23rd and 24th sold out,
done.
That's in Chicago,
September 19th and 20th in Denver. That
one is going to sell out, so is Sydney,
December 4th and fifth if you want to
come to the monster extreme ownership.com
that's where the details are.
They're all going to sell out.
All of them have sold out and all of them
will sell out, so if you want to come
get on there and get registered,
eff online already talked about that.
The F Overwatch is where we take
leaders from special operations,
from combat aviation,
and we placed them into companies that
need leadership inside their organization.
So you don't always want to hire someone
just because they've been working in
some industry for a long time.
Hire someone that has
leadership capability and then
get them up to speed on the
industry.
These guys are proven combat leaders.
They can step up and take
you to the place you need.
Efo overwatch.com and
be on a cruise with us hardcore
by the way, a hardcore cruising,
which is my recommended level of cruising
from time to time rest between sets
were on the interwebs,
Twitter,
Instagram and on Facebook that I was
going to do it like you didn't do.
Anyway.
I'm at Echo Charles and Jack was that
Jocko Willink on all of them and thanks to
all our military folks out there that
are on the front lines of Free Doma
Standing Watch and thanks to police and
law enforcement, firefighters, paramedics,
EMT is dispatchers,
correctional officer's border patrol,
secret service
and all first responders who
maintain vigilance 24 hours a day,
365 days a year to keep us safe here
at home and to everyone else out there
remembers some of those lessons
from Field Marshall Montgomery.
Okay.
Remember to cut through the overlying
difficulties and see the essential,
well, what you need to do and
then take a dispatching it,
a dispassionate view of good things and
bad things that are going to assail you.
Yeah.
And use your force of will
to keep getting after it.
And until next time,
this is echo and Jocko out.