The idea at the end of the Cold War.
And it started with George Hw Bush and
then continued with Bill Clinton was
what George Hw Bush called it a Europe
whole and free Clinton called it a
peaceful,
undivided democratic Europe.
The idea was let's take advantage of the
end of the Cold War to remove the
division in Europe and bring the former
communist part of Europe into the rest,
integrate it into the rest of Europe.
And there was,
you know,
there was the effort with central and
eastern Europe to bring those new
democracies in there where the wars in
the Balkans,
in Bosnia and Kosovo,
uh,
to try to end the repression that was
being carried out by the government in
Serbia,
uh,
to try to move you,
the former Yugoslavia onto a different
path.
And the Russia part was related to this,
trying to bring Russia closer as well.
But especially on NATO,
the idea was that the United States
could use this alliance to help anchor
countries like Poland and Hungary and
others in central and eastern Europe
into the West.
Because basically what NATO said to
those countries was if you can develop
democracy and markets and respect for
human rights and and respect for borders
that you can join this organization but
you have to carry out internal reforms
in order to join NATO.
And it was hugely important for the
stability of central and eastern Europe
and a huge success story after the Cold
War that these young democracies did it,
I mean they built democ democratic
market oriented states,
protected human rights and you know,
agreed that they weren't going to change
borders and it,
because there were a lot of,
a lot of issues from how those borders
had been drawn decades before that
people were worried about him.
You know,
for example,
Hungary and Romania,
you know,
worked out their issues and these
countries were able to join NATO,
which gave the European Union more
confidence about the stability in that
part of Europe,
which enabled those countries in 2004 to
join the European Union,
which you know,
has really been in terms of the American
effort to promote democracy after the
end of the Cold War.
Central Eastern Europe really is one of
the huge success stories.
It's also,
uh,
should have been sort of a cautionary
tale about what was required because a
lot of the people in the George h w Bush
administration in the period of 89 to 91
who were there when central Eastern
Europe started on this path saw and in
central and eastern Europe,
you know,
the bad guys were toppled.
Statues were pulled down and the
populations really wanted to join the
west.
And when these guys are end after 2001,
they're looking at Iraq and they're
thinking about it the way they saw
things in central and eastern Europe.
You get rid of the regime and you're
topless statues and the population
welcomes you as liberator's and wants to
join the west.
And they really took the wrong,
less,
I mean,
less than a central eastern Europe was
how much assistance was required,
how much,
how important it was that you had
institutions like NATO and the European
Union that could help bring these
countries in,
in these countries,
really saw themselves as,
as part of the West,
and that they had been denied that by
the Cold War.
And,
uh,
you know,
things didn't turn out that way in a
raft.
[inaudible].