You asked me if I knew the person's
looking for truth.
You see,
as a scientist,
we're even today like that.
Earlier I talked about the fact that all
we can do in science is construct
theories and that means,
for example,
that what we're ultimately doing is not
about the truth.
This is a confusion I think that exists
in many people's minds.
Science is not about finding the truth.
What scientists about is making our
beliefs of nature less false.
These are two different things,
and the second one involves mathematics,
imagination,
and the ability to measure.
So we're making our beliefs less false.
We're not necessarily finding it through
the fact,
I'm not sure.
Truth actually exists in science and
this is in fact a very famous statement
that Einstein made that he is not sure
what truth means in the context of
science.
So No,
I'm not searching for truth.
That's certainly not what I'm doing.
Sometimes when I look at my own career,
I feel a little bit like Captain Ahab
and I think probably a lot of us feel
that way,
that this is a great white whale that we
saw once and we're trying to capture it
in my own life.
Um,
I earlier spoke of this
interdisciplinary collaboration of
mathematicians and physicists and
computer scientists.
We're,
we're,
uh,
on the p Quad chasing my white whale.
There's this one problem that I know
about that I,
I've been able to develop some
particular insights into.
And this collaboration is actually
pursuing this problem.
We've been able to turn sets of
equations that the sorts of pictures and
these pictures can be processed.
And by manipulating the pictures,
you're massively using them to
understand properties are the equations
I call these pictures of Dinka and
thinkers.
A very interesting word.
It comes from west Africa and it
basically means pictures that have
hidden meaning.
And so that's what we've applied to
these mathematical objects.
And so yes,
I have my own personal moby Dick that
I'm after.
However,
I don't plan to suffer the fate of the
peak wise and it's capital.
No
theoretical.
Physics doesn't really make that kind of
company contribution to our
understanding.
In fact,
one of the another thing I tell people
about what science is versus other forms
of knowing the universe in science and
in particular in the physical sciences,
you can imagine a family that lives in a
home and you could say,
well Gee,
I want to study this situation,
but I want to put all the people out of
the house.
I wanted to study how the house works.
That's what the physical sciences do in
our universe.
The social sciences,
the liberal arts,
the arts themselves.
You'll put the people back in the house
and you asked how the whole system works
together.
So in physics,
we don't answer the question of how the
house behaves when the families in the
past.