I am one of the directors of science and
my specialty is communications and the
idea that a mission ends when you return
to the data,
when you make the discoveries,
when the scientists publish their
papers,
to me the mission doesn't end until you
have some sort of public involvement
until you have some sort of public
buyin.
I think that's as important as any other
part of the mission you had been trying
to tell people for years that our
communications team on a mission is just
like having your crack team of
electrical engineers or your or your
best computer programmers.
You need to have people that really
understand communication as well.
Uh,
it,
it helps.
I mean,
in my case,
I started out as a research
astrophysicist and so I understand a lot
of the topics as well,
but I do communications now a NASA and
as far as why NASA is important,
I think this is one of these things that
people have no idea.
We run at the moment,
108 science missions.
Those are mostly spacecraft.
Some of them are on balloons or sounding
rockets or on the space station.
Uh,
some of them are on the earth.
We have people embedded with the,
uh,
the Zombie reindeer herders,
trying to understand how climate change
is changing the migration of reindeer
herds.
I mean,
it's,
it's amazing that NASA is all over and,
you know,
everything from the disaster mitigation
from all of those hurricanes.
We actually sent staff to Puerto Rico
when Fema was overwhelmed.
They've been setting up communication
centers.
Um,
I mean everything from determining what
set off the big bang to,
you know,
where are those wildfires going to be
spreading to in southern California.
We have 108 missions and I've never seen
any organization operate more
efficiently.
I've never worked with more brilliant
people.
Um,
I think people often don't understand
what the real value is as far as blue
sky research.
You know,
people talk about spinoffs and people
joke about things like velcro and Tang.
I mean,
those are jokes,
but the,
uh,
the more intelligent people might notice
things like,
you know,
microprocessors started at NASA cell
phones,
the reason you have computers,
the reason the United States was poised
to lead the computer revolution was
because of the Apollo program.
But,
um,
I don't know.
I mean all of those kind of fall flat to
tell you the truth,
I think that people don't understand.
It was a,
a NASA satellite doing research just out
of curiosity to see what gases in the
atmosphere that discovered that the
ozone hole is being depleted in the 19
eighties.
And uh,
the NASA scientists with a number of
university scientists went running to
the UN instead.
If we don't do something,
we are literally going to destroy the
planet.
And they made the Montreal.
They actually got the Montreal protocol
sign.
They actually make treaties,
the other band,
these chemicals that we're depleting our
ozone layer.
And we've since done an atmospheric
models that show that we would have
actually destroyed the ozone layer.
Had we done nothing by the year 20,
60,
which if not in my lifetime is probably
in our children's lifetime.
And um,
basically that would have destroyed
agriculture.
Crops would've failed all over the
world.
You couldn't have livestock outside.
People couldn't have lived outside.
Um,
we very nearly destroyed civilization
and your grandchildren would have lived
through that.
And so when people talk about what's the
best NASA spinoff,
you know,
the worth of blue sky research that you
don't understand where it's going to
lead best friend,
if I know this grandchildren.