I'm often asked and occasionally in an
accusatory way,
are you atheist?
You know the only [inaudible] I am is a
scientist,
right?
I don't associate with movements,
I don't,
I'm not in ism.
I just,
I think for myself,
the moment,
once someone attaches you to a
philosophy or a movement,
then they assign all the baggage and all
the rest of the philosophy that goes
with it to you.
And when you want to have a
conversation,
they will assert that they already know
everything important there is to know
about you because of that association.
And that's not the way to have our
conversation.
I'm sorry it's not.
I'd rather we explore each other's ideas
and real time rather than assign a label
to it and assert you know what's going
to happen in advance.
So what people are really after is what
is my stance on religion or spirituality
or God.
And I would s I would say if I had to
find a word that came closest,
it would be a agnostic agnostic.
We're dates from the 19th century Huxley
to refer to someone who doesn't know,
but it hasn't yet really seen evidence
for it.
But it prepared to embrace the evidence
if it's there.
But if it's not,
it won't be forced to have to think
something that is not otherwise
supported.
Okay.
There are many atheists who say,
well,
all agnostics or atheists like,
okay,
I'm constantly claimed by atheist.
I find this intriguing.
In fact,
on my Wiki pay,
I didn't create the Wiki page.
Others did.
And I'm flattered that people cared
enough about my life to assemble it.
And it said,
a Neil,
the recitation is an atheist.
I say,
well,
that's not really true.
I said,
let me,
Neil degrasse Tyson is a agnostic.
Went back a week later,
it had been it,
it said Neil Tyson as an atheist again
within a week.
And I said,
what's,
what's up with that?
And I said,
I am not the word it a little
differently.
So I said,
okay.
Neil degrasse Tyson,
widely claimed by atheist is actually an
agnostic.
And some will say,
well that's,
you're not being fair to the fact that
they're actually the same thing.
No,
they're not.
The same thing.
And I'll tell you why.
Atheist,
I know who proudly wear the badge are
active atheist.
They're like in your face atheist and
they want to change policies and they're
there.
They're having debates.
I don't have the time,
the interest,
the energy to do any of that.
I'm a scientist.
I'm an educator.
My goal is to get people thinking
straight in the first place.
Just get you to be curious about the
natural world.
That's what I'm about.
I'm not about any of the rest of this.
And it's odd that the word atheist even
exists.
I don't play golf.
Is there a word for non golf players?
Do non golf players gather and,
and,
and strategize.
Do,
do non-skiers have a word and come
together and talk about the fact that
they don't ski?
I don't.
I don't,
I can't do that.
I can't gather around and talk about how
much everybody in the room doesn't
believe in God.
I just don't,
I don't have the energy for that.
And so I agnostic separates me from the
conduct of atheist,
whether or not this strong overlap
between the two categories,
and at the end of the day,
I'd rather not be any category.
I don't know.