Hello everyone,
it's been a very strange day.
So I'm going to tell you about what
happened and then I'll start the
lecture.
So I got up this morning and started to
put my day together and I tried to sign
into my gmail account and it said that
it had been disabled because I violated
the terms of service with g mail.
And I thought,
well,
I didn't violate any terms of service
that I know of now.
I set up a new youtube channel yesterday
called Jordan b Peterson clips and so we
made some technical changes and so I
thought maybe it had something to do
with that.
And I had been shot out of Google one
other time years ago.
So when you get a shout out like that,
there's a little form you can fill out.
And so I filled out the form and I said
that I had been shot out and uh,
that I didn't know why.
And I sent it off.
And then I realized one of my staff
members called me and said that she was
locked out of the youtube account.
And I thought,
Oh yeah,
the youtube account is hooked to the
Gmail Account,
so that meant that I couldn't get access
to any of my youtube videos.
They were still up and online,
but I couldn't get access to them.
I couldn't post last week's Biblical
lecture for,
for,
for example.
And so that was worrisome and made me
suspicious.
And then about two hours later,
something like that,
I got an email from Google and they said
that they had reviewed the my request to
be reinstated and that I had violated
Google's terms of agreement or terms of
service and they weren't going to turn
my account back on.
And I thought.
And they didn't say why they didn't say
anything.
I got,
there was no warning whatsoever about
any of this.
They didn't tell me why.
And they didn't say why in the email
response.
And so I wrote them back and I said,
because they said I could.
I wrote them back and I said,
this might not be a good idea,
basically,
and you might want to think about it.
And then I twitted tweeted what had
happened.
Right.
I took screenshots and I tweeted and I
contacted a whole bunch of journalists
because it turns out that I know a whole
bunch of journalists and so and so.
Then what happened then was that I got a
call from the daily caller in the United
States.
I had done an interview with them last
week,
which isn't posted yet and they
interviewed me and within 20 minutes
posted it online and so they have a
fairly big audience and so that was good
and then somebody phoned me from Ottawa
and I did a live radio show about that
and that was good.
And then a number of other journalists
contacted me and I sent them the
information,
but another one of my staff actually,
my son emailed me and he said,
look,
you should hold off because maybe there
still a mistake here.
And I thought,
yeah,
there might be.
It might be just a mistake,
but then why in the world did I email
google?
And they contacted me and they said they
would not reinstate it and they didn't
provide me with any information.
So I contacted the other journalists and
I said,
well,
you never know,
maybe this is just a mistake,
so let's hold off.
And then while I was about half an hour
later while I was trying to get into my,
I used this ad words account that's
linked to google.
I don't run ads on my videos but I need
the adwords account because it helps me
add some little gadgets to the videos
that I wouldn't otherwise be able to.
And I was.
I was playing with that.
The system came back online.
I thought,
well that's interesting and lots of
people that emailed me and twittered me
and some people within Google and some
people elsewhere and they were doing
whatever they were going to do to help
me get all this material back up and
running.
And so something worked.
My suspicions are that what worked was
the publicity now.
So,
but maybe not,
you know,
it's very weird being in this situation
because there has been a number of
recent episodes where these larger
companies,
facebook,
Google Patrion.
Not that it's a massive company,
but it's starting to become reasonably
significant,
have decided on rather arbitrary grounds
to shut down their users.
And this is very ominous to me,
partly because we've,
we've turned our communications over to
very large systems or very large systems
have emerged to mediate our
communication,
right?
I mean there's lots of benefit to it so
you don't want to get too cynical about
it,
but we're blind with regards to the
policies that regulate the,
the,
the actions,
the regulatory actions of these large
organizations.
And that's really a bad thing.
And something else has even more
ominous,
really ominous,
you know,
it's highly probable that we're going to
build political algorithms into our
artificial intelligence and this sort of
thing will be regulated by machines that
no one understands and that's a really
bad idea and that's a really likely
possibility.
So anyways,
I was all confused about this.
I thought Jesus,
maybe I flew off the handle,
you know,
because I was sort of was stressful man,
because I have like 150,000
emails in that account.
Like that's a lot of emails and it's all
my correspondence for the last 10 years,
you know,
so it's an archive as well as an ongoing
email system.
I have a commercial email system that I
just set up three weeks ago with like
six different email addresses now to try
to organize my correspondent so I wasn't
completely unable to communicate but my
was gone and that's a bloody disaster
because like I've got things scheduled
out forever and I don't remember what
they are.
I can't even remember what I'm doing in
a day so much less than a month.
But I thought maybe I flew off the
handle and I was worried that I
contacted the journalists too soon and
you know.
But anyways,
it all worked out.
So then what happened?
Well,
just as I was coming to this lecture,
I stepped outside and there was little
package outside.
Luckily it wasn't a bomb and there was
an here's a package outside.
Nice little packages.
We look,
my wife and I looked inside it and there
was a couple of bottles of wine in
there.
So that was nice.
And there was a little note and so I'm
going to read you the little note
because it's actually pretty
interesting.
So.
So this person said that they had
finally tackled the self authoring
suite,
so they seem to be happy about that,
but that's not so interesting except
peripherally.
A friend on twitter has contact with
Google engineers.
She said,
quote,
I spoke with some friends inside Google
who offered to help and I did get
contacted by quite a few people at
Google who said that they had been
watching my lectures and so on and we're
happy about what I was doing.
Anyways,
I spoke with some friends inside Google
who offered to help,
but they suggest he set up a backup
plan.
The teams are feeling significant
pressure from advocacy groups and quote,
I have at least four Google engineers
who offered to speak up on his behalf,
but they know the team dynamics and
unfortunately especially youtube is an
sjw cesspool.
I hope this information is useful to
you.
It's like,
yeah,
it's kind of useful.
Alright,
so that was,
that was part of what happened today.
And so anyways,
I still don't really understand it
right,
because I don't know why it got shut
down and I don't know if anything I did
got it turned back on and I don't know
the reasons for it.
And that's also rather ominous.
It seems to me that when I was thinking
it through and was that.
No,
I have a fairly,
what would you call it?
Respectable Youtube following and I
don't know if you necessarily call it
respectable.
It's fairly large youtube following and
it seems to me that it would have been
appropriate for Google if they were
going to shut down my account to tell me
why I would think and also maybe look me
up maybe especially after I emailed them
and then maybe not to have emailed me
back and said,
no,
we're not going to reinstate you,
but we're not going to tell you any
reasons that they didn't say.
They wouldn't tell me any reasons.
They just didn't tell me any reasons.
And then it also seems very strange to
me that it just all of a sudden went
back on after two hours and so well.
So I don't know what to make of that.
Maybe more information will come to
light over the next few days.
I hope that I didn't jump the gun,
but it's very,
very peculiar set of circumstances.
I thought it was kind of amusing
actually,
that the video that they stopped me from
posting today was the last Biblical
lecture.
You wouldn't necessarily think that that
would be the sort of thing that people
would want to stop from being posted.
But um,
we're in very,
very strange times.
So that was my adventure for today.
And so I didn't,
you know,
I hate speakers who apologized to the
crowd before they talk to them because,
you know,
if you're speaking to people and they
put all this effort into coming,
then you shouldn't tell them what a
sorry and useless creature you are
before you talk to them,
you know,
and asked for their forbearance and
forgiveness.
It's like,
it's a little,
you're a little late for that,
but I'm still gonna do that a little bit
today because I wanted to spend all day
preparing this lecture.
I mean,
I've prepared it a lot before hand,
but that rattled me up a lot and so I
didn't prepare as much as I could have.
Anyways.
We'll stumble forward and see how it
goes.
I,
I'm,
I'm reasonably familiar with the stories
now and so onward and upward.
So I'm going to reiterate this,
you know,
I've learned something.
I have this idea that it would be a good
idea for young people and older people,
citizens of the West,
let's say,
to learn more about their culture and
their civilization,
right?
Because it's a great civilization and
it's,
it's taken a lot of work to put
together,
but I don't think that we really know.
I mean I know a fair bit about it,
although I wouldn't consider myself
nearly as educated as a person should
be,
but I'm not too badly educated and.
But I tell ya,
going through these biblical lectures
verse by verse just makes me even more
aware of how unbelievably ignorant I am,
you know,
and partly for two reasons.
One is because I've been using this
bible hub dotcom place and I think I
told you last week,
but I wanted to reiterate it because
it's important.
It's so interesting the way that they've
set it up because you can go through the
biblical stories verse by verse and then
for each verse there's a whole small
font page of commentary from multiple
sources and so you know,
not only is the Bible hybrid hyperlinked
in the way that I discussed in the first
lecture with all the verses referring to
not all the other verses but lots of
them,
but it's,
and it's got its tendrils out into
literature,
you know,
direct commentaries on the text,
but also all the,
all the literature that's been
influenced by it.
So it's,
it's,
it's an unbelievably central and text
and
it's so interesting to read a book where
every sentence has been commented on
what really in volumes and then just to
get a sense of that volume of material.
You know,
how much power brain power there's been
put into this.
And,
and to also understand how bloody
ignorant,
like I'm so ignorant about this.
There's all this work and it seems that
we've left at to decay in the dust and
it's a big mistake,
man.
It's a big mistake because the people
who were writing these commentaries
like,
you know,
a lot of it's from the 14th and 15th and
16th century.
It's kind of archaic and it's,
and it's,
some of it's outdated and some of it you
wouldn't agree with,
but if you read all the commentaries
side by side,
you know,
you get a pretty good blast of wisdom
coming at you.
And like the thing about wisdom is it
stops you from running face first into
walls.
You know,
it's not just there to,
to so that you can talk to people at
parties about what university you
graduated from.
You know,
and it's there because the information
is unbelievably useful.
You know,
one of the things that I realized that I
want to return to tonight because I've
been thinking a lot about this idea of
the arc.
You know,
and I think I mentioned to you last week
that I'd figured out that there's this
idea that noah was perfect in his
generations and that meant that he has
said his family in order.
It wasn't just him,
but he had said his family in order and
because of that,
when,
when the catastrophe came,
like it comes to everyone,
he was able to withstand it because he
had the support of the people who were
near and dear to him.
And that's really important when things
come along to lay you low,
like if you're alone and in the flood
comes,
it's like man,
goodbye to you.
If you've got 10 or 15 people supporting
you in a tight network,
you know,
and,
and you're,
you're interrelationships with them are
pristine and you can tell them the truth
and they can tell the truth back to you.
It's possible that you might be able to
find that thin way that will preserve
you.
When,
when,
when you know the terrible things come
knocking at your door.
And so there's this idea of the arc is
very,
very concrete in Noah.
It's actually a structure that that he
inhabits.
You know,
what's a concretized almost like a
child's story,
and,
and I'm not being cynical about that
because there are some bloody brilliant
child children's stories,
but you know,
it's really concretized,
but then Abraham comes along and instead
of an arc,
there's a covenant right now,
it says in the story of Noah,
that Noah walked with God and,
and of course Abraham,
it isn't clear exactly these walking
with God or before God,
which we'll get into later,
but you see,
I see this as part of the increasing
psycho psychology,
ization of the sacred ideas that were
acted out by archaic people.
So first of all,
it's concretized in the form of a ship
that actually sustains you when the
floods come,
right?
It's,
it's very concrete imagery,
the sort of thing you might see in a
movie.
But then with Abraham,
it turns into a psychological covenant
in some sense.
It's like a contractual agreement.
Now it's a country.
It's a contractual agreement between
Abraham and God,
but that doesn't really matter that.
I mean,
obviously it matters,
but it's only,
it's only half of what's important about
that.
The other half is that it's a contract
and you know,
one of the things that you do with your
ideal,
let's say as you establish a contract
with it and you also establish a social
contract with other people,
right?
That's what keeps society organized and
so there's this idea that emerges in the
Abraham stories have a sacred contract
and that has the same function as the
arc and what it does because what
happens in Abraham and we'll see more of
this today is that he,
you know,
God tells him to go forward into the
world and we've talked about that last
week and he does that.
He encounters famine and he encounters
tyranny and he encounters powerful
people who want to take from him.
What is his.
I mean,
God sends him out in the world,
but it's not like he has an easy ride of
it.
It isn't easy at all.
It's as hard as it can be,
but there's this consistent emphasis in
the text and I think it's something
really worth attending to that.
If you maintain your contract,
which and that has,
that has to do with honesty and trust
and truth and all of those things.
If you maintain your contract,
then you have a good possibility,
the best possible possibility of making
your way through the catastrophe and the
chaos and the.
I don't want to be naive about this.
You know,
when I read young and I started to
understand the idea of the hero
archetype,
you know the idea that the human being
is a,
is a force,
a logos forest that can stand up against
chaos and catastrophe and tragedy and
evil and prevail.
I never did think that that meant that
if you did stand up and tell the truth,
that you would necessarily prevail,
right?
It's not,
it's not.
It's not a magic trick.
It's your best bet.
That's the thing.
You don't have a better option.
And so,
and that's what's.
That's what that I see the idea is
emerging in the abrahamic texts.
It's like people are figuring this out.
That would be progressive revelation.
That's one way of thinking about it and
you can think about that religious
terms,
but you can also think about it as
humanity consulting itself,
right?
Each individual talking to themselves,
which is what we do when we,
when we think and each individual
communicating with every other
individual and gathering a body of
wisdom that helps people or orient
themselves in the toughest conditions
and it's an incremental process and I
think that I really do believe that
that's speaking purely secularly.
I do believe that that's what manifests
itself in the biblical stories,
right?
It's the dawning enlightenment of
mankind,
something like that.
As we start to understand the principles
by which we have to live in order to
orient ourselves properly in the world.
So and I also do believe,
and this is,
this is the thing that's the unspoken
question,
is like you don't.
You don't have any idea how rich and
fulfilling your life could be despite
its tragedy and limitation.
If you stop doing the things that you
know to be wrong.
It's a really grand experiment and one
of the things that God tells Abraham
constantly as as the story progresses,
especially every time Abraham makes the
sacrifice,
God says,
walk with me and be perfect at something
like that,
and and so the injunction is well,
aim,
high established this relationship with
the highest thing that you can conceive
of which you might as well do that
because,
well,
what are you going to do?
Establish a relationship with the most
mediocre thing you can conceive of or
you're going to establish a relationship
with the lowest thing you can conceive
of.
People do that and I wouldn't recommend
it.
It's a really bad thing and there's a
lot of pain associated with that and
maybe you know,
there's the,
there's pain that can expand into a
world destroying forests down that route
and there's absolutely no doubt about
that.
So what is there something superstitious
and foolish about attempting to
establish a contractual relationship
with the source of all being?
I mean,
I,
I just don't see that as a,
as an erroneous conception and you know,
it's not necessary perhaps to get lost
in the details.
We can argue forever about what God
might or might not be,
but we could at least say that the
concept of God is an embodiment of
humanities,
highest ideal,
right?
We could at least agree on that.
And then you might say,
well,
is that real?
And the first thing I would say about
that is there's a lot of things about
the world we don't understand.
And the second thing I would say is it
depends bloody well on what you mean by
real,
that's for sure.
And that turns out to be a very
complicated question.
So.
Okay,
so we left Abraham,
remember at the end last time he had
just gone off to fight a bunch of kings
and get his nephew back,
which seemed to be a pretty courageous
act.
And so that brought a story to an end.
And it's interesting.
I think what happens in the narrative is
that there's a story.
So Abraham is somewhere and he goes
somewhere else,
right?
That's the story.
And he has adventures along the way and
those adventures are usually the typical
kind of adventure,
which is a rift in the structure of the
story.
And exposure to a kind of chaos and
novelty and then a reconstitution of
the,
of the motive being.
So that's classic classic story,
right?
You are somewhere.
You're a certain way,
you're moving forward.
Something happens that you don't expect.
It blows you into pieces.
It introduces chaos,
right?
You,
you face the dragon,
you get the gold,
or maybe the bloody thing eats you in.
The story is over and then and then you
get to where you're going.
But then the question is,
well,
what happens when you get to where
you're going?
And that's a really important issue
because one of the things that happens
to people all the time in their life is
that they get to where they're going and
then they don't know what to do,
right?
So for example,
you graduate from university,
it's like,
okay,
story over.
Who are you now?
Who are you the next day?
And so,
so what happens is when you succeed,
then there's the success crisis.
And the success crisis is,
well,
I've run this story to its end.
Now what?
And that's exactly what happens in,
in the abrahamic stories.
And there are punctuated by a period of
contemplation and sacrifice,
so every time an abrahamic story comes
to its end,
then Abraham makes another sacrifice and
commune with God,
and then he figures out what to do next
and that seems,
that seems right.
It seems psychologically right,
because what you should do when your
story comes to an end,
when you've achieved what it is that you
want to achieve or perhaps when you're
in terribly dire straights,
but we won't talk about that at the
moment.
When you've achieved what you need to
achieve.
Then the next question is,
okay,
well now I'm that person or I have that
character.
What?
What do I need to do next?
And some of that is always,
well,
what do I need to give up now?
What do I need to let go of so I can
move to the next plateau?
Right?
Assuming that your life is a hopefully a
sequence of upward moving,
what would you call them?
It's like Sisyphus,
except you're actually,
each time you climb up the mountain,
you get a little higher on the mountain
at something like that.
So it says office with an optimistic
bent and,
and,
and maybe if you push the rock up the
mountain properly and let it roll down
then.
And if you do that right,
then it's okay.
Every time you roll it back up,
it's,
it's better in some sense.
And I don't think that's unrealistic
either.
And so Abraham goes and rescues his
nephew from this tyrannical kings that's
very brave and he doesn't take any
reward for it because as far as he's
concerned,
it's just a manifestation of the right
thing.
And then he has another vision after
these things.
That's the battle of the word of the
Lord came unto Abraham in a vision
saying,
fear not Abraham.
I'm the shield and I exceeding great
reward.
And Abraham said,
Lord God,
what will give me seeing I go childless
and the steward of my house is this
Eliezer of Damascus.
Abraham said,
behold to me,
that was given no seed and lo,
no one born,
one,
one born in my host is mine.
Air and behold,
the word of the Lord came to him saying,
this shall not be nine heir,
but he that shall come forth out of own
own,
own bowels shall be done here,
and he brought him forth abroad and he
said,
now look to heaven and tell the stars if
you're able to number the number of
them,
and he said unto him,
so shall thy seed be and neighbor and
believed in the Lord,
and he counted it to him for
righteousness,
and he said unto him,
I am the Lord that brought the out of
the Chaldees to give this land to you to
inherit it.
And he said,
Lord God,
whereby shall I know that I shall
inherit it?
And then he does this sacrifice.
Take me an effort,
a heifer,
three years old and the sheep goat and a
ram and a turtle,
dove and a young pigeon,
and then God comes down and well,
Abraham goes into a trance.
That's what it appears to be in the
story and has a great terror.
And then God appears to him and I'll
just review this commentary again.
This is from Joseph Benson and when the
sun was going down,
that's about the time when you wash up
for the evening and he's,
he's,
he's praying and waiting towards evening
a deep sleep fell upon Abraham,
not a common sleep through weariness or
carelessness,
but a divine ecstasy that being wholly
taken off from things sensible he might
be wholly taken up with a contemplation
of things spiritual,
very strange,
very,
very strange series of interpretations
because it does seem that what happens
to Abraham that he falls into some sort
of revelatory trance.
And so,
um,
when,
uh,
as I've taken some pains to explain,
we don't really understand such things
and,
and we can't rule out their existence
because there's too much evidence that
they do in fact occur.
Perhaps it's a technology that we no
longer possess.
That's one possibility.
Perhaps we no longer know how to access
these sorts of states of consciousness.
It's certainly possible and lower horror
of great darkness fell upon him.
This was designed to strike all upon
this spirit of Abraham and to possess
them with holy reverence.
Holy fear prepares the soul for holy
joy.
God humbles first and then lifts,
lifts up.
Yeah,
well I think that's right too.
Like you know,
one of the experiences I've had in my
life fairly commonly in a variety of
different ways,
and this is especially true when I was
paying a lot of attention to my dreams,
which I did for about 15 years.
I guess something like that now.
And then I would feel like I learned
some things and had sort of consolidated
them and then before I went to sleep I
think,
okay,
I'm ready to learn something else.
It's like,
and it didn't say that without
trepidation and usually because usually
when you learn something,
you know it's not that pleasant because
you usually learn something about why
you're wrong and the deeper the thing
that you learn,
the more you learn about why you're
wrong and there's a death that's
associated with that because then you
have to let that part of you that's
wrong,
die.
And that's,
that's really,
that's the sacrifice,
right?
And so you have to make a sacrifice.
You have to be willing to make a
sacrifice before you're going to learn
something and the.
And perhaps your,
what you'll learn is in proportion to
your willingness to make a sacrifice,
and I really do believe that.
I do believe that as well because I also
think that if you commit to something
that means that you don't do a bunch of
other things.
Right.
So that's the sacrifice of all those
other things.
You commit to it and you set your sights
on it.
If you really commit to it and you get
the sacrifice right,
so to speak,
then the probability that that thing
will be successful vastly increases.
And I think that that's also not a naive
or or a naive way of thinking or a
foolish way of thinking.
I,
my experience has been that that's the
case.
And so back to the dream.
I mean,
I do think that we learn in trepidation
and that most of the time,
if,
if you have to be laid low before the
new revelation can make itself
manifest.
And I think that's also what happens to
people often in psychedelic experiences
when they have a bad trip,
is they don't get through the bad part
of it.
And maybe that's because there's so much
mess in their lives now I'm speculating,
but it's informed speculation.
There's so much mess in their lives that
the altered state of consciousness makes
manifest that it's like a little trip
through hell and,
but the mess is so complete and
comprehensive and all pervading that
there's no way they can get through it.
Now,
if they could get through it and started
to sort those things out,
then you know,
there would be perhaps a,
what would you call it,
a competent Satori positive revelation
at the end.
But the first thing is if you want to
learn something is that you're going to
encounter.
Well,
you have to figure out what's wrong
before you.
You can figure out what wisdom you need
next to guide yourself.
And that's no laughing matter.
Right?
And,
um,
so I think that that's what,
that's what this refers to.
I think that's the sort of psychological
experience that,
that refers to.
I also think we built this a little bit
into this,
into the future authoring program.
You know,
I read this really cool paper once
reviewed by this guy named Jeffrey Gray.
Jeffrey Gray wrote a book called the
neuropsychology of anxiety man,
and that is a great book.
It is impossible to read.
It took me really.
It took me like six months to read it
and the reason for that is that he
reviewed about 3000 papers and they're
all neurological papers and and and
heavy psychological slash biological
papers.
He actually read them all and he
understood them and synthesize them and
then he wrote this book about the
synthesis and so and he's very very
careful with this terminology and so to
read the book you have to understand
brain anatomy and you have to understand
neuro,
neuro pharmacology and you have to end
understand animal behavior.
The whole literature on animal behavior
knocked whole whopping dose of human
psychology and cybernetics.
It's like it's a vicious book,
but you really learn something when you
read it.
If you go through it by bit like it's
had an overwhelming influence on
psychology even among people who haven't
read it,
which is most of the people who cite it
by the way and so,
but he said he.
He outlined this real cool study.
Maybe it was a sequence of studies about
how to motivate rats and rats are a lot
like us on,
you know,
in,
in positive and negative ways and uh,
you know,
biochemically and,
and,
uh,
psycho pharmacologically,
they're very,
very similar and they have very complex
social environments and you know,
they have hierarchies and they play and
they laugh.
Jaak Panksepp,
Jaak Panksepp found out that routes
laugh.
If you tickle them,
you can tickle them with like the end of
a pencil eraser,
but you can hear them laughing because
they laugh ultrasonically like that.
So you have to record it and then slow
it down and then you can hear them
giggling away when you take a lump.
So,
so which is,
you know,
you think,
oh,
in I spend $50,000
on his study demonstrating that rats
laugh and you think,
well,
wait a second,
wait a second.
That's a major league study.
You know,
because he's outlined a eluded circuit
that's a place circuit.
And Jaak Panksepp discovered the play
circuit had mammals.
That's a bloody big deal.
You know,
if you get that by like rubbing rats
with a pencil eraser.
Well good for you.
So anyways,
so great.
Talked a lot about how to motivate a rat
and you might've heard about bf skinner,
you know,
he used food pellets to motivate his
rats,
but what you don't know about skinner is
that those rats were starved to three
quarters of their normal body weight.
So they would,
they would work for food and so
skinner's routes were kind of
oversimplified,
but you can get rats to work for food.
They don't have to be that hungry.
You can get them to work for food and
they'll do all sorts of things.
They'll press leavers and they'll open
our open doors and they'll solve
problems and you know,
they'll do all sorts of things.
And one of the things you can do to kind
of measure how much the rat is motivated
is,
let's say you've run them through a maze
and he knows there's some food at the
end of the maze.
You can tie a little spring to his tail
and see how hard he polls.
When you open the door to the maze,
so that's because that's how much prep
work the route is willing to do so you
can measure that or you can see fast,
he skitters down the maze and you can
get an estimate about the rats
motivation and so then you might say,
well how motivated is a hungry rat?
And the answer would be depends on how
hungry is,
but there's another answer.
It also depends on what's chasing him
when he was going after the food.
So if you have a rat and you have food
over here and you walked in,
some cat older rats hate cat odor and
it's innate.
They never have to see or smell acat to
be absolutely petrified by cat odor.
And so if you walked in some cat odor
and then opened the door,
that rat will zoom to that food a lot
faster than it will if it's just hungry.
So a rat running away from something
that it doesn't want toward.
Something that it does want is a very
motivated rat.
And so one of the things we did with the
future authoring program that's Germane
to this idea of terror,
because there's a business idea in the
Old Testament,
the fear of God is the beginning of
wisdom and it's a pretty harsh idea,
but,
but there's something really useful
about it because one of the things you
see with people all the time is that
there maybe they're trying to stumble
forward towards their ideal as poorly
defined as it might be,
but then they're afraid,
right?
They're afraid about what they might
encounter and that stops them because
fear does stop people.
It freezes you like a prey on them.
And so people move ahead,
but then they get afraid and then they
start moving ahead.
And so,
and that's not so good because negative
emotion is a really powerful motivator.
So we're more motivated by negative
emotion than positive emotion,
quantitatively speaking,
quantitative,
quantitatively speaking.
You can measure that.
And that's,
I think because we can only be so happy,
but we can really be suffering and it,
you know,
so we have to pay more attention to the
negative.
And that's bad because the negative can
stop you.
And then my clinical practice,
I often talk to people who are trying to
make a difficult life decision and they
are weighing out the costs and the
benefits of making the life decision,
you know,
and one of the things I always talk to
them about is wait a second,
that's an incomplete analysis.
You have to weigh out the benefits and
the costs of doing this and you have to
weigh out the costs and benefits of not
doing that,
not doing it.
And that's not the same as the zero that
you assume that you're starting with,
right?
Because to not make a decision also has
a cost and sometimes the cost of not
making a decision is far worse than the
cost of making a decision,
even if the decision is risky.
And so one of the things you can derive
from that,
and this is very useful,
I think,
is that
this is also why it's so useful to
contemplate your mortality,
so to speak,
as you're screwed,
no matter what you do,
you know,
and that actually frees you,
is that you,
you,
you have power,
hey that has catastrophes.
And you have path b that has
catastrophes and you don't get to have
the no catastrophe path,
but you get to pick which one.
And that's really something because if
you know that there's terrible risk
associated with everything that you do
and don't do,
then you can afford to take some risks
because you're not,
you know,
this is all within the arc metaphor.
I'm still making the case that despite
the fact that your life is essentially
catastrophic,
you can,
you can make a covenant with the highest
ideal and that will take you through it
the best way possible.
I'm,
I'm still making that case.
So.
So then you think,
okay,
well I'm trying to make this decision,
I'm going to go try to do something
difficult and isn't that terrifying?
And then you think,
yeah,
but wait a minute,
what's really terrifying is not doing
it,
and then you think about the cost of not
doing it.
So in the future authoring program,
we have people do this little meditative
exercise,
which is,
okay,
just think about your insufficiencies by
your own definition,
right?
The way that you don't do what you know
you should do about the things that you
do that you shouldn't do,
that you know you shouldn't do beyond a
shadow of a doubt,
right?
There's some things like that and that
that's bad habits and poor aim and all
of resentment and hatred and aggression
and unresolved conflicts and all those
things that are demanding you and
warping you and then think,
okay,
those things get the upper hand man,
they get the upper hand and they take
you the worst possible place you could
go in the next three to five years.
What exactly does that look like?
And so you schedule that out and you
think,
hey,
I don't want to go there.
And so the next time that attempt
Taishan comes up,
you think,
well,
it'd be a lot better for me if I didn't
succumb to this temptation.
It's like,
that's Kinda weak.
You'd look a little better if you didn't
eat like a cheese cake a day or
something like that.
You know,
that's something,
but it's not the same as,
um,
I'm going to have diabetes and I'm going
to lose my damn leg and in,
in five years if I don't get my eating
under control,
that's motivating.
And so then the temptation comes along
and you think,
oh,
how about no,
seriously how?
No,
not just because a higher good would be
obtained if I avoided it,
but because of a terrible catastrophe
would be averted if I didn't.
And so well.
So you want to get your fear behind you,
right?
You want to get it behind you where it's
pushing you forward instead of in front
of you where it's stopping you and you
get your fear behind you,
pushing you forward by actually thinking
through the consequences of not putting
your life together.
And the least of those is that you waste
it.
And suffer right,
because you're going to suffer anyways,
man,
so you wasted and suffer.
That's a bad deal because maybe if
you're going to suffer,
you could at least do something knowable
and Glorious and upright and powerful
and honorable and admirable and helpful
and difficult.
You know,
that's just so much better.
And maybe that's good enough so that you
think,
hey,
you know,
little suffering,
it's basically worth it.
At least it's a way forward.
You know,
at least it's a way forward.
And he said unto Abraham,
know of assurity that thy seed shall be
a stranger in a land that is not theirs.
And she'll serve those people and
they'll flick them for 400 years.
God,
he's hedging his bets here a lot,
right?
He says to Abraham,
will go out into the world,
and then he confronts him with a famine
and he confronts him with a tyranny and
with powerful people.
He wants to take his wife and then he
loses his nephew and he has a fight with
nanny,
has to go fight a war and now you know
he's reconstituting this covenant.
God says,
yeah,
you're going to have a nation is going
to come from you,
but they're going to be slaves to
tyrants for like 400 years is like,
he's not a great salesman.
Exactly.
But,
but the thing about it is that the thing
that I like about it is that it's
realistic.
You know,
and you gotta think too,
because who knows why it is that the
Bible exists or why people wrote it,
but you know,
if they're gonna sell you something.
I don't know if this is the way to do
it,
you know,
because unless you're a salesman who is
sophisticated beyond belief because
you'd think that if it was just a matter
of controlling the masses,
let's say,
which is one St Marxist interpretation
of religion or,
or providing people with a primitive
defense against death anxiety,
which is essentially the Freudian
interpretation that you'd kind of make
the deals that got cut with Abraham a
little more on the positive and polished
side.
Instead of making them a realistic offer
constantly like they are.
And that that's also that.
That part of the reason I think it is
reasonable to treat the Bible as
literature.
It's,
it's more than literature.
It's something other than literature,
but you can treat it as literature and I
think the reason that you can treat it
as literature is because the characters
are all complex,
including the character of God himself
is complex and sophisticated.
It's not one sided and it's paradoxical
and incomprehensible at times,
but I think good literature is like that
because you know true art.
Here's something about true art.
This is something I learned from young.
It's so smart.
He was so smart.
So imagine that you inhabit the land
that you know conceptually and
practically,
and then imagine outside of that,
there's that massive space of things
that you don't know,
and even outside of that,
there's this space of things that no one
knows,
right?
So it's the known territory surrounded
by the unknown.
That's the canonical architectural
landscape and the unknown manifests
itself to you and that's where new
knowledge comes from.
But the question is how is that
knowledge generated?
And it doesn't just leap from completely
unknown to completely articulated in one
move,
that isn't how it happens.
It has to pass through stages of
analysis before it becomes articulable.
And the first stage of analysis,
as far as I can tell is that you act it
out.
So if something really surprises you,
the first way that you react to it,
your category is actually embodied.
You'd like this,
that that's your first category.
It's not conceptual at all.
It's embodied.
And then maybe you start to like you're
at home at night and something startled,
senior freeze and then it's dark and
then your imagination populates the
darkness with whatever might be making
the noise.
And that's the sequence.
It's like embodied response,
imaginative representation,
exploration,
articulation.
That's how information moves from the
unknown to the known.
And artists are the people who stand on
that images stick frontier and they and
they put themselves out into the unknown
and they and they,
they take a piece of it and they and
they transform it into some mythological
image and they don't know what they're
doing exactly because they're guided by
their intuition.
If they're real artists,
otherwise they're just propagandists.
They have to be contending with
something they don't understand and what
they do is they make it more
understandable,
you know,
and,
and then people gays it,
those artworks or this or they listened
to the stories and then they start to
become informed by them,
but they don't know how or why.
I was at the Modern Art Museum Museum of
art and in New York,
I'm afraid.
I don't remember which one
unfortunately,
but I was in this amazing room,
you know,
it had all these
priceless paintings from the,
from the late renaissance hanging in it,
you know,
each painting worth who knows a billion
dollars.
Maybe they're priceless painting.
So the room was,
it's a shrine and it was full of people
from all over the world who are looking
at these paintings.
You think,
well,
what the hell are these people doing
coming to this room looking at these
paintings,
what are,
what are they up to?
One of them was a painting of the
assumption of Mary,
right?
Brilliantly composed.
And there was all these people looking
at it and I thought,
what are they doing?
They don't know what that means.
Sick.
Why are they looking at that painting?
Why is it in this room?
Why does it cost a billion dollars?
Why is that painting worth so much?
And the answer to that is,
well,
we don't really know like it happened to
their,
their sacred objects in some sense.
And we gaze at the in ignorance and
wonder.
And the reason for that is that the
unknown shines through the madness and
partially articulated form.
And so,
well
that's the role of art.
And that's the role of artists
in all
real artists.
Real artists are contending with
unknown,
right?
And they're possessed by it.
They have a personality trait,
openness that makes them do that.
They can't even help it.
And I've had lots of creative people in
my clinical practice.
I can tell you the worst thing for
creative people is to not be creative
because they just die.
And it,
because it's,
it's,
it's like maybe you're a tree with a few
major branches,
you know,
that's your personality.
So if you're extroverted,
man,
you can't be cut off from people because
you just wither and if you're agreeable,
you have to be an intimate relationship
or you die,
you know,
and if you're conscientious man and
you're unemployed,
you're just going to eat yourself up
because you have to have a duty and you
have to carry a load because just can't
stand it otherwise and open.
People have to be creative.
They have to be because otherwise they
die.
They don't have any vitality,
and so they're cursed with the necessity
of putting a foot out into the unknown
and making sense of it,
and then they're also cursed with
necessity of trying to make a living
while they're doing that,
which they can't because you can't.
It's almost impossible to monetize
creative creative action.
As many of you who are creative will no
doubt find out.
It's very,
very frustrating.
It's not that creative action is without
value,
right?
Because the creative people are
entrepreneurs and the creative people,
revitalized cities,
and the creative people make things
magnificent and beautiful.
You think about what's happened in
Europe over the last thousand years,
say 2000 years,
this amazing,
unbelievable collaboration to make
things so beautiful that they're their
jaw dropping when you walk into them and
you think about the economic value of
that,
right?
I mean,
I think it's.
It's either France or Spain that's the
most visited country in the world.
It's one of those two.
I think there's more tourists in France
than there are people most of the time
and part of the reason for that is it's
just so damn beautiful.
You just can't stand it and you think,
what's the economic value of that?
It's absolutely incalculable,
and what's interesting too is that you
build out beauty in and then the farther
away you get from it in time,
the more valuable it becomes,
right?
Instead of decaying,
it has exactly the opposite effect.
It's value magnifies.
And one of the things that I'm deeply
ashamed of as a Canadian is that our
sense of beauty is so underdeveloped
were so primitive print.
It's not even primitive.
That's the wrong word because I know
what it is.
It's,
it's,
it's second rate,
it's second rate.
At least it's terror too because people
are afraid of beauty,
but the idea that art is the
conservatives really have a problem with
this in particular because conservative
people tend to want to be that creative
and Mr.
Mr.
by temperament.
It's a mystery to me because they should
be concerned with economic development
and beauty is so unbelievably crucial to
economic development and just yells out
at you.
You know,
so anyway,
so that's what artists are doing.
And so one of the things I would say is
by a damn piece of art,
you know,
find one that really speaks to you and
buy a piece of art because you invite
that into your life and it's,
it's an lookout if you do it,
if it's a real piece of art because
you'll also get a little introduction to
the artist and then that'll seep into
your life and that'll change things like
mad,
but it's really,
it's unbelievably worth it because it
opens your eyes to the domain of the
transcendent.
That's the right way of thinking about
our real piece of art is a window into
the transcendent and that's what it is,
and you need that in your life because
your finite and limited and bounded
right by your ignorance and your lack of
knowing and unless you can make a
connection to the transcendent,
then you don't have the strength to
prevail and that's part of the covenant.
That's part of the covenant with God and
you can see that because you look at
these magnificent cathedrals that our
civilization built over the centuries,
you know,
some of those,
they're still building the Sangre de
Familia in Barcelona,
right?
And it's an amazing building.
I think it's going to take them like 300
years to build that.
You know,
people in the Middle Ages,
they'd start building a cathedral and
they think,
oh,
it won't be done this in 300 years.
You know,
imagine the vision that it took to
invest in something like that.
We look at quarterly reports,
we can think 300 years into the future
to build something of that kind of
remarkable,
remarkable what those cathedrals are.
So they're perfect.
They're trees first,
right there,
a forest,
right,
the gothic cathedrals there,
there are forest and the sun is shining
through the branches.
That's the stain glass and they're the
perfect balance of light and structure
because they're representing something
about the proper structure of being
which is something like the proper
balance between light and structure and
they represent like the sacred tragedy
of mankind.
That's why they're in the shape of a
cross and they're open to the sky.
That's why they have a dome and they're
full of gold so that it glitters because
that's like the city of God.
You know,
and and,
and you,
you can see that that integral to our
culture is the idea that beauty is one
pathway towards God and it's.
And it's saying if you can't find
another pathway,
then why don't you use beauty?
I'm sure most of you do that with music
because music is the one thing that
modern people can't be cynical about.
Thank God for that and being fascinated
by music.
Because of that,
it speaks meaning to people,
right?
Even nihilistic,
punk rockers are so damn engaged with
their music that they can hardly stand
it and you can knock on them and say,
look,
you know,
you're having a transcendent religious
experience and they'll just tell you to
fuck off.
Got Cause.
That's what punk rock yourself to do.
But,
but that's still what's happening,
you know what I mean?
It's still what's happening.
So.
Okay.
So,
okay,
so I,
I got into all that because I was
talking about about the Bible as
literature,
you know,
and,
and trying to enter into layout because
we need in our culture to justify the
art.
And you have to.
I don't want to do that by talking about
high culture,
talking about something abstract and
evanescent that's the wrong way to go
about it.
This is vital.
You know,
one of the things that's really
interesting about the University of
Toronto is that the one side of the
campus where we are,
is beautiful,
medieval cathedral.
Another side is God awful factory and
you know,
and,
and that,
and the thing is the attitude towards
knowledge has paralleled that
architectural transformation.
You know,
at one point the humanities,
let's say we're a sacred endeavor and so
was the art of being educated in the
university and that's turned into like
mass factory and that's reflected in the
architecture.
This isn't accidental.
None of this happens.
None of this happens by random chance.
You know,
it's not like there's a conspiracy or
anything because there isn't,
but that doesn't mean that these things
aren't tangled together.
And the loss of beauty in the
universities is a catastrophe because
without that,
but there's no call to higher being,
you know,
you.
This is also why I've mentioned to
people that they should clean up their
rooms.
That's become quite the Internet meme,
but I'm really serious about it because
it's really hard to do that.
And I've been cleaning up my room by the
way,
for about four months now because my
life was thrown into such a catastrophe
and,
and also we were renovating and so.
But it isn't just that you clean it up,
you also make it beautiful and beauty.
It's really hard to make something
beautiful and it's really worthwhile.
And what's really cool is if you learn
to make something beautiful,
even one thing,
if you could just make one thing in your
life,
beautiful,
then you've established your
relationship with beauty and then you
can start to expand that relationship
with beauty out into,
into the world,
like into other elements of your life.
And that is so worthwhile.
It's just incredibly crazily worthwhile.
And that's an invitation to the divine.
You know what?
You have to be daring to do that.
And people are terrified of it.
People are terrified of color.
They paint their walls beige.
They're terrified of art.
They buy some mass produced thing
because they don't want anybody laughing
at them for their lack of taste.
And they would get laughed at because
they have no taste.
But you have to while it's right,
because what do you know,
right?
You have to develop it.
And so you're going to stumble along and
make mistakes to begin with and you're
going to show yourself.
Because if you buy who I think this is
pretty,
and you know,
somebody comes over and goes,
hey,
what's up with you?
It's kind of hard on yourself esteem,
but,
but it's the stuff you're stumbling
towards the right,
you're stumbling towards the Kingdom of
God.
That's what you're stumbling towards
when you try to make an aesthetic
decision and to put something in your
life that's beautiful and it's
unbelievably worthwhile to do that and
you have to steer clear of the frauds
and the con artists and all of that and
art is full of that of course,
because it's to distinguish between the
real thing and the fraud,
but.
But it's unbelievably worthwhile.
And so back to literature,
and I'm telling you this partly because
I've been thinking a lot about the
humanities and the arts and practically
speaking,
because I know that artistic types are
also entrepreneurial types of the same
personality types and so it's very much
worthwhile to make an economic and
practical case for this sort of thing.
He studied literature in the humanities
so that you can familiarize yourself
with the wisdom of our civilization.
Man,
you should do that because people have
been working on this thing for a long
time and it's rich beyond comparison.
So why wouldn't you do that?
And you teach yourself to read and you
teach yourself to speak,
and you teach yourself to think and you
teach yourself to communicate,
and I can tell you if you can read and
think and communicate,
you are absolutely 100 percent
unstoppable and that's another thing
that's so interesting about humanities
education that's at the core of the
university.
It's like there's nothing more
economically valuable than teaching
people how to articulate themselves and
communicate because they can identify
problems,
they can formulate solutions,
they can negotiate to consensus,
they can negotiate on their own behalf
or on the behalf of others.
It's like there's absolutely no downside
to it except that there's responsibility
that goes along with it,
but it doesn't matter because there's no
escape from responsibility.
You can either take it voluntarily or
you can take it in voluntarily.
Those are your options,
but there aren't any other options.
And so we need to understand the role of
art and literature and and stop thinking
about it as an option.
It's not an option.
What is it said,
man does not live by bread alone.
That's exactly right.
We live by,
but we live by literature.
We live by art and literally not
metaphorically.
We cannot live without it because life
is too dismal and tragic in the absence
of the sublime,
so and ourselves.
We have to be sharp so that we can
survive properly an orient the world
properly and not destroy things,
including ourselves and so and so back
to the Bible,
which I do think is a reasonable.
It's reasonably construed as a piece of
literature because it's deep and because
the people who wrote it had at least one
foot in the unknowable and they're
trying to communicate what they
experienced in the unknowable to make it
known,
and that's partly what we're trying to
do in this series and what you're trying
to do while you're listening and all of
that and so good for that,
and also that nation whom they shall
serve.
I will judge and afterward they will
come out with great substance.
There'll be a period of tyranny.
You know,
and there's a psychological truth to
that too.
One of the things I learned from reading
Nietzsche,
because you can learn a lot from reading
nature,
that's for sure.
He.
He talked about the Catholic Church.
You know,
Ninja is often construed as a great
critic of Christianity and and he
certainly was,
but he was no casual critic.
In fact,
I think he was the sort of critic that
you'd like to have as a friend because
he was the sort of critic that said,
well,
here's the great things you've done and
that you could keep doing.
Here's a bunch of really neat things
that you did that you really should stop
doing.
And he talked about the Catholic Church
and he said,
what the Catholic Church had done to the
European mind in particular was
discipline it.
So that over a period of a thousand
years,
$1,300,
1400 years,
there was this rule that there was a
conceptual structure within which you
had to interpret everything and what
that did was turn the European educated
you European mind into a systematized
thing,
cognitive entity,
and that once that systematizing
cognitive entity at been established,
then it could free itself from those
underlying disciplinary structures and
go off and do such things as produced
the scientific revolution,
for example,
which required a credible systematic
thinking.
And so Nisha had this really interesting
idea about freedom and he believed that
slavery was an intermediary between the
undeveloped the individual and the free
individual that you had to.
You had to submit yourself to some
intense disciplinary process for some
period of time in your life before you
could develop any true freedom.
And so you think maybe you want to learn
to play the piano.
It's like,
that's not going to be any fun for a
really long period of time,
right?
Because you're really bad at it and
there's a million things you have to
memorize and you have to stumble around.
Like,
uh,
well,
like an amateur,
and the same thing happens when kids
learn how to read and some of them never
get past that point and they never get
to the point where they can enjoy
reading,
but in order to put yourself together,
you have to put yourself in a vice and
allow yourself to be constricted and
mangled and by the thing that enslaves
you,
but the goal should be that as a
consequence of submitting to the
discipline that you become disciplined
and then once you become disciplined,
you can emerge from the disciplinary
structure as someone who's free.
And that's something that's very much
we're thinking about as well.
So that's illustrated conceptually in
this,
in this piece of literature,
let's say,
because what,
what the psychological meaning of what
God tells Abraham is that all people,
all people are subject.
I mean not equally.
Obviously all people are subject to the
tyranny that proceeds freedom and that
that ideas is repeated over and over in
the Old Testament.
It comes out most particularly in the
story of Moses,
right?
Because of course,
that's the story of movement from
tyranny.
Where do you go from a tyranny?
It's an absolute catastrophe.
You go from maturity into the desert.
You know where you starve.
That's harsh.
That's what happens in the story of
exodus,
and so that's so interesting too,
because what it means is that sometimes
if you're going to move up hill,
the first thing that happens is you move
downhill a lot,
and so if you want to escape from the
straits that bind you,
now you're not going to move forward and
go up.
You're gonna move forward and go down.
And that's another reason.
This is also something that you haven't
talked about a lot is that you know on
the road to enlightenment,
you encounter all the things that you
don't want to encounter first.
Like all the weaknesses of yourself,
all the realizations of the tyranny of
the world and the catastrophe of nature
and all of that.
And so you step out of your
encapsulation,
you're ignorant encapsulation and it's
immediate,
plummet into something that's a desert.
Let's say,
where everything is chaotic and where
you're wandering around without
direction.
A real catastrophe.
So it's,
you know,
because one of the things you might ask
yourself is that if enlightenment is
possible and why aren't people
enlightened?
Because if it was just a matter of going
from a good place to a better place,
it's like,
well man,
let's just get at it.
It's no,
it's no problem.
Right?
Why would we ever stop doing that?
But it seems not to be that it's that
you're here and that's not good and it's
unstable and you step out of it and it's
like down,
down to where you don't want to be,
and you have to contend with that and
then maybe you can start your struggle
upward.
And so Abraham,
God is telling Abraham this and he's
also telling him that it's okay.
It's rough though and now now shall go
to their fathers in peace,
though shall be burned in the good old
age.
But in the fourth generation,
they shall come hither again.
That's the Israelites,
the descendants of Abraham for the
iniquity of the Amorites is not yet
full.
God is going to leave the tyrants alone
until they've manifested their full
tyranny.
For reasons that we don't fully
understand and it came to pass that when
the sun went down,
it was dark.
Behold a smoking furnace and a burning
lamp that passed between the pieces.
All Albert Barnes set the oven of smoke
and lamp aflame symbolize the smoke of
destruction,
which we've already talked about.
This catastrophe of,
of the initial stages and the light of
salvation.
They're passing through the pieces of
the victims and probably consuming them
as an accepted sacrifice are the
ratification of the Covenant on the part
of God as the dividing and presenting of
them were on the part of April.
In the same day,
the Lord made a covenant with Abraham
Saying Unto Thy seed,
I've given this land from the river of
Egypt unto the Great River Euphrates.
Now Sarai,
Abram's wife Barum,
no children,
and she had a handmade and the Egyptian,
whose name was Hagar.
So this is a big catastrophe for
Abraham,
especially in those times,
and perhaps now as much.
Although perhaps people aren't as
conscious of it as they once were.
For Abraham,
without a biological son,
there was no.
There was no.
There was no vision forward into the
future,
you know,
and I mean we don't really know what
sort of time span over which these
archaic people thought,
but the medieval people,
we already said good thing 300 years
into the future without,
without batting an eye,
and these people who were,
who were concerned about their
descendants were obviously thinking
about existence in a way that wasn't
just focused on their immediate
existence.
Right?
They were thinking about while their
children and their grandchildren,
maybe their great grandchildren,
maybe the whole society that that
stemmed out from them and that's,
that's smart know.
One of the things I learned from piaget
at least in part,
was that his idea of the equilla braided
state,
which he thought about as partly part of
the biological basis of the idea of
moral progress.
It's something like that.
He was very,
very smart pig and we said that the
proper equilibrated state is one where
imagine you have a family,
you've got five people in it and you're
doing what you want in your,
in your family,
what's good for you,
but you're doing it in such a way so
that the other four members of your
family agree with what you do and that
it also facilitates them doing what they
want and what they should be doing,
and so it's a really tricky arrangement
because it isn't just for you.
It's for you in a way that's for them
and you can also see that that would be
something that would be a multiplier,
right?
Because if you have everyone working
voluntarily towards the same common
goal,
then you get a multiplying effect of
that and then you might think,
well,
it's not just you and your family.
It's you and your family today and next
week,
next month,
next year and 10 years from now.
So you have to take the time span into
account and then it should be you and
your family in a way that works well in
society.
And then it should work well now and
next week and next year,
and into the future.
It should be iterative,
agile,
right?
That's like sustainability.
It's something like the idea of
sustainability and that's,
that's I would say that's a reasonable
way of conceptualizing the holy city.
It's something like that.
If you're.
If you're trying to make it concrete,
it's like,
how should you live your life?
Well,
let's say you live your life in a manner
that justifies its limitation and
tragedy.
That's a good start.
But then let's say that it does that in
a way that also reduces the limitations
and suffering of the people that you
interact with and now and into the
future.
Well maybe there's a way to do that.
I mean a good negotiation does that,
right?
Because if you're negotiating with
someone like your wife for example,
what you want is for her to agree with
the negotiation.
And one of the things that Piaget said,
which I think was brilliant,
brilliant.
He said,
if you take an equilibrated system,
a family,
let's say,
and a discipline celebrated system.
So that would be one way.
Or let's say the father is a tyrant and
everyone is operating under his whip and
you put them in a head to head
competition.
The equilibrated system will outcompete
the disequilibrium system because the
enforcement cost is such that it will
slow the system down,
you know,
because you'll get resistances from the
people inside the system.
They'll work at the system will be
working at counter purposes to itself.
Plus there's enforcement costs and so a
tyranny can be to neil calibrated system
and I was really excited to encounter
that idea because when I encountered it
I was also trying to figure out if there
was some quantitative difference between
the system say of the Soviet Union in
Mao's China and the systems of the west
apart from just arbitrary world
interpretation as the postmodern
nihilists might have it.
If there is something fundamental at
stake in the terrible cold war that we
fought or if it was just a matter of
opinion,
you know,
when the pig Eddie and take was that.
Well roughly speaking is that the West
was Nicola braided system.
Not perfectly equilibrated,
but reasonably celebrated in that people
were essentially.
Even if they were slaves to some degree,
they were at least voluntary slaves
instead of involuntary slaves and that
that was better.
The system was actually technically
better and not just as a matter of
interpretation.
So that's a lovely thing to know and I
think it's a really,
really solid,
really,
really solid idea.
I haven't been able to,
you know,
put crowbars under that idea and lifted
up.
I think it's a good one.
So now Sarah Abraham's wife,
barum new children's.
So.
Okay,
back to children must one of what?
One of the things that's we're thinking
about with regards to reading these old
stories because we're so new.
We're very arrogant,
modern people,
a,
we look at these old stories and we
think,
ah,
we've transcended all that superstition.
It's like,
don't be so bloody sure about that.
These people weren't stupid.
And so there's,
there,
there are ways that they viewed the
world that we don't have any more and
one of them seems to be this concern for
descendants because that just isn't part
of our way of thinking.
We have very short term way of thinking.
Maybe it's not even one lifetime long,
it's certainly not multiple lifetimes
long and it isn't clear to me at all for
the best and you know the,
the constant complaint that the
environmentalists generate,
some of which is justified in some of
which is just anticapitalist,
anti patriarchal nonsense that should be
cleared out of that entire conversation
is that we need to take a longer view
and consider more things in our purview.
We're not when we act and like that.
Fair enough.
Like do we really want an ocean that has
nothing in it but jellyfish because
that's really what we're doing and we're
doing it very,
very rapidly and the data on that are
very clear and so you know,
when you lift up your eyes and you make
a connection with something that's
transcendent,
then that should bring more of the world
within your purview.
And maybe that's concerned for the
endless number of descendants that you
might have,
might think to,
well,
you know,
if you're a successful person,
if you have a successful family,
God only knows how many people you will
be the father of.
Right?
It's completely because you're a nexus,
right?
All sorts of things have come together
in the cosmos to produce you and then
all sorts of things manifest themselves
from you.
You have no idea what your potential,
the potential consequences of your
actions might be as they cascade across
time,
right?
You have no idea,
and so Abraham at least is concerned
with these sorts of things and God seems
to be concerned too because he promises
Abraham that if he maintains the
covenant that the most important things
that he needs will come to him and
they're pretty serious about this.
So Sariah talks to Abraham.
She's not very happy about the fact that
she can't have children.
She says,
behold,
the Lord hath restrained me from
bearing.
I pray thee go in unto my made.
It may be that I obtained children by
her and Abraham hearken to the voice of
Siri.
Well,
that's not a very trivial thing.
I wouldn't think.
I don't imagine that that Sarah was
through.
I was very happy about turning her made
over to her husband
and potentially being usurped in the
whole child bearing and the whole
childbearing process.
Not In the least,
but it's also a major sacrifice on
Sarah's part.
There's no doubt about that on of
course,
it's very difficult for us to talk about
the ethics of the fact that Hagar was a
more or less than voluntary participant
in this,
but that was the times absolutely the
case,
and of course,
slavery in indentured servitude is the
way of mankind except in very,
very,
very limited circumstances.
Carl young had something to say about
that too,
which I really liked.
He said that part of the reason that
modern people have.
It's not the only reason.
There's the industrial revolution
obviously,
but part of the reason that modern
people have been able to escape from the
catastrophe of tyranny and slavery is
because we've agreed to make ourselves
our own slaves.
Right?
So instead of owning a slave,
you own yourself in a sense,
and so you try it yourself off to work
and exploit yourself so that you can
stay alive and maybe it's not something
that you want to do,
but you've taken on the role of slave in
some sense,
in relationship to your own survival.
Instead of forcing someone else to do
it,
which is also something I think that's
very noble about the West,
is that we're willing to enslave
ourselves as individuals and we're not,
we're not doing that to other people.
Now we're doing it to some degree,
obviously because the society is
imperfect,
but that's something that's very much
worth thinking about.
So an Abraham hearkened to the voice of
Surrey and Surrey.
Abram's wife took Hagar,
her maid the Egyptian after Abraham had
dwelt 10 years in the land of Canaan and
gave her to her husband Abraham to be
his wife.
That's the other thing that's been so
interesting about doing this.
One of the other things about doing this
biblical series,
and it's one of the things that's so
cool about Google,
um,
despite the fact that they cut off my
account,
um,
you can find any piece of art that ever
existed on Google.
And so that's great.
So,
you know,
when I'm trying to illustrate these,
these lectures,
I type in Abraham Renaissance and then
like I get 200 renaissance paintings.
It's so great.
And then I can look at them.
And one of the other things that's so
remarkable is that all of these,
the major themes of the stories have
been illustrated by people of
spectacular,
my mind,
mind expanding talent.
You know,
there's just this endless array of,
well,
look at that.
I mean,
that's an amazing painting.
And so,
and there's an of this,
uh,
there's,
there's dozens of paintings on this
theme and it's just another indication
of how obsessed people,
you know,
this was the only book that existed for
years and people were absolutely
obsessed by it and produced all these
amazing things from it.
And we're in danger of losing that.
And that's a big mistake because it's
magnificent.
A little humility would go a long way
towards restoring it.
And he went into unto Hagar and she
conceived.
And when she saw that she had conceived,
her mistress was despised in her eyes.
So Hagar was successful and that was a
hallmark of feminine success.
Now.
And certainly then.
And so she started to Lord it over
Sariah,
which seemed a little bit on the
ungrateful side,
I would say,
because I made a big sacrifice to allow
Hagar to become Abram's wife.
And so a little bit of gratitude would
have been an order,
I suppose,
at least that's how the story goes.
And Sarah,
I said unto Abraham,
my wrong,
be upon thee.
I have given my maiden to Buddhism.
And when she saw that she had conceived,
I was despised in her eyes.
The Lord judge between you and I,
and Abraham said unto him,
[inaudible],
behold,
thy maid is in dine.
Hand due to her as it pleases you.
And when Sarah dealt hardly with her,
Hagar fled from her face.
And the angel of the Lord Found Her by a
Fountain of Water in the Wilderness,
by the fountain in the way to assure.
And he said,
Hagar,
Sarah's maid,
whence chemists and whether wilt thou
go.
And she said,
I flee from the face of my mistress.
And the angel of the Lord said,
returned to my mistress and submit under
her hands.
And the angel said,
I will multiply your seed exceedingly,
that it shall not be numbered for
multitude.
And the angel said,
behold thou art with child and shall
thou shall bear a son and shall call his
name,
Ishmael.
And Ishmael means God hears by the way,
because the Lord hath heard thy
affliction and he'll be a wild man.
His hand will be against every man and
every man's hand against him and he
shall dwell in the presence of all his
brothers.
And she called the name of the Lord that
spake unto her thou God CSB for she
said,
have I also hear looked after him,
that me were for the wall,
well was called Beer la Roy.
And that means the well of sees me in
lives.
It's an interesting interlude because
you know Abraham,
God has established his covenant with
Abraham and obviously things are going
wrong in the household in a really
serious way,
like a really serious way because well,
he's now had a child by another woman
and that the two women are not getting
along and one is beating the other
because of her insubordination and,
and contempt.
And so she's so desperate,
she runs out into the desert where she's
probably going to die and God comes
along and says anyways to to to to Hagar
that her son Shell as well be the father
of nations.
And so that's partly a reflection back
on the power of Abraham's covenant,
right?
Even though even though things are going
terribly wrong locally,
let's say the fact that Abraham has made
this overarching agreement with God
means that all of these catastrophes are
taking place within a bounded space
within the arc.
We could say that's one way of looking
at it.
And I do think I do think that that's
right because it seems to me that you
know,
if everything falls apart around you,
there's this a couple of things you're
going to want.
You're going to want someone standing
beside you that's for sure,
that you can trust.
You're going to want your family around
you and you want to want them to have
your back and you're going to want to
know that you didn't do some God damn
stupid thing to bring all held down on
yourself.
And if you're lacking any of those,
when that crisis comes,
there's a high probability it will
flatten you and you won't be able to get
up.
You know,
it does seem to me,
you can ask yourself this question when
things collapse around you,
how much utility is knowledge of your
own moral virtue?
It's bad enough to be late.
It's bad to be laid load,
but to be laid low and to know that you
were the fault you were at fault for it,
and worse the things that you did that
you knew you did that were wrong,
brought you there.
Then I think you have nothing to stand
on in that situation.
And that's also the circumstances under
which I think you're more more likely at
least to be abandoned by people around
you.
So given that you know that the
catastrophe is coming right,
that the tragedy of life will strike
you.
The question is,
well,
how do you afford to fire yourself
against that?
And I'll obviously,
it's to some degree you do that by being
materially sensible and these old people
in the test,
in the Old Testament,
these ancient people,
they weren't blind to the utility of
having a good crop and some animals you
know that that's an that's an integral
part of their life to take care of
themselves physically,
but they're also wise enough to know
that there is an element of moral this,
what would you call it?
There's a necessity for moral
integration that defends you against the
catastrophe of existence even more
effectively than anything material and
even more that the stability of the
material things is more dependent on the
integrity of your spirit than the
integrity of your spirit is dependent on
the material things.
And I think the evidence for that is
actually quite clear.
I read it wrote,
read a very interesting book a while
back called the wealth and poverty of
nations that was written by a Harvard
emeritus professor of history and one of
the things that he claimed I liked it.
I thought it was very smart.
Was that the only true natural
resources,
interpersonal trust.
If you can set up a society where people
trust each other,
then it will instantly become rich and
he used the example of Japan,
which is a very conscientious society
and very rich society,
but the Japanese have no natural
resources,
right?
None to speak of,
and yet they're rich and then you have
countries like the Soviet Russia and
much of South America where there's just
natural resources that you know,
they're just like Venezuela.
It's just more natural resources than
you know,
what to do with and the places are
absolute catastrophes.
Absolute catastrophes of cynicism and
corruption.
And so he attempted to document the
relationship between default
interpersonal trust among citizens
within countries and their productivity
in their,
their GDP and their standard of living
and found a very,
very tight relationship.
And I liked that a lot and I've got a
story about that quickly that I think is
very interesting.
I'll tell you two stories.
One sort of generic.
I'll tell you one personal first.
So one day I lend my car to one of my
graduate students and he took it to
Montreal,
was this old Cadillac and he got.
It was a really bad rainstorm in
Montreal and he was in one of the
highways that are like set into the
ground and there was like six inches of
water and he was turning a corner,
hit the brakes and skidded on the water
and smacked it into the wall and on the
corner of the,
of the bumper,
you know,
and so then he brought it back and he
was very apologetic about it.
And,
and uh,
his name was matt shade will tell you
that because Matt might hear this and I
can shame them and they get for doing
this 20 years ago,
you know,
and uh,
he's a professor at the Ontario
Institute of Technology,
I think now quite a successful one.
But anyways,
he brought the car back and I went and
got it evaluated for damages.
It was like $1,700
or something to repair it and,
or maybe more,
but it was almost as much as the car was
worth.
And I thought,
well,
I'm not going to do that.
So I went online and I typed in the part
and if you do that you can get people to
bid on sending you used part from all
over North America.
So that's Kinda cool.
So there's all these junk dealers have
got together and they have this network
of communication.
So you put in the car part and then they
send you a bit.
And so this guy said,
well,
I'll send you that bumper assembly,
which is the whole bumper and the lights
for like 250 bucks.
And I thought,
yeah,
okay,
if you could do that,
that'd be good.
So then I said yes.
And then he called me up about half an
hour later if this guy from way down
south,
he had a really deep sort of Mississippi
accent.
He said,
wait a sec,
was that for the bumper,
the bumper assembly?
And I said,
well it was for the bumper assembly.
He said,
oh,
I thought it was for the bumper and then
he said,
but that's okay.
I'll send it to you anyways.
And I thought,
well that's pretty good.
So I said,
well thank you.
And then I hung up and then half an hour
later he called me up again and he said,
look,
I just went out and looked at that
bumper assembly and there's a plastic
trim piece on this side and it has a
scratch in it.
And I thought,
I better tell you that just in case you
didn't want it.
And I thought,
wow,
that's so amazing.
It's like there's a miracle man.
It's like this guy,
he's somewhere in Mississippi.
I'm never gonna see him again.
Ever.
Never going to have any contact with
them.
Like he made a bad deal,
right?
Because the part was worth more than he
decided to sell it to me for.
But he stuck with this deal.
And then he went over and above the call
of duty,
he said,
well,
this part that I'm selling you to you
for way less than it's worth is damaged.
So I thought I'd better tell you.
It's like,
man,
you got to recognize a miracle when you
see one that was a miracle.
So I said,
hey look,
thanks for calling man.
So okay,
I can handle the scratch then the part
needed.
And,
and I got the car fixed and forgave
Matt,
and you know,
it had a happy ending.
So that's trust,
right?
Because I didn't know him from Adam and
he's a primate full of snakes,
just like the rest of us.
And yet he was willing to simplify
himself to the point where I could just
take him absolutely at his word.
And that meant we could trade even
though we were strangers.
It's like,
man,
do not underestimate the utility of
that.
And then there's Ebay.
So when Ebay first started,
you know,
the idea was not gonna work because
you'll send me junk and I'll send you a
check that bounces and that'll be the
end of Ebay.
Right?
And so these escrow agents popped up so
you could insure your transaction with
them moves for like 10 percent of the
transaction.
They would get the check and the goods
and make sure that they were okay and
then send them on or ensure the
transaction.
But what happened was the escrow agents
didn't make any money.
And the reason for that was no one
cheated.
And you think about how amazing that is,
right?
You bring these people together across a
whole continent,
they've never seen each other before.
They're never going to interact with
each other again,
and this was before there were any
reputation ratings on Ebay and yet the
default transaction was you describe
your goods honestly,
including their flaws.
You set a reasonable price.
I decided to pay you.
You ship the goods and I pay you and it
works,
and what happened was that Ebay
produced,
produced a tremendous amount of capital
that was previously frozen,
so frozen capitalist,
when you've invested money in something,
but the thing is no longer useful to
you.
So the money is just sitting there
frozen,
right?
So to speak,
and you can't get it loose because,
well,
you've got an attic full of junk.
How are you going to get rid of that?
Oh,
he may,
and so all of a sudden all these things
that were just junk became valuable and
everybody got richer and none of that
wouldn't.
It would have happened without the
covenant that we established between
each other.
That's predicated on trust.
And so you might say that trust is the
currency and currency is trust.
Because it's a promissory note,
right,
and if people lie,
then the currency gets debased very,
very rapidly and so the economy runs on
trust and so that's part of the
overarching covenant.
So Abraham makes this covenant with God
and he decides that he's going to aim
high and live a good life and tell the
truth and that puts this boundary around
him.
It's like a walled garden.
It's like a walled garden and inside
there there's all sorts of things that
are happening that are complex and
difficult,
but outside there's a boundary and the
boundary is,
well,
maybe things won't.
It's like God says,
after the flood he says,
I'll never send a flood again.
That's part of the story.
And so there's an intimation there that
no matter how bad things get,
they won't get so bad that they'll be
catastrophic.
But there's a,
there's a Coda to that which is that you
have to maintain the covenant and we
don't know what that means,
you know,
because you know,
you think it's pretty obvious that if
you treat people well,
if you really think about it and you're
not being naively optimistic and like,
you know,
a nice,
good person for op with all the weakness
that,
uh,
that intimate,
if you're being hard nosed insensible,
you understand that if you treat people,
if you trust people,
that's an act of courage.
If you're not naive,
right?
If you're naive,
it's an act of stupidity because you
might get bit and you probably will.
And if you're naive and you get bit,
you will suffer for it.
It'll traumatize you.
But if you're not naive and you know you
can get that,
then you might ask,
well,
what should you do with people?
And the answer is you should trust them
not because you're naive and not because
they couldn't betray you and not because
you don't know that they could be trail.
But because if you hold out your hand in
trust and you're inviting the best part
of that person to step forward,
and that won't happen unless you take
that initial step and that's courage,
not naivety.
And so to trust someone,
once your eyes are open,
that's an act of courage and that opens
up the world.
You know when you might say,
okay,
and so there's this idea in this story
that you can withstand it.
A fair bit of the catastrophe of life by
establishing the proper covenant and by
acting in a trustworthy manner and
extending your hand to people properly.
And you might say,
well,
okay,
that's sensible.
I can understand how that would work and
I can certainly see how the opposite
wouldn't work.
Because you know,
if I have to be absolutely terrified
that you're going to be trained me at
every possible moment and we're in in
negotiation,
we're not going to get any work done
man.
Because I'm going to be figuring out
what you're up to all the time and
you're going to be figuring out what I'm
up to all the time and we're just not
going to get anywhere.
You'll come and say you're going to do
something and I can just simplify you.
I can say you're going to do what you
said you do.
I don't have to worry about you.
And then the same applies to me and then
we can go do something and that's how we
generate wealth.
So then you might say,
well,
if what's the ultimate limit of that?
You know,
like we know that there's corruption in
our society that people betray each
other than the deceit and all of that
and it causes things like the periodic
collapse in 2008,
which was complicated but was partly
engendered by corruption.
Like what would be the upside if we
acted,
if we really determined to act honestly,
what do you think it is that people
would be able to do with the world if we
stopped acting in a corrupt manner?
I mean,
what?
What's the like what,
what is the upside?
Do you think we could,
could,
could.
How far back could we push aging?
Do you think?
If we hit it hard for 50 years,
can we tripled our lifespan?
It wouldn't surprise me.
You know,
all these terrible diseases that we set
the planet.
We could get rid of them.
There's no reason for hunger and
starvation.
We make enough food.
It's like what would happen if we
stopped acting badly?
How much better could things get?
Or you start locally.
I think you start with yourself and you
start with your family,
but you know there's intimations of the
divine.
There's intimations of the Kingdom of
God and the Covenant with God in the Old
Testament.
It's like you think,
well,
we speak secularly.
You think,
well,
that's
an unprovable assumption.
It's like,
well,
we'll just.
Hold on a sec.
What's the assumption here?
Exactly?
What is the upper end for humanity?
I mean,
who's,
who's going to say?
Right?
Who's going to say,
especially in this day and age,
man,
there's so many things happening that
you can't even comprehend them.
What could we do if we put all of our
effort into it?
While you can experiment with that,
because you can start in your own
household,
you can start in your own room and you
could make miracles happen in the
confines of your own space.
There's no doubt about that.
Oh,
you have to do is try.
You'll see that that happens.
It happened and people are writing to me
and telling me that they're trying this
and that.
That's exactly what's happening and so,
so we don't want to be too cynical about
about where we might be headed,
and Hagar bore Abraham a son,
and Abraham called his son's name,
which Hagar bear,
Ishmael,
who is by tradition the forefather of
several Arab nations and of Mohammed
himself,
and Abraham was four score and six years
old when Hagar Ishmael to Abrams.
So that's the end of another story.
And then so that section ends,
and then again we have an encounter
between Abraham and God who when Abraham
was 90 years old and nine 99 years old,
the Lord appeared to him and said,
I am the Almighty God.
Walk before me and be thou perfect.
Alexander mcclaren,
who is our,
a biblical commentator who lived in the
early 19th century,
said this phrase,
walking before God is not precisely
walking with God because that's what
Noah did,
right?
He says,
it's rather that have an active life
spent in continual consciousness of
being naked and open before the eyes of
him to have whom we have to give
account.
I was pretty happy to stumble across
that because I mean I might've picked
and chosen.
Of course,
you'd never know that whether you do
that,
but it does seem in keeping with the
narrative strain of the chapter,
right?
Because what we've hypothesized so far
is that God has called Abraham and said,
you know,
get out there in the world gold,
gold to where it's unknown.
Go to where you're a stranger and get
away from the familiar.
Go out to the unknown,
establish yourself and great things will
come of it.
Regardless of the proximal evidence,
great things will come of it,
and so I think that's what the walking
before God refers to.
It's not like Abraham is acting in
certainty.
There's no certainty here that that's
the act of the leap of faith even
because it does require a leap of faith
for you to move into the world because
the world is a catastrophe of self.
Evidently the world is a catastrophe and
so there's,
there's,
there's every reason for you to assume
that you should just sit in your
basement and hide from it,
but that's not.
It doesn't help.
It doesn't make things better.
And the thing is perhaps you're not
built for that.
You're not built to hide.
I don't think that people are built to
hide.
I think it destroys them.
So walking before God in sense means
that Abraham
is,
we could say,
is taking the lead.
He's the person that's going out there
into the unknown.
God says,
well,
great things are gonna happen,
but he's a little short on details.
That's for sure.
So the weight is still on Abraham and
that's a good thing because it also that
ennoble Abraham Ham,
right?
That's the other thing that's so cool is
that if God had just laid out the whole
story and,
and,
and you know,
brush the branches from Abraham's path
while he was walking forward,
well then there'd be nothing for Abraham
to do.
There'd be no nobility in his own
pursuit and this is another thing that
we don't understand very well.
It's a really tough thing to understand
is like how much trouble would you want
there not to be.
It's a weird question,
right?
Because you want to have some to contend
with.
You want to have something that,
that forces from you the best that you
have,
and so you have to have real problems.
Something like that.
Would you dispense with all your real,
but you could just lay down on a bed and
have pablum infused into your mouth.
You know,
if all your problems were solved and so
maybe you want difficult problems that
you can solve something like that
because there's some.
I don't know what it is about it.
There's a,
there's the overcoming and the and the
growth that comes along with that.
There's something about the nobility of
the enterprise.
You certainly see that when you go about
having children,
for example,
which is,
you know,
the psychological literature is quite
clear if,
if you do moment to moment comparisons
of people who have kids and people who
don't have kids,
the people who don't have kids are
happier and so psychologists who tend to
get things wrong,
even when they make intelligent
discoveries like that one,
immediately some of them jumped to the
conclusion that because happiness is the
goal,
that while there's something about
children that make you unhappy and
that's not good,
it's like,
well,
wait a second,
and maybe that's the wrong metric.
It's like,
of course you're less happy once you
have children because you have to worry
about them.
You know,
my neighbor down the street who's very
smart woman said to me once,
you can only be as happy as your
unhappiest child,
which I thought was really good.
You know,
that's really smart,
but then it isn't.
Well,
if having children doesn't make you
happy,
the answer isn't don't have children.
It's like,
don't be so stupid about being happy.
That's the answer.
It's because there's a nobility in the
pursuit,
right?
And of course now you're responsible,
you know you have a new baby.
You think especially if you're a new
parent,
you think,
what the hell is this and what am I
going to do with it?
You know?
It's like,
and then you're,
you're done for the rest of your life.
You never sleep properly again because
you're going to be worried about this
creature that you have to take care of
it,
but like,
what the hell good are you?
If you're not doing that or something
else equally difficult because you just,
you just have been called out yet.
Unless you take on a responsibility like
that,
the idea that life is that happiness is
the purpose of life.
It's like great for happiness,
man.
If it comes along,
you should be thrilled that it's
visiting you,
but the notion that that's,
that that's what you should pursue.
That's the weakest possible notion.
First of all,
as soon as something terrible happens to
you,
you're done.
It's like life is to be happy.
It's like,
well,
now you have cancer,
so how's that?
How the happiness thing work it out for
you now,
or maybe it's not you,
you know,
maybe it's your father that has
Alzheimer's disease or some damn thing
and you know it's like it's a rare
person that doesn't have some
catastrophe.
One,
one person away from them.
He's like,
life is to be happy.
It's not right,
and we can at least derive that from
these stories.
That isn't what they say at all.
God's perfectly happy in these stories
to grant the people with whom he forms a
covenant happiness and prosperity,
but there's never a word that that's the
purpose.
The rule is aim high and get your bloody
act together.
That's the rule,
and establish this contractual covenant
with the ultimate ideal and that will
see you through the catastrophes and
that's a much more mature way of looking
at life as far as I'm concerned because
all you have to do is have your eyes
half open and you see that the
fundamental reality of life is tragedy
and suffering.
There's that's inescapable.
The quest.
That doesn't mean that it,
it makes life unbearable or that it
makes being something that shouldn't
have existed,
right?
That isn't what it means,
but it means that you have to contend
with it and you have to get ready and
the willingness to adopt responsibility
for yourself and for others is,
is the precondition for that.
And,
and then maybe if you do that properly,
then now and then you get some
happiness.
You know,
you can sit at the end of the day and
you have half an hour where your
conscience is clear and there's nothing
that you need to be doing and you can
relax and think,
you know,
that that's all right.
Things are okay and thank God for that.
And that's,
that's maybe where you get your
happiness.
So that's something that's growing up,
man,
obviously.
And,
and to not know that and to not be
taught that,
like everyone should be taught that it's
so obvious we should be taught that.
Well,
and that's partly what these biblical
stories do and I will make my covenant
between me and Thee and will multiply
the exceedingly and Abraham fell on his
face.
Yeah and God talk with him saying,
as for me,
behold my covenant is with Thee and Thou
shall be a father of many nations.
God says this a lot.
Tabor them right it.
So it's almost like he has to remind him
now and then.
And it's not surprising because he keeps
going through these unbelievable
adventures,
you know,
that are really psychologically and
socially shattering.
So it's a good thing that this reminder
pops up in a fairly frequently.
But of course Abraham is also open to
it.
And I think,
what does it mean?
You know,
I'll talk personally for a moment.
I guess.
So I've asked myself a lot of questions
in the last eight months.
Man,
I can tell you that and I'm still asking
myself a lot of questions and I've been
conferring with a lot of people because
I had lots of people who were helping me
negotiate whatever the hell this is
what's happening and you know,
I could ask them how it was doing and
they would tell me a bunch of things I
was doing wrong and some things I was
doing right and I could listen to them.
And I was asking questions all the time
about how the hell I should manage this
properly and you know what,
what I was trying to do and what seemed
to serve me properly was to figure out
how to do it correctly.
That was the issue.
It's like I didn't really care what
happened and I guess I really don't care
what happens,
but I do care if I do it correctly
because I don't want to screw it up.
I don't want to screw things up.
And that seems to be a reasonable goal
for people.
I mean,
wouldn't you like that as a goal that
you don't screw things up because he
can't control to your life isn't fully
under your control by any stretch of the
imagination.
But it might be nice to not have your
conscience seating at you saying,
look,
you know,
you had a big opportunity there and you
mocked it up because you're weak and
blind and he didn't listen.
That's no good.
The cast the catastrophes bad enough,
as I said,
without you being the bloody source of
it.
And so.
Well that's Abraham falling on his face,
I guess.
And also communing with God.
It's like you do.
He wants to get it right,
he wants to get it right,
and there's these,
these things that beckon in promise,
but,
but it's,
it's bloody easy to make a catastrophic
mistake and he'll do that in your life,
you know,
and maybe humility is one of the things
that can prevent that because you can
look and you can think,
okay,
what am I doing wrong?
What am I doing wrong?
What can I do better?
How could I do this properly?
And then maybe you know,
you get,
you get the intimation of the proper way
to move forward.
And maybe that's what protects you when
things are chaotic and in strife.
And who knows what that's worth,
neither shall thy name anymore be called
Abraham,
which means high king.
If I remember correctly,
a Thai name shall be Abraham for a
father of many nations.
Have I made the oh,
Abrams,
hi father.
Look at that.
Abraham means father of a multitude and
I will make the exceedingly fruitful and
I will make nations of the productive
right?
Productive.
And that seems to be something that's
good to be.
I mean like one of the things that I've
thought about deeply,
I thought deeply about death and the
death of my family members and about
funerals.
And I thought about it partly because I
had this weird experience once that I
think I told you about where I took one
of my clients to see an embalming,
which was very strange experience and I
had a chance to talk to the funeral
directors because they have weird jobs,
you know,
and there's this idea,
well the Freudian idea that people
suffer from this terrible death anxiety
and there's a whole line of social
psychological theory theorizing called
terror management theory that's
predicated on the idea that we defend
ourselves against death anxiety with our
belief systems.
And like puppets,
Ernest Becker's idea,
he wrote the denial of death,
which is a great book,
but there's a weakness in it because you
see some people who aren't like that,
you know,
like emergency room nurses aren't like
that.
And palliative care nurses aren't like
that might.
My sister in law is a palliative care
nurse.
That's a hard job,
right,
because you go there,
you're caring for people you have and
they're in pain and they're on their
last legs.
You try to make them comfortable and you
have a relationship with them because
how the hell are you going to make them
comfortable?
If you don't,
then they go and die on you and that
just happens.
That's what happens every day.
Right?
And what's weird is that people can be
palliative care nurses.
It's like,
how do you figure that out?
Because people can actually thrive in
the face of death strangely enough.
And like these funeral parlor directors,
they were interesting to talk to because
that's all they do,
right?
They just deal with.
They deal with death and grief all the
time and it was very interesting talking
to them because I talked to two of them.
They found their job extremely
meaningful and I asked them,
well,
you know,
what does that,
what does that do to your life?
You know,
you're saturated with death and
suffering and there,
and this is the same answer that I got
from the palliative care nurses,
that it doesn't undermine your life.
It enriches it now,
who would guess that?
Right?
I mean,
what the hell?
That just doesn't make any sense at all,
but what it does is speak to human
possibility because God only knows how
tough you are.
You know what I mean?
If you read history and you read about
what people have done,
you think,
wow,
we're pretty tough.
People are.
I read a,
there is a shipwreck in the Antarctica
100 years ago or so,
and I read the story.
It was not a biography.
If I remember correctly of the,
of the captain.
I might be wrong about that,
but I've got the basic story,
right?
Well,
they had a ship wreck and the Antarctica
was then they were there for a whole
year in the Antarctic arc,
you know,
and none of them died.
Not One.
He didn't lose a single man,
not one.
He kept the morale high and then they
took this boat that was on the ship and
they crossed like 400 miles of the
roughest ocean,
the roughest,
frigid ocean in the world.
Right?
You don't go in that ocean and then they
went to an island and they walked across
the island across these mountains that
no one else has ever climbed since,
and they went to the city on the other
side of the island and they got a boat
and they went and rescued their
compatriots and everyone survived.
It's like endurance is the name of the
book.
You read that book,
man.
You think,
wow,
people are really tough,
you know,
and if,
and it's ridiculous.
So who knows how tough you are and maybe
you find out by going out to find out
how tough you are.
Right?
So you take on a challenge,
one that you think you can master,
just that's just a bit beyond your grasp
and you master it and then you're a
little tougher and you think,
hey,
that worked out pretty well,
and so then you're more of a monster and
then you go out and find another
challenge that's even bigger and you
think,
well maybe I can do that too.
And then all of a sudden you can and you
get a little bit bigger and God only
knows what the limit is of you and you
find out by pushing yourself against the
world.
And of course that's what Abraham is
doing.
And so see,
we're very pessimistic.
US modern people you know,
were pessimistic about humanity,
that's for sure.
Dismal,
wretched planet destroying cancer on the
planet,
right as the club of Rome described us
so pleasantly back in the 19 sixties,
you know,
and I don't know,
maybe we're ashamed of the Cold War and
maybe we're ashamed of all the
destruction in the 20th century and the
hydrogen bomb and you know,
the continuing catastrophes of our
societies were deeply ashamed of that
and ashamed of ourselves personally.
But it's a hell of a thing to call us a
cancer on the planet.
There's just no excuse for that because
what you do with cancer is eradicated.
And I don't think that that's a very
knowable motive personally.
And I think it says a lot about the
people who would use such phraseology
that they would dare to conceptualize
humanity in that manner.
But you know,
it'd be nice if we could be optimistic
and I think began the problem with being
optimistic is that it's naive.
So then the question is,
is there an optimism that's not naive?
And I think there is an optimism that's
not naive as in just a visualization of
how strong people can be.
So one of the things that I tell people,
I've told my students in my class in
maps of meaning,
here's a goal.
You want to be the person at the funeral
of your father that everyone can rely
on.
How would that be?
You want to be the person who's broken
and,
and useless and adding to the misery in
the corner.
And look,
I'm not making light of people's grief.
You know,
I understand grief,
but who do you want to be when there's a
crisis,
right?
Do you want to be the person that
everyone can turn to for strength?
It's like,
why the hell not?
Why not?
That is a goal.
That would be a good goal because then
if there's a crisis and there will be,
it won't be such a bloody crisis because
there'll be someone there that can deal
with it.
You know,
so when I went and talked to these
people at the funeral home,
I envisioned that I thought,
okay,
well this is something you have to
contend with.
If you're going to be alive and adult,
you have to contend with death and
suffering and you have to be ready for
it and you have to be there for the
person because that's how they're going
to have.
And so there a goal man.
And in this time of nihilism,
you know what's,
what's the point of life?
People ask and they're taught that at
universities.
What's the point of life?
Everything's interpretation.
Humanities.
A cancer on the planet.
You know?
Well,
how about no?
How about not that?
How about the do something to us and I
will establish my covenant between me
and Dan seed after thee in their
generations for an everlasting covenant
to be a God unto Thee,
unto thy seed,
after the and I will give unto thee to
thy seed after the the land we're in now
art a all
the land of Canaan.
Because of course Abraham went out into
the land of strangers,
right?
But it says that he'll master if he,
if he keeps his covenant,
he'll master the land of strangers.
That's a wonderful thing to know and I
think a true thing,
you know,
because if you're dealing with
strangers,
I've dealt with lots of strange people
in my life.
If I'm a clinical psychologist,
and that isn't to say that everyone that
I've dealt with was strange because
that's not the case,
but I have encountered some very strange
people and you know,
the way to deal with strange people is
to.
You never lie to a strange person.
That's the thing,
especially if they're paranoid.
You never lie to someone who's paranoid
it.
It will come back to bite you.
And if you're in an extreme situation
with someone who's very unpredictable,
the only thing you have that works is
the truth that works.
I'll tell you a little story.
This is in my book.
So I had this landlord in Montreal.
He lived next door to me and he was an
ex hell's angels biker.
He'd spent a lot of time in prison and
his wife had borderline personality
disorder and she committed suicide when
I lived there.
And he was a rough guy and he was at Caa
Quebec law.
He spoke ul,
which I could hardly understand.
And uh,
he didn't really know what to make of me
and I didn't really know what to make of
him.
Um,
but we got along,
you know,
I was very careful talking to him as,
as you might imagine,
but,
but I,
I was,
it was very.
And we went over to my wife and I went
over there and we had a spaghetti dinner
one night and we sort of communicated.
And I bought a poster from him because
he made these wooden posters that had
neon on them.
And that's how he made a living.
He'd Kinda trained himself to be a bit
of an electronics guy and so we made
these things and he was trying to quit
drinking and we talked about that.
He was a lot older than me.
He was like 20 years older than me.
I was about 25 at this point and uh,
we got along pretty well,
but every now and then he'd go out and
get a drink and he could really drink,
you know,
like he was one of these guys who could
drink like 60 beer and you think,
well no one can drink that much and
you're wrong.
I studied alcohol for like 10 years,
some of my subjects,
father's drank 40 ounces of vodka a day
and had been doing it for 20 years so
you can drink a lot and he could drink a
lot.
And what would happen?
He was trying to,
not drink,
but he'd go out and go on a binge and
then he'd be gone for like three days
and he drink up all his money and then
we'd hear him out in the backyard
howling at the moon with this little
little ugly dog.
He had,
you know,
and he'd held and the dog would hell and
he'd haul them and the dog would haul
and,
and it was a rather unsettling and made
my wife nervous and uh,
but worse,
you know now,
and then he'd come to the door at like
three in the morning,
hey,
and he'd knock on the door and he'd be
standing there and I don't know how much
experience you've had with rough guys
who are and who were drunk,
but it's,
they can be upright and unconscious at
the same time.
And so that was the state that he was
in,
you know,
he'd be just swaying and he asked me if
I would like to buy his toaster or his
microwave because he needed some money
to keep drinking and you know,
I didn't really want to buy his toaster
or as microwave.
But when the x hell's angel,
you all speaking 60 beard,
drunk Quebecois biker shows up at your
door at three in the morning and the
offers you to sell offers to sell you
his microwave.
The easiest thing is to say,
I really need a microwave.
So.
So you know,
I bought the microwave and toaster and
some other things,
but then,
but then my wife talked to me and she
liked my landlord,
you know,
even though she was afraid of him,
she liked him and she said,
you can't buy any more,
any more appliances because it's not
good for him.
And I thought,
Huh,
that's an interesting problem,
you know,
so what the hell am I going to do about
this because no,
I don't want to buy your microwave just
doesn't seem to be the right answer at
three in the morning.
So.
So one time he took me out on his
sevenfifty Honda and he put me on the
back of it.
He wanted to show me his layer,
I guess his hangouts and I got his
wife's helmet on but it didn't fit it
just sit on the top of my head and he
said,
I go to the bike and he said if the cops
chase us,
we're not stopping.
And then away we went and we went to
these,
like these bars downtown on the wrong.
They were very rough places and he got
into like four fights that night because
he was a rough guy,
you know,
and these kind of punk guys would come
up to him and sort of challenge them and
act stupidly around him and he was very
skeptical and if you were acting
stupidly around him for any length of
time,
he just hit you because he felt that
that's what you deserved.
And perhaps he was right,
you know,
so.
So I had a firsthand opportunity to
observe him.
So anyways,
he sure enough,
about a week or two after we had this
conversation,
he showed up at the door,
knock,
you know,
open the door and they're standing there
with his eyes half closed and he was
swaying and he had.
I don't remember what the appliance was
this time,
but he wanted to sell it to me and I
said,
I'm not all I can buy this.
I'm not going to buy this because I know
you're trying to quit drinking.
And if I give you this money then you're
going to go and drink it up.
And it's not going to be good for you.
And what else did I tell them?
I think I told him as well that this
whole thing of him coming to my house at
like two in the morning was scaring my
wife who we liked and that it had to
stop and believe me,
man,
I was thinking about what I was saying
because he was watching me like a rough
guy watches you and a rough guy watches
you like this.
He thinks if you say one thing that
indicates contempt,
you're going to bloody well paid for it.
And so I was finding my words like,
you know,
I was crossing a swamp and trying to
look for the,
for the rocks underneath the surface.
And I said what I had to say very,
very carefully.
And he looked at me for about 15 seconds
and that's a long time to be locked out
at three in the morning.
And he laughed and he never came back to
sell me anything again.
And we got along fine.
But that's a good seal illustration of
this issue with regards to truth and
success in the strange land.
Because I was in the strange land when I
was talking to my neighbor,
my landlord Dan and I managed to say
what was true carefully enough so
despite the fact that he was a very
violent person and then he was very
intoxicated person and then he had every
reason to be suspicious of me and we
couldn't communicate very well and I
didn't do what he wanted,
that he took it and he left and there
was no problem and life went on just
fine after that and so we don't want to
underestimate the utility of
establishing this bounded relationship
with the ideal and attempting to live
with some nobility in truth will aiming
at the highest ideal.
There's nothing about that.
That's anything but strengthening and
positive and it's exactly what you need
to set against the catastrophe and
uncertainty of life and as far as I can
tell,
that's what these abrahamic stories are
attempting to communicate.
So we'll stop there.
Thank you.
Thanks.
I have to make an announcement.
I'm going to do a talk August 22nd I
think.
Not sure of the date,
but I'll.
I'll find out with Gad,
Saad from Concordia and so
with an x social worker named Serena
sing and with faith Goldie,
I think faith is going to be there as
well.
So the tickets for that will go on sale.
I'm not hosting this,
someone else's dealing with it,
but the tickets for that will go on sale
within approximately a week and I'll
post that on my.
I'll probably make an announcement on
youtube but I'll twitter,
tweeter it,
twitter it and all of that.
So.
And I think I mentioned to you guys last
week that I would like to continue this
series,
but I think I'll do it once a month and
I'll try to do it in this theater,
but I haven't got word from the people
who run the theater.
That's the university.
Whether or not it'll be accessible,
but I'll figure something out.
And so.
Oh,
hi.
Serena.
Serena is the person who's going to be
hosting this.
So August 22nd at 10:00
PM.
Seven 10 PM at Ryerson Monday.
Okay.
Tickets go on sale Monday.
All right.
And then.
And then,
uh,
oh,
there's a special freedom of speech
edition of the Hemingways Restaurant
Jordan Peterson discussion group
tonight.
So that's at 10:00
PM.
So you're all welcome to attend that.
So that's 1:42
cumberland street.
Okay.
So that's it for announcements I guess.
And then let's say for questions.
Yes.
I was going to let you ask the first
question.
Last time was not okay.
So I will do that.
And so let's make sure again,
everybody to speak into the Mike clearly
so that the youtube people can hear and
you know,
the ghostly youtube people.
And so go ahead.
I was quite impressed with your
presentation last week and uh,
I wasn't quite sure where it was going
at one point in,
wouldn't it?
Neither was on.
And that's okay.
Because at what point I,
I listened,
I thought what you basically were
talking about,
this is what I saw,
you were embodying mind,
body and spirit and bringing it all
together as one.
And you touched on it a bit tonight when
you,
when you talk about truth,
this is where we need to go.
Right?
And I know you say be positive and all
that and yeah,
that's right.
I agree.
It's scary what's going on right now.
However we have the power to stay in the
positive.
What you talked about last week,
you talked about using our intuition,
which I consider our higher self using
consciousness.
And you made reference,
I can't remember exactly what you,
what you said,
but you held your hand and you talked
about emotions and bringing intellect on
top.
And when you said emotions,
everything just lit up for me because
I'm thinking that's our heart Chakra.
That's what combines our lower self or
physical being,
the material stuff,
all the,
all the stuff that doesn't really
motivate us with their higher self.
And when I'm going to use talked about
emotion,
I wanted to talk about the emotion of
love.
And I find so many people are terrified.
It's a four letter word.
I know,
but it doesn't have to be bad.
Okay.
So I remember why when I talked to you
last week,
why I wanted you to ask this question.
So.
Okay.
So I've talked a lot in this lecture
series about truth and no,
I think there's a battle in the biblical
stories all the way through between love
and truth in terms of their primacy and
so,
and I've gone to contrasted lot on truth
in my own thinking,
but I,
and it's hard to talk about love because
it's a word that people have mouth to
death,
you know,
as soon as you start talking about love
than people should just go into a
different room and listened to you,
you know,
because it,
it gets,
it can get sappy and new age just like
that.
And I don't like that at all,
but,
but it's still something that has to be
contended with.
And I think.
So I've been trying to conceptualize,
let's say,
what this covenant might might
constitute.
And I think the love part.
So here's this.
So you know,
there's this book by Girtha called Faust
and it's in two volumes.
First one in to logically enough.
One was written much later than the
other hand.
Faust basically sells his soul to the
devil for,
for knowledge.
And the devil in faust is
Mephistopheles.
And Mephistopheles is quite a well
developed character and Gert that has
mephistopheles save what he's about,
which is really quite cool.
So it's like the adversary of the world,
evil itself gets a chance to speak and
make its case.
And [inaudible] thought this was so
important that he actually had
mephistopheles announced himself once in
faust one and then using the same words
you phrase differently again in part
two.
It really struck me.
And so what Mephistopheles says is that
the world is such a charter house of
suffering and destruction that it would
be better if it never existed.
And so that what he's working to is to
bring existence to an end because it is
not justified by it's suffering.
It's like that's.
It's an argument very similar to the
argument that's made by Ivan.
Camera.
Thank you.
Thank Russians.
A.
You can't pronounce them or live with
them.
You can,
but he basically,
he's an atheist and does a very good job
of detailing out the atheist argument or
maybe an anti theist argument and he's
arguing with his.
His brother Alioscha,
who's a monitor monastic novitiate,
who was a very good guy but not an
intellect,
Ivan's an intellect and a very powerful
one,
and he basically tells Lee Osha that the
all of the cosmos isn't worth the
suffering of one child.
He tells this story about this and this
Dostoevsky took this from a newspaper
about this parents that lost their four
year old daughter and an outhouse
overnight,
and she screamed about it until she
froze to death.
And so Dostoevsky used that argument.
He tied that into Ivan's anti theist
argument against Lee Osha.
It's very,
very powerful argument.
The brothers Karamazov is an absolutely
mind boggling,
amazing book.
I would highly recommend it.
Um,
and so that's the Mephistopheles and
perspective Mr Feeley and prospection.
It's perspective is that being itself is
so corrupted,
shouldn't exist.
So then you think,
okay,
well that's fair enough.
That's a decent argument.
It's understandable,
but the problem comes when you try to
implement that and what happens when you
implement it,
as far as I can tell,
you adopt out messed emphasis,
Ophelia and attitude of bitterness and
resentment and destruction is that you
make all the suffering that you're
complaining about far worse and I think
that's what happened at the base of
things in the 20th century,
is that there was a powerful movement
among human humanity to bring being
itself to a halt.
You know what culminated in the
development of the hydrogen bomb and the
high probability for many,
many periods of time that we were going
to do something permanent and fatal,
which seems like a bad idea.
It seems like a bad idea.
Well,
so what's the opposite of the myth,
Ophelia and attitude and I think the
opposite of that is what's presented in
the biblical stories in the guise of
love and that is the wish that things
would be good.
It's something like that.
That's what love is,
I think,
is that it's the attempt to orient
yourself towards making things better
and it's predicated on something like a
deep appreciation for being deaf despite
its suffering and deficiencies and maybe
a decision that you're going to act to
bring about things to move things
towards the good.
And I think that's the thing that sets
the parameters of the,
of them.
It's,
it's the opposite of the Memphis to and
attitude.
It's like to work towards the betterment
of being because you've decided that
you're going to open your heart to
existence,
something like that.
And it's within that framework that
truth takes place,
I think is truth has to serve something
kicked in.
True conserve truth,
but it has to be bounded inside
something.
And I think that's what it's bounded
inside.
So
what I was going to refer to it that was
um,
David Hawkins,
royal power versus force,
and he put it on a quantifiable scale.
All different emotions.
He called a consciousness.
Any put love at 528 hertz.
He put shame at 20.
I'm not sure if I've got these 100
percent right.
I'm guilty,
I think at 30 fear at 50 and it shows
you how far the people who are really
knocked down have to get to love and I'm
thinking if we could quantify love on a
term,
it means different things to everybody
and rightly so,
but can we get to that frequency and if
you look at the Solfeggio notes,
you know the musical notes.
Have you heard?
I'm afraid of.
I'm going to.
I'm going to ask you to stop if you
want,
because I should.
I should go to another question if you.
Thank you very much.
Okay.
Let's,
so you've been an educator through the
rise of the smartphone and my question
basically relates to procrastination and
task delay,
needless task delay specifically and
given the unprecedented level of
distraction that we have in today's
world.
I just wanted to get your perspective
from a psychological standpoint on other
than cleaning your damn room,
what would you suggest to a student
who's looking to overcome these lands?
Well,
I think with any,
let's call it addictive process,
mean emails powerfully.
Addictive,
right?
Partly it's a,
it's a slot machine and I mean that
technically,
so when you pull,
that's a variable ratio reinforcement
schedule,
if I remember correctly,
and it's very addictive because if you
pull on the slot machine arm enough,
you will win and you never know which
pole will reward you and so not only is
that addictive,
it's very hard to extinguish that and so
emails like that because there's always
something beckoning and now and then
it's a jackpot and social media is like
that because you know people are posting
interesting things and so well,
how do you overcome an addictive process
and partly you do it by replacing it
with something better,
right?
So when people study drug and alcohol
use,
they often make an elementary mistake,
which is to try to figure out why people
use drugs and alcohol.
Now it's,
that's not a smart thing to wonder.
We know why people use cocaine.
Cocaine directly stimulates the systems
that produce positive emotion,
so like,
so there's no mystery there.
The mystery with cocaine is very,
very simple.
Why don't people take cocaine all the
time until they die?
That's the mystery really.
Because you can get isolated rats to do
that.
So and,
and for some people alcohol has the same
kind of effect except it's mediated by
opiates,
but often what people have to do to get
themselves out of an addictive process
is to find something better to do to
replace it.
And so I would say the problem with the
gadgets,
and I mean there are amazing things is
that they interfere with the proximately
interfere with medium to longterm goals
I would say.
And so I think the first thing you have
to do to bring them under control is
figuring out what it is that they're
used is interfering with.
It has to be something important,
right?
So you think,
well I want to do something important.
What is that?
Oh,
it could be personal.
Maybe you want to have a relationship.
You want to get married,
you want to have kids,
you want to have a career that's
meaningful.
You know you want to have a life,
you want to have an abrahamic adventure
and be the father of nations,
let's say,
well,
you can't be ratting away on your cell
phone and doing that.
And so I think,
I think part of it is to set your sights
high ed and make a plan and figure out
who you could be and see if obsessive
utilization of smartphone fits into that
vision of nobility.
And it will,
partly because there are unbelievably
powerful communication devices.
But so,
so often it's,
it's for lack of something better to do
and it also interferes.
So that's about the best I can do with
that.
So,
uh,
you've been,
you've been talking with some of the
conservative candidates for leadership
this year on know you talked with most
all of them,
right?
Not all of them,
but a number of them.
You talked with Andrew though,
right?
Yes,
I did.
Yes.
So I'm,
so something very interesting popped up
in my facebook feed.
So it was a ad for the Conservative
Party and um,
it was suggesting that we a cut cut
funding to public universities that
don't support free speech.
And that was probably my fault.
Yeah.
See precisely because,
because this is something you say in
some of your wild or moments you suggest
that we should cut the university's
funding by 25 percent and let them
battle it out for the remains and he's
taken that to,
you know,
his,
his platform.
But now what you're doing is a will your
will.
One of the things you're doing is you've
created this website,
um,
that identifies a,
the postmodern lexicon and helps people.
I'm a distinguished between a postmodern
courses and not.
And so people don't take them or take
them if they want.
Yeah.
So that's it.
It'd be interesting to know,
like what sort of malevolent
postmodernist just study you
meticulously and try to use all your,
uh,
knowledge of it anyway.
So,
but,
but what you've said though,
you said that what we need to do is
starve it out from the source.
Yeah.
That look.
So when.
Yeah,
I do.
I know where you're going.
So about two weeks ago,
three weeks ago,
I went up to northern Saskatchewan.
My parents have a cottage up there.
It's way the hell out in the middle of
nowhere.
And there,
there's no cell phone,
although we do have internet now,
which is probably add in good.
But anyways,
I got to take a bit of a break,
which was good because I haven't really
been able to think more broadly about w
say what I'm doing because who the hell
I don't know what the hell I'm doing.
Exactly.
This is a,
this is all very strange and,
but,
but one thing I thought about,
I was out on the lake,
I was canoeing around and I thought I'd
thought about war.
No,
because I was very irritated.
I'm very irritated about what's happened
to the universities and there's a hint
of malevolence about it and I,
I'm not a fan of ideological possession
and I've been set back up on my heels a
lot over the last eight months by the,
the onslaught of what emerged when I
said that there was words I wouldn't
say.
And so it's put me into a defensive
posture,
let's say.
And I have been thinking in terms of war
metaphors,
you know,
like this is a battleground and that
there's a war going on an ideological
war.
And I do believe that that's,
but then I was reading and I did this
partly for this course,
I was reading the sermon on the mount
and one of the things it says is resist
not evil and I don't know what to make
about line.
And so I was talking to a bunch of
people about it and reading about it a
lot and trying to figure out what it
meant.
And partly what it means is don't waste
time,
right?
Because when you fighting against
something then there's something else
you're not doing.
And then I thought also when I was out
there on the lake,
I thought,
well do I really want to be in a war
because war.
That's not,
that's not,
that's not heaven,
that's for sure.
It's really stressful and people get
hurt.
And so I thought,
well maybe that's just the wrong way of
thinking about it even though there's a
battleground issue here.
And I thought,
well wait a second,
maybe,
maybe the right thing to do in a
situation like this.
And this is maybe something that those
on the alt right might consider.
Is that
the right thing to do?
Maybe is to outline a better way
rather than go out directly on the
attack.
Now that might be seem somewhat at odds
with my idea of the website and perhaps
it is somewhat at odds with that.
I'm.
I'm not sure about that,
but what I'm trying to do instead of
conducting this like a war,
let's say is two conducted like a
movement towards something better and
that would be better.
Now with regards to cutting the
university's funding.
I thought about that too and I thought,
wait a second.
That's not gonna work out because it's
inviting political interference into
higher education.
Now the political interference might be
over the counter balancing kind because
the evidence that the humanities in
particular have tilted almost 100
percent to the left is overwhelming and
so maybe some counter balance from the
right would set things more towards the
middle,
but the problem is is when you open up
the door to political interference with
higher education content,
you can't close the door again.
And so on reflection,
I thought that it probably was a sub
optimal idea and that would be better.
Instead was to and what are,
this is what I want to do.
When I launched the website,
I want to ask students,
the students who will be using it.
It's like,
what do you want from university?
Because here's,
here's your options.
You can.
You can come out ideologically
possessed,
right?
You can buy this doctrine is
pathological doctrine and you can become
bitter and resentful and you won't learn
to communicate properly and you won't
read the great works of civilization and
you won't learn to think and write.
You won't become knowable in body and
spirit.
Is that what you want?
Or do you want the opposite?
Do you want a real education?
And then I want to explain what that
means like I did tonight to some degree.
You know that there's absolute value in
learning how to put yourself together
and to communicate and to familiarize
yourself with,
with,
with the classic works of civilization.
And I want to offer that.
I want to do what I can to offer that as
the proper alternative.
Instead of staying in school winston,
this notion of a battle which is just,
I just don't think it's the right
metaphor.
So either in Dr Peterson.
I just want to say that I think what
you're doing is absolutely miraculous.
It's helps change my life.
Sure.
At least raise your hand if Dr Peterson
has helped change your life.
So for the better or for the worse,
asked him to look.
Well,
it's about,
it's about 40 people maybe.
And that's miraculous
and I think in your thinking is going to
be.
It's going to be,
it's gonna be all over the place in the
Canadian election in two years and I
think that that's a horrible thing to
say.
You better watch out for it buddy and
uni and,
and,
and there's,
there's gonna be a lot of talk about how
um,
how,
how Andrew Scheer's a political message
is going to stem from yours.
And I think it's really important that
he,
he doesn't censor himself like other
conservative politicians are doing and
because I don't know,
we need to unite under a valid,
thoughtful,
articulate,
conservative voice.
And what do we have now?
We have,
we have trump,
that's what's,
you know,
we don't have any,
we don't have any strong articulate male
voices in our,
in our,
um,
in our political discourse right now.
That's what it feels different.
Only time for you to develop one.
So it looks like you're on the right
path.
Thanks.
Hello
Peterson,
thank you for everything you've done
this past year and I do mean everything,
the political stuff,
lecture series,
so it gets you to move just to.
Yes.
Great.
Belted out man.
Okay.
So,
uh,
I'll try to be succinct.
I have two comments on one question.
First Common,
as you mentioned,
how you were prevented from uploading
your youtube video from last week.
Um,
I actually attended that lecture and I
make pretty detailed notes.
So if you want maybe I can email you.
It's okay.
I've got it.
It's my accounts reinstalled.
Reinstall,
reinstall restored.
Yeah.
And so it's okay.
It's okay.
It's,
it's straightened out and I'm going to
upload all the videos to a bunch of
other sites and so this isn't going to
happen again.
So.
But I appreciate that.
Some lectures and I do want to get them
online.
Yeah.
My second comment is about,
um,
sort of kind of going into the
commentaries of Christian theology is
over over the centuries are like you've
known yourself.
Um,
I just would like to encourage everybody
to also look at not just western
Christianity but also eastern
Christianity,
like the Orthodox writing's a,
there's a big difference between the two
in that the western sort of theology
comes out of the Roman Roman law,
Roman justice.
So there's a lot more of an emphasis on
can adjust the sin.
Christ came,
he died on the cross for our sin.
So there's that look kind of like legal,
a payback.
Do you know what I mean?
Whereas the eastern,
the eastern theology is a lot more,
um,
it's focused a lot more in love and on
sort of the,
uh,
the positive aspects.
And if you do read like the first four
centuries of Christianity where there
was no schism,
uh,
there's very little mention of a,
sort of a legalistic frame where it gets
a lot more,
I don't know,
a prosaic are more heartfelt.
I guess.
So I think it's important that we also
in the West,
look at the eastern counterpart,
um,
especially more so now because I,
I do perceive a lot of fake love as
being at the center of this my level and
said you mentioned so like,
you know,
this whole thing about I'm demonizing
the opposition saying that they're,
they're heartless to have no love this
and that.
I perceived that as a lot of fake love.
Um,
and I think that we have to keep in mind
what true love is.
Sometimes it looks ugly.
Like in dealing with psychiatric
patients,
maybe like other countries are not as
liberal as Canada,
but the of results a lot more often
units.
There's as many psychiatric patients on
the road,
for example,
in Greece where I'm from.
So yeah,
that was kind of my comment that we need
to focus a little more on what real love
is,
I think,
and not just the,
uh,
the kind of love that he put on a scale
because I don't think that he can put
love on a scale.
So I've been talking to some of,
you know,
to this Guy Jonathan Palio,
who's an Orthodox carver and he started
a youtube channel and he's talking a lot
about Orthodox issues and I'm pretty
ignorant when it comes to Orthodox
Christianity,
but from what I understand of it so far,
there's plenty to be learned.
So yeah,
I more than myself just recently came
back to my faith two years ago.
Basically that was the original
Christianity.
Then there was a schism of 1054 in
between East and west because of the,
the conflicts that these new
Christianity Christians have a pope.
And then after that you also had the
schism internally within the West
between Catholicism and,
and the Protestants.
So that's kind of like the big
difference said at Christianity actually
came from the east.
So I think that's why it's important
that we look at demos ancient times
because those were the ones that are
closest to the original message.
Um,
so not my question,
um,
it's about atheism.
You might hear a lot of times people
criticizing anybody that has any sort of
belief in a deity or a God that you're
just somebody that has an imaginary
friend,
you know,
like the,
the heavenly father that you have to
adhere to,
that you have no world of your own.
So then there's also like,
what are the counter argument be that,
okay,
so if I have a good relationship with my
father and that's why I'm more likely to
accept a higher degree than I could ever
be,
that you as an atheist,
um,
maybe you have conflict with your father
and that's why you're an adverse to kind
of submitting to a higher being that
I'm,
the kind of dictates your life while
you're,
you're attempting a psychoanalysis of
atheism,
you know,
and,
and there's many factors that go into
atheism.
Um,
I would say that you could make that
case in some situations,
but not in all.
Um,
I do think though,
and I think this is perhaps where your
question is stemming from,
is that it's no fluke that at the same
time that one of the consequences of the
death of God that Nietzsche announced
back in the late 18 hundreds is the all
out assault on masculinity that's
occurring in our culture now.
And those things are associated and I do
think that does have to do with a lack
of faith in the masculine spirit.
And that's a very bad thing because
what's a bad thing for everyone
obviously because women have a partially
masculine spirit and they have to put up
with men.
And so to demolish that or to fail to
nurture it,
which is certainly what's occurring is
just a pathway to absolute disaster.
So.
Yup.
Peterson.
So this is the type of question that you
hate because it's in the category of
why,
why you believe what you believe.
And uh,
it's a type of question that makes you
say,
if I have it right from the last time,
what the hell makes you think it's any
of your business on?
Okay.
Try to frame it properly.
And I'm asking this lecture 10 of 12 and
after having listened to quite a few
hours of you year and elsewhere,
and so in your second interview with
transluminal media,
you lay out a few things.
I have some quotes here,
I'll skip them for brevity.
You get to the point where you're
discussing the embodiment of the logos
by Christ as a historical figure,
and then you say,
quote,
is this resurrection real?
Did his body resurrect?
I don't know.
In today's lecture you,
you,
you alluded to the fact that there are
states of consciousness that perhaps we
don't know how to access anymore,
and let's say that I'm with you there.
Let's say I'm with the idea that there
are unknown or unknown ways to get
intimations of the divine.
That the embodiment of the logos is
associated with physiological
transformations,
the upper limits of which are unknown
and that we might currently classify as
paranormal.
But to dump it right back down to my
level,
I'm asking about the guy commonly
depicted with long hair nailed to a
cross until that is a door knob and all
of this goes to the heart of the
question of literalism and religious
interpretation.
It goes to the heart of what we're doing
here at this lecture series.
Are we examining the psychological
significance of these stories?
Are we entertaining the possibility of
these fantastical events?
I might be struggling with the concept,
but I haven't been able to square away
and reconcile those statements by you.
So the question is on the,
on the question of the resurrection of
Christ.
Why is your answer to your own question?
I don't know.
Instead of at the very least,
probably not.
Well,
you're definitely right about me hating
that question.
Well,
I called this series the psychological
significance of the biblical stories for
a reason.
You know,
and the reason was that I'm partially
qualified to talk about such things.
When I step outside of that,
then I'm not where I should be.
I don't think that.
See,
I don't think that this is.
I'm not going to get this right.
I can't get the words exactly right.
This isn't about what I believe
personally.
It's partly because I don't know what I
believe.
I don't know what I believe.
The world's a very strange place.
I've had some very strange experiences
in it.
I don't think it's helpful for me to
step outside my jurisdiction and
speculate precisely.
The easiest thing would be to say,
I think I said,
but I had to say today,
I don't think that we know what the
upper limits of human possibility are.
I don't know what that means.
Metaphysically.
What I do understand from the gospels is
that even the accounts of Christ's
resurrection are complex and difficult
to understand.
I think from reading you in large part
that you can make a very strong case for
the symbolic meaning of the death and
resurrection.
I think it does stand for the capacity
of the human logos to die and resurrect
continually as it strives upward.
I'm not willing to say that that's all
it means because I don't know what
everything means and I don't know about
the fundamental metaphysics of being
like.
I do believe that it's accurate to
construe being as a battle ground
between good and evil.
I believe that.
I believe that is the most accurate way
of representing being.
It's not the most accurate way of
representing the objective world.
That's not the same thing.
Being is that set of experiences which
we inhabit and that's only partly
objective and it's not obviously
reduceable to the material.
Not any straightforward way because we
don't understand the material substrate
of being at all.
You know it's.
It's and when we do attempt to
understand it,
say at the quantum level,
we run into mysteries that that baffle
the most,
the most intelligent of us and aware.
So I'm going to have to leave the
question hanging,
but partly because partly because I
don't know what I think,
but partly because
there has to be aligned between what I
believe in,
what what I can communicate.
You know,
what you believe is beyond your capacity
to articulate.
If you the most at the deepest levels of
belief,
and I can only share with you what I
have actually come to understand and
there's things that I don't understand
and that's definitely one of them.
I don't know how to draw a line between
the symbolic significance of the
biblical events,
say the symbolic and psychological
significance of the biblical events and
the metaphysics that's underneath them
and I think you see the same thing in
young because when you own rights,
technically,
informally,
he never talks about God.
He always talks about the image of God,
which is not the same thing.
The image of God would be your
subjective experience of God.
It says nothing about the objective
reality of God because your subjective
experience can't say much about
objective reality,
but even in young you get this mix.
You know,
sometimes it's psychological,
but then he,
he makes a metaphysical move and I think
that reflected also his,
the limits of his knowledge because
young had profound revelatory
experiences.
It was a very strange person.
You know,
and I,
I think so.
I think what's best for me is to stay on
the ground that I'm competent on and to
say what I can say about the psychology
and to reach beyond that briefly when
it's necessary,
but other than that to leave it the hell
alone until I understand it better,
assuming that I ever do so
because of these lectures.
I've been reading the Bible and
obviously not finished,
but I'm fairly familiar with,
with how it goes and the.
I've been thinking about two parts of it
in specific,
which is the story of Isaac and the
Crucifixion of Christ and particularly
one of the things that Christ says on
the cross,
which is my God,
my God,
why have you forsaken me?
And I've been trying to understand that
because that's one hell of a thing for
the son of God to say.
And you think that would have been
edited out.
Yeah.
No,
seriously.
It's like,
why isn't that gone?
You know,
it,
it's,
it's very inconvenient.
Yeah.
And in,
well we haven't,
you haven't touched on the story of
Isaac yet,
but there's this thing,
the cold topology,
which I'm sure you're aware of,
but basically the idea that what's going
on in the Old Testament,
he served the laying out of types for
Christ and that Isaac is essentially a
type of Christ because they have all
these similarities.
And so I've been thinking about it in
that context and thinking about the
parallels between them in between Isaac
and Christ.
And one of the things that also struck
me was mostly the differences between as
I can Christ.
And the main difference it seems to me
is sort of a difference in direction of
sacrifice.
So the sacrifices of Abraham is Abraham
sacrificing his son to God and then the
sacrifice of Jesus is God sacrificing
his son to.
And I've been trying to understand
basically how that works and in relation
to the,
in Western civilization for 2000 years.
Yeah.
Well there is these transformations of
sacrifice,
right?
So the next thing that happens in these
stories is that the circumcision
circumcision starts to come in as a
sacrifice.
And it seems to be something like the
beginnings of replacement for sacrifice
of animals.
It's,
you know,
there's this psychology ization of
sacrifice.
So first it's pure external,
enact it out,
and then it becomes something that's
more conceptual,
like it becomes embodied in the form of
the circumcision,
and then it becomes more conceptual and
that conceptual transformation keeps
occurring.
And,
and it seems to,
while it culminates to some degree in
this idea of the sacrifice of Christ,
who's,
who's God sacrificing his son to
mankind?
But the sacrifice is much more complex
than that,
right?
It's also Christ sacrificing himself to
God.
And I think that the issue there is
something like,
well,
let's say you're supposed to offer up
the best that you have to God.
That's the sacrifice.
That's what happens with the high
quality animals that,
that Abel sacrifices.
Okay,
but there's something better than the
best that you own.
Well,
what's that?
part of it might be,
well,
the relationships you have with people,
are you willing to sacrifice them to
pursue the highest good will?
Then are you willing to sacrifice
yourself or your son like your son might
be?
That's a tough one.
I can understand the idea of sacrificing
yourself better.
I'm still wrestling with this story of
Isaiah obviously,
because that's such a complicated story
and I do think it's reasonable to think
about it as a form of foreshadowing.
At least the way the Bible is set up.
Of course people who aren't Christian
would agree with that,
but that,
that's fine.
Um,
the idea that you would offer yourself
as a sacrifice to God,
that seems to me to follow quite
logically because,
well,
obviously you have nothing greater to
give them the best of yourself.
Right?
So you sacrifice yourself to the highest
good.
And that's part of the,
that's part of the way in which humanity
is redeemed.
That makes sense to me.
That just seems like for me,
that's,
that's a pretty straightforward
psychological truth.
The son issue.
That's,
that's a lot tougher thing to wrestle
with because
one of the things I was thinking with
the,
uh,
with what Jesus says on the cross is
that one of the interpretations of that
is basically that Jesus in that moment
is human,
basically is not the,
not just Jesus the human,
right.
But that always kind of felt a little
bit like avoiding the question to me
because you can just pause it,
something like the trinity and then say,
oh,
but in this moment that doesn't go
right,
that doesn't count.
So,
but if,
if we think about it in that way of like
the difference in the direction of
sacrifice.
And it seems to me that in the
sacrifice,
whoever's making the sacrifice surf aims
toward something so Abraham is so
reaching for the divine when he
sacrifices,
when he's going to sacrifice his son.
And so that would mean maybe God is
reaching towards the human.
And so that would make some sense of
that interpretation that Christ is only
human in that moment.
Right?
That it's the sacrifices accomplished
then the richmond down accomplished.
But I'm still left with a question.
What do I make of that?
Because that's one intuitive.
I mean it's useful to have a problem
like that because it gives you something
to think about,
right?
Something to study further and it's.
It's a major.
It's a major problem.
I mean the whole issue of,
well,
we could say,
what's the relationship between the
divine and the human,
which is obviously brought to the
forefront and the idea of Christ,
right?
But it's a personal issue because part
of the issue is what's the relationship
between you as a finite entity and the
transcendent infinity that surrounds you
while there's some relationship?
Because here you are and the
transcendent infinity around you exists.
So there's a relationship.
The question is what is the
relationship?
And we don't know that and,
and,
and it's dramatized in that story.
And so I mean,
partly the reason that there's so much
conflict and confusion in that story is
because it's trying to bring opposing
things together,
right?
How can something be God and man at the
same time,
it's just like the genie,
which is the root word of genius.
By the way,
the genie is this incredibly powerful
force that can grant wishes,
right,
but it's constrained in this tiny little
space.
There is an intimation there that for
something to be real,
it has to straddle the divide between
the finite and the infinite,
and that's what human beings do.
I think to some degree,
and that's dramatized in that story,
but it doesn't mean that we understand
it.
I mean you know that sometimes you're
going to feel that way when you're
called upon to make a sacrifice.
You're going to feel that you've been
betrayed by everything,
and I'm in the store is set up that way,
right?
Christ is betrayed by tyranny.
He's betrayed by his best friends.
He's betrayed by his mortality,
like it's an archetypal story because,
and he's innocent,
so the story can't be any worse.
That's why it's our temple,
and I mean the story says to some degree
that under such conditions,
even God himself would have doubt.
It's something like that and that's a
real.
That's a powerful idea.
It's a very powerful idea.
So that's the best I can make out of
that for now.
Thank you.
We have to stop,
so we'll convene again in a week.
Thank you very much.
You.