Thank you.
Thank you very much.
Thank you very much for showing up
again.
That's a really good to see everybody
here.
So
one of the things that I've been
realizing as a consequence of going
through these stories is that
the degree to which there are about
individuals is quite remarkable and I
think that's really telling,
you know,
one of the reasons I prefer Dostoevsky
tolstoy because tolstoy is more of a
sociologist.
He's more interested in the relationship
between groups of people.
This is an oversimplification because
obviously total story's a great author,
but I'd like to stfc better because he
really delves into the souls of
individuals and I think it's remarkable.
The degree to which all of the stories
that we've covered so far in genesis are
about individuals and they're quite
realistic,
which is quite remarkable to.
They're not really romanticized to any
great degree because all of the people
that are regardless,
regardless,
let's say as patriarchal or matriarchal
figures in genesis have no shortage of
ethical Gif.
No shortage of ethical flaws and also no
shortage of difficulties in their life
and the difficulties are realistic
there.
Their major league problems,
you know,
like familial catastrophes and famine
and war and revenge and hatred and all
those things.
It's not a.
it's not a pretty.
It's not a pretty book and that's one of
the things that makes it great.
I mean that's one of the things that
characterize this great literature
right,
is that it doesn't present you with a
whitewash view of,
of,
of humanity or of existence.
And that's really a relief I think
because as you all know,
because you're alive,
there's no such thing as a whitewash.
Existence like your to be alive is to be
in trouble.
Ethically and existentially.
I've been reading this book recently.
I'll talk about it a little bit later.
It's called better never to have been
and it was written by a philosopher in
South Africa in Cape Town named Bennett.
That's his last name and he basically
argues,
I think it's a specious argument and I
think it's artificially constructed,
but he basically argues that because
life is so of suffering,
even good lives are very much full of
suffering.
That it's wrong to bring children into
the world because the suffering
outweighs the good even in good lives
and it's actually wrong.
It would also be better not to exist for
exactly the same reason and my sense in
reading the book is that he came to that
conclusion and then wrote the book to
justify it,
which is actually the reverse of the way
that you should write a book,
but you should do when you're writing a
book is you should have a question and
you should.
It should be a real question,
right?
It should be one you don't know the
answer to and then you should be
studying and writing like mad and
reading everything you can get your
hands on to see if you can actually
grapple with the problem and come to
some solution and you should walk the
reader as well through your process of
thinking so that they can come to the,
well,
not necessarily to the same conclusion,
but at least track what you're doing and
I don't think that's what he did.
I think he wrote it backwards,
but then.
And so I was thinking about it a lot
because that's actually a question that
I've contended with in my writing.
There are Memphis to Ophelia and are
satanic figures,
for example,
in girth is faust and also Ivan in the
in the brothers Karamazov who basically
make the same case,
you know,
that existence is so rife with trouble
and suffering that it would be better if
it didn't exist at all.
And the problem I've had with that,
there's a variety of them.
But one of the problems I've had with
that is what happens if you start to
think that way?
Because what I've observed is that
people who begin to think that way,
that isn't where they stop.
Like they get angry at existence,
which is what happened to cane as we saw
in the Cain and Abel Story.
And then the next step is to start
taking revenge against existence.
And that cascades until it's revenge
against.
While I think the best way of thinking
about it as revenge against God for the
crime of being,
which is I think the deepest sort of
hatred that you can entertain.
And,
and,
and when you're in the grip of a really
deep emotion,
like a really profound emotion,
right at the bottom of emotions,
you're in something that's like a quasi
religious state and that's more or less
independent of your belief,
say in a transcendent deity.
I mean you can be in a profoundly
emotional state that's as deep as it can
be and it can have religious
significance without that necessarily
signifying anything about a transcendent
being,
you know,
but,
but then I was thinking,
see,
the problem with that argument is you
can gerrymander it endlessly,
you know,
because first of all,
how do you measure suffering and how do
you measure happiness?
It's like how do you assign weights to
them and God,
there's just no way of doing that.
You have to do it arbitrarily and so you
can make an argument that the suffering
outweighs the happiness.
You just wait the suffering more heavily
than you wait the happiness and that's
the end of that,
you know?
And so that's,
that's a problem.
But I think there's a deeper problem.
And I was reading this other book a
while back as well,
which was written by the guy who ran the
human genome project,
and I don't remember exactly what it was
called,
but it was something like a scientist's
case for God.
There's something like that.
And one of the things he referred to,
which didn't strike me as hard as it
should have to begin with,
was the he,
he,
he thought that one of the phenomena say
that justified a belief in a
transcendent being with something like
the moral intuition of human beings that
know we have a sense of right and wrong.
And uh,
you know,
certainly what happens in genesis and
the story of Adam and eve is that,
that,
that story announces the coming of the
sense of right and wrong,
right?
The knowledge of good and evil.
And it isn't something we ascribe to
animals.
It's something that's unique to human
beings.
Animals can be predators and you know,
and they can be gentle and and you can
have a relationship with them,
but you never think of an evil cat or
you know,
or an evil wolf even though they're,
they're predatory,
but human beings,
we have this capacity to judge between
good and evil,
right and wrong,
and it's really an integral part of our
being and I think you can make an
evolutionary case for that,
a biological case for that as you can
make a biological case for most of what
is relevant about human beings because
we are biological creatures,
but we don't really understand the
significance of that.
Like what happens in the story of Adam
and eve is that that's that realization
that coming to the knowledge of good and
evil is actually represented as a shift
of cosmic significance,
right?
It puts a,
it puts a permanent fracture in the
structure of being and you know,
if you think of human beings as
insignificant and so on,
a tiny dust mote in the middle of an
infinite cosmos,
a cosmos that cares less for us,
then who cares?
Fundamentally,
if human beings have the knowledge to
distinguish between good and evil,
but if you give consciousness a central
role in being and you can make a
perfectly reasonable case for that
because without consciousness there's no
being as far as anyone can determine,
so it may be much more central than we
think.
And and I,
I really don't think there's a counter
argument to that,
like not a solid one.
You can state that consciousness is
empathy,
phenomenal and that the world is
fundamentally materialistic and it
doesn't matter that there's
consciousness.
You can state that,
but you can make an equally credible
case the other way.
And certainly our lived experiences,
that consciousness is crucial obviously,
and we treat each other as if most of
the time we're valuable conscious beings
and we wouldn't give up our
consciousness even though it's often
consciousness of suffering.
And so then I think another problem with
the book is that it's,
it's sort of predicated on the idea that
life is for happiness and I don't think
that's right,
and I don't think that's how people
experience life and I might be wrong,
but it seems to me that people
experience life as something like a,
a series of ethical decisions.
It's something like that.
I mean,
when I just can't imagine,
maybe I'm being naive about this,
but I can't imagine that I can't imagine
another being that's like me in most
senses,
that isn't constantly wrestling in some
sense with what the next proper thing to
do is.
It's not like it's obvious.
It's not bloody obvious and it doesn't
mean you'll do the right thing because
you don't lot lots of times and you know
that by your own judgment,
right?
Because you're making mistakes all the
time.
Sometimes you don't know what you're
doing and maybe it's a mistake and maybe
it isn't.
And who's to say that isn't what I'm
talking about.
I'm talking about when you know that
what you're doing is wrong and you go
ahead and do it anyways.
People do that all the time and that's
also extremely peculiar.
Bloody well think that if you knew it
was wrong and you told yourself that it
was wrong,
that that would be sufficient so that
you would just wouldn't do it,
but that isn't what you're like at all.
You know,
and you can tell yourself something is
wrong a 50 times and you'll do it the
51st time and then you'll feel,
you know,
like,
like you deserve to feel probably and,
but it doesn't stop you.
And so,
so then I think the other problem with
the viewpoint,
the idea that the suffering of life
eradicates its utility is that it's
predicated on the idea that happiness or
lack of suffering even is,
is the right criteria by which to judge
life.
And I don't think that's how we actually
experience life.
I think what we do instead is put
ourselves through a series of
excruciating moral choices.
You know,
when.
One of the things that that's really
significant about the biblical stories,
and I think about the the entire
implicit philosophy you know that's
embedded in the stories,
is that that's how life is presented in,
in the stories,
is all of these individuals first
through individuals to not groups and
second,
they're agonizing over their moral
choices all the time,
all the time,
and they have a relationship with God
and but it's not a.
it's not a directive relationship.
Exactly.
Even the people to whom God speaks
directly,
which I suspect is not something you'd
would exactly want to have happen,
is it's there's still even the fact that
they have a direct relationship with God
doesn't stop them from being tormented
continually by their moral choices and
so the world is presented as a a moral
landscape,
not as a,
not as a place that justifies itself by
happiness.
It's presented as a more landscape and
people are presented as creatures who
traverse through the moral landscape,
making ethical decisions that determine
the course of the world and that seems
to me to be right and that's not a.
that's not the same as happiness by any
stretch of the imagination.
It's a whole different category of being
and
you know,
one that I've thought that through a lot
and I think,
well we do make choices and what we do
is contend with the future.
The future seems to appear to us as a
realm of possibility.
That's a more accurate way of thinking
about it.
Then then that the future presents
itself to it,
to us as a realm of determined thinks
it's,
it's presents itself as a realm of
possibility and there's good choices in
that realm and there's poor choices or
even evil choices in that realm and
we're negotiating continually deciding
which of those choices we're going to
bring into being.
That seems to me to be
phenomenologically,
indisputable,
and we certainly treat each other as if
that's what we're doing because we hold
each other responsible for our actions,
you know,
with some exceptions and that we're
deciding each moment whether to make
things better or worse.
And that seems to me to be correct.
And I think that that's what these
stories illustrate.
They don't say that directly,
you know,
although I think it gets more and more
explicit as the narrative unfolds,
but,
and then part of the realism of the
stories is that,
okay,
the people aren't.
The people that are being presented are
by no means good,
mean maybe with the exception of Noah.
Noah was seemed to be a pretty good guy.
All they did,
he did get drunk and you know,
and,
and end up naked exposed to his sons and
so forth.
And.
But I mean he,
he isn't talked about a lot as a
character.
It's a pretty compressed story.
But Abraham,
I mean Abraham had plenty of problems
not least of which was his inability to
leave home and then you know,
his lying about his wife and there
there's all sorts of mistakes.
And then Jacob,
who we're going to talk about tonight is
an even more morally ambivalent
character.
He's,
especially at the beginning of the
story,
he's,
it's,
he isn't the sort of person that you
would pick out.
Especially if you were a hack writer.
You wouldn't pick him out as the hero of
the story.
He does a lot of things that are really
pretty reprehensible and takes them an
awful long time to learn better,
and yet he's the person who's put
forward as the father of the 12 tribes
of Israel.
It's from this flawed person that the
people that,
that maybe that whose story you might
say is at the fundamental,
constitutes the fundamental underpinning
of our culture.
It's,
it's from this deeply flawed individual
that that group emerges.
And so you might think about as a relief
too,
because you know,
you're no knight in shining armor,
you know,
with,
with a,
with a pure moral past.
I mean,
people make mistakes of catastrophic
proportions nonstop,
you know,
and that also means that these stories
put forward.
Something approximating hope because in
their realism,
in their moral realism,
they present heroes.
I suppose,
the heroes of renown,
right?
The Patriarchs of old,
let's say,
who are realistic,
people who have fits of anger and rage
and who are murderous at times and who
are deeply,
deeply embroiled with family dispute
and,
and who,
who have adulterous affairs and like
they do all of the terrible things that
people do.
And the weird thing is,
is that God is still with them and
you know,
it isn't obvious what that means or even
if it means anything,
but it's very,
it's not disputable as far as I can tell
that a we're conscious and that
consciousness is a transcendent
phenomena which,
which we do not understand.
And that the landscape that we traversed
through his moral,
like every store you ever watch,
anything that grips your imagination on
the screen or in the theater,
like any story that grabs you is a story
of moral striving.
It's just not interesting otherwise.
Right?
The person has to be confronted with
complex moral choices.
And then you see the outcome and you
know,
the good guy does it right and the bad
guy does it badly and things don't go so
well for the bad guy generally.
And if it's a bit more sophisticated,
the good and the bad are in the same
individual.
And that's,
you know,
that's a more compelling story.
But so we could say,
well,
let's,
we could make the assumption that it
might be worthwhile thinking of the
world as a,
as it has been thought of classically as
a theater upon which the forces of good
and evil continually strive for
dominance and I,
for the life of me,
especially after I started reading
deeply into 20th century history and all
the terrible things that happened in the
20th century and all the terrible,
unbelievably incomprehensible things
that people did to one another.
I just couldn't see seeing things any
other way is realistic now because
I don't think that you can immerse
yourself in 20th century history without
coming to the conclusion that evil is a
reality.
And if it's a reality,
it depends on what you mean by reality.
But it's fundamental enough reality for
me.
And if it's a reality,
then I don't see how you can escape from
the conclusion that the cosmos as we
experienced it at least is a place of
moral striving.
And well,
that's one of the things that's really
illustrated in the story of Jacob.
And I found that quite striking.
So,
so the last time,
last lecture,
I ended with the abrahamic stories with
the death of Sarah Abraham's wife,
and so we're going to continue from from
there.
Remember Abraham had a son,
Isaac,
and he was asked by God to sacrifice his
son,
which we talked about in in some depth
and I was attempting to make the case
that you know,
the idea of sacrifice was one of human
kinds,
great discoveries because it meant the
discovery of the future essentially,
but it also meant the discovery that the
future was something that you could make
a bargain with and that you could give
up something now,
something impulsive,
some pleasure,
even a deep pleasure in the moment,
and you could strive and hypothetically
you could make a covenant to bargain
with the future.
And if your sacrifices were acceptable
and that seemed to mean an ethically
acceptable,
you had to sacrifice the right thing.
That that vastly increased the
probability that not only you would be
successful,
let's say,
but that your descendants would be too.
And I don't think that that's an
irrational proposition.
I mean,
you have to leave in it a bit with the
realization that sometimes you know you
get sliced off at the knees no matter
what,
right?
Because life has an arbitrary element
and and that can be tossed out,
but building in the arbitrary element
will say,
you still want to think,
well,
what's your best bet?
Given a certain amount of randomness,
and it seems to me that conscious self
aware sacrifice and proper ethical
striving is your best bet.
And you know there another idea that
I've always explained it when I've
explained it to people.
I've always used the movie Pinocchio as
an example.
You know that when Japan was trying to
make his puppet into a self aware and
autonomous moral agent,
which is what he wants above all else,
he aims at the highest good.
That he can conceive w which is the star
that he prays to essentially and hopes
for the transformation.
And there's also something in that
that's unalterably profound and maybe
that is somewhat independent of the idea
that you have to believe in God.
I would also say that what it means to
believe in God in the Old Testament is
by no means clear,
and that's something I also really want
to talk about tonight.
It's not obvious what it means and well
Japan know what he does,
at least his aim at the highest good of
which he can conceive,
you know,
and that that's actually been a
philosophical definition of God upon
occasion that God is the highest good of
which you conceive.
And that's different than the idea of a
transcendent being.
Precisely,
but it's in line with.
It's in line with certain interesting
psychoanalytic speculations.
This is one of the things I really liked
about Carl Young,
you know,
young was so radical,
a thinker.
It's just beyond belief.
Like I've read a lot of critics of young
and I've always,
I've always got a kick out of them
because the things they accuse young of
are so trivial compared to the things
that young actually did that it's like
accusing a murderer of jaywalking.
Like because young was unbelievably
radical.
Like here's one of his ideas.
You know,
he thought that it was necessary.
He believed that psychotherapy could be
replaced by a supreme moral effort and
so the moral effort would be something
like aiming after good and then trying
to integrate yourself around that and
that the good at which you aim would be
something approximating what you would
be like if you manifested your full
potential and that you have a glimmering
of what that full potential was,
so that would be the potential future
you and he thought of that.
He thought of people as four dimensional
entities,
especially essentially that we're
stretched across time and that you as a
totality across time,
including your potential manifested
yourself also in the here and now and
that part of what your potential
manifested itself was something like the
voice of conscious conscience or
intuition.
It's amazing idea.
It's an amazing idea,
right?
Because it's like what you could be in
the future,
beckons to you in the present and helps
you determine the difference between
good and evil.
It's a mind boggling idea and you know,
I think that it's an idea you have to
contend with and then he went further
than that.
This is,
this is also remarkable idea,
you know,
he,
he was interested in this symbolic
representation of Christ and I mean
psychologically speaking,
and he thought of Christ as the
representation of the ideal potential
human.
It's something like that.
So it was a symbolic,
at minimum,
that's what Christ was,
is a symbolic representation of the
ideal potential of a human being.
And so for young,
there was no difference between,
there was no psychological difference
between who you could be in the future
beckoning to you and the prey in the
present and orienting yourself in
relationship to Christ psychologically.
Those were the same thing.
And then so that's a pretty mindboggling
idea.
Like,
seriously,
that's a mind boggling idea,
you know,
especially when you add the
psychological idea that the.
One of the things that characterize as
your ideal future self is the ability to
make sacrifices,
right?
And the deeper the sacrifice,
the better.
And then also to recover from the
sacrifice,
right?
So that's the death and rebirth.
So the part of you that's most essential
to your full flowering as a,
as a being is your ability to let things
go.
And then spring back from that,
so to die in some sense and to be reborn
in the service of a higher good.
And then,
well then the next part of that is that
the direction of the world depends on
you doing that.
So not only your own life but your
family's life.
And because we're networked so intently
together,
you know,
the,
the whole panoply of human kind and
maybe the structure of the,
of the cosmos.
And you know,
you might think,
well no,
but you know,
it's not so simple.
It's not so simple.
First of all,
one person can wreak an awful lot of,
there's absolutely no doubt about that.
And as we get more technologically
powerful,
that becomes even more relevant and
important and crucial.
You know,
one of the things that you said was that
we had to wake up because we are too
technologically powerful to be as
morally asleep as we are.
And that seems to me just to be self
evident.
That's.
Yeah,
for sure.
That's true.
We're,
we're,
we're half asleep with nuclear bombs.
It's not a good idea.
It's seriously not a good idea.
And so.
Well,
and then you might ask yourself too,
you don't.
We're like,
what is the ultimate potential of a
fully developed human being?
And well,
we certainly know that you have
admiration for people who are more
developed rather than less developed.
That's,
that just happens automatic or
resentment that.
But that's okay.
It's the same thing.
It doesn't matter,
but it's not like you can't identify
them.
You can identify them,
you know,
and,
and they're put forward to you in,
in,
in drama and fiction and all of that
constantly.
So that's another form of moral
intuition,
you know,
you can read,
you can discern the wheat from the
chaff,
let's say.
And,
and so
the other thing that I was thinking
about it's worth consideration too,
is that,
you know,
and maybe this is,
maybe this is petty,
but I don't think it is.
Somebody asked me the other day if I
believed in miracles and I hate being
asked questions like that,
you know,
and you know,
it's also people ask me to do,
I believe in God and I'm like,
I don't know what they mean when they
say that.
So I don't know what to answer because I
don't think we're taught necessarily
going to talk about the same thing,
but in any case I said yes and I have a
variety of reasons for that,
but one of them is that,
you know,
the consensus among physicists is that
we can track the origin of the cosmos to
something like 100 million of a
millionth of a second after the big
bang.
It's like it's so close to the big bang
that the difference is literally
infinitesimal.
But the consensus is that before that,
whatever that is,
the laws of physics themselves
breakdown,
well,
what?
What do you call an event that
exists outside the laws of physics?
That by definition that's a miracle.
Now that doesn't necessarily mean that
there's a transcendent daddy that caused
the event.
That's a separate issue,
but it does imply a barrier of some sort
beyond which we can't go where some
other set of rules apply.
And so I find that interesting as well.
So all right,
so dies and Abraham makes a bargain with
the hittites to purchase a burial place
for her and they offer it as a gift and
he insists upon paying for it.
It's a little story that basically
indicates two things that Abraham was
the kind of guy that you trust pretty
much when you see them and that even if
something is offered to him as a gift,
he's going to do everything to be
reciprocal about it.
And so it's not a massively important
part of the story,
but it's,
it's in keeping with the same narrative
flow.
And so if Ron,
who's a hittite,
offers a burial place as a gift and
Abraham says,
no,
you know,
you have to let me pay for it,
and everyone says he will.
And that works out very well.
And so he has a burial place for his
wife.
And then Abraham decides that Isaac
needs a wife.
And so he sends his eldest servant to
Mesopotamia to find a wife for Isaac.
And there's this strange ritual that's
performed.
So it says in the story that the servant
places his hand under Abraham's thigh
to,
to swear,
but that isn't really what it means.
It means that he places his hand.
I don't know exactly how to say this
properly.
Well,
use your imagination.
How about that?
And the idea is that as far as I can
tell that he's swearing on the future,
he's swearing on future people.
It's something like that.
So that,
that's sort of what testified means,
right?
Think about the route while.
I'm not kidding,
I'm not kidding.
That is what that is the derivation,
right?
If it is the derivation.
So,
so,
uh,
so anyways,
this is a serious issue.
So that servant has to go and find
Isaac,
a good wife and he wants him to find
a wife who is willing to accept the same
fundamental belief system,
which is something like the belief in a
God that's a unity rather than a
plurality.
You know,
the other thing that young was very
insistent upon was that there was a
relationship between polytheism and
psychological confusion and monotheism
and psychological unification.
And I really liked that idea too,
that you know that that what you're
trying to do,
because you are a plurality,
that that's one of the things the
psychoanalysts were really good at
figuring out that the cognitive
scientists haven't touched yet as far as
I can tell they're way behind the
psychoanalysts and that element of
thinking is that you are composed of sub
personalities which all have their own
desires and their own viewpoint in their
own thoughts and their own perceptions
and they're in a war with each other
constantly,
maybe even a Darwinian war.
It's been.
It's been portrayed that way by certain
neuroscientists and that that one of the
goals of life is to
integrate all of that plurality into a
hierarchical ethical structure that has
some canonical ethic at the pinnacle.
Right?
We've talked a little bit about that and
it's not obvious what should be at the
pinnacle,
but we can guess at it.
It's,
it's that which we admire.
That's one way of thinking about it.
It's that that describes fair play
across a sequence of games.
That's another good way of thinking
about it.
It's,
it's the heroic ideal that's another way
of thinking about it,
but it's combined with generosity,
you know,
because the hero,
the mythological hero goes out into the
unknown and slays the dragon and gets
the gold,
but then comes back to the community and
distributes what's found.
And so it's courage plus generosity and
um,
and so all of your,
all of that interior struggling that
you're doing is an attempt to hang
yourself against the world with
challenge,
constantly to hit everything together,
like you're beating on a piece of iron
to,
to cure it,
let's say,
so that you don't,
you're not an internal contradiction.
You're not massive competing God,
something like that because it's just
too psychologically stressful and hard
on everyone else and impossible for them
to get along with you if you're one
thing,
one moment and another thing,
another moment.
And so.
So anyways,
Abraham insists that Isaac find a wife
from among people who are likely to
carry off forward the monotheistic
tradition.
And I'm not sure that the monotheistic
tradition is actually indistinguishable,
is actually distinguishable from the
individualistic tradition.
I think they might be the same thing at
different levels of analysis,
you know,
so because individual means and divided
in some sense,
right?
To be an individual means to be one
thing and the other thing that mitigates
against the idea of life is happiness is
it isn't obvious to me that it's
happiness.
That is what molds you and shapes you.
You know,
it's something more like optimal
challenge voluntarily undertaken at
something like that.
Right.
And I think that's echoed in the idea
that everyone has a moral obligation to
raise their cross,
something like that,
to accept the fact of their mortality
voluntarily.
I believe that that's the case and I do
actually think that that's a
prerequisite to proper psychological
development because if you're not
willing to take your mortality on
voluntarily,
like if you're kicking and fighting
about it constantly and you have every
reason to don't get me wrong,
then you can't act forthrightly in the
world.
Right?
You're going to be afraid and when
you're afraid,
then you can't voluntarily take on a
challenge.
And then if you can't take voluntarily
take on a challenge,
then you can't develop.
And so again,
the life seems to be something like if
it's a proper life is a voluntarily
voluntary taking on of great challenges
and maybe that's better than happiness.
Like it's certainly more noble,
you know,
it's not a word we use very much
anymore.
The idea of nobility because we're so
obsessed with happiness.
But I think happiness is a,
like if it comes along,
man,
great,
you know,
wonderful.
Don't,
don't take it lightly or for granted
because it's fleeting.
But the idea that that's what you should
be for in some sense to seems to me,
if,
if that's what life is for,
then maybe it shouldn't be.
Maybe that's correct because that isn't
what life is,
but it also doesn't.
It isn't obvious to me that that's what
life should be,
you know?
I mean,
if you really loved someone like your
son,
let's say,
would you say,
well,
I hope he has a happy life,
or would you say,
I hope he accomplishes great things.
It seems to me that that's better than
that.
The accomplishing of great things
because that's admirable.
You know?
It's like a happy person is a happy
person.
But a noble person has an admirable
person and and that's,
that's better at man,
and so maybe there are better things
than happiness and so you can't judge
being on the basis of the ratio of
suffering to pleasure,
something like that.
It's,
and I don't think we do that.
I don't believe we do that be comedians
are happy,
right?
But everyone doesn't aspire to be a
comedian and you don't watch comedy all
the time,
even though you could laugh nonstop more
or less if the comedians funny.
You want to get your teeth into
something.
And also seems to me that this is one of
the reasons I liked existential
philosophy was that,
you know,
the existentialists believed it's sort
of an original sin idea.
They believe that we came into the world
with an ethical burden already laid upon
us something,
something like that,
and that we had a felt sense that it was
necessary for us to justify our being.
And if we didn't do that,
then we weren't authentic to ourselves.
We weren't moving towards individuality.
We weren't sustaining the community.
We weren't living properly and that and
that,
that idea was deeply embedded in people
as part of their ordinary experience and
that also seems to me to be accurate and
you know,
I've dealt with lots of people say in my
clinical practice and
they don't really cut.
They are,
they will come and say,
I wish I wasn't so unhappy,
but they don't usually come and say I
wish I was happier and those things
aren't the same.
And then when,
when,
when you talk to people who are having
trouble,
you know,
they want to straighten things out and
figure out how to do them right.
It's something like that.
And,
and that that's the primary,
that's their primary goal.
And
so anyways,
Abraham sends his eldest servant off to
his place that God has granted him to
find a wife.
And interestingly,
it,
the borders of the promised land under
quite similar to the current borders of
Israel.
I mean,
these are estimates right?
Based on the biblical and didn't mean
that's not a fluke obviously,
but it's interesting to see the
concordance between these ancient
stories in the present day world.
So I thought that was very interesting
and it shows once again that the past,
you think the past is the past,
but it's not,
it's still here.
It's embedded in the present,
you know,
just like the future in somehow in some
ways is folded up inside the president
waiting to unfold.
The past is all folded up inside the
present too.
So anyways,
the servant goes to
the land that he's been charged to go to
an end.
He,
he's,
he's trying to figure out how in the
world am I going to find a good wife for
Isaac.
I mean I don't know any of these people.
And so he has this little dialogue
that's presented in the form of a prayer
I suppose.
Um,
and he thinks,
well,
I'm going to go to the,
the place where you water,
where people get water and water,
the animals.
And um,
because that's a place where everyone
gathers.
So that's a good place to find someone.
And,
and it,
it's,
it's not a place of fun and lightness
and relaxation and impulsivity.
It's a place of,
of,
of life sustaining work.
And then he thinks something like,
well,
what would a decent girl do at a
watering place?
And he thought,
well,
maybe she would offer a stranger some
water and also offer to water the camels
because that would be brave to approach
the stranger and then generous and then
indicative of the willingness to make an
effort.
And when you know that a camel,
I think he took 10 camels.
It was quite a few camels anyways,
not just one.
And that accountable can drink 20
gallons of water.
And Rebecca,
who was drawing water from the wet turns
out to be Rebecca is drawing water from
the well,
which is hard,
right?
Because water's heavy and you have to
lift it up and it's 10 camels.
And so that's like 200 gallons of water.
So,
you know,
she has to put herself out a fair bit in
order to make this stranger happy.
And so that's what happens.
And then the service has brought along
gifts and that sort of thing.
And any ways to make a long story short,
uh,
Rebecca agrees to come back,
to come back with the servant and marry
Isaac.
And so
then she has,
she gets pregnant and she has twins and
this is an interesting thing.
The twins fight inside her,
she can tell that they're not getting
along.
And this is an echo,
right?
It's an echo of Cain and Abel and the
mythological motif that the unions have
called the hostile brothers,
the hostile brothers,
and you see them all the time,
Batman and the joker or hostile brothers
and thor and or hostile brothers and I,
it's an unbelievably common motif.
And you know,
the ultimate hostile brothers or Christ
and Satan.
So that's the,
that's the archetipal representation of
the hostile brothers,
right?
The ultimate good and the ultimate evil.
And so and so it's an echo of the Cain
and Abel Story.
Although it's a little more complex,
I would say from a literary point of
view because it isn't obvious which of
these brothers,
his cane and which of them is able,
they have parts of both in each of them.
So Esau,
who's turns out to be one of the
brothers and Jacob who turns out to be
the other oath,
have they're admirable qualities and
their fault.
Anyways.
I'm Esau comes is born first,
but Jacob hasn't by the heel and so
there was a fight within the womb to see
who would emerge first.
Now that's relevant because the
firstborn had a special status.
While it has a special status in many
communities,
especially agricultural communities,
and there's a reason these people were
more hurts people.
But if you divide your property equally
among all your children that had like
three generations,
everybody has one goat and everybody
starves to death,
you know,
or the same thing happens with land.
So one of the ways that,
that traditional communities solve that
is they just give almost everything to
the first board and then the everyone
else knows,
well you go out and do whatever you can
and it's kind of arbitrary and unfair,
but you know,
at least it's predictably arbitrary and
unfair instead of doom over four
generations,
you know,
so it actually mattered to be the first
born and,
and God generally favors the first born.
And then you might think,
well,
what is it about being born first that's
so relevant apart from the,
the cultural practice of,
of aboard.
Generous inheritance.
And I would say,
well the first born is something like
the model for the leader of the family,
right?
Because the first born child should be,
if there's a number of siblings,
a should take care of the siblings at
least to some degree,
but also should be a role model for
them.
So it's like a natural position of
leadership.
But there's a cycle,
there's a cycle psychology ization of
the idea of the first board in these
stories because God often passes over
the firstborn in favor of a later born
child.
Um,
he seems to do that on the basis of
moral character essentially.
And so there's this idea that,
well,
there's a natural proclivity towards
leadership that's just a biological fact
that would be associated with being a
first born.
But there's an element of
characterological development that
transcends that.
And so that you,
it's more important to be spiritually a
firstborn,
let's say,
than to be biologically a first born.
And God recognizes that continually in
these stories and inverts the natural
order and favors a later board.
And who's,
who's done more work with regards to
characterological development.
And that's also interesting too,
you know,
I've talked to lots of business people
about leadership and there's a
literature on leadership,
but it's not a good literature.
It's pretty shallow,
um,
partly because it's not that easy to
define leadership and partly because
there are different,
you know,
people have different temperaments and
different temperaments can be leaders.
They just do it in different ways.
Now there's something in common about
being a leader though.
And I would say one is that if you're an
actual leader,
you actually know where you're going,
right?
Because what are you going to do lead
people in circles.
It's like maybe they'll follow you but
you're not a leader,
you're just a charlotte.
And so you have to know where you're
going and then you have to be able to
communicate that and then people have to
trust you.
So you actually have to be honest
because people aren't that stupid,
at least not for a long period of time.
And then where are you going has to have
some value because otherwise why would
anyone want to go along with you?
So,
and then you might say,
well,
what,
what are the attributes that make you a
leader?
And I would say,
well,
they're characterological fundamentally,
and this is not naive optimism or,
or,
or casual moralizing.
It has nothing to do with that.
You know,
we know,
for example,
that conscientious notice that the
personality trait is a good predictor of
longterm success in,
in most occupations,
not all but most,
and that one of the things that's
associated with conscientiousness is the
people keep their word,
they're trustworthy.
And that's certainly one element of a
leader,
especially across any reasonable amount
of time.
You have to be able to trust the person.
They can even be harsh,
right?
It doesn't matter because you can see
harsh leaders and kind leaders,
but as long as they do what they say
they will do,
then then you can follow them and you
know that the future payoff is,
is,
is secure,
something like that.
So the idea that character,
logical development is more important to
leadership than primogenitor.
I think that's the right word,
a primal genesis anyways,
being a first born,
that's a very crucial psychological
realization that it's characterological
development that makes you favored of
God.
You know,
and I do think we've forgotten this in
many ways because there isn't a lot of
emphasis in our education system on
characterological development and that's
very,
very surprising to me.
I think maybe it's partly because in our
fractured society,
we can't agree on what constitutes a
reasonable characterological goal.
So we just throw up our hands and don't
educate our kids to any degree at all,
especially in schools about what an
admirable person is like or even let
them know that,
well,
maybe you should actually try to be one.
You know,
that that's actually the most important
possible thing that you could learn.
Right?
So,
and I also think,
and I think this is laid out very
thoroughly in the biblical stories as
well,
that if there are enough people who are
admirable,
then things work and if there aren't,
then things.
Things are terrible.
You get wiped out.
You remember when Abraham is bargaining
with God with regards to Sodom and
Gomorrah,
he asked God to save the city if there's
like 40 admirable people,
right?
Respectable,
but let's say admirable,
right?
I don't want it.
I don't want to say good because good is
being corrupted in some sense by casual
usage.
I mean admirable noble people,
right?
I think Abraham bargains God down to
like 10.
If there's 10 of them in the city,
the city won't be destroyed and that
that's not very many in the city.
So there's an interesting idea there
which is that there,
there doesn't have to be that many
people in a group who have their act
together,
but zero is the wrong number and if it's
zero then then we're seriously in
trouble.
And I think that goes along with the
idea of the Preto principle in economics
too,
which is that it's a small minority of
people who do most of the productive
work in any given domain,
but so,
so a small number of properly behaving
people might have enough of an impact to
keep everything moving.
And that might also.
That might actually be true,
but it can't fall below some crucial
level and I do think that we're in some
danger of allowing it to fall below some
crucial level because our society seems
to be at war in some ways against the
idea of the individual and individual
character per se.
And I think that's absolutely.
I think that's absolutely catastrophic
and that's part of the reason that I'm
doing these biblical lectures,
you know,
because I think that I've known for a
long time that the moral presuppositions
of a culture are instantiated in its
stories.
They're not instantiated and it's
explicit philosophy.
There might be a layer of explicit
philosophy and of course there is in the
west and a layer of explicit law,
but underneath that there are stories
and there isn't anything under the
stories except maybe behavior,
you know,
and that's so implicit.
It doesn't even actually count.
It's not a cognitive operation.
And so this is the story.
These are the stories that are
underneath our culture and so there
better be something to them.
That's what we hope.
And but more importantly,
maybe we shouldn't toss them away
without knowing what they mean because
if we toss them away,
then we are throwing everything that we
depend on a way as far as I can tell and
we'll we will pay for it.
We'll pay for it individually because
we'll be weak,
you know,
because if you're not firm in your
convictions than someone else who's from
in their convictions,
can your,
their puppet like instantly.
And then you're also the puppet of your
own doubts,
right?
Because unless you have convictions,
you're going to generate doubts like mad
because everyone does.
And then the doubts when,
and you'll be paralyzed because there'll
be,
you know,
50 percent of you moving forward in 50
percent of you frozen,
stiff and that'll be enough just to
lodge you in place.
And so,
okay,
so there's a psychologist,
creation of the idea of leadership,
which is very important.
And then it's associated with the idea
of character or logical development and
it's associated with the idea of
struggle,
not happiness.
And it's also associated with this
abrahamic idea,
which I really liked,
which was something that's been very
useful to me as a consequence of doing
these lectures because remember,
at the beginning of the abrahamic
stories,
Abraham's like a stay at home guy,
right?
He's like the guy who's 40 years old
living in his,
in his,
in his mother's basement,
and God says like,
get,
get the hell out of there,
you know,
get out in the world where you belong.
Go do something difficult because what
you're doing isn't acceptable.
And you know,
the first thing he does is go somewhere,
there's a terrible famine and then he
goes somewhere.
There's a tyranny.
So,
you know,
it's,
it's pretty funny.
He follows God's call and it's not like
sweetness and light and paradise
immediately.
It's nothing like that.
It's,
it's instantaneous combat,
you know,
of the most difficult kind.
So,
but,
but Abraham does in fact follow that
impulse.
You know?
It's interesting too.
I mean,
I don't know.
Here's another thing that made me a
really an advocate of psychoanalytic
thinking it.
It was the sort of thing that started to
terrify me about what the human psyche
was actually like.
I started to understand that not only
were we like an amalgam of,
of relatively autonomous
subpersonalities,
each of which had the possibility of
gaining control,
but that we're also victim,
you might say,
or beneficiary of impulses that were
beyond our conscious formulation or,
or,
or understanding or capacity to resist.
So here's this,
here's a funny story.
So I was talking to one of my patron
people online this week and he said he's
a,
he was a committed atheist and that's
fine,
you know,
lots of atheists are very honest people
and they're atheist because they don't
know how to reconcile what they know
with traditional claims,
let's say.
And they're not willing to just mangled
them together,
you know,
and there might be cynicism,
all data associated with it as well.
But he said he was,
he said he was entranced by these
biblical lectures,
you know,
which is pretty weird.
And he said,
if someone would have told him a year
ago that he was going to like be
obsessed with a sequence of biblical
lectures,
he would have told them that they were
mad.
And so we had a bit of a discussion
about that because this is an
interesting thing,
you know,
and he,
he mentioned this,
he said it was something like,
you don't choose your interests.
They choose you.
And that's really worth thinking about
too,
man,
because you know it's really hard to get
interested in something you're not
interested in.
Even if you know there's a good reason
for it,
you know you're studying for an exam,
you find the material boring.
You know anything will be more
interesting than,
than this studying.
Even though you know that that's what
you need to do.
You can't voluntarily grab yourself by
the scruff of the neck,
let's say,
and shake yourself and say,
sit down and concentrate.
Your mind will just go everywhere.
But then if you're interested in
something,
and even if it's something you shouldn't
be interested in,
because that happens all the time,
then it's like you're a laser focused
man.
You can pay attention forever,
you can work until you're exhausted,
you won't even notice it.
Then you remember everything.
It's like,
okay,
if you can't control your interest,
what does?
And now I tell you,
you can think about that for a very long
time.
So you talked about the spirit
Mercurius,
you know,
Mercury's the wing messenger of the gods
and,
and here's how he conceptualized it.
Psychologically,
he thought this is what the ancient
people who thought about mercury as the
winged messenger of the gods were trying
to state psychologically,
you know,
your,
your interest flits around.
It's like there's something that
captures it and that moves your interest
from place to place.
You know,
like if you walk into a bookstore,
you'll get interested in a particular
book.
It's as if the book grips you because
you don't know why you're interested in.
You might,
but often you don't know why you're
interested in that book and you know
your interest is flitting around.
And so that's mercury.
The thing that makes your interest flick
flick around his mercury,
the winged messenger of the gods and
mercury is the messenger of the gods
because it's the things behind the
scenes psychologically that are
manipulating your attention and for
young those were equivalent in some
sense to the last gods.
And so for young your,
your interest was being manipulated
behind the scenes by unseen forces that
were associated with your character or
logical development across time.
That was the manifestation of the self.
So the self is this the,
the potential you let's say,
and the way it operates in the present
is by gripping your interest in
directing it somewhere.
And that's part of the instinct of self
realization.
It's a mind boggling idea,
man.
Really,
it's,
I think it's correct.
I can't see how it can't be correct.
It doesn't mean I understand it
completely,
but it certainly seems
phenomenologically correct and I mean
the potential that you are has to
manifest itself somehow in the here and
now it has to.
And what better way than by directing
your attention,
you know,
it's like it seems like this might be
useful for you,
or maybe you get attracted to this
person.
Maybe you admire this person.
That happens with kids a lot.
They'll admire someone and then copy
them and you can see that that's
obviously part of their developmental
progression,
right?
It's a form of hero worship,
but kids are very imitative and they
hear a worship at the drop of a hat and
so they're.
They're entranced by the next stage of
development.
And if they see someone who embodies
that,
especially if it's in the zone of
proximal development,
it's some something they could achieve
stretching a bit.
They find someone who embodies that next
stage of development and then they start
to imitate them and act like them while
we're adults are no different.
We're no different.
We're just.
We do it at a perhaps more abstract and
sophisticated level.
So okay,
so Jacob and Esau are are hostile
brothers.
They're like Cain and Abel except the
mixture of Cain and Abel and they're
very different.
Esau was red and covered with hair.
He was a hunter and a man of the field.
So he's like your basic jock,
right?
He's extroverted,
he's outgoing,
he's really tough.
He's like extraordinarily masculine.
He haunts and he's a real favorite of
his father.
And so,
and,
and Jacob isn't,
he's a dweller intense and um,
yeah,
right.
Exactly,
exactly.
Exactly right.
And it says Isaac loved Esau,
but Rebecca loved Jacob.
Now that's a problem,
right?
That's a big problem.
And that there's a freudian element to
this.
It's like this family is now divided
because one child is the favorite of the
mother and that's Jacob and one child is
the favorite of the father.
And so Jacob is kind of a mother's boy,
I guess to use an arc rather archaic
phrase and certainly not as admirable
from his father's perspective as Esau
who was a tough guy who goes out with a
bow and Arrow and like,
you know,
wanders around in the plains and brings
animals home.
And he's tough.
He's a tough guy.
So,
and,
but,
but there's this discord in the family
because one parent prefers one child and
the other parent prefers the other.
And it's obvious from the story that the
parents do not communicate about this
because they really take sides.
And so there's a split in the family and
that's,
I think very realistic because one of
the things that you do learn if you have
a family,
and of course most of you do,
but if you also think about families,
is that there's,
there's deep divisions within families
very,
very frequently that no one will ever
talk about and,
or even think about often because it's
too painful to think about,
you know,
Freud himself said Freud was clearly his
mother's favorite and the family
sacrificed a lot,
including some of the potential
ambitions of the other children in order
to kind of put Sigmund Freud up on a
pedestal.
And,
and advanced is education.
And it worked.
I mean,
you know,
he,
he turned into a great man,
but there was a cost to his siblings and
Freud himself said that there was
something about being the favorite of
the mother that gave a person additional
confidence throughout their life.
And you know,
there's,
there's something to be said about that.
Even someone like Eric Erickson,
you know,
he noted that he was very interested in
child development,
that that first bonding with the mother
was the,
was the place where trust was
established,
maybe trust,
even in the goodness of existence was
established.
And so anyways,
Jacob is Rachel's favorite and a Isa was
Isaac's favorite.
Now Esau being extroverted,
let's say,
is also a bit impulsive and maybe he's
not.
He's a man of action.
He's not a forward thinker,
but he's also doing hard work.
And so,
you know,
he goes out and he's hunting and he's
worn out and he comes home and he's
faint with hunger and Jacob is at home.
Cooking is boiling up lentils,
red lentils and um,
you know,
Esau comes in from the Honda at east,
like half starved to death and he's
sitting there and the aroma of these red
lentils reaches them and he's exhausted
and,
and he tells Jacob that he wants some of
this stew and Jacob who's being a pain
in the neck,
fundamentally have basically says no,
there's a,
there's a teasing thing going on here
and won't give them any.
And,
and,
and there's,
you have to imagine this because it's
not laid out explicitly in the story,
but there's some dispute about whether
Esau gets to have lunch and Jacob
finally says,
well,
I'll give you some,
but you have to,
you have to give me your birthright and
Esau,
you think he must say something like,
well,
to hell with it,
take it,
you know,
you son of a bitch,
take it.
Just give me some damn stew at something
like that.
So that's what happens.
But you know,
with these archaic people,
once he made a statement like that,
that was,
you were done.
That was it.
And so I'm.
Esau sells his birthright and this turns
out to be incredibly significant.
Benson who wrote Biblical commentary
said,
Oh,
there's a bit of a twist to it.
So Esau eats the red lentils and then
from then on,
his name is red and you've got to use
your imagination a bit.
I mean,
people are making fun of him,
right?
That's why they're calling them red.
I mean he's already read because we
established that,
but no one was calling them read before
this.
And so for the rest of his life,
you know,
every time he goes out amongst his
friends and family,
they call them red and sort of snicker
because he's the,
you know,
half famished idiot who sold his
birthright for a bowl of lentils.
And so it's,
it's not,
it's not that funny actually.
And so Esau is not happy about this and
it actually turns out that this.
So what does it mean?
It means don't sell the future for the
desires of the present and don't be
casual about what you have.
And then there's an archetype will
element to this too.
And Benson says,
various have been the opinions what this
birthright was,
which Esau sold,
but the most probable is that together
with the right of sacrificing.
So determining what should be sacrificed
and when and being the priest of the
family,
it included the peculiar blessing
promised to the seed of Abraham,
that of being the progenitor of the
Messiah and the error of the special
promises of God,
respecting Christ's kingdom.
It was at least typical of spiritual
privileges.
Those of the firstborn that are written
in heaven.
Well,
that's a lot harsher than meets the eye
to begin with,
and so there's a very interesting deep
moral story there,
which is,
it's sort of Esau does the opposite of a
sacrifice.
It's the reverse,
right?
He sacrifices the future for the
present.
And so the story basically says,
the way it's laid out across stories is
that if you're the sort of person that
sacrifices the future to the present,
then that eradicates the possibility
that you will bring the most noble being
into existence.
That's what it means.
And you can,
again,
this is the psychological significance
of the biblical stories.
So
that's a bad thing to do if you want to
realize your potential.
Let's say you don't do reverse
sacrifices,
that's a very bad idea.
And so esl really did himself in by
being too attached to the present
without a vision of the future.
So he's too in the moment,
you know,
and,
and he pays a heavy price for it.
I mean,
he's the,
first of all,
he loses his birthright and his double
inheritance.
So there's a practical consequence and
then there's a spiritual consequence.
And then he's,
while he's been made a fool of by his
brother,
Jacob means supplanter by the way,
that's what the name means.
And Jacob is always trying to usurp esl
as,
as we see.
And so Jacob gets one over on them and
you know,
that's not,
doesn't make an older brother happy when
a younger brother gets something over on
them,
that's for sure.
And then he loses the opportunity to be
the progenitor of the Messiah,
which is like,
he probably didn't realize that
precisely,
but it seems to be,
you know,
it's kind of rough.
That.
So.
And then there's,
there's a statement in Matthew Sixteen,
26 for what is a man profited if he
shall gain the whole world and loses his
own soul or what shall a man give in
exchange for a soul?
It's an echo of the same idea.
You know,
when you think,
well,
what is this idea of soul mean?
And it's not intellect.
And it said something like,
it's something like consciousness allied
with character.
I think.
And I think the reason that it's valued
so much is that because he got to ask
yourself,
well,
what do you really have when it comes
down to it?
So life is suffering,
let's say,
and you know you can,
you can pile up worldly goods,
and the God in the Old Testament doesn't
seem to have anything against that
radiate,
right?
The people who he favors seem to prosper
quite nicely in the world,
but they also have to make a choice
between whether they're going to
fundamentally sustain their character or
whether they're going to prosper in the
world when push comes to shove and the
idea of constantly is that really what
you have in the world that allows you
the best possible defense against the
suffering that's intrinsic to being as
your character.
That's what you have,
period.
And I don't think there is anything
that's more psychologically true than
that,
you know,
because everything else.
Well,
first of all,
your relationships with others depending
on your character.
And certainly this is part of the story
of Noah's Ark,
you know,
because his generations were perfect.
So we had a very tight familial
arrangement.
Everyone trusted each other.
That's a big deal.
If you hit a rocky patch in your life,
right,
and it's character that it's character
that determines that you know,
if you're generous and honest and all of
those things and people know they can
rely on you,
assuming they're not resentful,
that's a whole different story.
Then they're going to come to your aid
when,
when it's necessary,
they're going to pull it together with
you and you know when people are really
after you for one reason or another and
they're accusing you of all sorts of
things and you're guilty because you
have a past.
It's laden with character,
logical errors.
Then it's very easy for people to take
you down because they'll poke,
they hit a place where you're guilty and
then you're done because you'll do
yourself in with your own judgment and
so well.
So He makes a very big mistake and
there's a sacrificial idea here too,
which is,
you know now,
and then you're going to be faced with a
situation where it's something you
really want or your character.
Maybe you'll have to lie about something
you know and you'll think are what
difference does it make you know a lie
about it.
Jacob does this,
but the problem,
there's a bunch of problems with that.
One is that,
well,
now you know that you're the sort of
person that will in fact deceive
yourself about the nature of reality if
something shiny is dangled in front of
you,
and that's not good because it
undermines your faith in yourself and
when you're really in trouble,
they call that the dark night of the
soul.
When you're really in trouble,
that's what you've got.
You've got whether or not you can trust
yourself and that's it.
You know when things are really harsh,
and so if you've betrayed yourself in
that manner,
then you weaken yourself under the worst
possible circumstances.
And that's just,
that's really not a good thing.
So this is very practical advice.
Um,
it's not casual moralizing.
There's very little casual moralizing in
these stores.
In the next part of the story,
there's some parallels with Abraham and
that's built into the narrative,
I think because Isaac is Abraham's
descendant.
And so we have to keep the narrative
echoing forward,
otherwise it loses its continuity and
there was a famine in the land that
Isaacson and God tells him to stay the
course anyways,
repeating the promise he gave Abraham,
although Isaac goes to check also
telling the king and people that Rebecca
was his sister,
which is exactly what Abraham did when
he went to Egypt.
And so there's another echo there of the
same,
the same.
It's as if the story is being told for a
second time essentially.
And that's supposed to remind you of
the,
of the previous story,
but they're careless.
The king sees that Rebecca and Isaac are
intimate together.
And um,
luckily he doesn't have them put to
death.
He just tells everybody in the kingdom
that there to be left the hell alone.
And then Isaac prospers in Atlanta,
just like Abraham did in Egypt until the
Philistines ask him to leave.
He's just getting too rich and powerful.
Things are going too well for him.
So he's asked,
he's asked to leave.
Now,
in the meantime,
Esau gets married,
and this is a funny little story.
He says he marries two women who give
grief to Isaac and Rebecca,
so whoever he saw Mary's,
they're not popular with his,
with their in laws,
not in the least.
That actually becomes relevant a little
later because they drive rebecca quite
mad.
So I get a kick out of that because
that's very common,
you know,
it's not easy to integrate new people
into your family and,
and hope that that will go smoothly.
It's one of the real catastrophes
in life,
right?
You have a kid,
maybe you get along with them and maybe
you don't,
but let's assume you do,
but then they marry someone that you
just don't like and or maybe you think
is wrong for them.
I mean,
that's really rough.
That's what are you going to do about
that?
You know,
because you're basically screwed both
ways.
If you have the person you love around,
then you have to put up with this
horrendous creature that they allied
themselves with.
And if you,
if you get rid of them completely,
well then you know you don't have your
child anymore.
So it's very,
very difficult position.
And so that's another example of the
realism,
I think,
of the stories.
Now,
Isaac,
who's hypothetically on his deathbed
asks Esau to hunt for Venison because he
likes fitness and he's happy that his
son is a hunter and Rebecca overhears
this,
so she conspires with Jacob,
um,
to,
to slaughter to small goats and make his
father some stew because he wants to
make them stew out of venison.
But Rebecca,
who's being,
I would say,
let's say slightly deceitful or horribly
lying that would be more accurate,
she conspires with Jacob.
So Jacob kills two little goats kids and
boils up a stew.
And then he puts on some,
uh,
goatskins because Esau was a hairy
character.
And,
and Rebecca Dresses Isaac in east
clothing because Isaac can't see very
well at this point.
And so then Jacob goes into his father
with the stew and he's trying to
disguise his voice,
but it doesn't work very well.
And so Isaac asks him to come close and
Jacob puts out his arm with the goat
skin on it.
And,
and Isaac smells them too.
And he smells like Esl.
And um,
which maybe wasn't the best thing,
but,
um,
and feels like,
and,
and so,
uh,
because Isaac thinks he's on his
deathbed,
he decides to deliver a blessing to
hypothetically to east south.
And so,
but it's Jacob.
And so that's a big deal too because the
blessing is actually,
as I said before with these ancient
people,
it appeared as though once you said
something,
you didn't get to take it back.
You couldn't say,
well look,
you've deceived me so it doesn't count.
It was like they weren't maybe as,
as well.
Week might be one way of thinking about
it,
but another way is they weren't quite as
attentive to context,
you know,
because if I make you a deal and then it
turns out that you've betrayed me,
I may feel that the deal is no longer
valid because the assumption was you
were being honest to begin with.
And that violates the whole spirit.
But that isn't how these people thought.
They said once he promised man,
you promised.
And that was that.
So Isaac Blesses Jacob.
He says that God gives you the dew of
heaven and the fatness of the earth and
plenty of corn and wine.
Let people serve you and nations bow
down to you.
Be Lord over thy brethren,
that's going to be rough on Esl.
Let thy mother's sons bow down
to the cursive,
be everyone that curses and blessings
be.
He blesses it,
and so there's a credit remarkable
painting of that.
So there's Rebecca.
She's looking pretty old and Isaac's
Look Pretty Blind and Jacob's taking
directions from his mother and we might
say he's perhaps a little old to be
taking moral lessons from his mother,
especially given how she's acting.
And so it's a pretty ugly scene
altogether,
especially that we also know that Jacob
already tricked Esau out of his
birthright and so now he's taken the
birthright and he's taken the blessing.
And so as I said that Jacob,
he turns out to be the father of Israel.
It's like he's a reprehensible
character.
These are major league betrayals that
he's engaging and it's not trivial.
He really,
really pulls the rug out from under his
brother and you know,
you could say,
well,
Esl is not as awake as he might be,
you know,
he's kind of a wild man and fair enough,
but it's certainly seems to me that the,
the predominant moral error falls on
Jacob's shoulders.
It's very treacherous behavior,
what he's doing.
So then Esau shows up and he's got a
nice stag for his dad and it's like
little late for that and he states that
his brother was rightly named Jacob,
which means supplanter because he's been
deceived twice and Isaac says,
Isaac answered.
He's asking a yes.
I was asking fundamentally if there's
anything at all left over for him,
and Isaac can't give them the same
blessing because that's already been
given.
So he has to think of something else.
And I'm Isaac says,
hold.
I've made him my lord and all his
brothers I've given to him for servants,
which includes you and with corn and
wine.
Have I sustained him?
What shall I now do on tv?
My son and Esau said unto his father,
how have you even one blessing for me?
My father and bless me also,
and an esl lifted up his voice and wept
and you know,
we already know that Esau is a pretty
tough guy by all appearances and you
know,
he's out there hunting on his own and
camping and it's like he's no pushover,
and the fact that this reduces him to
tears is an indication of the magnitude
of the betrayal.
And Isaac says,
behold thy dwelling shall be the fatness
of the earth and of the dew of heaven,
from above and by Thy Sword,
thou shall live,
and thou shalt serve your brother and it
she'll come to pass when you will have
the dominion and you'll break the yolk.
His yoke off from died neck.
And the Esol hated Jacob because of the
blessing where with his father blessed
him.
And Esau said in his heart,
the days of mourning for my father are
at hand.
Then I will slay my brother Jacob.
So fundamentally,
you know,
if Isaac dies or when he dies,
then we'll mourn for him.
And then Jacob better look the hell out
because it's like it's,
it's serious death coming his way.
And you know,
he's got a,
he's got a point,
he's in Dante's inferno,
I think I mentioned this at one point.
So Dante's inferno is a very interesting
story.
It's a descent into hell and it's
actually one of the places that we sort
of derive the popular conception of hell
was partly based on Dante's,
on dmts imagination on his work.
And what Dante was trying to do was to
discover the hierarchical structure of
evil.
And you know,
you might think there's a hierarchical
structure of good,
some things are better than other
things,
but there's also a hierarchical
structure of evil.
Some evils are greater than other evils.
And he put the trail in the,
in the,
in the lowest part of health,
right?
So if you were betraying people,
you were right beside Satan himself.
And so,
and I think that's good,
that's very smart.
While Dante was a genius after all,
um,
and I think the reason for that is that
you see,
if someone trusts you,
they're laying their vulnerability open
to you.
Now they might just be naive,
let's say.
And that's,
we won't think about that because you're
just a child.
If you're naive,
you can still be betrayed.
But if you're an adult and you trust,
it's often because you,
if you're an actual adult,
is you willingly open yourself up
knowing that you could be hurt,
right?
Because you're not naive anymore.
So you decided to trust and you see all
open myself up and I know that I'm
leaving myself open to you.
If you choose to use that power and then
that's a good thing to know.
You know,
if you've been hurt as a child hurt,
as a naive person,
you might say,
well,
why should I ever trust to get?
Which is a really good question.
And the answer is the reason you trust,
again,
once you're an adult is because you're
courageous.
You're courageous.
It's an act of courage to trust.
And the reason it's useful is because if
you trust someone,
you opened the door to reciprocity and
negotiation and cooperation and you
entice the best part of the person
forward.
And so it's A.
It's a courageous act.
But then if you betray someone,
then what you've done is you've taken
the best part of them,
which is the part that will courageously
trust it with open eyes.
Right?
And you've stuck a dagger in that.
And so you've purposefully damaged the
best part of the.
And so that's why it's such a egregious
fault.
And,
and it's often people don't recover from
that sort of blanket you.
If you be betray someone badly enough,
you can,
you can damage them like you can give
them posttraumatic stress disorder if
you really,
if you really put your mind to it and
you know that's not just a psychological
disorder.
If you have posttraumatic stress
disorder,
it produces permanent neurological
alterations that make you more neurotic,
more sensitive to negative emotion
really for the rest of your life.
Like you can,
you can recover from it to some degree,
but stress will tend to re instantiate
that ptsd.
So you,
you hurt someone and it's not merely
cycled.
Not,
not that psychological is merely,
but it's not merely psychological,
right?
It's,
it's fundamental physiological damage.
So anyways,
Jacobs smart enough to get out of there.
And which is also not really a testament
to his integrity,
right?
I mean,
he's done these terrible things at the
behest of his mother because he wants
power and,
and he wants to get it without deserving
it.
And then he finally goes too far and he
hightails it out of there to his,
to another family member,
to his mother's brother.
And so it's not exactly the world's most
heroic story,
that's for sure.
And so now there's an interlude here,
and this is a really interesting
interlude.
It's the story of Jacob's ladder.
So he's off to visit la ban or lab and
who's,
uh,
his,
his mother's brother.
And on the way he,
he,
he has a sleep and he lighted upon a
certain place and tarried there all
night because the sun was set and he
took of the stones of that place and put
them for his pillows,
which seems to indicate very bad
planning on his part and,
and lay down in that place to sleep.
And he dreamed and behold,
a ladder set up on the earth,
and the top of it reached to heaven and
beheld the angels of God ascending and
descending on it.
And behold the lord stood above it and
said,
I am the Lord God of Abraham,
thy father and the god of Isaac,
the land we're on to the I will give it
and to thy seed.
And so this story of Jacob's ladder has
really possessed the imagination of the
West.
And then there's a reason for that.
It's because it's an archetypal story
because the idea of a ladder that
reaches to heaven is one of the oldest
ideas of mankind.
So you'll find it widely distributed
among the shamanic cultures,
for example.
And it's a hallmark of psychedelic
experience.
That's another way of thinking about it,
which is a very peculiar thing.
So there's one representation of the
ladder you see got up at the top there.
I'm peeking out from the clouds.
Now,
you know,
that's sort of where we get the idea
that God is in heaven and the heavens up
in the sky.
And,
and that's an easy story to make fun of
because you know,
we've gone up to the moon and there's no
god there and,
and,
but,
but this,
this is not a reasonable way of
conceptualizing what these experiences
are about,
these experiences,
what this is the opening up there that's
more like an opening into an alternate
dimension.
That's a better way of thinking about
it.
It's beyond like from,
from the Judeo Christian perspective,
one of the things you have to understand
is that God is beyond space and time.
He's not in the universe,
he's outside the universe in some
manner.
And so the idea that that you have an
experience of God and it's up,
isn't the AAP is the best that the human
imagination can do with what's
essentially a form of extra dimensional
experience or that's the best way to
conceptualize it.
And these experiences aren't rare.
You know,
they,
they make the,
they make up the core of,
of the shamanic tradition.
And so there's an intrusion of the
ancient shamanic tradition,
which is tens of thousands of years old
into the biblical stories at this point.
Now why Jacob had a essentially shamonic
experience is very difficult to tell
because we don't know what these old
people we're up to.
Right,
and we don't know how much of the
archaic,
traditioned,
archaic religious tradition was still
extent at that at that point in time,
but we certainly do know that our
ancient forebears were using psychedelic
substances constantly like am Anita
Mascara,
mushrooms,
for example,
which were widely used in India before
they became extinct.
That's the theory anyways,
and that seemed to be the basis of the
Chemical Soma,
which a much has been written about,
and so we hear it over.
This is a dream or has the vision and
perhaps that's what it was,
but perhaps that wasn't what it was
either and perhaps it was an experience
that was induced by by the same
processes that shamonic people have
always induced these experiences and so
we're going to go through this a little
bit.
So anyways,
there's A.
There's a connection between heaven and
earth that opens up.
That's,
that's,
that's the,
that's the vision,
and there's messengers moving up and
down.
Now,
one way you can conceptualize that is
psychologically,
as we already discussed,
that you know there,
there are forces within you that are
active and alive and you can think of
them in some sense as messengers of the
higher self and so you could think about
this as an image of a psychological
reality,
but and so we can stick with that,
but,
but
here's some of the representations that
have been made.
I really liked the one on the right.
That's William Blake.
I liked the helix idea and I don't think
that that's a fluke.
There are helixes and double helix is in
all sorts of images,
imagery,
very ancient and very modern that are
associated with both healing and with
this kind of vision.
So,
and you see the blake representation.
God is associated with,
well really with the sun and with light
and you see that on the left as well,
that wherever God is is where light is.
And so that's a very interesting idea as
far as I'm concerned as well.
There's some other representations,
one by chagall.
So now there's this idea that there's a,
there's the possibility of opening up a
line of communication between the human
psyche and the transcendent divine,
and there's a.
there's a great image of Christ as
Panto.
They're so creative.
The world at just one of the first
mosaics,
if I remember correctly,
and I wish I knew,
remember where it was,
but I don't,
but it's a very interesting image.
I'm having a carving of it made at the
moment by a friend of mine.
But you see Christ face it portrayed in
a medieval manner and he's holding a
book.
So it symbolizes the importance of the
You know,
as a means of transmitting wisdom and
his face is very asymmetrical and the
eyes are different.
One side and the other and half of the
face represents the human part and the
other side of the face represents the
divine part.
And you know,
I also think about that psychologically
because I do think that that's the right
way to conceptualize human beings is
that there's an aspect of us mortal,
human and limited.
But there's an aspect of us that's
transcendent and divine as well.
And it's latent in some sense,
but there are times when it manifests
itself,
and this is not speculation,
right?
This is like the oldest experience of
human beings now.
It's not necessarily an easy experience
to have,
but it's reported everywhere and it can
be reliably induced as we've discussed
before by chemical means,
which and I don't know what that means
exactly.
We've talked a little bit about
psilocybin mushrooms for example,
and you could say that the mystical
experiences that have been invoked in
the newest experiments down at at Johns
Hopkins are derangements or forms of
psychosis because they have some
similarity to psychosis psychotic
experiences.
Although psychotic people were given lsd
in the sixties and they always said that
that was something different than what
they were having and if you give
psychotic people I'm fed up means you
can make them worse.
So there biochemically separate and we
know that.
But also the thing that's so interesting
about the psilocybin experiences is that
they reliably produce mystical
experiences that the people rate as
among the most important experiences of
their life.
And among those who have the psychedelic
experience,
positive things happen to them.
And so that kind of messes with the
whole psychosis theory,
right?
Because what are you gonna do you're
gonna claim that you give someone a pale
and they have a psychotic break and then
they're healthier.
It's like,
no,
that isn't how psychotic breaks work.
You're not healthier after having one.
You're like,
you're a broken Haig and it's not easy
to put you back together.
So,
and we know that people all over the
world have discovered every manner of
psychedelic substance that you could
possibly,
while you imagine there's lots of hungry
people wandering the earth for a long
time and they eat every damn thing they
could get their hands on and now,
and then something very peculiar
happened as a consequence.
So.
So I'm going to tell you a little bit
about the harmonic,
a tradition,
because it's associated with Jacob's
ladder.
So,
um,
according to Eliana Mircea Eliade,
who was a great historian of religion,
a compatriot of viewings and,
and,
and the influenced each other quite
substantially.
Eliana believe that shamanism that used
psychedelics was a degeneration from the
original,
more pure shamanism,
but I think later scholarship has
demonstrated that that's incorrect,
that that the romantic ritual per se,
was a direct consequence of the use
discovery of an and ritualistic use of
psychedelic substances.
But anyways,
Eliana identified three pathways to
shamanism and the Sherman in it,
in a tribe was more educated than the
typical person with a larger vocabulary
and was the repository of the oral
tradition and so learned all the stories
that had been passed down.
Word of mouth and people by the way are
very,
very accurately tell the same story
across generations.
That's been quite well documented so
and,
and people who can't read really can
remember because what else are they
going to do?
Their memories are far greater than
modern peoples memories because we can
forget everything because we can just
look it up.
But they remembered things because they
had no choice.
My father knew someone who was
illiterate and and,
and,
and couldn't use numbers either when,
when he grew up in Saskatchewan,
you know,
60 years ago,
and he was a,
he had a sheep,
if I remember correctly,
and although he couldn't count,
he knew if one of his sheep was missing
because he knew all the sheep and so he
could tell just by looking if one of the
sheep was missing,
but he couldn't count and so well.
So people who don't have our particular
set of skills,
first of all,
they're not stupid and second they have
other skills that we don't understand to
fill in the gaps.
So Eliana identified spontaneous
vocation.
So you were just,
you had this spirit of a showman,
let's say.
So you're probably extremely high in
openness,
let's say from a modern perspective,
hereditary transmission.
So you know,
your father was a showman and your
grandfather was a showman and so forth,
and you got initiated into that process
or a personal quest in Siberia.
This is from Eliana in Siberia.
The youth who is called to be a showman
attracts attention by his strange
behavior.
For example,
he seeks solitude,
becomes absent minded,
loves to roam in the woods or
unfrequently places,
has visions,
and sings in his sleep.
You know,
if you put someone in a in a place
that's deprived,
that's where you're deprived from a
sensory perspective,
it fit normal.
People will hallucinate quite quickly,
so it seems.
What happens is that if you dampen down
the sensory input,
then you start to become aware of the
background processes of your mind.
It's something like that.
It's like the signal to noise ratio.
I got to get this right.
As the noise decreases,
some of the noise become signal,
the background noise become signal,
and you start to become aware of your
own internal psychological processes.
It's something like that.
He has visions and sings in his sleep.
In some instances,
this period of incubation is marked by
quite serious symptoms among the Yakut.
The young man sometimes has fits of
theory and easily loses consciousness,
hides in the forest,
feeds on the bark of trees,
throws himself into water and fire and
cutting themselves with knives.
We went to a potlatch in northern
northern Vancouver Island about a year
ago and they had this one dance.
It was the Kwakwaka'wakw natives and
they had this interesting dance that was
the dance of the wild man.
And so the person who invited us was the
wild man and he was dressed up in tree
branches and so forth.
And so he was the person who'd been in
the Bush too long and he in as a
cannibal and there there was genuine
cannibalistic rites among these people.
Not so long ago.
He came in as a cannibal and everybody
had to wear this like cedar head dress
because if you had a cedar headdress on
then the Cannibal wouldn't take a bite
out of you and they actually took this
route as seriously so you should have
your Cedar headdress on.
And so he's looking around the crowd and
there's like 400 people in this place
and he could really act two.
And so he's doing this wild man dance.
And then all the women stood up and
started to kind of dancing place and
saying.
And they were taming him.
So that was really cool.
It was really interesting to see that
because those people are about,
they've had an unbroken culture for
about 13,000
years.
Say That's how long they've been out on
the island there.
And it was very interesting to see that
dramatization of the domestication of,
of man by women laid out in that dance
in that way.
But it was also interesting in
relationship to the shamanic tradition
because he came in as a wild man,
right?
And he had to be re civilized in some
sense and brought back down to earth.
So,
but by whatever method he may have been
designated as Sharman is recognized as
such,
only after having received two methods
of instruction.
The first is ecstatic dreams,
trances visions.
The other thing that this guy told me,
I have no reason to doubt him.
He's also not illiterate person.
Um,
and so has a great memory.
He does carving traditional carving and
he's very good at it.
He carved a 53 foot totem pole that's
now in front of the Museum of art in,
in downtown Montreal.
So if you ever go there,
you can go see it,
I won't be there forever,
but it's there right now.
And uh,
he was taught to carve by his
grandparents and he said that he dreamed
in what the Haida images look like.
So the Kwakwaka'wakw kind of like the
high,
that same sort of imagery he told me
that he dreamed in those images.
So when he dreams,
that's the forum that the things he
dreams about takes.
And he also said that he would talk to
his grandparents and his dream.
So if he was working on a piece of wood
and trying to figure out how to carve it
and he ran into a particularly difficult
problem,
he dream in his,
he'd have a conversation with his
grandparents and they'd help them figure
out how to solve the problem.
And then he'd wake up and he could go
carve the.
And the thing is he told me these things
sort of matter of factly,
right?
Like,
you don't.
You know what I mean?
It wasn't like he was telling me these
weird things that happened to him,
although he was doing that to some
degree.
I asked him a lot of questions about
what he carved and what it all meant and
um,
you know,
that was just part of his explanation of
how he did it and he,
he carved me a couple of doors that I
have in my house and one of them is
quite interesting.
Well,
the,
to make a panel and they're an
underwater scene and under the water
there's a bunch of mythical monsters.
Some of them are killer whales and I
think there's an octopus down there and
carved in this particular style.
And he said that the other thing that
happens to him when he dreams as he goes
down to the bottom of the water where
these mythical creatures are and he gets
inspiration from them.
And so I thought that was extremely
interesting to know.
We,
we don't know what a mind that isn't
hyper civilized,
let's say hyper literate like,
like our minds are because we're so
bombarded by external stimuli can.
We have no idea what the natural mind is
like really.
And so it was quite interesting to,
to,
to listen to that and also to see the
consequences because you quite a great.
He's quite a great carver.
So the first is ecstatic dreams,
trances visions.
The second is traditional shamanic
techniques,
names and functions of the spirits and
mythology and genealogy of the clan.
A secret language.
This twofold teaching imparted by the
spirits and the old masters Sherman's
constitutes initiation.
Well.
So,
you know,
modern people have a problem with that
because we don't really get initiated.
But I would say
that,
you know,
let's say that we're each on a quest of
some sort.
You wouldn't be here,
I don't think if you weren't because why
else would you be here,
can you.
And so you're on a quest of some sort to
figure out,
to struggle with the meaning of life,
let's say.
And you don't want to do that alone
because you only last 70 years and good
luck figuring it out on your,
on your own.
It's just not going to happen.
It's too complicated.
And you'll be too isolated,
right?
If it's just you,
that's insanity.
That's no one can stand that.
And so you hope that other people have
things to tell you and that your culture
has something to tell you,
you know,
so you're on a quest,
maybe not with the same intensity as a
shamonic initiate,
but you know,
let's give you some credit and then
you're also trying to understand the
wisdom of the past.
And that's the second part of this.
It's like,
okay,
well you're a human being and human
beings have been telling stories for a
long period of time trying to figure out
what's going on,
trying to figure out how to orient
themselves in the world.
And so you know,
partly what you're doing here is exactly
what the shamonic initiate does in the
second part of the process,
which is to expose yourself to the
degree that you can to names and
functions of the spirits,
mythology and genealogy of the clan.
And the secret language.
This twofold teaching imparted by the
spirits and the old master shamans
constitutes initiation.
So it's,
that's the rebirth,
right?
That's what initiation is.
It's being born again and,
and that's the birth of the spirit
rather than over the body.
It's something like that,
and so it's the rebirth of an integrated
psyche that's one way of thinking about
it and a psyche that's that's
individual,
but also grounded in common humanity and
the wisdom of common humanity and that
makes you strong,
or at least it makes you stronger
because there's a limit to your
strength,
but God only knows to some degree what
that limit is.
You know,
people can be unbelievably tough,
unbelievably tough,
and I think it's even more admirable for
human beings to be tough because we're
so conscious of we can be hurt and we're
so conscious of what that hurt can lead
to.
You know,
you can have your family taken away from
you and you can be destroyed,
and the fact that you can be courageous
in the face of that at all is something
that is absolutely unbelievable.
Right?
And people deserve a lot more credit,
I think,
than people give themselves because the
fact that we can be honorable under
conditions of life and death,
right?
Of suffering.
That's,
that's a testament to the human spirit
and there's a profound anti human ethos
I think that pervades our culture.
You know,
that considers human beings cancers on
the planet,
something like that,
you know,
and that there should be less of us.
It's the same spirit that motivated the
guy who wrote the book about it better
to have never been and it's like I don't
see it that way.
You know,
I mean,
I think people do pretty well for,
you know,
for having their leg caught in a bear
trap and their head caught in advice.
They're actually doing pretty well
because life is really hard and the fact
that we're not absolutely brutal and
murderous all the time is really
something remarkable given what we
actually have to contend with it.
We can go out of our way to be honest
and generous and altruistic and to care
for each other and under unbelievably
dire circumstances and to act nobody
sometimes under the most trying
conditions,
you know,
and soldier in the Gulag archipelago.
He tells story after story of people who
acted a bismal Lee,
but also people who under the worst
threats imaginable never sacrificed
their character.
You know,
in reading about that is really.
While it really makes you wonder,
that's what it does,
the future shamans among the tongue
tongass as they approach maturity go
through a hysterical or history crisis,
but sometimes their vocation manifests
itself.
At an earlier age,
the boy runs away into the mountains and
remains there for a week or more feeding
on animals,
which he tears to pieces with his teeth.
He returns to the village filthy
bloodstained,
and it's only after 10 or more days that
have passed that he begins to babble
incoherent words.
The strange behavior of future showman's
has not failed to attract the attention
of scholars and from the middle of the
past century,
several attempts have been made to
explain the phenomena as a mental
disorder,
but the problem was wrongly put four.
On the one hand,
it is not true that showman's always are
always have to be neuropathic in
mentally deranged.
On the other hand,
and this is the critical issue,
those among them who had been able to
become shamans precisely because they
had succeeded in becoming cured,
so it was.
It's not the descent into this strange
subterranean psychological state that
constitutes the transformation that
makes the showman,
but it's the emergence back out of that
and that's a journey to the underworld
and and a rebirth.
Right?
And so there's this great book.
This is a great book by a guy named
Henri Ellenberger,
Jay,
and he was an existential,
a psychoanalyst and philosopher,
and he wrote a book called the discovery
of the unconscious,
which I would highly recommend it.
It's on my list of recommended readings.
It is a great book if you want to know
about the psychoanalytic tradition,
it's the best introduction there is.
And he discusses Adler and young and
Freud and does a very credible job of
all three,
but also takes the history of
psychoanalytic thought back three or 400
years before Freud.
And so it's very engaging,
reading and,
and,
and very interesting.
And one of the things Ellenberg shape
points out quite clearly is an.
And he associates this to some degree
with the shamanic tradition that both
Freud and young union particular
underwent very intense periods of
psychological disturbance,
let's say.
And I would say what was happening is
that because they were questioning their
axioms at the most fundamental level,
they were deranging their cognitive and
perceptual structures,
right?
And Ewan was also experimenting with
imaginative techniques with visionary
techniques which he,
which he did a lot and there was a
period of his life where he was having
constant,
a constant stream of visions which you
wrote down in a book called the red
book,
but at the same time he was still
functioning as a psychiatrist and
operating normally in the world.
And so,
you know,
people have suggested that what he had
was a psychotic break.
But that's ridiculous because you don't,
don't,
that's not how it works,
man.
If you're having a psychotic break,
you,
you're not being an effective
psychiatrist.
Those things do not go together,
especially not for a long period of
time.
And so there,
there's the possibility of extreme
experience without cyclocross
psychopathology.
And so,
um,
and the Burgy,
he says much the same thing about Freud
and about Charles Darwin as well,
who underwent a terrible period of,
of,
of mental confusion,
I would say,
as a consequence of formulating his
theory of evolution,
which was really hard on him because he
was a,
he was a die hard Christian and he knew
what he knew,
what the implications of his theory
word.
He didn't know what to do about that,
you know,
so it was very,
very hard on him.
So it's quite common for people of
genius to go through an intense crisis,
psychological crisis,
but then resolve that.
And the genius is in the resolution,
right?
The precondition for the genius is the
disillusion in some sense because you
have to be obsessed with a problem.
It has to grip you completely before
you're going to concentrate on it.
So obsessively that you might come up
with a solution.
But it's the people who come up with a
solution that are the prophets in the
Sharmane and so forth and so on and,
and,
and so that's not.
This isn't something that only
characterizes our cultures.
We just don't recognize it in our own
culture properly,
and that's a problem.
Well,
sometimes we do.
Right?
You remember that in,
in,
in the lion king,
right?
That he shows up.
He's the chairman,
he,
he brings,
he brings a Simba down that tunnel dark
tunnel.
That's the dark night of the soul.
He has them reflect upon himself in a
pool when he reflects upon himself,
deeply sees the reflection of his father
then becomes a core thing of cosmic
significance and his father appears in
the sky just like God appears to Jacob
and basically tells them that it's time
for him to grow the hell up and to
return to the devastated kingdom and to
set it right.
You know,
and so and that's right.
That's exactly right.
I mean,
we live in the devastated kingdom.
That's an eternal truth and it's the
responsibility of the individual to grow
the hell up and to set it right because
when it's devastated and when things are
not in place,
then everyone suffers too much and
that's not good and there's no excuse
for not doing something about it because
you don't have anything better to do so.
And even like children's movies tell you
this.
So this is a fun one.
This is from the ead wind salter,
ninth to twelfth century.
That's how Adam and eve,
but the,
there is speculation that the fruit that
they're eating there,
you see these psilocybin mushrooms,
right?
Because they're the only kind of
mushroom that girl like that.
So that's pretty wild you might say.
And then this is the,
I think it's called banisteriopsis vine
if I remember correctly,
and it's what Iowasca is made out of and
it has this double helix forum which is
very,
very interesting.
And they,
the people that natives,
nobody could figure out how the hell
they made this Iowasca which,
which transports people spiritually in a
very intense manner.
And there's a whole religion based on
it,
like a modern religion as well as the
archaic religion and to to to make this
stuff,
they had to take two plants that don't
grow anywhere near each other and like
there's like a million plants in the
Amazon,
so like how do you figure that out?
Nobody knows.
And then you have to cook them in this
very particular way for a particular
amount of time before you produce this
stuff.
So one of the plants has dmt in it,
which is a very intense psychedelic,
but it's very short acting and the other
has a Mao inhibitor.
So if you take the DMT and you take the
Mao inhibitor,
then the DMT trip lasts for much longer.
And so that's what these Amazonian
natives figured out.
No one has any idea how they managed it
and if you ask them,
they tell you that the plants told them
how to do it,
which isn't much of an explanation as
far as modern people are concerned.
But then when modern people take the
IOWASCA and the plant,
so to speak,
starts to talk to them.
There are a little less leery of the
whole theory that the plants had
something to do with this,
so you know,
and these things that these.
I'm loath to talk about this because I'm
not an advocate for drug use,
but by the same token,
you can't ignore empirical data.
It's not reasonable,
and the empirical data that psychedelic
substances can produce mystical
experiences and that those often have a
transformative effect.
I mean,
one of the latest study showed that if
you took people who were dying of cancer
and you and you gave them silicide been
in a sufficient dose to produce a
mystical experience that you radically.
It decreased their fear of death.
It's like
you gotta think about that,
man.
That's,
that's tough.
That's a tough experiment.
You just wouldn't expect that,
that you think you take someone,
you do range them intensely and then
when they come back they're not.
Even though they're dying,
they're not nearly as afraid of dying.
You know,
you got to kind of wake up and smell the
roses when you see something like that.
And the people who are doing this
research are very reliable people.
So there's the Amanita Mascara,
you know,
there's this old idea,
it's quite a funny idea.
Toadstools so flies like avenue to
Mascara and there are some,
this is ridiculous.
There's some evidence that they actually
liked getting stoned so because animals
will eat these,
like reindeer will eat these things too
and they get pretty tripped out by them.
And so I have this book on psychedelic
use among animals,
which is a small book,
but.
And so,
so there's that,
there's this idea that toads used to sit
around the they haven't eaten miscarry
and wait for the stone flies to like
bought badly around them and then snap
them up.
So that's pretty funny.
I think can.
So,
and you know,
there are mushrooms in,
in the US that are the oldest,
the oldest organisms on the planet.
Hey,
there's one mushroom,
I can't remember where it is,
but it covers something like,
Oh God,
I don't know,
like square hundreds of square miles.
It's like this huge thing because it's
all underground.
Right?
And they have these very complex
networks of,
of Mycelia they're called and they think
the thing is like 150,000
years old,
something like that.
So there's plenty of things about the
world that we don't know,
that's for sure.
There's the chemical makeup of the
classic psychedelics.
You see they all have the same
fundamental structure.
This is Serotonin,
that's the one of the major brain
neurotransmitters.
And so what happens with the
psychedelics is that they,
they alter the,
they alter the brain function by
altering the,
the neurochemical utilization of
Serotonin.
They changed the manner in which the
serotonergic systems work.
And that is the serotonin system is very
basic system may because when you're an
embryo and your brain is developing,
it's the serotonin projections that
basically orchestrate the development of
your brain.
So they're.
And they're very archaic circuits,
very,
very archaic circuits.
So,
and this is the paper,
I think I stole this from silicide,
Ben Griffiths,
who's been doing a lot of this research
suicide can occasion,
mystical type experiences having
substantial and sustained personal
meaning and spiritual significance.
So why,
that's a good question.
Right?
Like so,
so here's a question for you.
It is beyond dispute that human beings
are capable of religious experience.
Why?
Why is that?
Exactly?
And they're like,
you can associate with psychosis,
but that doesn't work is the theory
doesn't hold.
The theory doesn't hold water.
It's not the same thing.
So why is it there?
Exactly.
And it,
it's not an easy thing to figure out.
Like I've been trying to figure.
I'm always trying to figure it a
biological explanation for everything,
right?
Because if you want to find something to
stand on,
you want to make sure that it can resist
a challenge.
And so if I can find an explanation for
something that's reductionistic and
materialistic and biological,
then I'm going for that.
But that's a tough one.
Consciousness is a tough one.
The moral sense is a tough one.
They're not easy things to crack.
The Big Bang is a tough one.
So
you know what I mean?
A cynic might say that maybe sometimes
when people are close to suicide,
they'll have a mystical experience,
you know,
and you maybe you say,
well,
it's a last ditch attempt of your brain
to delude you into thinking that your
life has some significance,
you know,
and that that's a plausible theory,
but I don't think it accounts for the
generality of the phenomena.
So,
so I don't buy it.
What happens in the show,
manic experiences that the Scherman has
the experience of being reduced to a
skeleton first.
So death,
a death experience on very realistic
death experience.
And then the next thing that happens is
that he finds himself in a place where
he's communing with his ancestral,
the ancestral spirits.
And then after that there's the climbing
of something like the ladder,
Jacob's ladder say,
and an encounter with God for all
intents and purposes.
And uh,
it's very widespread phenomena.
It's the world tree.
And I thought about this a lot,
trying to figure out what this,
what this represents.
According to a Yak who'd informant
that's in Siberia,
the spirits carry the future showman to
hell and shove them in a house for three
years.
Here he undergoes is initiation.
The spirits cut off his head,
which they set off to one side for the
novice,
must watch his own dismemberment with
his own eyes,
disillusion to the primary elements in
some sense,
and hack his body to bits which are
later distributed among the spirits of
various sicknesses.
It's only on this condition that the
future showman will obtain the power of
healing his bones then covered with new
flesh and his.
Some Casey has also given new blood,
so there's a death and resurrection
experience that's associated with this
shamanic ritual.
We're here in the presence of a very
ancient religious idea which belongs to
the hunter culture.
Bone symbolizes the final route of
animal life.
The mold from which the flesh
continually rises.
It is from the bone that men and animals
are reborn for a time.
They maintain themselves in an existence
of the flesh.
Then they die and their life is reduced
to the essence concentrated in the
skeleton from which they will be born.
Again,
a good graphic representation of the
experience.
It's an old painting by,
I think it's Hieronymus Bosch,
if I remember correctly.
And I really liked that because it's
reminiscent of the near death
experiences that you hear people
describe and they're quite common as
well.
And,
and,
uh,
I had a very weird experience once.
I don't think I've told you this story.
I was,
I was assessing someone who had gone
through a car windshield and he was very
depressed and had happened a long time
before,
but he was very depressed and the
insurance company was basically accusing
him of a malingering because he'd been
depressed for so long and you know,
he'd sort of healed up and everything.
But if your left hemisphere is damaged,
especially the frontal part of your left
hemisphere,
then you can be in a chronic state of
depression because the left hemisphere,
generally speaking,
is responsible for positive emotion.
And so if it isn't there,
then it's like negative emotion for you.
And so I went and assessed him and I was
giving him this,
I think it was called the MMPI,
the Minnesota multiphasic personality
inventory,
which is a kind of a standard,
a path personality test,
half psychopathology test.
And uh,
he was filling it out.
He was a very serious guy,
middle aged guy.
Nothing about him was new age in the
least.
He was like an accountant I think.
I think in fact he was an accountant if
I remember correctly.
Um,
and there was one question and it said,
my spirit has left my body.
I think that's right.
It's very close.
And he stopped and he asked me what,
well,
he said,
I'm not sure how to answer this.
And so I said,
well,
why?
And he said,
well,
after I went through the car windshield,
I was in a coma for three weeks,
something like that.
And I died.
I think he said he died three times and
he said that he could remember he
couldn't remember anything during that
period of time and he couldn't remember
the car accident.
That's retrograde amnesia.
It's quite common with head injuries.
And he said that during one of those
experiences,
and this is all he remembered from the
hospital,
was that he came out of his body and
went down the tunnel of light.
You've heard these near death
experiences and then saw his family
members there.
And so the heavenly light,
and then realize that it wasn't his time
and came back to his body.
Now what was interesting about this guy
was that,
well,
first of all,
I didn't ask him about this,
right?
He basically volunteered this story and
it was instigated by this question and,
and he didn't know that anybody else had
any hey,
ever had an experience like that because
I asked him if he'd ever heard anything
about like that.
And he said No.
So that was interesting.
But what really was interesting is how
the hell did he remember that?
Right?
Because he had amnesia during that
entire period of time.
He was in a bloody coma.
It's like he didn't remember anything
but he remembered that.
And so.
Well those experiences are more common
than you think.
And then there's a,
there's a painting of one which is quite
interesting.
And that's like a tunnel to heaven.
It's the same basic idea.
It's a little bit more suffering going
on in this one I think.
But that's pretty much typical of
Hieronymus Bosch.
I mean,
I don't know what was up with that guy,
but he was.
He was one strange character.
Now the scandinavians have this idea
that the world is a tree,
and I've been thinking about that a lot.
I think that the tree idea tree is
something that is grounded in in matter,
let's say,
and that reaches up to heaven in the
Scandinavian tree at the bottom.
There's quite a cool idea at the bottom
of that.
See,
this tree is constantly being nod by
snakes.
You can sort of see the snakes at the
bottom and at the same time it's being
watered and the water makes the tree
grow at the same rate that the snakes.
No,
on its roots.
So it's like a Yin Yang idea.
You know,
that there's continual chaotic
destruction and replacement at the basis
of whatever this process is.
But the tree seems to me to be a
representation,
not so much of.
It's like a different dimensional space.
That's,
that's what's trying to be represented.
So imagine that you know,
your structured,
if you take powers of 10 magnification,
say human beings are boat in the middle
of the tiniest thing and the largest
thing if you do it by,
by powers of 10,
and so you know,
you have a subatomic level and an atomic
level molecular level and you know,
then,
uh,
that are maybe the level of organs and
then there's you and then there's your
family and so on,
all the way up the tree fundamentally.
And so I think that what this tree
represents and this is the things that
thing that the shaman moves up and down,
I think that's what it represents.
It's this,
it's this different view of,
of its dimensionality at something like
that.
And I think that what happens in the
psychedelic experiences that
consciousness can travel up and down
that structure.
It's something like that,
and maybe not only up and down it,
but maybe right through it.
I know that's a radical claim.
It's a really radical claim and it might
be wrong,
but it's probably wrong even because
most radical claims are wrong,
but,
but I'm not so sure it's wrong.
Here's something cool.
So that's the Scandinavian world tree.
And that was drawn by an anthropologist
who visited the tribes in the Amazon who
use IOWASCA.
No,
you see it's a snake.
It's a tree with snakes.
Well,
you know,
that's reminiscent of the story of Adam
and Eve obviously,
but it's also reminiscent of our primate
dwelling place.
Right?
Because that was basically our ancestral
home,
a tree surrounded by snakes and the
snakes like to eat us and this is a long
time ago.
This is like
50 million years ago.
It's really a long time ago.
And so we don't know where these images
come from precisely,
but I do have the suspicion that we use
the circuitry that we developed to
detect snakes to represent the unknown
as such because it like a snake is
something that comes out of the unknown.
And like we evolved,
right?
We all evolved out of an animal
substructure and so we had to get our,
our biological cognitive structure from
somewhere and we have this capacity of
thinking about the absolute unknown and
the terrorists that are involved in
that,
that the horrors that can emerge from
what we don't understand and it stands
perfectly the reason that we would use
circuits that were already pre developed
for that and that this is a reasonable
representation of the existential
structure of the world.
So.
Right.
And I think I might've showed you this
before,
but it never ceases to amaze me this,
this picture.
So my son drew this when he was nine,
eight.
And so on the right you see mushroom
houses and they have the names of all
his friends on them and so that's order,
right?
And then on the left side you see chaos
there and that little orange thing is a
bug and then there's a river that runs
right down the middle.
And so that's like the,
you know,
the Yin Yang symbol with the divided in
the middle.
So that's quite cool.
And then there's,
there it is,
there's Jacob's ladder.
It's like Jack and the beanstalk,
which is by the way,
another variant of the same shamonic
story and there are bugs going up and
down it and then they're taking messages
from heaven and then up there and
haven't got the sun and there's St Peter
and I don't know where in the world he
got this.
It's not like he had a lot of religious
education.
I mean despite me.
Um,
and you know,
there's the pearly gates up there and
then that was the world as far as his.
He had a very well ordered psyche I
would say and still does,
but when he drew that,
it just absolutely blew me away.
And so I had it laminated and it's in my
office because,
well,
I don't know because like,
what the hell do you make of that?
You know,
that's,
that's why so.
Well you sort of get the picture there,
you know,
the cathedral is the great cathedrals of
Europe or they're like the forest in
stone,
right?
And they try to represent the light
coming through the leaves and so it's
sort of our ancestral forest home,
but it's,
it's transformed into these great
sculptures of stone and you know,
they produce all because of the
combination of light and darkness and
color.
But also I think for the same reason
that huge trees produce Roi and people,
you know,
and we don't want them cut down,
they seem sacred in some sense.
And perhaps they are,
but no.
And it also,
to me,
this is an intuition that the,
the architects of these great cathedrals
were trying to get.
They're trying to express something
that's deep and structural heart.
They're trying,
trying,
trying to express the idea that if being
was constituted properly,
then it would be organized from the
subatomic level all the way up to the
highest cosmic level perfectly.
So every layer stacked on top of each
other without any contradictions.
Now that would be an ideal mode of being
and everything would come together under
those circumstances.
And that's what's being expressed in
these cathedrals.
It's not all that's being expressed
because they're also shaped like a
cross.
And you know,
the idea is that the center of the
Cross,
which is the center of suffering,
is also the place of the individual and
the place where the transformation takes
place.
That's all built into the architecture
as well.
So
then there's the tree like structures
that make us up.
It's stretched down to the tiniest
realities,
the microcosm,
and there's this,
this idea,
it's all represented in the same way.
Again,
it's this idea,
especially the Mandela up in the top,
right?
It's the idea of perfection of
crystalline structure and that's what
the Yogis are trying to attain when they
organize their bodies.
They're trying to get every single layer
of there being aligned properly and it's
something like,
and you can kind of see an echo of that
in the.
I think that's a Tibetan sand painting,
if I remember correctly on the on the
bottom left idea,
is that if you get yourself aligned
properly,
then the information can flow along that
tree.
That that's you without,
without impediment.
Something like that.
And that would be like a state of
optimal health and that both physical
and spiritual exercises can put you in
that state and that's while those are
all clouds of ideas that surround this
idea of a ladder to heaven.
So Jacob is talking to God and God says,
behold,
I am with thee and I will keep the in
all places where you go and bring you
again into this land for I won't leave
you until I have done that which I have
spoken to you have.
And Jacob awakened out of his sleep
had he said,
surely the Lord is in this place.
And I knew what not,
and he was afraid and said,
how dreadful is this place?
This is none other but the house of God
and this is the gate of heaven.
And Jacob rose up early in the morning
and took the stone.
Then he had put for his pillows and set
it up for a pillar and poured oil on top
of it.
That's a sacrifice.
And he called the name of that place
Bethel,
but the name of the city was called Luz
at the first.
And Jacob vowed a vow saying,
if God will be with me and will keep me
in this way,
that I go and will give me bread to eat
and Raymond to put on so that I come
again to my father's house in peace,
then shall the Lord be my God.
And this stone,
which I have said for a pillar shall be
God's house.
And they'll have all of that that is
given to me.
I will surely give the 10th unto Thee.
And that's a pretty good place to stop.
So now I'll just
conclude.
So you have this very morally ambivalent
character who's so far,
pretty much everything he's done that
we're familiar with is not good.
So He's,
he's betrayed his brother horribly,
twice,
badly enough so that he,
his brother wants to kill him and
everyone can kind of sympathize with his
brother.
So.
And then he runs away essentially
because his mother tells him to,
which is not exactly a testament to his
character.
And despite that,
strangely enough,
he has this experience,
you know?
And that's heartening,
I guess.
And that's the point,
is that people are predisposed to
terrible error.
There's no doubt about that,
and yet when I was writing my latest
book,
I had a friend of mine,
Norman Doidge wrote the foreword and
Norman has written a couple of great
books and he's Jewish and he read some
of what I'd written and he took me to
task for making the God of the Old
Testament,
you know,
from a Christian perspective,
too harsh and unforgiving,
and I rewrote a fair bit of it because
of his criticism and because of what
I've learned doing these lectures.
It's like it's not exactly right.
You know what I mean?
What happens in the Old Testament is if
you screw up,
especially if you know you do and you
decide that you're not going to do
anything about it,
so it's conscious and deliberate,
then look the hell out.
You are in serious trouble and I
actually think that's also
psychologically accurate.
One of the things young pointed out,
and it's always struck me was that if
you don't know what you're doing,
this is actually in the gospel of Thomas
as well.
Interestingly enough,
is one of the gnostic gospels.
Christ tells his followers something
like,
if you make a mistake and you don't know
what you're doing,
then you'll be forgiven for it,
but if you make a mistake knowing what
you're doing and you do it anyways,
then like good luck to you.
And,
and,
and I think that's,
I think that's,
that's psychologically accurate.
We,
one of the things that's very
interesting about the judgemental God in
the Old Testament however,
is that he can be bargained with and
even if you make mistakes,
especially if you're unconscious of
them,
if you haven't learned yet,
let's say,
then you will always have the
opportunity to return to the proper
path.
And that's.
People get cynical about that because
there's no this mostly Christian idea
that you could live a terribly sinful
life,
but if you repented on your deathbed,
it's like heaven for you.
And it's like,
well that's,
that sounds like great deal,
right?
It's like you can do whatever the hell
you want until just before you die.
Of course you might not know when that
is.
So that's a problem.
You then you can just say,
well,
I'm sorry,
and you know everything's forgiven,
but the problem with being cynical about
that sort of thing is that it's no
trivial matter to repent,
you know,
because to repent means a figure out
what you actually did and the worst
things that you did,
the more horrible it is to figure it
out.
It's no joke,
right?
And there's no genuine repentance
without understanding of the depth of
your depravity.
And so if you lived to particularly
reprehensible life and you come to
understand it,
I think that in and of itself could kill
you.
You know,
it's a terrible thing to wake up and see
what you've done.
If what you've done is truly terrible,
so there's no easy way out.
It's not an easy out.
It's just pure cynicism.
To associate that idea with an easy out.
It's not,
but there is that positive idea that
it's continually represented is that the
individual is the source of moral choice
and the individual is prone to genuine
error and temptation in a believable and
realistic way,
but that that doesn't sever the
relationship between the individual and
the divine.
And the possibility of further growth
and then I would say,
well thank God for that because without
that,
like who would have a chance,
right?
Who would have a chance?
And so the idea that the daddy as
presented the infinite,
let's say as presented in the Old
Testament,
is merely judgmental,
is definitely wrong.
And,
and is in fact something that you can
contend with and arguing with.
Oh,
I'll close with one thing.
One of the things that I learned while I
was going through this was the meaning
of the name Israel because Jacob
eventually it gets named Israel and,
and I'm jumping ahead a little bit to
the next lecture,
but Israel.
And so he's also the father of Israel
and the father of the 12 sons who make
up the 12 tribes of Israel.
But what Israel means is he who
struggles with God.
And that's such an interesting idea
because it's again a psychological idea.
And that's why I said earlier that it
isn't obvious in the old testament what
it means to believe in God.
Because what Jacob does a struggle with
God.
And I think that that's a really good
characterization of an ethical life
because if you're trying to lead an
ethical life,
that's what you're doing is you're,
you're struggling like blind belief
isn't helpful because you don't know
what you're believing in,
like it's just not that helpful.
But if you're possessed by,
by the desire to orient yourself
properly,
but also confused by the,
by the existential structure of the
world,
which we all are,
then,
then what you're doing when you're
trying to orient yourself properly in
life is struggling ethically.
And Jacob actually gets quite hurt.
He wrestles with God.
Literally God dislocates his,
his,
his thigh.
And so know the idea there is
watch the hail out,
right?
The thing that you're contending with,
his powerful,
although you can contend with it,
that's the thing that's so interesting,
but you know,
you do it at some genuine peril,
which I think is exactly right.
But the idea that Israel.
So there's Israel,
the state,
let's say in Israel,
the promised land and all of that,
but there's this more important idea,
which is again,
a psychological idea,
which is the state of Israel,
which is the promised land is the state
that everyone who wrestles with God
exists in,
and that's not happy,
naive belief in,
you know,
uh,
an eternally blessed afterlife.
It's not that it's not a wish
fulfillment,
it's,
it's to be actively engaged in life and
the difficulties of life,
right?
And trying to find the path because
that's what wrestling with God is trying
to find the path.
And that seems to me what belief means
fundamentally in the Old Testament,
perhaps in the new testament as well as
that belief is expressed in trying to
find the path.
And that's an ethical struggle and it's
a real struggle.
It's the struggle of life.
So as long as you're willing to engage
in that struggle,
then hypothetically you have the divine
behind you.
And so I believe that.
I think that's true because the other
thing I see is that the people who set
things right,
so the,
the,
uh,
the horrible forces of cosmic
destruction don't do us see,
and the people who are trying to set
things right are the ones that are
struggling ethically and so and that
there is a redemptive element to that
and I don't think there's any way of
being cynical about that.
So.
Well,
so thank you.
Will.
Thank you.
So remember to speak right into the mic
because there are all these other people
watching that will hear it.
Will hear us.
So.
Okay.
Hi Dr Peterson.
So with the story of Jacob today,
there was a theme of betrayal and you
can see that from the beginning because
he was very angry and jealous of his
brother and I was thinking are there any
stores or Wakening,
say about betrayal that does come from a
loved one,
right?
Where it's not from a place of soul,
black and white of anger,
resentment and bitter.
And how the parties,
um,
kind of recover from that.
Or is there any way to renamed up or is
it as black and whites?
If you'll be traced on one,
then it's like Jacob where he's.
He was bitter.
He was born
hatred.
No,
and in fact,
in this story it's not black and white
because we know we're only halfway
through it and one of the things I've
noticed as a clinician,
let's say,
is that an as an observer of people in
general,
is that I've never ever seen anyone get
away with anything and Jacob doesn't get
away with any of this.
And so,
you know,
he's humbled by his eventual experiences
and he learns that he did it wrong and
there's reconciliation that happens
throughout the story of Jacob.
So,
and there's minor betrayals and major
betrayals.
You know,
that some of them have tremendously
serious consequences in some of them
have lesser consequences,
but there is an underlying idea that
things can still be set right.
Even though it's.
Well,
I think it takes Jacob some 20 years,
something like that to set things right.
And even then it's like touch and go.
So if I answer your question,
okay.
Yeah.
Hey,
you speak frequently in your lectures
about,
I guess the war between good and evil or
the struggle of life really is a
struggle between good and evil being at
the core of a conscious lived existence
and I guess on that note,
if you were 100 percent certain that
there was no afterlife,
would you still be able to preach that
there's a positive meeting in life?
If you're a 100 percent certain,
some atheists seem to be 100 percent
certain and yet they still preach that
there's some positive meaning to life.
Would you be one of those or would you
turn into cane?
You know,
so cynical.
I think that,
well as far as I'm concerned,
one of the things I learned from
studying 20th century history is that
like even if the idea that even if you
take the most cynical of ideas,
let's say that life is irredeemable
suffering and and perhaps isn't even
justified because of that.
It still seems to me that you have an
ethical duty,
let's say,
to live in a manner that reduces that to
the degree that that's possible.
And so,
and I think that that can be experienced
as meaningful in some sense
independently of the transcendent
context.
Now I don't exactly know how to strip
off the transcendent context because one
of the things I would say that's
happened to me is because I've spent so
much time looking at the horrible things
that people have done is that it's like
young said that he wanted.
This is one of his famous quotes.
He said,
no tree can reach up to heaven unless
its roots reached down to hell.
And so as I've dug deeper into the
depravity of human beings,
my sense of the possibility of human
beings has also grown.
What would you say in proportion and
until I've become convinced actually
that good is a more powerful force than
evil.
Evil.
Evil is an powerful force.
And so I can't really strip the
transcended way.
Now whether what bearing that has on
eternity say on an afterlife?
I mean,
I,
I can't say anything about that.
The only thing I guess I can say is that
there are many things about being that
we don't understand in the least.
And we don't understand the nature of
consciousness or the nature of time.
So I,
I'm not,
I wouldn't despair about that,
but yes,
I think that life can still be
meaningful without,
without there being a necessity of an
afterlife.
So,
no,
no.
By Dr Peterson.
So since studying your work,
one of the things that I found most
fascinating is your analysis of the
story of Cain and Abel.
And my question is,
um,
if,
if cain got to the point that he did
right before a killing his brother
murdering his ideal and decided that
that was something he didn't want to do,
what advice or guidance would you,
would you give a person that got to that
point?
Well,
there's a story I read called the
cocktail party.
I've mentioned this before by ts Elliot
in the cocktail party,
there's a scene to play where this woman
approaches a psychiatrist in and starts
talking to him about her problems.
And she said something that surprises
him.
She says,
I hope that I'm the problem.
And he says,
well,
why would you hope that?
And she says,
well,
I thought about it a lot.
And if the world is the problem,
then I'm done because I can't change the
world.
But if I'm the problem,
then maybe there's something about
myself I can change and I can undo this
terrible situation that I meant.
And so I would say that's repentance.
Fundamentally,
it's like there if,
and I say this carefully because I
understand that people are susceptible
to bad fortune.
Sin and ignorance can make that worse,
but independently of that like good
people suffer.
Make no mistake about it,
but if things aren't right for you,
if you're resentful about being because
that's the right way,
because that's the deepest way of
thinking about.
If you read the writings of the people
who do the mass killings for example,
that's what you see over and over.
It's cane.
It's like they are angry beyond
comprehension at the intolerability of
being and they're angry at God.
Even if they don't say it exactly like
that,
they come so close to saying it like
that it's.
There's no difference.
You know what God says?
Cain is look to yourself first before
you criticize being,
and that strikes me is right.
It's because to not do that as arrogant
beyond belief.
That's satanic arrogance.
Literally if something like that can be
literal,
it's like don't make yourself the judge
of being before you clean up your your
room,
let's say,
and it because the other thing too is
this is something I learned in some part
from soldier Nixon when he was in the
prison camps and trying to understand
how these heroic people he saw could
possibly manage it.
One of the exercises he undertook and he
really viewed this within a Christian
Orthodox context of Repentance and
redemption,
is he said he went over his life with a
fine tooth comb and tried to imagine all
of the ethical mistakes he made in his
entire life that he knew were mistakes.
Right?
Hey,
there was.
This was a soul search.
Not,
wasn't relying on external standards of
morality except in so far as we're
inevitably influenced by those.
And then his idea was,
is there something I could do right now
to put that right?
And that's the right question.
Like if things aren't going your way,
and I think that means that you're
resentful and arrogant and deceitful.
Those are the three things that clump
together.
I think that that,
that constitute the core of evil at
something like that.
And so if you're possessed by that,
which is a hell,
then it's repentance.
That's the right answer.
And what that means is you have to
figure out what you did wrong and you
have to pay for it,
and then at least you could think,
well look,
I can try that with all of my soul,
let's say and see what happens.
Right?
It could it be an experiment?
And then I would also say that that's an
act of faith.
It's an act of faith to conduct that
experiment because you put yourself on
the line,
right?
And that's what an act of faith is.
You don't know the outcome,
but you don't know the outcome of your
life.
So live in some sense as an act of
faith.
If you're putting faith in something
that that's why you're moving forward.
You couldn't move forward without an act
of faith.
You know,
and people say,
well,
I only move forward on the basis of the
fact.
It's like,
yeah,
but you select the facts and there's an
infinity of facts and they don't just
tell you what to do.
So it's not a credible answer.
So if you're in that situation,
it's like look to yourself,
you know,
and one of the things about soldiers
nets that's a bloody amazing is that's
what he did.
And then he wrote the Gulag archipelago
and you know,
he took an ax to the intellectual and
moral substructure of,
of the totalitarian communist states.
So while he was redeeming himself,
let's say he was simultaneously
redeeming the world and you see
something like that,
like you,
you got to wake up,
man.
That's,
that was really something.
So yeah,
Dr Peterson,
I have a lot of questions that arise
from your comments that the bell for 100
event,
you.
I'm one of three video your recent
discussion with Ayaan Hirsi Ali and your
comments on Islam and the West in
general.
And in your comments there's this common
theme that one of these things is not
like the other.
You put the Judeo Christian tradition on
the one side and Islam on the other,
specifically the quote complex problem
of Islam and the quote as a quote
totalizing system.
Before I go further,
let me state that if hypothetically,
a final analysis of Islam resulted in as
total denunciation as your analysis of
postmodernism or neo Marxism,
I wouldn't be personally offended at
all.
This isn't a a personal question.
In your recent interview with ion or
shelly,
she said Western values are superior to
Islamic law and Islamic values.
I agree with that.
Basically,
certainly in the context of,
let's say,
current global affairs.
I'll skip the quote from reason magazine
interview,
but you should read them because hers is
a worldview which is very much the west
versus Islam.
Not Radical Islam,
but Islam,
including necessarily the military
option.
So my question is at the level of
psychological significance of these
stories at the level of mythology and
archetype,
how Islam so different from thej
Christian tradition because Adam,
Adam,
eve of Satan,
Shaytan,
so on and so forth.
Everything from the fall to the flood.
A lot of what you've discussed in this
lecture series is necessarily part of
Islam as well,
and in fact,
I think one of the strongest criticism
of Islam is that it's perhaps pretty
unoriginal tonight.
You said that the moral presuppositions
of a culture and instantiated in its
stories.
I see a lot of the same stories.
So current global fairs aside,
I'm asking it the deepest levels.
How different are these stories in the
moral presuppositions?
Okay,
well that's,
that's a killer question.
Well,
okay.
So the first thing I would say is
fundamentally,
I don't know.
And so part of the reason that I'm.
One of the things I'm planning to do is
to have a series of discussions and
plenty of people have contacted me about
discussing with Ion Hirsi.
Ali has,
as you know,
she has powerful and serious fobs and
they're not happy with her black and
white distinction.
And so now I read infidel and I really
liked that book.
Like I,
I,
my sense was that she,
she was a heroin.
Now what that means in relationship to
Islam,
that's a different story because she
came out of a,
uh,
like a,
a totalitarian,
let's say family structure in a
relatively totalitarian society and you
could make the case that there is a
correspondence between that in Islam and
you could make the case that there isn't
in and of course that's the critical
issue and so there's a couple of things
that I can't wrap my head around with
hap wrapped my head around easily in
relationship to Islam and so one is what
I see as the failure to separate church
from state and a problem.
Now it may not be a problem as such,
but it's certainly a problem in
relationship to the relation between
Islam and the West because we separate
church from state now.
There's fundamentalists in the United
States,
Christian fundamentalists who think that
that separation is a mistake.
So it's not only,
it's not only an idea that's rooted in
Islam that those should be united,
but it's definitely a problem with
regards to our coexistence because
that's a fundamentally different
presumption.
Okay,
so that's problem number one.
Problem number two,
for me,
and again this may be a consequence of
my ignorance,
which I'm trying to rectify.
Mohammed was a warlord and I,
I don't know what to do about that fact,
like one thing you can say about Christ
hypothetically,
let's say I'm not talking about a
historical reality necessarily,
although I'm not denying it either,
is that of all the things he was war
lord was definitely not one of them and
I don't know what to do about that and
so I don't know how to reconcile that
and I don't know how to reconcile.
Like not only was Mohammed a warlord,
which I don't think is an unreasonable
thing to proclaim.
The expansion that he initiated was
unbelievably successful.
I mean within 600 years it was the
biggest empire the world had ever seen
and a demolished Byzantine Christianity,
which is something that western people
don't even know.
You know,
I've read thinkers who said that the
west was so traumatized culturally,
let's say by the demolition of Byzantine
Christianity that we can't even study it
now.
And so I don't know if that's true,
but I don't know that it's not true
either and the Buddhists were wiped out
of Afghanistan,
um,
and we saw that echoed in the Taliban's
destruction of those great Buddhist
monuments.
And so,
so what I'm hoping is that there's a
bridge
there better be a bridge and that's why
I want to have these discussions because
I'd like to understand if there's a
bridge.
And so lots of people have sent me
people who I should talk to who they
think represent Islam far better than I
on her Zellie and perhaps they're
correct and hopefully I'll get an
opportunity to talk to them because I
would like to know why I would like to
know if what I think is wrong because if
it's wrong,
it's important that I know it's wrong.
But at the moment I don't a,
I don't know what's wrong.
And B,
I don't see.
I'm not sure what it signifies.
So.
And I don't think anyone is sure.
Right?
Because we have this entangled
entangling of the civilizations.
You know,
when there's other things too,
like I'm not very happy with the Saudi
Arabs in the wall.
Hobbies,
I don't think there are allies.
I don't see how any Western woman can
possibly think that there are allies and
I'm not happy with the fact that the
petro dollars that we send them are
transformed in substantial part into the
kind of propaganda that's definitely a
threat to the west and I'm not very
happy with the fact that our politicians
appear stupidly blind to that.
Now.
That may again be a consequence of my
ignorance.
It's certainly possible,
but those are the sorts of things that
that I can't reconcile.
And so you know,
I've seen.
I've also seen parallels between the
ideas that I'm presenting here and other
religious traditions,
Taoism,
Buddhism,
Hinduism.
It's harder for me to bridge the gap
with Islam and I'm not sure why that is.
I think it has something to do with the
things that I just laid out now.
What I don't know about Islam would feel
very many volumes,
many of which I have sitting on my
shelves at home right now because I want
to do the reading,
you know,
as I progressed through this,
but
Yep,
Dr Pearson.
Thanks for continuing this series.
Even as atheists appreciate the
interaction and the,
uh,
the,
conversation.
I wanted to ask you something that is
both emotional and analytical because
oftentimes you're basically pegged as
seeing things very analytically.
So you were talking earlier about,
um,
you were talking about the,
the,
the juxtaposition between happiness and
um,
uh,
honor even though I don't think they're
mutually exclusive personally,
but if there's a situation,
let's say someone is truly in love with
someone else and they loved them for
many years and decades.
They have a whole history together and
then someone and then one of the people
in this grouping,
um,
start falling in love with someone else.
So it's not that there's less love for
the original partner.
How analytically and emotionally do you
take care of a situation like that when
you feel
that you want to stay honorable and be
happy?
Okay.
So the first thing I would say is the
devil's always in the details,
right?
So one of the things that I'm not happy
about with much modern moral theorizing
is that it takes a story like that and
then tries to extract out a general
moral principle and often that's
impossible because the particulars of
the situation are very important.
But having said that,
all right,
so let me think about that for a minute.
I'm not sure that it's possible to be
honorable in a situation like that
because I think that you've acted out
the violation already and having acted
out the violation to confess it might be
the right thing to do,
although perhaps not,
you know,
because if you.
It isn't obvious to me that if you'd be
trained someone then you get to have the
right to tell them about it.
I know,
I know you're not,
I understand that.
Yeah.
Yeah,
I understand.
Um,
my observation has been that if there's
a tight relationship and if one party
has betrayed by the other in that
manner,
that it's almost always irreconcilable.
It breaks it.
And,
you know,
I've,
I've helped people try to struggle
through that bone on both sides of it.
The person who was betrayed and the
person who did the betrayal,
um,
I've seen people grow up and not do it
again.
And this was in situations where their
partner didn't know.
And in a couple of those situations it
seemed to me that it might've even been
unnecessary learning experience for the
person who did it,
you know,
it,
it helped them develop.
That doesn't mean I'm justifying it,
but life is complicated.
But,
but I think that society works better.
All things considered
when you make a promise and you stick to
it.
And one of the things I learned from
reading young,
which,
which I really liked was,
you know,
he believed that he had his affairs too.
So you might think about it as somewhat
hypocritical,
but,
but I think that people can make
mistakes without having what they think
necessarily be wrong.
You know,
he said that there were things in a
marriage that you can't have unless
you're all in.
And I believe that.
I believe that.
And so if there's a back door open or
the like to begin with,
or a backdoor opens,
then I think that there's something
about the relationship that is lacking
at least,
and I think you pay a big price for
that.
So I mean it depends on whether you
regard to marriage as a practical
arrangement or a spiritual arrangement.
Now really it's both,
you know,
both are important,
but if it's a spiritual arrangement or a
psychological arrangement above,
then I do think that you don't get the
transformation without being all in.
And if you violate it,
then even if you can work it out with
your partner,
there's something that you will never
get as a consequence.
So.
Yup.
Last question.
Okay.
I hope I'll make this good.
Thanks.
Also for continuing to electric series.
I haven't listened to all of the
lectures,
but it seems like you focus very much on
the appeal of the biblical stories to
the individual psychology.
Do you have any thoughts on the relative
importance of crowd psychology to the
appeal instinct,
power of the Bible and also the the
reason why the Bible or the biblical
stories took precedence over other
ideologies which could have taken its
place?
Okay.
Well,
let's go to the second one first.
I think it's the same thing that happens
when someone both creates an edits,
a great movie.
It's no one knows like imagine how many
choices are there,
integrate movie.
Let's say it's an animated movie because
absolutely everything in an animated
movie as constructed everything.
There's God only knows how many choices.
Like maybe there's millions of choices
and each choice is guided by some
intuition of narrative suitability or
beauty or there's some higher ideal
motivating it,
right?
The desire to produce a masterpiece.
Maybe that's it.
That was certainly the case with the
Disney movies,
for example,
and so that that aspiration then then
makes the decisions and so I would say,
well,
something like that guided the writing
and the selection of the stories in the
biblical Canon now could have there been
other stories included while the
Catholics and the Protestants don't have
the same biblical tradition and neither
do the Jews and the Christians and so it
isn't exactly clear what to make of
that,
you know,
I mean that's a can in some sense,
to the discussion we just had about
Islam and Christianity are in some sense
I've left that aside,
that specific question except in so far
as I've just answered because I'm trying
to take what we have,
which I know is at the root of our
culture and to figure out what it is
that we have,
why it is that we have at.
Well,
I made some attempt to explain that in
the manner that I just described,
but I don't have a final answer.
I could.
It have been different.
It could have been different at some
levels,
but the same at others.
You know,
I mean one of the things that scholars
of comparative religion who haven't been
infected fatally with postmodernism have
definitely realized so young,
for example,
in Eliana and people who are interested
in grand narratives.
One of the things they pointed out quite
clearly is that there's,
there's,
there's a set of common mythological
themes across many cultures and I tried
to outline that in maps of meaning and
that that worked out quite nicely for me
at least as far as I was concerned
because once I had the basic
architectural structure mapped out,
it opened up all sorts of stories to me
from all sorts of different cultures and
that's been unbelievably useful.
Like the Mesopotamian story of it.
The enuma elish when,
when I figured out what that meant as
far as I was concerned,
like I've never forgotten that.
It just seared itself into my memory.
And the same with the Egyptian stories
and you know,
some Buddhist writings that I've read in
some.
The Tao Te Ching is also very powerful.
So I think that things can be different
on one level and the same at another,
but that humanity kind of coalesces on
what's the same over a reasonable period
of time because there isn't that many
ways that human beings can live properly
as individuals and as groups together.
And so there's this constant force that
makes our ethical presuppositions
converge and then that's automatically
expressed in the stories.
It's something like that now.
It's an imperfect process and it's full
of error.
So.
Yep.
Thank you.
Just one announcement.
Well two announcements.
The next lecture I believe is November
14th,
so I'll hopefully finish off the story
of Jacob.
Looks like it.
And then I'm also appearing on a panel
with Gad,
Saad and slash or an amateur on November
11th.
And there's still quite a few tickets
available for that.
So if you're interested you could go to
my website and pick up those tickets.
So it should be.
Well,
hopefully it'll be interesting.
I think it will be and it might be too
interesting.
That's one possibility.
So we'll see.
But I'm going to do two more of these
this year and I hope I get through the
story of Joseph and then I can start in
the new year with,
with exodus,
and that's a story that I know quite
well and the exodus and leviticus and
what's the one after that?
Um,
yes.
Thank you.
Um,
so I'm very much looking forward to that
because that is one killer story
mountain.
So,
and,
uh,
I've got some surprises for that as
well.
So anyways,
thank you very much for coming and,
uh,
hopefully we'll see you November 14th.