Alright,
so the last time I was here,
many of you were as well.
We got halfway through the story of
Jacob and I've been digging underneath
the story sporadically since then to try
to find out what other themes are being
developed and I've got some things that
I think are really interesting to talk
about.
So um,
so we'll get right into it.
So I'm going to review a little bit
first.
So we were talking about Jacob and I'll
re update his biography a little bit so
that we can place ourselves in the
proper context before we go on.
So his mother,
Rebecca gave birth to twins and the
twins,
even in her womb,
we're struggling for a while,
what they were struggling.
And of course the story is that they
were struggling for dominance the older
or the younger,
against the older.
Really because Jacob,
Jacob means you surper and Rebecca had
a,
uh,
what would you call a vision from God
that said that Jacob would supplant
Esau.
And so even before her twins were born,
they were in a state of competition.
And that's a recapitulation of the motif
of the hostile brothers,
right?
It's a very,
very,
very common mythological motif and we
already saw that really well developed
in the story of Cain and Abel and Cain
and Abel were essentially the first two
human beings,
the first two natural born human beings.
And they were instantly locked in the
state of enmity,
which is symbolic of first the enmity
that exists within people's psyche
between the part of them you might say
that saving at the light and the part of
them that's aiming at the darkness.
And I think that's a reasonable way of
portraying it.
Obviously it's a way that sort of rife
with symbolism,
but my experience of people,
especially when you get to know them
seriously or when they're dealing with
serious issues,
is that there is quite clearly a part of
them that's striving to do well in the
world or even to do good.
And another part that's deeply cynical
and embittered that it says to hell with
it and is self destructive and lashes
out and really aims at making things
worse.
And so that seems to be a natural part
of the human psyche and that's also
reflected in the,
the idea of the fall.
And so those ideas are not easily
castaway.
They're associated with the rise of self
consciousness right in,
in the story of the garden of Eden.
And I think that's right because I do
think that our selfconsciousness
produces that division within us because
more than any other creature,
we're intensely aware of our finitude
and suffering.
And that tends to turn us at least to
some degree against being itself.
You know,
I was watching a bunch of protesters in
the US last week scream at the sky.
How about trump?
You know,
and uh,
it was interesting,
like I thought it was an extraordinarily
narcissistic display,
but,
but despite that,
there was something symbolically
appropriate about it.
I also,
there's a movie I really like,
sadly enough called Fubar.
I don't know how many of you have seen
that.
Yeah.
You know that movie I take it.
It's about the people I grew up with.
So.
Yeah,
that's true,
man.
I'm telling you.
That's true.
So the guy,
the main actor in Fubar,
who's quite bright but completely
uncivilized,
gets testicular cancer and there's one
great scene where he gets far too drunk
and he's stumbling around the street,
you know,
in,
uh,
virtually comatose state.
And of course he's not very thrilled
with what's happened to him and he's
shaking his fist at the sky.
It's pouring rain and he's cursing God
and you know,
it's like,
well,
you can kind of understand is
positioned.
So that Kinda reminded me of these
people who were yelling at the sky,
you know,
they were basically they are at
dramatizing the idea of in rate they
were enraged at while you could say God,
of course most of them wouldn't say
that,
but would they were the ones yelling at
the damn sky.
I mean,
you know,
so you gotta you gotta look at what
they're doing rather than what they say.
And they were outraged that being was
constructed such that trump could have
arisen as president.
And so well.
So this idea,
you know,
that we can be easily turned against
being and work for its destruction is a
really.
It's a really common,
common common theme.
It never goes away.
You see it echoed in stories like with
the new marvel series for example,
you see the enmity between thor and
Loki.
That's a good example of the same thing,
or between Batman and the joker,
there's superman and Lex luthor.
These.
There's these pairs of a hero against
villain that's a really dramatic and
easily what everyone can understand that
dynamic,
right?
It's a basic plot and the reason it's a
basic plot is because it's true of the
battle within our spirits,
our own individual spirits.
It's true within families because
sibling rivalry can be unbelievably
brutal.
It's true between human beings who are
strangers.
It's true between groups of people like
it's true at every level of analysis and
then in some sense it's.
It's architecturally true at least with
regards to deep religious symbolism
because you see that echoed in many
stories as well,
so I think the clearest representation
is probably Christ in St and that's the
closest to a pure archetype.
Although there is in the old Egyptian
stories,
there's Osiris and seth or horus and
seth and seth is a precursor to Satan
etymologically,
so it's a very,
very common motif and so that's what
happens again in Rebecca's womb is that
this thing,
this idea has played out right away and
the two,
the two twins are actually,
what would you call it there they have a
superordinate destiny because one of
them is destined to become the father of
Israel and of course that's a pinnacle
moment in the Old Testament obviously
and arguably a pinnacle moment in human
history.
Now the degree to which the stories in
the Old Testament actually constitute
what we would consider empirical history
as a matter of debate,
but it doesn't matter in some sense
because as I mentioned,
I think before in this lecture series
know there are.
There are forms of fiction that are met.
A true,
which means that they're not necessarily
about a specific individual.
Although I generally think they are
based on the life of specific
individuals.
It's the simplest theory,
but who knows,
right?
But there are more real than reality
itself because they abstract out the
most relevant elements of reality and
present them to you.
And that's why you watch fiction.
You know you don't want.
You want your fiction boiled down,
right?
You want to boil down to the essence.
That's what makes good fiction and that
essence is something that's truer than
than plain old truth.
If it's handled well.
And so you know,
if you watch a shakespeare play,
half a lifetime of events can go by in a
shakespeare play and it covers a wide
range of scenes and so on and and so
it's,
it's cut and edited and compressed all
at once.
But because of that blasts you with with
a kind of emotional and ethical force
that just the mirror videotaping of
someone's daily life wouldn't even,
wouldn't even come close to
approximating.
So then this motif of the hostile
brothers,
that's a,
that's a deep,
deep archetipal truth.
And God says to Rachel,
two nations are in thy womb,
and two manner of people shall be
separated from the bowels and one people
shall be stronger than the other,
and the elder shall serve the younger.
And so there's a inversion there,
right?
Because as we've discussed historically
speaking in traditionally speaking,
it's the elder son that to whom the
disproportionate blessings flow.
There's some truth in that too.
Even more.
What would you say more empirically?
Iq tends to decrease as the number of
children in the family increase the
younger.
The oldest is the smartest.
Generally speaking,
it isn't clear why that is,
but it might be that they get more
attention,
but who knows?
So those of you who are younger can be
very unhappy about that fact.
Now Jacob.
Okay,
so there's another,
there's another plot line here too,
because I'm a Abraham and and Rebecca
are at odds at.
Sorry,
Isaac and Rebecca are at odds about the
children.
Right?
So there's a,
there's an eatable twist to it too,
because.
Well,
Isaac is allied with Esau who turns out
to be the hunter type.
So he's your basic rough and tumble
character,
you know,
and he's kind of a wild looking guy
called Harry and he likes to be outside.
He lives in tents,
he likes to hunt.
He's a man's man.
That's one way of thinking about it.
Whereas Jacob dwells intense,
you know,
he doesn't go outside much.
He's more,
well maybe he's more introverted,
but he's certainly the sort of kid
adolescent say who hangs around home and
there's some intimation that he's as
well.
He's clearly as mother's favorite and
with all the advantages and I suppose
disadvantaged that go along with that.
And Isaac and Rebecca don't see eye to
eye about who should have predominance
among the sons.
And Rebecca is quite complicit with
Jacob in inverting the social order.
So the first thing that happens that's
crooked is that Esau comes in from
hunting and he's,
you know,
maybe he's been out for a number of days
and he's ravenous and he's kind of an
impulsive guy,
doesn't really seem to think about the
longterm very much.
And Jacob was cooking some lentil stew
and Esau wants some of it and Jacob
refuses.
And then says that he'll trade his,
his birthright for it,
and uh,
Esau agrees,
which is a bad deal,
right?
It's a bad deal.
And so you,
you could say that Esau actually
deserves what's coming to them,
although at minimum you'd have to think
of them both as being equally culpable.
It's a nasty trick.
And so that's Jacob's first trick.
And then the second trick is that it's
later and Isaac is old and blind and you
know,
close to death and it's time for him to
bestow a blessing on his sons,
which is a very important event
apparently among these ancient people.
And Esau again is out hunting and Rachel
dress dresses.
Jacob in a hairy puts a goat skin on his
arm.
So he's Kinda hairy like Esol and
dresses.
A Minnesota was closed so he smells like
Esau.
And Isaac Tells Esau to go out and hunt
him up some,
some venison I think it is.
And which is a favorite of his.
And Rebecca has Jacob Cook up a couple
of goat kids and serve that to Isaac and
play the role of Esl.
And so he does that.
It's pretty damn nasty.
Really all things considered,
you know,
to play a trick like that both on your
brother and on your blind father and in
collusion with your mother.
It's not the sort of thing that's really
designed to promote lot of familial
harmony and so especially because you've
already screwed them over in a big way.
Once you know,
you'd think you'd think that would be
sufficient.
So anyways,
he's successful and ESL loses his
father's blessing and so that Jacob ends
up really in the position of the first
born.
And it's quite interesting because you
know,
God tells Rachel that Jacob is going to
be the dominant twin and you'd think
again with God's blessing or at least
the prophecy that Jacob would end up
being in a good guy,
but he certainly not presented that way
to begin with,
which is also quite interesting given
that he's the eventual founder of
Israel.
And it's another indication of the
realism of these old stories.
You know,
and it's,
it's quite amazing to me.
It's always been quite amazing to me how
unprinted fight these stories have
remained.
You know,
because you'd think that if you're even
the least bit cynical,
especially if you had the kind of
Marxist religion is the opiate of the
masses kind of viewpoint,
which,
which is a credible viewpoint,
you know,
although it's wrong,
but it's.
Well,
I think it's a shallow.
I think it's a shallow interpretation
and a part of the reason I think it's a
shallow interpretation is because the
stories would be a lot prettier if that
was the case.
These characters wouldn't have this
strange,
realistic,
moral ambiguity about them.
You know,
if you're going to feed people a
fantasy,
then if you want it to be like a
harlequin novel or,
or,
or our greeting card or something like
that,
you don't want it to be a story that's
full of betrayal and deceit and murder
and mayhem and genocide and all of that.
That just doesn't seem all that.
What would you say?
Calming I guess would be the right
answer.
So anyways,
Jacob gets away with this,
but Esau is not happy and,
and Jacob is quite convinced that he
might kill them.
And I think that was a reasonable fear
because Esau was a tough guy and he was
used to being outside and he knew how to
hunt and he knew how to kill and he
actually wasn't very happy about getting
seriously screwed over by his,
you know,
stay at home brother twice.
And so Jacob runs off and goes to visit
his uncle and on the way.
And this is a very interesting part of
this story.
He stops and to sleep and he takes a
stone for a pillow and then he has this
vision.
It's called a dream,
but the context makes it look like a
vision of a ladder reaching up to heaven
and with angels moving up and down the
ladder,
let's say.
And there's some representations of
that.
I showed you some of them the last time
we met,
but I'll read it to you first.
He lighted upon a certain place and
tarried there all night because the sun
was set and he took of the stones of
that place and put them for his pillows
and lay down in that place to sleep.
And he dreamed and beheld a ladder set
up on the earth,
and the top of it reached to heaven and
behold the angels of God ascending and
descending on it.
And behold the lord stood above it and
said,
I am the Lord God of Abraham,
thy father and the god of Isaac,
the land.
We're on the Elias to the I will give it
Nti seed.
And I see job as the dust of the earth.
And now schultes spread abroad to the
west and to the east and to the north
and the south.
So that lays out the canonical
directions,
right?
So now there's a center with the
canonical directions,
like the thing that you see,
that little symbol you see on maps,
it's the same thing that symbolically
placed upon the earth.
So a center has been established with
radiating well with,
with what?
With with directional lines radiating
from it.
So it establishes as,
as a place and in the seed shall all the
families of the earth be blessed.
So that's pretty good news for Jacob.
And it's not self evident why God is
rewarding him for running away after
screwing over his brother.
But that seems to be what happens.
And so here's a couple of
representations,
classic representations.
The one on the right is William Blake
has one I particularly like,
you know,
on Blake assimilates God with the sun
when with light,
right?
So that's quite a common mythological
idea that God is associated with light
and the day
behold I am with thee and will keep the
in all places,
whether thou go list and we'll bring the
again into this land for I will not
leave thee until I have done that,
which I have spoken to the of and Jacob
awaked out of his sleep.
And he said,
surely the Lord is in this place.
And I knew what not.
And he was afraid,
which is exactly the right response.
And said,
how dreadful is this place?
It is none other than the house of God
and this is the gate of heaven.
And Jacob rose up early in the morning
and took the stone that he had put for
his pillows and set it up for a pillar.
And poured oil on the top of it and
that's,
that's a more important thing than you
think.
And what will go into that a little bit
more deeply because up to this point in
the story,
there isn't anything really.
There isn't.
That's really emerged to mark a sacred
space,
right?
There's no,
there's no cathedral,
there's no church,
there's nothing like that.
But here's this idea that emerges that
you can mark the center of something
that and that's important and you mark
it with a stone and a stone is a good
way to mark things that,
that are important because the stone is
permanent,
right?
And we mark things with stones now like
we marked graves with stones for
example,
because we want to make a memory and to
carve something into stone,
to carve a stone.
And then to carve something into stone
is to make a memory and to use stone is
to make a memory because stone is
permanent.
And to set it upright as to indicate a
center.
And so that's what happens in pours oil
on the top of it,
which is kind of offering.
And he called the name of that place
Bethel,
but the name of the city was called
[inaudible] at the first and Jacob vowed
a vow saying,
if God will be with me and will keep me
in this way,
that I go and will give me bread to eat
and Raymond to put on
than a 10th of what I earn,
I will give him.
I missed that.
That's interesting too,
because now there's a transformation of
sacrifice,
right?
Because until that point,
sacrifices have had been pretty
concretized.
It was the burning of something.
Whereas here,
all of a sudden it's the offering of,
of,
of productive labor per se,
like a tie.
This tie is a form of sacrifice.
And so there's an abstraction of the
idea of sacrifice,
sacrifice.
It's really important that the idea of
sacrifice gets abstracted,
right?
Because it should be abstracted to the
point where it's,
it's used the way that we use it today,
which is,
you know,
we make sacrifices to get ahead and
everyone understands what that means.
But the sacrifices are generally some
combination of psychological end and,
and practical.
So we're not acting them out.
We're precisely,
we're not dramatizing the Mer
ritualizing and we actually act them out
in our,
in the covenant that we make with the
future,
and we do that well unless we're
extraordinarily impulsive and aimless in
our lives and have really no conception
whatsoever of the future and are likely
to sacrifice the future for the present,
which is what Esau does,
right?
Then we make sacrifices and you gotta
think like the idea of making sacrifices
to make the future better is an
extraordinarily difficult lesson to
learn.
It took people,
God only knows how long to learn that,
you know,
like we,
we have no idea.
It's not something that animals do
easily.
Chimpanzees don't store leftover meat,
you know,
they just needed to wolves,
they just,
a wolf can eat about 30 pounds of meat
in one city and that's where the idea of
wolfing it down comes from.
They're not hiding it,
saving it for later,
you know,
they can't do that,
so they can't sacrifice the present for
the future.
So this is a big deal.
This,
that,
this happens.
Now I want to tell you a little bit
about the idea of the pillar because
it's,
it's an unbelievably deep idea and it
orients us in ways that we still don't.
It's still orienting us in ways that we
don't understand.
In fact,
it's actually the mechanism by which
we're oriented or,
and if it's lacking then we become
disoriented.
And so I'll show you some pictures and
describe them first.
Okay.
So first of all,
there's a walled city.
So let,
let me tell you that you could think
about that as an archetypal human
habitation.
Maybe it's a reflection of something
like a fire in the middle of the plane
or the forest or the jungle for that
matter.
Although it's kind of hard to get a fire
going there.
Imagine a fire ringed around with logs
and perhaps ringed around with
dwellings,
right?
So the fires in the center and the fire
defines the center and then as you move
away from the fire,
you move out into the darkness,
right?
So the fire is light and communion and
safety.
And as you move away from the fire,
you move out into the darkness.
And what's terrifying out beyond the
perimeter.
So what's beyond the perimeter is
terrifying.
You can feel that if you go camping
somewhere that's wild,
you know you're pretty damn happy,
especially if the wolves are howling,
you're pretty damn happy to be sitting
by the fire because you can see there
the fire keeps the animals away and you
know if you do wander into the bush,
into the darkness,
then you're on alert and you know your
Predator detection systems are on alert.
And so you could think about the
classical human habitation as two
places.
One where your Predator detection system
isn't on alert and another where your
Predator tech detection system is alert
on alert.
And you can think about that roughly as
the distinction between unexplored
territory and unexplored territory.
And really the founding of a place is
precisely.
This is a lot of this I got from reading
virtually Eliana.
The founding of a place is precisely the
definition of a explored center set
against the unexplored periphery.
And you know what's interesting about
that,
so you can kind of think about that with
regards to the walled city,
right?
Everything in the wall is cosmos and
everything outside the wall is chaos and
you know,
but it also extends to the conceptual
realm because imagine that you're the
master of a field of study,
and so that's an interesting metaphor
because the field is that a geographical
metaphor,
right?
And if in the center of the field are
those things that everyone knows really
well,
the axioms that everyone abides by in
the field,
and then as you move towards the
fringes,
you get to work towards the unknown,
towards the frontier of the discipline,
and as you become expert,
you move from the center to the frontier
and so then you're on the border.
When you're,
when you're,
when you're a scholar,
a competence call,
you're on the border between the
unexplored or the explored an unexplored
and you're trying to further that
border.
So even if you're just doing this
abstractly,
it's the same thing and it's a
reflection of the fact that every human
environment,
concrete or abstract,
it makes no difference recapitulates the
cosmos chaos dichotomy or the order
chaos dichotomy.
And that's why endow isn't.
For example,
it's the union of chaos.
And order that constitutes being itself
and that you stand on the border between
chaos and order because that's the
proper place to be,
to orderly too much in the explored.
You're not learning anything too much
out there where the predators lurk,
then you're frozen with terror and
neither of those positions are
desirable.
So.
And that's what you know.
And so you think,
and this is a concrete reality obviously
as well as a psychological reality,
there were reasons for those walls,
right?
Because inside the walls were all the
people like us.
And so that begs the question,
what does it mean for people to be like
us?
And then outside the wall of the rows,
all of those people because they were
the worst forms of predators because
people are actually the worst forms of
predators who aren't like us.
And the wall is there to draw a
distinction between like us and not like
us.
And so,
and that was a matter of life and death.
You can tell that because I mean look at
those walls,
they had to build those by hand.
And you know,
you do see walled cities that have three
rings of walls,
so these people were terrified but not
so terrified as the people who built
three walls,
they were really terrified and they had
their reasons.
So okay,
so now there's an idea that's,
that's reflected in the Jacob's ladder
story,
that the center where you put the pillar
is also the place where heaven and earth
touch.
And so that's,
that's a complicated idea I think that
you can.
I'm trying to look at these stories from
a psychological perspective and so then
you could say that that's a symbolic
place where the lowest and the highest
come together.
And so it's a place where earthly being
stretches up to the highest possible
ethical abstraction.
And that's the center because one of the
things that defines us say,
as opposed to them,
is that we're all united within a
certain ethic.
That's what makes us the same.
This is a complicated line of reasoning
and,
but I'll go back to it after I show you
some more pictures.
But.
So that's,
that's the first idea is that the center
is the place where the lowest and the
highest touch simultaneously.
And so you could say that in some sense
it specifies the aim of a group of
people.
That's another way.
You know if you get together with people
to make a group even at work,
you group yourself around a project and
that unites you and the United States
because we all have the same name.
You're all pointing to the same thing
and that makes you the same in some ways
because if you're after the same thing I
am,
then the same things are going to be
important to you that are important to
me.
And the same things are going to be
negative to you that are negative to me
because our emotions work out that way.
And that means I can instantly predict
you know how you're going to behave.
And so our aim,
which is basically our ethical amy,
it's because we're aiming at something
better.
At least in principle,
we're aiming at something better.
So our ethical aim that unites our
perceptions and that's what aligns our
emotions.
And so that sort of begs the question,
if you're going to build a community
around what aim should the community
congregate?
Okay.
So the idea here is that the center of
the community is the pillar that Unites
Heaven and earth.
So it unites the lowest with the
highest.
So there was some intimation of the idea
that it's the highest that unites the
community.
Okay.
And so keep that in mind.
And that's a very old idea as well.
That's the idea of the Axis Mundi,
which is the center pole that Unites
Heaven and earth.
It's an unbelievably old idea.
Tens of thousands of years old.
It might even stretch back to whatever
our archaic memories,
memories,
I don't know how,
what you would describe them,
archetipal memories of are excessively
old ancestry and trees when the tree
itself was in fact the center of the
world and that it was ringed by snakes
and chaos.
And so while we have no idea how old
these ideas are,
but they're very,
very old and evolution is a conservative
business.
Once it builds a gadget,
then it builds new things on top of that
gadgets,
like a medieval town,
right?
The center of the town is really old and
new,
newer areas of the town get built around
it,
but the center is still really old and
that's what we're like.
You know,
our,
our platforms like our,
our basic physiological structure.
This,
this skeletal body is some tens of
millions of years old or older than
that.
If you think about vertebrates,
it's much older than that and that's all
conserved.
So everything's built on top of
everything else.
All right,
so there's a kind of a classic town and
there's the idea I showed you this,
this Scandinavian world tree,
same idea unites heaven and earth and
around the roots of that tree are snakes
that eat this tree constantly.
So that's the idea that there's
stability,
but there's constant transformation
around that stability.
And at the same time the snakes are
knowing and the roots,
there's streams that are nourishing it.
So it's sort of,
it's sort of an echo of the idea that
life depends on death and renewal
constantly because your cells are dying.
And being renewed constantly,
right?
If they are just proliferating,
then you have cancer.
If they're just dying then you dye it.
You have to get the balance between
death and life.
Exactly right.
So that you can actually live,
which is also a very strange thing.
So.
And that tree is something that reaches
from the bottom layers of being maybe
the microcosm all the way to the
macrocosm.
That's the idea.
Anyways.
So then there's,
okay,
so there's,
there's a Jacob and his is pillar.
He's got this idea that you can mark the
center with this stone.
Like it sort of symbolizes what he was
laying on when he dreamt,
but now he's got this idea,
you put something erect and it marks the
center and it symbolizes his vision of
the highest good.
Something like that.
And the promise that's been made to him.
And then this is an Egyptian obelisk,
the pyramid on top of it that's in
Paris.
It was taken from Luxor and put in
And so that's a much more sophisticated
instance of the same idea.
Okay.
And there was a stone age culture is
across Eurasia that put up these huge
obelisks everywhere.
These huge,
like the stonehenge is a good example of
that,
although it's very sophisticated and
there are also markers of places we
don't know exactly what their function
is,
but they're very much akin to this some
permanent marker of place.
There's a good one.
So that's in St Peter's and I really
liked this one because you can see the
echoes of Jacob's vision for the
establishment of a territory there,
right?
You've got the obelisk in the middle and
then you've got the directions radiating
from the center.
And of course St Peters.
This is the St Peter's Basilica in Rome,
which is an absolutely unbelievable
place.
It's just jaw dropping.
And so there's the cathedral at the back
of it.
And then there's this circle of pillars
that surrounds it.
You can just see them a little bit on
the,
on the middle left there.
That goes all the way around that entire
enclosure.
And uh,
you know,
very large number of people can gather
there.
And then.
So that pillar marks the center and that
would be the center of Catholicism,
essentially.
That's what that represents,
right?
The symbolic center of Catholicism.
Although you could make the case that
the cathedral is the center,
it doesn't really matter.
They're very close together and it's.
It's half a dozen of one in six of the
other.
And then here's another representation
of the same idea,
right?
Is that this is why people don't like
the flag to be burned because
conservative people see the flag as the
sacred thing that binds people together
and so they're not happy when that
sacred thing is,
even if it's destroyed in the name of
protest.
Whereas the people who burned flags
thank well there are times to dramatize
the idea that the center has been
corrupt and you can demonstrate that by
putting it to the torch,
you know as a representation that,
that this,
that the corrupt center now has to be
burned and transformed.
And the thing is they're both right.
They're both right all the time because
the center is absolutely necessary and
is sacred and is almost always also
corrupt and in need of reparation.
That's also an archetypal idea and,
and that's a useful thing to know
because you know,
it's easy for young people in particular
to think that while the world's going to
hell in a hand basket and it's the fault
of the last generation,
they've left us this terrible mess and
leave feeling pretty betrayed about
that.
Now we have to clean it up.
It's like,
yeah,
people have been thinking that for like
35,000
years.
It's not new.
And,
and the reason it's not new,
it's because it's always true.
You know,
what you're handed is a sacred center
with flaws always,
always as partly because it's the
creation of the dead right in the dead.
Can't see and they can't communicate.
And so they're not in touch with the
present.
And so what they've bequeath to you,
apart from the fact that it might
actually be corrupt,
which is a slightly different thing,
is at least blind in dead.
And so what the hell can you expect from
something that's blind in dead?
No,
you're lucky if it just doesn't stomp
you out of existence.
So.
So that's,
uh,
a lovely photograph obviously.
And that's the establishment of a new
center.
Then the center can be a cathedral to
and often is of course in classic
counts,
European towns in particular,
although it's not only European towns
that are like this,
there's a center that's made out of
stone.
So that would be the cathedral and it's
got the highest tower on top of the
tower.
There's often across and that's the
symbolic center.
So people are are drawn together around
whatever the cross represents.
Now that the cross obviously represents
a center because it's an x,
right?
X marks the spot.
So the center of the Cross is the
center.
And then the cathedral is often in a
cross shape which also marks the center.
And then in the cathedral there's a dome
often in that's the sky.
And that's that ladder that reaches from
Earth to heaven.
So it's a recapitulation of the same
idea.
So,
and people are drawn to that center and
the center is the symbol of what unites
them.
And what unites them is the faith that
the cathedral is the embodiment of.
And you think,
well what does the faith mean?
And again,
we're approaching this psychologically,
and what it means is that we,
everyone who's a member of that group,
accepts the transcendent ideal of the
group.
Now the thing is,
if you're the member of a group,
you accept the transcendent ideal of the
group.
That's what it means to be a member of a
So if you're in a work team and you're
all working on a project,
what you've essentially done is decided
that you're going to make the goal
unquestionable,
right?
I mean you might argue about the
details,
but if you're tasked with something,
you know,
here's a job for you.
10 people organize yourself around the
job.
You can argue about how you're going to
do the job,
but you can't argue about the job.
Then the group falls apart.
And so there's an act of faith in some
sense.
The reason that the act of faith is
necessary is because it's very,
very difficult to specify without error
what that central aim should be.
Given that there's any number of aims,
right?
And it's a very,
very difficult thing to figure out.
And this is something we're going to do
a little bit tonight is like what should
the aim be around which a group would
congregate?
So especially if it's a large group and
it's a large group that has to stay
together across very large swaths of
time and the group is an incredibly
diverse,
you know,
what possible kind of ideal could unite
a large group of diverse people across a
very large stretch of time.
That's a really,
really hard question and I think part of
the way that question has been answered
is it's been answered symbolically and
in the images because it's so damn
complicated that it's almost impossible
to articulate so.
But obviously you need to have a center
around which everyone can unite because
if you don't then everyone is at odds
with one another.
Like if I don't know what you're up to
and you don't know what he's up to.
We have no were just strangers and we
don't know that our ethics match at all.
Then the probability that we're going to
be able to exist harmoniously decreases
rapidly to zero.
And that's obviously just no good.
That's a state of total chaos,
so we can't have that.
It's not possible to exist without a
central ideal.
It's not possible and it's deeper than
that.
It's deeper than that.
Partly because it's.
I'll try to get this right.
This is the sort of thing that I was
arguing with Sam Harris about.
You see,
your category system is a product of
your aims.
That's the thing,
like if you have a set of facts at hand,
the facts don't tell you how to
categorize the facts because there's too
damn many facts.
There's a trillion fact and there's no
way without imposing some a priority
order on them of determining how it is
that you should order them.
So how do you order them?
Well,
that's easy.
You decide what you're aiming at.
Now,
how do you do that?
Well,
I'm not answering that question at the
moment.
I'm just saying that in order to
organize those facts,
you need it aim and then the aim
instantly organizes the facts into those
things relevant to the ame tools.
Let's say those things that get in the
way and a very large number of things
that you don't have to pay attention to
at all.
Right?
It excludes vert like if you're working
on an engineering problem,
you don't have to worry about a
practicing medicine in your
neighborhood.
You don't.
There's a bunch of like if you're
focusing on a particular,
what would you say?
Any,
any job,
any,
any set of skills implies that you're
good at a small set of things and then
not good at an incredibly large number
of other skills.
It simplifies things and so you can use
your aim as the basis of a category
structure and so you also have to keep
that in mind because what it means is,
as far as I can tell that what it means
is that your category system itself,
which is what structures your
perceptions is actually dependent on the
ethics of your aim.
It's directly,
it's a moral thing.
It's directly dependent on your aim and
that's a stunning idea if it happens to
be true.
It's not how people think about
thinking.
We don't think that way.
We think that we think deterministically
let's say,
or that we think empirically or that we
think rationally and none of that
appears to be the case.
What we do is we pause it a valid aim
and then we organize the world around
the aim and there's plenty of evidence
from that in in psychological studies of
perception,
right?
That that does look like how the
perceptual systems work.
Mostly they ignore because the world's
too complicated.
They focus on a small set of phenomena
deemed relevant to whatever the aim is,
and then of course the aim is
problematic.
Again,
it's complex because the aim I have has
to be an aim that some of you at share
or at least don't object to because
otherwise I'm not going to get anywhere
with my damn aim.
It has to actually be implementable in
the world.
It has to be sustainable across at least
some amount of time.
It can't kill me like it's really hedged
in this aim.
It's.
It isn't any old thing.
There's hardly any things that it can
be.
So you know,
Jacob's aim,
for example,
in undermining Esau almost gets him
killed and you can understand why that's
the other thing you think,
well,
that,
that was a nasty bit of work.
You can understand [inaudible] rage.
It's even though we're separated from
the people in these stories by what,
4,000
years,
3000 years,
something like that,
you know,
in immediately why everyone feels the
way they do.
At least once you understand the context
of the story that none of that
mysterious in the least.
So,
so there's the church and the church is
underneath the cross,
right?
So that St Peter's Basilica.
And so there's the cross on the globe,
on top of the basilica,
and then there's the cross on the,
uh,
obelisk as well.
And so what that means is that,
and this is where things get insanely
complicated,
is that the center is defined by
whatever the cross represents.
Now the cross represents a crossing
point.
Geographically,
it's certainly that the cross probably
represents the body to some degree,
but then the cross also represents the
place of suffering obviously.
And more importantly,
it,
it represents the place of voluntary
suffering transcended.
I'm speaking psychologically,
right?
Not Theologically.
That's what it represents.
And so you might say,
so here's the idea behind putting down
the obelisk with the cross and saying
that that's the center.
So that's the thing that everyone's
aiming at.
And so the I,
the idea would be,
well,
if you're going to be a member of the
group defined by this obelisk,
then what you do is accept your position
at the center of suffering voluntarily
and therefore transcended.
That's the idea.
And that is one hell of an idea.
It really is,
man,
that is a killer idea because it's
actually a signal.
It's a really clear signal of
psychological health,
you know,
because one of the things you do if
you're a clinical psychologist and
someone is paralyzed by fear,
is what you do is you break their fears
down into relatively manageable bits and
then you have them voluntarily confront
their fears.
And it might also be things that they're
disgusted by,
say if they have obsessive compulsive
disorder,
but it produces very strong negative
emotion,
whatever it is.
And then you have them voluntarily
confront whatever it is that produces
that overwhelming negative emotion and
that makes them stronger.
That's what happens.
It doesn't make them less afraid.
It makes them more courageous and
stronger.
And that is not the same thing.
It's seriously not.
It doesn't decrease the fear.
It increases the courage.
And so that's a mind boggling idea and
it's deeper.
You know,
one of the things that's really
interesting about these archetipal ideas
is that maybe it's partly because of the
hyperlink nature of the Bible.
That's part of it,
but it's not.
The whole thing is that no matter how
deep you dig into them,
you'll never get to the bottom.
You know,
you hit a bottom,
you think,
God,
that's so unbelievably profound.
And then if you excavate a little
underneath that,
you find something else that's even more
profound and you think,
wow,
that's got to be the bottom.
And then you dig under that.
It's like there's no bottom.
You can just keep digging down while as
far as I can tell,
you can keep digging down layer after
layer and we'll talk a little bit about
more,
a little more about what the cross
signifies as the center because you see
what people were trying to figure out is
what is it that we need to unite under,
right?
What's the proper thing to unite under?
I can give you another example,
so in the Mesopotamian societies,
the emperor,
you know who was more or less than an
absolute monarch,
he lived inside what was essentially a
walled city and the god of the
Mesopotamians was Martin and Martin was
the figure who had eyes all the way
around his head and he spoke magic
words.
So he's very attentive and very
articulate,
and it was Martin who went out and
confronted the goddess of chaos,
the dragon of chaos,
and cut her into pieces and made up the
world.
Okay,
so you can kind of understand what that
means.
So Marta goes beyond the frontier into
the place of predatory chaos and
encounters the thing that's terrifying
and then make something productive out
of it.
So it's a hero myth and Martech is
elected to the position of preeminent
God by all the other Mesopotamian gods
because he manages that.
So the Martech idea emerges up the holy
dominance hierarchy and hits the
pinnacle so that and God only knows how
long that took.
It would be the amalgamation of many
tribes and then the,
the what,
the distillation of all the tribal myths
to produce this emergent story of what
constitutes top God.
And then the job of the emperor was to
act out Martik.
That's what gave him sovereignty.
So the reason that he was the center
around which people organize themselves
wasn't because he was when he was being
a proper emperor,
wasn't because there was something super
special about him,
like the power didn't exactly reside in
him,
which is a really useful thing to
separate,
right?
You want the power,
which is why it's kind of Nice to have a
symbolic monarch.
You get the symbolic power separated
from the personality power,
right?
Because otherwise they get conflated.
That's what happened in Rome.
It's a very.
And you can see attending to happen now
and then in theu ,
s like with the Kennedy dynasties and
that sort of thing.
So the idea was the emperor had
sovereignty as long as he was acting out
Marta properly and going out into the
chaos and cutting it into pieces and
making order.
That was his jobs they used to take
about side the city on the New Year's
festival and strip him of all his
emperor garments and humiliate them and
then force him to to confess all the
ways that year he hadn't been a good
martik so he wasn't a good ruler.
And so that was supposed to clue him in
and way come up.
Right.
And then they would ritually reenact the
battle of Marduk against Pi about the
chaos monster using statues.
And then if that all went well,
then the emperor would go back in and
the city would be renewed for another
year.
And we still have echoes of that in our
New Year's celebration.
Right.
It's the same idea that's echoed down
all those all those centuries,
thousands of years.
So it says such a staggeringly brilliant
idea,
right?
Because so part of the idea is that the
thing that sovereign,
so that's the pillar at the center,
that,
that everyone gathers around his,
at least in part,
the thing that courageously goes out
into the unknown and make something
useful out of it for the community.
So that's very,
very smart.
It's very smart.
So this is another example of a center.
So these,
this is the flag,
this is the Union Jack.
And so it's made up of a bunch of
crosses,
right?
And so the first cross,
the English cross,
that's the flag of St George.
That's the flag of England.
And say,
what does St George Do?
Slays the Dragon.
Exactly.
Same idea,
right?
So St George,
patron saint of England goes out and
slays the dragon and freeze the virgin
from the grip of the Dragon.
Same idea,
right?
So that's the center.
And then the second cross is called a,
a Saltier,
but it's another crucifix.
So it's the cross on which St Andrew was
crucified.
Set.
So it's the same idea.
It's the,
the center is the center of suffering
voluntarily undertaken because St Andrew
was a martyr.
And then St Patrick is the third cross.
What did St Patrick do in Ireland?
Chased out all the snakes,
right?
So it's the same thing.
Right?
And so the flag of Great Britain is the
combination of all of these three
crosses that defines the center and
that's what the flag is.
So that symbolizes all of that.
So that's,
you know,
completely mind boggling.
So.
And there's more about St Patrick too,
so he banishes this snakes after a 40
day fast.
And so that's an illusion to the 40
years that Moses spends in the desert
and also the 40 days that Christ fasts
in the New Testament and his walking
stick when he plants it grows into a
tree.
So that echos all of the ideas about the
center that we just described.
And he also speaks with the ancient
Irish ancestors,
which if you remember,
is a characteristic of the shamanic
rituals where we're.
So in the typical shamonic ritual,
which seems to be elicited by
psychedelic use.
The Sharman dissolve down past their
bones and then they go up into heaven
and speak with the ancestors,
and then they're introduced into the
heavenly kingdom and then the flesh is
put back on their bones and they come
back and tell everybody what happened,
and that's a repeatable experience,
right?
The shamanic tradition is unbelievably
widespread,
so all over Europe,
ancient Europe and Asia,
and perhaps as far down as South
America,
right?
It's highly conserved and it's out of
that tradition in all likelihood that
are religious ideation and merged so and
you can see echoes of that here so,
so back to the story of Jacob and his
ladder so that I can come again to my
father's house in peace.
Then shall the Lord be my God and this
stone,
which I've said for a pillar shall be
God's house and of all that,
that thou shalt give me.
I will surely give the 10th on the.
So that's.
That's also an echo,
I would say,
of the obligation of those who climb the
power hierarchy hierarchy to attend to
those who are at the bottom right.
Because if you think about the tithing
as a form of wealth distribution,
which is essentially what it is,
the part of the ethic that defines the
proper moral endeavor that's related to
that center is not to advance yourself
at the expense of the entire community.
So if you're,
if you're fortunate enough so that you
can rise in authority and power and
competence within the confines of a
community,
you still have a obligation to maintain
the structure,
maintain and further the structure of
the community within which you rose.
And that's obvious,
right?
Because if people didn't do that,
after a couple of generations,
the whole thing would fall apart.
So you know,
you,
it's not reasonable to destroy the game
that you're winning.
It's reasonable to strengthen the game
And so that's another thing because that
also describes the ethic that should
allow you to be an active member of the
community around which,
that,
that gathers around that center.
So,
so,
so one of the things I've learned about
the hero mythology that I really,
really liked his.
So you see this pretty clearly in the
figure of Christ,
but because two things are conjoined in
in that story,
but Christ is also the here.
There's two kinds of heroes.
Say there's the hero that goes out into
chaos and confronts the dragon of chaos
and gathers the treasure as a
consequence,
and then shares it with the community.
That's one.
The other form of hero is the hero who
stands up against the corrupt state and
rattles the foundation of the state,
has it collapsed,
and then reconstructs it,
right?
So because the two great dangers to
human beings are an protected exposure
to the catastrophes of the natural world
and subjugation to tyranny,
right?
Those are the two major dangers.
And so hero is the ultimate hero is the
person who reconstructs the structure of
the state by using the information that
he gathered by going out into the
unknown that unites them both.
And so what that means,
here's the,
here's the rub as far as I can tell.
So a structure,
a center has to risks associated with
it.
One is that it will degenerate into
chaos and the other is that will
rigidified into tyranny and it'll
degenerate into chaos even if it just
stays doing what it's doing,
so if it just does exactly what it's
doing and it doesn't change,
it will degenerate because things change
and if it doesn't change to keep up,
then it gets farther and farther away
from the environment and it'll
precipitously collapse and so and then
if it just changes willy nilly so that
nobody can establish a stable
centralize,
a game that it into chaos immediately
and no one can get along.
So there's a rule for being longing to
the community and the rule has to be
that you have to act in a manner that
sustains and that sustains the community
and increases its competence.
That's the fundamental moral obligation
for belonging while an obviously so
right,
because why would you belong to a.
Why would you walk into a club House
that was on fire?
Like that's just not smart,
right?
If you're going to be part of the game,
if you've decided that being part of the
game is worthwhile,
you've also taken on the moral.
You've also decided even if you didn't
notice it,
that you have to work to support that
game because by deciding to play that
game,
you said that it's valuable and if it's
valuable,
then obviously you should work to
sustain and expand it because that's the
definition of having a relationship with
something that's valuable and so that's
the criteria for membership in the
community and that's partly why.
If you regard the cross,
say as the symbol of voluntary
suffering,
two suffering,
excepted voluntarily,
something like that,
which is means that there's another
element of that too that's worth
thinking about.
So you know,
the reason that cain gets so out of hand
is because he's suffering and he won't
accept it.
He certainly won't accept responsibility
for it.
He's angry and bitter about it and no
wonder,
right?
I mean we have to be realistic about
these sorts of things there.
Your guys,
all of you people are going to suffer at
some point in your life to the point
where you're angry and bitter about it.
I mean,
there's just absolutely no doubt about
that and you're even going to think,
well,
it's no bloody wonder that I'm angry and
bitter about it.
Everyone would be and things are so god
awful that there's no excuse for them to
even exist,
and that's a powerful argument.
Although I think it's ultimately self
defeating.
Well,
that's kind of what the story of Cain
and Abel,
and Abel.
What would you say?
That's the moral of the story of Cain
and Abel essentially.
So what that means instead is that even
under those conditions of relatively
intense suffering,
you have to accept it voluntarily
because otherwise it turns you against
being and then you start to act in this
terrible manner that makes everything
worse.
And it seems to me that there's a
contradiction in that if,
if the reason you're complaining is that
things are bad,
then it isn't reasonable for you to act
in a manner that makes them worse.
Right.
I mean,
even if it's no wonder that people do
that,
but it's degenerating game and so
that's,
so the idea,
part of the idea of the cross and the
suffering that it represents is that if
you could accept that voluntarily,
regardless of its intensity,
then you won't become embittered and
resentful and vengeful to the point
where you pose a danger to the stability
of the community.
So,
or to your own stability for that matter
because it's,
you know,
it might be your own stability,
the stability of your family,
the stability of the community and the
stability of the world.
It might be all of that.
And increasingly I think it is all of
that.
So.
Okay,
so now Jacob,
we get the second part of Jacob's story.
He goes to meet his uncle laband and he
meets Rachel there again by a well.
He falls in love and goes to live with
Lebanon.
There are two daughters there,
Leah,
as well as Rachel.
Leah is not a particularly attractive
person.
It isn't exactly clear why,
but the story makes it quite clear.
She's definitely the least desirable of
the two daughters and the story makes
reference to her eyes and it isn't clear
if there's something wrong with her
physiologically or if there's something
wrong with her attitude.
It's not obvious but doesn't really
matter.
The point is she's the older daughter
but she's the less desirable one.
Jacob stays a month,
which is the limit of hospitality in in
that time,
if you stayed for a month,
you were welcomed but you had to work
for your keep.
I think after about three days,
something like that,
which seems rather reasonable and so he
stays a month and then he has a chat
with Le and he says he's.
He's fallen in love with Rachel by this
time and he says,
I'll stay with you and work for seven
years.
And then all we had Rachel and Liban
says that's fine deal,
and then the seven years passes and
there's a wedding ceremony.
It's quite a long thing and the bride is
veiled and
the bride goes into the tent with,
with Jacob and if I remember the story
correctly,
I haven't looked at it for a month or
so.
Rachel is outside the tent speaking,
but Leah is inside the tent and so Jacob
thinks he's getting married to Rachel,
but he's actually getting married to
Leah and this is,
it's an inversion a because he's in the
dark like Isaac was when he fooled
Isaac,
so now it's jacobs turned to be in the
dark and he gets betrayed by his uncle
and his bride to be Rachel and her
sister in a manner that's broadly
parallel to the trick that he pulled on
Esol.
And so there's a Karma notion there
which I,
which I'd like,
you know,
I mean,
you might think of Karma as a
superstitious idea,
but.
And there are ways of interpreting it
that might make it the case,
but I don't think that's what it is.
It's no bad deed goes unpunished at
something like that.
You know,
maybe you've done something bad to
someone and therefore there's part of
you that feels quite guilty about that
hopefully,
and that part is looking for punishment
to set the stage.
Right,
and you might think,
well no,
but things are yes,
unless you're a psychopath.
That's how things work.
If you're interested in that kind of
thing,
you should read Dostoyevsky's crime and
punishment because it's the definitive
study of that sort of phenomena.
Right?
Because in that book,
the main protagonists risk,
all cough gets away with murder,
like he does it successfully.
No one suspects him and he drives
himself so crazy with guilt that he
basically falls into the hands of the
police.
He drives himself into the hands of the
police because he can't tolerate what he
did.
It's very,
it's amazing.
It's an amazing book.
But anyways,
the point is here Jacob falls prey to
the same sort of crookedness that he
used to ratchet himself up the ladder
and that happens far more often in life
than people think.
And it's really not like he can complain
about it right now.
If he has any sense.
It's like he does.
He brings Leah out to see Lebaron and he
says,
what's,
what's with this sister?
You know,
and Lebaron basically says to him in our
culture,
it's the custom to marry the eldest
daughter first,
which is exactly right.
And he said,
well,
it would bring,
you know,
he's rationalizing obviously because
he's just screwed over Jacob in a major
way,
but it's a little late to take it back.
The marriage has been consummated and
the ceremony has been complete and all
hell would break out if there was any
attempt to sever the relationships.
So that's how it is.
So Leah's married and Jacob has the
wrong wife.
So then,
so this is Jacob area,
you see on the left,
he's got the little flowery hat and he's
pointing to Leah and he's saying like,
what?
What's up here?
And loved the band.
The band is coupled goat and he's not
really all that sad about it.
In fact,
you can imagine that he's going to go
so,
so okay.
Then he asked to work another seven
years,
any gains Rachel,
but because God is a tricky character,
there was another twist in this story.
Rachel turns out not to be very good at
having children or Rachel and Jacob
turned out not to be very good in having
children,
but Leah,
she's really good at having kids,
so she provides Jacob with Reuben,
simeon,
Levi,
believe and Judah,
and the names of those meanings of those
names are there.
Reuben means see a son.
Simeon means hearing that.
I think that was the Lord heard my
prayer.
I think that's what that was a Levi
means joined.
Judah means praise to yeah,
Yahuah,
um,
and it's Judah from WHO's tried Christ
arises.
Judah is essentially promoted to the
status of first born.
Later in the story.
This is important because Ruben,
simeon and Levy all do something
reprehensible.
And so Judah gets,
gets promoted to firstborn.
And that's partly why in the logic of
the narrative that it's from the tribe
of Judah that Christ arises.
So,
so now while this is going on,
Rachel is like suicidally desperate for
children's.
She's jealous of her older sister who's
rather ill favored as we pointed out,
but who seems to be damn good at
producing sons and she's really not
happy with Jacob.
And so she chose him out and Jacob
basically says like,
what do you want me to do about it?
I'm not gone,
which is a reasonable response,
I would say.
And so in her desperation,
she gives Jacob Bella,
who's her maid servant.
We've seen that sort of thing happened
before.
And to bill up produces two children,
Dan and NAF telly.
I'm the reason I'm detaining out all
these sons.
It's important because Jacob is the
founder of Israel and his sons are the
founder of the 12 tribes.
So it's a pivotal moment in the story,
right?
It's because he's the,
he's the fundamental patriarch of,
of those who wrestle with God because as
we'll see,
that's what the name Israel means.
He gets the name Israel.
You'll see why in a while.
But,
but it's in the,
you need to know these genealogies in
this situation because they play an
important role in everything that
happens afterwards.
So Nafta,
Lee is the second,
uh,
and her name or his name means with
great wrestling's.
I've wrestled with my sister,
right,
contended with her,
and have prevailed.
So that gives you some indication of the
tension in the household.
Now Leah is now past bearing children.
She gives Jake Jacob,
her maid servant to Silpada to keep up
with her sister,
I guess.
And uh,
now Zilpah bears to children for Jacob.
So he's piling up the kids left right
and center here.
I'm one of them is named Gad,
good fortune and the other is named
Asher,
happy or blessed.
So there's more rivalry going on between
the sisters.
This is quite an interesting little
story.
So Ruben,
who's Leah's daughter,
goes out and looks for mandrakes.
Now mandrakes have aphrodisiac
properties,
so that's a little odd to begin with,
but it doesn't matter.
That's what happens.
And Rachel is Rachel wants the mandrakes
because she's still interested in having
some children.
And so she bargains with Leah to give
her a night with Jacob in exchange for
the mandrakes and sons emerge as a
consequence of that.
So.
And Rachel find the gifts.
Birth Joseph and Joseph plays a key role
in the last story in Genesis,
which I hope we'll get to in the next
lecture.
And then we can close off genesis.
That's the plan anyways,
so now Jacob isn't really very happy
about the whole arrangement because he.
He's been there 14 years and he's got
two wives.
It's not too bad,
but he,
you know,
he got he the bargain wasn't exactly
clean.
He doesn't really trust law,
Bannon,
and there's no reason for him to do so.
Lebanon was poor before Jacob came.
Jacob turns out to be a very useful
person to have around and so he tells
labounty he wants to leave and go back
to his home country and that he'll take
the speckled and spotted cattle,
the brown sheep and the spotted and
speckled goats from the flock,
and they're in the minority.
So that's the idea.
And so la ban or lab and takes all those
animals out of his flock.
So the.
There was an idea that the speckled
goats and the brown sheep would breed
true.
So if you have two male goat and a
female goat and they're both speckled,
they'll have speckled kits.
That's the theory.
And the same with brown sheep.
And so what [inaudible] does is he takes
all the speckled animals out of the
flocks,
gives them to his son,
and they go three days away with them so
that Jacob is left with the flock,
but with no,
with none of these animals.
Now the idea was that all the newborns,
we're going to be his.
And so what Liban is basically done is
set it up so that in principle I'm,
Jacob is going to get nothing for his
work.
So that's another time when Jacob
experiences betrayal,
you know,
it's almost as if God isn't done with
reminding him of the magnitude of what
he did in the past,
that that's the moral of the story in
some sense.
Now,
there's a weird little twist in the
story here.
So what Jacob does is some sympathetic
magic.
And so when the animals are rotting,
he puts speckled objects in front of
them,
speckled branches,
and so forth,
I guess to remind them about what
they're supposed to be producing,
something like that.
And it works.
And so all these animals that live band
left are,
are,
uh,
producing spotted animals like mad.
And so that's,
I guess God's changed his mind and let
Jacob off the hook slightly here.
So
Sooni was very wealthy,
much cattle maid servants,
men,
servants,
Campbell's analysis,
laband son,
sons become jealous.
And laband is outraged.
Well,
you know,
obviously there's some competition there
between Jacob and the sons,
which is hardly surprising.
And the band played this trick to strip
Jacob of all his property and instead he
got far more than he was going to get to
begin with.
So you can imagine that spit a bit
annoying.
So Jacob thinks he better get out of
there.
So we tell Rachel and Leah and said unto
them,
I see your father's countenance that
it's not toward me as before,
but the god of my father has been with
me and you know,
with all my power,
I've served your father and your father
is deceived me and changed my wages 10
times.
But God so far has suffered him not to
hurt me if he said,
thus the speckled shall be thy wages
than all the cattle bore speckled.
And if he said,
thus the ring straight shall be thy
higher than all the cattle board ring
straight,
thus God has taken away the cattle of
your father and given them to me and
they decided to sneak away and they're
unhappy with the inheritance.
That lack of inheritance from labatt.
So as they sneak away,
Rachel steals the idols that her father
has in his house and it's not exactly
obvious why.
There's a lot of contention about why
she's doing that.
Some of them is to punish him to bring
with her the images of her ancestors.
You know,
maybe she's loaned some moving away from
home just out of spite to show them that
the idols were actually powerless for
protection to stop her father from
dividing the root of their escape.
That last one is the strangest one
because the idea would be that the ban
would have used some sort of ritual with
the idols that would help them infer
their escape route and men could chase
them.
So anyways,
that's the range of speculation about
that.
I think.
It sounds to me mostly like a little act
of revenge maybe with a bit of
loneliness mixed in Lebaron pursues
them,
but God comes into dream to tell him to
leave Jacob unharmed.
Lavonne catches up with them and
reproaches Jacob saying that he would
have thrown a great party if he would
have known that they were going to
leave,
you know,
he didn't want them to sneak away in the
night and eat a can't tell from the
story whether that's true or not.
And you know,
these people were pretty rough and
impulsive I would say.
And maybe there was a 50 percent chance
of a slaughter and a 50 percent chance
of a party.
Who knows.
I've been to parties like that actually.
So laband complains that his gods are
gone and Jacob says that whoever has
them,
he will have them killed.
And Rachel who's really quite a sneaky
character,
all things consider basically claims
that she's having her period and she's
sitting on the carpet with all the idols
underneath and she can't move.
And so they search everywhere and can't
find them.
And she's like laughing away behind her
hand about that sneaky little maneuver,
but
she,
she doesn't die.
So that's probably a good thing.
So the laband,
she checks everything out,
checks the camp out,
and he can't find anything.
So they reconcile.
And so that's the first reconciliation
that Jacob engages in.
It's sort of like
the,
what would you say the Karmic debt has
been paid.
That's one way of thinking about it.
That's so he got punished for his
wrongdoing.
He's learned his lesson perhaps.
And it's,
it's,
that's good enough as far as he's
concerned,
you know,
he got away good enough and they make
peace.
So then the next thing that happens as
they're traveling is that Jacob was left
alone and there wrestled a man,
man,
Angel God.
It's not clear.
We'll go with angel with him until the
breaking of the day or God.
And when he saw that he prevailed not
against him.
He touched the hollow of his thigh in
the hollow of Jacob's thigh was out of
joint.
As he wrestled with him and he said,
let me go for the day breaks.
And Jacob said,
I will not let you go unless you bless
me.
And the Angel said unto him,
what is the name?
And Jacob said,
Jacob,
and the Angel said,
thy name shall no more be called Jacob
supplanter,
right?
The overthrow thrower with that kind of
intonation of or implication of
crookedness but Israel,
which means he who wrestles or strive
successfully with God for as a prince,
hast thou power with God and with men
and have prevailed.
That's quite a story.
Like I don't know exactly what to make
of it.
There's obviously a symbolic level of
meaning,
which is that that is what human beings
do in some senses they they wrestle.
I would say they wrestle with the divine
even with the concept of the divine for
that matter.
And
but the question is,
do they prevail?
Like it's of odd thing that Jacob
actually seems to win this battle,
right?
Or at least he wins it enough so that
whoever he's wrestling this divine
figure that he's wrestling is willing to
bestow a blessing on them.
I guess maybe that's a testament to his
courage.
It's something like that.
Maybe it's an indication that he has
paid for his sin sufficiently so that he
sort of back on the moral high ground,
but,
but I think it's really telling that the
transformation of the name from Jacob
Israel and what Israel means is he who
wrestles with God or who struggles with
God and perhaps successfully,
but it's also so interesting that
actually emerges victorious.
You wouldn't necessarily think that that
would be a possibility,
especially given you know,
God's rather hot headed nature in the
Old Testament.
You don't want to mess with him too
much,
but.
But Jacob does it successfully,
but even more importantly is the idea
that whatever Israel constitutes,
which would be the say,
the land that Jacob found is actually
composed of those who wrestle with God.
I think that's an amazing idea because
it also seems to me to shed some light
on perhaps what was meant by belief in
those days.
You know,
like I've often thought of rep of
marriage as a wrestling match,
right?
If you're lucky,
the person that you marry,
someone you contend with,
it's not exactly.
I don't think it's exactly.
It's not tranquil.
Precisely,
you know,
you might have noticed that some of you
and,
but,
but the thing is if you have something
to contend against,
then that strengthens you and that's
actually better than having nothing to
contend against.
And so Jacob is the person who's also
strengthened by the necessity of this
contending and that seems to be the
proper relationship with God or the
angel is that contending the battling,
right?
Rather than some sort of kind of loose,
weak statement of belief.
I mean,
I'm not trying to denigrate that to any
great degree.
It just doesn't seem like the right
motive conceptualization,
right?
Because human beings aren't,
aren't like that were were contentious
creatures and that's actually seems to
be something that meets with God's favor
in this situation.
So especially given that that's actually
what he names the while the whole
kingdom of the chosen people is the idea
is that that's composed of those who
contend with God.
So that's a hell of an idea that that's
for sure.
And Jacob ask
him and said,
tell me I pray thee thy name.
And he said,
we're force it though.
Dos Ask after by name.
So there's no that's not happening,
and he blessed him there and Jacob
called the place of the name of the
place.
Peniel for I or Peniel for I have seen
God face to face in my life is preserved
and passed over denial.
The Sun rose upon him and he halted upon
his thigh.
Now Jacob does walk away injured from
this right?
So he has a permanent limp after that.
And so that's also an indication of just
how dangerous that contention actually
is.
Like he gets blast,
he wins,
but he doesn't get away Scot free.
And so now.
So Jacob goes back to East Esau and he's
terrified even though it's been 14
years,
he thinks maybe his heart headed brother
hasn't calmed down yet and he has good
reason to think that I would say so.
He sends messengers,
Esau,
who then sets
out with 400 men and so Jacob is not
very happy with this whole idea and he
breaks his people into two bands so that
maybe half of them can not be killed.
And then he takes from his large flocks,
a bunch of animals and a bunch of
servants.
And He sends them out to me that you saw
basically to say,
look,
I'm,
I'm a jerk and sorry about the whole
birthright thing and,
and here's some animals and you know,
maybe maybe that's the beginnings of,
of an apology.
It's something like that.
And so,
but he's not very convinced that that's
actually going to work.
But Esau who actually turns out to
perhaps have matured in the interim,
perhaps that's one way of thinking about
it,
meets Jacob and says that just seeing
him is enough.
But Jacob insists that he takes the gift
and Esl accepts and which is probably a
wise thing because even if Esau is 95
percent convinced that just seeing his
brother is enough,
there's probably five percent of them
that's still really not all that happy.
And so you have to be careful,
you know,
when you say that you forgive someone
because there might be a part of you
that really doesn't,
that really needs something else before
you can actually say,
okay,
look,
fight.
You know,
and you don't want to fool yourself
about that because that five percent
that hasn't been completely convinced
will find its voice at some point and
then maybe undermine the whole
reconciliation process.
So you don't want to think that you're
any better than you are any nicer than
you are.
It's not helpful.
And so Esau is smart.
I think so while Jacob smart to say no,
no like thanks a lot,
but take the damn goats and Jacob and
Esau is smart enough to accept that and
he might do that maybe to you know,
to please Jacob.
But also I think so that there really is
the possibility of establishing peace
because hypothetically the gift that's
being offered is of sufficient magnitude
to erase the debt of the loss of the
birthright at something like that.
Right?
It's,
it's,
it's the payment of the real debt.
And Esau said,
what Mina style by all this drove which
I met and Jacob said,
these are to find grace in the sight of
my Lord,
and Esau says,
I have enough brother.
Keep Thou,
keep that,
that thou hast unto myself.
And Jacob said,
this is interesting statement,
I think,
no,
I pray you.
If if I have now found grace in thy
sight,
take the president at my hand for
therefore I have seen my face as though
I had seen the face of God and now it
was pleased with me and so that's so
he's.
He's taking the honorable judgment of
his brother because it is honorable
because Esau did get betrayed,
so he has a right to be standing in
judgment and he equates that judgment
with with what would you say,
with the highest virtues.
It's appropriate judgment and so he
wants to make complete amends to Esau as
if Esau as a representative of the
divine element of justice.
And
I guess that's convincing to Esl.
It's quite a thing to say,
you know,
that I need to be reconciled to you
because that would simultaneously
reconciled with God.
It's like it's crucial.
This is between us,
but it's.
There's a higher principle at stake
that's vital and I think that is the
case with betrayal.
That's very frequently the case because
if you betray someone,
you really have violated,
you've deeply violated.
What can only be called a sacred trust.
It's the right terminology for that.
Take it.
I pray the blessing that is brought to
the because God has dealt graciously
with me and because I have enough and he
urged him and he took it.
So you know,
the story seems to be something like,
well,
Jacob was kind of an arrogant,
crooked,
deceitful character,
maybe over impressed with his own
ability.
He thought it was pretty amusing to pull
a fast trick or two on his brother.
Then he ran off,
which is not all that brave.
And then he got wall up a lot and
perhaps learn something.
And then when he came back,
you know,
he was a different person.
And so that's,
that's a reasonable story.
And you know,
he,
he has to repent completely of
about what he did before he can rectify
the situation properly.
And he's willing to do that.
So that's an interesting idea too
because it's,
it's,
it's the early reflection of the idea
that it is,
if you do something wrong in the past,
a that you can learn from it,
right?
So that you're actually capable of
learning.
And B,
that you can set the balance right in
the present.
Those are very optimistic ideas,
you know,
because you might say,
well,
once you've committed some sort of
crime,
that's it.
There's no hope for you,
but that's pretty rough because the
probability that you've done unethical
things at some point in your life is a
hundred percent.
And so if there was no way of setting
the balance right after that,
then everybody would be.
And so,
so then the story gets rough again.
Jacob settles in.
Sholom sholom.
Diana has daughter goes looking around
for France,
Czech,
I'm the son of Hamor,
lays with her.
And then once her for his wife,
he actually has the order reversed
there.
That turns out to be a problem.
Jacob hears of this,
the fathers talk and so they make an
agreement.
The agreement is,
is that if all of hammers,
men including hammer and his son are
circumcised.
So that's the proper offering,
I guess that brings them into the
familial fold and indicates that they're
willing to make a sacrifice to do so.
Especially after you know,
check and put the cart before the horse.
Let's say the man of Hammer,
circumcised,
they agree to do so.
That turns out to be a big mistake,
so while they're laying around the next
day,
suffering Madley from the circumcision,
simeon and Levi come in and they sneak
in and kill all of them and take their
wealth and their women and children.
That's rough.
It's rough.
Yeah.
I guess you guys noticed that a so,
so their honor societies,
right?
There's still lots of honor societies in
the world and so they don't take kindly
to what happened to their,
to their sister,
although they don't kill her,
so now it turns out that,
yeah,
it says,
as it came to pass on the third day when
they were sore,
the two of the sons of Jacob,
simeon and Levi,
Diana's brother and took each man his
sword and came upon the city boldly and
slew all the males and they slew hammer
and check them.
His son with the edge of the sword and
took dine out of Shechem's house and
went out.
The sons of Jacob came upon the slain
and spoiled the city because they had
defiled their sister.
It took the sheep and the oxen and the
assets and that which was in the city
and that was which was in the field and
all their wealth and all their little
ones and their wives took vacate,
captive and spoiled everything else that
was in the House and Jacob actually
turns out not to be very happy about
that because he'd met with hammer and
they hammered out a deal and that and
that's where they were living and so he
figured,
well that he was making the best of a
bad lot,
let's say,
and his sons went behind his back and
Jacob says to Simeon and Levi,
you have troubled me to make me,
to make me stink among the inhabitants
of the land,
among the Canaanites and the parasites
and I being few in number.
They shall gather themselves now
together against me and slay me and I
shall be destroyed.
I had my house and they said,
should he deal with our sister as with a
harlot?
And God said Unto Jacob,
and this is where we get back to the
idea of the center.
God says to Jacob,
arise,
go to Bethel.
And dwell there.
So Bethel was where Jacob had originally
put that pillar.
So now it's back.
So it's.
It's,
it's a real hero's journey,
right?
There's,
there's the place that he has a set
place.
He goes out and has these adventures and
and undergoes a moral transformation
reconciles and then he comes back to the
same place,
right as a transformed person that's a
full hero's cycle.
Arise,
go to Bethel and dwell there and make an
hour there.
An Altar unto God that appeared to the
Windale fled is from the face of Esau.
Die Brother and Jacob said to his
household and to all that were with
them,
put away the strange gods that are among
you and be clean and change your
garments and let us arise and go up to
Bethel and I will make an altar unto God
who answered me in the day of my
distress and was with me in the way
which I went and they gave unto Jacob
all the strange gods which were in their
hand and all their earrings which were
in their ears.
And Jacob had them under the oak,
which was by a checkup.
And they journeyed and the terror of God
was upon the cities that were round
roundabout them,
and they did not pursue after the sons
of Jacob.
So Jacob came to laws which is in the
land of Canaan that is Bethel.
So that's the place where he put up the
pillar to begin with.
He and all the people that were there
with him and he built there an altar and
called the place l Bethel because their
God appeared to him when he fled from
the face of his brother and God appeared
to Jacob again when he came out of pet
dander,
Ram and blessed him and God sent unto
him [inaudible].
My name is Jacob.
Thy name shall not be called anymore.
Jacob,
which he remembered means usurper,
but Israel shall be thy name.
He who wrestles with God
had he called his name Israel.
And God said to him,
I am God Almighty.
Be fruitful and multiply a nation and a
company of Nations shall be of the Kings
shall come out of my loins.
And the land which I gave Abraham and
Isaac to the I will give it and device
seed after the will I give the land.
And God went up from him in the place
where he talked with them.
And God says,
Jacob setup a pillar in the place where
he talked with them a pillar of stone
and he poured a drink offering their on
any poured oil they're on.
And Jacob called the name of the place
where God spake with him Bethel.
So He's,
he's returned to the central place which
had been given to him as his territory.
Rachel dies in Labor in the process,
giving birth to an only son of my
sorrow,
whose name was then changed to Benjamin
son of the right hand.
Now Ruben.
So Simeon and Levi have already done
something unforgivable.
Now,
Ruben Reuben's term,
he sleeps with Bill [inaudible],
who's Jacob Israel's concubine.
So he's the third of the sons to make an
unforgivable error.
And Jacob Slash Israel gets wind of it.
So Robin is no longer.
He would have been the premier son given
that the two older sons were put out of
the running.
So to speak,
because of their disobedience and
impulsive,
vengeful cruelty,
and then rubin can't keep his.
What do they say?
Well,
you get the idea.
Yeah.
Seems to be something that's still quite
surprisingly common.
So then we have the story that basically
ends with the establishment of the 12
tribes of Israel.
From Leah.
There's Reuben,
simeon,
Levi,
Judah is a car and Zebulon from zillow
powders,
Gad Asher from Bella.
There's Dan and Naphtali and from
Rachel.
There's Joseph who figures
extraordinarily importantly in the next
story that we're going to cover,
which hopefully we'll wrap up genesis
and Benjamin,
and so now Israel itself is established
and so then we turn to actually going to
end this early tonight.
That's quite bloody miracle.
So this story then turns to Joseph and
the story begins essentially now Israel
loved Joseph more than all his children
because he was the son of his old age
and he made him a coat of many colors
and so that seems to me to indicate no
coats in dreams very often seems to be
particularly true of women's dreams.
That's,
that's been my,
my clinical observation.
Clothing footwear in particular
symbolizes a role and that makes sense,
right?
Because you dress for the role.
It's not that big a mystery,
but so then you might say,
well,
what does a coat of many colors indicate
and know if you think of that
multiplicity there,
it's something like the mastery of
multiple domains,
right?
Or or maybe something like plural
potentiality and so Jacob is is Israel's
are Joseph is Israel's favorite and
because he sees in this access
possibility and he basically tells his
other sons that Jacob is going to be the
head son,
which they are not happy with,
right?
Because he's just this young punk
fundamentally these clearly his father's
favorite and he gets this coat that's
sort of indicative of this higher status
and so Israel inadvertently sets up a
tremendous amount of sibling rivalry in
the household again,
and that
that's the,
the understructure of the last story in
genesis.
And so in the last of this lecture
series for 2017,
we'll cover the story of Joseph and his
coat of many colors and what happens as
a consequence of his,
of the favoritism shown to him by his
father,
and we'll track what happens as a
consequence of that.
And so I'm going to stop there because
I'm finished.
So
thank you.
Hello,
Dr Pearson.
Um,
this is an idea I've been wrestling with
for quite some time now.
Um,
this idea of a lot of the greatest
sources of wisdom that we've received
throughout human history,
either through text experiences or
scriptures,
seems to always come from people going
into isolation and then coming back.
So I've had a hard time trying to figure
out from a scientific point of view or
evolutionary point of view,
what would it compel an organism to that
is that is centered around it's
behavior.
It's behavior centered around surviving
in,
especially for humans as social groups,
as well as reproducing to want to go
into isolation.
And then not only that,
but obtaining some level of information
that actually helps the group in coming
back.
That's a really good question.
Um,
okay.
So there's this neuroscientist
neuropsychologist named El Conan
Goldberg,
and Goldberg was a student of Alexander
Luria and Alexander Luria was a Russian
neuropsychologist,
perhaps the foremost neuropsychologist
of the mid to late 20th century,
and he had students soaked in vinegar
Dova who discovered the orienting
reflex.
For example,
the orienting reflex is the,
reflects that orients you win something
anomalous,
interferes with your goal.
Directed behavior is a major discovery,
like one of the,
one of the four or five most important
discoveries that have ever been made in,
in,
in psychology,
I would say certainly in neuroscience.
So lauria was a big deal and he,
he was the first person who really
established the functional role of the
prefrontal Cortex as well.
So,
and had it very nice overall view of how
the brain functioned.
His book was written in 1980 and it's
still,
there's still lots in it that's really
useful,
which is pretty strange for a science
that's advanced that quickly.
Anyways,
so Goldberg came from a great pedigree,
I believe Larry,
his teacher was Pavlov,
if I remember correctly.
So anyways,
Goldberg,
you know,
you hear some of you may have heard the
idea that the left hemisphere is more
linguistic than the right hemisphere is
that left hemisphere is specialized for
language and the right hemisphere
specialized for nonverbal imagistic
communication.
The left hemisphere has a pretty well
organized microstructure and the right
hemisphere is more diffuse as well,
and that's true in lefthanded males in
particular,
so the circuitry can be switched around
a bit,
but it's okay.
The modules are basically the same,
although they can be moved a little bit,
but Goldberg thought that it isn't
language versus non language,
it's routine versus novelty.
And so the left hemisphere and there's a
neuropsychologist physician named Rama
Shaundra who's done some very
interesting work that's pertinent to
this.
Maybe I'll tell you a story about him.
Anyways.
Goldberg believed that the right
hemisphere say you have very old systems
underneath boast both cortical
hemispheres that do things like respond
to anomaly to the thing that doesn't fit
to the Predator in the distance.
Some of that's extraordinarily fast,
so that would be like a snake reflects
that can move you away from a snake in
less time than it takes the snake to
bite,
and it's really a reflex.
It doesn't even hit your brain.
It's really super fast.
And then there's a defensive crouch
that's,
that's instantiated higher up in the
nervous system,
but that's still remarkably fast.
And then there's fear as an emotion and
and the orientation of attention.
And then there's the cognitive
processing and that all streams out
across a time span,
right?
And maybe that time span is half a
second.
So,
and that's really a long time if
something is attacking you.
So you got those initial responses are
quite primitive,
but they're extraordinarily fast.
All right?
So there's subcortical structures that
orient you towards novelty and prepare
you for,
for freezing or for attending.
And the right hemisphere seems to be
dominated by those systems.
So imagine that.
What happens is that something threatens
you.
You Orient towards it.
The right hemisphere produces a bunch of
images about what it might be.
So imagine that's what happens when a
child is afraid of the dark,
the child's on the bed,
they're afraid of the dark,
they're crouched because they're frozen
like a prey animal.
And their right hemisphere is producing
monsters to inhabit the,
the darkness that are the child's
hypotheses about what might be out
there.
Okay?
Because that's what you want to know,
right?
You want to know what's out there and
then you want to know what to do about
it.
I can tell you two kids' dreams that are
sort of relevant to that.
So when my daughter was about three,
she came into the bedroom that my wife
and I had and she was crying,
she'd had a nightmare and she said that
she saw stream and there was garbage all
over the street and she didn't like
that.
And so I sat her down and I said,
okay,
so imagine the stream with the garbage
in it.
Now imagine that you're taking the
garbage out and throwing it in the
garbage bin.
And so she and I got her to like
visualize that because that kind of puts
her back in the semi dream state.
And then she cleaned up the mess and
then she could go off to sleep.
Now you could tell the child,
don't worry about the dream isn't
real.
That's not true because it's not real
like other day time things are,
but it's not like it's not real.
It's a dream like a dream is real.
It's just not the same kind of real.
And so what I did with her was to
indicate to her practically that if she
saw something anomalous,
something that was out of place,
right?
Something that was a mess,
that it was within her capacity to set
it right.
Okay.
And so,
okay,
so now your right hemisphere tells you
what monster's might inhabit the,
the darkness.
Now what you have to do is figure out.
There's two things you have to figure
out.
One is what to do about a given monster.
And the other is to do.
What about is to figure out what to do
about the class of all possible
monsters,
right?
That's a whole different thing.
That's something that only human beings
are capable of that level of
abstraction,
right?
And so what you might do about a
particular monster is hide or go out and
get rid of it if it was just an actual
animal,
right?
But that doesn't help because there's
all the other potential predators that
are still there.
And so maybe you can go hunt them down,
but that doesn't help either because you
can't hunt them all down.
It's not our,
it's not very likely anyways.
So instead what you have to do is figure
out how to configure yourself so that
you're in the best possible position to
fight off the monsters when they come.
That's your best bet.
All right,
so now people are trying to figure this
out forever.
They're trying to figure out what's the
answer to the problem of the class of
all possible monsters.
Part of that sacrifice.
So there are routines.
For example,
in Hinduism with the goddess Kelly,
you make offerings to Kelly,
who's this devouring goddess,
and then she turns into her benevolent
counterpart.
And so sacrifice is actually one way
that you can tame the monsters.
If you think about the monster has the
set of all negative future
potentialities,
you make the proper sacrifices.
Those monsters stay at bay,
but then there's heroism as an
alternative to which,
which means the act of confrontation of
the class,
of all possible monsters and the
building of yourself up into this sort
of courageous person that can do that.
It took a tremendous amount of
meditation to transform those images,
say of the monsters in,
into it,
or to solve the problem of the class of
those monsters.
So,
so now I'll tell you another child
street.
So some of you have probably heard this
before,
but it's such a great dream that it's
worth.
It's worth telling.
So you know,
is that my sister in law's house once
and her son was running around is about
four very precocious,
very verbal,
very intelligent,
running around with a night hat on and
his sword.
So he's engaged in this pretty intense
play world.
And when he goes to sleep,
he puts the night hat on his pillow and
the sword bias pillow.
And at the same time he's having night
terrors.
So he's waking up and it had been for a
number of weeks,
nate waking up,
screaming and then,
but he doesn't know why.
There's some things that aren't going so
well in the household and the parents
get divorced shortly afterwards.
Okay.
So that's,
that's,
that's what's going on underneath.
Right.
And he's also going to go to
kindergarten and so he's about to go
into the world and so he's coping with
this,
you know.
So I'm watching them zoom around as this
night and thinking that's pretty cool.
And that night he woke up and had a.
everyone was screaming and so we're all
at breakfast the next morning and I
said,
did you dream anything?
And he got really intense.
And he said,
yes,
I had a dream.
And I said,
well,
what was the dream?
And he said,
well,
I was out on this field and all these
like dwarfs came up to me.
They're only about as high as my knees
and they didn't have any arms.
They have powerful legs.
And they were covered with Harry
feathers in Greece and there was cross
carved into the top of their head.
And they had beaks and whenever he moved
anywhere they would jump out and with
his,
with their beaks.
And there were lots of them and everyone
like just said nothing at breakfast.
It was like,
because he was right into this story.
And so we're all like,
yeah,
well that accounts for all the screaming
and so.
And then he said,
yeah.
And then in the background there was a
dragon and every time the dragon puffed
out smoke,
it would turn into these dwarves.
It's like,
Oh man,
kid,
you already got a problem there.
You got,
you got beat things that are biting you
and you can kill them.
And that's fine.
But then there's the dragon just puffing
out new ones.
So it's like a Hydra problem,
right?
The old hydro is the serpent.
You cut off one head,
seven more grow.
It's not a good thing.
And it's such a cool dream because it
really portrayed this class of all
possible monsters problem.
So you've got the specific monsters and
that's a problem.
So you've got to get rid of them.
But that's not the problem.
The problem is is that there's a,
there's something in the background
that's just generating monsters like
Matt.
And so I said to him,
what do you think you could do about
that?
And that's a,
that's a loaded question,
right?
That's like leading the witness in a
trial.
You don't get to ask a question like
that because it implies that it implies
the answer.
What could you do about that is not any
different than saying you could do
something about that.
Right.
So,
so I,
I hinted at that as a possibility and
his eyes lit up.
Now you remember he's already running
around as at night.
Hey.
So we kind of already knew what to do
because he had the whole sword in the
hat and with that,
you know that you can go after the
dragon.
He kinda got that and he said I'd get my
dad and then I jump up on top of the
dragon and I poke out both of its eyes
with my sword and then it go right down
its throat to the firebox where the fire
comes out and I carve out a piece of the
firebox.
And then I'd use that as a shield and I
thought yes,
right,
right.
Man is so smart.
Hey,
because he got the thing instantly he
knew that he knew.
So imagine first of all,
he thought,
okay,
I have to go to the heart of the
problem.
Right?
And really to the heart,
not to the dragon,
but right down the damn things gullet
right to the place where the fire was
actually being was actually being
created because there was there you
could find the shield and that he'd take
this thing that was fireproof and make a
shield out of it.
And so that was just get bloody perfect.
It was so cool.
And you think,
well how could a kid come up with that?
And there's a bunch of answers.
I mean,
one is we know snake fear is innate.
We knew that now there's been recent
research data that,
that,
that has demonstrated that okay,
so.
And we've been preyed on and being
predators for a very long period of
time.
So the idea that,
and I found something else interesting
about the brain out out about the brain
recently too,
in Book I was reading by Ray Kurtzweil
called how to build a mind.
I think that's what it was called.
It was quite a good book.
So I think it was in that book or it was
in the neuroscience paper I was reading.
It doesn't matter,
but it was one of those two places.
So you know that scanning technology has
got more and more high resolution over
the last few years.
Right.
It just gets more and more high
resolution all the time and so people
are now able to look at the micro
structures of the brain in a way that
hasn't been possible before.
And so the old idea with the cortex
basically was the cortex was full of a
bunch of neurons and then when one
neuron and another fired at the same
time,
they would wire together and that's kind
of how your brain learns to make
connections.
It's a bit more complicated than that,
but that will do.
And then it was found that it wasn't
quite that simple because what your
cortex is made out of are these columns
of neurons that are duplicated,
sorta like a,
like a centipedes legs,
you know,
it's very simple genetic code data,
another leg set of legs to ascend to
pete is sort of like that with your
brain.
It's made out of all these columns and
the columns are basically already quite
wired up.
And then as you learn the columns wired
together.
Okay,
so there's some preexisting structure
there,
but there's more preexistent structure.
Then that was thought.
So it's,
it's basically that there are already
tracked that link columns together that
are in different parts of the brain and
the columns,
the columns themselves can send out
invites to these highways which are
already there.
And then the super highway is there and
then it can generate connections to the
columns at the end of the super highway.
So what that means is that there's a
tremendous amount of cortical structure
already in place,
but there's plasticity around that.
And when I read that,
I thought,
well that's part of the source of the
archetypes.
There's already an archetypal structure
there that as well as the subcortical
structures,
so you could say that like the kid
already had within him,
not only the capacity to represent not
only the monster,
but the class of all possible monsters
and the fact that the problem wasn't
monsters.
The problem was that monsters could
continually be generated,
which is way worse problem,
and then the answer to that isn't to
kill an individual monster.
The answer to that is go to the source
of the monstrous itself and defeat it.
So it's absolutely staggering and you
could imagine that it would take a
tremendous amount of meditative effort
for people to have come up with that
solution over a very long period of
time.
So now the point of the representation
is to formulate a picture of what it is
that's the threat so that you can then
formulate a general purpose solution.
And so there's this image of Kelly which
I really like because Kelly is sort of
the goddess of the darkness,
let's say,
and destruction.
And so Kelly is.
She has a headdress of fire,
her hair is on fire and she has a
headdress of skulls and she has hands
cut off all around her neck and she has
a belt that's often snakes,
but it's sometimes she sometimes eating
the intestines of this guy that she's
just given birth to and that she's
sitting on and she has eight legs like a
spider and she's in a web of fire and so
she's a monster in some sense that
represents everything that might terrify
and devour you.
And the question is,
so you come up with that representation,
has an image to represent the class of
all terrifying things and then you have
to generate a solution in the face of
that class.
And sacrifice is one of the solutions.
But that heroic encounter is another one
of the solutions.
And that's the one that he catalyzed.
Now.
He'd been read lots of books.
He'd watched lots of Disney movies,
you know,
and he'd seen the heroic pattern
portrayed many,
many places and his little brain was
working like mad to extract out the
essence of that and who embody it.
And when I asked them that question,
it just went snap and all those things
lined up and his night terrors went
away.
That was it.
And I followed up with his mum because
it was really quite remarkable,
the whole set of occurrences,
you know,
and he didn't have night terrors that
night even though he'd been having the
nightly and that was the end of them
because he solved his problem.
Like he needed to be the courageous
night that went after the dragon.
And so that is what people need to be.
So I think when we go into solitude,
we shut off the external stimulation and
we let the dreaming part of our mind
emerge.
And that's this nonverbal pattern
detector that thinks in images.
And it's,
it's the thing that mediates between
what we don't understand and what we do
understand.
If you understand it completely,
you can say it and you can act it out if
you don't understand it.
You represented in images and they're
like,
it's the emotion.
Fear,
withdrawal,
paralysis.
And then that manifests itself in an
image of what that might be.
And that image is the basis for the
story and it's the basis for further
development of the idea and to go into
isolation is to let those images emerge
and to dream a little bit,
and then that moves you,
that moves you ahead into the future.
So to use your
which they used before,
it's not enough just to map out the
danger that is imminent in front of you,
but all the potential dangers that you
could come up with an abstract form.
Yeah,
well remember what happens when God
throws Adam and Eve out of out of
paradise,
they become aware that they're going to
die,
right?
The future becomes a problem because you
could say the future is the place of all
potential monsters.
Right?
And so just the monster that you have
right in front of you.
It's like,
yeah,
well you get rid of that,
but that doesn't solve your problem,
does it?
The problem is how do you exist in a
world full of monsters?
And part of that answer is why you
become a monster yourself.
That's a big part of the answer,
but it's an incomplete answer because if
you're just a monster then you're just
as bad as the monsters,
so you have to transfer,
you have to be a monstrous enough to
contend with the monsters,
but then you have to be civilized enough
so that you're not a monster yourself
and that's more or less equivalent to
the union inter integration of the
shadow.
So.
Yep.
Thank you.
Hi,
Dr Peterson.
I've been wanting to ask you this for
awhile now since I started watching your
lectures.
After I started reading and Nietzsche's
beyond good and evil,
I came upon a paragraph in his chapter
on scholars that really,
really bothered me and it's actually
bothers me to this day.
Uh,
he,
he talked about this kind of person,
like they were just a mirror,
like they stretched,
he said every part of their skin
basically to allow every new piece of
information that they took on.
And then all they ever were was just an
instrument.
They were just a mirror on reflecting
what they had learned.
Never actually having generated anything
on their own.
And it's bothered me because I feel like
in a way it sort of like,
it's,
it's impacted my identity a lot because
I don't know,
how are you supposed to create
something,
you know?
So.
Okay,
well that's okay that,
that's a really good.
I mean,
nature is often clashed with the
existentialists right?
And so one of the tenants of
existential,
it's,
there's two real tenants of
existentialism.
There's more,
but obviously we're oversimplifying,
but one is that life is a problem.
It isn't because there's something wrong
with you,
it's that life is a problem.
And so that's often contrasted with the
Friday and view,
which is that if you have a problem,
it's because something went wrong during
your development.
The existentialist said,
no,
no.
It's like life is a problem.
Make no mistake about it.
And that
the purpose of the purpose of
scholarship is in some sense to solve
that problem.
And so for Nisha,
like he said,
all truths are bloody truth to me.
And what he meant by that was that if an
idea didn't incarnate itself in you and
transform your perceptions and your
actions,
then you were merely possessed by the
idea.
You're merely a spokesperson for the
Or You could say that the idea possessed
you.
You're a puppet for the idea.
It's not you,
it's the idea is in you and it has you.
You haven't taken the idea and
incorporated with you and made it part
of your life.
And so there's a romanticism that's
associated with that,
right?
That's the passionate scholar.
The person for whom ideas are not
merely,
they're not merely,
what would you call abstracted
representations that can be tossed about
as if they're commodities.
They're,
they're,
they're more like,
they're more like personalities.
That might be another way of thinking
about it.
And so if you're,
if,
if those ideas are compelling,
then you don't like.
One thing I learned along time ago,
and I think this is probably relevant.
I know when I was a kid,
I liked to argue and I like to win
arguments or,
or,
or lose them.
Although I liked winning them a lot
better.
But I didn't really mind so much what
the content of the argument was,
you know,
I,
I could engage in it like a sparring
match and it was in some sense to
establish dominance,
right?
To establish intellectual dominance.
I quit doing that when I was in my mid
twenties because I thought that that was
too shallow and approach to the ideas.
They're not commodities of that sort.
They're there,
they have tendrils that reached down
into the living.
That's the right way to think about it.
And so niches,
criticism of scholars.
And he did this a lot,
was that they were bloodless,
you know,
they didn't,
they were full of performative
contradictions.
That's another way of thinking about,
they'd say one thing and do another
because their intellect was completely
dissociated from their,
from their actions.
And he,
he,
he thought that was a very bad idea.
And I think that that's a good
criticism.
I think it is a bad idea.
I also think it makes for an
extraordinarily boring lecturer,
you know,
because you can tell if you're listening
to someone,
whether the ideas that you're hearing
are merely being passed through the
person as if they're being memorized,
say,
or whether they're part of the dynamic
core of the person and if they're part
of the dynamic core of the person,
then they're almost always engaging in
gripping and so he wasn't a fan of
bloodless scholars and I think that's
correct because one of the things that I
see,
it's not a good idea to have ideas
possess you unless you know what the
ideas are up to and lots of people are
possessed by ideas rather than
possessing them.
Not.
What that means is they haven't taken
the ideas and integrated them into their
own being.
They haven't.
It's like an incarnation in a sense.
They have an incarnated the ideas in
embodied form and so they're incomplete.
You know,
nature also in thus spake Zarathustra.
When zero booster comes down the
mountain,
he sees a bunch of people gathered
around a famous individual.
I think maybe a scholar but doesn't
really matter and when zero theaster
goes and looks at the person,
only sees his little tiny midget with a
gigantic ear and so he's a hyper
specialist.
Right.
And so he has a pretty impressive ear,
but he's only this big and that was
niches,
images,
stick commentary on the danger of hyper
specialization and also on the danger of
adulation for hyper specialization and
because he thought about it as a kind of
deformity now nature was a pretty harsh
guy,
but,
but he did address the issue of the
relationship between intellectual
knowledge and an action because for
nature those things are not to be
separated in some sense.
So yeah.
So maybe,
I don't know why.
Maybe it bothered you.
Like it's hard to say why it bothered
you.
It might have bothered you because it's
sort of undermine the idea of scholar.
But the other possibility,
and this isn't an accusation because
obviously I don't know anything about
you,
but it might also be that it struck a
chord,
you know,
and that maybe you were doubtful or
questioning how tightly associated your
intellectual endeavor was with your
actual character and your practice.
So that's another possibility.
I mean,
that's a really good thing to think
about because generally speaking,
that integration is very much lacking.
People are a lot smarter and fluid with
their ideas that they are ethical and
consistent and characterized by
integrity.
So,
hey,
um,
so last week you talked about how you
hated people asking you if you believe
in God or do you believe miracles are
you disliked those questions,
leds,
but you also talked about how,
and I want to put words in your mouth,
but I think he said something about the
idea of an empirical evidence for
religious experiences or spiritual
experiences.
And I wonder how those two ideas can a
spiritual existence or can a spiritual
experience exists without God or how did
I,
I had trouble reading.
Who knows?
You know,
I don't know what.
I don't know what to make of that.
I mean you could.
It depends on what you're willing to
accept as proof.
I suppose that's where things get
tricky,
you know,
if you have to demonstrate the existence
of God objectively than subjective
experiences of the transcendent are
irrelevant.
Right?
But,
and that's a perfectly reasonable
standpoint.
If your initial presupposition is the
only thing that has actual existence is
those things that can be demonstrated
objectively and I'm not putting that
down,
like that's a powerful methodology.
Our technology is basically dependent on
the acceptance,
at least a partial acceptance of those
axioms,
but I also think that it's difficult for
me to deny the existence of these
patterns of thinking that seemed to
exist cross culturally,
like the existence of the representation
of the Dragon,
for example.
Especially given that I can see an
evolutionary rationale for the emergence
of these representations.
So and then there's also the
indisputable fact that religious
experiences are accessible to people
through a number of different avenues.
Now and one of the things I mentioned
when I discussed this before as well,
you could say,
well those are no different than
experiences of psychopathology,
but they are different because the
experiences of psychopathology damage
people.
Whereas the evidence is that the
transcendent experiences actually help
people.
So unless you can,
unless you're willing to say,
well,
there are some forms of
psychopathological experience that
actually facilitate health,
which is a possibility,
but you know,
I think you're.
You're pushing your hypo yearly
hypothesis.
At that point.
Would it hurt to define what a religious
experience is in this case?
Then?
Because I feel like the semantics,
like I.
I'm not sure if what you're saying about
a religious experience is what I'm
understanding.
Well,
generally a religious experiences,
something like an experience of the,
of the renewal of the world.
That might be one way of thinking about
it so that everything sort of leaps
forward as crystal clean and perfect as
if you had been viewing it from behind a
mask before.
Another would be a sense of the Union of
everything.
And so you're a singular being and
you're isolated and in religious
experiences.
So for example,
there's a book written recently by a
neuroscientist,
my stroke of,
what's it called?
My stroke of insight.
Yeah,
that's right.
And I believe she had a left hemisphere
stroke,
if I remember correctly,
and she was sufficiently well developed
neuroscientists to understand what was
happening as she had the stroke and,
and she had intense religious experience
as a consequence of that and she
experienced it as a dissolution of the
ego into this state of union with
everything and this transcendent
experience of law and,
and the open.
Well,
I don't remember the rest of it.
I mean there are other elements of
religious experience that are quite
common.
The idea of the opening of the heavens,
that's one.
The communion with the ancestors,
that's another,
the reduction of the body to a skeleton,
the movement up into heaven there.
These are well documented phenomena and
lot of them are associated,
well a fair number of them are
associated with psychedelic use,
but that's not the only avenue to
experiences like that.
And epilepsy can produce experiences
like that too.
And people usually report near death
experiences.
Well,
you know,
people usually report that those
experiences have life altering
significance.
Now,
that in and of itself only proves that
people are capable of having subjective
religious experiences,
right?
It doesn't definitively prove that
there's anything outside of that.
So Young Carl Young,
for example,
most of the time he didn't talk about
God,
he talked about the God image,
which is not the same thing because you
could have a god image that was even
evolutionarily instantiated without that
necessarily being related to any
transcendent being beyond the image.
Right?
So who knows,
who knows?
Um,
again,
I think it depends on what you're
willing to accept as proof.
Now the proof,
the is beyond question that people can
have life changing religious
experiences.
Another example of that is that the best
treatment for alcoholism is religious
conversion.
It's well documented in the literature,
and I studied alcoholism for a long
time.
So one of the cures that sticks is
religious conversion and the 12 step
programs essentially attempt to
instantiate religious conversion and
it's hard to document their success
because they succeed for the people who
stick with it.
But that's not a very good measure,
right?
It's sort of,
it's sort of self evident that they work
for the people who stick with it.
I'm not cynical about about alcoholics
anonymous or anything,
but we don't have good data on,
on outcome,
but there is good data showing that
religious transformation is a good cure
for alcoholism.
So.
And that's an interesting phenomena to
um,
it's too complicated.
I probably can't.
Okay,
I'll try.
I'll try this for a second.
So here's how I think religious
conversion might work.
So imagine you've got the left
hemisphere and it's the place where your
habitual interpretations reside.
So I can give you a quick example of
this.
So this Guy Ramachandran who,
who's a neurophysiologist,
I think that's his,
that's his field of study.
I think he's at Ucla.
He studied people who had neglect.
Neglect is a very,
very bizarre phenomena.
So if you have a stroke that damages
your right parietal lobe,
you'll lose the left part of your being,
not just your body.
It's really weird.
It's like.
So for example,
if you have a right parietal stroke and
you look at a clock,
you only see you only,
only half the clock exists for you.
It's not like you only see half the
clock.
It's weirder than that.
It's that there's only the right side of
the clock.
There's only the right side of you.
There's only the right side of my body.
I don't know that this exists.
And so sometimes people with right
parietal damage will wake up after the
stroke and grabbed their left arm and
throw it out of bed and or their leg and
throw it out of bed because it's not
theirs.
And then of course they fall out of bed,
which is quite a shock to them.
So and so they'll only eat half the food
on the plate.
Nobody can really understand this for
Norman logically,
right?
Because we can't imagine what that must
be like.
I think it must be like,
you know how you know there's things
behind you,
but you don't not see them.
They're just not there.
It's not like it's black or anything or
there's a space,
it's just not there.
And so I think what happens is the not
there extends to three quarters of the
field instead of half the field.
That's a guess.
Anyway.
So now the funny thing about people with
neglect is that if you tell them,
if you pointed out,
you say,
well,
I noticed that you're not moving your
left foot today.
They'll say,
well it's,
it's arthritic and I can't move it and
say,
well what are you?
Just try to move it.
So No,
look,
Dr already told you it's in too much
pain to move.
It was working fine this morning.
Now it can be months after the the
accident.
So it's a denial.
And people thought actually that that
was trauma induced denial for a long
time before they figured it out was
actually a consequence of the
neurophysiological damage.
Now Ramachandra and found that if you
irrigated the contralateral ear,
say now if you pour cold water in
someone's ear,
it upsets their vestibular system and
their eyes will move back and forth like
this.
You can try that at a party if you want.
And anyways,
Ramachandra was testing vestibular
function on these patients and the
irrigated the right ear with cold water
and they woke up.
Maybe what happened was that that was
shocking.
So imagine the networks in the right
hemisphere were degraded but not
completely gone,
and they needed a really high threshold
of activation to snap into function.
So here's an example of that.
If you have Parkinson's disease,
imagine you're frozen there,
okay?
And I throw a ball at you.
You'll go like this and catch it,
but you can't throw it back so you can.
The stimulus is enough.
That's enough to push you past
threshold,
but you can't do it voluntarily.
Now if you have Parkinson's,
like right to the nth degree,
you won't even be able to catch it.
But there's a stage where you could
still do that.
There's a great case study where this
grandpa was in a wheelchair,
he had Parkinson's and his young
grandson was playing out on the dock and
fell in the water and started to drown
and he got out of his wheelchair,
went into the ocean,
rescued him,
brought him onto the beach,
sat back down in his wheelchair and was
paralyzed again.
So that was enough.
So you can imagine there was enough
network left.
So if the emotional tension became high
enough that the degraded circuits could
still function.
So okay,
so back to Ramachandran.
So you irrigate the year.
All of a sudden the right hemisphere
connections flashed,
the remainders managed to connect and
the person goes,
oh my God,
I've had a terrible stroke.
I've lost the left side of my body.
They're crying.
They're like completely catastrophic,
really overwhelmed by it.
And then 20 minutes later the day
effects wear off and they snap back in
and now they,
they've lost her left side again.
They don't remember it.
And so what seems to happen is that the
right hemisphere is collecting anomalous
information.
That's what it does.
That's what it does when you're
dreaming.
It's,
it's,
it's representing that anomalous
information in image form and sort of
slowly passing it to the left hemisphere
so it doesn't overwhelm it and maybe if
it gets overwhelming,
you wake up and you're afraid and you
tell someone about the dream that helps
you figure out what it was,
but anyways,
so that the right hemisphere is always
trying to tap the left hemisphere into
transformation.
Right?
So now imagine that that can happen a
little bit or a lot,
so maybe you're just ignoring a little
bit of anomalous information.
You just have some mildly frightening
dreams or maybe you've just stacked up a
whole bunch of things that you're
ignoring and there's some major league
monsters that you haven't contended
with.
Maybe there's situations where the right
hemisphere is stored up enough,
counter enough of a counter hypothesis,
let's say about how the world works out,
make making sense.
Out of all those things that you've
ignored that one day it just goes snap
and you're a new personality and maybe
the new personality isn't addicted.
So it's something like it's something
like that.
I think so,
yeah.
Joke.
Good Morning Citizen Peters.
I've prepared a real doozy for you here.
It's a good thing you've got extra time
to handle this one.
I'd even say it's rehearsed a little
bit,
so it's going to be ultra ineffective,
you know.
Now I understand that a lecture on the
psychological significance of anything
really is going to induce notably wander
off into an anthropocentric worldview,
but as a practitioner of the hard
sciences,
I wanted to dig a little bit deeper,
you know,
so I sought out I guess a religious
interpretation of both creative freedom
and I guess the very nature of time
itself and I found it obviously that's
why I'm here.
And if you think you have an
anthropocentric worldview,
it's nothing compared to Joseph Cardinal
Ratzinger's.
Now I like to think that this microphone
here,
the one that you keep muting out on me,
you know,
this microphone is an object which
exists outside of our individual
perceptions.
That's just the way I like to look at
it.
Hmm.
But then I think about the concept.
Beauty is in the eye of the beholder and
certainly,
I mean when you're talking about art,
the appreciation of art,
there has to be some sort of subjective
element integrated into them,
but there also must be a limit as well.
I mean certain works of art.
We appreciate as absolute masterpieces,
like Michelangelo's Pieta for example,
what you bring up frequently because it
really is that good.
But there's other things which are just
by comparison to like vandalism,
you know,
um,
now there's always a temptation to
invoke the principle of a non
overlapping magisterial.
But that seems like sort of a Capo,
right?
So I formulated,
I guess for myself,
for standards of measure,
which helped me separate what's the
difference between art and mediocrity?
And here's the four.
Number One,
education,
number two,
time commitment.
You got to put in the time.
If you're an artist,
it's probably going to become your full
time occupation is that you have to be
that passionate about it.
Number three,
public display art isn't something that
you own for yourself.
You hide it in your basement,
then it's not.
Art is something that you have to
express,
you know,
something which you've got to share,
and number four,
and I think this is the most one,
efficacy of vision.
If you're an artist,
you've got to have a vision and we talk
about the dream state here a lot.
You go into the dream state,
you have inspiration,
but it's not enough to just have the
inspiration because that's totally
subjective for you.
The Art,
the art part of it is having the
techniques and the skill and the intent
and I guess the capacity to turn that
into something real.
You know that you can then express or
share.
So can you read Cardinal Ratzinger,
his explanation for the nature of time
and then address the concept of beauty
in the eye of the beholder with specific
reference to the body positivity
movement.
How speech?
No,
I don't think I can.
I think that's
right.
I think that you,
you tangled together so many things and
this is also a tangle of things.
Not that that's a criticism that I can't
pull them all together with sufficient
rapidity not to bore the audience to
death.
So I'm gonna,
I'm gonna.
Wait,
I'm going to rate Dr Peterson.
I'm fascinated by the idea of faith,
what faith means.
Jacob listens to a voice and believes
it.
He probably heard other voices.
Why did he believe this one?
Why what?
There must have been an a priori sort of
functional necessity for him to believe
the voice that told him one thing or
another.
And I think that that's a string that
runs through the Bible and then through
the new testament we are expected as
well.
I confess I'm a Christian.
I'm I act like I believe God is real.
And and so there is this a call of faith
and also the in every hero story we,
we see now there is always a moment in
that story where the hero
must believe something beyond the
evidence that is before then,
which is to say they must take a leap of
faith.
So I'm wondering if you could just kind
of unpack that experience of faith in
the understanding of how a human being
makes the choice to believe one thing or
another.
God,
that's a great question.
I mean,
is this still on?
Is this still working?
Okay.
Okay,
good.
Um,
I don't,
I don't precisely know the answer that
it's a very peculiar thing because we
think many things,
or you could say many voices appear in
our minds because when Nisha took
descartes,
I think therefore I am a part.
And he said,
well,
it isn't so obvious that there's an eye,
first of all,
that it's a unity,
like a unity transparent unto itself,
which of course the psychoanalysts
picked up in a big way and then he
wasn't sure that it was the eye who
thought in some causal manner.
He said,
well,
no,
it's more like thoughts.
It's something like thoughts appear in
the phenomenal field and maybe you
choose between them or maybe they
possess you.
Like there's lots of other ways of
thinking about it.
It isn't exactly obvious to me why we
choose to take one pathway rather than
another when so many of them could offer
themselves to us.
You know,
people tend to talk about that as
something like conscience,
right?
And now maybe it's that
it's gotta have something to do.
I think it's an endless regress because
you can always ask why the why any
assumption became primary,
but I'll put that aside for a moment.
It seems to me to have something to do
with your aims.
You know that you're more likely to
listen to a voice that is in keeping
with your most fundamental aims and then
the question is where do your most
fundamental aims come from?
And from what I've been able to
determine,
and I'll speak psychologically again,
is that to begin with,
you're a concatenation of rather
primitive,
subpersonalities hungry.
One's tired,
one's upset ones laughing one.
So you can see that in babies,
you know,
they cycle through those states very
rapidly.
There's a infantile unity above all
that,
but it doesn't have control.
Right?
And so then the developing individual
has to figure out how to integrate those
primitive subpersonalities into a
unified personality.
At the same time,
they integrate the unified personality
into a social unity.
So it's partly individual integration,
but it's fed by social forces.
I mean even when you watch an infant
breastfeed,
it's established a relationship with its
mother and there's a reciprocity that's
already at play there,
so then that underlying multiplicity
starts to form itself into a unity and
then the question,
and I would say that something like
that's something like the emergence of
the individual out of out of the titans.
That's a reasonable way of thinking
about it,
like a sovereign out of the titans at
something like that,
but then there's another division which
seems to me to parallel a parallel that
the Cain and Abel Division is that that
integration can be oriented towards
something that's positive,
but it can also be oriented towards
something that's negative and that's the
split of the world into good and evil.
I think.
And then it looks like you're navigating
between those.
And I can only account for that with
something like choice.
Like I think the free choice,
even though I don't understand it,
I'm unwilling to deny the existence of
free choice merely because I don't
understand it because it looks to me
like that's how people are.
That's how the expect to be treated.
And that societies who that structure
themselves in accordance with the idea
that people have free choice actually
work now that doesn't prove that there's
free choice,
but people have been arguing about that
forever.
So,
but it looks to me.
So those are two possible means of
integration and that I think what you're
doing is feeding one or the other
constantly.
And I think you probably choose which
one to feed.
I think that's an.
I mean that's how it feels that way to
me as well.
Like when I look at my own,
you know,
maybe you're really aggravated with
something,
maybe you're aggravated with your wife,
you know,
or,
or your child or something like that,
you know,
and you're feeling kind of nasty and
maybe even know that you're in the
wrong.
And an idea comes into your head.
You can think,
I could say that and you know,
you could say it and you know what it
would do,
but then you pause and you think,
would that make it better or worse?
And then maybe you go to hell with it.
Which is quite the thing to say.
I've got a little story about that in a
minute and then you say it,
but you knew,
you knew that you took the low road,
right,
and you know it,
and then you're guilty about that and
defensive and that makes the fight way
works because then there's no damn way
you're going to admit that you actually
did that and so things do go to hell and
so.
So here's,
here's an ugly little idea.
So that's,
that's,
that's relevant to the question.
So imagine you're playing around with
cocaine.
Now I'm using cocaine because it's very
addictive,
but it's a very interesting chemical
because it's a dopaminergic agonist.
And what?
What dopamine does is two things.
It makes you feel like what you're doing
is worthwhile,
but it also imagine that there's a bunch
of neurocircuits that are active and
then they get a hit of dopamine or you
do in those neurocircuits get a little
bit more powerful.
Okay?
So it,
it has a rewarding
property,
which is that it makes you feel like
what you're doing is important and it
has a reinforcing property which is,
it makes neurocircuits grow.
So now what that means is that whatever
you were doing just before you took
cocaine,
grows,
okay?
So now imagine there's a bunch of
different things that you do just before
you take cocaine,
but there's a string of decisions and it
one decision point is the same for all
of those different occurrences.
And that decision point is because you
know you're in trouble and that decision
point is well to hell with it.
Okay?
So then you think that each of the 200
times that you take cocaine,
even though you do it different places,
but that one thought is there all the
time and that thing grows because you're
reinforcing it and it grows and it grows
and it grows.
And so now that's in you.
That's,
that's part of you.
And it's the thing that says to hell
with it.
Okay,
so now,
and maybe that's not such a good thing
to grow inside your brain.
So then you,
you're addicted and they take you to a
cocaine treatment center and after a
week you're no longer physically,
physiologically addicted.
You're not craving.
You don't have a problem as long as
you're there.
But then they take you back to your
normal environment and you see like
cocaine,
Joe,
your friend,
and as soon as you see him up,
that thing comes in,
Bang,
you're back on your back,
on the trail with a track and that's
while you're in where you will end up
too,
if you reinforce that particular
perspective long enough.
So that's akin in a sense to the
decision making process.
You know,
if you,
if you take the low road,
then that winds and it gets a little
stronger because everything that wins
neurologically gets a little stronger.
It's like a Darwinian competition.
So one rule is don't practice what you
don't want to become because you really
do become that.
It builds,
it builds itself right into your neural
architecture.
And that's one of the terrifying things
about addiction,
you know,
because you think,
well,
it's kind of psychological.
It's like,
yeah,
kind of.
It's also kind of neurophysiological and
you build a one eyed cocaine monster in
your head if you hit yourself enough
with something that reinforcing.
So yeah.
Thanks.
Last question,
I guess.
Hallelujah.
I'm just a really simple question then
take that long suffering when it,
one of the things though is noticing
from the stories of Jacob and a lot of
these biblical narratives is you do have
this all powerful God who is able to
kind of essentially be the hidden
protagonist in the narrative.
But then the funny thing is that he's
kind of revealing some of his qualities
throughout the course of the story.
So you were talking about,
um,
the weird paradox of the fact that God's
somehow alive as Jacob Israel to win the
fight.
He does that with Abraham to.
Yeah.
So my question is relating to penn steps
thing about the rats that you told like
three or four times and the number of
occasions I saw one of your more recent
videos.
You've talked about it where the bigger
rat lets the smaller Rhett when,
because then the other smaller rat won't
engage in the game.
So the question is twofold.
For me.
One is God allowing humanity to when
periodically.
So that's to allow us to actually engage
in the dialogue through these stories.
And two,
is it a much more primitive version of
the virtue of humility,
which you wouldn't normally characterize
of an of an of an omnipotent deity?
Hmm.
Well,
those are excellent questions that I
really liked.
The second one in particular that that
God's decision to allow human victory
from time to time is actually a
manifestation of something approximating
humility or at least mercy.
But humility is an interesting take on
it.
Well,
it's also connected to Paul's image of
how Christ handed them hands himself
over and allows himself to be defeated
by men and therefore a conquers sin,
which is man's enemy.
It's a weird.
It's the same paradox where God enters
into that dynamic with people and loses
and willingly loses.
Yeah.
Well that's okay.
So the first thing I would say is that.
That's a really interesting analogy.
I,
I can't.
It's complicated enough questions so
that I can't go be.
I don't think I can go beyond the
question actually because it's so
complicated that I don't think I can
formulate it any better than you already
did.
Like it's an interesting string of
ideas.
I'd have to play with it a while to see
it does.
She had an interesting light on why God
is amenable to negotiation in the Old
Testament,
which is really a strange.
As you pointed out,
it's really a strange thing.
It's like this is omnipotent God who
obviously can do whatever he wants and
yet he allow,
he can be bargained with and then that
also opens up the question of why like
your hypothesis as well.
If you don't let the little rat win now
and then,
then they get dejected and quit playing.
And that's.
I mean,
that's,
that's a pretty good observation if
people don't get to win now and then you
know,
that's Kinda what happens to cane.
God says,
well,
you're not playing a straight game.
That's why you're not winning.
But
I don't know.
There's an intimation in the old
testament and I think it's more
developed in the New Testament.
Maybe not that the straighter the game
you play,
the more likely you are to win.
And so maybe part of the reason that God
lets Abraham Bargain and and even Jacob
is because they've started to play very
straight games.
And so maybe you do when in you're
wrestling with God if you play a
straight gay.
I mean,
I think.
I actually think that's.
I think the reason that's true is
because that's actually why we would
define it as a street gate now.
Then we could speak psychologically.
Again,
I think that what we've come to
recognize as a straight game is the game
that in the broadest number of
situations across the widest range of
time spans is most likely to produce a
positive outcome.
And that's,
that's actually the grounds for our
sense of ethics that it's really
practical.
Not to Belabor it too much because there
was,
there was an interesting insight from
Chesterton's demand who was Thursday
where God sets himself up as the
benevolent antagonist so as to
accelerate
game.
Yeah.
Well,
I think that's a really interesting
idea.
I mean,
there is,
there is hints,
I would say throughout the biblical
stories that the reason that God
tolerates Satan,
let's say is because without an
adversary,
you're soft and that's,
I mean,
that's tied in with the notion that life
is something like a moral struggle.
You know,
that that's the fundamental essence of
being a moral struggle.
Now I think that that's phenomenal.
Logically a reasonable observation.
Maybe it's maybe other people don't
experience it that way,
but it seems to me like within my own
experience that that's accurate.
Now I don't know what Dan,
I don't know what that says about the
fundamental nature of reality,
but I had a vision at one point that I
was in a ring with Satan actually,
believe it or not,
and it was like a Roman coliseum and I
was rather upset to find myself there,
but I won and I asked God afterwards why
he would do such a thing and his answer
was he knew I could win.
That's interesting,
you know,
because like,
I don't know what to make of that.
Believe me,
I have no idea what to make of that.
But the idea was that if you're trying
to encourage someone rather than protect
them,
because those are really different
things,
right?
To protect someone isn't to make them
strong,
to encourage them is to make them
strong.
Then you set them a series of
challenges,
right?
Right.
At the point where they may win and
maybe you could make a case that that's
what you do if you really care for
someone.
Now I know that that's it.
I'm not saying that that interpretation
is correct,
but there's something mean you
definitely with your children,
you know when you're wrestling with
them,
say when you're playing with them,
you use,
you push them to the limit of their
ability because otherwise they don't
transcend their current abilities.
So.
Yep.
Thank you.
So we'll see some of you,
perhaps most of you in December and I
think we'll finish off genesis at that
point.
And then in the new year,
probably not till the spring,
I'll start with exodus,
which I'm really looking forward to
because I really liked the exodus story.
It's an amazing story and unbelievably
deep.
Not well.
The ones we've covered so far have been
pretty good as well,
but so thank you all for coming and will
perhaps see you in about a month.