Yeah,
I'm really looking forward to this
lecture,
not like I wasn't looking forward to the
other ones,
but the stories that I want to cover
tonight,
I.
One of the things that just absolutely
staggers me about them,
especially the story of Cain and Abel,
which I hope to get to is like,
it's so short.
It's unbelievable.
It's like 10,
11 lines.
There's nothing to it at all and I've
found that it's essentially
inexhaustible in its capacity to reveal
meaning and I don't exactly know what to
make of that.
I mean I do.
I think,
you know,
because I said I was going to take as
rational approach to this issue as I
possibly could.
I think it has something to do with this
intense process of condensation across
very long periods of time.
That's the simplest explanation,
but I'll tell you the information in
there,
it's so densely packed that it really
is.
It's really,
it's not that easy to come up with an
explanation for that.
Not one that I find compelling.
I mean,
I do think that the really old stories,
and we've been covering the really
archaic stories in the Bible so far,
I think that one of the things that you
can be virtually certain about is that
everything about them that was memorable
was remembered,
right?
And so in some sense,
and this is kind of like the idea of
Richard Dawkins ideas of means,
which is often why I thought that
Richard Dawkins,
he was a little bit more,
uh,
mystically inclined,
he would have become Carl you because
there are theories are unbelievably
similar.
The similar of meme in the similar of
the idea of archetypes of the collective
unconscious are very,
very similar ideas except the union
ideas far more profound in my
estimation.
Well,
it,
it just is.
He thought it through so much better,
you know,
um,
because darkens,
tended to think of me.
Ms Dot is sort of like a mind where,
you know,
something that would infest the mind and
maybe multiple minds,
but he never really took.
I don't think he really ever took the
idea with the seriousness that deserved.
And I did hear him actually make a joke
with Sam Harris the last time they
talked about the fact that,
that,
uh,
there was some possibility that the,
the production of meme say religious
means could alter evolutionary history
and they both avoided that topic
instantly.
They had a big laugh about it.
Men decided they weren't going to go
down that road.
And so that wasn't fair.
That was quite interesting to me.
But,
um,
these,
the,
the density of these stories I do really
think still is a,
is a mystery.
It's,
it certainly has something to do with
their absolute.
They're in the impossibility to be
forgotten,
you know?
And that's actually something that could
be tested empirically.
I don't know if anybody has ever done
that because you could tell naive people
to stories,
even equal length,
right?
One that had an archetypal team and the
other that didn't.
And then wait three months and see which
ones people remembered better be.
It'd be relatively straightforward thing
to test.
I haven't tested it,
but maybe I will at some point.
But anyways,
that's all to say that I'm very excited
about this lecture because I get an
opportunity to go over to the story of
Adam and eve and the story of Cain and
Abel and I hope we manage both of those
today and maybe we'll get to the story
of Noah and the Tower of Babel as.
But I wouldn't count on it.
Not at the rate we'd been.
Not at the rate we'd been progressing,
but that's okay.
That's no problem.
It's,
there is no sense rushing this.
Alright,
so we're going to go.
Before we go that before we do that,
I want to finish my discussion of the
idea of the psychological significance
of the idea of God.
And I've been thinking about this a lot
more,
you know,
because of course this lecture series
gives me the opportunity on the
necessity to continue to think.
And you know,
it,
it certainly is the case.
So the hypothesis that I've been
developing with the trinitarian idea,
something like that,
the trinitarian idea is the earliest
emergence in image of the idea that
there has to be an underlying cognitive
structure that gives rise to
consciousness as well as consciousness
itself.
And so what I was suggesting was that
the idea of God,
the father is something akin to the idea
of the,
a priority structure that,
that gives rise to consciousness.
That's an inbuilt part of us.
So that's our structure.
You could think about that as something
that's been produced over a vast
evolutionary time span.
And I don't think that's completely out
of keeping with the,
with the,
uh,
with the ideas that are laid forth in
genesis one,
at least if you think about them from a
metaphorical perspective.
And it's hard to read them literally
because I don't know what,
you know,
there's an emphasis on day and night.
But the idea of day and night as a 24
hour diurnal,
you know,
a daytime and nighttime interchanges
with are based on the claw on the
earthly clock.
Seems to be a bit absurd when you first
start to think about the construction of
the cosmos,
so just doesn't seem to me that a
literal interpretation is appropriate
and it's another thing that you might
not know,
but you know,
many of the early church fathers,
one of them,
origin in particular stated very clearly
this was in 300 and that these ancient
stories were to be taken as as as wise
metaphors and not to be taken.
Literally like the idea that the people
who established Christianity,
for example,
we're all the sorts of people who were
biblical literalists.
It's just absolutely historically wrong.
I mean some of them were and some of
them still are.
That's not the point.
Many of them weren't and it's not like
people who lived 2000 years ago were
stupid by any stretch of the imagination
and so they were perfectly capable of
understanding what you know,
what constituted something approximating
a metaphor,
and also knew that fiction in some sense
considered as an abstraction,
could tell you truths at that nonfiction
wasn't able,
wasn't able to get at lest.
You think that fiction is only for
entertainment and I think that's a very,
that's a,
that's a big mistake to think that.
So.
Alright.
So here we go.
So yeah.
So with regards to the idea of,
of God the father.
So the idea is that in order to make
sense out of the world,
you have to have an,
a priori cognitive structure.
And that was something that Emmanuel
Kant,
as I,
as I said last time,
um,
uh,
put forward as an argument against the
idea that all of the information that we
acquire during our lifetime as a
consequence of incoming sensor data.
And the reason that con objective to
that,
and he was absolutely right about this,
is you can't make sense of sense data
without any prior restructure.
You can't extract from census data the
structure that enables you to make sense
of sense data.
It's not possible.
And that's really been demonstrated,
I would say,
beyond a shadow of a doubt since the 19
sixties.
And the best demonstration of that was
actually the initial failure of
artificial intelligence because when the
ai people started promising that we
would have fully functional autonomous
robots and artificial intelligence back
in the 19 sixties,
um,
what they didn't understand and what
stalled them terribly until about the
early 19 nineties was that it was almost
that the problem of perception was a
much deeper problem than anybody ever
recognized.
Because like when you look at the world,
you just see,
well look,
there's objects out there.
And by the way,
you don't see objects.
You see tools.
Just so you know,
in the neurobiology of that's quite
clear.
You don't see objects and infer utility.
You see useful things and infer object.
So it's actually the reverse of what
people generally think.
But the point is,
is that regardless of whether you see
objects or useful things,
when you look at the world,
you just see it and you think,
well,
seeing as easy because they're,
the things are no,
you have to do is turn your head and
they appear.
And that's just so wrong that it's,
it's almost impossible to overstate the
problem of perception is staggeringly
difficult and one of the primary reasons
that we still don't really have
autonomous robot,
so there were a lot closer to it than we
were in the 19 sixties is because it
turned out that you actually have to
have an a body.
You have to have a body before you can
think,
and even more importantly,
you have to have a body before you can
see because the act of seeing is
actually the act of mapping the patterns
of the world onto the patterns of the
body.
It's not things are out there.
You see them,
then you think about them,
then you evaluate them.
Then you decide to act on them and then
you act.
I mean that,
that you could call that a folk idea of
psychological processing or perception.
It's not.
That is not how it works.
Like your eyes for example,
map.
One of the things they do is map right
onto your spinal cord.
For example,
they might write onto your emotional
system,
so it's actually possible,
for example,
for people to be blind and still be able
to detect facial expressions,
which is to say you can put someone
who's cortically blind,
so they've had their visual cortex
destroyed often by a stroke.
They will tell you that they can't see
anything,
but they can guess which hand you put up
if you ask them to.
And if you flash them pictures of angry
or fearful faces,
they show skin conductance responses to
the more emotion laden faces.
And it's because imagine that the world
is made out of patterns which it is.
Now.
Imagine that those patterns are
transmitted to you electromagnetically
you'd have through light.
And then imagine that the pattern is
duplicated on the retina and then that
pattern is propagated along the optic
nerve.
And then the pattern is distributed
throughout your brain.
And some of that pattern makes up what
you call it,
conscious vision,
but other parts of it just activate your
body.
And so for example,
when I look at this,
uh,
this,
whatever,
whatever it is,
a battle,
that's the word,
you know,
when I look at it,
especially with intent in mind,
as soon as I look at it,
the pattern of the bottom of the bottle
activates the gripping mechanism of my
hand and part of the action of,
or the,
the active perception is to adjust my
bodily posture,
including my hand grip to be of the
optimal size to pick that up.
And it's not that I see the bottle and
then think about how to move my hand as
too slow.
It's that I use my motor motor cortex to
perceive the bottle.
And that's actually somewhat independent
of actually seeing the bottle as a
conscious experience.
So anyways,
the reason that I'm telling you that,
all of that,
and there's much more about that that
can be told Rodney Brooks,
he's someone to know about.
He's a robotics engineer who worked in
the 19 nineties and he invented the
Roomba among many other things.
So he's a real genius,
that guy.
And,
uh,
he brooks was one of the first people to
really point out that,
uh,
to have,
to be able to have a,
an n,
a machine that perceived well enough to
work in the world that you had to give
it a body and that the perception would
actually be built from the body up
rather than the,
from the abstract cognitive perceptions
down and so well that,
that turned out to be the case.
And Brooks boiled all sorts of weird
little machines in the 19 nineties that
didn't even really have any central
brain,
but they could do things like run away
from light and so they could perceive
light,
but their perception was the act of
running away from light.
And so perception perception is very,
very,
very tightly tied to action in ways that
people don't normally perceive.
Anyways,
that's all to say that you cannot
perceive the world without being
embodied.
And you know,
you're embodied in a manner that's taken
you roughly three and a half billion
years to pull off.
Right?
There's been a lot of death as a
prerequisite to the embodied form that
you take.
And so it's taken all that trial and
error to produce something like you that
can interact with the complexity of the
world well enough to last the relatively
poultry 80 or so years that you can
last.
And so I think about that as,
this may be wrong,
but I think it's a useful,
at least it's a useful a hypothesis.
I think the idea of God the father is
something like the birth of the idea
that there has to be an internal
structure that I would've wished
consciousness itself arises that gives
form to things.
And well if that's the case and perhaps
it's not,
but if it's the case,
it's certainly reflection.
It's a reflection of the kind of factual
truth that I've been describing now.
And then like I also mentioned that I
kind of see the,
the idea of both the Holy Spirit also of
Christ and most specifically of Christ
in the form of the word as the act of
consciousness.
That that structure produces and uses
not only to to formulate the world
because we formulate the world,
at least the world that we experience.
We formulate,
but also to change.
And modify that world because there's
absolutely no doubt that we do that
partly with our bodies which are
optimally evolved to do that,
which is why we have hands on like
dolphins that have very large brains
like us,
but can't really change the world.
We're really adapted and evolved to
change the world.
And the world in our speech is really,
uh,
an extension of our ability to use our
hands.
So the speech systems that we use are
very well developed motor,
a very well developed motor skill and
generally speaking,
you're your dominant linguistic
hemisphere,
the same as your dominant hand and
people talk with their hands like me,
he has,
you may have noticed and we use sign
language and there's a tight
relationship between the use of the hand
and the use of language.
And that's partly because language is a
productive force and the hand is part of
it,
part of what changes the world.
And so all those things are tied
together in a very,
very complex way with this a priori
structure.
And also with the embodied structure.
And I also think that's part of the
reason why classical Christianity put
such an emphasis not only on the
divinity of the spirit,
but also on the divinity of the body,
which is a harder thing to grapple with.
You know,
it's easier for people to think if you
think in religious terms at all,
but you have some sort of transcendent
spirit that somehow detached from the
body that might have some life after
death,
something like that.
But the Christian Christianity in
particular really insists on the
divinity of the body.
So the idea is that there's an
underlying structure that's got this
clause,
I patriarchal nature,
partly because it's for complex reasons,
but partly because it's a reflection of
the social structure as well as other
things.
And then that uses consciousness in the
form particularly of language,
but most particularly in the form of
truthful language in order to produce
the world in a manner that's good.
And I think that's a walloping powerful,
powerful idea.
Especially the relationship between the
idea that it's truthful speech that
gives rise to the good.
Because that's a really fundamental
moral.
And I think that's a tough one to beat
man,
because one of the things I've really
noticed is,
and this isn't just me,
that's for sure,
is that,
you know,
there's a lot of tragedy in life.
There is no doubt about that.
And lots of people that I see,
for example in my clinical practice are
laid low by the tragedy of life.
But I also see very,
very frequently that people get tangled
up in deceit,
in webs of deceit that are often
multiple generations long.
And that just takes them out,
you know,
and so that.
So deceit can produce extraordinary
levels of suffering that,
that last for very,
very long periods of time.
And that's really a clinical truism,
you know,
because Freud of course identified one
of the problems that contributed to the
suffering we might associate with mental
illness,
with repression,
which is kind of like a lie of omission.
That's a perfectly reasonable way to
think about it.
And you stated straight out that there
was no difference between the
Psychotherapeutic,
the curative psychotherapeutic effort
and supreme moral effort,
including truth.
That those were the same thing as far as
he was concerned and Carl Rogers and
other great clinician who was at one
point at Christian missionary before he
became a more,
more,
more strictly scientific,
he believed that it was in truthful
dialogue that that,
that a clinical transformation took
place and you know it,
it,
and of course one of the prerequisites
for genuine transformation in the
clinical setting is that the therapist
tells the truth and the client tells the
truth because otherwise,
how in the world do you know what's
going on now?
Can you solve a problem when you don't
even know what the problem is and you
don't know what the problem is unless
the person tells you the truth.
That's something really to think about
in light of your own relationships
because you know if you don't tell the
people around you the truth and they
don't know who you are,
and maybe that's a good thing,
you know,
because while seriously people have
reasons to lie,
right?
I mean that aren't trivial,
but it's really worth knowing that you
can't even get your hands on the problem
unless you formulate it truthfully and
if you can't get your hands on the
problem,
the probability that you're going to
solve it is just so low.
And so then I'd been thinking about as
well the this,
this,
and this idea has become more credible
to me.
The longer I've developed it,
the longer I've thought about it,
you know,
the idea that there's,
I'll go back.
It's partly the idea that,
well,
let me,
let me figure out how to start this
property.
Friend of mine,
business partner and guide that I've
written scientific papers with very
smart guy.
Took me to task and I think I told you
this a little bit about using the term
dominance hierarchy,
which might be fine for like chimpanzees
and for lobsters and for creatures like
that,
but not,
not,
not for chimpanzees even so much.
And,
and he said something very interesting.
He thought that the idea of dominance
hierarchy was actually a projection of
early 20th century Marxist hypothesis
onto the animal kingdom that was being
observed.
And the notion that the hierarchical
structure that you see that
characterize,
say mating hierarchies in,
in chimps,
for example,
the idea that that was predicated on
power was actually a projection of a
kind of political ideology.
And I thought that really bugged me for
a long time when he said that because
like,
because I agree to be used to using the
term dominance higher can,
I thought he told me all that I thought,
oh,
that's so annoying,
so annoying because it might be right.
And then it took me months to think
about it.
And then I,
and then I was also reading friends to
wall at the same time.
And he's a primatologist and also Jaak
Panksepp who was a brilliant,
brilliant affective neuroscientist who
unfortunately just died.
He wrote a great book called affective
neuroscience.
And for rats to play,
they have to play fair or they won't
play with each other.
And that's,
that's a staggering discovery,
right?
Because anything that helps,
um,
instantiate the,
uh,
the emergence of ethical behavior in
animals and that associates it with an
evolutionary process,
which is essentially what,
what,
what Panksepp was doing gives credence
to the notion that the ethics that guide
us are not mere social logical EPA,
phenomenal constructs.
They're deep,
deeply rooted.
If rats ended their rats for God's sake,
you can't trust them and they still play
fair,
you know,
and the well notice that the chimp
troops that he studied like that,
it wasn't,
it wasn't the barbaric barbaric chimp
that ruled with an iron fist.
That was the successful ruler because he
kept getting torn to shreds by his,
by the compatriots that he ignored and
stomped on.
Susie showed some weakness.
They just tear them into pieces.
The chimp leaders that were stable,
you know,
that had a stable kingdom,
let's say.
We're very reciprocal in terms of their
interactions with their friends and
chimps have friends and they asked.
They actually last for a very long time.
Chimp friendships and they're also very
reciprocal in the ranch or interactions
with the females and with the infants.
And I thought that's,
that's a friends to wall is a very smart
guy and I thought that was also
foundational science because it's really
something to note that the attributes
that give rise to dominance in a male
dominance hierarchy sort of use that
word,
let's call it authority.
That might be better or even shutter
competence,
which I think is a better way of
thinking about it,
is that that's not predicated purely on
anything that's,
that's,
that's as simple as brute power.
And I think too,
you know,
I think as well that the idea,
and this is a deeply devious and
dangerous political idea in my
estimation,
the idea that male dominance
hierarchies,
sorry,
male hierarchies are fundamentally
predicated on power in a,
in a law abiding in a law abiding
society,
I think is.
I think all you have to do is think
about that for like a month.
Say she isn't that long.
To understand how observed that is.
Because most people who are in positions
of authority,
let's say are just as him then by
ethical responsibility or even more so
than people at the other levels of the,
of the hierarchy.
And we know this even in the managerial
literature because we know generally
speaking that managers are more stressed
by their subordinates than the
subordinates are stressed by their
managers.
And that's not surprising.
Yeah,
you want to be responsible for like 200
people.
You really want that.
That's hard work,
man.
And I mean I know it's a pain to have a
boss because you have to care about what
the boss thinks and maybe the person is
arbitrary,
in which case they're not going to be
particularly successful,
but it's no joke to be responsible for
200 people and you have to behave very
carefully when you're in a position of
responsibility and authority like that
because you will get called out if you
make mistakes constantly.
So it's not like you're.
It's not like because you have a
position that's higher up in the
hierarchy that you're less constrained
by ethical necessity.
Now,
if you're a psychopath,
while that's a whole different story,
but psychopaths have to move pretty
rapidly from hierarchy to hierarchy,
right?
Because they get found out quite quickly
and as soon as their reputation is
shattered,
then they can't get away with their
shenanigans anymore.
So okay.
So all of this is to say that there is
something very interesting about the
pattern of behavior,
so imagine that.
Imagine that sexual selection is working
something like this and we know that
sexual selection is a very,
very,
very powerful biological force even
though biologists ignored it for almost
a hundred years after Charles Darwin
originally wrote about it,
thinking mostly about natural selection.
They didn't like the idea of sexual
selection because it tended to introduce
the notion of mind into the process of
evolution because it deals with choice,
you know,
but so imagine on the one hand that you
have a male hierarchy.
We know that the men at the top of the
hierarchy are much more likely to be
reproductively successful then the men
at the bottom.
And it's particularly true of men.
So you have twice as many female
ancestors as you have male ancestors.
Not going to do the math,
but,
and I know it doesn't sound plausible,
but you could look it up and figure it
out.
It's perfectly reasonable fact that
actually happens to be true.
So there's twice as you have twice as
many female ancestors because females
are twice as likely on average to leave
offspring as men.
Now what happens is any man,
man who does reproduce,
tends to reproduce more than once,
but a bunch of the reproduce zero.
Whereas so would be the average man who
reproduces has two children.
And the average man who doesn't
reproduce has zero obviously.
And the average woman who reproduces has
one shop.
So that means that there's twice as many
females in your life as there is males,
so that,
that's a big deal.
And so imagine that it works.
Something like this.
So the men who elect the dough,
the,
the competent men who were,
are admired and who are and who are,
uh,
I can't say dominant,
who are,
who are given positions of authority and
respect,
let's put it that way.
And it's like an election now.
It could be an actual democratic
election,
but it's at least an election of
consensus or it's at least an election
of while we're not going to kill him for
now,
which is also a form of the election,
right?
It's a form of tolerance,
you know,
so,
and then what happens is the women for
their part peel from the top of the male
hierarchy.
And so you've got two factors that are
driving human sexual selection across
vast stretches of evolutionary time.
One is the election of men by men to
positions where they're much more likely
to reproduce.
And the second is the tendency of women
to peel off the top of male dominance
hierarchies,
which is extraordinarily well
established cross culturally.
Even if you flat out a socioeconomic
disparity,
say between men and women like they've
done in Scandinavia,
you don't,
ah,
reduce the tendency of women to peel off
the top of the male hierarchy by much.
And why?
Why would you,
I mean,
women are smart.
Why in the world wouldn't they go for
four?
Why wouldn't they strive to make
relationships with men who are
relatively successful?
And why wouldn't they let the men
themselves define why that,
how that constitutes success.
It makes sense.
Like if you want to figure out who the
best man is,
why not let the men compete and let the
man,
the man who wins whatever the
competition is,
is the best man by definition.
How else would you it?
So okay,
so why am I telling you all that?
Well,
the reason is is because it seems to me
that there's this comp,
there's been this complex interplay
across human evolution between the
election of the male dominance hierarchy
and sexual success.
And that's a big deal.
If it's true,
it could be because what would happen
you see is that as men evolved,
they would evolve to be better and
better at climbing up the male hierarchy
because the ones who weren't good at
that wouldn't reproduce.
So obviously that's going to happen.
But then it wouldn't just be a hierarchy
because there's a whole bunch of
different hierarchies.
And so then you might say,
well,
are there commonalities across
hierarchies?
That's a reasonable thing to propose it.
I mean,
they're not completely opposed to one
another.
At least if you're more successful,
relatively more successful in one
hierarchy,
then you're more probable,
it's more probable that you'll be
successful in another,
and that's actually a really good
definition of general intelligence or
Iq.
And that's actually one of the things
that women select men for now.
Men also select women for that,
but the selection pressure is even
higher from women to men.
And General Iq is one of the things that
propels you across dominance hierarchies
because it's a general problem solving
mechanism.
And the other thing that seems to do
that to some degree is conscientiousness
and there's also some evidence that
women prefer conscientious men.
So and of course,
why wouldn't they?
Because you can trust them and,
and,
and they work.
And so those are both good things.
So then you think,
okay,
so men have adapted to start to climb
the male dominance hierarchy,
but it's the set of all possible
hierarchies that they're adapted to
climb.
And so then you think there's,
there's a set of attributes that can be
acted out that and that can be embodied,
that will increase the probability that
you're going to rise to the top of any
given hierarchy.
And then you could say,
well then as you adapt to that fact,
then you start to develop an
understanding of what that pattern
constitutes.
And so that starts to become the
abstract representation of something
like multidimensional competence.
And that's like the abstraction of
virtue itself.
Well the and the,
none of that has been.
None of that's arbitrary now.
Not as bloody well grounded in biology
as anything could be.
And I think that's a really hard
argument to refute.
And like one of the things I should tell
you about how I think is that when I
think something,
I spend a long time trying to figure out
if it's wrong,
you know,
because I like to hack at it from every
possible direction to see if it's a weak
idea.
Because if it's a weak idea then I'd
rather just dispense with it and find
something better.
And I've had a real hard time trying to
figure out what's wrong with that idea I
had.
It's,
it seems to me that it's pretty damn
solid.
And then the idea that,
you know,
if you watch what people do in movies
and so on,
and when they're reading fiction,
it's obvious that they're very good at
identifying both the hero and the anti
hero.
We could say the Antihero,
generally speaking,
the bad guy is someone who strives for,
for,
for authority and position but fails
generally speaking,
not always,
but sales.
So he's a good,
bad example.
A kid,
you take a kid to a,
a good guy,
bad guy movie the kid figures out pretty
fast that he's not supposed to be the
bad guy and,
and fingers out very quickly to zero in
on the good guy.
And that means that there's,
there's an affinity between the pattern
of good guy that's being played out in
the fiction and the perceptual capacity
of the child.
You know,
and one of the things I told my son when
he was a kid,
I used to take them to movies that were
sometimes more frightening than they
should've been,
but one of the things I always told him
was I'd never said,
don't be afraid because I think that's
bad advice for kids.
What I said was,
keep your eye on the hero,
right?
Keep your eye on the hero.
And the Nike was gripped by the movie
and often quite afraid of them,
you know,
because movies can be very frightened.
So he just like zero in on that guy and
helping him.
Do you know what it's like in a movie?
You hope that the good guy wins
generally speaking.
And I mean,
why do you do that?
Where does that,
where does that come from?
You see how deeply rooted that is inside
you.
You're bloody well go line up and pay to
watch that happen.
It's not an easy thing to understand and
it's,
it's so self evident to people that we
don't even notice that.
It's a tremendous mystery.
And so why is it so unreasonable to
think that we would have actually over
the millennia come to some sort of
collective conclusion about what the
best of the best guys are,
best of the good guys are and what the
worst of the bad guys are.
And to me architecturally speaking,
thinking of that as the the hostile
brothers.
So that's Christ and Satan or Cain and
Abel,
for example.
Very common mythological motif.
The hostile brothers.
It's like those are.
Those are archetypes.
It's like the.
The Satan for example,
is by definition the worst that a person
can be.
And Christ by definition,
this is independent of anything but
conceptualization is by definition the
best that a that a man can be.
Now,
as I said,
I'm speaking psychologically and
conceptually,
but given our capacity for imagination
and our ability to engage in fiction and
our love for fiction and our capacity to
dramatize and our love for the story,
stories of heroism and catastrophe and
good and evil,
I can't see how it could be any other
way like so.
Well,
so.
So that's part of the idea that's
driving the notion of the evolution of
the idea of God and even more
specifically,
he driving the evolution of the idea,
at least in part of the trinity.
So God is an abstracted ideal,
formulated in large part to dissociate
the ideal from any particular
incarnation or man or any ruler.
And there's another rule in the biblical
stories,
which is that when the actual ruler,
I mentioned this before,
when the actual ruler becomes confused
with the abstracted ideal than the state
immediately turns into a tyranny and the
whole bloody thing collapses.
So the idea is so sophisticated,
you don't.
One of the things that we figured out,
and this was a hard thing to figure out,
was that you had to take the abstraction
and divorce it from any particular power
structure and then think about it as
something that existed as an
abstraction,
but a real thing,
right?
Real limited governed your behavior it
in everyone's behavior,
including the damn king.
The king was responsible to the abstract
ideal man.
That's an impossible.
That is such an impossible ideal.
If you know,
why would,
if they agreed to that 5,000
years ago,
but one of the things that you see
continually happening in the old
testament is that as soon as the
Israelite,
for example,
the Israelite Kings Become Almighty,
the rear guard comes along,
it just cuts them into pieces and then
the whole bloody stayed,
falls apart for hundreds of years.
So like,
I think that's a lesson that,
that we have not thoroughly,
consciously yet learn.
It's still implicit in the narratives.
We still haven't figured out why that's
the case.
Again,
I think that's a real hard argument to,
to,
uh,
to dispense with.
So.
All right,
so we looked at this a little bit.
The trinitarian idea is that there's a,
there's a,
a father,
uh,
that's maybe the,
the,
uh,
the dramatic representation of the
structures that underlie consciousness,
the embodied structures that underlie
consciousness.
And then there's the sun and that's
that.
That's consciousness,
but in its particular historical form,
that's the thing that's so interesting
about the figure of the sun.
And then there's consciousness as such.
And that seems to be something like the
indwelling spirit had.
So I'm mean,
these psychological ideas came from
somewhere,
right,
that they have a history they didn't
just spring out of nowhere and they
emerged from,
from dreams and hypothesis and artistic
visions and all of that over a long
time.
And maybe they get clarified into
something like consciousness.
But it takes a long time to get from,
to get from watching,
you know,
from two chimpanzees watching each other
to a human being saying,
well,
we're,
we all,
we all exhibit this faculty called
consciousness.
I mean,
man,
that's a long journey.
You know,
that's a really long journey and there's
going to be plenty of stages in between.
One of the things I really like about
John Piaget,
the developmental psychologist,
was that he was so insistent that
children act out and dramatize ideas
before they understand them.
And,
and I,
and Merlin Donald who is a psychologist
at Queen's university,
wrote a couple of interesting books
along those lines at all as well.
Looking at the importance of invitation
for the development of higher cognition
and human beings.
And so the notion that we embody ideas
before we abstract them out and then
represent them in an articulated way,
I think is an extraordinarily solid idea
and I really can't see how it could be
any other way.
And if you watch children,
you see that like think about what a
child is doing when he plays house or
she plays house,
you know the,
the,
the child acts out the father or the
mother.
But what's so interesting about new
think,
well look,
isn't that cute?
She's imitating her mother.
It's like,
no,
she's not.
That's not what happens because when
you're a child imitates you,
it's very annoying because you move your
arm and then they move their arm and you
know that you move your head,
the copy you.
No one likes that.
It's direct direct invitation.
That's not what a child is doing.
When the child is playing,
what the child is doing is watching the
mother over multiple instantiations and
then extracting out the spirit called
mother and that's whatever his mother
like across all those multiple
manifestations.
And then laying out that pattern
internally and manifesting itself in an
abstract world,
it's so sophisticated,
it's just I'm,
that's what you're doing when you're
playing house or having a tea partier or
taking care of a doll.
It's not like you've seen your mother
take care of a doll,
you haven't seen that.
It's that you're smart enough to pull
out the abstraction and then embody it.
And certainly the child is attempting to
strive towards an ideal at that point,
you know,
she's not lighting her doll on fire,
or well with certain exceptions,
but generally ones that we try to not
encourage.
Right?
So,
so you see that capacity and,
and children and,
and it's something we also know that if
children don't,
don't engage in that sort of dramatic
and pretend play to a tremendous degree
that they don't,
they don't get properly socialized.
It's really a critical element of,
of developing self understanding and
then also developing the capability of,
of being with others.
Because what you do when you're a child,
especially around the age of four,
you jointly construct a shared fictional
world will play host together,
let's say.
And then you act out your,
your joint rules within that shared
fictional world,
you know,
and,
and that's a form of eggs at a very
advanced cognition.
It's very sophisticated and I see that
and Piaget did as well.
And so did you and sorted Freud,
these brilliant observers and,
and also Merlin Donald,
these brilliant observers of the manner
in which condition came to be,
they noted very clearly that embodied
imitation and dramatic abstraction
constituted the ground out of which
higher abstract cognition emerged.
And how could it not be,
because obviously we were mostly bodies
before we were mines clearly.
And so we were acting out things way
before we understood them.
Just like the chimpanzees act out the
idea that you know,
you have to act reasonably sensibly if
your head chimpanzee or you're going to
get yourself rip,
rip apart.
And you see that role.
Because when wolves have a dominance
dispute,
you know,
they puff up their hair at each other to
look big and they growl and bark and
they,
you know,
they're very menacing.
And one wolf chickens out,
rules over puts up his neck.
And basically what he's saying is,
yeah,
I'm pretty useless so you can kill me if
I want to,
if you want to.
And the other wolf says,
yeah,
you know,
you're pretty useless and I could tear
out your throat,
but tomorrow we might need to bring down
a wolf so,
or a moose,
so I'll keep you out.
And it's sort of like they think that
because they don't know,
they don't think that they acted out as
a behavioral pattern.
Then if you're an anthropologist and
aura,
I'm not an ecologist and you went and
watched the wolves,
you'd say it's as if they were acting
according to the following rule.
And that often confused me because I
thought,
well,
the wolves,
wolves act out rules.
And I thought,
no,
no.
A rule is what we construct when we
articulate a behavioral pattern,
right?
We observe a stable behavioral pattern
and when we articulate it,
we can call it a rule,
but for the walls,
it's not a rule,
it's just a stable behavioral pattern.
And so we acted like wolf troops or
chimpanzee troops,
all of that as well.
And for for untold,
really untold tens and perhaps hundreds
of millions of years before we were able
to formulate that pattern of behavior in
anything approximating a story or an
image and an even longer before we could
articulate it as a set of,
of,
of ethical rules.
And I'm dwelling on this.
I know I've repeated this,
some of this before,
but it's so important because you know
there's this tremendous push,
especially from the social,
the social constructionists,
to make the case that ethics is
arbitrary and ethics or morality is
relative.
There's no fundamental biological
grounding in relationship to human
behavior,
especially in the,
in the category of ethics.
And I think that that's.
Well,
first of all,
it's dangerous because that means that
people are anything you want to turn
them into and you bloody well better be
careful of people who think that.
And second,
I just think that the evidence that
that's wrong is so overwhelming that we
should just stop thinking that way.
I mean the.
And that's partly why I'm also attacking
this from an evolutionary perspective.
There's lots of converging lines of
evidence that ethic ethical standards
of,
at least of the most of the most crucial
store sort not only evolved but also
spontaneously reemerge,
for example,
in the dramatic play of children.
So we need to take that seriously and
so,
well that's partly what we're doing
here.
Trying to take that seriously.
So
okay,
so the idea there,
at least in part was that the father
employed the sun to generate habitable
order out of chaos.
I also think there might be something
more approximately true about that as
well too,
because one of the things we do know,
here's something that's cool about men.
Men are much more criminal than women
and that by the way,
that does not look like it's
sociocultural,
partly because it peaks.
When testosterone kicks in around 14,
I could just spikes the hell up and then
it really,
it,
it stays pretty high until about 27.
And so standard peanut logical theory
for those of you who don't know this,
is that if you have a repeat offender,
you know a guy,
he just won't stop getting in trouble.
He has throw them in prison until he's
28 and it isn't like you're
rehabilitating and or anything.
It's like by 28 he's done with his
criminal career because the crime curve
is peaks at 15 and then falls down
around 27 or so.
It burns out and that's often,
by the way,
that's often,
that's.
That's often when men get married and
settle down and stabilize.
One of the things that's one of the
things that's cool about that is the
creativity curve for men and is almost
exactly the same thing.
It ramps up when testosterone kicks in
and then it starts to flatten out around
27 that the curves match very,
very closely so that.
So that's quite cool.
At least the creativity element of it
that I'm particularly interested in
because their creativity is in many ways
had attribute of youth and that's.
Look,
I mean
if you look at that sentence and you
stripped it of its religious context,
what you would say is that the older
people use the younger people to
generate creative ideas and renew the
world.
It's like,
yeah,
that's,
that's what happens.
And you know,
we also have no idea how many of the
things that we discovered or invented as
human beings,
we're stumbled across by children and
adolescents,
you know,
because they're,
well,
they're much more exploratory.
There are less constrained by their,
by their already extend knowledge
structures and they're less
conservative.
So yeah,
that seems right to me.
So right in an extraordinarily important
way,
[inaudible].
It also means that if,
like if you're an actual father,
one of the things that it means is that
that's part of what you should be
encouraging your son to do,
right?
Which is,
which is because the role of a father is
to encourage that is clearly the role.
And to encourage just to say,
well go out there,
confront the chaos of,
of the unknown and the chaos that
underlies everything and grappled with
it.
You know,
because you can do it.
You're as big as the chaos itself and
you know,
do something useful as a consequence and
make your life better and make everyone
else's life better.
And you know,
you can do it.
And Man,
that's the right thing to tell.
That's the right thing to tell.
Young men and talking to young women is
more complicated because they have more,
more let's say,
issues to deal with because their lives
are more complicated in some ways,
but that's definitely the right thing to
be to be telling your,
your son and one of the things that I've
really noticed recently since I've been
lecturing,
especially in the last seven or eight
months,
most of my audiences being young man and
and I've talked a lot of them too,
a lot.
I've talked a lot to them about both
truth and responsibility and I think
that those,
those are the two things that underlie
this capacity and it seems to me to be a
tremendous hunger for that idea.
It's not the same idea as rights,
you know,
it's a very different idea.
It's,
it's the counterpart to rights and so
it's,
you know,
life is hard.
It's chaotic,
it's difficult.
It's really definitely a challenge.
And so you can either shrink from that
and no bloody wonder because you know
what's going to kill you.
It's not,
it's no joke,
man,
or you can forthrightly confronted and
try to do something about it.
Well,
what's better?
And then you say to the person,
look man,
you could do it like that's what a human
being is like,
and if you just stood up and get
yourself together and you'd find out by
trying that,
you can in fact do that.
And I do think that that's,
that's a great core religious message as
far as I can tell and I think that's
deeply embedded in this sort of,
in this sort of idea.
So.
Alright,
so this is what I've been telling you.
This is something like how knowledge
itself is generated.
First of all,
there's the unknown as such,
and that's really what you don't know
anything about.
And generally when you encounter that
you don't encounter it with thought.
You encounter it like this,
right?
And that that's the first representation
of the absolutely unknown.
It's something that is beyond your
comprehension and it's terrifying and
because it's beyond your comprehension,
you cannot perceive it.
You can not understand it,
but you still have to deal with it.
And the way you deal with it is that you
freeze.
That's what the.
That's what a Bassa lisc does say to
the,
to the kids in Harry Potter,
right?
They take a look at it and they freeze.
That's the snake,
the terrible snake of chaos that leaves
underneath everything you see that that
thing freezes you,
and that's because you're a prey animal.
But at the same time it makes you
curious.
And so that's the first level of contact
with the absolute unknown is the
emotional combination of freezing and
curiosity.
And that's reflected,
I think in the dragon stories.
The dragon is the terrible thing that
lives underground the hordes gold or
hoards virgin.
Very,
very strange behavior for a reptile,
as we pointed out before.
But the idea is that it's a symbolic
representation of the predatory quality
of the unknown,
combined with the capacity of the
unknown to generate nothing but novel
information.
And it's very.
You can see that as very characteristic
of human beings because we are prey
animals,
but we're also unbelievably exploratory
and we're pretty damn good predators.
And we occupied this weird cognitive
niche.
And so one of the things we've learned
is that if we forthrightly confront the
unknown,
terrifying as it is,
there's a massive prize to be gained
continually.
And so that seems to be true,
right?
It's true as anything is.
And then I would also say that that
idea,
now we know that one of the metaphors
that underlies God's extraction of
habitable order out of chaos at the
beginning of time is an older idea and
more archaic idea that God confronted
something like the Leviathan.
That's one of the words for this
serpent,
like chaos creature that's often used in
the old testament or the a leviathan and
the Ba,
Bam off.
Yeah,
that's the other thing.
And so there's this idea that I think
came probably came from the
Mesopotamians that the god either in the
sunlight aspect or in the farther aspect
is the thing that confronts this
terrible beast that represents the
chaotic unknown and cuts it into pieces.
And then sometimes give the body parts
to the populace in order to feed them.
So you can see a hunting metaphor there
as well.
But it's deeper than that.
And so,
all right,
so,
so the first thing is that there's the
absolute unknown and the unknown is what
you do not understand.
It's what's beyond the campfire.
Maybe it's what's beyond the tree.
Even more anciently,
you know,
when we,
when we lived in trees,
it's out there,
they were,
you don't know,
and what's out there,
crocodiles and snakes and birds of prey
and cats and all sorts of things like
predatory cats and they will eat you,
but there's utility and going out there
to find out what's there.
Like maybe you go and you don't kill the
snake.
You killed the damn nest of snakes and
that makes you pretty popular just as
you should be,
not accelerates your,
your,
uh,
reproductive potential,
let's say.
And we're descended from people who did
that.
And so we have this notion about how the
world is structured,
this deeply embedded in our psyche,
like really,
really deeply,
way,
way down,
way below the surface cognition way down
in the limbic system.
And these ancient parts of the brain
that are like $60,
million years old or 100 million years
old or older than that.
Ancient,
ancient brain structures and so the
first thing we do is we act out our
encounter with the unknown world and we
act that out in the same way,
in a manner that's analogous to the
manor that's presented as a description
of what it is,
but God does at the beginning of time to
extract habitable order out of chaos and
and I,
I will tell you about the other part of
that for now.
So you act it out first.
And then the second thing is you watch
people who acted out and you start to
make representations of that.
That story's right and maybe you admire
them and then after a long time you
collect a bunch of those stories and
then you can say what that is.
You can articulate it as a pattern.
And so this is something needs shift
also figured out to begin with because
prior to Nisha I would say he did so
many things.
First it was quite remarkable.
You know,
there was an idea that you first think
and then you act and people like to
think that,
but of course you do it complete bloody
rubbish because you're in as impulsive
as you can possibly imagine.
You're always doing things before you
think and sometimes that's a really good
idea.
So the idea that you see things and then
think and then act,
it's like,
really?
No,
I'm sorry I don't do that.
No one I know I know does that.
And they certainly do that.
Don't do that.
When they're emotional,
you know,
you act first.
And one of the things that Nisha said
very clearly was that our ideas emerged
out of the ground of our action over
over thousands and thousands of years.
And then when philosophers were putting
forward those ideas,
what they were doing wasn't generating
creative ideas,
they were just telling the story of
humanity and it's already there.
It's already in us.
It's already in our patterns of
behavior.
And,
and it strikes me that that's.
Well,
he was a genius and that was one of the
genius,
one of his
many,
many observations of pure genius.
And so you can think about it,
you know,
you can think about it like this too,
is that there's the unknown and then you
act in the face of the unknown and then
you dream about the action and that's
what you're doing in a movie theater.
And then you speak about it.
And so,
you know,
and of course,
once you speak about it,
that effects how you dream and how you
dream affects how you act.
It's not like the,
all of the causal direction is,
is one way because it's not these things
loop,
but it's still from the unknown,
through the body,
through the imagination,
into articulation.
That's the primary mode of the
generation of,
of wisdom,
let's say.
And you can easily map that onto an
evolutionary explanation because the
body comes first,
right?
And they,
the imagination,
which is the body in abstraction and
only then the word.
And of course,
that's exactly how things did evolve
because we could imagine things long
before we could speak,
at least that's the theory.
So,
and I represented that this is a,
uh,
a image from my book maps of meaning.
And so,
so the idea is that this is the
fundamental representation of the
unknown as such,
it's half spirit because it partakes of
the air like a bird and it's half matter
because it's on the ground like a,
like a,
like a snake.
And,
and that's what you think is there when
you don't know what is there.
That's how your body reacts to what's
there.
When you don't know what is there,
you know that too.
Because if you're alone at night,
you know,
and maybe you're a little rattled up for
one reason,
another,
maybe you watched a horror movie and you
know there's some weird noise in the
other room.
It's dark and you can just try this one.
So it's like,
so you're on edge,
you think you want to turn the light on
and go in the room and see,
don't do that.
Just opened the door a little bit and
sneak your hand in and just watch what
your imagination fills that room with,
right?
And then,
then you remember what it's like to be
three years old in bed and afraid of the
dark.
Right?
And I read a good book on dragons
lately,
recently that,
that,
that had a very interesting hypothesis
about the bi thought.
One of the things the guy did was a
track,
I can't remember his name,
unfortunately track how common the image
of the dragon was worldwide.
It's unbelievably what?
Widespread.
It's crazily widespread.
And he thought that this was actually
the category of a primate Predator and
the Predator was.
So Predator is a weird category,
right?
Because like there's,
there's crocodiles in it and there's
lions and they don't have much in common
except they eat you.
So it's a functional category.
And so this is the,
this is the images stick representation
of the functional category of Predator.
And his Predator theory was,
well,
if you're a monkey than a bird would
pick you off like an eagle.
And so that's this.
Right?
And then if it wasn't illegal,
it was a cat because they clump cherry
trees and give you a good chomping.
And then if it wasn't a cat,
you go down to the ground and a snake
would get you.
Or maybe a snake would climb up the
tree.
Cause snakes.
Like do that and get you,
and so that's a.
that's a tree cat,
snake,
basically free cap,
snake bird,
and that's the thing.
You really,
that's the thing you really want to
avoid.
You don't want to come across one of
those and so.
And then the other thing it does is
breathe fire,
which is quite interesting because
obviously fire was both greatest friend
in greatest enemy of humanity and we've
mastered fire for a long time.
It might be as long as two or 3 billion
years.
That's what Richard Wrangham,
I think it's rang him.
He wrote a book recently on,
I think it was random who wrote a book
on when human beings learn to cook.
That was about 2 million years ago.
And cooking increase the increase the
availability of calories.
You know how chimpanzees are sort of
shaped like a big,
like they're ugly.
They're shaped like a big bowling ball.
You know,
they're really,
they look really fat and it's.
And they're short and they're wide and
that's because they have intestinal
tracts that are like 300 miles long.
And the reason for that is because they
have to digest leaves and so you go out
in the forest and like sit there and eat
leaves for a whole day and see how that
works out for you.
You know,
they have no calories in them.
So chimps spend to bite,
I think it was,
I think it's eight hours a day chewing
and it's because what they eat has no
nutritional value and then they have to
have this tremendous got to in order to
extract anything at all out of it.
And human beings at some point just
thought,
oh to hell with that,
we'll cook something.
And then we traded our gut for brain,
which,
you know,
more or less has worked and I think it's
made us a lot more attractive as well.
So.
Okay,
well,
so the idea here was that,
well that's the basic archetype of the
unknown as such.
And then I liked the St George version
of this.
It's so cool because St George,
it lives in a castle and the castle is
partly falling down.
And it's partly because there's a dragon
that's come up too,
like it's an eternal dragon.
It's come back to give her two in a
rough time,
which always happens because there is an
eternal dragon is always given,
giving our fallen down,
castle's a rough time.
Oh.
And so then St George is the hero who
goes out to confront the dragon and he
frees the virgin from its grasp.
And I would say that's a pretty
straightforward story about the sexual
attractiveness of the masculine spirit
that's willing to forthrightly encounter
the unknown.
That's.
It looks just straight.
It looks like a straight biological
representation to be.
And it's a really,
really old story,
right?
It's the oldest written story we have.
And that's basically the Mesopotamian
creation myth,
the Enuma Elish,
which,
which basically lays out precisely that
story.
And so,
and it's replayed,
I mean,
I bet you the movie goers among you,
especially the ones that are more
attracted to the superhero,
you know,
they're really flashy,
sort of superhero type movies.
You've probably seen the St George story
like 150 times in the last 10 years.
You never get tired of it because it's
the central story of mankind,
so you've got the unknown as such,
and that is what you react to with your
body.
Then in the existential terror and
extraordinary curiosity or gripping you,
and then it's like the unknown unknowns
that,
uh,
who's the politician under Bush
Rumsfeld.
Yeah.
I think the reason that that phrase
caught on so well is because he nailed
an archetype.
There's unknown unknowns and there's
known unknowns and the unknown unknown.
And you have to be able to react to an
unknown unknown because they can get you
and you can't just plead ignorance
because then your dad that doesn't work.
Like human beings are the sort of
creature who has to know what to do when
they don't know what to do.
And that's very paradoxical.
And what we do is we prepare to do
everything that's right.
We're on guard.
We prepared to do everything very,
very stressful and,
but also very engaging and very,
very much something that heightened
consciousness and maybe those circuits
are tr permanently turned on in human
beings because we also know that we're
going to die and no other animal knows
that.
And so sometimes I think that our,
that our stress circuits are just on all
the time and that's part of what
accounts for our heightened
consciousness.
So you have your unknown unknowns and
then you have your relatively,
you have the unknowns that you actually
encounter in the world,
like the mystery of your,
of your,
uh,
a romantic partner when you have a fight
with them.
It's like,
what?
We're having a fight?
Who the hell are you mean you're not the
absolute unknown because I know
something about you,
but you're the unknown as it's
manifesting itself to me right now.
Right?
And,
and,
and then there's the known that we
inhabit and then there's the knower.
And the known is given symbolic
representation as far as I've been able
to tell in patriarchal form,
in the form of a male deities.
And the unknown as you encountered is
given feminine form,
so we won't get into that too much,
but if you're interested in that,
you could look at my maps of meetings,
lectures,
or maybe take a look at the book.
But I think it's a good.
I think it's a good schema for religious
archetypes.
I've,
I've worked on a long time.
It seems to fit the union criteria quite
nicely.
It maps nicely on to Joseph Campbell's
ideas.
He got almost all his ideas from you,
however.
Um,
and it also makes sense from a
biological and evolutionary perspective
as far as I can tell that's a lot of
cross validation,
at least in my estimation.
So.
Okay.
So back to the hierarchy of dominance.
Well,
let's take a look at it a little bit.
So I'm quite enamored of lobsters as
some of you might know because I found
out this just blew me away when I found
it out.
I mean I've done a lot of work in
neurochemistry,
functional neurochemistry,
chemistry,
because I used to study alcoholism and
drug abuse and alcoholism to study
alcohol.
You have to know a lot about the brain
because alcohol goes to everywhere in
the brain.
It affects every neurochemical system
and so if you're going to study alcohol,
you kind of have to study neurochemistry
in general,
and so I did that for quite a long time.
I really got a narrative,
a book called the neuropsychology of
anxiety by Jeffrey Gray,
which is an absolute work of genius,
although extraordinary diff like it.
I don't know how many references that
book has.
It's like must be a thousand and gray
actually read them and worse he
understood them and then he and then he
integrated them into this book and so to
read it you have to really master
functional neurochemistry and animal
behaviorism and and motivation and
emotion and neuroanatomy like it's a
killer book,
but man,
it's really rich and it's taken
psychologists about 40 years to really
unpack that book,
but one of the things I learned about
that was just exactly how much
continuity there was in the
neurochemistry of human beings and the
neurochemistry of animals.
It's absolutely staggering.
It's,
it's the sort of thing that makes the
fact of evolution.
Something like self evident.
I do think it's self evident for other
reasons that I'll,
I'll tell you about later.
I think evolution or I think natural
selection,
random mutation and natural selection is
the only way you can solve the problem
of how to deal with an environment
that's complex beyond your ability to
comprehend.
I think what you do is you generate
endless variants because God only knows
what the Hell is gonna happen next.
They own almost all of them die because
their failures and a couple of propagate
and you know,
the environment keeps moving around like
a giant snake.
You never know what it's going to do
next.
And so the best you can do is say,
well,
here's 30 things that might work and you
know,
28 of them are going to perish.
Or if you're.
Or if you're an insect,
it's like the ratio is way,
way higher than that.
So anyways,
back to the lobsters and all of these.
So these creatures engaging in dominance
disputes and,
and I think dominance is the right way
to think about it because lobsters
aren't very empathic and they're not
very social.
And so it really is the toughest lobster
that wins,
you know,
and what's so cool about the lobster is
that when,
when a lobster winds,
he flexes and gets bigger,
so he looks bigger because he's a
winner.
It's like he's advertising that in the
biological,
the neurochemical system that makes him
flex is Sarah to Nirjah and you think,
well,
who cares?
What the hell does that mean?
Well,
tell you what it means.
It's the same chemical that's affected
by antidepressants and human beings.
And so like,
if you're depressed,
you're defeated lobster.
Like you're like this.
I'm small,
I'm not,
you know,
things are dangerous.
I don't want to fight.
You give someone a united depressants
like cup,
they stretch and then they're ready to
like take on the world again.
Well,
if you give lobsters who just got
defeated in a fight,
Serotonin,
then they stretch out and they'll fight
again.
And that's like we separated from those
creatures on the evolutionary timescale.
Somewhere between 350 and 600 million
years ago and the damn neurochemistry is
the same,
and so that's another indication of just
how important hierarchies of authority
are.
I mean,
they've been conserved since the time of
lobsters,
right?
There were trees around with lobsters
first first manifested themselves on the
planet.
And so what that means is these
hierarchies that I've been talking
about,
those things are older than trees.
And so one of the truisms for what
constitutes real from a Darwinian
perspective is that,
which has been around the longest period
of time,
right?
Because it's had the longest period of
time to exert selection pressure.
Well,
we know we evolved and lived in trees,
something on the order of 60 million
years ago.
We're talking 10 times as far back as
that for the hierarchy.
And so the idea that human beings that
the hierarchy is something that has
exerted selection pressure on human
beings is I don't think that's a
disputable.
That's not a disputable issue.
How it's done at an exactly what that
means we can argue about,
but like that sort of biological
continuity is just absolutely
unbelievable.
I,
it was funny because I revealed this
finding,
you know,
I didn't discover this,
I read about it,
but I talked to my graduate students
about it.
I used to take them out for breakfast,
you know,
and they were very contentious,
snappy bunch and uh,
and they're always trying to one up each
other and they were quite witty and for
like six months until it got very
annoying.
Every time one of them went up the
other,
they'd stretch themselves out,
like snap their hands.
Like.
So that was,
that was very funny.
It was,
it was really very funny.
So you'll see this in lobsters.
And so that's pretty amazing.
So,
you know,
and one of the other thing that's really
cool about lobsters is that,
um,
let's say you've been like top lobster
for a long time,
but you're getting kind of old and some
young lobster just,
you know,
whales the hell out of you.
And so you're all depressed,
but thing is your brain is dominant,
but you don't have much of a brain
because you're a lobster.
And so now what are you going to do?
Because you just lost.
And the answer is while your brain will
dissolve and then you'll grow a
subordinate brain.
Yeah.
And so that's where thinking about too
right here for a couple of reasons.
First of all,
if any of you who've ever been seriously
defeated in life,
you know what that's like.
It's like it's a death,
a descent,
a dissolution,
and if you're lucky,
a regrowth and and maybe not as the same
person,
that's what happens to people with
posttraumatic stress disorder,
right?
Their brains undergo permanent
neurological transformation and,
and they then inhabit a world that's
much more dangerous than the world that
they inhabited to begin with.
But we also know too,
if you have posttraumatic stress
disorder or depression,
that your hippocampus shrinks or he dies
and shrinks and you can sometimes get it
to grow back.
Your hippocampus shrinks and your
amygdala grows and the Amygdala
increases emotional sensitivity and the
hippocampus inhibits emotional
sensitivity.
And so if you've been badly defeated,
the hippocampus shrinks and the amygdala
grows.
Now if you recover,
the hippocampus will regrow.
And antidepressants actually seemed to
help that.
But the damn Amygdala never shrinks
again.
And so well.
So that's another lesson from the
lobster.
It's quite a terrifying one,
but,
but it's one like,
it's so interesting that you can relate
to that.
Right now.
It's like I get what that poor
crustaceans going through.
No.
So,
okay,
here's the rats and this is from Yak
Panksepp's work,
right?
He was the first guy who figured out
that rats giggle
and you might think,
well,
what kind of stupid thing is that to
study?
It's like $50,000
research grant giggling rats,
you know?
And so.
But he discovered the place circuitry
and mammals.
That's a big deal,
right?
It's like discovering a whole new
continent.
There's a place circuit in mammals.
It's built right in.
So it's not socially constructed.
There's a,
there's a biological platform for that.
And so what?
What,
what panksepp would do with rats,
he found out if rats,
if you take a rat pup away from its
mother,
it dies.
Even if you feed it,
even if it keep it warm,
it dies.
Now you can stop it from dying by taking
a pencil with an eraser on the end and
massaging it right?
Because rats won't live without love and
the same thing happens to human babies,
and we saw that in Romania when there
was that catastrophe after Cho Chesko in
the orphanages were the orphanages were
full of unwanted babies because
Ceausescu insisted that every Romanian
women was constantly pregnant,
so the orphanage just stacked up with
unwanted babies and lots of them didn't
even have names and they were
warehoused.
Warmth,
shelter,
food,
devastating.
Lots of them died.
Most of them died before the first year
and the ones that didn't die,
we're permanently dysfunctional because
you have to be touched.
If you're a human being,
it's not an option you have to be played
with.
It's not an option.
It's part of neurodevelopmental
necessity.
And,
and you have to also play fair,
so because otherwise you produce a very
disjointed child who isn't able to
engage in the niceties of social
interaction,
which is continual play in some sense in
reciprocity.
So what Panksepp did with his wrath,
he noticed the male rats,
juveniles really liked to wrestle and
they wrestle just like humans beings
wrestle.
They pin each other for crying out loud.
It's like that,
that have just lost,
he's down for a 10 count,
right?
And so,
so what you do is you take juvenile
routes and you can find out that they
want to play because you can attach a
spring to them and then they'll try to
run and you can measure how hard they're
running by,
how hard they're pulling on the spring
and then you can estimate how motivated
they are.
And so you can find out that a nice,
well fed rat who doesn't have anything
on his mind was still work hard to play
if it,
to enter an arena where he's been
allowed to play before,
he'll work for that.
So that you think while the rats
motivated.
So the two rats go out there and they
play and,
and so they're,
they're playing like dogs play and
everyone knows what that looks like.
If you're,
you know,
if you have any sense about dogs that
kind of go like this and kids do that
and maybe you do that with your wife if
you're going to play with her a little
bit.
My poor wife man,
when she,
she was,
uh,
she was uh,
a young,
she had older siblings and so she wasn't
played with as much when she was little,
as she might've been in,
um,
I used to like,
you know,
if you take a pillow and he'd go like
this three times,
right.
That means lookout,
a pillow is coming your way.
So I go one,
two,
three.
Wow.
She,
she looked,
she was completely dismayed at and he's
like,
what do you do that for?
And I thought,
well,
I eventually tartar that rule.
The other thing I used to,
yeah,
the other thing I used to do,
you know,
is sometimes she'd come out and be like
this when we were playing around and I
grabbed her wrist and I know Parker her
hands through her knuckles together and
she used to just get completely annoyed
about that and I thought that's what you
do.
You just open your hands.
While she didn't know that either.
So she hadn't been played with enough
when she was a little rat.
So
anyways.
Anyways,
so you let the wrap the little rats go
out there.
Right.
And so let's imagine one of them is 10
percent bigger than the other,
and so that the 10 percent bigger wins
because 10 percent is enough in route
wait to ensure that you're going to be
the pinner rather than the pity.
Okay?
So.
So that's fine.
So when the rat,
the rat pins the pins,
the little route and now the big rat is
the is the authority rat.
And so then the next time that the rats
play,
the little rat has to invite the big rat
to play.
So the big rats out there being cool and
the little rat pops up and you know,
does the whole will you play with me
thing?
And the big rat will deign to play with
them.
But if you pair them repeatedly,
unless the big rat lets the little rat
win,
30 percent of the time the little rack
will not invite him to play.
And panksepp discovered that.
It's like,
I read that.
That just blew me away.
It's like,
that is so amazing because you see walls
first of there.
There's an analogy to Piaget's ideas
about the emergence of morality out of
play in human beings,
so that was very cool,
but the notion that that was built into
rats at the level of wrestling was,
and they're social,
they're deeply social animals,
right?
They have to know how to get along with
one another and most of their authority
disputes,
dominance disputes.
You don't want them to end in bloodshed
and combat because you know,
if you're a rat one and I'm rat to and
we tear each other just threat shreds
and the dominance dispute.
Rats three is just going to move in.
It's really not a great strategy and so
it'd be better if we could settle our
differences,
you know,
somewhat peacefully and so.
Wow.
So rats.
Anyways,
panksepp figured out that rats plan,
not only do they play,
they play fair and they seem to enjoy
it.
He also figured out,
this was really cool too,
that if you give juvenile rats,
attention deficit disorder drugs,
Ritalin suppresses,
pray,
play.
So that's worth thinking about.
It's like,
well,
why do you have to give juvenile human
beings amphetamines in school?
Well,
because they need to play.
Well you don't,
you don't get to play.
They don't get to wrestle around.
I mean,
that's oppression as far as I can tell.
They don't get to wrestle around.
That's fine.
Feed him some amphetamines,
man.
That'll shut down the old place
circuits.
Well,
here's the other problem is Panksepp
found out that if you don't let juvenile
male rats play their prefrontal cortexes
don't develop properly.
Surprise,
surprise.
You're not letting them mature.
It's like,
what else would you expect?
So you know,
that's something to think about really
hard.
I would say so.
Well also there's some wolves going at
it and we're not exactly.
There are some wolves having authority
dispute,
but more technically speaking and a lot
of it's posturing.
You know,
they,
they tend,
they tend not.
Well socialized wolves tend not to hurt
each other during the authority disputes
because,
well for obvious reasons it's too
dangerous.
And so they have other ways of
demonstrating who should be listened to
authorities and there's chimps doing and
now this particular,
I think if I remember correctly,
I think it's right.
This is a really cool picture because I
think this chimp chimps don't like
snakes by the way.
So for example,
if you take a chimp that's never seen a
snake and you showed a snake,
it is not happy,
it will get the hell away from that
snake.
If you bring a chimp anesthetized into a
room full of chimps,
chimps,
we'll all get away from that.
And then look at the body.
They don't,
they don't like that either.
And if you bring a big snake into a
chimp cage,
even if the chimps have never seen it,
like they'll get away from it and then
stare at it.
And chimps out in the wild,
if they see a big snake,
they'll,
they'll stand there and they have a
noise that means something like,
holy crap,
that's a big steak,
you know?
Um,
it actually means that technically,
I'll tell you why in a minute.
I'm a.
But they get,
they stand away from it.
And then they make this,
this noise,
which means,
oh my God,
look at the snake.
And then they'll stand there for like 24
hours looking at the snake.
And so the snakes are really,
really,
they're super stimuli for chimpanzees.
So that's pretty interesting in this
champ theme to learn how to take a dead
snake and goes,
she's scare other chips with it.
And that was,
that was partly how he established
authority and you know,
and while there there's a,
there's a,
there's a threat to you,
like if I was you and I was around that
chip,
I would take that threat seriously
because those things are no joke man.
And you see the same thing here with
the,
I don't remember what kind of monkey
that is,
but they're engaged in agonistic
behavior.
And so,
so.
And there has been,
by the way,
there has been recent research showing
that in higher order primates that there
is snake detection circuitry that's
built into them.
Right?
So it's not learned,
not learned steeper than that.
Now,
for a long time,
psychologists,
psychologist knew for a long time that I
could make you afraid in a conditioning
experience,
experiment much faster using a snake or
a picture of a snake than a gun or a
picture of a gun.
So we can learn fear to snakes very
rapidly,
spiders as well.
And so then people thought,
well,
maybe we were prepared to develop fear
of snakes or spiders,
that sort of thing.
But the more recent research has
indicated that it's more than just
prepared,
is that we have the detection circuitry
built right into us.
And that well is because,
well,
why wouldn't we?
That's,
that's really the issue.
It's like,
it's not really that much of a surprise
unless you think of human beings as a
blank slate.
And if you think that,
then,
um,
I don't know,
you should crawl out of the 16th
century.
That's how I would look at it because I
mean,
that's,
that's just gone,
that idea.
It's,
it's,
it's so wrong.
So,
so maybe you can think about this as a
dominance hierarchy,
but wolves,
look for wolves,
look for credibility and competence as
well.
And,
and chimpanzees don't like brutal
tyrants and so we'll talk about it as
the hierarchy of authority.
And so while this is kind of how it,
it starts to develop,
you know,
who you see.
Well,
these girls are negotiating the domestic
environment here and how to behave
properly and how to share and all that
and and take turns and so they're
negotiating the hierarchy of authority
and if you're good at reciprocity at
sometimes you're the authority and
sometimes the other person is the
authority.
That's fair play.
Right?
And so these boys are doing the same
thing and you see they're all smiling
away and so it looks like aggressive
behavior and people who are not very
attentive and who are paranoid and who
don't like human beings can confuse this
with aggression and they forbid it at
schools,
which is,
you know,
I know it wouldn't.
When my kids were going to school,
for example,
this was quite awhile ago now,
they were forbidden to pick up snow on
the off chance.
They might throw a snowball and we know
how terrible that is.
So what I told my son was is that he was
perfectly welcome to pelt any teacher he
wanted to in the back of the head with a
snowball,
as long as he was willing to suffer the
consequences of doing it.
And I don't know if he ever did,
but he was happy,
he was certainly happy with the idea
which may be very happy about him.
So yeah,
so,
so you know,
kids need to do this,
they really,
really seriously need to do this.
It's what civilizes them and they know
that needs to happen between the ages of
two and four because if they're not
civilized by the time,
therefore then you might as well just
forget it.
And that's a,
that's a horrible statistic.
But it's unbelievably well born out in
the relevant developmental literature.
Like there's lots of aggressive two year
olds,
most of them are male and if they stay
aggressive past the age of four,
they tend to be lifetime aggressive.
They make no friends,
they're outcasts,
they're much more likely to end up anti
social,
criminal delinquent and in jail.
And so your kids need to be socialized
between the ages of two and four.
And that's particularly true for the
more aggressive males.
And most of them are aggressive.
Two year olds are male and that isn't
socialization by the way.
So there's more,
you know,
more abstract representation of the same
sort of thing and I'm,
I'm trying to make the case that this,
that the,
that the hierarchy of authority emerges
out of a game like Matrix and underlying
game like Matrix.
And that's one of the things that is one
of the things that's so brilliant about
John Piaget,
he figured that out,
it's so smart and he was interested in
the biological origin of morality and he
identified he,
he,
he traced the origin to play and the
emergence of morality out of play and
it's so,
it's just,
I just can't believe how smart an idea
that was because it's the bottom up
construction of,
of,
of morality don't.
Piaget was a constructionist and to some
degree of social constructionist,
he underestimated the role of biology,
but that doesn't invalidate his theory.
It's really easy to put a biological
underpinning underneath,
underneath Piaget's theory.
We know the biology well enough to do it
quite quite nicely now.
So I mean we.
Well the fact that Panksepp for example,
could identify the play circuit is a
really good start with that,
right?
Because play has been around so long
that we have a circuit that's dedicated
to it and so that's,
that's a very,
very ancient.
That's a very ancient issue and so you
know,
this is,
this is very much of an abstraction of a
game here and then of course you get the
ultimate abstraction and representation
in a representation like
like that where
even the,
even the landscape of the game is
fictional and of course we've migrated
to a large degree into those sorts of
fiction landscapes,
fictional books,
movies,
video games.
So it's the same.
It's an extension of the same thing.
So practice for practice,
for real life.
The shades in some cases into real life
itself.
So.
Alright,
more representations of God the father.
I liked these representations.
I like the triangle idea.
I mean I don't know why God is wearing a
triangular hat.
It's kind of a strange fashion choice,
but I think it's associated with the
idea of the pyramid and I think that's
associated with the idea of the
hierarchy of authority.
And I think that's why the Egyptians put
their pharaohs inside pyramids.
I know there's more to it than that,
but I think some of that has to do with
the notion of this hierarchical
structure and you see this on the now
that's speculative obviously,
and I don't want to make too much of it,
but.
But I can't help but think that there's
something to that through that.
On the back of the American dollar bill,
I liked that a lot.
That's like the eye of horus from the
Egyptians and so the idea here is
something like at the top of the
hierarchy is something that is no longer
part of the hierarchy.
Right?
So if you move up the hierarchy enough,
what happens is that you develop the
ability as a consequence of moving up
that hierarchy to be detached enough
from the hierarchy so you're no longer
really part of it and so that you can
move in all sorts of different
hierarchies.
And the thing,
the idea here is that the thing that
you're really developing is the capacity
to pay attention.
And I would say from a,
from a mythological perspective,
the one thing that seems to compete with
the idea of the spoken word as the,
as the source of the extraction of
habitable order from chaos is the eye is
the capacity to pay attention.
So Martin,
for example,
the Mesopotamian Creator,
God who,
who,
who emerged in the hierarchy of
Mesopotamian gods and came out at the
top right,
he was the victor of the gods.
He had eyes all the way around his head
and he could speak magic words.
And I really liked that.
I really liked that idea.
And Egyptians developed that idea too
because they're god.
Horus was the eye.
Everyone knows the eye of horus that,
that that image is so compelling that we
still know about.
Everybody has seen the eye of horus with
a really open pupil.
And what the Egyptians learned was that
the open I was,
what revivified the dead society.
It's so smart.
So what do you do if your life isn't in
order?
Bloody well pay attention.
And that isn't the same as thinking.
It's a different process.
Paying attention,
thinking is like the imposition of
structure in some sense.
I know I'm over simplifying,
but paying attention to something like
watching for what you don't know and so
like one of the things that I often
recommend to my clinical clients if
they're having trouble with a family
member is number one,
shut up.
Don't tell them anything about yourself.
Just and I don't mean in a rude way.
It's just like no more personal
information.
Number two,
watch them like a hawk and listen,
and if you do that long enough,
they will tell you exactly what they're
up to and they will also tell you who
they think you are and then you'll be
shocked because they think you're
something.
Generally speaking.
That's not like what you are at all and
when they tell you,
it's like a revelation to both of you,
but attention is an unbelievably
powerful for us and you see this in
psychotherapy to because a lot of what
you do and in any repairative
relationship is really pay attention to
the other person.
Pay attention and listen,
and you would not believe what people
will tell you or revealed to you if you
watch them as if you want to know
instead of watching them so that you'll
have your prejudices reinforced.
That's usually how people interact.
It's like,
I want to keep thinking about you the
way I'm thinking about you and so I'm
going to filter out anything that just
proves my theory now.
It's not what I'm talking about at all.
It's like I'm gonna Watch you and figure
out what you're up to.
Not in a rude way.
None of that.
I just want to see what's there and
that'll be good for you probably and
also be good for me.
And so well.
So that's the idea that,
you know,
climbing up a hierarchy of authority can
give you vision and that vision can
transcend the actual hierarchy.
And I think that's also the.
I think that's also the,
uh,
that's the metaphysical space that an
artist occupies because artists really
aren't in a hierarchy there outside of
hierarchies.
You've watched the lion king,
most of you.
Yeah.
That's a zoo.
You know the little bird.
That's the eye of the king and it's the
same thing there.
So and that's,
that's echoed in this idea as well,
so,
so well that some more,
more ideas of hierarchy.
Same idea.
This is great.
Gold,
silver,
bronze.
Why gold gold is the sun.
Gold is pure,
right?
And so the idea is that the thing that's
at the top of the hierarchy is
incorruptible because gold doesn't mix
with anything else,
right?
It's this sort of metal that doesn't
ever become corrupted.
It's a noble metal,
it doesn't become corrupted and so it
shines like the sun and it's associated
with what's ever at the top of the
hierarchy and the gold,
the medal is a disc like the sun and
it's awarded to those people who've,
who've occupied the top position and who
are manifestations of the ideal.
And here here's,
here's,
I got to tell you a quick story.
So imagine that you're watching.
And Olympic contest.
I found this happens to me very often
with gymnastics because the gymnast or
so,
absolutely unbelievable.
You know,
so you go watch a gymnastic performance
and the person's out there bouncing
around like,
you know,
you can't even imagine doing it.
There are so perfect at it.
So you see this person,
they're going through this routine.
They're just absolutely spectacular and
flawless at it.
You know,
at the end they stop and everybody claps
and they were all excited to see what a
human being can do and that's why we're
in the audience watching because we want
to see what a human being can do.
And the judges go like nine point eight,
nine point eight,
nine point eight.
Everybody's thrilled.
And then the next contestant comes out
and it's like,
well,
they're just basically screwed,
right?
It's like this person came out there and
was perfect.
How are you going to top that?
That's an interesting question because
this is a representation of what you do
to top perfection itself and you can do
it and here's how you do it and you know
this even though you don't know you know
it.
So let's say the next contestant comes
out and they're kind of shaky because
it's like,
oh man,
the bar has been raised high.
So what they do is they put themselves
right on the edge of chaos and you can
tell by watching them that they are one
bloody fraction of a second from
catastrophe.
There are pushing themselves farther
than they've ever gone in the direction
of their perfection.
And everyone in the room is so tense,
they can hardly stand it,
right?
You could hear a pin drop and that
person is flipping around and they're
just,
it's just right on the edge of
catastrophe.
And at the end they go like this,
you know?
And there's that gesture that the
triumph that goes along with that and
everybody rises in one instant and just
collapsed,
like mad.
It's like,
well,
why?
What are you doing?
What are you doing when you're doing
that?
Right?
You can't even help it.
It grabs you right in the core of your
being and you stand up and it's an act
of worship.
That's what it is.
And you saw someone go beyond their
perfection into the domain of chaos and
establish order right in front of your
eyes and you're so thrilled about that.
You know you're happy to be alive and
everyone's celebrating it all at the
same time and it's an absolutely amazing
thing.
And that's what,
well,
sometimes that's what this represents.
And sometimes that's what this
represents and that's what we're trying
to get at that because that's the
pinnacle of the hierarchy,
right?
Not only are you doing what you should
be doing,
but you're doing it in a way that
increases the probability that you'll do
it better the next time you do it,
and then you could say,
here's another thing to think about
along the same lines,
and I know we haven't got Adam and eve
yet.
You tell your kids to play fair,
right?
You say it's not him.
It's not whether or not you win.
It's how you play the game and you say
that you don't really know what you
mean.
You feel kind of stupid saying it even
though you know it's true and your kid
looks at you like there's something
wrong with you because he doesn't know
what you're talking about either,
but you know it's true,
and so here's why.
It's true.
Life isn't a game.
It's a set of games and the rule is
never sacrificed victory across the set
of games for victory in one game.
Right?
And that's what it means to play
properly.
You want to play so that people keep
inviting you to play because that's how
you win,
right?
You win by being invited to play the
largest possible array of games and the
way you do that is by manifesting the
fact that you can play in a reciprocal
manner every time you play,
even if there's victory at stake and
that's what makes you successful across
time.
And we all know that and we even tell
our kids that,
but we don't know that we know it.
And so we're not adapting ourselves to
the game and victory in the game.
We're adapting ourselves to the metagame
and victory across the set of all
possible games.
And that's what that.
Well,
that's exactly what,
as far as I can tell,
that's exactly what this is aiming at to
that.
That's the same idea that there's,
that there's a transcendent,
there's a mode of being that transcends
the particularities of this,
of the localized contest.
That's the other way to think about it.
And to act morally is not to win today's
contest at the expense of the rest of
possible contests.
And again,
I don't see that as something that's
arbitrary.
It's not relativistic.
There's an absolute moral does an
absolute moral stance there and everyone
recognizes it.
And,
and I also think it's the key to
success.
And I would also say it's very much a,
in his strange way,
like the,
uh,
the,
the person who is the master at being
invited to play the largest possible
games,
number of games is also the same person
I haven't quite figured out.
The precise relationship between these
two is also the same person that goes
out forthrightly to conquer the unknown
before it presents itself as the enemy
at the door.
They're the same thing.
Now I don't,
I can't have,
haven't figured,
well why that is exactly,
but,
but well,
I'll figure it out eventually when I do.
I'll tell you if you're interested,
so okay,
so here's some other ideas of,
of,
of God as,
as,
as hierarchical authority figure.
So strip the religious preconceptions
off what you observe and just look at
what you see.
Well look,
there's primate looking upward at
dominant figure that that's what you see
there.
Now it's very interestingly symbolically
represented because you have God the
father there with the cross and I think
what that means as far as I can tell is
that there's a recognition there in the
image that the person who's most
dominant is the one who's or the most
has the most authority,
is the one who's voluntarily accepted
the suffering.
That's part of being and that's what
that picture represents.
It's like the authority holes that says
this is what you have to accept and
that,
that transfixed as the viewer because
of,
because of the fact that it's true and
you think,
well,
is that true?
Okay,
well think about it this way.
Do you like brave people or do you like
cowards?
Well,
that that's pretty straightforward and
what's the ultimate act of bravery.
It's to come to terms with the fact that
you're mortal and limited and to live
forthrightly regardless.
Well,
obviously that's at the core of what's
of what's admirable and why would we
presume that that's not the case.
We act as if that's the case.
It's what everyone dreams and wishes
that they could.
They could do.
I mean assuming that you know,
you've dispensed with the idea that
you're going to be a mortal,
I suppose that might be worth wishing
for it to or or perhaps not immortal is
a very long time,
but you certainly want this and that
image says,
well,
this is what you should be and you know,
we've got that same opening into the sky
going on in that image that I showed you
before.
It's like this is a transcendent truth.
It constantly,
we manifest self across time and space
and young would say it's built into your
psyche that image.
Now you know,
there are elements of it that are
culturally constructed.
It wouldn't necessarily have to be the
cross,
although the cross is a very old symbol.
It's far older than than its use in
Christianity and it's been used in many,
many religious representations,
but that echoes the sole echoes with
that
no and
well,
and then there's Moses on the mountain
receiving the,
the,
the law.
And so we'll talk a lot more about that
when we get the exodus.
But if.
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
If we get to exodus,
so.
Well look,
where does it happen?
Well,
on a mountain.
Well that's a pyramid.
That's op,
right?
That's off the top.
It's up in the stratosphere,
it's up in the sky.
We're where you'll look upward.
Okay.
And then so what's happening to Moses?
Well,
here,
here's a bit of a clue as far as I can
tell.
I figured this out partly again by
reading jumped piaget,
because one of the things that Piaget
said about kids was that they first
learned to play a game,
but they don't know what the rules are.
Meaning that if you have a bunch of kids
together,
they can play a game,
but if you take one of the kids out of
the game when they're young,
say six and you say what the rules are,
what are the rules,
they can only sort of give you a
representation so you take 60 year old
one and he'll tell you some of the rules
and six year old to will tell you
different rules and and you know,
six year old three will tell you
different rules,
but if you put them all together they
can play.
So they have the knowledge embodied
either individually or in the group.
The knowledge is there to be extracted.
Well then they get a little older,
they can extract the rules and then they
start to play by the rules.
And then the last step was,
well it isn't just the kids play by the
rules,
is that they learned that they can make
the rules and he thought about that as
moral progression.
First you can play,
then you can play by the rules.
Then you learn maybe because he didn't
think everyone learned this,
that you're actually the master of the
rules.
That doesn't mean the rules are
arbitrary,
but it means that you can be the
generator of the rules assuming you knew
how to play the game,
and he thought about that as a moral
moral progression and then I thought,
well that's exactly what happened to
Moses and in the story of exodus,
because Moses is out there leading all
those Israelites around and like they
don't have a law,
they don't have a law giver.
They have a tradition and they're all
like crabby because while they're in a
desert,
it's like they were in a tyranny,
but now they're in a desert.
It's like that's no improvement.
So they're really getting pretty bitchy
about it and so they're worshiping false
idols and having one catastrophe after
another and they get Moses to judge
their conflicts and so he does that for
God only knows how long forever crabby
Israelites come to Moses and bitch at
them.
It's like,
wow,
he did this and she did that and and so
then he has to figure out how to make
peace and he does that so long that one
of his,
I think it's his father in law,
tells him he has to stop doing it
because he's gonna exhaust himself.
Well then you think,
well,
what's happening?
Well,
and I'm not assuming that this is a like
a literal historical story.
I think again,
it's a condensation well,
any group has a set of customs just like
a wolf pack does,
and so then the customers are being
manifest in someone who's a genius is
watching and thinking,
okay,
well what's the rule in this situation?
What's the rule of this situation?
What's the rule in this situation?
And then in his imagination,
the rules turned into a hierarchy and
then he goes up on the mountain and it
goes bang,
and he thinks,
oh my God,
here's the rules that we've been living
by all this time.
And that's the revelation of the
commandments.
Well,
and you think,
well,
how else could it be?
I think that rules came first and
obeying them came second.
So like know the rules come first,
sorry,
the actions come first,
the the old obeying them comes first and
then you figure out what everybody's up
to and you say,
hey look,
this is what you've been up to all
along.
And everybody goes,
Oh yeah,
that seems to make sense.
And if it didn't,
who would follow them?
No one was going to follow them.
If they don't match what's already
there,
you just think about that is unjust and
so that's,
that's portrayed here as a cataclysmic
human event.
It's like,
Oh my God,
we've been chimpanzees.
We've been in this hierarchy of
authority for so long.
We have no idea what we were doing and
all of a sudden poof.
It burst into revelatory consciousness
and we could say,
here is the law.
And you say,
well,
is it given by God?
Well,
hey,
it depends on what you mean by God.
We could start with that presupposition,
but it's not like it just came out of
nowhere.
It took.
And this is something else nature
observed.
So interestingly,
and he said,
you know that a moral revelation was the
consequence of a tremendously long
process of initial construction and then
formulation thousands and thousands and
thousands and thousands of years of
custom of building custom before you get
the revelation of the articulated law
and that's a description of the pattern
that works and let's say,
well,
what's the pattern that works?
It's the game that you can with
everybody else day after day with no
degeneration and that's another thing
piaget figured out.
That's so brilliant and that's his idea
of the equilibrated state.
It's,
it's an extension of a manual counts
idea about the universal maximum right
act in a way so that each action could
become a universal rule.
That was fundamental moral maximum.
And Piaget put a twist on that.
He said,
no,
that's not exactly yet.
It's act in such a way that it works for
you now and next week and next month and
next year and 10 years from now,
and so that while it's working for you,
it's also working for the people around
you and for the broader society and,
and,
and that's the braided state and you
could think about that as an intimation
of the Kingdom of the city,
of God on earth.
It's something like that and it's based
on this idea that a morality has to be
interoperable and you know,
there's lots of,
there's been lots of simulations online
already,
artificial intelligence,
simulations of trading gapes,
right?
I mean,
the people who've been studying the
emergence of moral behavior say an
artificial intelligence systems have
already caught onto the idea that one of
the crucial elements to the analysis of
morality is interability.
You can't play a degenerating game
because.
Because it degenerates,
like obviously you want to play a game
that had least remained stable across
time and God,
if you could really get your act
together,
maybe it would slowly get better.
And of course that's what you'd hope for
your family.
Right?
That's what you're always trying to do
and let,
unless you're completely hell bent on
revenge and destruction.
It's like,
is there a way that we can continue to
play together that will make playing
together even better the next day?
That's what you're up to and
well,
I don't see anything arbitrary both that
and part of it,
and this is also why I think that bloody
postmodernists are so incorrect because
you know,
they say something like there's an
infinite number of interpretations of
the world and that's actually true,
but then they make a mistake and they
say,
well no interpretation is to be
privileged over any other
interpretation.
It's like wrong,
wrong.
That's,
that's where things go seriously off the
rails because the interpretation has to
be,
and this is the psg and objection is
like if you and I are going to play a
game.
Rule one is we both have to want to
play.
Rule two is other people are going to
let us play.
Rule three is we should be able to play
it across a pretty long period of time
without it degenerating and maybe rule
four is,
well,
we're playing,
the world shouldn't kill us.
It's like there are not very many games
like you don't send your kids out to
play on the super highway.
Right?
So they're not playing hockey on the
superhighway because the world kills
them and so there there's an infinite
number of interpretations,
but there is not an infinite number of
solutions and the solutions are
constrained by the fact of the world and
are suffering in the world and then also
constrained by the fact that we
constrain each other.
And so that's,
that's where I think that's gone
dreadfully,
dreadfully wrong.
So.
All right,
it's really fun to look at these old
pictures once you kind of know what they
mean.
You know,
the delayed.
At least that's what I've discovered is
that once I kind of understand the
underlying rationale for.
I mean someone worked hard on that.
That's an engraving,
right?
They took a long time.
Making that picture there are serious
about it and when you understand what it
means,
you know,
all those people there,
their prostate,
prostrate at the,
um,
at the,
at the revelation of the law.
It's like,
well,
no wonder it's like break the law and
see what happens.
Break the universal moral law man and
You know,
I see people in that situation.
We'll ask you all,
do all the time perhaps me more than you
because I'm a clinical psychologist,
you know,
and if the people I'm seeing having
broken the universal law,
then you can bloody well be sure that
people around them have.
It's no joke,
like you make a mistake and things will
go seriously wrong for you.
And so it's no wonder that you'd be
terrified at the revelation of the
structure that governs our big.
One of the things that's so remarkable
about the old testament,
this is another thing,
nature commented or he was a real
admirer of the Old Testament,
not so much of the New Testament.
He thought it was a sin for Europe to
have glued the new testament onto the
old testament because he thought the old
testament was a really accurate
representation of the phenomenology of
Ba.
It's like stay awake,
speak property,
be honest or watch the hell out because
things will come your way that you just
do not want to see at all and it might
not just be you.
It might be everyone you know in
everything about your culture that is
demolished for,
for generation after generation.
It's like stay awake and be careful.
And I like.
I think that people only don't believe
that when they're being hubris stick.
And I think that most people know that
deep in their hearts.
You know when you get high on your
horse,
that happens fairly often.
If you have any sense,
you think,
Geez,
I better be careful.
Tap myself down a fair bit because if I
get too puffed up,
man,
something's going to come along and take
me out at the knees and everyone knows
that pride comes before a fall.
It's like if you have any.
That's why it says in the Old Testament
that fear of God is the beginning of
wisdom.
It's like I've never in all my years as
a clinical psychologist,
and this is something that really does
terrify me.
I as I have never seen anyone ever get
away with anything at all.
Even once you know,
there's that old idea that God has a
book,
you know,
and it keeps track of everything in
heaven.
It's like,
okay,
okay.
You know,
maybe it's not a book,
fine,
but that is a really useful thing to
think about because while I'd maybe you
disagree,
maybe you think people get away with
things all the time.
I tell you,
I've never seen it.
What I see instead is that thing
happens,
right?
Someone twists the fabric of reality and
they do it successfully because it
doesn't snap back at them that moment.
And then like two years later unraveled
and they get walloped and they think,
oh my God,
that's so unfair.
And then we track it.
It's like,
well,
what happened before that?
This one,
then what?
This,
and then what this,
and then what?
Oh,
oh,
this,
that's where it went wrong.
It's,
yeah,
because you can't twist the fabric of
reality without having it snapped back.
It doesn't work that way.
And why would it?
Because what are you going to do twist
the fabric of reality?
I don't think so.
I think it's bigger than you.
You know,
and I think one of the things that
really temps people is the idea that,
well I can get away with it.
It's like,
yeah,
you try,
you see how well that works.
So like you,
you get away with nothing and that is
the beginning of wisdom and I had
something that deeply terrifies me and
you know,
ever since last September when I came to
more like broader public attention,
one of the things I'd be terrified of
making a mistake because I certainly
know I'm more than capable of making a
mistake and thank God so far.
Either I haven't made one or no one's
found out about it.
So.
But it's like,
you know,
we walk on a very thin and narrow edge
and we're very lucky when things aren't
degenerating into chaos around us or
rapidly moving too far,
too much order and it's not an easy
thing to stay on that line and you can
tell when you stay,
you're on that line because the things
are deeply meaningful and engaging when
you're on that line.
But if you're not existentially
terrified about the consequences of
wavering off that,
then you are truly not awake.
So.
And that's what I see in this picture,
you know,
it's like look out man,
because there are rules and if you break
them,
God help you.
Thank you.
So one of the things that seems to be
the case with regard,
I mentioned this in the question period
a bit last time,
is that one of the things that seems to
be actually one of the advantages to
gluing the new testament onto the old
testament is the idea of a
transformation and morality that is
analogous to the Piagetian idea that
after you learn to play by the rules,
you can learn to make the rules.
Because I think that's actually what
happens to some degree in the transition
between the Old Testament and the new
testament,
because in the Old Testament,
most morality is prohibition.
Here are things you shouldn't do.
It's like,
fair enough.
Now it's a lot of what you do with your
kids.
Don't do this.
Do it.
Especially when they're happy,
you're always going around and telling
them to stop being so happy because all
they're doing is causing trouble.
It's quite painful if you're a parent
and you noticed that,
but the first morality is prohibition,
right?
Control yourself so you don't cause too
much trouble.
And then maybe if you get that down and
you're good at it,
then the next thing is,
well,
once you're disciplined,
then you can start working towards
something that's a positive good.
And that's the transformation that seems
to me to be fundamentally characteristic
of the juxtaposition of the new
testament onto the old testament.
But in these images,
it's still something like serve
tradition.
Serve the father,
psychologically speaking,
support the tradition because you live
on it there.
In the old Mesopotamian story,
um,
the Enuma Elish,
which you can,
which you can read about if you're
interested in the original gods who are
really badly behaved,
they're like two year olds.
In fact,
there are a lot like two year olds,
they kill the primordial God absolute
who's the Patriarchal God,
to kill them and try to live on his
corpse.
Well,
that's what we all do,
right?
Because we live on a corpse of our
ancestors.
You could say we live in the Corpus of
our culture.
It's dead and that's not a great place
to live.
So you have to keep reinventing it.
So the damn thing you know,
stays active and awake.
You,
you stay on the carbs for too long and
then the devil of or the demon of chaos
comes back.
And that's what happens in the
Mesopotamian story.
It's like,
don't be thinking that you can stay on
the core of your ancestors for too long
without contributing to the
revivification of the system because the
chaos that all of that holds,
that all of that holds,
that Bay will definitely come and visit
you.
And you'll see that in stories like a
Hobbit,
you know,
hobbits,
they're nice,
they like to eat,
they're kind of fat,
they're short,
they're not very bright,
you know,
they're a hubris stick.
They have no idea what's out there in
the broader world.
They're protected.
If you remember by the striders who are
the sons of great kings who look like
tramps,
they have nothing but contempt for them.
They patrol the borders and keep the
bloody harbored safe.
But I would.
They're it out there in the periphery.
All Hell is brewing and chaos is,
is,
is generating and forming.
And that's an archetypal story.
And that's why people liked that story
so much because that's exactly right.
Like we're the hobbits and there are,
we are protected from chaos by the
spirits of our data ancestors and we're
too damn stupid to know it.
And we think,
oh well we don't need them anymore.
And that,
to me,
that's postmodernism.
That's what the bloody universities are
doing with the humanities to absolutely
appalling.
And we will pay for it.
So unless we wake up and hopefully we'll
wake up because that would be better
than paying for it even though being
awake is rather painful.
So.
So then I had this vision one time and I
kind of portrayed in this,
in this image of,
of what the world was like.
And I thought,
well,
it's not a pyramid.
It's not a single hierarchy of
authority.
That's not what it is.
It's,
it's an array of hierarchy of authority.
So you imagine this sort of infinite
plane and in the infinite plane there's
nothing but pyramids and inside the
Pyramids there are strata of people
everywhere,
far as you can look.
Some of the pyramids are tall,
some of them are short,
they overlap there.
It's endless.
The plane is endless and those are all
the positions to which you could rise
and everybody's inside the pyramid sort
of crammed up trying to move towards the
top.
And then there's the possibility of
sailing across overtop of all of them
and seeing how the structure itself
works.
And that's.
And that's the I that floats above the
pyramid and the sees the structure
itself and the highest order of being is
not to be at the top of the pyramid,
it's to use the discipline that you
attained by striving towards the top of
the pyramid to release yourself from the
pyramid and move one step up.
And that's,
I think that's one of the things that's
instantiated in the idea of the,
for example,
of the Holy Ghost.
So,
and I think that's a kin to that that
says office and need you to set of
Sisyphus,
if I remember correctly,
that one has to imagine him happy.
Well if there's a rock at the bottom of
the hill,
then you might as well push it up the
hill.
And if it rolls back down,
well then you've got something else to
do.
Don't you can push the damn rock back up
the hill and there's no shortage of
rocks to put up to push up the hill.
And that's what we're built for anyways.
And so let's go out and like push them
down,
boulders up the hill,
and then maybe we could have enough self
confidence and enough enough respect for
ourselves that we wouldn't have to turn
to hatred and revenge and try to take
everything down because I think that's
the alternative.
So he's not weak.
That's one thing you can say about them.
Yeah,
same idea represented there,
right?
That's atlas.
Who voluntarily takes the world on his
shoulders.
It's like the idea of Christ taking the
sins of the world on his shoulders.
It's exactly the same notion,
which is the notion that you should be
able to recognize in yourself all the
horror of humanity and take
responsibility for it because that's
what that means.
And the thing that's so interesting
about that is that if you can recognize
yourself in yourself,
all the horror of humanity,
you will instantly have a hell of a lot
more respect for yourself than you did
before you did that.
Because there's some real utility in
knowing that you're a monster now,
and just because you're a monster
doesn't mean you have to be a monster,
but it's really useful to know that you
are one.
So one of the things that you knew,
and this is something that I find so
amazing about his writing,
is I think something that really
distinguishes him,
for example,
from Joseph Campbell who talked about
following your bliss,
is like you said,
very clearly that the first step to
enlightenment is the encounter with the
shadow and what he meant by that was
everything horrible that human beings
have done was done by human beings and
your one of the.
And so if you don't understand that,
and to understand that really means to
know how it was that you could have done
it,
and that's a shattering thing.
To try to imagine that.
To try to imagine yourself as someone
who's engaged in medieval torture,
to see how you could in fact do that.
You're never the same after you learned
that,
but being never the same after learning
that is unbelievably useful.
Because when you understand that,
that's what you're like,
then your whole different creature and I
don't think,
and this is something I did learn from
young,
is that you cannot be a good person
until you know how much evil you contain
within you.
It is not possible and it's partly
because you just don't have any potency.
Like if you're just naive,
if you're just nice,
if you'd never hurt anyone,
you'd never heard of fly.
You don't have the capability for any of
that.
Why would anyone ever take you?
Seriously?
You're,
you're just,
you're a animal at best,
you know,
and uh,
rather contemptible one at that.
And it's a very strange thing because
you wouldn't think that the revelation
of the capacity for evil is a
precondition for the realization of
good.
But I believe that,
first of all,
why would you be serious enough to even
attempt to pursue the good?
Unless you had some sense of what the
consequences of not doing it,
you,
you have to be serious about these sorts
of things.
It's not a,
it's not a,
it's not the game of a child,
right?
It's the game of a fully developed adult
and you have learned this in part when I
had little kids,
I wrote a chapter for my new book called
never let your children do anything that
makes you dislike them.
And why was that?
And I read,
I read that,
wrote that after I knew I was a monster
and I thought I'm going to make sure I
like my kids.
I'm going to make sure that they behave
around me so that I liked them because
I'm way bigger than them and I'm way
more cruel than they are and I've got
tricks up my sleeve that they cannot
even possibly imagine.
And if,
if they irritate me,
I will absolutely take it out on them.
And if you don't think that you're the
sort of person that would do that,
then you are the sort of person who is
doing it.
You know,
we're not going to get to Adam and eve.
Haha.
I watched this great documentary once a
called Hitman Hart and was about Bret
Hart,
who was the most famous Canadian in the
world for awhile and he was,
he was a world wide wrestling federation
wrestler,
you know,
and he was a good guy and uh,
he came from this famous family of
wrestlers who all came from Alberta,
I think there were seven brothers who
were wrestlers and seven sisters and all
of the sisters married wrestlers and
they were all offspring.
Children of Stu Hart,
who,
who was wrestling impresario like 40
years ago.
And it was,
it was such a cool documentary because I
was always wondering why in the world do
people watch wrestling and,
and,
and believe it,
you know,
believe it.
Do you believe movies when you go watch
them?
It's like,
that's a hard question to answer while
you're there.
You do.
And so if you're watching wrestling and
you're a wrestling fan,
do you believe it?
Well,
it isn't a matter of belief.
It's a matter of being engaged in a
drama and there are different levels of
drama.
Right?
So let's say worldwide Wrestling
Federation drama is not the most
sophisticated form of drama,
but I'm not being not being assessed
smart Alec when I'm saying that there
was drama of different sophistication
for different people and that's also why
religious truths exists at multiple
levels simultaneously.
Right?
There's gotta be something in it for
everyone and that's a hard belief
system.
That's a hard system to put together.
Something for the unbelievably
sophisticated and something for the
common person.
Okay.
So we have wrestling and Brett Hart was
a good guy and
he fell into the archetype of being a
good guy and that's partly what the.
What the story's about.
It was a bit too much for him,
but one of the things that he he laid
out so carefully was because he figured
that a 120 million people knew him,
something like that and that everywhere
he went,
he was treated like a hero and he found
that quite a bit of quite a burden,
as you can imagine if you think about
it,
but he portrayed what was happening in
the wrestling ring as classic good
against evil but not conceptualized in
discussed,
right.
Embodied,
fought out,
act it out,
you know,
like,
like thor and the hulk,
except like right in front of you.
And so.
Well that's exactly this sort of thing.
I mean,
we could consider hockey more
sophisticated than wrestling,
perhaps not.
As I said,
I'm not being a critic of these.
I am not being critically minded about
these things.
I understand their purpose and I would
highly recommend that documentary.
It's a brilliant documentary,
but this is,
it's the same thing.
It's a Silver Cup,
right?
It's like there's the hero of the team
that's the hero of the teams,
you know,
here's something cool.
If you're the fan of the Toronto Blue
Jays are the Toronto Maple leafs,
of course this hardly ever happens to
you if you're a fan of the Toronto Maple
leafs because they always lose,
but,
but if you're watching a game and your
team wins and we take your testosterone
levels,
then they went up and if you watched the
Toronto Maple leafs and they lost and
you're a fan,
then your testosterone levels go down.
So that's pretty damn funny,
you know,
I mean really don't you see how deeply
instantiated this as in people.
I mean,
it bloody well alters your biochemistry,
like your,
your,
your testosterone levels.
It's all more my team lost know there'll
be no.
There'll be nothing in it for the wife
tonight.
Yeah,
well this is the cosmos.
I think from,
from the phenomenological perspective,
and one of the things that,
that,
that has come to my realization is that
this is real.
This is real.
It's not a metaphor.
It's way deeper than a metaphor.
The most real things about life are the
place you don't know and the place you
know.
And you could say,
well,
that's explored territory and unexplored
territory that's real,
and it's been around forever.
Back to the lobsters,
lobsters in a new place.
The first thing they do is go around
their territory,
finding places to hide,
and also making a burrow.
So the first thing they do is establish
what they know against what they don't
know.
And that's real.
It's real from the Darwinian
perspective.
And we're going to say that what's real
from the Darwinian perspective is plenty
real enough because we're alive and
everything.
And so sort of thing matters.
It's like,
well,
that's what this is the dallas symbol.
That's what it says is that what's Wade
says,
what is experienced made of eternally
outs.
Easy.
Okay,
off in order.
And in every bit of chaos,
there's the possibility of order and
every bit of order there's the
possibility of chaos.
And that's the way,
right?
That's the path of life,
that's life itself.
And where you're supposed to be is right
on the border between the two of those.
And why is that stable enough?
Engaged enough,
right?
So not only are you doing what you
should be doing,
you're doing it in a way that increases
the probability that you'll do it better
tomorrow,
and you can tell when you're doing that
because you're engaged,
you're in the right time and place,
and your,
your,
your neurology tells you that.
That's what meaning is.
That's what transcendent meaning is.
And that's so cool because I also think
that that is the antidote to existential
suffering.
The antidote to existential suffering is
to be at the right place at the right
time and you know you want to get
technical about it.
Okay?
Anxiety and pain,
that that's the key.
That's the reality of existential
suffering.
Okay?
So let's say you're in the right place
at the right time.
What happens to biochemically
dopaminergic activation?
What does that do?
Suppress this anxiety and it's
analgesic.
Now it's more than that because it also
produces positive emotion and the desire
to move forward and it underlies
creativity and,
and so,
so not only do you get the positive
engagement from a neurochemical
perspective,
you get the Analgesia and you get the
ante and you get the reduction of
anxiety.
So it's not hypothetical,
it's an.
And it is the case that the dopaminergic
systems,
those are the exploratory systems,
unbelievably ancient and archaic are
activated when you're optimally
positioned to be,
to be,
um,
what incorporating new information,
which is what human beings do because
we're information foragers and so we
want to be secure,
but building on our security at the same
time.
And then we want to do it for ourselves.
We want to do it for other people.
We want to do it for our families,
we want to do it for broader society.
We want to bring the whole world
together in alignment to do that.
And that's meaningful and God only knows
what we could do about the suffering of
the world.
If we did that,
you know,
we have no idea what we could do if we
started doing things properly and maybe
so many of the things that dismay us
about life.
We could,
we could stop.
I mean,
we stopped a lot of them in the last
hundred years.
You know,
things are a lot better than they were a
hundred years ago.
Obviously they're not perfect,
but 100 years ago,
120 years ago,
man,
you know,
the average person in the western world
lived on less than a dollar a day in
today's dollars.
It's like he just try that for a week
and see how much fun that is.
So the daoists wow,
what is this?
Well,
this is the pre caused chaos out of
which the word of God extracted
habitable order at the beginning of
time.
It's the same thing.
It's the same thing and that chaos.
We'll talk a bit more about that later I
guess because it's a very complicated
thing to,
to describe,
but it's certainly the thing that when
you encounter the chaos is what you
encounter when the twin towers fall.
Right.
Do you remember what that was like?
Right,
so it was.
It was September 10th.
While that was the World Cup.
Everyone knew what the world was like
and then it was September 11th and
everyone walked around days for three
days because the building's felt,
but so what?
You can see a building fall.
You can understand what it's.
What happens when a building falls,
so then what's going on with the being
dazed while it's the chaos that
underlies or how to bill order
manifested itself in those buildings
collapsed.
It was a brilliant act of terrorism and
everyone was frozen and curious because
that's how we react to that sort of
thing.
The,
the.
It's like,
it's like the shark.
You don't remember that famous,
that famous movie poster for jaws with
the woman's swimming on the top of the
water in that terrible leviathan shark
underneath coming up too,
to take her out.
Well,
that's life,
man.
That's the world.
And now and then you see that and when
something falls like the twin towers
fall,
you remember that?
The ocean below you the abyss,
right?
The primordial best.
That bloody thing is deep.
And the end,
you're a fragile and that happens when
someone betrays you and it's happened.
It happens to you.
When your dreams fall apart,
you encounter that chaos again from
which the world is extracted.
And then you're called upon to act out
attention and the word in order to bring
the world back into order.
And none of that is,
none of that is superstitious.
None of that is superstitious.
None of that's even metaphorical.
It's real,
it's real.
It's more real than anything else.
And I think the reason for that in part
is that this has been.
It's been this way forever,
right?
As long as there's been life,
this has been the rule of life.
And that's the cosmos.
That's reality.
That's what we inhabit.
And so one of the things,
you know,
the,
the so called new atheists tonight,
I don't want to go on a tangent about
new atheist because I think atheists are
often remarkably honest and very
consistent in their analysis.
So,
but I just don't think they're taking
the problem seriously.
They're like,
I don't think they take their
evolutionary theorizing nearly with the
seriousness that it that it
necessitates,
and I don't think that.
I don't think that you can dispute the
proposition that the longer something
has had a selection effect on life,
the more real it is.
It's the fundamental axiom of Darwinian
biology and I think the Darwinian world
is more real than the physical world.
That was the argument that I was trying
to have with,
with with Sam Harris and I didn't do the
world's best job of that.
Although it went not too bad the second
time,
but it's.
It's not something to be taken lightly.
It's a very serious,
profound and meaningful proposition and
people acted out and want to act it out
whether they know it or not.
That's Martin.
So the story of Martin,
I'll just give it to you very briefly.
Time out and aps who are locked in
embrace at the beginning of time.
God is of salt water garden,
fresh water together,
chaos and order,
right?
They give rise masculine,
feminine.
They give rise to the world of the elder
gods and those are,
to me,
they're primordial motivational forces
or something like that and their rage
and their lust and their love and all
these things that possess us that are
there forever and they're out in the
world acting and they carelessly slay
appsu their father and their making a
rocket and then they collapse zoo and
then tie them out,
gets wind of that,
and that's time out right there.
By the way,
she's kind of a rough looking creature
and she's the mother of all things and
so she's not very happy about this
though.
Her children have destroyed structure
itself,
plus they're noisy and careless and so
she thinks all right,
just like Noah,
just like the God that brings the flood
to know what exactly the same idea.
Time Matt comes back and says,
you know,
okay,
enough is enough.
I'm going to take you out,
and she makes this battalion of monsters
and puts the worst monster there.
Is that the head of the battalion,
his name is king.
Knew.
He's like a precursor to the idea of
Satan and she lets the gods know,
hey,
I'm coming for you,
and so they're not very happy about this
because their gods,
but like,
yeah,
she's chaos itself.
Right?
She gave birth to everything.
This is no joke,
and so they send one got out after
another to confront her and they all
come back with their tails between their
legs.
There is no hope and then one day
there's a new God that emerges and
that's Marduk and the gods know,
as soon as he pops up,
they know he's something new.
Remember,
and this is happening while the
Mesopotamians are assembling themselves
into one of the world's first great
civilizations.
So all the gods of all of those tribes
are coming together to organize
themselves into a hierarchy to figure
out what proposition rules,
everything.
And so Marta has elected by all the gods
and he says,
look,
I'll go out there and I'll take on time
map,
but here's the rule from here on,
you follow me.
I determined destiny.
I'm the top God.
I'm the thing at the top of the
hierarchy and all the other gods say,
hey look,
no problem.
You get rid of chaos.
We do exactly what you say.
Now Martin,
his eyes all the way around his head and
he speaks magic words.
Those are his primary attributes and so
he takes a net and he goes out to
confront time at and and he,
he,
he encloses her in the neck,
which I think is so cool because it's an
encapsulation,
right?
It's a conceptual encapsulation.
He encloses chaos itself in a conceptual
structure.
He puts it in the net and then he cuts
her into pieces and he makes the world
and then
that he creates human beings to inhabit
that world and to serve the gods and he
creates human beings out of the blood of
king,
of the worst of the demons.
And that took me a call.
Andy Young,
who was a student of mine helped me
figure that out.
He thought,
because that's pretty damn pessimistic.
It's like,
you know what exactly?
It sounds like a fall metaphor.
It's like the idea of original sin,
but,
but our joint conclusion with regards to
that was that human beings are the only
creatures in creation that can truly
deceive,
right?
We have the capacity for evil,
just like it says in the Adam and Eve
story.
We can actually do that and that's why
we're made out of the blood of King,
knew the king of the demons,
the we are that thing that can deceive,
that can twist the structure of reality.
Well,
so Marduk now the massive team has had
an emperor,
right?
And the emperor was the
Avatar of Marta.
That's what made him emperor.
He was only at Emperor.
If he was going to be Murdoch,
he had to be a good duck.
Which man,
he.
I do confront time,
chaos and cut her up and make order out
of her pieces and what the Mesopotamians
used to do.
After New Year's celebration,
they'd go outside their walled city and
that's explored territory versus
unexplored territory.
They go outside their world's citi into
chaos,
and they bring all the statutes that
represented the gods and they'd act this
out because they're trying to figure
something out,
right?
You're trying to figure out what this
means.
They're acting it out,
and then they'd take their emperor and
the priest would make them kneel and
they take all his king,
all his king uniform off is emperor
uniform off and make them Neil and
humiliate them and nail them with a
glove and say,
okay,
how were you not a good Martech this
year?
Right?
And then he'd recount all the ways that
he was inadequate in confronting chaos,
and then they'd do the celebration and
Martech would win and the king would go
sleep with a royal prostitute.
And the reason for that was it's the
same idea as St George pulling the
Virgin from the Dragon.
It's exactly the same idea that if you
call,
if you encounter the reptilian chaos,
you can extract something out of it with
which if you unite,
you produce creative order.
That's what they were acting out and
that was the basis for the Mesopotamian
idea of sovereignty.
It's so smart,
it's so unbelievably smart,
and you know,
the Mesopotamians had a massive
influence on the civilizations that then
had a massive influence on us.
It's one of the stories of how the
notion of sovereignty itself came to be.
It's the evolution of the idea of God.
That's one way of thinking about it,
but even more importantly,
it's the evolution of the idea of the
redemptive human being.
Right,
and that's taken to.
It's one of its conclusions while in the
story of Buddha,
but also in the story of Christ,
the idea of the perfect individual and
the notion is,
well,
that's the word that speaks truth into
chaos at the beginning of time to
generate habitable order.
That is good.
That's the story.
And so with that,
let's see.
Oh sure.
I'll just show you these pictures
because they're so interesting once you
know what they mean.
They're so cool.
That's a symbol of infinity.
That's Hercules and the hydro.
Well,
what's life like?
It cut off one head.
What happens?
Seven more grow,
right?
What do you do?
Run whole.
Well,
no,
that's not what you do it.
This is what you do.
You fight it.
It's the.
It's the chaos that generates partial
chaos.
It's the ultimate chaos that generates
partial chaos,
but that also is what revivified his
life because otherwise it would just be
static.
Mercury headed Hydra,
right?
Freezes.
You have St George.
He's doing it peacefully,
which is so interesting,
right?
There's got to be a terrific look on his
face and that particular representation.
Another St George,
right?
The Virgin in the background.
I think that's safe and if I remember
correctly,
St George,
he's the patron saint of England.
Okay.
Here's an interesting one.
This actually sheds light on,
on the human proclivity for warfare.
Say George,
that's a Muslim soldier.
It's really easy to transform the enemy
into the Dragon,
right?
Because the enemy is often the Predator
and we do that instantaneously,
right?
With without a second thought,
and so then we can go to war morally
because why not take out the snakes?
Well,
you know,
the problem is where are the snakes?
Well,
maybe they're outside and maybe they're
not.
Maybe they're in this room and even
worse,
maybe they were in you and that's
wisdom.
When you know that they're renew,
why wouldn't she be happy about that?
Especially if she had a.
especially if she had a child right?
Seriously,
and that's horace,
right?
The God of vision,
and he was a.
He was a can because falcons have great
vision.
They fly above everything and they can
see everything and so that was the
Egyptian creative God,
Horus,
and I'll tell you the story about horace
at some points as well.
Now here's some pictures that
demonstrate what I had described as the
emergence of let's say the Metta hero
out of the hero,
so there's the person you admire and
then there's the set of people that you
admire and then there's the set of
admirable people and the extraction of
that ideal.
As far as I can tell,
that's just what's portrayed in these
images.
That's a great one.
It's very sophisticated image.
You see the two sides of Christ's face
or not.
Oh,
symmetrical one's garden ones,
man.
That's what that icon means,
and so the fully developed person in
this,
it's one of the oldest representations
of of this sort that we know.
The idea is that
there's a,
there's the human person
in his ordinariness let's say,
and then there's this,
this kinship with the divine that's
associated with the willing adoption of
the responsibility of moral mortal being
and that produces this union and then
it's manifest in a book,
right?
Because that speech and it's associated
with the sun,
right?
It's the proper way of being.
And that's a perfect example,
I think of the emergence of the
archetype of the multitude.
That's what it looks like to me.
And so I guess now we're done with
genesis one and that took three
lectures,
but God is complicated,
you know,
that's the thing.
So
thank you.
So thank you.
Next week.
By all appearances,
that's where we are.
So we've got 20 minutes
questions.
So,
um,
in the past I've done some work with big
brother,
big sister and whatever.
Um,
that being said that the most common
story I tend to hear from the youth is
that they read,
they're raising a single family home,
usually with a mom,
daddy's there on the picture and
alcoholic,
whatever,
whatever that brought her.
So we have this child who is trying to
seek ways to make himself healthy and
empower himself in ways that a healthy
father should have done.
So,
you know,
between the formative years of like one
to four.
So I think,
you know,
ongoing with this,
um,
how,
let's say for someone who born without
like a good father figure,
where would they go out in the world and
like what four spheres of influence
where they try to expose themselves to,
to like gain access to that Fountain of
Health and knowledge at a father or a
good father figures should have provided
them to in the first place.
Okay.
Well partly,
I mean certainly to some degree a good
mother can provide that,
right?
To some degree,
although it's hard for one person to be
everything right.
You know,
and I think one of the conundrums that
face women,
and this is a tough one and this is why
I think women are higher in trait
agreeableness and higher in trait
negative emotion is that,
you know,
the primary problem that a woman has
with an infant is why not throw it out a
window?
Because it's very annoying,
I mean it's there all the time.
It's constant demand.
It's absolutely constant man,
tremendous dependency and so a woman has
to be tilted towards mercy.
That's how it looks to me and especially
during.
It's so important during the.
Especially the first year when children
are so unbelievably vulnerable and so I
think it's very difficult for women to
be merciful like that and to make the
shift to encouraging.
I think that's a very difficult thing
for people to do simultaneously.
Although you know,
people,
people.
I'm not saying that women are always
only merciful and men are always only
encouraging disciplinarians,
but things do sort themselves out to
some degree like that and I think also
the biochemical transformations that
accompany pregnancy and childbirth and
lactation also tilt mother towards that
as well because he has to really love
that little thing.
Right?
It's,
it's number one,
no matter what it demands and then
telling it what to do and making sure
it's behaving properly.
That's,
that's a whole different issue.
No,
but the kids who lacked fathers,
I mean,
first of all,
they can find that to some degree in
their friends and that's often look for
the boys do in particular they,
they,
they go into gangs and they generate the
missing men masculinity in the game.
Well that's not so good because like
what the hell do they know it?
Well,
they don't know anything,
right?
They're just stupid kids and they're
like 15 years old and their testosterone
is pumping and they're trying to get the
hell away from their mother,
which is what they're supposed to do and
they're not in the right position to
exercise any authority over themselves.
So that's not good.
They can find it in education.
They can find it in books,
they can find it.
Movies,
they can find it in sports heroes and so
forth because the image of the father is
fragmented and distributed among the
community,
but it's very,
very difficult to not have a father.
And you know,
one of the things that we're doing in
our society,
which I think is,
I think it's absolutely appalling,
is that we're making the case that all
families are equal.
It's like,
sorry,
no wrong.
And there's no empirical data supporting
that proposition.
By the way.
It's much better for kids to have two
parents who those parents are.
That's a whole different issue.
And if I could just to add one more
thing,
how would you ask that question too?
Let's see.
A daughter who is her father because she
would often see how different ways to
find those fragments of her missing
father then like a boy wouldn't said
because obviously they're raised
differently or at least they should have
been.
Well,
I think it's the same issue.
You know?
I mean,
I think,
I think that another danger that
emerges,
Mrs Freud's of course famous observation
is that,
you know,
if,
if there's mum and child or father and
child relationship can get a little
closer than it should.
And then the lines get blurry and mixed.
And I'm not saying that that happens to
everyone obviously,
but,
but it's still a danger that that's
inherent in the situation.
They're thrust together too tightly
without sufficient resources.
And so the responsibility has to be
distributed more and like,
I really do think that it's the sign of
the degeneration of the society when
the,
when,
when single parenthood becomes anything
approximating the norm,
it's not a good idea.
Then the,
I.
part of the reason I believe that,
and I think this has to do with the
overwhelming selfishness of,
of,
of modern life,
is that marriage isn't for the people
who are married.
It's for the children obviously.
And like if you can't handle that,
grow the hell up Sarah.
No,
I mean seriously,
seriously,
once you,
once you have kids,
it is not about you,
period.
Now that doesn't mean it isn't about you
at all,
but it just seems so self evident to me.
I can't believe that anybody would even
would even question it.
Oh,
question.
Oh yes.
Well,
I'm certainly aware of that.
Yes.
It's questioned.
It's almost illegal to question it now,
you know,
to to or illegal to make the set of
propositions that I'm making,
so that's the best I can do.
That's excellent.
Thank you.
Going to the first part of first year
lecture,
but it's also something that's been on
my mind listening to lectures or the
past few months and that's when we
talked about the psychological truth or
significance of the Bible.
To what extent does that psychological,
psychological truth has to be embodied
in specific historical events or people
and so for instance,
the thing that's sort of been bugging on
my mind is there's a.
there's a part that St Paul's talking
about in the new testament somewhere in
one of his letters and he.
He's talking about the resurrection and
he says,
if it didn't happen,
then it.
This whole thing is just meaning the
faith is meaningless.
Like for him,
there had to be that embodiment of that
historical person or event in that case.
Well,
the best answer I have to that at the
moment is that I'm really happy that I'm
not at that point yet in this lecture
series because I know because that is a
crucial issue there and I don't know
exactly what to make of it and my
approach at the moment as I said,
is to approach this as rationally as I
possibly can and I hope I know a hell of
a lot more about what I'm doing by the
time I get to that particular question.
Um,
and I,
I do have the beginnings of ways to
answer that,
but I'm not going to answer that at all
right now because it's so bloody
complicated.
It would just burn me to a frazzle and
I'm already mostly bird to a frazzle
after that lecture.
So I,
I couldn't attempt to even start to
sketch it out.
I don't know.
I mean,
part of it is to be just rational about
it,
just to be rational about it.
There is something about the idea that
continual death and rebirth is a
necessary precondition to proper human
adaptation.
Like every time you learn something new
that's important,
part of the stupid old you has to die
and sometimes that can be an awful lot
of you and in fact in can be so much of
you.
Sometimes you just die,
right?
You just can't handle it.
And so there is,
there is a real idea that you have to
identify with the part of yourself that
transcends your current personality that
can constantly die and be reborn.
Now.
Then I could say,
well,
that means that all of this is
psychological and symbolic and that's
the simplest answer.
But I'm not satisfied with that answer
even though I think it's coherent and
complete because the world's a very
weird place and there are things about
it that we don't understand.
So,
so I,
I can't go.
I can't go any farther than that at the
moment.
So that.
Yep.
I got to Peterson.
Um,
I just recently watched one of your
videos of you debating with
transgendered protesters at uft,
a free speech rally in October.
And one of the protesters,
one of the comments,
one of the protests are said to you,
which was in particularly very,
very chilling,
was,
um,
why do you have the right to determine
whether an individual is worthy of you
using their pronouns?
I'm the scary thing to me is how common
this type of view is among radical left
wing protesters on university campuses
who feel they have the right to tell
other people what they can think,
what words they can use and what
speakers they can or cannot listen to.
Um,
the scarier part is that our government
is creating legislation to backup their
Adl ideologies,
uh,
which is evident through bill.
See 16 and one slash three and bill 89.
So my question is,
what do you think the end game is in all
of this because it seems every year or
we're
in the process of finding that out.
You know,
and I'm sorry,
I'm sorry.
We're in the process of finding that
out.
Um,
I don't,
I mean,
I think the end game that underlies all
of that,
in my estimation,
is best summed up by Jacques Derrida's
Christian or her criticism of Western
civilization.
It's fell logo centric.
Now we've already talked about what the
logos means,
right?
And so,
and so for,
for decorative,
that was a sign of,
it's after a,
what would you call it,
utter despair,
the utterly despicable dominant nature
of western culture.
Well,
that,
that's what animates the postmodernists.
Now they may not know that because I
need the,
gets fragmented across its adherence and
then it only access the coherent
ideology wouldn't hold those adherence
come together in a mall.
And then you see the animating spirit.
So I said,
I think that there's a battle going on
that's a battle exactly at the level
that Derrida described,
and that's a theological battle with a
philosophical,
uh,
with a,
with a philosophical implications and
out of those philosophical implications,
political implications,
but it's not primarily political and
it's not primarily philosophical,
it's deeper than that.
And the postmodernist out there,
their criticism was designed to be
fundamental and it also emerged out of
Marxism and let's not forget that the
Marxist criticism was not only
fundamental but just about resulted in
the nuclear annihilation of the world.
These are not trivial issues and we're
back in the same insane boat.
And so what do I think should be done
about that?
Well,
I thought about that way before any of
this happened and I think that what we
should do about it is we should tell the
truth because there isn't anything more
powerful than that.
And that's the right theological answer
because the spoken truth brings good
into Ba.
While that's the foul logo centric idea,
and I've,
I'm trying to revisit that to explain to
people what it means and to see if they
think that's a good idea.
I mean that's what we have to figure out
is,
is that an idea worth adhering to or
not?
The alternative is the see for the
postmodernists.
The world is that landscape of pyramids
that I described,
but there's no transcendent vision
that's over above that.
And all of those pyramids are equally
valid and it's a war of everyone against
everyone.
It's like,
it's like the nightmare of Hobbs,
Thomas Hobbes,
excepted.
It's not individuals,
it's groups.
And everyone said group your group,
your whatever your group is.
It's like,
that's death as far as I'm concerned.
It's,
it's,
it's utterly reprehensible
and,
and we better sorted out because if we
don't sort it out we are bloody well
going to pay for it.
So thank you.
Hey,
how's it going?
I just want to say thank you for doing
all this.
And I really.
That was bob and Doug Mackenzie,
right?
Yeah.
Hey,
how's it going?
I'm glad you caught that.
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
I knew the facebook
pull some people who are familiar with
your work and uh,
a question kind of rose to the top,
like just right out of the blue.
It was spectacular.
And uh,
what it was you,
you didn't really touch it here.
I'll,
but you touched a little bit in your
lectures.
It was about integrating the shadow and
one of the main questions was,
how does one go about that?
Especially in the modern world?
You know,
like,
uh,
usually sheltered from anything
resembling that kind of concept.
You know,
we don't engage like the unknown.
We don't come into life or death
situations.
Most of us actually work is like an
ambulance,
you know?
Um,
well that's one thing you can do
without,
is the one thing you can do.
Well,
yeah,
you can search out experiences that put
you there because while you can do that
as a volunteer for example,
I mean,
you can.
One of the things I saw once I was in
Montreal,
I was in this outdoor mall in Montreal
on Saint Hubert.
And I saw this great big 17 year old
kid,
you know,
and uh,
he had a Mohawk and he was dressed in
leather and studs and like he,
he was,
uh,
he was doing modern barbarian thing and
he had it really down and you know,
his standing in the corner with two pink
shopping bags.
So I was looking at him and I thought,
you know,
if someone offered him the,
the,
the opportunity to drop those God damn
sleeping bags or shopping bags and go
fight with Isis.
He'd be there in a second.
Yeah,
right.
Because what the hell is some monster
like that doing,
standing on the corner of St Hubert
holding two pink shopping bags.
So I mean,
so some of it is that you need the,
you need to find out where you can push,
where you need to find out that edge
that you can push yourself against it.
It's going to be different for different
people.
But there's,
there's the call to adventure and
heroism in the EU.
There are life and death situations
everywhere around you.
If you want to involve yourself in them,
you know,
and it,
it sometimes that might be like two to
put yourself together to the degree that
you can say physically or spiritually or
intellectually.
It could be an intellectual battle.
It could be a moral battle.
Like the frontier is everywhere.
The frontier is just the edge between
what you know and what you don't know.
You want to put yourself on that damn
edge and make yourself into something
and you can retreat into comfort in the
modern world.
And I think that is a problem.
You know,
I mean,
I've noticed that,
um,
it's one of the pathologies of wealth I
would say because one of the problems
with being relatively wealthy if you're
a parent is that you cannot provide your
children with necessity and that's a big
problem because they need necessity to
call them into being.
And we know if you don't have a lot of
material resources and your children ask
you for something,
you can say no because no is the answer.
It's like,
no,
we can't do that.
But if you can say yes,
then it's really hard to say no because
then you're just arbitrary.
Well,
I don't know.
It's like character guard said,
you know,
there will come a time when we have so
much security and comfort that what
we'll want more than anything else is
deprivation and challenge.
And I think,
I think that's particularly what young
men want now.
I think that that's partly because young
women there,
they're stuck without anyways because
they have to.
It's,
it's,
it's the necessity of living in the
world and the responsibility of infant
care in particular like that occupies
them.
Men have to do it voluntarily.
Women now too,
because of the birth control pill.
But you know,
that's 30 years ago.
We hardly have to talk about that at all
yet.
So it's just so much.
Thank you.
Hi,
Dr Peterson.
So I'm actually a Coptic Orthodox and
Egyptian.
So I found your talk today incredibly
interesting.
I've also taken a deep interest in the
early church fathers and as you you're
talking about hierarchies.
I Harken back to St Athanasius in the
idea of theosis that you brought up last
time that God became man so that man can
become like God.
So I was thinking about this in terms of
the hierarchies and is that an example
of how the top of the pyramid,
the hierarchy sort of gets inverted or
descends to the bottom and brings it up
to the top.
And that sort of an attraction to,
of Christianity that's sort of make
Christiana such a powerful idea.
What are your thoughts on that?
Oh,
well,
it certainly one of the.
I mean,
it certainly one of the things that made
not just Christianity a powerful idea
because one of the things that happened,
this was called the democratization of
Cyrus,
if I remember correctly,
like what happened,
see if I can answer this question using
this approach for a sec.
Is that to work?
Hmm.
I don't know if I can answer that
question that way.
The,
the,
the part of the attraction of
Christianity.
But this was something that emerged
across time was the notion that even if
you were in a lowly position,
that there was something about you that
was akin to the divine.
And now you might say,
well,
that's just wish fulfillment.
That's what Freud would say.
That's what Marx would say.
Right?
The opiate of the masses.
I tweeted yesterday something I thought
was pretty funny,
which was that,
um,
like religion was the opiate of the
masses.
But that Marxism with the meth
amphetamine,
if the Max of the masses.
So,
so,
so I think the attraction was that it,
it,
it allowed people to recognize their
intrinsic dignity.
And one of the things I'd been thinking
about is the juxtaposition between
genesis one and genesis two.
Because what happens in genesis two is
that human beings collapse and fall,
right?
And then were these fallen creatures
that no evil,
but in,
in the beginning,
in genesis one,
it's really an optimistic story because
it says,
well,
what are the sorts of creatures that
partake in the calling forth of being
from chaos?
And that's in our essential nature.
And to some degree,
if you juxtapose both of those,
it says,
if that's the entire biblical story,
Ram together in the first two chapters,
which is partly why we're taking so long
to get through this.
By the way,
is that to there to return to genesis
one is the antidote to genesis two,
is to continue to act out the doctrine
that you're made in God's image.
And that means that you're,
you're capable of speaking good being
into existence through truth.
And that that's also the antidote to the
fall,
which I think is actually the
fundamental narrative message of the
entire biblical structure.
And I also think of Western civilization
for that matter.
So there's a nobility,
and this is also why think Nietzsche was
fundamentally wrong in his criticism of
Christianity because he thought about it
as slave morality.
The vengeance of the bottom against the
top,
that's more historical than theological.
It's like it gives dignity it,
it illuminates the dignity of the human
being and,
and it requires responsibility.
So it's not just wish fulfillment.
It's not Friday and wish fulfillment.
The Freudian theory,
which I thought about a lot,
is not tenable in my estimation.
It also doesn't account for the
existence of hell because it's only wish
fulfillment.
Why bother with hell?
I mean,
it's a lot more if you're really going
to just fulfill a wish,
just like everybody gets to go to
heaven,
no matter what they do,
you don't have hell,
which was of course something absolutely
terrifying to medieval Christians.
And then to plenty of people now for
that matter.
So it's the nobility.
It's the idea of the nobility that I
think steeply attractive to people and
that's all there is.
I mean,
what do you have to fight against your
worm?
Like fragile,
mortal existence is the possibility of
transcending that with nobility of
speech and act.
That's what you have and who can hear
that without feeling ennoble by that.
Now you might say,
well,
you might say,
I don't,
I can't bear the responsibility.
It's like,
well,
fair enough,
man.
You know what I mean?
That,
that's a reasonable criticism,
but the consequences of not bearing the
responsibility is.
That's help really.
So thank you.
And thank you very much.
If you had told him,
um,
I don't know if you're familiar with the
works of Nassim Taleb,
I'm,
I'm reasonably familiar with,
so I think it's fair to say that he has,
he talks about the idea that people in
especially modern people have a failure
to recognize the unknown's unknowns as
such.
Yes.
Right.
That's a good way of thinking about it.
Can you move the mic up a bit so that
people can hear you a little better?
Thanks.
Can you?
Yes.
Um,
well I was wondering,
do you think that that failure might,
might be in some way related to the way
that people fail to relate to the idea
of God,
so in the sense that you know,
people can't really grappled with the,
the notion of God either you that as
much as you can give a rational argument
for it,
you can't feel God in the way that
perhaps a more religious person or more,
I'm an older person,
might have felt God.
Do you think that that inability to
recognize the unknown unknowns might
play into that?
No.
Okay.
So that seems to be related to this idea
of the absence of necessity.
So something like that.
Is that because I think that I think
that what you're,
you're making a claim,
maybe tell me if I've got it wrong,
that if you're sheltered too much,
then it,
it also,
it also separates you from anything
that's divine.
I guess that might be right because
there's not enough intensity of
experience at something like that.
Is that,
is that part of the.
Is that part of the issue?
It might be more related to the idea of,
um,
like realizing the absolute infinitude
of what you don't know,
like the,
like the mysterium tremendum that,
that kind of,
you know,
if you believe through statistical
analysis,
you can get everything under control and
you genuinely believe that at some point
you'll get into a wonder,
you know,
so.
Okay.
So,
so,
well that's also,
I think part of the danger of
rationality that the Catholics have been
implicitly warning against for forever
is that rather the rational mind tends
to fall in love with its own productions
and then to worship them as absolutes,
which is,
I think what Milton was trying to
represent by his satanic figure in
paradise lost.
I think of that as like a precursor,
a prophetic precursor to the emergence
of totalitarian states in the modern
world.
And so yeah,
I think that you can believe that what
you know is sufficient to banish
permanently what you don't know.
And I do think that that does
paradoxically,
although you'd think that that would
make you secure.
It also does destroy your relationship
with,
with his spirit that might help you deal
with what it is that you really don't
know with the unknown unknowns.
So yeah,
I mean we don't know to what degree
extreme experience is necessary to bring
forth extreme experience,
right?
What do you have to be through before
you encounter a religious revelation?
Or people might say,
well,
you can't because there's no such thing.
It's like,
well,
don't be so sure about that.
I mean,
people have reported them throughout
history,
but they don't generally occur when
you're,
that's my favorite trope when you're
eating cheeses and playing on playing
Mario brothers.
Right?
So,
yeah,
so that's the best I can do with that.
Thank you very much.
This has to be the last question.
I'll make it quick.
Yeah.
Um,
earlier when you talked about
criminality and creativity trends in,
in men peaking at 14,
it reminded me of something you said.
I think it was Joe Rogan.
I'm talking with sjws and kind of in how
they create their own chaos.
Talking about how adolescents have this
drive to change the world.
And I was wondering if,
uh,
if those three,
the criminality,
creativity drive to change the world are
linked,
and if so,
if they manifest differently in men and
women and if they kind have come from
the same.
Well,
I think they are linked,
but I'm going to concentrate more on the
second part of your question.
So I'm going to ask you guys to think
about something.
So I talked to a friend of mine the
other day.
He's a very,
very smart guy and we'd been talking
about all the sorts of things that we've
been talking about tonight for a long
time.
And we were talking about the relatively
relative evolutionary roles of men and
women.
This is speculative obviously.
And,
and because our research did indicate
it's tended of research so far that,
that the,
the,
the SGS sjw sort of equality above all
else,
philosophy is more prevalent among
women.
It's predicted by the personality
factors that are more common among
women.
So agreeableness and high negative
emotion,
primarily agreeableness.
But in addition it's also predicted by
being female.
And that's interesting because in most
of the personality research that I've
done and as far as I know in the
literature at,
you know,
in more broadly speaking,
most of the time you can get rid of the
attitudinal differences between men and
women or at least reduced them by
controlling for personality.
So if you take a feminine man in a
masculine woman,
then you know the,
the polls reverse.
But that didn't seem to be the case with
political correctness.
And so I've been thinking about that a
lot because,
well men are bailing out of the
humanities like Matt and pretty much out
of the universities except for stamp.
The women are moving in like mad and
they're also moving into the political
sphere like Matt and this is new,
right?
We've never had this happen before.
And we do.
No,
no.
Do not know what the significance of it
is.
It's only 50 years old.
And so we were thinking about this and
so I don't know what you think about
this proposition,
but imagining that,
that,
that historically speaking,
it's something like women were
responsible for distribution and men
were responsible for production.
Something like that,
and maybe maybe that's only the case
really in the tight confines of the
immediate family,
but that doesn't matter because that's
most of the evolutionary landscape for
human beings anyways.
What the women does it did was make sure
that everybody got enough.
Okay.
And that seems to me to be one of the
things that's driving,
at least in part,
the sjw demand for,
for equity and equality.
It's like,
let's make sure everybody has enough.
well look,
fair enough.
You know,
I mean,
you,
you can't,
you can't argue with that,
but there's,
there's an antipathy between that and
the reality of differential
productivity,
you know,
because people really do differ in their
productivity.
So.
All right,
so to answer your question fully,
I do think that the rebellious tendency
of adolescents is associated both with
that criminality spike,
especially among men and with
creativity.
Yes.
I think that the sjw phenomena is
different and I think it is associated
at least in part with the rise of women
to political power and,
and we don't know what women are like
when they have political power because
they've never had it.
I mean there's been queens obviously and
that sort of thing,
just being female authority figures and
females have wielded far more power
historically than feminists generally
liked to admit,
but this is a different thing and we
don't know what,
what a truly female political philosophy
would be like,
but it might be,
especially if it's not been well
examined and it isn't very sophisticated
conceptually.
It could easily be,
but let's make sure things are
distributed equally well.
Yeah,
but sorry that that's just not gonna
fly.
Do you think in terms of the west with
sjws and you talked about last lecture
as well,
creating chaos when there is none.
Otherwise it'd be Sadek.
Do you think there would be any validity
in saying that in a country like Canada
where we're pretty gender equal,
is there any merit to thinking sjws are
trying to create chaos even when they're
arguably is none on a level?
Obviously
there's still problems.
Why would they do that?
Otherwise it would be static and that
drive it wouldn't,
but I'm just wondering is this.
I read this quote once and I don't.
Don't remember who.
Who said it.
It might've been Robert Heinlein for
crying out loud starts fiction author
that springs to mind,
but it probably,
it probably wasn't the proposition was
that men tested ideas and that women
tested men and I kinda liked that.
There's something about that,
you know,
and now it obviously it's an
overgeneralization,
but we also don't know to what degree
women test men.
Surely through provo provocation it's a
lot because like if you want to test
someone,
you don't have a little conversation
with them.
Like you poke the hell out of them and
you see,
okay,
like I'm gonna like go after you and see
where your weak spots are.
And it seems to me that this.
It seems to me that in this constant
protest and use of shame and all of that
that goes along with this,
with this sort of radical movement
towards egalitarianism,
that there's a tremendous amount of
provocation.
And God,
I'm going to say this too,
even though I shouldn't,
but it,
but we may not.
I don't believe this,
but I'm trying trying to figure it out.
You know,
I thought it was absolutely comical when
50 shades of grey came out that just,
I just thought that was just so insanely
comical that at the same time there's
this massive political demand for like
radical equality and and say with
regards to sexual behavior and the
fastest selling novel the world had ever
seen was snm domination.
Right.
It's like,
oh well we can know where the
unconscious is going with that one don't
make.
And sometimes I think like because one
of the things that I've really tried to
puzzle out,
and it's not like I believe this,
right.
I'm just telling you what were the edges
of my thinking have been going is that
you have this crazy alliance between the
feminists and the radical Islamists that
I just do not get.
It's like the feminist is like why they
aren't protesting nonstop about Saudi
Arabia is just completely beyond me.
Like I do not understand it in the
least.
And I wonder too,
I just wonder bloody wellness,
this is the frightened me is like,
is there an attraction,
you know,
the.
Is there an attraction that's emerging
among the female radicals?
For that totalitarian male dominance
that they've chased out of the west and
I mean that's a hell of a thing to
think,
but I am after all,
I am a psychoanalytically minded and I
do think things like that because like I
just can see no rational reason for it.
The only other rational reason is that,
well,
the West needs to fall and so the enemy
of my enemy is exactly.
Now what is it?
The I got that wrong,
but the enemy of an enemy is my friend.
Yes,
exactly.
The elements tend to vote liberal as
well as well,
so that that could be the case,
but I'm not going to shake my suspicion
about the this unconscious balancing
because as the demand for egalitarianism
and the eradication of masculinity
accelerates,
there's going to be a longing in the
unconscious for the precise opposite of
that.
Right?
The more you you scream for equality,
the more your unconscious is going to
admire dominance and so.
Well that's,
that's,
that's well,
that's how you think.
If you're a psychoanalytically minded
and you know I'm a great admirer of
Freud,
he knew a hell of a lot more than people
like to think and and so,
which is partly why everyone still hates
him even though it's 100 years since
he's really,
really been around.
So.
All right,
we should stop.