Okay.
Hello everyone.
Thank you again for showing up.
So,
um,
tonight we're going to finish off the
story of Noah and also the story of the
Tower of Babel and I don't think that'll
take very long and then we're going to
turn to the abrahamic stories.
And uh,
there are very complex set of stories.
They sit between the earliest stories in
genesis that I would say end with the
Tower of Babel.
And then the stories of Moses which are
extraordinarily well developed or the
abrahamic stories.
There's a whole sequence of them,
multiple stories conjoined together.
And uh,
there I found them very daunting.
They're very difficult to understand and
so I'm going to stumble through them the
best that I can.
I would say that's probably the best way
to think about this because they,
they,
they have a narrative content that's
quite strange.
Um,
I was reading a book while doing this
called the disappearance of God that I
found quite helpful.
And the author of that book argues that
one of the things that happens in the
old testament is that God is very
manifest at the beginning in terms of
personal appearances even,
and then that proclivity fades away as
the old testament develops and there's a
parallel development that it's mainly
maybe causally linked.
I'm not exactly sure how to
conceptualize it,
but it appears to be causally linked.
Is that the.
The stories about individuals become
more and more well developed so it's as
if it's as if as God fades away so to
speak,
the individual becomes more and more
manifest and there's a statement in the
Old Testament,
the location of which I don't recall,
but I'll tell you about it in future
lectures were God essentially tells
whoever he's speaking with and I don't
remember who that is,
that he's going to disappear and let man
essentially go his own way and see what
happens.
Not a complete disappearance,
but maybe a transformation to something
that modern people regard more as a
psychological phenomena rather than the
sort of objective entity that God to be
in the beginning of the biblical
stories.
And so I've been wrestling with that a
lot because the notion that God,
God appears to Abraham Multiple Times,
and that's not a concept that's easy for
modern people to to grasp in.
For us,
generally speaking,
apart from say,
issues of faith.
God isn't some thing.
Someone who makes himself personally
manifest in our lives.
He doesn't appear to us.
That's I suppose,
why the question of belief is so
paramount for modern people.
I presume that if God had was in the
habit of appearing to you,
you likely wouldn't have a problem with
belief.
I mean it might be more complicated than
that,
but that's how it seems to me.
And so when we read stories about God
making himself manifest either to a
nation,
say in the case of Israel or to
individuals,
it's not easy to understand.
It's not easy to understand why people
would write stories like that if they
thought like we thought.
And I mean really it wasn't that long
ago that the Bible was written,
say from a biological perspective,
it's really only yesterday.
It's a couple of thousand years,
say 40,000
years,
something like that.
That's not very long ago from a
biological perspective,
it's,
it's nothing.
So the first thing I tried to do is to
see if I could figure out how to
understand that.
And so I'll start the lecture.
Once we finished the,
the remains of,
of the story of Noah,
I'll start the lecture with a d with an
attempt to situate the abrahamic stories
in a context that might make them more
accessible.
These two contexts that worked for me to
make them more accessible.
Let's conclude the newest story first.
However,
when we ended last time,
the art had come to its resting place
and Noah and his family had debarked.
Uh,
and so this is the stories of what
occurs immediately after afterwards.
It's a very short story,
but I think it's very relevant for both
of these stories.
The Tower of Babel as well,
very relevant for our current times.
And the sons of Noah that went forth of
the Ark were shem and ham and Japheth,
and ham is the father of Canaan.
These are the three sons of Noah and of
them was the whole Earth overspread.
And Noah began to be a hud husbands men,
and he planted a vineyard and he drank
of the wine and was drunk,
and he was uncovered within his tent and
Ham.
The father of Canaan saw the nakedness
of his father and told his two brethren
without and Shem and Japheth took a
garment and laid upon both their
shoulders and went backward and covered
the nakedness of their father and their
faces were backward and they saw not
their father's nakedness.
And Noah awoke from his wine and knew
what his younger son had done unto him.
And he said,
curse it to be Canaan,
a servant of servants,
shall he be unto his brethren.
And he said,
blessed shall be the Lord God of
chairman.
Canaan shall be his servant and God
shall enlarge Japheth.
And he shall dwell in the tents of Shem
and Canaan shall be his servant.
And Noah lived after the flood,
350 years and all the days of Noah were
950 years.
And he died.
And the whole earth was of one language
and of one speech.
Okay,
so I remember thinking about this story.
It's got to be 30 years ago
and I think the meaning of the story
stood out for me.
Sometimes when you read complicated
material,
sometimes a piece of it will stand out.
It's for some reason it's like it
glitters.
I suppose that might be one way of
thinking about it.
It's it,
it you're in sync with it and you can
understand what it means.
I've really experienced that reading the
Tao Te Ching,
which is document I would really like to
do a lecture on at some point because
some of the verses I don't understand,
but others stand right out and I can
understand them and I think I understood
what this part of the story of.
No Amanda and I think it means,
you know,
we talked a little bit about what
nakedness meant in the story of Adam and
eve and the idea essentially was that to
know yourself naked is to become aware
of your vulnerability,
the physical,
your physical boundaries in time and
space and your,
your,
your physiological,
your fundamental physiological
insufficiencies as they make might be
judged by others.
So there's biological insufficiency that
sort of built into you because you're a
fragile mortal,
vulnerable half insane creature and
that's that's just an existential truth.
And then of course even merely as a
human being,
even with all those faults,
there are faults that you have that are
particular to you that might be judged
harshly by the group while might be,
we'll definitely be judged harshly by
the group.
And so to become aware of your nakedness
is to become self conscious and,
and to,
to know your limits and to know your
vulnerability.
And that's what is revealed to him when
he comes across his father naked.
It's.
So the question is,
what does it mean to see your father
naked?
And it seems to me,
and especially in an inappropriate
manner like this,
it,
it's,
it's as if
ham,
he does the same thing that happens in
the Mesopotamian creation myth.
When when timeout an absolute give rise
to the first God's there,
they're the father of the eventual
Deity of redemption.
Martech there are very careless and
noisy and they kill app sue their father
and attempt to inhabit his corpse and
that makes timeout enraged and so she
bursts forth from the darkness to do the
men.
It's like a precursor to the flood story
or an analog to the flood story and I
see the same thing happening here with
him is that he's.
He's insufficiently respectful of his
father and and the question is exactly
what does the farther represent and you
can say,
well there's,
there's,
there's the father that you have and
that's a human being.
That's,
that's a man like other men,
a man among men,
but then there's the father as such and
that's the spirit of the father and
insofar as you have a father,
you have both at the same time.
You have the personal father.
That's a man among other men just like
anyone out there,
his father,
but in so far as that man is your
father.
That means that he's something different
than just another person.
And what he is is the incarnation of the
spirit of the father.
And to see that,
to take it to what to disrespect that
carelessly,
maybe even like,
no,
it makes a mistake,
right?
He produces wine and gets himself drunk
and you might say,
well,
you know,
if he sprawled out there for everyone to
see,
it's hardly hams fault if he stumbles
across it,
but the book is laying out a danger and
the danger is that,
well,
maybe you catch your father at his most
vulnerable moment and if you're
disrespectful,
then you transgress against the spirit
of the father and if you transgress
against the spirit of father and lose
the spirit of the father and lose
respect for the spirit of the father,
then that is likely to transform you
into a slave.
That's a very interesting idea and I
think it's particularly interesting.
Maybe not particularly interesting,
but it's.
It's particularly Germane,
I think,
to our current cultural situation
because I think that were pushed
constantly to see the nakedness of our
father,
so to speak.
Because of the intense criticism that's
directed towards our culture and the
patriarchal culture,
so to speak.
We're constantly exposing its weaknesses
and vulnerabilities and let's say
nakedness and there's nothing wrong with
criticism,
but the thing about criticism is the
purpose of criticism is to separate the
wheat from the chaff.
It's not the burn everything to the
ground,
right?
It's to say,
well,
we're going to carefully look at this.
We're going to carefully differentiate.
We're going to keep what's good and
we're going to move away from what's
bad,
but the point of the criticism isn't to
identify everything is bad.
It's two separate.
What's good from what's bad so that you
can retain what's good and move towards
it and to be careless at that is deadly
because you inhabited by the spirit of
the father,
right in so far as you're a cultural
construction,
which of course is something that the
the postmodern neo Marxists are
absolutely in phatic about.
You're a cultural construction in so far
as you're a cultural construction.
Then your inhabited by the spirit of the
father and to be disrespectful towards
that means to undermine the very
structure that makes you not all of what
you are.
Certainly,
certainly not all of what you are,
but a good portion of what you are in so
far as you're a socialized cultural
entity and if you pull out,
if you pull the foundation out from
underneath that,
what do you have left?
You can hardly manage on your own,
you know,
it's just not possible.
You're a cultural
creation and so hamm makes this
desperate error and is careless about
exposing himself to the vulnerability of
his father.
Something like that.
He does it without sufficient respect
and the judgment is that not only will
he be a slave,
but so will all of his descendants and
he's contrasted with the other two sons
who I suppose are willing to give their
father the benefit of the doubt,
something like that.
And so when they see him in a
compromising position,
they handle it with respect and,
and,
and don't capitalize on it.
And maybe that makes them strong.
That's what it seems to me.
And so I think that's what that story
means.
It has something to do with respect.
You know?
And the funny thing about having respect
for your culture,
and I suppose that's partly why I'm
doing the biblical stories,
is because they're part of,
they're part of my culture.
They're part of our culture perhaps,
but they're certainly part of my culture
and it seems to me that
it's worthwhile to treat that with
respect to see what you can glean from
it
and,
and not kick it when it's down,
let's say.
So.
And so that's how the story of no ends,
you know.
And the thing too is Noah is actually a
pretty decent incarnation of the spirit
of the father.
That which I suppose is one of the
things that makes Hams misstep more
egregious is that,
I mean,
Noah just built an ark and God everybody
through the flood man,
you know,
it's not so bad in.
So maybe the fact that he happened to
drink too much wine one day wasn't
enough to justify humiliating him.
And you know,
I don't think it's pushing the limits of
symbolic interpretation to note on a
daily basis that were all contained in
an arc.
Right.
And that's the arc that you could think
about that as the arc that's been
bequeathed to us by our forefathers.
That's the tremendous infrastructure
that we inhabit,
that we take for granted because it
works so well.
That protects us from things that we
can't even imagine.
And we don't have to imagine because
we're so well protected.
And so one of the things that's really
struck me hard,
I would say about the disintegration and
corruption of the universities is the
absolute in gratitude that goes along
with that.
Criticism,
as I said,
is for fine thing.
If it's done in the spirit in a proper
spirit and that's the spirit of
separating the wheat from the chaff.
But it needs to be accompanied by
gratitude.
And it does seem to me that anyone who
lives in in the west,
in the western culture at this time,
in history and in this place and who
isn't simultaneously grateful for that
is is,
is half blind at least because it's
never been better than this.
And it could be so much worse.
And it's highly likely that it will be
so much worse.
Because for most of human history,
so much worse is the norm.
So
then there's this little story that
crops up that seems in some ways
unrelated to everything that's gone
before it,
but I think it's also an extremely
profound little story.
It took me a long time to figure it out.
It's the tower of Babel and it came to
pass as they journeyed from the east,
that they found a plain in the land of
Shinar and dwelt there.
That's Noah's descendants.
And the whole earth was of one language
and of one speech and it came to pass as
they journeyed from the east,
that they found a plain in the land of
Shinar and they dwelt there and they
said to one another,
go,
let us make brick and burn them
thoroughly.
And they had brick for stone and slime
they had for mortar.
So they're establishing a city.
And they said,
go.
Let us build a city and a tower whose
top may reach unto heaven and let us
make a name lest we be scattered abroad
upon the face of the earth.
And the Lord came down to see the city.
And the tower which the children of men
built,
and the Lord said,
behold the people is one and they all
have one language and now this they
begin to do,
and now nothing will be restrained from
them,
which they have imagined to do.
Go to let us go down and there confound
their language that they may not
understand one another's speech,
so the Lord scattered them abroad from
thence upon the face of all the earth,
and they left off to build the city,
therefore is the name of it called Babel
because the Lord did there confound the
language of all the earth.
And from thence did the Lord scatter
them abroad upon the face of the earth.
Very difficult story to understand.
It's on the face of it.
It doesn't seem to show God in a very
good light,
although that happens fairly frequently
in the old testament as far as I can
tell,
but
you know the thing to do if you're
reading in the spirit of the text,
let's say,
is to remember that it's God that you're
talking about.
And so even though you might think that
he's appearing in a bad light,
your duty as a reader,
I suppose is to assume that you're wrong
and that what he did was right,
and then you're supposed to figure out,
well,
how could it possibly be right?
Because the axiomatic presupposition is
that it's God and whatever he does is
right,
and you might say,
well,
you can disagree with that.
And it's also the case that some of the
people that God talks to in the Old
Testament actually disagree with him and
convince him to alter his actions.
But the point still remains that it's
gone.
And if he's doing it,
then by definition there's a good
reason.
There's an idea of much later that John
Melton develops in in paradise lost,
which is an amazing home.
And it,
it's,
it's a profound enough poems so that
it's almost been incorporated into the
biblical structure.
I would say.
So the Corpus of Christianity Post
Milton was saturated by the mill tonic
stories of Satan's rebellion.
None of that's in the,
in the,
in the biblical texts or it's only
hinted at in very brief passages.
And Milton wrote his poem to justify the
ways of God to man,
which is quite an ambition,
really.
It's an amazing,
profound ambition to try to produce
something to produce a literary work
that justifies being to human beings
because that's what Milton was trying to
do.
Something.
One of my readers here sent me a link
the other day or our viewers to a work
of philosophy by an Australian
philosopher whose name I don't remember
who basically wrote a book saying that
being as such human experience is so
corrupt and so permeated by suffering,
that it would be better if it had never
existed at all.
Sort of the ultimate expression of
nihilism and Gertha in faust.
His mephistopheles who's Santana
character obviously has that as a credo.
That's Satan's fundamental motivation is
his objection to creation itself is that
creation is so flawed and so rife with
suffering that it would be better if it
had never existed at all,
and so that's his motivation for
attempting to continue to destroy it in
Milton's Paradise Lost Satan as an
intellectual figure and you see that
motif emerged very frequently by the way
in popular culture.
So for example,
in the lion king,
the figure of scar who's a satanic
figure is also hyper intellectual and
that's very common that you know it's
the evil scientist Motif or the or the
evil advisor to the king,
the same motif.
It encapsulate something about
rationality and what it seems to
encapsulate as the idea that rationality
like Satan is the highest angel in God's
heavenly kingdom.
It's a psychological idea.
You know that the most powerful sub
element of the human psyche is the
intellect and it's the thing that shines
out above all within the domain of
humanity and maybe across the domain of
life itself.
The human intellect.
There's something absolutely remarkable
about it,
but it has a flaw and the floor is that
it tends to fall in love with its own
productions and to assume that their
total solzhenitsyn,
when he was writing the Gulag
archipelago had a warning about that
with regards to totalitarian ideology
and he said that the price of selling
your God given sole to the entrapments
of of human dogma was slavery and death
essentially,
and Satan in May in Milton's paradise
lost.
Satan decides that he can do without the
transcendent.
He can do without God,
and that's why foment rebellion.
It's something like that and the
consequences of that.
The immediate consequence from Milton's
perspective was that as soon as Satan
decided that what he knew was sufficient
and that he could do without the
transcendent,
which you might think about as the
domain outside of what you know,
something like that.
Immediately he was inhale and when I
read paradise lost,
I was studying totalitarianism and I
thought,
you know,
the poet,
the true poet,
like a prophet is someone who has
intimations of the future.
And maybe that's because the poetic
mind,
the philosophical or prophetic mind is a
pattern detector and,
and there are people who can detect the
underlying.
It's like the melody of nation,
melody in Song,
the song of a nation and could see how
it's going to develop across the
centuries.
You see this,
you see that nature because nature,
for example,
in the mid,
around 18,
60 or so,
and he prophesied what was going to
happen in the 20th century.
He said that he said specifically that
the specter of communism would kill
millions of people in the 20th century.
It's amazing prophecy.
He said that in the notes that became
will to power and Dostoevsky was of the
same sort of mind.
Someone who was in touch enough with the
fundamental patterns of,
of,
of human movement that they could
extrapolate out into the future and see
what was coming.
And I mean,
some people are very good at detecting
patterns.
And,
and,
uh,
Milton I think was of that sort and I
think he had intimations of what was
coming.
As human rationality became more and
more powerful.
Technology became more and more
powerful.
And the intimation
was that we would produce systems that
dispensed with God,
that we're completely rational and
completely total that would immediately
turn everything they touched into
something indistinguishable from hell.
And in Milton's warning was embodied in
the poem,
is that the rational mind that generates
a production and then worships it as if
it's absolute immediately occupies hell.
So what does that have to do with the
Tower of Babel?
Well,
you know what?
Back in 2008,
when the,
when,
when we had that economic collapse,
the strange idea emerged politically and
that was the idea of too big to fail.
And I thought about that idea for a long
time because I thought there's something
deeply wrong with that is one of the
things that made marks wrong was Marx
believed that capital would flow into
the hands of fewer and fewer people and
that the dissociation between the rich
and the poor would become more extreme
as capitalism developed.
And like so many things that mark said,
that's kind of true.
It's kind of true in that
the distribution of wealth and in fact
the distribution of anything that's
produced follows a peritoneal pattern
and the prieto pattern basically is that
a small proportion of people end up with
a bulk of the goods and it isn't just
money.
It's,
it's anything that people produce,
creatively ends up in that distribution
and that's actually the economists
called up the matthew principle and they
take that from US statement in the New
Testament and the statement is to those
who have everything more will be given
and from those who have nothing.
Everything will be taken and it's.
It's a map of the manner in which the
world manifests itself where human
creative production is involved and the
map seems to indicate that as you start
to produce and you're successful,
the probability that you will continue
to be successful or accelerate increases
as you're successful.
And as you fail.
The probability that you will fail
starts to accelerate.
So in your progress through life looks
like this or like this.
Something like that.
And the reason that Marx was right was
because he noted that as a feature of
the capitalist system,
the reason that he was wrong is that
it's not a feature that's specific to a
capitalist system.
It's a feature that's general to all
systems of creative production that are
known and so it's like a natural law and
it's enough of a natural law by the way,
that the distribution of wealth can be
modeled by physical models using the
same equations that govern the
distribution of gas molecules in a
vacuum.
So it's a really profound,
it's a fundamentally profound
observation about the way the world lays
itself out and it's problematic because
if resources accrue unfairly to a small
minority of people and there's a natural
law like element to that that has to be
dealt with from a social perspective
because if the inequality becomes too
extreme,
then the whole system will destabilize.
And so you can have an intelligent
discussion about how to mitigate the
effects of the transfer of creative
production into the hands of a small
number of people.
Now,
the other reason,
however,
having said that,
the other reason that Marx was wrong,
there's a number of them.
One is that even though
creative products end up in the hands of
a small number of people,
it's not the same people consistently
across time.
It's the same proportion of people and
that's not the same thing.
You know,
like imagine that there's water going
down a drain and you say,
well,
look at the spiral.
It's permanent.
You think,
well,
the spirals permanent,
but the water molecules aren't.
They're moving through it and it's the
same in some sense with the prieto
distribution is that there's a one
percent and there's always a one
percent,
but it's not the same people.
It's the stability of it differs from
culture to culture,
but there's a lot of movement in the
upper one percent,
a tremendous amount of movement and one
of the reasons for that movement is that
things get large and then they get too
large and then they collapse.
And so in 2008,
when the politicians said too big to
fail,
they got something truly backwards as
far as I can tell.
And that was,
it was a reverse.
The statement was reversed.
It should have been so big it had to
fail.
And that's what I think the story of the
Tower of Babel is about.
It's a warning against the expansion of
the system
until it encompasses everything.
It's a warning against totalitarian
presumption.
So what happens,
for example,
when people set out to build the Tower
of Babel,
is they want to build a structure that
reaches to have it right?
So the idea is that it can,
it can,
it can replace,
it,
can replace the role of God.
It's something like that.
It can erase the distinction between
Earth and heaven.
And so there's a utopian kind of vision
there as well as we can build a
structure that's so large and
encompassing that,
that,
that it can replace heaven itself.
That's an interesting.
The fact that that doesn't work and that
God objects to it is also
extraordinarily interesting and it's an
indication to me of the unbelievable
profundity of these stories.
It's like I think one thing we should
have learned from the 20th century,
but of course didn't was that there's
something extraordinary dangerous
totalitarian,
utopian visions at something Dostoevsky
wrote about,
by the way,
in his great book notes from underground
because Dostoevsky had figured out by
the early 19 hundreds that there was
something very,
very pathological about a utopian vision
of perfection,
that it was profoundly anti human and
and notes and notes from underground.
He demolishes the notion of Utopia.
One of the things he says that I loved,
it's so brilliant,
he said,
imagine that you brought the socialist
utopia into being and dusty,
Esq says that human beings had nothing
to do except
eat,
drink,
and busy themselves with the
continuation of the species.
He said that the first thing that would
happen under circumstances like that
would be that human beings would go mad
and break the system,
smash it just so that something
unexpected and crazy could happen
because human beings don't want Utopian
comfort and certainty.
They want adventure and chaos and
uncertainty,
and so that the very notion of a utopia
was anti human because we're not built
for static utopia.
We're built for a dynamic situation
where there's demands placed on us and
where there's the optimal amount of
uncertainty.
Well,
we know what happened in the 20th
century as a consequence of the
widespread promulgation of Utopian
schemes and what happened was a ham on a
scale that had never been matched in the
entire history of humanity and that's
really saying something because
there was plenty of mayhem before the
20th century.
I guess there wasn't as much industrial
clout behind it and so,
so early.
See so early in the biblical narrative,
you have a warning against Hubris and
and some indication that properly
functioning systems have an appropriate
scale.
I read an article in the Economist
magazine this week about the rise of
nationalist movements all over the world
as a counterbalance to globalization.
Maybe it's most market with the European
Economic Community and the economist
writers.
We're curious about why that counter
movement has been developing,
but it seems to me that it's also a
tower of Babel phenomena is that maybe
this is most evident in the European
Economic Community to bring all of that
multiplicity under the,
what would you call it,
under the umbrella of a single unity is
to similar caneously erect a system
where the top is so far from the bottom
that the bottom has no connection.
The top,
you know,
your,
your social systems have to be large
enough so they protect you,
but small enough so that you have a
place in them and it seems to me perhaps
that's what's happened in places like
the EEC,
is that the distance between the typical
citizen and the bureaucracy that runs
the entire structure has got so great
that it's an element of destabilization
in and of itself,
and so people revert back to say
nationalistic identities because it's
something that they can relate to it.
There's A.
There's a history there and a shared
identity,
a genuine identity,
an identity of language and tradition.
That's not an artificial imposition from
the top and artificial abstract
imposition in in the Egyptian creation
myth.
The version I'm familiar most familiar
with in the previous creation myth,
the older one,
the Mesopotamian creation myth,
mostly what you see menacing humanity is
tie matt.
She's the dragon of chaos and so that's
nature.
It's really,
it's really mother nature,
red in tooth and claw,
but by the time the Egyptians come
along,
it isn't only nature that threatens
humanity.
It's the social structure itself,
and so the Egyptians had two daddies
that represented the social structure
and one was,
oh,
cyrus,
who was like the spirit of the father.
He was a great hero who established
Egypt but became old and and willfully
blind and and,
and,
and senile,
and he had an evil brother named seth,
and Seth was always conspiring to
overthrow him.
And because Cyrus ignored him long
enough,
seth did overthrow chopped up into
pieces and distributed all around the
kingdom on his son.
Horace had to come back and fight.
Well,
Cyrus's son,
horace had to come back and defeat seth
to take the kingdom back.
And that's how that story ends.
But the Egyptian seem to have realized
maybe because they had become
bureaucratized to quite a substantial
degree,
that it wasn't only nature that
threatened humankind.
It was also the proclivity of human
organizations to become too large,
too unwieldy to deceitful and to
willfully blind and therefore liable to
collapse.
And again,
I see echoes of that in this story of
the Tower of Babel.
So it's a calling for I kind of humility
of social engineering.
One of the other things I've learned as
a social scientist,
and I've been warned about this by I
would say great social scientists,
that you want to be very careful about
doing large scale experimentation with
large scale systems because the
probability that if you implement a
scheme in a large scale social system
that that scheme will have the result
you intended is negligible.
What will happen will be something that
you don't intend and even worse,
something that works at counter purposes
to your original intent and so and that
that makes sense.
Because if you have a very,
very complex system and you perturb it,
the probability that you can predict the
consequences of the perturbation is
extraordinary low.
Obviously if the system works though,
you think you understand it because it
works and so you think it's simpler than
it actually is,
and so then you think that you're more
love.
It is correct,
and then you think that your
manipulation of the model which produces
the outcome new model will be the
outcome that's actually produced in the
world.
That doesn't work at all.
I thought about that an awful lot
thinking about how to remediate social
systems because obviously they need
careful attention and adjustment and it
struck me that the proper
strategy for implementing social change
is to stay within your domain of
competence and that requires humility,
which is a virtue that is never
promoted in modern culture.
I would say it's.
It's a virtue that you can hardly even
talk about,
but humility means you probably not as
smart as you think you are and you
should be careful.
And so then the question might be,
well,
okay,
you should be careful,
but perhaps you still want to do good,
you want to make some positive changes,
how can you be careful and do good?
And then I would say,
well,
you try not to step outside of the
boundaries of your competence and you
start small and you start with things
that you actually could adjust that you
actually do understand,
that you actually could fix.
I mentioned to you at one point that one
of the things Carl Jung said was that
modern men don't see God because they
don't look low enough.
So very interesting phrase,
and one of the things that I've been
promoting,
I suppose online is the idea that you
should restrict your attempts to fix
things to what's at hand.
So there's probably things about you
that you could fix,
right?
Things that you know that aren't right,
not anyone else's opinion,
your own opinion that aren't right.
You can fix them.
Maybe there's some things that you could
adjust in your family.
Although that gets hard.
You have to have your act together a lot
before you can to adjust your family
because things can kick back on you
really hard and you think,
well,
it's hard to put yourself together.
It's really hard to put your family
together.
Why the hell do you think you can put
the world together?
Right?
Because obviously the world is more
complicated than you and your family,
and so if you.
If you're stymied in your attempts even
to set your own house in order,
which of course you are,
then you would think that what that
would do would be to make you very,
very leery about announcing your broad
scale plans for social revolution.
Well,
it's a peculiar thing because that isn't
how it works because people are much
more likely to announce their plans for
broad scale social revolution than they
are to try to set themselves straight or
to set their family's straight and I
think the reason for that is that as
soon as they tried to set themselves
straight or their families,
the system immediately kicks back at
them right instantly.
Whereas if they announced their plans
for large scale social revolution,
the lag between the announcement and the
kickback is so long that they don't
recognize that there's any error there
and so you know,
you can get away with being wrong if,
if,
if nothing falls on you for a while and
so,
and it's also an incitement to hubris
because you can now see your,
your plans for large scale social
revolution and stand back and you don't
get hit by lightning and you think,
well,
I might be right even though you're not.
You're seriously not right.
I might be right.
And then you think,
well,
how wonderful is that?
Especially if you could do it without
any real effort.
And I really do think fundamentally,
I believe that that's what universities
teach students now.
That's what they teach them to do.
I really believe that and I think it's
absolutely appalling and I think it's
horribly dangerous because it's not that
easy to fix things,
especially if you don't.
Especially if you're not committed to
it.
And I think you know,
if you're committed because what you try
to do is you try to straighten out your
own life first and that's enough.
I think it's a statement in the new
testament that it's.
I think it's in the new testament that
it's more difficult to rule yourself
than to rule the city and that's not a
metaphor.
It's like all of you who've made
announcements to yourself about changing
your diet and going to the gym every
January know perfectly well.
How difficult it is to regulate your own
impulses and to bring yourself under the
control of some.
What would you say?
Well structured and ethical,
attentive structure of values.
It's extraordinarily difficult.
And so people don't do it and instead
they wander off and I think they create
towers of Babel and the story indicates,
well those things collapse under their
own weight and everyone goes their own
direction.
I think I see that happening with the
lgbt community.
I think because one of the things I've
noticed,
it's very interesting because the
community is in some sense it's not a
community,
but
that's a technical error,
but it's.
It's composed of outsiders,
let's say,
and what you notice across the decades
is that the acronym list keeps growing
and I think that's because there's an
infinite number of ways to be an
outsider and so once you open the door
to the construction of a group that's
characterized by failing to fit into the
group,
then you immediately create a category
that's infinitely expandable and so I
don't know how long the acronym list is
now.
It depends on which acronym list you
consult,
but I've seen lists of 10 or more
acronyms and one of the things that's
happening is that the community is
starting to fragment in its in its
interior because there is no unity.
Once you put a sufficient plurality
under the sheltering structure of a
single umbrella,
say the disunity starts to appear
within,
and I think that's also a.
it's a manifestation of the same issue
that this particular story is dealing
with.
So that ends,
I would say,
the most archaic stories in the Bible.
There's something about the flood story
and and also the Tower of Babel.
I think they outline the two fundamental
dangers that be set mankind.
One is the probability that
blindness and sin will produce a natural
catastrophe or entice one.
That's something modern people are very
aware of in principle,
right?
Because we're all hyper concerned about
environmental degradation and
catastrophe and so that's the continual
reactivation of an architectural idea in
our,
in our unconscious minds that there's
something about the way we're living
that's unsustainable and that will
create a catastrophe and so interesting
because people believe that firmly and
deeply and but they don't see the
relationship between that and the
archetypal stories because it's the same
story.
Overconsumption greed,
all of that is producing an unstable
state and nature will rebel and take us
down.
Right?
You hear that every day in every
newspaper and every TV station.
It's broadcast to you constantly,
so that idea is presented in,
in Genesis,
in the story of Noah,
and then the other warning that exists
in the stories.
One is beware of natural catastrophe
that's produced as a consequence of
blindness and greed will say the other
is be aware of social structures.
That overreach because it'll also
produce fragmentation and
disintegration,
and so it's quite remarkable.
I think that that with at the close of
the story of the Tower of Babel,
we've got both of the permanent
existential dangers that present
themselves to humanity already
identified
at the end of the story of Adam and eve.
There's like a fall into history,
right?
So in one way history begins with the
fall,
but there's like a second fall,
I think with the flood in the Tower of
Babel and history in even more real
sense begins now.
It begins with the story of Abraham and
and it's,
it's.
We're no longer precisely in the realm
of the purely mythical.
That would be another way of thinking
about it.
We have identifiable person who's part
of an identifiable tribe,
who's doing identifiable things.
We're in the realm of history and so
history begins twice in the Old
Testament.
I suppose it begins again after Moses as
well,
but we've moved out of the domain of the
purely mythical into the realm of
history with the emergence of the
stories about Abraham.
This is from Elvis Huxley.
So the first thing that that I want to
talk about in relationship to the
abrahamic stories is this idea of the
experience of God,
because Abraham,
although quite identifiable as an actual
individual,
is also characterized by this
peculiarity and the peculiarity is that
God manifests himself to Abraham.
Both has a voice and but also as a
presence.
The story is never described exactly how
God manifests himself except now and
then he comes in the form of an angel
that's fairly concrete,
but it's a funny thing that the author
of or authors of the Abrahamic stories
seems to take the idea that God would
make an appearance more or less for
granted,
and so it's very.
I think the part of the reason that I've
struggled so much with the abrahamic
stories is because it's so hard to get a
handle on that and to understand what
that might mean and so I'm going to hit
it from a bunch of different
perspectives and we'll see if we can
come up with some understanding of it.
The first thing I'll do is tell you a
story about female neurologist whose
name escapes me at the moment.
She wrote a book called my stroke of
insight.
Jill bolte a I think is her name,
and she was a harvard trained.
She was.
She had.
She had medical training from Harvard in
neuropsychological function and knew a
lot about hemispheric specialization.
We talked a little bit about hemispheric
specialization before.
One of the ways of conceptualizing the
difference between the two hemispheres
is that the left hemisphere operates in
unknown territory and the right
hemisphere operates in unknown
territory.
That's one way of thinking about or the
left hemisphere operates in the orderly
domain.
In the right hemisphere operates in the
chaotic domain or the left hemisphere
operates in the domain of detail,
and the right hemisphere operates in the
domain of the large picture.
It's something like that.
Now people differ in their neurological
wiring,
so those are over generalizations,
but that's okay.
We're.
We'll live with that for the time being.
It's certainly not an overgeneralization
to point out that you do in fact have
two hemispheres and that their
structures differ and if the connections
between the market which could happen,
for example,
if you had surgery for intractable
epilepsy,
that each hemisphere would be capable of
housing its own consciousness that's
been well documented by a neural neural
neurologist named [inaudible] who did
and Sperry who did split brain
experiments must be 30 years ago now,
so and we know that the right and the
left hemisphere are specialized for
different functions.
The Right Hemisphere,
for example,
seems to be more involved in
degeneration of negative emotion and the
left hemisphere more involved in the
generation of positive emotion and
approach.
So the right hemisphere stops you in the
left hemisphere,
moves you forward.
Anyways,
Jill Bolty,
I hope I've got that right.
Had a stroke and maintained
consciousness during the stroke and
analyzed it while it was happening and
she was able.
Well,
it was happening to hypothesize about
what part of her brain was being
destroyed and what.
So she had a congenital blood vessel
malformation and had an aneurysm and it
just about killed her.
But she said that it affected her left
hemisphere and she said that she
experienced a sense of divine unity as a
consequence of the stroke because the
left hemisphere function was disrupted
and destroyed and so she became a right
hemisphere dominant and her experience
of that was the disillusion of the
specific ego into the into absolute
consciousness,
something like that.
Now that's only a case study and you
don't want to make too much of case
studies,
but there is an overwhelming amount of
evidence that those two kinds of
consciousness exist.
One being your consciousness of you as a
localized and specified being and the
other being this capacity to experience
oceanic disillusion and the sense of the
cosmos being one.
Now why we have those capacities for
different conscious experiences is very
difficult to understand.
I mean,
part of me thinks that maybe we have a
generic human brain that's the brain of
the species and allied with that.
We have a specific individual brain and
one is the left hemisphere and the other
is the right hemisphere,
the left hemisphere of being the
specific individual brain,
and usually it's on and working because
you obviously have to take care of
yourself as a specific entity and not as
a generalized cosmic phenomena.
It's hard to dice salary when you're a
generalized cosmic phenomena,
right?
So you have to be more pointed than
that,
but,
but look,
let's make no mistake about it.
The fact that those different states of
consciousness exist is not disputable.
They can be elicited in all sorts of
ways,
and so I'm going to read you something
that Elvis Huxley wrote about this back
I think in 1956.
This was after he started his
experimentation with masculine because
the psychedelics were introduced into
Western culture in the 19 fifties and
whole bunch of different ways.
Siliciden mushrooms,
Lsd was discovered right at the end of
World War II was discovered by accident.
Actually Laboratory sandow was labs.
The guy who discovered it,
Albert Hoffman had spilled some on his
hands.
You can absorb it through your skin,
and he was biking home and had the
world's first LSD trip,
which was somewhat of a shock to him and
then to the entire world.
Huxley,
who was a great literary figure,
a real genius.
I'm experimented with masculine in the
late fifties,
and he wrote a book called the doors of
perception,
which had a huge impact on the emerging
psychedelic culture,
both on the east coast,
at Harvard and on the West Coast with
Ken keyes.
He and his merry pranksters,
the people who popularized lsd.
That's all documented in a book called
the electric koolaid acid test,
which I would highly recommend.
It's Tom Wolf.
It's brilliant book.
I'm on east coast.
It was timothy leary.
I had timothy leary's old job at
Harvard,
so that was kind of cool,
you know,
warped way.
So I met people there who knew him,
who didn't think much of them also,
but who did know him,
but Huxley had this masculine experience
and it transported him to this
alternative consciousness.
And he said that during his masculine
experience that the entire world glowed
from within.
Like if there was an inner light,
like a paradisical inner light,
and then everything was deeply
meaningful and symbolically suggestive
and overwhelming and beautiful and
timeless,
so he had an experience of divine
eternity,
I suppose is this most straightforward
way to to put that and we know perfectly
well that the psychedelic drugs that all
share the same chemical structure,
they interact with the brain chemical
called Serotonin,
which is a very,
very fundamental neurotransmitter.
They all have approximately the same
range of effects,
although those effects are very.
There's a very large multitude of
effects that that sort of exists.
Underneath that umbrella.
Huxley was
staggered by his masculine experience.
He,
he didn't really know what to make of it
and I think that that's the common
experience of people who have
exceptionally profound psychedelic
experiences.
And I'll,
I'll,
I'll tell you some documentation about
that in a moment,
but he spent quite a long time trying to
come to grips with what this might mean
from an intellectual perspective.
And Huxley had a great brain.
I mean,
if someone was going to wrestle with a
problem like that,
he was a good candidate.
He must've had a verbal Iq of 180,
I mean he's.
His books are incredibly literate,
incredible,
incredible mastery of language and
complexity of characterization and and
intellectual discourse.
Really remarkable.
So this is what Huxley had to say after
his masculine experience.
He talked about heaven and hell and he
talked about that in reference to bad
trips essentially because it was known
by that point that a psychedelic
experience could transport you to an
ecstatic domain of divine revelation,
but could take you to the worst
imaginable place as well.
And Huxley was very interested in why
you would even have the capacity for
experiences like that and which I think
is a very good question and it's
completely unanswered question.
I mean,
we don't know much about consciousness
and we know even less about
psychedelics.
I would say they are an absolute
mystery.
I don't think we understand them in the
least.
Huxley did a good job of starting to at
least map out the mysteries of the
terrain.
He said like the earth of 100 years ago,
our minds still has its darkest
Africa's.
It's unmapped,
bordeauxs and Amazonian basins in
relation to the fauna of these regions.
We are not yet zoologists.
We are mere naturalists and collectors
of specimens.
The fact is unfortunate,
but we have to accept it.
We have to make the best of it.
However lowly the work of the collector
must be done before we can proceed to
the higher scientific tasks of
classification,
analysis,
experiment and theory making like the
giraffe and the duck billed.
Platypus.
The creatures inhabiting these remoter
regions of the mind are exceedingly
improbable.
Nevertheless,
the exists they're facts of observation
and as such they cannot be ignored by
anyone who was honestly trying to
understand the world in which he lives.
When psychiatrist started to study lsd
that was mostly in the late fifties and
running forward from that,
they thought about the drug has a
psychotomimetic which was a chemical
substance that would induce psychosis,
but that turned out to not be true,
not with the psychedelics because
schizophrenia were given lsd and the
schizophrenia reported that while the
experience experience with certainly
extraordinarily strange,
it wasn't like being schizophrenia and
then it was found later that if you gave
schizophrenia amphetamines,
that made them worse.
In fact,
you can induce a paranoid psychosis in a
normal person by overdosing them with
amphetamines,
so whatever the hallucinogens or
psychedelics are doing,
it's not the same thing as mania and
it's not the same thing as
schizophrenia.
Not at all.
So,
so you can't just write the experience
off as and induced psychosis,
whatever it is,
independent of its utility or lack
thereof.
It's not that
now it can be induced by drugs can be
induced by deprivation,
right?
I mean,
there are accounts throughout history of
people putting themselves in the extreme
physiological situations in order to
induce transformations of consciousness.
Fasting is one of the routes to doing
that.
Dancing is another root isolation,
prolonged periods of isolation will also
do it.
Now you could say that exposing yourself
to any of those nxs produces a state
that's in distinguishable from illness
and that there's no reason to assume
that the phenomena that are associated
with illness have any utility
whatsoever.
Although it's interesting to me that
a disrupted consciousness can produce
coherent experiences.
It's not exactly what you'd expect if it
was just an illness.
You know,
if you develop,
say a high fever,
your experience isn't transcendent and
coherent.
It's fragmented in pathologized and and
the difference I think is quite
distinct.
Although we don't only.
We don't have to only speculate about
that because there's been enough
experimental work done now with with
hallucinogens.
Psychedelics to indicate that the notion
that what they produce is something
that's only akin to pathology is wrong
because it's not a matter of opinion at
this point in the sequence of scientific
and historical investigation.
In fact,
there was a large scale study done 10
years ago,
five years ago,
of 200,000
people who had experimented with
psychedelics and they were mentally and
physically healthier than people who
hadn't on virtually every parameter.
They examined,
in fact the rate of flashbacks.
You heard of LSD flashbacks,
that mostly a hypothetical phenomena,
but the rate of self reported flashbacks
was higher among the non psychedelic
users that among the psychedelic users,
so that was very interesting.
It was a huge study.
Now it might be,
you could say that those who had
experimented with psychedelics were
prone to be healthier to begin with,
but that still contradicts the pathology
argument,
so it doesn't matter either way.
The pathology argument is contradicted
now.
Oh,
I didn't put that in.
It was Dr Jill,
Jill Bolte Taylor.
This is what she said about her stroke.
I remember that first day of the stroke
with terrific bittersweetness.
In the absence of the normal functioning
of my left orientation association area,
my perception of my physical boundaries
was no longer limited to where my skin
met air.
I felt like a genie liberated from its
bottle.
It's a good metaphor.
The energy of my spirit seemed to flow
like a great whale gliding through a sea
of silent euphoria.
The absence of physical boundary was one
of glorious bliss recently.
It's Dr Roland Griffith.
I met him once at a conference in San
Francisco.
Surprise,
surprise.
I conference on awe and this was just
when he was embarking on his experiments
with Psilocybin,
which were the first experiments on
hallucinogens that were permitted by the
National Institute of Mental Health in
some three,
four decades.
He,
he had to be very careful to lay out the
scientific protocols so that the ethics
committees would approve the experiments
and so that the federal funding agencies
would also allow the experiments to go
through.
He started to experiment with silicide
man and he's found a number of and
published a number of very interesting
results.
One was that a single siliciden trip and
I specify trip because sometimes when
people take psilocybin at the doses that
griffith uses,
they don't have a psychedelic
experience.
Most people who take the dose do,
but not everyone.
Those who take the dos and don't have
the mystical experience don't
experienced the consequences of taking
the drug and the consequences can be
quite profound,
so one consequence is that if you have
the mystical experience that's
associated with suicide than ingestion,
you're liable to
represent that to others and yourself as
one of the two or three most important
experiences of your entire life,
so that would be at the same level as
the birth of your child or your
marriage,
let's say assuming that those were
transcendent experiences,
but,
but that's,
but that's how people describe them.
So that's very interesting in and of
itself.
Then the next thing that griffith,
another thing that Griffith reported was
that one year after a silicide than dose
a single psilocybin dose profound enough
to induce a mystical experience,
that trait openness of the participants
had increased one standard deviation,
which is a tremendous amount,
and so it looked like one dose produced
a permanent neurological and
psychological.
Now I'm not saying that that's a good
thing.
I'm not saying that because I don't
think that openness is a n troubled
blessing,
but it's certainly a testament to the
unbelievable potency of the of the
drugs.
There's about a 10 percent chance by the
way,
with suicide,
but ingestion of a trip to hell,
and so that's certainly something very
much worth considering when you're
thinking about the potential effects of
this kind of experience.
So the mystical experience produced by
Psilocybin is rated by people as the
most profound,
among the most profound experience of
their life as life changing.
It produces permanent personality
transformations.
80 five percent success in smoking
cessation with a single dose,
right?
That's another thing that griffiths
demonstrated.
Now that is mind boggling because there
are chemical treatments for smoking
cessation.
Buproprion is one.
It reduces craving to some degree,
but it's success rate is nowhere near 85
percent,
certainly not with a single dose,
and so we don't understand how it can be
that that occurs,
but it's nicely documented by Griffith
team in this experiment he gave
Psilocybin to people who are dying of
cancer.
Cancer patients often develop chronic
clinically significant symptoms of
depression and anxiety.
Previous study suggested Siliciden may
decrease depression and anxiety and
cancer patients.
Aldous Huxley took Lsd on his death bed
by the way,
so the idea that there was something
about psychedelic substances that could
buffer people against the catastrophes
of mortality is an idea that's as old as
experimentation with the drug itself.
The effects of Siliciden were studied in
51 cancer patients with life threatening
diagnosis and symptoms of depression and
or anxiety.
Unsurprisingly,
I don't really know if it's reasonable
to describe the emotional state of
people diagnosed with cancer of
uncertain prognosis or mortal
significance as depression.
Precisely.
You know,
you know what I mean is that if you go
to the doctor and he tells you that you
have intractable fatal cancer,
the normative response is to be rather
upset and anxious about that,
and so it.
One of the things that bothers me about
clinical psychiatry and clinical
psychology is the automatic
presupposition that even overwhelming
states of negative emotion are properly
categorized as depression because I
don't think you're depressed when you
get a cancer diagnosis.
I don't think that's the right way to
think about it.
I think that you have a big and
it's not surprising that you're
overwhelmed by negative emotion and to
think about that as a psychiatric
malfunction is a major error,
but anyways,
it's a side issue with regards to this
study.
The effects of Psilocybin were studied
in 51 cancer patients with life
threatening diagnosis and symptoms of
depression and or anxiety.
I cannot imagine how they got this
through an ethics committee.
It's just we're going to take people who
have uncertain diagnosis of cancer that
are potentially life threatening and
we're going to give them psychedelics.
It's like,
but they did it.
They did it and I think it's a testament
to griffiths stature as a researcher
that that that was allowable.
This was a randomized double blind
crossover trial.
Very carefully designed clinical
investigation.
People were assigned to the treatment
group or the drug group or the non drug
group randomly blindly and investigated
the effects of the drug.
Also with different doses,
which is another hallmark of a well
designed pharmacological study.
Very low placebo like dos one or three
milligrams per 70 kilograms of body
weight versus a high dose 22 or 30
milligrams per 70 kilograms of of
siliciden chemical psilocybin
administered and counterbalance sequence
with five weeks between sessions in a
six month follow up instruction to
participants and staff minimized the
effects of expectancy participants,
staff and community observers,
rated participant moods,
attitudes and behaviors throughout the
study,
and it's also the hallmark of a well
designed study because they didn't rely
on a single source of information for
the outcome data.
Right?
They got self reports,
that's fine,
but they had relatively objective
observers also gather data at the same
time,
high dose psilocybin produced large
decreases in clinician and self related
measures of depressed mood and anxiety
along with increases in quality of life,
life meaning and optimism and decreases
in death anxiety.
That's an interesting.
It's a subtle and scientifically spar
statement,
but it's a very interesting one.
It was the in there's a.
there's an intimation of a causal
relationship here,
increases in quality of life life
meaning and decreases in death,
anxiety.
I mean,
the intimation there is that one of the
ways of decreasing your anxiety about
death is to increase the felt meaning in
your life and the psilocybin dose just
potentiate that,
but it's a good thing to know in a
general manner if it happens to be a
generalizable truth,
right?
If you're terrified of mortality,
terrified of vulnerability,
there's always the possibility that the
life path that you're following isn't
rich enough,
the buffer you against the negative
element of existence.
It's a reasonable hypothesis and an
optimistic one.
I think although a difficult one at six
month followup,
these changes were sustained with about
80 percent of participants continuing to
show clinically significant decreases in
depressed mood and anxiety.
Stephen Ross commenting about this,
he was a co investigator,
said it is simply unprecedented in
psychiatry that a single dose of a
medicine produces these kinds of
dramatic and enduring results,
right?
Which means we have no idea why this
happens.
Participants in attributed improvements
and attitudes about life slash self,
mood,
relationships,
and spirituality to the high dose
experience with more than 80 percent
endorsing moderately or greater,
increased wellbeing in life
satisfaction.
Community observers showed corresponding
changes,
mystical type silent psilocybin
experience on session day mediated the
effect of Psilocybin dose on therapeutic
outcomes.
What that means is that,
well,
when researchers were trying to look at
a causal relationship between drug
ingestion and the positive outcome,
the causal relationship was drug
ingestion,
mystical experience,
positive outcome.
It wasn't drug ingestion,
There had to be the experience produced
by the pharmaceutical agent in order for
the pharmaceutical agent to have had its
effect.
Now we don't.
Again,
we don't know why that is either.
Maybe some people needed a higher dose.
Who knows because people vary
tremendously in their sensitivity to
pharmaceutical substances.
Now,
why am I telling you all this?
Well,
I'm telling you for a variety of
reasons.
One is the first is make no mistake
about it.
Human beings have the capacity for forms
of consciousness that are radically
unlike our normative forms of
consciousness and the evidence that
those alternative forms of consciousness
are purely pathological,
which is the simplest explanation,
right?
You perturb the system produces
pathology,
that's negative.
That is the simplest explanation.
The evidence for that is weak at best.
Leaving out the bad trip issue,
which which is non trivial,
the empirical evidence as it accrues in
fact seems to suggest that the
consequence of mystical,
positive mystical experiences associated
with psychedelic intake is
overwhelmingly positive.
Even in extreme situations and you
really can't find a more extreme
situation than uncertain cancer
diagnosis with concomitant and
depression and anxiety.
Like.
I mean that's not as bad as it gets,
but it gets kind of in the ballpark.
And so the fact that even under
circumstances like that,
there was the overwhelming probability
that the experience would be positive
because that's another thing you
wouldn't expect.
You know,
even from some of the earlier earliest
discussions about psychedelic use that
were put forth by people,
including Timothy leary describing the
importance of set.
Right so that the early experimenters
noted that if you had a psychedelic
experience and you were in a bad state
or in a bad place,
that that was one of the precursors to a
bad trip.
That the negative emotion that you
entered the experience with could be
magnified tremendously by the,
by the chemical substances.
So that it was necessary to be somewhere
safe.
To be around people that you trust,
to be in a familiar environment,
to get all the variables that you
couldn't control under control,
but here's a situation where that isn't
what's happening at all because people
have this cancer diagnosis of a cancer
diagnosis of unspecified outcome and
they still,
the vast majority of them had a positive
experience and the positive experience
experience had long lasting positive
consequences.
So,
so the case that the transcendent
experience is not real,
that's wrong.
It's real.
Now we don't know what that means
because it actually challenges to some
degree our concepts of what constitutes
real,
but it certainly well within the realm
of normative human experience.
So it's part of the human capacity.
And you know,
there there's been other neurological
experiments to.
There's,
there's a researcher,
Canadian researcher,
if I remember correctly,
who invented something.
He called the God helmet and it used
electromagnetic stimulation,
brain stimulation to induce mystical
experiences.
Now,
I don't remember what part of the brain
he was shutting off or activating with
that particular gadget,
but and you know,
there's,
there's all sorts of other indications
of this sort of thing that have cropped
up in other domains of the neurological
literature.
For example.
It's very common for people who are
epileptic to have religious experiences
as part of the prodromal to the actual
seizure.
That was the case with Dostoyevsky,
for example,
who had incredibly intense religious
experiences that would culminate an
epileptic seizure and he said that they
were of sufficient quality that he would
give up his whole life to have had the.
And the funny thing too is that in my
reading of Dostoevsky at least is that I
think that epileptic seizures and the
associated mystical experiences were
part of what made him a transcendently
brilliant author.
I don't think that he would have broken
through into the domains of insight that
he possessed without those strange
neurological experiences.
And it was certainly not the case that
his epilepsy or the experiences that
were associated with it produced what
you might describe as an impairment in
his cognitive function is quite the
contrary.
At least that's how it looks to me.
Here's another.
Here's another something worth
considering.
I don't know how important it is,
but it might be really important.
It depends on how important this is.
Something that Carl Jung said.
So it depends on how important youngest,
now Freud established the field of
psychoanalysis and with an
investigation,
I would say rigorous investigation into
the contents of the unconscious and
modern psychologists and psychiatrists
like to.
What would you say denigrate Freud,
but.
And I think there's a reason for that.
I think that Freud's fundamental
insights were so profound and so
valuable that they got immediately
absorbed into our culture and now they
seem self evident.
And so that all that's left of Freud,
his,
his errors.
No,
because we believe everything else.
We believe all the profound things he
discovered,
we just take them for granted.
And so we don't believe the things that
he said that weren't quite on the money.
And that's all we credit with him with
now,
but he was certainly the first person
who brought up the idea of the
unconscious in a in a rigorous manner,
and he was the first person to do a
rigorous examination of dreams because
the interpretation of dreams is a great
book.
It's well worth reading,
and he was the first person to note that
people were in some sense inhabited by
subpersonalities that had a certain
degree of autonomy and independent life.
Brilliant observation.
The cognitive psychologists haven't
caught up with that at all yet.
Ewan was profoundly affected by Freud.
Jung was profoundly affected by nature
and by Freud.
Those were his two main intellectual
influences.
I don't think one more than the other.
He split with Freud on the religious
issue.
That was what caused the disruption in
their relationship.
And I think it's an extremely
interesting historical occurrence.
It might be a profound significance.
Freud believed that the fundamental myth
of the human being was the Eda Pole
myth.
And the myth
from a broader perspective is a failed
hero's story.
So the eatable myth is the myth of a man
who develops who grows up,
but then accidentally becomes too close
to his mother,
sleeps with her,
he doesn't know who she is,
and as a consequence blinds himself and
there's a,
there's a warning about human
development gone wrong in that story and
I think that Freud put his finger on it
extraordinarily well because human
beings have a very long period of
dependency.
And one of the things that you do see in
clinical practice is that many people's
problems are associated with their
inability to break free of their family.
Like they're consumed by the family
drama,
right?
They can't get beyond what happened to
them in their family.
They're stuck in the past.
It's.
And that's,
that's equivalent symbolically speaking,
you might say to the idea of being too
close to your mother of,
of,
of the boundaries being improperly
specified.
And that happens far more often than
anyone would like to think.
As I said for I thought it was a
universal,
but you see,
he had a different idea and his idea was
that it wasn't the hero story.
That was the universal human myth.
It was the successful hero's story and
that's a big difference.
I could seriously a big difference
because the successful hero story is
your member in sleeping beauty.
You may remember this in the Disney
movie,
the evil queen traps the prince in a
dungeon and she's not going to let them
out till he's old.
Right?
And so there's this comical scene where
she's down in the dungeon,
he's all in chains and she's laughing at
him,
telling him what his future is going to
be like.
She's quite evil and you know,
she,
she paints this wonderful picture of him
being freed in like 80 years and
hobbling out of the castle on his,
his horse that's so old,
he can barely stand up and him with gray
hair.
And,
and you know,
she,
she recites this story of his eventual
triumphant departure from the castle as
a old and decrepit man.
And she has a great laugh about it and
it's nice,
you know,
it's a real punchy story.
It's really something wonderful for
children.
That story and he gets free of the
shackles and the things that freedom our
three little female ferries,
the positive aspect of the feminine that
frees him from the dungeon,
so it's very interesting and very
accurate from a psychological
perspective.
It's the negative element of the
feminine that encapsulates him in the
dungeon and it's the positive element of
the feminine and that frees him and then
he.
He has a queen.
The Evil Queen is not very happy when he
escapes.
You may remember that she stands on top
of her castle tower and starts to spin
off cosmic sparks.
I mean,
she's quite the creature enveloped in
flame and then she turns into a dragon
and she then the prince has to fight
with her in order to make contact with
sleeping beauty and an awakened her from
her comatose existence as her
unconscious existence and wants a
brilliant.
It's a brilliant representation of a
successful hero myth.
He,
he doesn't end up staying in an unholy
relationship with his mother.
Let's say he escapes and then conquers
the worst thing that can be imagined and
is ennobled by that and that as a
consequence,
he's able to wake the slumbering
feminine from its coma and that's a
union story and that's the story that he
juxtaposed against Freud.
See Freud thought of religious phenomena
as part of an old tide.
That would be,
that would drown.
Rationality,
rationality.
That's why Freud was so vehemently anti
religious and you thought,
no,
it's not the case.
You're throwing the baby out with the
bathwater.
There's something profound and central
to the hero myth and union clinical work
is essentially the awakening of the hero
myth in the,
in the analysis and in the client or the
patient to conceptualize yourself as
that which can confront chaos and
triumph and that that's associated with
an ennobling of the of consciousness and
the establishment of pop.
Proper positive relationships between
male and female.
And you know,
I'm a skeptical person.
I'm a very,
very skeptical person and I've tried
with every trick.
I have to put a lever underneath young
story and lifted up and disrupt it and
I,
I can't do it.
I think he was right and that Freud was
wrong.
I mean,
I have great respect for Freud.
I think he got the progam problem
diagnosed very,
very nicely and in my clinical work I
see the phenomena that Freud described
emerged continually,
constantly the best.
If you're interested in that,
there's a documentary you should watch.
I may have mentioned it before.
I think it's the best documentary ever
made.
Certainly the best one I've ever seen.
It's called crumb and it's about a
underground cartoonists.
Robert Crumb,
who who is part of the hippie movement
in,
although he hated hippies,
he was part of the hippie movement in
the sixties in San Francisco and started
the entire underground comic.
What culture that that manifested itself
eventually in graphic novels,
there's quite a significant figure from
the perspective of popular art and a
very,
very intelligent man and also I would
say a hero,
although a very bent and depraved and
warped one.
Someone very acutely aware of his own
shadow and the documentary outlines his
attempts to escape from his absolutely
dreadful mother and the failure of his
two brothers to do the same thing.
One of whom ended up as a street beggar
in San Francisco and the other who drank
furniture Polish and died six months
after the documentary was produced.
It's an unbelievably shocking
documentary.
It's the only piece of film that I've
ever seen that captures Friday and
pathology.
I've never seen anything because he
can't see it generally,
unless you're in a clinical situation,
unless you know the details of someone's
lives,
the personal intimate details,
you cannot communicate it,
but the documentary as who made the film
was Robert Ziegler off,
if I remember correctly,
was a friend of the crumbs and so he got
access in a way that no one else would
have and they were also very forthright
and forthcoming about their situation.
In general.
I would highly recommend that it's.
It's a real punch.
If you want to know how a rapist thinks,
like if you actually want to know,
because maybe you don't want to know.
In fact,
you probably don't want to know,
right?
Because do you really want to know that?
Because to understand that means to put
yourself in that position and to
understand it.
If you really want to know how a serial
sexual Predator thinks and why,
if you watch crum and pay attention,
you'll know and that's only a tiny bit
of what the film has to offer.
It's really quite remarkable.
Anyways,
young split with Freud on the issue of
the oedipal story as the fundamental
myth of humankind and on the issue of
the validity of the religious viewpoint
and young came down heavily on the side
of the validity of the religious
viewpoint and he established that in a
book called symbols of transformation
which was written in 1914,
and that's the book that broke,
that produced the break permanent split
with Freud and that book,
I would say that books actually been
written three times.
It was written as symbols of trip four
times written as symbols of
transformation,
which young extensively revised when he
was old,
and then it was rewritten in is in a
sense by a student of Yoga called Eric
Norman,
who is also something someone I would
really recommend.
Eric Norman,
I think is [inaudible] greatest student,
and he wrote two books.
He wrote one called the origins and
history of consciousness,
which is a description of the
development of consciousness,
out of unconsciousness,
using the hero myth as a,
as an as a,
as a,
what would you say as a,
as an interpretive skeleton,
so Newman viewed the hero myth as the
dramatized story of the emergence of
human consciousness out of the
surrounding unconsciousness in which it
was embedded,
the struggle for consciousness,
the struggle of consciousness upward
towards the light,
like a lotus flower struggles up through
the muck and they and the water to to
lay itself on the surface of the water
and and bloom and reveal the Buddha,
which is of course what the lotus flower
does from a symbolic perspective and
for,
for for Norman.
The hero's story was the story of the
development,
the successful development of
consciousness and the origins of
consciousness.
The origins and history of consciousness
is a great book.
Interestingly,
Camille Paglia row read the origins and
history of consciousness.
She's one of the few mainstream
intellectuals that I've ever encountered
who read that and commented on it,
and she believed that it would be
sufficient antidote to postmodern
denigration of literature.
She thought it was that powerful work
and I believe that.
I think it's a remarkable book.
Carl Jung wrote the foreword to that
book and he said in the forward that it
was the book that he wished he would
have written,
so it's sort of like young.
He wrote,
I don't remember how many volumes,
dozens of very thick,
difficult volumes was.
Norman was able to
what?
Distill those into a single volume
statement,
and so I would also say if you're
interested in young,
the best book to read is the origins and
history of consciousness.
It's the best intro into into the union
world.
Soon,
it's very difficult to,
very difficult to understand.
It requires a real shift of perspective
in order to understand what he's talking
about.
And Norman wrote another book called the
great mother,
which is a little bit more specialized
in some sense,
but it's also extremely interesting
because it fleshes out the archetype of
chaos and its representation as feminine
and it's a brilliant book as well and
highly highly worth reading both those
books.
Anyways,
young was a very strange person and a
visionary and and so that's kept them
outside of the academic realm almost
entirely.
I mean,
I was constantly warned as an
undergraduate and then a graduate
student and then a professor against
ever talking about young in any way
whatsoever.
When I went on the job market,
when I was at mcgill,
when I had graduated from mcgill,
I had done my scientific research and
analysis a holism and I had a fairly
lengthy publication record that was pure
empirical research and really neuro
physiological research into the
pharmacology of alcoholism and I
established a reasonably solid dossier
publications,
but at the same time I was writing this
book that became maps of meaning and so
I'd split my time in graduate student
school.
Between these two endeavors.
One very specifically neurological and
pharmacological and really biologically
based and the other very abstract
religious,
symbolic,
psychoanalytic,
the complete opposite,
but I could see that the two things
overlapped really nicely and there was a
number of scientists at the time that
we're also drawing the same conclusions,
the same relationship between the
biology and the psychoanalysis.
Jaak Panksepp who wrote a book called
affective neuroscience,
which is a great classic,
is one of those people who who saw the
relationship between the neurobiology of
emotion and motivation and the
psychoanalytic insights never became a
mainstream view,
but I think it's too complex.
I think that bridging the gap between
the biology and the and the symbolic is
too much for people.
Generally speaking,
you know,
it was certainly virtually too much for
me because I got quite ill when I was a
graduate student.
I think for a variety of reasons.
I also would go out and party three
nights a week and so that probably had
something to do with it,
but,
but working on those two things
simultaneously was also rather
exhausting.
Now you was a tremendously insightful
clinician and he was a strange person,
introverted,
visionary,
high and introversion,
very,
very high in openness,
like off the charts and also God only
knows what his Iq was.
I mean,
every time I read young,
it's like reading Nietzsche.
It's terrifying because you know,
he's,
he's so damn smart that he can think up
answers to questions that you don't
even.
It's not like you don't understand
answers.
This is the,
you never conceptualized the damn
questions.
It's really something to read.
Someone like that,
right?
Who says,
well,
here's a mystery and you think,
wow,
I'd never thought of that is a mystery,
and here's the solution.
It's like,
okay,
that's,
that's something you know,
and he could read Greek and he could
read.
He read all the ancient.
He read a very large variety of ancient
languages and was very familiar with the
entire corpus of,
of astrological thought and of l
chemical thought and of classic
literature and Biblical stories.
And I mean educated in a way that no one
is educated now,
and so he's very daunting person to
encounter and terrifying.
Absolutely terrifying.
His Book Ion,
which is the second volume of the second
volume of volume nine,
which is the archetypes of the
collective unconscious.
That damn book has just absolutely
terrifying because young,
he's one of these visionaries who can
see way underneath the social structures
and look at patterns that are developing
across for you in young's case across
thousands of years and lays them out and
so that's a really.
That's really something to to encounter.
Ion is a terrifying book.
Anyways,
one question might be,
well,
because I read the organ,
I think,
how the hell did he know these things?
How could he figure these things out?
I can't understand how he could possibly
know these things.
Well,
here's a partial answer.
Young was a visionary,
and so what that means as far as I can
tell,
and we could do a little quick survey
here.
How many of you think you think in words
and put up your hand.
See,
do you think in words?
Okay,
so it looks like.
What about pictures?
How many of you think in pictures?
Okay,
so that's interesting.
How many of you think that's about half
and half by the way?
Probably have fewer on the word side.
How many of you think in pictures and
words?
Okay,
so all right,
so it was roughly a third in each
category,
but that's also something that I really
haven't encountered any research on from
the neuropsychological perspective.
It's like,
well,
do you think in pictures or do you think
it words and.
And is that actually a reliable
distinction?
I think I think in words most of the
time,
but I can think in pictures like if I'm
trying to build something,
I can think in pictures very almost
instantaneously,
but it isn't my natural mode of
thinking.
I'm hyperverbal and so my natural mode
of thinking is to think everything
through in words,
but I know my wife doesn't like that.
She thinks in images and then has to
translate them into words and so
anyways,
you was very literate and he could
really think in words,
but he could really think in images.
Also talking to my wife quite
extensively like her,
the intensity of her visualization
vastly exceeds mine.
So for example,
if I close my eyes and then try to
imagine the crowd in front of me,
it's pretty low resolution and vague and
brilliantly colored and vivid.
You know what it's.
It's like I'm seeing through a glass
darkly,
let's say I can't bring images to mind
with that with spectacular clarity,
but my wife is very good at that and
young seem to be absolutely a genius at
that kind of thinking and he had a lot
of visionaries in his family history as
well.
So I don't know to what degree there's a
hereditary component of that and I don't
know to what degree that's actually like
a neurological specialization,
I presume that would be associated with
the trade.
Openness distinguishes itself,
differentiates itself into interest in
ideas and interest in in statics.
And my suspicion are is that the people
who are more interested in aesthetics
are the visionary types,
the ones that think in images anyways.
You could really think in images and he
could imagine beings.
And I had a client once who was a lucid
dreamer and how many of you have had a
lucid dream?
So you know,
you're dreaming while you're many that
that phenomena wasn't really even even
identified as a phenomenon until the end
of the 19th century.
There was a book written about it that
Freud tried to get his hands on but
couldn't because it was a very rare
book.
And then there was a researcher about 30
years ago who started to study lucid
dreams.
But anyways,
I had a client who was a lucid dreamer
and one of the things she could do was
ask her dream characters what
information they were trying to convey
and they would tell her.
So that was very interesting and one of
the consequences of that was,
and I don't have the story completely
right in my memory,
but it's close enough.
She was afraid of a very large number of
things.
And in her dream,
I think it was a gypsy standing by a
wagon,
told her that if she was going to be
successful in university,
that she would have to visit a
slaughterhouse.
And that was something that was way
beyond her capacity to tolerate.
She was a vegetarian.
She couldn't stand the sight of raw meat
even.
And so,
and she was very oppressed and depressed
and anxious because of the
slaughterhouse nature of existence.
And so her dream focused on that and one
of the consequences of that,
because the slaughter house was out of
the question as a clinical intervention,
um,
I took her to an embalming,
right?
Because,
because I asked her,
I asked her what,
what,
what might be equivalent to that.
And so she suggested that.
And you know,
exposure therapy is a hallmark of
clinical psychology,
right?
One of the things you do with people as
a clinician is you find out what they're
afraid of and you gradually and
voluntarily expose them to that.
And that cures them.
And that's associated with the hero
myth,
right?
It's exactly the same thing.
It's like there's a dragon and it's
stopping you because there's lots of
dragons.
Most of them aren't stopping you.
You can ignore them.
You don't have to just go,
you know,
slash away at randomly.
You're not supposed to be fighting
dragons that aren't in your way,
but if they are in your way,
you can't ignore them.
And then you decompose them into sub
dragons and you have people you know,
take them on and as they take them on,
they dispense with the dragon and they
gain the power of the drag.
It's like a video game.
Actually.
A video game is like that.
That's why people like the video games.
Well that's right,
right.
There's a reason that you absorbed power
when you overcome things,
when you play a video game.
It's not like that's intrinsic to the
video game structure.
That's an archetypal idea.
Anyways,
we went and saw an embalming,
which was a very interesting experience
and,
and quite,
quite useful for her because she knew
what she could tolerate after that and
it was a hell of a lot more than she
thought she could tolerate.
And so that's very useful to know.
Back to you.
He's a visionary thinker now.
My client,
I said she could lucid dream and she
could ask her dream characters what they
wanted and what they were trying to
communicate to her.
So that was pretty interesting.
That happened.
Spontaneous.
They had nothing to do with me.
You know,
I'm interested in dreams in any of my
clients are great dreamers,
especially the creative ones because I
think it's a hallmark of creativity to
have vivid dreams and to be able to
remember them,
but that was a faculty that was natural
to her young had this other client at
one time.
At one point she had a variety of fears
and she had this dream that she told me
and she was walking down a beach and on
the side of the beach,
up a dune,
small noon.
There was this old man with a snake,
a big python,
and there's a crowd around him.
And uh,
she was walking by the snake handler and
the snake and the crowd and she didn't
want to have anything to do with them.
He was sort of showing people this
snake.
And she told me that dream and I
thought,
well,
you know,
you probably need to go see that snake.
And so I relaxed or quasi hypnotic
technique,
and it's very straightforward.
Hypnosis is generally nothing but
pronounced relaxation low.
You have to be susceptible to hypnosis
to actually fall into a hypnotic trance.
As a consequence of being relaxed or
just relaxed her,
I had her breathe deeply and pay
attention to different parts of her body
and just relax her muscles one by one
essentially so that she could
concentrate and then I told her we play
with the dream a little bit and say
union technique.
I said,
well,
so called the dream image to mind,
which she could do quite well.
Said,
okay,
so let's,
let's explore it.
So like pretend it's like pretend play
in.
You know,
if you're a kid in your pretend playing,
you don't exactly direct the game,
right you,
you,
you play the game.
So it's partly your direction obviously
because you're the player,
but the thing also happened
spontaneously of its own accord and you
can think about that as a dialogue
between the conscious mind and the
unconscious mind.
In some sense,
it's developmental dialogue.
It's not a fun game if you just direct
it.
It's only a fun game.
If you're inviting in something is
welling up as a consequences.
It's the same thing that happens when
you're.
You're engaged in some kind of artistic
or literary production.
If it's all top down,
you know,
if you're forcing it then it's
propaganda,
it's empty.
What do you want to sort of put yourself
in a receptive state of mind in an
imaginative state of mind and it's sort
of half you and half nature itself
manifesting itself in your creative
imagination.
And that was the sort of state that we
were striving for and she,
I asked her when she was in relaxed,
I said,
well,
what do you think about the snake
handler?
And she said,
well,
he's probably a charlatan and he's just
there trying to impress the crowd and to
show off.
And she was afraid to go up there
because she thought people would push
her towards the snake and she'd have to
touch it.
And so there was a fear of the crowd
issue going on there too.
And I said,
well just look,
go up there,
but do it under these conditions is
that,
you know,
if,
if people get pushy,
what are you going to tell them?
And so we figured out something.
He said,
look,
just tell them that you know,
you want to look at the snake at your
own pace and that you don't need any
encouragement or help and it would be
good if you were just left alone,
so that enabled her to defend herself.
So she was afraid that the crowd would
push her to do something that she didn't
want to do.
That was part of the theme of the dream.
So anyway,
she eventually climbed the Dune in her
imagination and went into the crowd and
the crowd turned out to be quite
welcoming and not hostile and not pushy,
which isn't what you'd expect,
right?
Because you'd think the crowd would have
reacted in accordance with their fears
since it was her fantasy that that's the
thing about fantasies.
They have this autonomous quality,
but the crowd was welcoming and not
hostile and it turned out that the snake
handler wasn't a charlatan.
He was just an old guy who had this
snake and he was out there just showing
it to people because he thought it was a
cool thing and and and that maybe it was
good for people to come and look at a
snake and so she got close enough to the
snake to touch it.
And so.
So I'm telling you that because I want
you to understand a bit more about what
[inaudible] was trying to do.
And so he wrote these books,
notebooks that haven't been published
yet called the block books and the black
books are the documentation of his
experiments with his imagination and
what he would do is daydream like,
like a child daydreams.
He regained that faculty.
Although I think with us it was a
faculty that has never really
disappeared.
And he had figures of imagination that
came to him that he could speak with.
And he spoke with these figures of
imagination and documented that over a
very long period of time.
And that was originally.
That was eventually distilled into a
book called the Red Book,
which was published about three or four
years ago.
And it was a book that young regarded as
the central source from which all his
inspiration emerged,
sort of the way it looks to me is that
we embody a lot of information in our
action,
right?
And our action has developed as a
consequence of imitating other people
and not only the people or the people
around us,
but of course the people around us
imitated the people who came before them
and those people in mutated the people
who came before them and so on so far
back that it's as far back as you can
go.
And so you embody these patterns of
behavior that are extremely informative,
that you don't understand,
that are consequences of collective
imitation across the centuries.
And then those patterns can become
manifest as figures of the imagination.
And those figures of imagination are the
distillations of patterns of behavior.
And so as the distillations of patterns
of behavior,
they have content and it's not you that
content.
It's you could even think about it as
content that's evolved.
Although it's culturally transmitted,
it's content that's evolved and so these
figures of the imagination can reveal
the structure of reality to you and
that's what happened with young and
that's what he described in the red book
and that was what permeated his
psychology,
psychology.
That was based on the presupposition
that the fundamental architectural
structures of religious belief.
We're not pathological,
not deceitful,
not protective in some delusional sense
against the fear of death,
but quite the contrary,
the very stories that enabled us to move
forward as confident human beings in the
face of chaos itself and it's
conceivable,
I think perhaps probable that nothing
more important conceptually happened in
the 20th century than that because it
was the first time post enlightenment
that ever prashant between the intellect
and the underlying religious archetipal
substructure occurred.
You have in the capacious intellect of
young and the same thing happened to
some degree with piaget.
The religious domain and the factual
domain were brought back together and
the fact of young's enduring and
increasing popularity and influence,
I would say,
is a direct consequence of that.
Now.
Some of his work was spun off into the
new age and and the new age is a very
optimistic and naive movement is
predicated on the idea that you can do
nothing say,
but follow your bliss and that will take
you ever hire to enlightenment and
that's not the union idea at all.
The union idea is that what you most
need will be found where you least want
to look.
So this story,
King
Arthur,
there's the story of King Arthur,
the.
They're all in a round table,
right?
King Arthur and his knights,
they're all equals.
They're all super ordinate,
but they're all equals and they go off
to look for the holy grail.
The holy grail is the container of the
redemptive substance,
whatever that is,
might be the cup that Christ used at the
last supper might be jealous that was
used to capture his blood on the cross,
right when he was pierced by a sword.
The stories differ,
but that's the holy grail and the holy
grail is lost.
That's the redemptive substance and the
knights of King Arthur go off to search
for the holy grail and but they don't
know where to look,
so where do you look when you don't know
where to look for something you need
desperately,
but I've lost.
Well,
each of the nights goes into the forest
at the point that looks darkest to him
and that's union psychoanalysis in a
nutshell.
It's like that which you fear and avoid
that which you hold in contempt,
that which disgusts you and that you
avoid.
That's the gateway to what you need to
know.
There's nothing new agey about that.
That's for sure.
Now,
young,
when he started this endeavor,
we started with this.
This is part of the notebooks from the
block book.
He said
he wrote my soul,
my soul.
Where are you?
Do you hear me?
I speak.
I call you.
Are you there?
I've returned.
I'm here again.
I've shaken the dust of all the lands
from my feet and I've come to you.
I'm with you.
After long years of long wandering,
I have come to you again for the unions.
The Hero's journey is a journey within
and and I think that that's probably the
bias of introverts to believe that the
hero's journey isn't only an inward
journey.
I think that it can be an outward
journey too because I don't think it
matters where you confront the unknown,
whether it's within her,
without what matters is whether or not
you confront the unknown.
That's what matters,
but he found that what he had ignored
was an undiscovered part of themselves,
so that might be something that was
equivalent to Huxley's notion that there
were tremendous,
tremendous potential breadth in the
realm of human conscious experience and
Huxley was influenced to some degree by
Yung.
Now Yung knew of Huxley's experiments
and had commented on psychedelic use and
he said something like,
beware of wisdom you did not earn.
And Don was very good at stating things
very profoundly,
very simply.
And that's a very intelligent piece of
advice.
Be Aware of wisdom you did not earn.
He wrote a paper if you're interested in
this sort thing.
He wrote a paper called the relations
between the ego and the unconscious,
which is an absolute master work,
but completely incomprehensible unless
you know what it,
unless you know what it's about and what
it's about is the danger of what he
called ego inflation,
and so one of the things that can happen
as a consequence of a revelatory
experience is that the division between
the individual ego and and the and what
would you call it,
so hard to come up with a word that
isn't somehow naive or or or cliched,
to erase the relationship,
the boundary between the specific
consciousness of the ego and the more
generalized consciousness and more
generalized consciousness as such,
is a dangerous thing to do because you
can start to equate yourself,
your specific self with that more
generalized consciousness as such,
and you thought about that.
Is it something akin to a psychotic
inflation and the paper relations
between the ego and the unconscious is a
document that tells you how to avoid
that.
If you're
playing in this kind of realm and one of
the injunctions is to keep your feet on
the ground.
He thought that was what partly what
happened to Nisha was that Nina wasn't
grounded enough in life.
He wasn't grounded enough in day to day
rituals and routines and the mundane.
Now you can debate whether or not that's
the case,
whether or not that's a reasonable
argument,
but that was still what you unbelieved.
Okay,
so why am I telling you all this?
I'll finish with this from December 19,
13 onward.
Young Carrie going in the same
procedure,
deliberately evoking a fantasy in a
waking state and then entering into it
as a drama.
These fantasies may be understood as a
type of dramatize thinking in pictorial
form.
In retrospect,
he recalled that his scientific question
was to see what took place when he
switched off consciousness.
The example of dreams indicated the
existence of background activity and he
wanted to give this a possibility of
emerging just as one does when taking
masculine.
These journals are youngest
contemporary,
contemporaneous clinical ledger to his
most difficult experiment or what he
later describes as a voyage of discovery
to the other pole of the world,
young unbelief that we were dreaming all
the time,
but that during waking life,
that pressure of external images was
such that the unconscious fantasy
imagery was,
or that the fantasy imagery was of
insufficient magnitude to be conscious,
but that we were always situated in a
dream in relationship to the world.
So
when we started talking about the
creation of the universe at the
beginning of the genesis stories,
I spent quite a long time setting the
stage for the stories because
there's no point in having a
conversation about the God who gives
rise to being unless you have some sense
of what that might conceivably mean to
the modern mind.
And I felt the same way about
neighborhood Amec stories is I couldn't
get a handle on them until I could
understand and articulate more clearly
what it might mean.
How a modern person might understand a,
uh,
a direct experience of God.
And the first question would be,
is such a thing possible?
And the answer that seems to be a
qualified yes.
First of all,
it's a universal human experience.
That's a very strange thing.
It's not something that people have made
up as Freud might have it as a defense
against death.
It's not a tenable hypothesis.
It's a realm of potential experience.
Now that experience doesn't necessarily
have to have the Judeo Christian content
that we've been discussing.
Quite the contrary.
They are manifestations of this,
these alternative forms of consciousness
all over the world that take on their
own peculiar forms.
Although their pattern to some degree,
that's like the hero myth,
for example,
of myth of the fight against the dragon
seems to be unbelievably widespread and
so it's not as if it's random.
Sorry,
I should just see what time it is here,
but there's not much point in having a
discussion about what happens to Abraham
unless you can conceptualize it in terms
that are amenable to modern skeptical
consciousness so we can establish the
proposition that mystical experience is
not only possible,
it's quite common and it's inducible in
a variety of ways and the manner in
which it's inducible is reliable and
there's no evidence as well that it's
pathological in in fact there's a fair
bit of evidence that the patterns of
behavior that are associated with the
mystical experience are core elements of
proper human adaptation in the world.
The Abrahamic stories open up with a
manifest God.
Now I'm going to read you some things
from Friedman who wrote the
disappearance of God.
He was trying to look at the underlying
structure of the stories.
Now no freedom and noted that the books
in the Old Testament were written by a
lot of different people at very
different times and then they were
sequenced by other people.
For reasons that we don't exactly
understand,
but there's still an underlying
narrative.
There's multiple underlying narrative
unity's despite the fact of that rather
arbitrary sequencing and that's a
strange thing,
you know,
I guess you could say if you had a
collection of ancient books and you were
trying to put them together,
you try to put them together in some way
that made sense,
right,
and it wouldn't make sense unless you
stumbled across some kind of underlying
narrative that allowed you to order
them,
and so it's not entirely surprising that
that are ordered in a manner that's
comprehensible,
but Friedman's comments on the
underlying narrative structure,
part of it was,
well,
we'll go through this.
The books of the Old Testament were
composed by a great many authors
according to both traditional religious
views in modern critical scholarship,
the phenomenon of the diminishing
apparent presence of God across so many
stories through so many books by so many
authors spread over so many centuries is
consistent enough to be striking,
impressive and ultimately mysterious,
but the hiding of the divine phase is
only half the story.
There's another development also
extending across the course of the
entire narrative of the Hebrew Bible,
which we must see before.
We can appreciate the full force of this
phenomena and before we can pose the
solution to the mystery of this,
of how this happened,
gradually from genesis to Ezra,
an estimate,
there is a transition from divine to
human responsibility for life on earth.
The story begins in genesis with God in
complete control of the creation,
but by the end,
humans have arrived at a stage at which
in all apparent ways,
they have responsibility for the fate of
the world.
The first two human beings,
Adam and eve,
take little responsibility themselves.
They do not be design or build anything.
When they're embarrassed over their
nudity,
they do not make clothes.
They cover themselves with leaves.
It's God who makes their first clothing
for them.
No.
I'm by no means a fully developed
personality.
No,
it is not an every man either.
Broadly speaking,
he reflects a step beyond Adam and eve
and human character and responsibility.
Abraham,
beyond that counts of divine commands
that Abraham does carry out.
The narrative also includes a variety of
stories in which Abraham acts on his own
initiative.
He divides land with his nephew lot.
He battles kings.
He takes concubines,
he argues with his wife Sarah,
on two occasions,
he tells kings that Sarah,
his sister,
out of fear,
that they will kill him to get his wife,
and he arranges his son's marriage in
the place of the single story of Noah's
drunkenness.
There are,
in the case of Abraham the stories of
man's life.
The Abraham section thus develops the
personality and character of a man of
man to a new degree in biblical
narrative will picturing and him a new
degree of responsibility.
It is not just that Abraham has kindler
kinder,
gentler,
more intrepid,
more ethical,
or a better debater than his ancestor
noah.
Rather.
Both the Noah and Abraham stories or
pieces of a development of an
increasingly stronger stance of humans
relative to the deity.
Before the story is over,
humans will become a great deal,
stronger and bolder than Abraham.
I don't know what that means,
you know?
See,
it isn't.
It is certainly the case that the
individual exists in the modern world,
the differentiated self aware,
self conscious individual,
and it's certainly the case that that
wasn't the case at some point in the
past and so it's the case that there's
been a development.
I don't know if you could call it a
progression,
but a development of the autonomous
individual over some span of historical
time.
Now we don't know how long that's been,
but my suspicions are.
It hasn't been that long.
I mean
I read once about a Neolithic ceremony
that involve the particular placement of
a bear skull in a cave and then I read
that and they had found these placements
in caves that were at least 25,000
years old and then I read that they
found caves in Japan among the Ainu who
were the indigenous inhabitants of
Japanese territory and rather archaic
people who had the same ceremony with
the bear and that put the skull in the
same orientation and place in caves.
And that that tradition remained
unbroken for about 25,000
years.
And you think it will.
Is it possible for an oral or ritual
tradition to remain unbroken for spans
of tens of thousands of years,
and the answer to that is not only is it
possible,
it's actually the norm because like
one chimpanzee is like the next
chimpanzee,
right in the.
In the progression,
in the biological progression.
If you took a chimpanzee troop now and
you went back 25,000
years and you looked at a chimpanzee
troop,
it'd be the same thing.
There's no historical progression.
That's how you can tell the chimps
really don't have culture because if
they could even accrete one,
1000th of a percent of culture
transmissible culture progeneration,
it wouldn't take more than about a
million years before they'd have a whole
civilization and they don't.
They're the same as they were and so the
continuity,
the stability and unchanging nature of
his species,
essentially speaking is the rule that
the variant is us.
It's like what the hell happened after
the last ice age,
15,000
years ago,
we went from tribal uniform stable to
whatever the hell we are now.
It's this transition from generic too
specific.
It's something like that and I can't
help but think that that's reflected in
this text and it has something to do
with this transition of consciousness
from,
from what?
From possession by the generic divine to
dominance by this specific individual.
If something like that,
is that a neurological transformation?
Is that what this is a record of being?
We don't know.
One of the things you said about God
because young's relationship with God as
an object of belief is very complex,
hidden in his technical writing,
he always talks about the image of God.
He never talks about God.
He talks about the image of God.
He said that the image of God dwells
within us,
not the same thing as God dwelling
within.
Right?
Because we could mean all of these
capacities that we have for transcendent
consciousness could be a byproduct of
biological evolution.
They could have no reflection.
They can have no relationship whatsoever
to an actual transcendent reality.
There's no way of telling the
transcendent reality seems to manifest
itself as an element of experience,
but that doesn't mean that it has in
reality,
outside of this objective,
even if it's even if it exists as it is,
it clearly does,
but
Friedman suggests that what's happening
in the biblical narrative is the
sequential emergence of the individual
as a redemptive force and that the old
testament documents that implicitly,
unconsciously as a consequence of
descriptive fantasy and that that's
what's going on in the book and that so
the Cosmos is under the control of
generic daddy to begin with,
something like that,
and then that controls shifts to
localized,
identifiable,
increasingly personal and detailed
individuals and you see that in Noah and
then you see the neighborhood and then
you see it in Moses and then there's
this working out of what it would mean
to be a fully developed individual and
that's what these stories.
They're there,
they're there.
They're like prototypes.
There are attempts to to to bring about
the proper motive being right and so
Abraham is a,
is a manifestation of that because he
enters into a covenant with God.
He's selected by God,
interest into a partnership with God.
It's not exactly obvious.
God provides him with forward motion and
intuition and leads them towards a
successful mode of being and it's
complex,
successful mode being because Abraham is
a very complex life.
There's plenty of ups and downs,
right?
It's not unbroken purity of being
towards a divine hand.
Abraham lies and cheats and deceives and
does all sorts of things that that a
real person would do and and Moses,
for example,
kill someone and so these people that
the biblical people are very genuine
individuals,
but they're given with all their faults,
right,
with all their sins,
with all their deceit,
they're still put forth as potential
modes of proper models of potential
proper being in the world and the entire
Corpus of the Bible seems to be nothing
but an attempt to keep up variance
of the personality.
Trying to experiment to find out what
personality works in the world.
Of course,
from a Christian perspective,
that culminates in the figure of Christ
as the redemptive word and that's
associated as we've already talked about
with the force that brought order out of
chaos.
At the beginning of time and so well,
that's my attempt to provide proper
context for the understanding of
Abrahamic stories and so hopefully with
that context we can move forward being
able to swallow the camel so to speak,
of the initial presence of God in the
stories and so we'll return to all of
that next week.
Thank you.
Let's wait one second.
Until people have an opportunity to
leave,
I would very much like to ask the people
who are asking the questions to take a
few seconds before they asked the
question and make sure that the mic is
positioned properly so that everyone can
hear you because people keep writing and
complaining that while they're very
happy with the questions and I would say
the questions have been a very high
caliber so far,
but they're not very happy that they
can't hear them,
so I know that you're obviously nervous
and in a hurry when you want to ask you
a question,
but take a second or two to set the mic
up properly and make sure that everyone
can hear you and so have a way out.
It blew Dr.
Peter says,
Hey,
there we go.
I'd like to ask you
about two different psychological
disorders.
The first being borderline personality
disorder,
so two lectures ago,
somebody asks you about it and you gave
a very sparse answer.
I can't remember exactly what you said,
but it seemed like it was,
it was too much complexity to just
answer it right there and then.
And then somebody else.
All Cox asked you about the same
disorder in your Patriot on live stream
recently and when they,
when they asked you that you kind of,
you kind of stopped for a moment and
something I don't know,
something kind of flicked on in your
head and it seemed like in you and you
thought for a couple seconds and then
you said,
you know what?
I don't think that I can answer that
right now because it's just too.
It's just too bloody complex.
And I was wondering just like many young
men have gravitated towards your
lectures,
do you think that there's something
about this particular disorder that a,
there's something about people with this
particular disorder that might gravitate
to your insights and your.
Okay.
Okay,
so now I would say probably no to the
second one,
but I could comment more about
borderline personality disorder.
I think I have enough mental energy to
do that tonight.
So technically speaking,
it's often considered the female variant
of anti social personality disorder.
So it's,
it's,
it's classified or it's classified in,
in,
in the domain of externalizing
disorders,
acting out disorders.
And I think what happens,
we don't understand borderline
personality disorder very well and it's
characterized by tremendous impulsivity,
radical confusion of identity,
um,
and then this pattern of idealization
of,
of people with whom the person afflicted
with the disorder is associated with
radical idealization of those people and
then radical devaluation of them.
And then there's another theme that sort
of weaves along with it,
which is the proclivity of people with
borderline personality disorder to
presume that they will be abandoned and
then to act in a manner that makes such
a bad admin,
virtually certain.
And so it's very complicated disorder.
But that I think gets at the crux of it.
One of the things that's interesting
about people with borderline personality
disorder in my experience is that
they're often quite intelligent and you
see in the person with borderline
personality disorder,
something like that,
the waste or the squandering of
tremendous potential,
they seem capable of thinking through
the nature of their problems and
analyzing them and discussing it,
but not capable whatsoever of
implementing any solutions
and
technically there's no relationship
between Iq and conscientiousness.
It's very weird because if you read the
neuropsychological literature and you
read about the functions of the
prefrontal Cortex,
they're usually conceptualized in
intellectual terms and they're
associated with planning and
strategizing and so forth,
and that's what conscientiousness is,
is planning and strategizing and
implementation,
but the correlation between Iq and
conscientiousness is zero and so as the
correlation between working memory and
conscientiousness is zero and zero is a
very low correlation.
Right?
I mean really,
it's hard to find things in psychology
that are correlated at zero.
Things tend to be correlated to some
degree.
They tend to be interrelated.
The borderline seems to be able to
strategize the abstract
but not to be able to implement.
And so this,
the intellect per se seems to be
functional,
but it's not embodied in action.
It's very.
So it can be frustrating to be
associated with someone who has
borderline personality disorder because
they can tell you what the problem is
and even tell you what the solution
might be,
but there's no implementation.
So maybe something went wrong
developmentally.
We don't know exactly how these sorts of
things come about.
The other thing that seems to be
characteristic of borderline people with
borderline personality disorder is that
they remind me very much of people who
are two years old and in some manner
like people with borderline personality
disorder can have temper tantrums.
In fact,
they often do and you know now and then
you see a temper tantrum and they're
usually thrown by two year olds.
Right?
Most people grow out of temper tantrums
by the time they were about three.
They're very rare at four,
which is a good thing because if they're
still there at four,
that is not a good diagnostic predictor.
That's a good diagnostic predictor.
But it's not the kind that you want.
And you know,
it's funny the way that we respond to
two year old temper tantrums because the
two year old will throw themselves on
the ground and eat their hands and their
legs on the floor and scream and yell
and turn red or even blue.
I saw a child once who was capable of
holding his breath during a temper
tantrum until he turned blue,
which was really an impressive feat.
You should try that,
right?
It's really hard.
You really have to work at it.
And you see that in adult borderlines,
they'll have temper tantrums.
And the funny thing is when a two year
old does it,
it's like it's,
you know,
it's a little off putting.
But when an adult does it,
it's completely bloody terrifying.
And it happens very frequently with
borderlines.
And so I would also say to some degree,
they didn't get properly socialized
between that critical period of
development between two and four.
And you see the same thing with adult
males who grow up to be antisocial
because a large proportion of adult
males who grow up to be anti social are
aggressive as children,
as two year olds.
So there's a small proportion of two
year olds who are quite aggressive,
they'll kick and hit and bite and steal
if you put them with other two year
olds.
It's about five percent of the,
of the males,
smaller fraction of the females,
but most of them are socialized by the
time they're four,
but there's a small percentage who
aren't and they tend to stay antisocial
and they tend to turn into longterm
offenders and,
and it,
and the develop that critical period for
socialization development seems to be
between two and four and it seems to be
mediated by pretend play in rough and
tumble play in those sorts of
mechanisms.
And if it isn't instantiated by the age
of four,
it doesn't happen and it doesn't look
like it's addressable.
Now,
there are dialectic behavioral therapies
that have been developed for people with
borderline personality disorder and
their purported to be successful.
But.
Okay,
thank you.
If I,
uh,
severe second,
a psychological disorder I wanted to ask
you about is a psychopathy.
So you've mentioned that a psychopaths
tend to switch from dominance hierarchy
to dominance hierarchy because people
get tired of their shenanigans.
And they have to be volunteer fresh
people,
um,
and psychopaths also tend to be very low
in conscientiousness.
And you said that when you see some of
these protesters at your speeches,
some of the men in particular,
uh,
your,
you're a clinical intuition tells you
that there's something seriously
pathological about them.
And,
uh,
I was wondering if you would suspect
that some of these men might be
psychopathic
as well.
Some of them likely are,
but I don't know if a higher proportion
of the ones who show up at protests and
sort of creeped me out or I don't know
if,
if there's a higher proportion of people
like that at the protests are not.
I mean,
I suspect in general that regardless of
the protest,
the proportion of people who have
personality disorders among protestors
is higher than the proportion of people
who have personality disorders in the
general population because you just
expect that you just expect that kind of
acting out behavior.
I'm not,
believe me,
I'm not saying that all protest is
associated with personality disorder.
I'm not saying that at all.
There's plenty of reason for protest,
but some of the reason for protests are
credible reasons and some of them aren't
credible reasons,
so
seeing that like the social justice
hierarchy,
so to speak,
would be one of the last that these
confused
that's,
that's a different issue.
You know there are,
there are analysis of the dangers of
agreeableness,
so agreeableness is a personality trait
that underlies the radical egalitarian
ethos because agreeable people want
everything to be shared equally and it's
a good.
I think it's a good ethos for a small
group for a family because family is
kind of a communist system in some
sense.
Right?
It's like you want the food to be
divided up equally among the children
clearly,
and you want all the children sort of
regardless of their inherent abilities
to have the same opportunities and
perhaps even the same outcomes.
So I think agreeableness which is
associated at least in part with
maternal maternal,
the maternal instinct,
let's say maternal patterns of behavior.
I think it's,
it's a good first pass motivational
approximation to a localized familial
ethic.
I think it's a catastrophe at larger
scales.
I don't think it scales at all.
I actually think that's why we evolve
conscientiousness,
because conscientiousness is the
principle that allows larger scale
organizations to exist.
Agreeableness won't do it now.
Conscientiousness is a mystery,
right?
We don't have a neurological model.
We don't have a conceptual model.
We don't have an animal model,
we don't have a pharmacological model,
and we really only have one way of
assessing which is self and other
reports of personality proclivity.
So anyways,
the problem with agreeableness,
this has been modeled by game theorists,
is that a population of cooperative
people can be dominated by a single
shark,
so agreeableness is insufficient as a
principal because it opens itself up to,
what do you call that?
Manipulation and manipulation.
Let's let's leave it at that to
manipulation and,
and,
and exploitation.
That's the other thing.
Exploitation.
So
thank you.
Hi,
Dr Peterson.
I had one quick comment and aggression
of somebody's comments was about your
idea of subpersonalities is one nine
monsters.
Now there's the idea of multiple
personality or split personality
disorder.
It's controversial as to whether or not
it exists,
but there's some recent research that
suggests that you may actually have
multiple personalities that use
different parts of the brain,
so they have differential access to the
hippocampus.
They have their own memories and they
can,
um,
they use their brain differently,
but that seems to be an exaggeration of
some personalities to me,
which is quite interesting.
The question I had was about,
um,
so you talked about young and how um,
you should confront that which you don't
want to confront the most or you're most
afraid of,
are disgusted by that you have the most
resistance to,
um,
so,
but we were talking about psychedelics
and uh,
and the experience of hell.
So,
uh,
at least some of the people I've talked
to,
they're described negative trip says I'm
an experience of a,
of constant fear,
prolonged fear,
and um,
some of the most dramatic and
personalized that they've ever
experienced.
So shouldn't a negative psychedelic
trips elicit the kind of concentration
that a young thought you should engage
in?
Could be?
Could well be it?
It's conceivable that I read this
strange book once that made the claim
that what was in the Ark of the covenant
was a mixture that was made from am
Anita Mascara,
mushrooms,
and that's not as far fetched as you
might think because there was a
mycologist in amateur knit mycologist
named Gordon West saw who established
credibly the notion that it was an Itam
is scarier potions that was the Soma of
the rig Veda,
and so it's a strange idea,
but
it's not an idea that's completely
outside of the realm of possibility and
the Amanitas must carry out the Flyer
Erik,
the red mushroom with white dots and
it's used in shamanic rituals in cross
Asia and it's apparently not toxic and
it's dried form.
Although that is not a recommendation.
No,
this is serious,
serious and dangerous speculation and
material.
One of the things that the priests had
to do before they communed with what was
ever in the Ark of the covenant was
purified themselves and so one
possibility is that the bad psychedelic
experience is a involuntary
confrontation with what you'd describe
as the shadow.
Like so be aware of experimenting with
substances that produce divine
revelations if you're in a serious state
of disorder.
And I do think that is what happens to
people is that they encounter everything
about them that's chaotic and out of
place and some people get trapped in
that and they can't get beyond it and
that's because there's so much of it
and so,
but we don't know enough to know.
So thanks.
So you a son of a bitch.
How are you?
I'm not too bad.
You got a question?
No,
I've got a real question.
I got a question.
You're going to like this one.
Okay.
It's about inspiration because you talk
about inspiration quite a bit in this
lecture series and also I wanted to
point out you have a I guess a 45 minute
armchair discussion which you have a
video of of one paragraph of Nietzsche's
beyond good and evil just posted and it
seems like you're awestruck at the
structure and the choices and I guess
the ideas contained in various layers of
this paragraph and you're inspired and
that inspires you to I guess,
do your work that you do.
I encountered I guess a similar
phenomenon here with one sentence
written by the Great Joseph Cardinal
Ratzinger and I mean this one sentence
answers the question,
why do people search for God and if you
could read it out and then
deconstructed.
It's once.
It's at the end of page one.
Oh,
five.
If you want to read it from the book or
I just.
That's the question.
That human existence not only poses but
itself is the inconclusiveness inherent
in it.
The bounds it comes up against and that
yet urine for the unbounded,
more or less in the sense of niches,
assertion that all pleasure yearns for
eternity.
It experiences itself as a moment.
This simultaneity of being limited and
of yearning for the unbounded and open
has always presented,
man from resting and himself made him
sense that he is not self sufficient,
but only comes to himself by going
outside himself and moving toward the
entirely other.
An infinitely greater well.
It's a hell of a sentence.
When I read that sentence,
I decided I wanted to write like Joseph
Cardinal Ratzinger.
I had a very similar experience when I
watched the Joe Rogan podcast.
Eight 77.
I said,
I want to speak like Jordan Peterson.
That's what I wanted to do.
So I had this.
I had this discussion with a patron and
supporter this week,
a young guy from Australia and and he
said something very interesting that's
related to this and it's,
it's something that's very profound.
I said,
I think there's this idea in
Christianity that we've discussed
briefly that the judge and the redeemer
are the same figure.
Now,
you know in the book of revelation,
you may know this and you may not,
Christ comes back as a judge and he has
a sword coming into.
It's a revelatory vision that that book,
it's a very strange.
It's the last thing you'd expect.
Conservative Christian is to believe in,
believe me,
it's such a visionary hallucination,
the book of revelation,
but Christ comes back with a sword
coming out of his mouth and he comes
back as a judge and he divides the
damned from the redeemed and most are
damned in some are redeemed who's very,
very harsh.
A young believer that the figure of
Christ in the Gospels was too agreeable
to merciful,
to tilted towards mercy and that that
called out for a counter position and
that was the counter position of
judgment.
Very interesting hypothesis,
but then,
but then there's this melding of the two
ideas that the judge and the redeemer
are the same thing.
Okay?
Now,
this young man told me that his life
lacked purpose and direction and meaning
and that he was nihilistic until he
started.
He read Zen and the art of motorcycle
maintenance,
which is a book I actually liked quite a
bit.
I've read it three times at different
decades of my life and one of the things
that's very interesting about that book
is that it's an examination of the idea
of quality,
of the idea that there are qualitative
distinctions between things and that we
have an instinct to make qualitative
distinctions,
and so a qualitative distinction is
simply this is better than that,
which is a judgment.
Okay.
What ratzinger is hypothesizing is that
the person ended up,
you know,
how the idea of the modern ideas,
you're supposed to accept yourself.
I think that's an insane idea,
by the way.
Really.
I think.
I can't think of a more nihilistic idea
then that you're already okay.
It's like,
no,
you're not,
and the reason you're not is could be
way more than you are,
and so what do you want to be?
You want to be okay as you are or do you
want to strive towards what's better?
And this young man,
this Australia,
and he said that the reason that Zen and
the art of motorcycle maintenance had
such an impact on him was because he
wasn't happy with his current mode of
being right.
He didn't consider the manner in which
he conducted themselves sufficient and
the fact that the author of Zen and laid
out the notion that you could make
qualitative distinctions in there.
There really was a difference between
good things and bad things are great
things and evil things.
It gives you direction.
It gives you,
gives you the possibility of moving
upward and and ratzinger is pointing out
at least to some degree that human
beings are insufficient in and of
themselves and need the movement upward.
And so they need to conceptualize
something like the highest good.
And then to strive for that.
And the thing is is that there isn't any
difference between conceptualizing the
good and being judged.
Because if you're going to conceptualize
the good and move towards it,
what you have to do is separate from
yourself.
All those things that aren't good and
leave them behind.
And that's why the redeemer and the
judge or the same thing,
and one of the things that's really
appalling,
I think about our modern world is that
we're rejecting the notion of
qualitative distinctions.
You said,
well,
we don't want to hurt anybody's feelings
by saying that one thing is better than
the other.
It's like,
okay,
fair enough.
It's not fun to be cast off with the
damned,
that's for sure.
But if people are in fact insufficient
in an in their present condition,
which seems to be the case,
we try finding someone who isn't.
Then if you deny the possibility of
qualitative distinction because you want
to promote a radical egalitarianism,
then you remove the possibility of
redemption because there's no movement
towards the good.
And it seems to me that it's a
catastrophe to sacrifice the good for.
Well,
it's a catastrophe to sacrifice the good
for the equal because for us to be
equal,
it would be mean as far as I can tell
that we would all be equally unredeemed
and miserable.
And so you also mentioned in the
previous paragraph,
I believe that even in the case when you
experienced the human life at its
fullest,
at its most beautiful as it's most
meaningful,
you have a deep,
I guess understanding that you have
something to be thankful for you.
You need to thank somebody for that.
It's not
based entirely on your own merit and
that points you toward something else.
And also in that you can have a
profoundly positive experience,
you know,
in the best sense without that
accompanying it.
That's a feeling of being blessed.
It's something like that back.
And also I'd like to wait,
hold it.
I'm going to stop you.
Okay,
because I'm going to ask this person,
but I would like to say that those were
remarkably good questions.
So the experience and thank you for the
wonderful lecturer.
I'm giving you a working definition of
truth and say within the Abrahamic
religious tradition,
would you say that the more perhaps
mystical sects and denominations which
play place more emphasis on the
transcendental experience of God or the
experience as opposed to the more
fundamentalist Orthodox literalist which
perhaps emphasize the,
what I've noticed,
um,
moral policing of behaviors.
Would you say that the former is more
true than the latter?
No and no.
And,
and it continues to be.
We could former in some way serve as an
antidote to extremist literalism
jihadism,
fundamentalism.
Okay.
So,
yes to the second part,
but the first part,
it's a great question.
We do.
We did some research on this awhile back
because we were looking at the different
religious proclivities of liberals and
conservatives and liberals.
Like if you're liberal it means you're
high in openness and low in
conscientiousness and if you're
conservative than your high in
conscientiousness and low in openness
and that the liberals are spiritual and
the conservatives are dogmatic,
but it's best to think of those as
partners,
right?
Because the,
the spiritual mystical end is where the
revelations emerge and the renewal.
But that's where there's chaos and
discord as well because what's new
disrupts what stable and so what's new
has to be turned into.
It has to be integrated into what stable
and so you need both those poles and of
course if the dogmatist get the upper
hand,
then everything turns into a tyranny of
stone that that's Egypt,
Egypt in the Old Testament.
But if the,
if the.
If the mystics get the upper hand,
then everything floats off the earth
into some impractical ether.
That is equally counterproductive.
And so there has to be a dialogue
between those different polls.
And I think you see that in the
distribution of human temperament.
You know the conscientious types,
they tend to be orderly.
The orderly types tend to tend towards
the kind of a right wing
totalitarianism.
That's their proclivity when they.
When,
when they.
When things get out of hand,
if they're low in openness,
that's a danger.
But you see the same thing with the
people who are too open and not
conscientious at all.
They're dreaming all the time,
but they never do anything.
There's never anything implemented and
that that's a bad.
That's a bad thing,
so I don't think that you can say that
like the dogmatic structure is necessary
because that perpetuates the system and
the revelatory elements is necessary
because that renews it when renewal is
necessary and there has to be a
continual dialogue between those
elements so that neither of them fall
prey to their own particular form of
pathology.
And that's one of the problems with the
current political.
What would you call it,
polarization that's occurring across the
West,
is that the right and the left are not
talking to each other anymore and it's a
very bad thing because the left will
wander into a pit and fail without
boundaries.
And the right will enclose itself in
smaller and smaller spaces until it
can't move without the left.
And one of the reasons that democracy
works is because it makes people talk or
allows them to talk.
You can have it either way,
but it,
it's,
it's because every virtue has its vice.
Right?
And so,
uh,
met a virtue is something like the
amalgamation of singular virtues into
something that's a transcendent
structures that has more to do with the
harmony of virtues rather than with any
given virtue,
even though I think that free freedom of
speech is the clearest manifestation of
that harmony of virtues.
So.
And so all could be a lubricant for the
beginning of this discussion.
Do you think between the Liberals and
conservatives?
I don't know how to answer that doesn't,
doesn't follow immediately from your,
from your initial presuppositions.
So the ar experience is a different
issue.
Yeah.
Well the.
Yes.
At least exposing conservatives to some
form of that experience because it,
could it be a prerequisite for more
productive dialogue?
See,
I mean in,
in,
in the church,
in a church ceremony,
let's say a classical church ceremony,
there's some intermingling of both,
right?
You mean you think about a church
ceremony that takes place in a gothic
cathedral.
We started,
got the dogma and the and the,
and the relatively rigid rule structure,
but at the same time that's aligned with
intense beauty in the architectural
forms.
In the,
in the light streaming in through the
stained glass windows and the music and
I mean the Gothic cathedral is a forest,
right?
It's a stone forest with sunlight
streaming in through the trees and
instead it's a balance between structure
light there absolutely unbelievable
structures and then they speak of the
transcendent but it.
But inside that there's a structure and
so it seems that in order for the
religious impulse to be balanced
property,
there has to be a reasonable
dialog.
Even in practice between the mystical
are inspiring,
transcendent,
and the dogmatic.
Yeah.
Either of those can go as either of
those goes to straight without the
other.
If you're too dogmatic,
do you need all likely?
Yes.
Because that would show you that there's
something beyond your own
presuppositions.
So,
so all I should tell you something
interesting about,
ah,
as a,
as a physiological phenomena,
you know how you're listening to music
and you get chills.
Some people experienced that more than
others.
Open people experienced that more.
Or music is a pretty reliable solicitor.
Have chills.
That's Palo erection.
That's your hair standing on end.
You see a cat when it sees a dog puffs
up,
that's all.
It's the same thing like that.
That chill is your hair standing on end
and that's the.
That's the sensation you get in the
presence of a predator.
It's something like that.
And so there are experiences.
I mean obviously it's become very
cognitively and emotionally complex and
human beings,
but it's fundamental evolutionary
underpinning is the instantaneous pilot
erection that you see in prey animals
when they're confronted by a predator.
And of course that would be,
if you are a rabbit,
you can bloody well believed that you
see a wolf and it would inspire all,
that's for sure.
I mean,
if a wolf that was 20 feet high came
bounding in here,
man,
you'd feel off.
So now that will convince you that
there's something that you still need to
know.
Last,
last question,
perfect timing.
Hi Dr.
Beard Peterson.
My name is Gary and I'm a clinical and
counseling master's student right now.
And so one of the key ideas that's been
surfacing time and time again in your
lecturers is the idea that phenomenology
is structured and flows mythologically
and the way that plays out as I'm
supposing effectively just pay attention
to what comes up kind of naturally and
you can locate the cow elements and your
experience and product them with
whatever degree of necessity you think.
So I'm trying to situate this within the
clinical context.
We can conceptualize psychotherapy as a
kind of guided journey just as you
touched on in this lecture where it's
more of a metal journey in a sense,
a meadow heroic journey,
but I know how you want to think about
it,
but just for those of us who are
interested in kind of grounding and
implementing these ideas within
psychotherapeutic practice,
what should we watch out for in the
process itself?
What comes up?
What should we be afraid of,
were fearful of or cautious about,
or what should we tend towards?
That's my question.
Well,
I think one of the,
one of the people who I've read that's
had the biggest impact on me as a
clinician was Carl Rogers.
Um,
and the reason for that is that Carl
Rogers put tremendous emphasis on
listening,
like it's almost impossible to
overestimate how useful it is to listen
to your clients.
Like you need a Meta scheme in some
sense and the metal scheme I think is
laid out in the sermon on the mount.
It's something like Orient Yourself and
your client towards the good that the
client has to conceptualize what that
might be.
You can serve as a guide,
but it has to come from that person
because one of the things that you want
to find out from your client is okay,
what's wrong they have to tell you and
what would not having something wrong
look like,
like what is it?
If you could have what you wanted and
that and that,
that would be good.
What would that look like?
Okay.
So that establishes your star,
right?
It's like Japan establishing the
relationship with the Star at the
beginning of Pinocchio.
Here's what we're aiming at.
Okay,
so now you've got that Schema.
Here's what we're aiming at.
Now you might say you might think,
well now what happens to the client as
they meet their dragons along the way
and their dragons would be,
well now you know what you want and
there are things in your way,
and some of those things might.
Many of those things are going to be
intensely practical,
but they're practical slash
psychological,
so like so maybe someone is has a job
and they would like to move forward in
their job,
but they're terrified of speaking in
public.
Well,
you know,
is that a psychological problem or a
practical problem?
It's both.
It's also a real problem in many
positions.
Unless you can speak fluently publicly,
you're going to hit a ceiling and you're
not going to go anywhere and so for the
person to move towards that goal,
then they have to confront the obstacles
that manifest themselves within that
framework.
And part of your job as a clinician is
to identify the obstacles and to
discriminate them from things they don't
have to worry about.
Right?
Part of it is,
you know,
you can't just run around and try to
combat all of the chaos in the world.
Some of it is your chaos and a bunch of
it isn't,
and the chaos that's yours is the chaos
that emerges as you move towards a
necessary goal and so partly what you're
doing by listening to your client is to
help them cut their dragons down to
size.
You know,
because what'll happen if you start to
talk to somebody about public speaking
and you really talked to them,
is that you decompose the problem into a
set of maybe 20 sub problems like,
well,
do you know exactly how to give a
speech?
Like what's your theory of,
of,
of public speaking?
You know how to look at people when
you're talking.
Do you know how to speak loudly enough
so that people can hear you?
Do you have a philosophy of,
of public speaking?
I mean all those things are necessary.
In order to do it properly,
you need to decompose
that with the client and then to make
those problems,
you have to decompose them to the point
where they can be met by a practical
solution and then you have to guide the
person through the implementation of the
practical solution and mostly you do
that by listening.
It's like what you need to be is the
person who helps the person that you're
working with orient themselves towards a
better future.
That's the compact.
You and I are in this space at this time
to make things better.
First of all,
we have to decide what better would look
like and second we need a strategy and
third we need to.
Once we have that,
we're going to see the obstacles and
some of those are going to be
psychological and some of them are going
to be practical and we're going to
engage in joint problem solving of
whatever sort is necessary in order to
minimize the impact of those problems or
to gain from the problems in dream
analysis can be extremely useful for
that.
By the way,
it's even more useful for helping the
person identify what the goal is because
that's often difficult for people,
so like,
well,
I know that something's wrong,
but I don't know what I want.
Sometimes people get so stuck there that
they just can't get.
They just can't get out of it.
So.
And then what would you watch out for
phenomenal phenomenologically?
The way it shows up,
the way it's experienced?
Well,
I would say as a clinician,
one of the things that you should watch
out for is resentment.
So there's A.
There's a couple of rules of thumb I
that I think are useful.
Don't do anything for your clients that
they can do for themselves and don't do
them any favors.
Now I think you can step beyond the
confines of your role carefully now and
then to show that there's a more human
connection than the merely contractual.
I think that's very useful,
but their problems are not your
problems.
You do not have any right to their
problems and so you have to maintain
that detachment because otherwise you
can steal their destiny.
You don't want to be the person that
solves their problems because you steal
their destiny.
When you do that,
you want to be someone with whom they
can figure things out for themself and
so there's.
There can be hubris and being a
clinician because you can be the problem
solver and that elevates you to a
position.
You elevate yourself to that position.
You'll fall flat on your face,
you'll hurt your clients and things will
kick back on you very,
very hard because what the hell do you
know?
Right?
Nothing because that person is very
complicated and they need to.
They need to sort themselves out and.
But you can be a facilitator for that,
but that's all you should be and so you
have to watch that.
You have to watch over.
Becoming over entail really entangled,
so you have to maintain your detachment
in the best sense and you have to not
overstep your.
It's easy to become hubris stick when
the person is looking to you for the
answers.
It's like you might.
You don't have the answers,
although you might be able to find,
help the person find their way.
That's what you do with everyone you
love to write.
I mean you don't provide them with the
answers because then they become little
clones of you and unhappy,
bitter,
resentful and angry little clones of
view because you usurped their destiny.
And so the same thing applies within
familiar arrangements or friendships,
all of that.
So
thank you.