Today I want to present to you some of
the things I've been thinking and
writing about his Easter approached.
I'm going to do this in five separate
parts which hopefully will make up a
coherent hole.
I'm going to read all of this because
it's complicated in part one,
the nature of experience.
There are two ways of looking at the
world as a place of things and there's a
forum for action because we are living
beings and must make our way
pragmatically in the world.
The second way of looking has to take
precedence.
This means that the world as a place of
things is nested inside the world as a
forum for action.
This means that our conceptualization of
the world as objective must remain
subordinate to our conceptualization of
the world as a place of being.
This is from the first part of my book.
Maps
meaning quote,
the world can be validly construed as
forum for action or place of things.
The former manner of interpretation,
more primordial and less clearly
understood,
finds its expression in the arts or
humanities,
enriched reuel drama,
literature and mythology of the world as
forum for auction is a place of value,
a place where all things have meaning.
This meaning which is shaped as a
consequence of social interaction is
implication for action or at a higher
level of analysis implication for the
configuration of the Interpretive Schema
that produces or guides action the
ladder manner of interpretation.
The world as place of things finds its
formal expression in the methods and
theories of science.
Science allows for increasingly precise
determination of the consensually
validatable properties of things and for
efficient utilization of precisely
determined things as tools.
Once the direction such use is to take
has been determined through application
of more fundamental narrative processes.
No complete world picture can be
generated without use of both modes of
construal.
The fact that one mode is generally set
at odds with the other means only that
the nature of their respective domains
remains insufficiently discriminated.
Adherence of the mythological worldview
tend to regard the statements of their
creeds as indistinguishable from
empirical fact.
Even though such statements were
generally formulated long before the
notion of objective reality emerged,
those who by contrast except the
scientific perspective who assumed that
it is or might become complete,
forget that an impossible golf currently
divides what is from what should be.
I wrote this a little later.
It's also relevant as introduction to
what we're going to discuss in a bit.
The world can be validly construed as a
forum for action as well as a place of
things.
We described the world as a place of
things using the formal methods of
science.
The techniques of narrative,
however,
myth,
literature,
and drama portray the world as a forum
for action.
The two forms of representation have
been unnecessarily set at odds because
we have not yet formed a clear picture
of their respective domains.
The domain of the former scientific
domain is the objective world.
What is from the perspective of
intersubjective perception?
The domain of the ladder drama narrative
is the world of value.
What is and what should be from the
perspective of emotion and action.
The world as a forum for action presents
itself in two stories.
The normal story,
I was at point a and I was going to
point b and the revolutionary story.
I was at point a and well going to point
b,
something entirely unexpected and earth
shattering happened meant I had to
abandon my story,
question my assumptions,
a lot of my old beliefs to die and be
reborn.
A new.
The second story which is deeper,
is essentially religious part to some
axioms of the Christian revolutionary
story,
number one,
to decide that and then enact the
proposition that being is good despite
its tragedy and malevolence.
Number two,
to work in consequence for the continual
and eternal improvement of that being
and to know that as love.
Number three,
to do such work in truth.
Number four,
to let everything inadequate burn off in
that pursuit and to welcome its
replacement by what is better.
Number five,
to know that as the sacred imitation of
Christ.
Number six,
do you understand that although Christ's
sacrifice redeemed us,
all the work still has to be done.
Number seven,
to accept that work as the sacred
meaning of life.
Number eight,
to strive toward the heavenly city on
the hill in that manner,
part three,
narratives and sacrifice for my new
book,
12 rules for life.
Rule seven,
pursue what is meaningful,
not what is expedient.
Every man for himself and the devil.
Take the hindmost as the old proverb
hasn't.
Why not simply take everything you can
get whenever the opportunity arises,
why not determined to live in that
manner
or is there an alternative and if so,
why should we bother with it?
Our ancestors worked out very
sophisticated answers to such questions,
but we still don't understand them very
well.
This is because they are in large part,
still implicit manifest primarily in
ritual and myth,
and as of yet in completely articulated,
we act them out and represent them in
stories,
but we're not yet.
Why is it enough to formulate them
explicitly?
We're still chimps in a troop or wolves
in a pack.
We know how to behave.
We know who's who and why.
We've learned that through experience or
knowledge has been shaped by the
interaction with others.
We've established predictable routines
and patterns of behavior,
but we don't really understand them or
know where they originated.
They've evolved over great expanses of
time,
but we didn't and still don't understand
what it all meant.
The Biblical narrative of Paradise and
the fall is one such story fabricated by
our collective imagination working over
the centuries.
It provides a profound account of the
nature of being and points the way to a
mode of conceptualization and action,
well matched to that nature in the
garden of Eden prior to the dawn of self
consciousness,
so goes the story.
Human beings were sinless.
Our primordial parents,
Adam and Eve walked with God,
then tempted by the snake.
The first couple ate from the tree of
the knowledge of good and evil,
discovered death and vulnerability and
turned away from God.
Mankind was exiled from paradise and
began it's effortful,
mortal existence,
the of sacrifice.
Enter soon afterward,
beginning with the account of Cain and
Abel and developing through the
Abrahamic Adventures and the exodus.
After much contemplation,
struggling humanity learns that God's
favor could be gained and his wrath
averted through proper sacrifice,
and also that bloody murder might be
motivated among those unwilling or
unable to succeed in this matter.
The delay of gratification when engaging
in sacrifice,
our forefathers began to act out what
would be considered a proposition if it
were stated in words that something
better might be attained in the future
by giving up something of value in the
president.
Recall,
if you will,
that the necessity for work is one of
the curses placed by God upon Adam and
his descendants in consequence of
original sin.
Adam's waking to the fundamental
constraints of his being,
his vulnerability.
His eventual death is equivalent to his
discovery of the future.
The future
that's where you go to die.
Hopefully not too soon.
Your demise might be staved off through
work,
through the sacrifice of the now to gain
benefit later.
It is for this reason among others,
no doubt that the concept of sacrifice
is introduced in the biblical chapter
immediately following the drama of the
fall.
There's little difference between
sacrifice and work.
They're also both uniquely human.
Sometimes animals act as if they're
working,
but they are really only following the
dictates of their nature.
Beavers build dams.
They do so because they are beavers,
beavers build dams.
They don't think,
yeah,
but I'd rather be on a beach in Mexico
with my girlfriend while they're doing
it.
Prosaically such sacrifice work is delay
of gratification,
but that's a very mundane phrase to
describe something of soul shattering
significance.
The discovery that gratification could
be delayed was similar to the discovery
of time and with it causality,
at least the causal force,
a voluntary human action.
Long ago in the mists of time,
we began to realize that reality was
structured as if it could be bargained
with.
We learned that behaving properly now in
the present,
regulating our impulses,
considering the plight of others could
bring rewards in the future in a time
and place that did not yet exist.
We began to inhibit control and organize
our immediate impulses so that we could
stop interfering with other people and
our future selves.
Doing so was indistinguishable from
organizing the discovery of the causal
relationship between our efforts today
and the quality of tomorrow.
Motivated the social contract,
the organization that enables today's
work to be stored reliably,
mostly in the form of promises from
others.
Understanding is often acted out before
it can be articulated just as a child
acts out what it means to be mother or
father before being able to give a
spoken account of what those roles mean.
The act of making a ritual sacrifice to
God was an early and sophisticated
enactment of the idea of the usefulness
of delay.
There is a long conceptual journey
between merely feasting,
hungrily and learning to set aside some
extra meat smoke by the fire for the end
of the day or for someone who isn't
present.
It takes a long time to learn to keep
anything later for yourself or to share
it with someone else,
and those are very much the same thing
as in the former case you are sharing
with your future self.
It is much easier and far more likely to
selfishly and immediately wolf down
everything in sight.
There are similar long journeys between
every leap and sophistication with
regards to delay and its
conceptualization,
short term sharing,
storing away for the future
representation of that storage in the
form of records and later in the form of
currency and ultimately the saving of
money in a bank or other social
institution.
Some conceptualizations had to serve as
intermediaries or the full range of our
practices and ideas surrounding
sacrifice and work and their
representation could have never emerged.
Our ancestors acted out a drama fiction.
They personified the forest,
that governance fate as a spirit that
can be bargained with,
traded with as if it were another human
being,
and the amazing thing is that it worked.
This was in part because the future is
largely composed of other human beings,
often precisely those who have watched
and evaluated and to praise the tiniest
details of your past behavior.
It's not very far from that to God
sitting above on high tracking your
every move and writing it down for
further reference in a big book.
Here's a productive symbolic idea.
The future is a judgmental father.
That's a good start,
but two additional archetypal
foundational questions arose because of
the discovery of sacrifice of work both
have to do with the ultimate extension
of the logic of work,
which is sacrifice now to gain later.
First question,
what must be sacrificed?
Small sacrifices maybe sufficient to
solve small singular problems,
but it is possible that larger,
more comprehensive sacrifices might
solve an array of large and complex
problems all at the same time.
That's harder,
but it might be better adapting to the
necessary discipline of medical school
will,
for example,
fatally interfere with a licentious
lifestyle of a hardcore undergraduate
party animal.
Giving that up is a sacrifice,
but a physician can quote George W
really put food on his family that's a
lot of trouble dispensed with over a
very long period of time,
so sacrifices are necessary to improve
the future and larger sacrifices can be
better.
Second question,
set of related questions.
Really,
we've already established the basic
principle sacrifice will improve the
future,
but a principal once established has to
be fleshed out.
It's full extension or significance has
to be understood.
What is implied by the idea that
sacrifice will improve the future in the
most extreme and final of cases,
where does that basic principle find its
limits?
We must ask to begin what would be the
largest,
most effective,
most pleasing of all possible
sacrifices,
and then how good mike the best possible
future be.
If the most effective sacrifice could be
made.
The Biblical story of Cain and Abel,
Adam and Eve sons immediately follows
the story of the expulsion from
paradise.
As mentioned previously,
Cain and Abel are really the first
humans since their parents were made
directly by God and not born in the
standard manner.
Cain and Abel live in history,
not in Eden.
They must work.
They must make sacrifices to please God
and they do so with alter and proper
ritual,
but things get complicated.
Ables offerings pleased God,
but canes do not able is rewarded many
times over,
but Kane is not.
It's not precisely clear why,
although the tech strongly hints that
Keynes Heart is just not in it.
Maybe the quality of what came put
forward was low.
Maybe his spirit was begrudging or maybe
God was vexed for some secret reasons of
his own,
and all of this is realistic,
including the texts,
vagueness of explanation.
Not all sacrifices are of equal quality.
Furthermore,
it often appears that sacrifices of
apparently high quality or not rewarded
with a better future and it's not clear
why,
why isn't God happy?
What would have to change to make him
so?
Those are difficult questions and
everyone asks them all the time,
even if they don't notice.
Asking such questions is
indistinguishable from thinking.
The realization that pleasure could be
usefully forestalled dawned on us with
great difficulty.
It runs absolutely contrary to our
ancient fundamental animal instincts
which demand immediate satisfaction,
particularly under conditions of
deprivation,
which are both inevitable and common
place,
and to complicate the matter,
such delay only becomes useful when
civilization has stabilized itself
enough to guarantee the existence of the
delayed reward in the future.
If everything you save will be destroyed
or worse,
stolen,
there's no point in saving.
It is for this reason that a wolf will
down 20 pounds of raw meat in a single
meal.
He isn't thinking,
man,
I hate it when I binge.
I should save some of this for next
week,
so how was it that those two impossible
and necessarily simultaneous ad call,
months delay and the stabilization of
society into the future could possibly
have manifested themselves?
Here is a developmental progression from
animal to human.
It's wrong,
no doubt in the details,
but it's sufficiently correct for our
purposes in theme first,
there's excess food,
large carcasses.
Mammoths are other massive herbivores
might provide that.
We a lot of Mammas,
maybe all of the with a large animal.
There's some left for later after a kill
that's accidental at first,
but eventually the utility of for later
starts to be appreciated.
Some provisional notion of sacrifice
develops at the same time.
If I leave some,
even if I wanted now,
I won't have to be hungry later.
That provisional notion develops to the
next level.
If I leave some for later,
I won't have to go hungry and neither
will those I care for and then to the
next.
I can't possibly eat all of this
mammoth,
but I can't store the rest for too long
either.
Maybe I should feed to other people,
maybe they'll remember and feed me some
of their mammoth when they have some and
I have none.
Then I'll get some mammoth now and some
mammoth later.
That's a good deal and maybe those I'm
sharing with will come to trust me more
generally.
Maybe then we could trade forever in
such a manner.
Mammoth becomes future,
mammoth and future.
Mammoth becomes personal reputation that
the emergence of the social contract to
share does not mean to give away
something you value and get nothing
back.
That is instead only what every child
who refuses to share fears.
It means to share means properly to
initiate the process of trade.
A child who can't share,
who can't trade,
can't have any friends because having
friends is a form of trade.
Benjamin Franklin once suggested that a
newcomer to a neighborhood ask a new
neighbor to do him or her a favor citing
this old maxim.
He that is once done,
you a kindness will be more ready to do
you another.
Then he whom you yourself have obliged
in Franklin's opinion,
asking someone for something not too
extreme,
obviously was the most useful and
immediate invitation to social
interaction and trade,
such asking on the part of the newcomer
provided the neighbor with an
opportunity to show him or herself as a
good person at first encounter.
It also meant that the ladder could now
ask the former for a favor in return
because of the debt incurred,
increasing their mutual familiarity and
trust in that manner,
both parties could overcome their
natural hesitancy and mutual fear of the
stranger.
It is better to have something than
nothing.
It's better yet to share generously this
something you have.
It's even better than that.
However,
to become widely known for generous
sharing.
That's something that lasts,
that something that's reliable,
and at this point of abstraction we can
observe how the ground work for the
conceptions,
reliable,
honest and generous have been laid.
The basis for an articulated morality
has been put in place.
The productive,
truthful sharer is the prototype for the
good citizen and the good man we can see
in this manner how from the simple
notion that leftovers are a good idea,
the highest moral principles might
emerge.
It's as if something like the following
happened as humanity developed first
where the endless tens or hundreds of
thousands of years prior to the
emergence of written history and drama.
During this time,
the twin practices of delay and exchange
begin to emerge slowly and painfully.
Then they become represented in
metaphorical abstraction as rituals and
tales of sacrifice told in a manner such
as this.
It's as if there's a powerful figure in
the sky who sees all and is judging you,
giving up something you value,
seems to make them happy and you want to
make them happy because all hell breaks
loose if you don't.
So practice sacrificing and sharing
until you become an expert at it and
things will go well for you.
No one said any of this,
at least not so plainly and directly,
but it was implicit in the practice.
And then in the stories auction came
first.
Has it had to,
as the animals we once were,
could act,
but could not think.
Implicit,
unrecognized value came first as the
actions that proceeded thought embodied
value,
but did not make that value explicit.
People watched the success will succeed
and the unsuccessful fail for thousands
and thousands of years.
We thought it over a drew,
a conclusion.
The successful among us delay
gratification,
the successful among us bargain with the
future.
A great idea begins to emerge.
Taking evermore clearly articulated form
in evermore clearly articulated stories.
What's the difference between the
successful and the unsuccessful?
The successful sacrifice things get
better as the successful practice,
their sacrifices,
the questions become increasingly
precise and Cymbalta caneously broader.
What is the greatest possible sacrifice
for the greatest possible good,
and the answers become increasingly
deeper and profound.
The God of western tradition like so
many gods requires sacrifice.
We've already examined why,
but sometimes he goes even further.
He demands not only sacrifice,
but the sacrifice of precisely what is
loved best.
This is most starkly portrayed,
most confusingly evident in the story of
Abraham and Isaac.
Abraham,
beloved of God long wanted to Sun and
God promised them exactly that after
many delays and under the apparently
impossible conditions of old age and the
long barren wife,
but not so long afterward when the
miraculous we born,
Isaac is still a child.
God turns around and an unreasonable and
apparently barbaric fashion demands that
his faithful servant offer his son as a
sacrifice.
The story ends happily.
God sends an angel to stay Abraham's
obedient hand and accepts a ram in Isaac
stead.
That's a good thing,
but it doesn't really address the issue
at hand.
Why is God's going further necessary?
Why does he?
Why does life impose such demands?
We'll start our analysis with a truism
stark self evident and understated.
Sometimes things do not go well.
That seems to have much to do with the
terrible nature of the world with its
plagues and famines and tyrannies and be
trails.
But here's the rub.
Sometimes when things are not going
well,
it's not the world that's the cause.
The cause is instead that which is
currently most valued subjectively and
personally.
Why?
Because the world is revealed to an
indeterminate degree through the
template of your values.
Thus,
if the world you are seeing is not the
world you want,
it's time to examine your values.
It's time to rid yourself of your
current presuppositions.
It's time to let go.
It might even be time to sacrifice what
you love best so that you can become who
you might become instead of staying who
you are.
There's an old and possibly apocryphal
story about how to catch a monkey that
illustrates this set of ideas very well.
First,
you must find a large narrow neck jar
just barely wide enough in diameter at
the top for a monkey to put his hand
inside.
Then you must fill the jar parkway with
rocks so it is too heavy for a monkey to
carry.
Then you must scatter some treats
attractive to monkeys near the jar to
attract one and put some more inside the
jar.
A monkey will come along,
reach into the narrow opening and grab
while the grabbing is good,
but now we won't be able to extract his
fist now full of treats from the jar,
not without unclenching his hand,
not without relinquishing what he
already has,
and that's just what he won't do.
The monkey capture can then walk over to
the jar and pick up the monkey.
The animal will not sacrifice the part
to preserve the whole something valuable
given up ensures future prosperity,
something valuable sacrificed,
pleases the Lord.
What is most valuable and best
sacrificed,
or what is it least emblematic of that
choice cut of meat,
the best animal in a flock,
our most valued possession.
What's above even that something
intensely personal and painful to give
up that symbolized perhaps in God's
insistence on circumcision as part of
Abraham sacrificial routine where the
part is offered symbolically to redeem
the whole.
What's beyond that?
What pertains more closely to the whole
person rather than to the part
what constitutes the ultimate sacrifice
for the gain of the ultimate prize?
It's a close race between child and
self.
The sacrifice of the mother offering her
child to the world is exemplified
profoundly by Michelangelo's great
sculpture.
The Pieta,
Michelangelo Crafted Mary cradling the
nearly naked body of her adult son
crucified and ruined.
It's her fault.
It was through her that he entered the
world and it's great drama of being.
Is it right to bring a baby into this
terrible world?
Every woman asks herself that question.
Some say no,
and they have their reasons.
Mary answers,
yes,
voluntarily knowing full well what's to
come as do all mothers if they allow
themselves to see it's an act of supreme
courage when it's undertaken
voluntarily.
In turn,
Mary's son Christ offers himself to God
and the world to be trail torture and
death to the very point of despair on
the cross where he cries out those
terrible words from Matthew Twenty
seven,
46,
my God,
why Hast Thou forsaken me?
That is the archetypal story of the man
who gives his all for the sake of the
better.
Who offers up his life for the
advancement of being who allows God's
will to become manifest fully within the
confines of a single mortal life?
That is the model for the honorable man
in Christ case.
However,
as he sacrifices himself,
God,
his father is similar,
sacrificing his son.
It is for this reason that the Christian
sacrificial drama of Sun and self is
archetypal story at the limit where
nothing more extreme,
nothing greater can be imagined.
That's the very definition of archetypal
and that's the core of what constitutes
a religious pain and suffering.
Define the world of that.
There can be no doubt.
Sacrifice can hold pain and suffering in
abeyance to a greater or lesser degree
and greater sacrifices can do that more
effectively than lesser of that.
There can be no doubt.
Everyone holds this knowledge in their
souls.
Thus,
the person who wishes to alleviate
suffering,
who wishes to rectify the flaws and Ba,
who wants to bring about the best of all
possible futures,
who wants to create heaven on earth will
make the greatest of sacrifices of self,
end of child,
of everything that is loved to live a
life aimed at the good he will forego
expediency,
he will pursue the path of ultimate
meaning and he will in that manner bring
salvation to the ever desperate world.
Part four from my blog on the Ark of the
covenant,
the Cathedral and the Cross Easter
message,
one abridged from wikipedia.
The Ark of the covenant was elicited.
Gold leafed wouldn't chest containing
the two stone tablets of the Ten
Commandments.
According to various texts within the
Hebrew Bible,
it also contained Aaron's Rod and a part
of Manna.
God was said to have spoken with Moses
from between the two Cherubim on the
arcs cover,
the biblical account states that the
arch was created a year after the
Israelite exodus from Egypt according to
a pattern given to Moses by God at the
foot of Mount Sinai.
Thereafter,
the gold plated acacia chest was carried
by it staves while en route by the Levi.
It's in advance of the people went on
the march towards the promised land or
at the head of the Israelite army in
transport.
The arc was concealed under a large veil
made of skins and blue cloth,
carefully hidden even from the eyes of
the priests and the Levi who carried it
when at rest,
a portable building,
the tabernacle,
meaning residents or dwelling place was
set up to how's the arc.
It was built of woven layers of curtains
along with 48 boards clad with polished
gold standing like vertical blinds.
Solomon's Temple in Jerusalem superseded
it as the dwelling place of God.
Some 300 years later commentary.
There has to be a bridge between the
finite and the infinite.
There has to be a place where the
ephemeral meets the eternal.
There has to be a bridge between the
knowable and the unknowable and there
has to be bedrock at the foundation.
The arc,
which is the portal to God,
is to be carried on the shoulders of
those who are holding it is not to be
touched.
To touch the ark is to risk death.
There are holy things that cannot be
touched except at mortal risk.
Those things that cannot be touched or
at the very foundation of the community,
the art must be placed at the center of
the temple.
The temple must be placed at the center
of the community.
The community must be arranged around
what is untouchable and unshakeable.
The untouchable and unshakeable is what
is axiomatic.
The people following the arc have
determined to journey together toward
the eternal promised land.
The city arranged properly around the
Ark of the covenant is eternal.
Jerusalem,
something must be axiomatic or
everything.
Shakes and falls.
The axiomatic to not be expressed fully
in words.
Instead the axiomatic,
untouchable and unshakeable is what
makes communication in words possible.
The axiomatic is a spirit,
a process,
a living force,
its manifestations.
However,
our concrete,
that is the transformation of the spirit
into matter.
That is the generation of the tablets of
stone.
The Ark of the covenant contains the
rules that are derived in the first
order from the axiomatic principle.
That principle is the spirit that made
the rules manifest.
That spirit is the ultimate inhabitant
of the arch and the rules,
the result of its action.
That spirit is the creative logos,
the Ark of the covenant and the Temple
are replaced by the Cathedral at the
center of the community.
The cathedral is the cross in
architectural form.
The Cross is where the transformation
takes place.
The transformation is the incorporation
of the body of Christ.
That incorporation is a dramatic ritual,
is the embodiment of the decision not to
believe in Christ,
but to act him out,
which is to believe in a much deeper
manner than to merely believe Christ is
he who transcends death.
By voluntarily accepting death,
Christ is he who rejects the kingdoms of
this world.
For the Kingdom of God.
Christ is he who speaks the truth that
creates the habitable order that is
good,
from the chaos of potential that exists
prior to the materialization of reality.
Christ is he who wields potential as the
sword that cleaves death.
Christ is he who's radical,
acceptance of the conditions of life,
defeats the hatred,
bitterness and vengefulness that the
tragedy and malevolence that taints
being otherwise produces
without the acceptance of death,
bitterness,
rules,
and hell triumphs.
Christ is the potential of men and
woman.
It is said that men and women alike are
made in the image of God and that God is
he who uses the eternal logos to
generate habitable order from the chaos
of potential.
This is the axiom.
This is the diamond at the center of the
world.
This is the spirit in the arch that is
untouchable.
This is the bedrock of the culture that
brings peace and prosperity and that
respects the dignity of man.
This is the great truth.
This is the responsibility who's
acceptance allows each of us to live
despite the catastrophic fragility of
our limited being.
Our likeness to God gives each of us a
value that transcends the finite
individual and society of like are
charged with the ethical demand to
respect that value.
This is not only the presumption that
grounds the idea of the rights of man.
It is the presumption that lays upon
each of us the ultimate responsibility
that is the inevitable corollary of
those rights.
Face the chaos of the future.
Employ the logos of which you are a part
to transform that chaos into habitable
order that is good.
Speak the truth,
embodied the truth
except impossibly the limitations that
make being possible dispense in that
manner with resentment,
hatred,
and the desire for infinite and
unbounded vengeance and all the cruelty
and evil that accompanies it.
Pick up the cross of your tragedy and
betrayal,
except it's terrible.
Wait,
hoisted
onto your shoulders and struggle
impossibly upward toward the Kingdom of
God on the hill.
The alternative is death and hell.
Part Five.
The psychological meaning of the death
and resurrection of Christ.
Easter message to this is a somewhat
extended,
an altered version of a commentary that
I wrote for the London Sunday Times
magazine.
In the beginning only the king was
sovereign.
Then the nobles became sovereign.
Then with the Greeks,
all men became sovereign.
Then came the Christian revolution,
and every individual male,
female,
beggar,
men,
tax collector,
prostitute and thief became so
impossibly equally sovereign.
Then our cultural and legal systems
wrapped themselves tightly around that
ultimately unlikely narrative of
individual sovereignty and made it their
central unshakable pillar.
Now we all give each other the respect
of individual citizens who are sovereign
without remembering or noticing that we
are assembled,
accepting the proposition that every
single one of us is a divine center of
logos at the center of the eternal word
that brings habitable order into being
through the voluntary truthful
confrontation with chaos and the
unknown,
and if any one of us has not treated in
this manner.
If anyone,
no matter how powerful reacts to any of
us,
no matter how downtrodden,
as if our freewill is illusory or our
role in choosing the outcomes of our
lives,
nonexistent.
Then we get offended and angry and
agitated and insulted and rightly so,
are spectacularly and miraculously
functional.
Western legal systems are predicated on
the acceptance of the intrinsic value of
the individual predicated on the idea
that each person can step forward,
voluntarily accept the burden of being
transformed positively in consequence,
and share the results of that
transformation with everyone else.
It is in that manner that each of us
pushes everything away from the abyss
and a bit more heavenward is the
apparent necessity for such insanely
high regard an illusion.
It is certain that it is at least
functional and therefore not so
obviously illusory.
It is also equally certain that we have
not outlined any more viable,
materialistic alternative
you might well ask is the hypothesis of
intrinsic human value justified is our
apparent ability to face the as of yet
unmanifest future and decide on the
nature of its realization in the
present,
genuine and real?
Is it true despite the
incomprehensibility that we are free
conscious beings and that our conscious
freedom plays a role in constructing the
cosmos?
It could merely be as the cynics and
reductionists hold that consciousness is
an Epi phenomenon of materialistic
processes that there is no free will or
at least none of any genuine import,
that there is no accompanying moral
responsibility or freely chosen destiny.
There are however valid and not so
simply dispensed with reasons to avoid
too premature and casual acceptance of
such conclusions.
Even the greatest of us do not
understand consciousness,
not a bit much less comprehend the role
it plays in being.
We have no idea currently,
seriously no idea how the material
substrate of the brain produces the
awareness and more the self awareness
that seems so vital to the existence of
the cosmos.
If there is no center of experience to
experience something,
anything,
then it is very difficult to say in what
manner that's something or anything
exists.
Reality requires an observer and as far
as we can tell that observer is
consciousness.
Even more so self consciousness,
our awareness or self awareness appears
to confront the unformed potential of
the future and to cast it into the
concrete reality of the present.
Our consciousness acts on possibility
like the logos of the father acted on
the pre cosmogony chaos at the beginning
of time.
It is in that manner that we are made in
the image of God and we all demand to be
treated as if that were true and who
would dare to deny that such a demand is
made for valid and perhaps even
ultimately valid reasons.
Consider the evidence from our actions
when you treat yourself as if you matter
than you thrive.
When you treat those around you as if
they are inhabited by a spark of
divinity,
then your relationships stabilize and
grow simultaneously.
When we produce societies predicated on
the great idea of the inherent value of
each individual from st to criminal than
men become free and productive and
capable of living the meaningful lives
that lended dignity to the tragedy of
their limited existences and when we
fail to do so than our society's
degenerate,
into the tyrannical and murderous tribal
structures that seem to exist as the
only certainly manifest alternative is
this not all indicative of the existence
of some profound truth.
Obviously we are constrained and
severely so by the manner of our
corporeal being.
We're subject to deterministic rules in
a seriously profound manner.
We do not have the power to shape things
in any old way whatsoever at any time or
place,
but we can certainly and demonstrably
and apparently willfully advance in the
direction of our imagination and in
quite a staggering and compelling
manner.
Is this not indicative of who we
genuinely are?
Is this not as perhaps the primal
existential truth?
We are in danger in the west of
abandoning our culture of leaving our
great foundational stories to die on the
altar of our inquisitiveness,
cynicism,
carelessness of degenerating into
nihilism or returning in a reactionary
manner to an archaic and destructive
tribalism of the right or the left.
It matters not these twin dread paths
will not lead us to where we would want
to be if we decided to be conscious and
careful.
Such abandonment will weaken us fatally
as individuals.
It will lay us open to possession by all
manner of demonic conceptual
alternatives.
It will make us vulnerable to our
enemies within and without.
It is psychologically true that each of
us should open ourselves up to the
tragedy of being.
It is psychologically true that we
should pick up our tragic burdens and
crosses,
die continually and renew our souls
continually.
It may be more than psychologically true
as well.
It may be a truth of cosmic
significance.
That is the death and resurrection
celebrated by Easter and it is time for
us to wake up,
become conscious and recognize it as
such.
It is not possible to encapsulate within
any finite written account the total
import of the idea of Christ's death and
rebirth,
the impossible claim of the bodily
resurrection of one man conjoined with
the notion that this event was both of
world redeeming and cosmic significance
simply cannot be understood once and for
all within any singular frame of
interpretation,
even for die hard atheists have the
scientific type.
Think Richard Dawkins and Sam Harris.
A great mystery remains.
Why has this strange and thoroughly
implausible story exercise such immense
impact?
It is because each life is a tragedy
tainted by malevolence.
It is because life is suffering as we
all are.
Each of us vulnerable and ignorant made
all too frequently bitter,
resentful and angry because of just that
and more than willing to make things
worse in that anger,
but we all admire courage and the
willingness to abide by the truth.
No matter how terrible in the face of
that suffering,
we all recognize in such courage and
truth,
at least by our admiration of it,
an antidote to the catastrophe of life.
We all know that in the absence of such
courage and truth,
mirror catastrophe degenerates all too
frequently into hell.
Imagine that acceptance of vulnerability
in ignorance is the precondition for
growth.
Imagine that confrontation with the
terrible unknown with it's paralyzing
manifestations of tragedy and
malevolence is necessary to catalyze
both wisdom and maturity.
Imagine finally that human consciousness
plays some central and as of yet poorly
understood role in the reality of the
cosmos,
at least as necessary.
Observer.
Imagine all of that.
Then ask yourself,
what is the absolute hypothetical limit
of human attainment with vulnerability
and ignorance are fully and completely
accepted.
When the unknown is squarely confronted
and when consciousness is given,
it's due as the very center of the
world.
That's Christ's acceptance of the
crucifix.
That's his willingness to be betrayed,
subject to the evil of his closest
companions and the state and his embrace
of brokenness and death.
It is pure truth that even a small
leaving of humility and courage in
genders,
resilience,
progress and growth,
it is pure truth.
That resentful rejection of the price of
finite being multiplies suffering
endlessly and unnecessarily.
What is the ultimate expression of those
truths taken to their final conclusion?
Who is to say who we are and what we
might be capable of achieving if we
develop the courage to accept our
terrible fates,
live in truth and stumble uphill?
This is the question posed by
Christianity and its very essence would
you put everything you have and
everything you are on the line so that
you could learn to conduct yourself in
the best possible manner?
Would you be willing to allow who you
might be to continually and painfully
triumph over who you currently are in
the most ancient religious language?
Would you sacrifice what you love most
to God to find out who and what you are?
We are in the final analysis,
neither structured nor chaos.
Each of us is instead best understood as
a process,
as a living dynamic process,
as the very process by which what we
know,
what we know so insufficiently is
transformed into what could yet be.
That is the process by which our
continued forward.
Movement through life is constantly and
inevitably dependent.
To understand that and to welcome it.
That is voluntary.
Acceptance of the necessity of eternal
transformation as an alternative to
nihilistic despair or desperate and
fatal identification with the state.
This is the idea enacted during the
ceremony of the Christian Eucharist.
Incorporation of the body of Christ is
the symbolic transformation of the
participant,
not into a believer of a set of fact,
religious,
though those facts may appear,
but into the act of imitator of Christ
into the person willing to undergo
whatever death is necessary to bring
about the next and better state of being
into the person,
willing to embrace his or her
confrontation with the tragedy and
malevolence of life.
To learn from that process of embrace
and to move one step closer in
consequence to the eternally receding
city of God.
The idea of the dying and resurrected
God is one of the oldest ideas of
mankind,
widespread and exceptionally variant in
its forms.
It forms part of the set of
presuppositions that underlie the most
ancient shamonic rituals carried over
perhaps from the stone age itself.
It is echoed in the foundational stories
of ancient Mesopotamia,
Egypt and Greece.
It manifests itself in allegorical forms
in the figure of the Phoenix,
for example,
which emulates itself,
regains its youthful form and rises in
triumph from the ashes.
It recurs repeatedly in the tropes of
popular culture as well,
bringing even those entirely devoid of
religious education under the spell,
Marvel's iconic ironman plummets like
icarus from sky to ground.
After saving the world from demonic
serpentine other world forces and then
arises from his death,
the child wizard,
Harry Potter must ultimately die and be
reborn to defeat voldemort,
a very thinly disguised Satan.
All of that creative variation on a
theme speaks of a deep ineradicable and
eternally re-emergent psychological
reality.
We all see this in our day to day lives
and we all know it because we see it.
A small failure,
a small disappointment,
frustration or disenchantment and
genders within us,
a small death,
a small descent into the underworld,
a small requirement for rebirth.
A large failure produces a
proportionately large catastrophe and
transformation.
When you are compelled to talk to
someone because you faced divorce or the
failure of a treasured ambition or the
illness or death of someone close,
you are walking yourself through the
eternal narrative stability,
crisis,
death,
transformation,
rebirth.
That's the story of our lives.
That's the fall and the reestablishment
of paradise.
The idea that the savior is the figure
who dies and resurrect is a
representation in dramatic or narrative
form of the brute fact that
psychological progress,
indeed learning itself requires
continual death and rebirth of lesser
and greater magnitude.
If you are engaged in this serious
interpersonal conflict or argument or
facing a true crisis in your life,
the new information confronting you
cannot be incorporated without the old
so painful demise of your previous
conceptions and all of the resistance
comprehension of that pain necessarily
entails.
That's part and parcel of the process so
famously described as assimilation and
accommodation by the great developmental
psychologists jumped piaget,
we each confront the world with a set of
preconceptual patients whose function is
Cymbalta obviously to delimit and render
pragmatic are very perceptions,
thoughts,
and actions.
In the absence of this eight priority,
we simply cannot function nonetheless.
It is still insufficient.
No one ever knows enough and what we
each do not yet know will at some moment
of crisis become a vital importance when
something new and like confronts us and
shakes us to our core.
What is old and anachronistic within
must therefore emulate itself and die.
It is very rare indeed to learn
something profound without suffering the
terrible pain of dashed dreams and the
soul shaking terror of uncertainty and
doubt.
This means that none of us should
identify in the most fundamental sense
with what we currently know and presume
means as well,
that we should all come to understand
that so that we do not remain confused
about who we are.
This means that it is never sufficient
to be conservative or to identify with
the past or to become ideologically or
dogmatically committed or to remain
stubbornly anachronistic and unchanged.
The environment transforms headlong
around us and we all must run as fast as
we can as Ellis as red queen,
well new just to stay in the same place.
It is not sufficient either to abandon
tradition and structure entirely in a
headlong and irresponsible rush towards
the anomalous and revolutionary
structure is insufficient,
but it is still necessary and the
ethical requirement for respecting and
maintaining it is still a paramount
import.
We each must as well.
Similarly,
avoid falling prey to the temptation of
identifying with the chaotic,
depressing,
anxiety ridden and nihilism inducing
state of affairs in gendered by the
terrible confrontation with the
genuinely unknown,
even when thrust into the underworld by
the dread events of our life,
we must not characterize ourselves as
permanent inhabitants of that dark and
dread place,
lest we lose hope,
despair,
and seek revenge to progress.
Psychologically,
you must let go sacrifice time and again
in the face of success of obstacles,
you must abandon those things.
That and often those people who are
impeding your progress,
despite the fact that you may have held
them very close to your heart when
you're wrong,
when you've missed the mark,
when you've sinned,
because that is the meaning of sin.
You must let the part of you that is
wrong and aiming improperly die.
Then you must allow the new spirit
manifesting itself within two spring to
life,
that new spirit,
that's the terrible information
contained in whatever error you
committed in living conjunction with the
now transformed structures you
originally employed to frame the
situation that new spirit,
it's a manifestation as well,
and in other words,
have the potential within you that had
not yet been called forth by the
previous travails of your life.
Christ is symbolically the way and the
truth of life and no one comes to the
father except through him embracing the
process of voluntary death and rebirth
that is identical with psychological
development means determining to move
forward and upward despite the horrors
of life.
It means as well,
symbolically speaking,
rejuvenating the dead father or rescuing
him from stagnation and deterioration in
the eternal underworld.
Forthright individual confrontation with
the unknown,
renews the Individual,
but also catalyze this cultural
revitalization.
This is the essence of Christian ritual
and belief articulated as a
psychological principle.
We must identify with that part of
ourselves that is always stretching
beyond what we currently know and has
the faith to let go of old certainties
so that new patterns of being can be
brought into place.
It is through identification with the
process symbolized by Easter,
that we are each redeemed and our
culture revivified and salvaged.
We are all the slaves of Pharisees and
lawyers,
have those who place dogma above spirit,
at the cost of spirit.
We're all subject to be trail by
ourselves and by all those who surround
us.
We're all facing extinction in the most
torturous of manners,
but there is a spirit within us with
sufficient courage to confront the true
horrors of existence forthrightly to
allow the transformation,
even death that's such confrontation.
Catalyze this to occur and to leap
forward,
renewed.
How is it that life might prevail in the
face of death and hell with arms open
embracing its fate.
We are all fallen creatures and we all
know it.
We are all separated from what should be
and thrown into the world of death and
despair.
We're all brutally crucified on the
cross.
That is the reality of life itself.
To rebel against that fate merely
worsens it transforming what could be
mirrored tragedy into something
indistinguishable from hell to argue
bitterly and despair around the deathbed
of a loved one.
To take a single example is to turn all
the pain of death and loss into
something far worse.
To accept instead is that simultaneously
to transcend it?
Certainly courage and truth and perhaps
even love,
and these three forces are something to
behold.
Are they more powerful than despair and
the desire for vengeance?
That is the Christian suggestion and the
Christian command to act out the
proposition that courage and truth and
love are more powerful than death and
despair and to accept what transpires as
a consequence.
That is Easter and the death and
resurrection of Christ.
We forget or remain blind to such things
at our great peril.