Congratulations.
Yes.
Do you when?
Well,
to all of us,
dear view is a visual politic.
It may have gone unnoticed,
but this is a historical events.
This not for the first time in the
entire history of humanity.
We live in a world where poverty no
longer effect.
Most of the population surprised
well,
you shouldn't be here or visual politic.
We've already told you that this was
about to happen.
Folks today,
let's forget all about the apocalyptic
perspectives that we've covered for so
many years about the world we live in.
The truth is that today on our planet's
most of the population either belongs to
the middle class or do the wealthiest
classes.
Yes.
In other words,
as you can see,
poverty is now not such a looming issue
that is still a lot of poverty,
but the truth is that we've never before
known a world where poverty didn't
affect most of the population and don't
tell me that that's not great news,
but just hold on a second because some
of you might be asking some questions in
your mind right now.
Like for example,
well,
what on earth are you talking about,
Simon?
What do you mean exactly?
If that's the case,
why is everyone so pessimistic?
Or maybe you're even asking,
is all of this sustainable?
Can the environments with the such a
heavy burden?
Oh,
we have perhaps on the threshold of the
world's very destruction.
Well,
we're going to explore all of those
questions in today's video.
So that's up.
The general impression of most people
you can't deny it is that we live in a
world full of misery of inequality or
injustice and yes,
all of that does exist,
but fortunately it's becoming less
frequent.
Just one area or with just one plane.
Monday,
a battery fire in an auxiliary power
unit in the belly of the plane.
Right now it's rated as very unhealthy
by the US embassy monitoring site.
Extraordinary snake of trash.
I mean literally it rolls around the
hillside,
so yeah,
every time you turn on the TV or your
visit a news website,
you'll find catastrophes of all sorts of
kinds.
Unfortunately,
we don't usually find much good news
even though this is the kind that is
generally much more
awesome.
You'll see,
according to the Brookings Institute in
the world,
datalabs estimates,
we hit an extraordinary milestone this
past September of 2018 for the first
time in the history of mankind to most
people who live in the world are no
longer poor.
We're talking about more than 50 percent
of the world's population.
Approximately three point 8 billion
people who belong to a middle class or
wealthy homes.
In fact,
this is the rough distribution of the
world's population today,
so
bounce.
Now,
some of you might be wondering,
well,
what exactly do you mean by middle class
time?
Well,
fundamentally this is people with enough
purchasing power.
Do you allow them to live comfortably?
That is they can buy washing machines
and refrigerators,
they can go to restaurants and they can
go on vacation.
They can endure some unexpected
instability such as an illness or a
period of unemployment without falling
back into
awesome.
To be more specific for this particular
studies offers the households that have
a consumption capacity of more than $11
per day per person that just did for the
price level are part of the middle
class.
Yes.
That is not all the best is yet to come.
That allow me to explain.
As you know,
there's still a lot of poverty in the
world.
No less than 650 million people live in
extreme poverty.
They aren't even guaranteed the most
basic things like food and of course 650
million people is far too.
The good news is that changes are
happening so quickly that in the next
few decades this issue may have
disappeared entirely,
so now you might be wondering,
well,
how fast are we really talking about
here?
Well,
to give you an idea of how fast things
are changing,
check out these figures
in all wells for every second that
passes,
one person escapes extreme poverty every
single second.
It is exactly this lightening fast rate
that has caused the population living in
conditions of extreme poverty to fall by
75 percent from 1990 to 2015,
but even with this news,
without a doubt,
what's most surprising is what's
happening with the middle class in that
same period of time that is every single
second,
approximately five people leave poverty
behind and join the middle class.
Five people per seconds.
That folks means that if this rate
continues in just 12 years,
by the year 20,
30,
the middleclass,
who would make up the vast majority of
the world's popular
good
use.
Wouldn't you agree?
The middle class would mean a world with
fewer poor people with a greater
commitment to academic studies and
knowledge with a greater tendency to set
up companies and also a population
that's more demanding towards
politicians.
Among other things.
This is because the middle class is a
proprietary class.
People in the middle of class,
they have houses,
they have savings businesses,
and that of course it leads them to be
more committed to stability and to be
more demanding.
Not only that,
as we've told you many times,
this huge growth means another thing,
hundreds of thousands of opportunities
for enterprise.
Now,
hold on just a moment and here's the
question that many of you may be asking
yourselves and we know you're asking it
because we see asking in the comments
and that is,
can our weld support so many consuming
such a large amount of stuff?
Aren't we really sowing the seeds of our
destruction?
Well,
let's see a path to the abyss.
Climate Change,
mass extinction,
water pollution.
Folks,
I don't even have to say,
uh,
we are facing many challenges.
In fact,
if we take a look at the news,
we could get the impression that we're
heading full speed towards some sort of
precipice and of course with so many
people consuming more and more
resources,
it's normal for our lives to be pervaded
by the question of what's going to
happen to the planet.
But what if it wasn't exactly like that?
What if after a certain level,
the relationship between the
environments and wealth actually became
positive?
Well,
folks,
that's the direction that things are
actually moving.
See,
when we talk about development and
economic growth and consumption to
issues logically concern us a lot.
One is pollution and damage to the
environment,
and the second is whether or not there's
going to be enough resources for
everyone.
So let's start with the first one first.
Is it possible that things aren't going
to go down such a bad path?
Let's take a look.
For example,
what happens in recent years in the
largest economies on the planet,
so that is the United States,
the European Union,
China and Japan.
Yeah.
Nineteen,
63.
Nineteen states issued zero point nine,
four kilograms of co two for every
dollar of production in 2014.
This value was just point three four,
which is 64 percent less for,
it's called the European Union reduced
co two emissions per dollar of
production by 54 percent between 1991
and 2014.
And the same is true of Japan,
even China or infamous China,
the country that used coal for
everything has reduced its relative co
two emissions by 75 percent over the
past four decades.
That is to say technological
developments.
And New environments or concerns are
helping the world produce more policing.
Last,
yeah.
You heard the absolutely right.
Improved technology and increasing
concern for the environments are
managing to slow down and even reverse
the damage to our planet's.
Take a look at the United States,
Dannon,
again,
environmental improvements once deemed
impossible have taken place since 1970
when the environmental protection agency
was established.
United States has slashed.
It's a missions have five air pollutants
by almost two thirds over the same
period.
The population grew by more than 40
percent and those people drove twice as
many miles and became two and a half
times Richard Steven pinker.
The truth,
folks is that it's becoming increasingly
clear that the relationship between the
environments and wealth has an inverted
u shape.
That is to say after a determined level
of wealth,
societies begin to worry more about the
environments.
They begin to take measures to take care
of it,
and they begin to develop and use clean
technologies.
Renewable energies will dominate the
future German electricity sector thanks
to the impulse of offshore wind and
geothermal.
For example,
this is what the environmental
performance index an index constructed
from metrics that measure the quality of
our water forest and natural inhabitants
indicates out of the 180 countries that
make up the index,
but to have improved in the last decade.
On the other hand,
the index shows that the richer a
country is on average,
the cleaner it's environments becomes.
There's more environmental awareness and
so it gets better results.
Sure.
I mean,
if we think about it,
it's really quite logical.
Richer countries can allocate more
resources towards technological
developments and protecting natural
areas.
In fact,
since 1990,
as the world has become richer and
richer,
protected areas have almost doubled.
Today,
more than 15 percent of the surface of
the planet is protected,
and not only that,
the forestation,
one of the great ecological threats is
undergoing a clear decline deforestation
for the world's largest tropical forest.
The Amazon peaked in 1995 and from 2004
to 2013,
the rate fell by four fifths.
Steven pinker,
when the laundry middle class will mean
more resources to care for the
environment,
more people developing cleaner
technologies and a greater level of
environmental awareness.
Now,
don't get me wrong,
there are many challenges ahead,
but the trend isn't nearly bad as often
portrayed,
but we don't really need to take our
foot off the gas.
We do need to promote cleaner production
methods and technologies,
but we're not in an apocalyptic or
irreversible situation.
Bands,
of course,
the empirical evidence tells us that the
best way to overcome these challenges is
with more investments ends with richer
and better formed societies.
Regarding the second question as to
whether natural resources will be
exhausted on Austin,
I think we can rest assured that they
won't be not so many because there are
many resources,
but above all,
because human activity aims to seek
better ways of production,
including recycling the development of
new technologies that allow for the
exploitation of new resources for the
managed to do more.
With
all of these reasons,
and don't worry,
we're going to talk much more about this
topic in the future.
I think we have to be more than
satisfied that for the first time in the
history of humanity,
our average condition isn't poverty or
hunger.
Yes,
humanity is managing to defeat poverty,
and so I really hope you enjoyed that
video.
If you did,
please do hit that like button.
Don't forget to subscribe for brand new
videos.
Also,
don't forget to check it off.
Friends at the reconsider media
podcasts,
they provided the vocals in this episode
that we're not mine.
Also,
this channel's made possible because of
patron ends,
our patrons on that platform.
Please consider joining them and
supporting our mission of providing
independent political coverage,
and as always,
I'll see you in the next
problems aren't in just one area or with
just one plane right now.
It's rated as very unhealthy by the US
embassy monitoring sites.
Extraordinary snake of trash.
I mean literally it rolls around.