Don't want us to become something like
the Asian version of Asterix and Obelix
is irreducible village,
a small enclave surrounded by a great
empire that wants to engulf.
It ends as with the small Gaelic
village.
The citizens of Taiwan also have their
own magic potion to defend themselves
against their enemies.
Of course,
in this case,
we aren't talking about potions made by
a druid.
We're talking about the power of the
United States of America.
Well,
the United States,
and also reasonably well something else
folks.
Taiwan has a new ally,
a new secret advantage that is already
fueling Beijing's wrath,
so listen up.
Beijing's rat one is facing enormous
pressure from mainland China,
which as you know,
planes the island as part of its
territory,
and we're not talking about the usual
international politics tug of war where
you know the usual.
You get to that.
Can you take it?
I get angry,
I threaten you.
Then we ultimately let it be known.
That is not the situation here at all.
Beijing,
they've actually even set a deadline.
The Chinese government has made it clear
time and time again that it's ready to
do what it takes,
and the fourth year,
20,
49 for the centennial of the People's
Republic of China,
Taiwan will have to rejoin mainland
China.
Yeah.
Course.
This leads to a problem maddens and not
exactly a small one that I went is
they're not really in favor of it.
In fact,
they want nothing to do with it.
as we mentioned here on visual politic
in 2016,
the Democratic Progressive Party of
sight in Wang who by the way,
it was one of our 2017 are award winning
leaders of the year and there's
something of an independent games at
power in Taiwan.
All the power,
both of Congress and the presidency.
And since then,
let's just say Beijing hasn't taken it
very well.
Uh,
in fact,
that wouldn't be accurate.
They took it horrible.
Tying Wang became president practically
from the very first minute Beijing's
pressures against the island have
multiplied.
And in recent months it's already
reached politically obsessive levels.
They've cut diplomatic ties,
try to punish Taiwan economically and
have implemented huge military exercises
all around the island.
That's not all Tszujing things.
Government is also using all leds means
to,
uh,
raise Taiwan's name and identity from
the map.
For example,
when we published our first video about
Taiwan,
20 countries formally recognize the
islands government in Taipei is China's
legitimate government.
Yes,
as we've covered before,
Taiwan has never declared its
independence,
but for years it's claimed it's China's
legitimate government.
And of course diplomatically our country
can only have one recognize government.
Well,
Beijing has multiplied its diplomatic
agenda to end the situation today,
just a year later.
Only 17 countries consider it so,
and almost all of them are tiny,
but that's not all.
In fact,
given the circumstances,
Beijing's move would be understandable.
Something like you're,
I'm the legitimate government of China,
but this is no longer a question of
who's the legitimate governments,
but simply the Beijing has said both
actively and passively that it will
never allow Taiwan to become
independent.
And one way to prevent that is precisely
by trying to erase all traces of the
islands.
National identity tried essentially he
wants people to think Taiwan wants that
car.
Brands you see in order to pull this
off,
Beijing is blocking the presence of
Taiwanese representatives and even it's
journalists from all of the
international bodies that it can,
such as the World Health Organization,
it's finding companies that sell
products in China with the mainland
Taiwan label.
This is something that has happened to
the Japanese Jane Muji.
Another case we know about is that of
the gap clothing Shane,
which had to apologize for selling tee
shirts in North America that didn't
include Taiwan as part of China.
Even say when he's music groups like the
Indie punk band,
fire axe.
So you don't support the reunification
are disappearing from Chinese streaming
music services.
And how about one more example?
Well,
due to Beijing's threats,
airlines from all over the world and no
longer using the islands name.
Yep.
You're really did hear that,
right?
Even American companies aren't using
Taiwan's name anymore.
I mean,
yes,
you can absolutely book a ticket from
New York to Taipei,
but don't ask which country you're going
to.
Although yes,
unlike other international companies
such as British Airways or Lufthansa or
who are already selling tickets to
Taiwan,
this part of China,
American companies have simply resorted
to the ghost country trek.
The ghost country trick is them just
selling tickets to Taipei and when
anyone asks,
it's just a response of who cares.
We can't blame them.
The trainees aviation market is simply
too big and many companies have direct
interests in that country.
Trainers goal regarding Taiwan has never
changed.
That goal is just swallow up.
Taiwan,
sovereignty,
exterminate Taiwanese democracy,
and achieved ultimate unification Lee
tongue where Taiwan's first
democratically elected president to the
New York Times without getting any
further.
American Airlines is a shareholder of
China,
Southern Airlines and Delta on the other
hands of China,
Eastern Airlines.
However,
just a moment here because it's not all
bad news for Taiwan along with the US is
support.
The island has gains and other powerful
ally,
or you could say hi.
One is developing its own magic potion
that no,
I'm not talking about weapons.
Listen Up Mecca
folks.
Taiwan has been chosen as the first
Asian host of the Oslo Freedom Forum,
like a Congress and international
meeting on human rights,
but some of you might be wondering a
congress,
I mean is that rarely so important while
devalue it.
In fact,
it is not so much for the congress,
but ultimately what it means.
Even though
global democracy has experienced a
general trend of backsliding in the past
few years,
Taiwan's democracy has persisted and
continues to thrive.
Taiwan can continue to serve as an
inspiration to Democrats in Asia,
including those in China.
Ketty Jen,
vice president of the Taiwan Foundation
for democracy.
You see,
for decades,
Hong Kong was the great bastion of
freedom of expression in this area of
the world.
So if international media and human
rights organizations establish their
headquarters there,
and not only that,
Hong Kong mostly became a refuge for
many political exiles.
Like for example,
the student leaders who lead the
Tiananmen Square protest.
However,
in recent times as we've seen here on
visual politic,
things have changed and Beijing has
tightened its grip on Hong Kong's
politics.
Kong was originally the first choice for
the Asia Bureau,
but today China doesn't just suppress
its own people.
It is now increasingly exporting that
suppression to Hong Kong.
Will Eric,
I see an emeritus member of Reporters
Without Borders and a student leader of
the 1989 tiananmen protests
boss.
As this change was taking place,
Taiwan consolidated itself as a vibrant
democracy and one of the freest places
in the region,
but that's precisely why it's replacing.
Hong Kong is the Mecca for freedom
activists and human rights in Asia.
This is even though Taiwan until 1987,
was under the control of an ironclad
dictatorship.
Now,
for example,
one of the human rights film festivals
that used to be held in Hong Kong has
been moved to Taiwan.
Lamb,
winky,
one of the Hong Kong book publishers who
was kidnapped by the Chinese government
two years ago has announced that he will
reopen his bookstore in Taiwan and
Reporters Without Borders announced in
2017 that it's first Asian office will
be in Tai Pei.
Freedom of expression is a big part of
Taiwanese culture.
Cedric the Taipei bureau director of
Reporters Without Borders.
These are just some examples of what it
was already becoming.
A generalized trends,
democracy,
political plurality,
freedom of expression,
human rights,
same sex marriage.
Taiwan is becoming a benchmark for all
of them and obviously this poses a huge
problem for China's interests.
Yeah,
for one,
the Taiwanese love freedom,
so of course they don't want anything to
do with being ruled again by Beijing and
for another while the Chinese government
attempts to erase,
to annihilate at the time when he's
identity throughout the wells,
the country has suddenly emerged as a
center of freedom with all the influence
that that entails.
Also,
it's much harder to consider attacking a
country that is famous for its
commitment to human rights.
International community simply would not
accept it,
and the truth is that this maybe
Taiwan's best move this one up,
the new move,
July 2018,
the second Apache helicopter squadron
made in Taiwan went into service.
It's part of what is strengthening the
partnership between Washington and
Taipei,
of which incidentally we're going to
speak about in a future video.
Among other things,
this includes a significant increase in
the sale of equipment and military
technology to the island.
One is buying helicopters,
tanks,
missiles,
anti aircraft systems,
and now even wants to develop its own
submarines.
However,
despite all of this,
it seems increasingly clear that
militarily,
it'll be difficult for Taiwan to stop
China.
The budget difference is simply
overwhelming.
China's military budget is between 15
and 20 times that of Taiwan and it
shows,
yes,
it's true nowadays there's the United
States umbrella,
but even that isn't enough to have the
guarantee that the international
community would act in their favor.
Taiwan needs to reinforce its influence
in the world,
especially if it wants to become an
independent country.
Now the question we need to ask
ourselves here is how on earth I think
going to be able to achieve this?
Well,
folks that may surprise you,
the military strategy,
while essential may not actually be the
most important thing here,
Taiwan has to gain influence and
prominence in the world while overcoming
the economic problems that we talked
about in a previous video.
To do so,
it can,
for example,
seek to attract students from all over
Asia and indeed the world by giving them
facilities,
promoting programs in English and
attracting first grade teachers.
That would mean gaining a lot of
influence and of course human capital.
Seconds,
Taiwan can set in motion and aggressive
policy to attract multinationals and to
get them to establish not only factories
here,
but above all research centers and
administrative headquarters.
They can do so by devoting special
attention to attracting content creation
companies,
media,
film studios,
Youtube as et Cetera,
et Cetera,
that
the government could seek to become a
logistics enclave,
for example,
by developing its app or capabilities
and thus becoming a large communication
sub for thick and attract more
professionals from the rest of Asia.
This would allow her to both face the
islands aging population problem and
also to strengthen its ties with the
workers,
places of origin and fifth,
it must continue to promote its role as
a center for human rights and freedom of
expression.
All right,
so maybe this plan is not as exciting as
just buying huge weapons,
but it would certainly be cheaper as
trying to compete with China only via
the military route seems complicated and
it would boost the island's economy as
well as give it a lot of influence
around the world given the
circumstances.
A university,
a film studio,
a hotel,
or the headquarters of a human rights or
multinational organization can be much
more important for the island survival
than for example,
a battleship.
This is not about giving some ultra
pacifist discourse or anything like
that.
It's just about pure pragmatism.
Okay.
If we're talking about guaranteeing
Taiwan's independence and freedom,
this is how to do it,
but now it's your turn.
Do you think the international community
should guarantee Taiwan security?
Well,
leave your answer in the comments as
well as in this survey and I really hope
you did enjoy this video.
Please do hit that like button if you
did and don't forget to subscribe.
We've got brand new videos every Monday
and Thursday.
They also do not forget to check out our
friends at the reconsider media podcast.
They provided the vocals in this episode
that we're not mine.
Also,
this channel is possible because of
patriots ends,
our patrons on the platform of Patriot
one final p,
and that would be,
please consider joining them and
supporting our mission of providing
independent political coverage.
And as always,
I'll see you in the next video.
Okay.