Unless you are watching this video from
Syria,
it's fair to say that no matter how bad
the situation in your country,
Venezuela is doing worse,
as of 2015,
they are experiencing more inflation
than any other country in the entire
world.
Furthermore,
their capital Caracas is currently
ranked as being the world's most violent
city,
beating out other famously violent
cities in both Mexico and it's okay.
Columbia,
something as simple as buying toilet
paper has also become a practically
impossible in Venezuela and scarcity has
become a norm in supermarkets.
Other products such as condoms have to
be bought and sold on the black market,
and all of this is happening in a
country with the world's largest oil
reserves.
In fact,
it wasn't so long ago,
the Venezuela was the richest country in
the whole of South America,
but today,
over half the population lives in
poverty.
So the big question is how did they ends
up there?
How did the government destroy the
economy in such a short amount of time?
Today we're going to tell you that
story.
Well,
the variant revolution,
the first character in our story is Hugo
Chavez.
The father of modern day Venezuela,
or should we say the Bolivarian Republic
of Venezuela.
He became presidents after a landslide
victory in 1999.
His campaign was based on the promise of
equality and poverty reduction,
a policy that he called 21st century
socialism.
One of his first policies was called the
system for the democratization of jobs.
This was meant to be implemented in the
PD Vsa,
the stage company that extracts
Venezuela's oil,
and don't forget now that we're talking
about a country that has a bigger oil
reserves than Saudi Arabia.
Yeah,
vsas payroll has more than doubled to a
hundred and 15,000
employees.
See,
Chavez took office in 1999 and that has
recent them since 2006 to 34 billion US
dollars.
This was pretty big news considering the
VSA is the largest company in South
America.
Nevertheless,
Venezuela kept producing the same number
of barrels per year.
This means that the staff increase had
nothing to do with corporate reasons,
but rather political ones.
In fact,
this job or democratization,
it was a way to employ all of the
unemployed Venezuelans.
The same thing happens in the government
during the Chavez administration,
public spending,
this
men's,
more government workers and more social
programs have an ever before.
However,
none of this was a problem.
As long as the oil exports kept paying
the bills.
In fact,
Chavez cut poverty in half despite being
an oil rich country.
Before Chavez.
Sixty percent of the population lived in
poverty.
Ten years after Chavez,
only 30 percent did display ship as his
rhetoric that capitalist countries were
trying to destroy the revolution,
no one would reject Venezuela's oil.
Even Nicolas Sarcozi,
Francis Conservative presidents over the
volume was complimenting Venezuela's
level.
It's with their strong turnout.
The shows,
once again,
the vitality of democracy in Venezuela.
So all of these policies we must add the
famous know I've got this literally
means expropriate.
This expropriation being the taking away
of private property from its owner.
Chavez was no fan of private businesses
and it was not uncommon for him to visit
a city and go around declaring that
various businesses being nationalized.
This would include all sorts of
businesses,
including things like small shops.
All of this ended up with Venezuela
having an economy if it was fully
dependent on its oil buying 2012 brands
barrels when 95 percent of Venezuela's
exports.
We should also note here that PD and
higher costs than any other oil company,
and this was largely because of the
staff increases.
Nonetheless,
as long as the oil price remains high
enough to cover the production costs,
it's Venezuela kept making oil and
everyone was happy.
Well,
just hold on a minute because this is
where things turn sour.
In 2014 oil prices fell in Venezuela was
the first country to feel the effects of
this.
For their profit per barrel shrank and
more and more every single day.
The
last now by that time the oil crisis
started.
Hugo Chavez had already passed away and
his successor was a guy named Nicolas
Maduro.
I always look at me funny.
Then flew over my head and I could feel
the spirit of Chavez in the field.
No,
this is not a joke,
nor is it a quote taken out of context.
Maduro found himself the head of the
country that wasn't making enough money
from.
It's only export and Maduro had wages to
pay.
Then on top of all this,
we have the famous now because of all
that expropriating that was going on,
we've been left with a Venezuela that
has no private companies,
so even if he decided to raise taxes,
there's no one left the pavement,
and this is when Missouri made the most
irresponsible decision that any
political leader can make.
He decided to print money having
devalued the Venezuelan currency,
the believer inflation skyrocketed.
Here's an example of how bad this was.
Imagine you're sitting in a bar and
crackers in July of 2016,
met emily called steel around 50 bullet
boss.
Then you go back to the same bar in
Caracas in September,
and that same beer would cost you $100
boulevards.
This has been happening in Venezuela
consistently for the last three years.
This had the effect of destroying all of
the poverty reduction measures that
Chavez had implemented.
Oh,
and believe me,
it gets worse from here.
Just when things were looking really
terrible,
but decided to demonstrate just how much
worse they can get.
Youtube to finish with the price
increases will be the creation of the
maximum sales brides.
Neil Matsumoto.
According to Missouri,
the hyperinflation was caused by those
evil capitalists.
He wanted to destroy Venezuela.
So the logical solution of course was
the fight them.
So you're probably wondering right now
what exactly the outcome of all of this
is.
Well,
this time,
let's imagine that you own butcher shop
in the beautiful city of Maricado.
You believe meat from a Colombian farmer
and you pay with US dollars.
For example,
let's say the pounds of beef costs you
$10 for Venezuelan central bank has an
official exchange rate of 10 boulevard
store one US dollar,
but no one's going to sell you dollars
at that price because the market price
is way higher.
This means that if he wants to buy beef
from your Colombian producer,
you're going to have to pay the price
set by the market.
This is the equivalent of 10,000
Bolivares per 10,
right?
It's fine,
but then you go back to your shop and
you want to sell this pounds of beef
that you bought,
but then he find out that the government
has set a maximum sale price of a
thousand boulevards,
which is 10 times less than what you
paid,
so now you've got two options.
You can close up your shop or to sell
your meat on the black market.
Now some of you might be wondering,
why do they have to buy foreign name?
Why can't they just buy meat that was
made inside Venezuela?
The answer is that whatever product you
buy it,
it's going to require something that is
made outside of the country that you
bought the product in.
For example,
if you want to grow weeds,
you're going to need a tractor which is
manufactured somewhere else and you
might find that even the seeds or the
fertilizer also need in a different
country one way or another.
There is no country on earth that is
capable of producing all that they
consume,
not even the United States.
Oh,
and don't forget now that Venezuela
based their entire economy on the export
of oil,
and so dave still,
that's not going so well.
Venezuelan oil has become so expensive
that they'd rather buy it from external
sources than even use their own
be.
The BSA has lounge,
one of it's largest oil tenders ever
seeking to buy some 8 million barrels of
us or Nigerian light crude for delivery
from April through June.
As I mentioned previously,
Venezuelan oil is really expensive to
produce and it turns out that they've
just rolled the blind from other
countries that use their own oil.
Meanwhile,
shops cannot import goods.
This is leading to a scarcity of toilet
paper and there's even lead to
situations where people have stabbed
each other over a small piece of.
Yeah,
so now that we've given you the rundown
on Venezuela,
we'd love to know what you think.
Do you think Madeira,
we'll be able to pull this country out
of collapse.
Do you see there's an alternative for
him to pursue?
We'd love to know your opinion.
Just let us know in the comments below
and do not forget that we applied brand
new videos every Monday and Thursday,
and if you want to get notified about
those,
please do subscribe to this channel.
Also,
if you enjoyed this video,
please do hit that thumbs up button
below and I'll see you next.