Did you know that the United States is
the largest energy power on the
planet's?
Yep.
That's absolutely right.
The United States has taken the position
as the world's largest fossil fuel
producer.
No other country,
not even Russia or Saudi Arabia.
Even come close to this North American
giants.
The golden era of American energy is now
underway.
This energy revolution is having
important consequences and it's changing
politics in the USA and it's also the
topic that we're addressing in this
visual politic video.
Just eight years ago,
the supply of petrol and natural gas was
one of the biggest concerns that the USA
had about their future.
And this wasn't a particularly new
concern.
The country had been dependent on
foreign petrol and gas for decades.
The other thing is that we have only
leased out and began to explore two
percent of our outer continental shelf
for oil where it is believed by everyone
familiar with that few will and that
source of energy,
that there are vast supplies you have to
be found.
Uh,
secondly,
we need an active exploration program in
market.
They only way to become less dependent
on foreign sources of crude oil is to
explore at home.
I think we can easily within seven,
eight,
10 years if we put our minds to it,
we can eliminate our dependence on the
places in the world that our national
security,
if we don't achieve our independence
from the most important thing we can do
is to make sure we control our own
energy.
So here's what I've done since I've been
president.
We have increased oil production to the
highest levels in 16 years.
At the time it was said that the
national security over the US,
they rely on being able to ensure the
supply of natural gas and petrol to the
industry and economy.
That we're so dependent upon it and this
well,
it wasn't really easy to do at that
time.
It's possible you might remember this.
The world's seem to be facing an
imminent decline in fossil fuels.
It really did seem as if we were about
to run out of them.
Let's have a quick look at the situation
in the USAID.
Back at that time
from the early seventies,
the petro reserves in the United States
were declining year after year
production had dropped by about 50
percent and even the production of
natural gas was starting to decline.
In other words,
the United States was quickly running
out of energy resources and they were at
risk of having to rely on suppliers
well,
when it's exactly trustworthy in the
opinion of those responsible for
national security.
We are of course talking about countries
like Saudi Arabia,
Russia and Nigeria.
However things they've changed a lot
since then and as sometimes happens,
the predictions were wrong and creamed
storage tanks,
the world all continue,
Phil.
Well,
what exactly is happening?
let's take a closer look at that.
Petrol power returns.
United States has gone through an
important energy revolution.
In the last few years.
Oil production has almost doubled,
and the reserves which can be exploited
guarantee that supply for many years to
come.
Look at this chart that we've taken from
the Wall Street Journal.
It shows the increase of oil production
in the USA since 2011.
You can probably guess the fact that the
USA has almost doubled.
It's all production is closely related
to the huge drops in oil prices since
2004,
not just the petrol.
Something really similar that has
happened with natural gas as well.
Today.
The US is the world's largest producer
of both of these resources and as you
can imagine,
this as consequences on multiple fronts,
but what has happened so that this boom
could take place.
As many of you know,
it is all due to a technological
revolution known as fracking.
Well,
it's actually nothing new.
We've known about it for decades,
but until recently it wasn't really
economically viable.
And look,
before we get into this topic any
further,
we need to point out that fracking.
It's a pretty controversial topic and
for now it's only used to produce petrol
on a large scale in four countries,
the US,
Canada,
Russia,
and Argentina.
At the end of this video and in the
description below,
we're actually going to leave a link to
something that will explain how this
process works in its defense,
would also like to point out that it is
a pretty new technique and as this
technique is being used and developed,
its actual impact is being reduced
anyway.
The safety and that sort of thing is
actually a discussion for another video
because in this video we're going to
focus on both the economic and the
political consequences of fracking
feeding the economic engine.
Civil oil imports to the U.
S had been reduced significantly in the
United States.
Sanders laws of supply and demand
applying all of this additional petrol
has made the prices drop.
This means the lesser amounts of petrol
that the country is still important,
but it's also significantly the price of
gas slash petrol at the pump to faults,
so much so that it's actually estimated
that American consumers are saving about
a $150,000,000,000 every year.
This is money that is then used for
purchasing other products or setting up
businesses or just putting it into a
savings accounts,
but hold on a minute because this is not
the end of today's story.
Oh,
not even close,
cheaper petrol and gas also benefits
industry and not just those industries
that use this type of energy,
but also industry that uses it as their
raw material.
Of course
now talking about the petro chemical
industry,
the one that produces plastic and pvc,
the culmination of a large quantity of
petrol available,
the certainty of supply and low prices
are triggering an industrial boom in the
petro chemical sector and it's really
important to look at these numbers
closely because that absolutely huge
petrochemical sector is developing
projects valued at $185 billion dollars
just in the United States.
20 16.
These sorts of projects.
We're 50 percent of the entire national
industrial investment.
It's expected that these investments
will turn the United States into a great
plastic export
just so I can get an idea.
They expect that in just a few years,
the net exports of petrol based products
like plastics and also fertilizes and
solvents will exceed $110,000,000,000 a
year.
This is almost as much as all of the
petrol,
Saudi Arabia exports.
You've got to pinch yourself sometimes
and say,
this is the envy of the world.
Neal Chapman,
president of the chemical division at
Exxonmobil.
It's not your business will certainly
help us reduce that trade deficits,
a deficit that trump is always
complaining about.
Let's wait a second because,
well,
there's yet more the supply of petrol.
It's something no longer a priority or a
concern for the countries and national
security.
In December 2015 us Congress moved the
prohibition on exports of natural gas
and petrol.
Now
the US is about to become a net exporter
of natural gas and it is calculated that
the US will sell an average of 1 million
petrol barrels per day in 2017.
US oil exports double reshaping vast
global markets.
Well,
the United States still important forum
petrol,
but much less than it used to because
countries like to have energy security
by diversifying their sources.
Many countries are willing to pay a
premium for this US supply and you can
be sure that the companies in the US on
taking advantage of that natural gas
where this change has been the greatest
and so recently the transport of gas was
difficult and huge gas pipelines when
needed,
but now thanks to the new technology of
liquefied natural gas,
it can easily be transported like petrol
in giant
tankers.
The gas supplied this way is almost half
of the world's supply and here American
companies are.
The superstars is now projected to be
one of the top three natural gas
exporters in the world by 20,
20 less importance.
Gas Exports,
a revival of the industrial sector.
It all looks like rather bad timing for
trump's protectionism.
Well,
hold on just a minute because this
energy revolution,
it also has political consequences
diplomatically.
Most of all,
to understand the US international
politics.
If we don't consider the impacts of this
energy revolution,
let me explain.
I'll console now.
The supply of petrol was a priority for
national security.
The Middle East and oil and gas
producing countries had an important
role in the American diplomatic agenda.
Yeah,
petrol scheme of the United States.
This caused priorities to change.
For example,
a new focus has been placed on Asia,
which is we've talked about before,
is a goldmine of opportunity
singly.
Without this change in priorities,
Obama would have probably kept the
troops in Iraq ends.
The situation in Yemen,
Libya or Syria would have been very,
very different,
but let's be really extra clear.
Have all of this petroleum means that
the Middle East is not really that
important to the United States anymore.
A country that can now even afford to
support these so called Arab Nato,
which is something pretty much like,
okay,
well you and take care of your own
safety man's.
Every now and then we'll give you a
hands to hopefully avoid the risk of a
global crisis or something.
Needless to say,
this energy independence has also given
Washington the opportunity to place more
demands on the petro monarchies of the
Persian Gulf,
especially when it comes to human
rights,
and by the way,
if there is something that is absolutely
certain,
it is trump's support for fracking,
the new president and wants to continue
Obama's work,
but to do it faster,
eliminating any obstacle that might be
in the way.
Yeah,
American Energy First America
first,
America first.
Donald trump has little doubt.
He made the promise during his campaign
and has kept his word since taking
office is priority,
has been to give petrol and gas
developments,
the green light,
among other things he promised to
eliminate many of the rules and
restrictions Obama passed,
which could cause fracking to slow down
trump well.
He wants cheap petrol panties willing to
push to get it sooner rather than later.
Trump has also chosen to surround
himself with key people closely related
to the petroleum industry.
As Secretary of state's trump decided to
go for rex Tillerson,
who used to be the CEO of Exxon Mobil.
Then there's Rick Perry,
the former governor of Texas,
who has been placed in charge of the
Department of Energy.
Thanks.
This is a stage that is very closely
related to the industry and then there
is the head of the US Environmental
Protection Agency,
Scott Pruitt to the attorney general in
Oklahoma,
another state,
well connected to the petroleum
industry.
Great.
Anyway,
this is a revolution that the US is
going through.
I did some revolution that just put
greater limits on the power of.
Okay,
now there is no question that fracking
has its risks,
but the reality is is that it's a
technology that's not going anywhere and
it does seem that with time and
development it's going to become safer,
but until that time comes,
environmental controls are absolutely
yes,
and now it's your turn.
We'd love to know what you think of this
energy revolution.
Do you think it's the start of a new era
for cheap petrol?
You can leave your opinion in the
comments below as well as in this survey
and if you enjoyed this video,
please do click that like button below
and make sure you subscribe.
You always hear about all new videos
falsely,
please do check out that you reconsider
media podcasts.
They provided the vocals in this episode
that are not mine,
and as always,
I'll see you in the next video.
America first.