Today we're going to talk about South
Korea or as Kim Jong UN would call the
Bad Korea.
You've probably heard of this country
because it's probably the way your
mobile phone,
your TV screen or possibly even your car
with manufacturers or perhaps because
it's the place where the most watched
youtube video of all time came from lone
star.
Yes,
South Korea is a big power,
not only at the cultural level but also
at an economic one.
I'm sure every one of you watching this
video haven't least one product from
Samsung or lg arounds you South Korean
companies on absolutely on fire,
and this is a surprise given that in the
19 sixties,
South Korea was an extremely poor
country and no,
we're not talking about relative poverty
here.
Other countries like Zimbabwe where
actually more developed with this,
right?
The West in just one generation,
South Koreans went from starvation to
one of the most prosperous societies in
the world and so now comes the big
question.
What exactly did South Korea do to
become quite so rich and hold on a
second because if you're a regular
viewer,
I probably know what you're thinking.
You're thinking,
oh,
it's another video where visual politic
tell me how marvelously wealthier
country became because of free market
capitalism,
right?
Rice,
while I'm sorry to disappoint you,
more,
not as much of the story of South Korea
is a bit different.
Fritz
compared with their neighbors to the
north.
South Korea is a free paradise,
but their economic model has one
peculiarity that sets it apart from the
rest of the world.
So then the question is what are the
reasons that explained this incredible
progress in South Korea,
and more importantly,
why was Gangnam style so controversial
in South Korea?
Both of these questions,
I promise they are actually related and
these are the questions that we're going
to answer in today's video to the
bottom.
As you probably know,
in 1953,
the Korean peninsula was split into two
halves after a war,
which killed over 2 million people.
At that moment,
we could actually say that South Korea
is the country that was actually in more
trouble economically,
the normal pads,
all of the industries and companies,
while the south was agricultural and
under develop,
had no desks and most of the children,
golden majority of their nutrition from
powdered milk that was given by theu ,
s and Europe.
This is why in 1960,
after many protests General Park Chung,
he organized a coup d'etat and took
power.
This is how the first South Korean
dictatorship started.
During the following 27 years,
the country had three different
dictators.
All of them came into power in a violent
way by overthrowing the previous one.
Nevertheless,
despite the political instability in
those times,
the South Korean
a minute,
because this economy is not as free as
you might.
In fact,
a free market is organized in a bottom
up fashion.
The private businesses decide how,
when and what they want to sell.
Then the state comes in and regulates
all of that activity through various
laws.
Well,
puncturing east system was quite the
opposite.
This was a top down system is policy was
to meet with the most important families
in the country who controlled most of
South Korea's industries.
This group included the founders of
Samsung and lg
Jean,
so essentially he put them in a room and
said,
look,
from now on I will give you whatever you
need to grow.
If one year you kind of weigh your
taxes,
it's okay,
I'll forgive you.
Do you need some ground swell?
But here you go.
You can have it.
You need to borrow some money from
abroad.
Well,
the government is going to back your
loan.
Even if you can't pay your debts,
the state is going to help you.
Our country will be in jeopardy in order
for a country not to fall.
It must cultivate its own strength.
Nonetheless.
Unlike other countries like France,
South Korea didn't put up any barriers
to international trade.
Actually since that very first moments
and the government's guaranteed rule of
law and low taxes for all businesses
regardless of where they came from.
That's not only that's Pacchiu.
He gave all kinds of tax incentives for
companies and individuals to invest and
save money.
In other words,
the big conglomerates like xy or Latte
gods to compete in an open markets with
other corporate juggernauts from Japan
or the United States,
but at the same time they also help from
the government in South Korea has no
natural resources,
but a big population.
Those companies put a focus on
industries that required a large
workforce that's manufacturing and this.
This was the beginning of
all nation.
Imagine the life of one of the hundred
thousand workers employed by Samsung in
South Korea.
He gets up in the morning in a house
built by Cyt,
the construction company run by the
Samsung Group wanting his breakfast.
He watches the latest visual politic
video groups that we'd like to think on
his Samsung Galaxy phone.
Then he takes his Renno Samson car.
Yep.
You read that right?
Rented cars are manufactured by Samsung
in South Korea.
And guess where as this car insurance?
Yep.
The all guessing.
The friends here.
He gets it from
Samsung
after a hard day working at.
Yeah.
Okay.
You're getting the picture now.
Now South Korea,
man,
he wants to go get some beers with his
colleagues,
so he goes to the Cantina.
It's again,
you're getting the picture.
We can come and our friend wants to
spend some quality time with his wife
and children,
so we decided to take them to a park.
So do you think you'd go?
Yep.
He goes to some things very own Disney
style theme park.
In other words,
if you work for Samsung,
the company is everything.
Okay.
We're
talking about the biggest cable and all
of South Korea and now you might be
wondering what exactly is the Chi ball
tribals are big conglomerates supported
by the state?
Some of them like to already defunct.
Diu were started by the administration
itself.
Others were born in the 1945.
Most of them started being family owned,
but as they grew they became public
companies and all of them have a number
of different business lines and
products.
For example,
LG is famous for that.
Tvs and then mobile phones,
but in South Korea they will all say the
distributors of Coca Cola in total
around 100 cables.
Ams,
they own the biggest asset in the South
Korean economy.
Now,
as I said before,
the government does place in red carpet
tons of their feet,
but this doesn't mean they have a blank
check.
This is why I went to Cabo as big as
day.
We went bankrupt.
No one came to bail is a clear incentive
for these companies to be on the edge of
innovation.
For instance,
in 2008 Suny,
the Japanese wanted to create the first,
Oh,
led tvs,
but this technology there wasn't
advanced enough and the screens were
pretty expensive,
even priced too high for most of the
luxury markets.
So the Sony guys,
but the project on hold and they never
really got back almost.
Whereas South Korea and lg at the same
technology now they have the same
problem
so well.
What did they do?
Well,
they launched mobile phones with a much
smaller display.
This way.
They took advantage of their assets and
what is more important is they learned
how to work with this new technology.
This is why in a very short amount of
time,
they found ways to produce affordable
own led TV screens.
Spell hold on for just a minute because
there's another more important parts
which helps explain this very innovative
culture.
South Korean education.
We'll know it's South Korean children
that have always had one of the best
marks in the international piece of
test.
The whole country stops during
university entrance exams in South
Korean school suspends it,
whatever they need to guarantee the best
education for their boys and girls.
Now,
the flip side of this coin is that those
kids have the biggest suicide rate in
the world.
In fact,
all of South Korea has a problem with
suicide.
The country having these second highest
suicide rate per capita in the world
since the beginning.
The government is understood.
The cables would need high skilled
workers.
Yes.
Are they
designed an educational system that
works in line with the nation's
companies?
This explains why South Korean children
are incredibly good at math center of
excellence,
memorization,
abilities.
Further their respect for authority and
hierarchy.
It's always religious and this is why
none of them want to start a company.
The dream of every South Korean is the
winds up working in one of these cables.
If they work hard,
they might even become a manager and to
get a house in paradise on earth.
That is a famous district of Seoul with
a name that's going to sound pretty
familiar to you.
Yup.
I'm talking about the Gangnam district.
Oh God.
The meaning of Gangnam style called
human warm Gal during the day,
a glossy one,
someone who knows how to enjoy the
freedom of a cup of coffee,
but when the night comes down,
her heart gets warmer because she has a
goal with two faces.
Hey,
sexy lady,
your big brother,
Gangnam style.
This is an extract from that famous song
that became so popular back in 2012,
even led to the main thing aside,
getting into some trouble with the
authorities and due to the lyrics,
having inappropriate content for society
that's obsessed with respect for
authority.
Something's aesthetics or something as
radical as the hipaa movements from
Elvis back in the 19 fifties,
but the truth is that a hierarchical
economy,
one which relies on a few big
corporations,
is not a good recipe for a state of the
economy.
In fact,
South Korea big as it is in the
manufacturing industry,
lags behind in other fields such as
services or.
Yeah,
economy depends so much on governmental
and Kabul decisions.
There is almost no space for
entrepreneurs.
Think about it.
I mean even if you wanted to start a
company,
it's pretty hard to compete with your
competitors are supported by the
government,
but not only that,
these hierarchical structures are not as
efficient as you might think.
In fact,
most of the Chi balls have become
bureaucratic bmo that require lots and
lots of money to work.
This phone leads the sales of mobile
phones in the entire world.
However,
they make almost no profits and that was
it
probably
right.
Things are starting to change.
A lot of self driven.
Youngsters have been educated in Europe
or America and now they are coming back
to their country of origin with a new
ends,
more critical mindset,
more entrepreneurial spirits.
This generation is creating the rates
for a startup ecosystem,
but that is still a lot of work to be
anyway,
whether you like as an ot,
we must admit that this top down model
has been successful in South Korea lines
of all of this.
There are still some questions that must
be onset.
What would happened if a country like
Samsung collapsed?
What would happen to the country as a
whole and not only that,
but this marriage between politics and
business has created lots of incentives
for corruption on a massive scale,
but that's something we're going to
cover in a future video.
You should absolutely check out this
other video we made about the rising
Asian middle class and also do not
forget to check out.
We'll reconsider media podcast where you
can hear the voice.
That isn't my voice on this
videos.
I was.
No,
but the question is,
do you think that this crossover between
hierarchy and the free market could ever
work in other countries,
and what's your opinion about the South
Korean system?
Please do leave your opinion in the
comment section below.
We'd love to hear from you.
I do not forget that we are building
brand new videos every Monday and
Thursday,
so don't forget to subscribe so you
won't miss anything,
and if you like this video,
please do give us a thumbs up and as
always I'll see you in the next video.
If
you'd like to hear more of my lovely
voice,
you can join us at reconsider the
podcast that covers politics,
but don't do the thinking for you
available on your favorite podcatchers.
See you there.