Imagine in a country with a population
of Manhattan,
but with huge reserves of oil and gas,
the country surrounded by the wealthiest
oil rich monarchies,
or am I talking about?
Well,
that would be Bahrain so tiny that we
almost can't see it on the map.
Yes,
yes,
I know what you're thinking.
Life must be wonderful hair,
right?
Money for everybody.
A prosperous economy and amazing growth.
Right?
Well,
the opposite is in fact,
true
brain downgraded to junk as political
crackdown continues unabated.
Yeah,
you heard that right?
Bahrain debt is considered to be a junk
bonds on the international market.
This means investors are so hesitant
about their economy that they don't
believe Bahrain.
We'll be able to give back those loans.
The truth is things in Bahrain,
they're getting really,
really sour.
If you've followed visual politic for a
long time,
you already know that within the Islamic
world there are two big groups,
Sunni Muslims and Shia Muslims and well,
they really hate each other.
As you know,
Saudi Arabia is something like the Sunni
Muslim Hollywood and the Islamic
Republic of Iran is of the same,
but for the sheer Muslims,
this is why they've been in a state of
cold war for decades,
but
in the context of this Cold War,
Bahrain is actually in the funniest
position of all.
Basically in this country,
the majority of the population is Shia
Muslim.
At the Royal House that rules the
country is Sunni Muslim.
This is why that monarchs stuff turns
political oppression into something of
an art form.
All right,
so so far nothing in this video has
probably surprised you're that much.
But then again,
the title of this video is why Bahrain
rain could become the world's wealthiest
country or something like that.
Honestly,
at the time of recording,
we haven't actually decided the title of
this video,
but so why don't we say something like
that?
Well,
because of this rate discovers largest
oil field in countries since 1932.
Yes,
dear viewer.
They already had dinosaur juice,
but now they have even more.
Basically Bahrain could have more oil
than Russia and with a fraction of
Russia's population,
so basically this means that there are
less people to split the money with,
but the question is,
is this enough to be the wealthiest
country on the planet?
Why even with sonar trial,
are Bahrain's data barns still
considered to be junk?
What the hell is going on in Bahrain?
Well,
today we are going to answer all of
those questions,
but as always,
let's take a look back at the history
cage.
All right.
If any of you out there,
once it become a dictator one day,
here are some pro tips.
Basically,
there are two ways to make people follow
you.
The first one,
good old oppression.
The problem with that though is that if
you go too crazy with the oppression,
you're gonna risk.
A popular uprising and maybe ending up
with Gaddafi.
There was a band that involved.
It's not a good time.
Don't watch that video.
We've told you thousands of times,
Aaron visual politics,
being a dictator is a risky job.
Not many of them go and die of old age.
Sure,
but there is an alternative and it's
healthier and it's more sustainable and
is what we're calling the money for
nothing.
Strategy.
Basically you shower all of your
citizens in gold if that wealthy and
they don't need to get a job,
they don't worry about politics.
All right,
so the Al Khalifa family,
the ruling family in Bahrain has
combined both of these methods in a very
effective fashion.
In fact,
the prime minister who happens to be the
kings uncle,
holds the world record for the longest
lasting ruler.
He has been in power since 1971.
Nonetheless,
how can I Sunni Muslim families stay in
power for such a long time in the
country with a sheer majority
population?
Well,
let's be honest,
before we have the good old iron fist
protest against the government,
hey,
great.
You'll automatically be considered a
terrorist.
You'll go to jail and you're probably
either be given the death penalty or
exiles,
and we're not talking about an isolated
example here.
This is something that happens.
Every single rain strips 115 of
nationality over terrorism allocations.
Over 700 people in Bahrain have had
their citizenship revoked since 2010.
Well,
and yes,
I know what you're going to say.
Oh,
come on,
Simon.
Don't be such a snowflake and other
democratic countries that Retalia
citizenship too,
and of course,
well,
you're right,
but the difference is the proportions.
For example,
in the United Kingdom there are some
examples,
sure,
but in fall rain we're talking about
hundreds are so now you might say,
well,
things are changing Simon.
I mean the world is evolving.
The Middle East,
it's getting more modern.
Well,
I'm sorry to say,
but in this case,
that's not true at all.
In fact,
the opposite is true.
In 2011,
the Shia citizens took to the streets as
part of the Arabs,
right?
Rabia,
along with the United Arab Emirates sent
troops to help the Bahraini government
to suppress these demonstrations.
Today,
one out of every 500 people in Bahrain
are political prisoners among them,
many leaders,
but on any of that,
since 2011 Bahrain passed new laws to
make it easier to retire one
citizenship.
And believe me,
losing Bahraini citizenship is a big
shame.
Citizenship means that you lose all of
your rights.
Yes,
you'll have to give up your passport,
your driver's license.
You cannot own a house,
a car,
a phone,
or a bank account.
You cannot marry in the country.
And if you decide to leave,
you cannot go back.
If you happen to stay well,
you can't leave.
In summary,
opposing the government tends you into a
second class citizen and well,
this is a big shame because being a
first lawsuit as an embodied brain,
it's actually pretty great.
And this,
this is where that money for nothing
policy comes into play.
This is what we call Bahrain's social
contract.
Basically,
if you forget about politics,
you don't have to worry about anything
looking for a job,
you can get one.
Even the governments,
don't worry,
nobody's going to check if you even go
to the office,
need to pick up some things in the
supermarket.
Don't worry.
Everything is super cheap because it's
all subsidized.
Need fuel for your car.
Well,
that's also crazy cheap.
All right,
so now you might be wondering,
well,
what happens if I don't want to work for
the government,
Simon?
I don't like it.
I want to work in a private business.
Well still,
no problem.
The government guarantees quotas for
local workers,
so no immigrants is gonna take away your
job.
This is actually the funniest part of
all the immigrant quote.
Basically they're there to reserve the
coolest jobs for the local.
Yeah.
For example,
50 percent of bank workers have to be
from Bahrain in the cool,
fancy shops.
It's 30 percent,
but construction work as well.
That's just five.
Why?
Because he wants to lay bricks under the
hot bar,
rainy son.
This is why it 55 percent of the
Bahraini population are immigrants and
they are the ones who actually get the
countries work done and well,
to be fair,
I need to make an aside here.
Look,
having more immigrants than locals is
very common in the Middle East.
For example,
foreign citizens make up 75 percent of
Qatar's population,
but Bahrain is a pioneer in another way.
They are one of the few countries that
ban the socorro and so.
Well,
what is the godfather roller balance?
this is a sort of modern day slavery.
The Catholicism links foreign workers
with a national who is that patron?
This patron can decide whether the
immigrants can change his or her job or
even leave the country at all.
So well.
Bahrain has actually abolished this
inhuman practice so.
Well that's good.
Nonetheless,
despite all of this,
what you might wonder as well kind of
country where nobody works actually
prosper and the answer is,
well of course not
$120 living without working is
expensive.
They already manages in Bahrain because
of one thing,
oil makes up more than 60 percent of
their exports in 75 percent of the
government's income.
Plus in order to cover all of the costs,
the government needs the oil barrel
price at $120 less than that.
They didn't make enough profit to make
ends meet.
And now you might be wondering,
well,
is $120 too much or too little?
Well look at it's historic.
That happens
in July of 2008 when oil was $147,
but as you know,
in 2014 oil prices fell in January 2016,
they went down a dozen little as $26.
And this explains news like
yes,
p cuts Bahrain rating b plus.
So what did they do with low prices and
lack of income.
Of course they took on more and more
debt and the results it speaks for
itself.
In just two years,
public debt has gone from seven percent
to 70 percent and despite crude oil
prices going up again,
it seems pretty unlikely that it will
reach $120 a barrel anytime soon.
So far Bahrain has already revoked
subsidies on meat products and.
Well this is only the beginning.
We'll introduce VAT by end of 2018 says
finance minister.
Yeah.
You had that right.
In Bahrain there is no income tax and so
far they didn't even have indirect
taxation,
but the situation is desperate and they
need to create a new taxes that simply
didn't even exist before.
But what does this mean for Bar rain?
Well,
do you remember how this particular
authoritarian rule works?
Well,
they've sheer population except Sony
oppression in exchange for money for
nothing.
So when the economics fail,
politics fails to now only a miracle can
save the outcome for family and well,
that miracle is this one oil miracle so
far,
Bahrain produces 200,000 barrels a day.
This is nothing compared with the tens
of millions in Saudi Arabia.
But it's insane when we take into
account in the country's size,
as I said before,
Bahrain has just discovered a big old
oil that.
And they could start pumping dinosaur
juice in as little as five years
according to optimistic analysts.
This could double production and ends
the deficit problem.
Alright,
so this all sounds fantastic and
wonderful.
So what exactly is the problem?
Well,
if you watch visual politic often you
probably have guessed and that's that
not every type of oil costs the same to
extract.
And
this new oil that has all the
ingredients needed to be very,
very expensive.
First of all,
it's underwater.
That means that Bahrain has to build
platforms on the sea floor.
Second is shale oil,
which means it's under a rock.
You need fracking technology to break
that rock and that fracking is really
expensive.
In this chart you can see the cost of
production of a barrel of oil in
different countries.
We don't know how much fracking would
cost in Bahrain,
but we can look to see how much it
costs.
For example,
in the United States,
if you pay attention to the chart,
you can see that fracking,
shale oil is significantly more
expensive than extracting oil in more
conventional methods.
If Bahrain wants to make a profit,
the barrels should cost over $60,
but since they need a huge profit to
cover all of their expenses,
they need an even higher market price.
So wait a second.
What?
What can save Bahrain from ruin?
Well,
the answer is the same as other Middle
Eastern countries and that's
diversification.
They need to produce other things that's
not just oil and this explains news.
Yes,
La opens $90,
million dollar factory of the future in
Bahrain,
but of course if you really want to
attract business from other industries,
you need something other than oil beds.
You need rule of law,
you need clear taxes and you need a
government that doesn't send people to
jail without a trial.
We've told you several times on this
channel do buying and generally
speaking,
the United Arab Emirates started down
this path of years ago.
Now Saudi Arabia,
it's probably going to follow suit,
although we're not really sure about
that.
And look,
it's only a matter of time before
Bahrain's dance doing the same,
but of course,
if those economic reforms mean that the
Bahraini people have to pay taxes or
even,
you know,
work hard than the ruling family is
going to be in.
Right?
So the big question now becomes,
do you think the Bahraini citizens are
going to accept such an authoritarian
governments?
If they no longer enjoying the money for
nothing policy,
do you think they're going to find a way
to reform the system while please leave
your onset in the comment section below?
Also,
please visit the reconsider media site,
the podcast that provided the vocals in
this episode that we're not mine,
and do you know,
forget that we published brand new
videos every week,
so subscribe to this channel,
hit that bell icon so you won't miss a
post.
And if you liked this video,
do give us a thumbs up.
I was always.
I'll see you next time and if you want
to learn more about politics and hear
even more of my voice,
you can join us at reconsider media.
We have a podcast@reconsideredmedia.com
slash podcast.
See you there.