Oh,
France,
the country where the far right wing as
it is known today,
was born way before the financial
crisis,
way before Donald Trump,
the game,
the presidents of the United States way
before breakfast,
and the uprising of xenophobic parties
in Europe.
Way before all of that,
France have an extreme nationalist
party,
the National Front,
and this had a real chance to winning on
the light.
Sure.
Julie,
in 2002,
the rest of the political players in the
country from the left to the sense of
rice had to join forces just to keep it
from becoming the president of France.
In April,
2017 French people are going back to the
voting stations.
A lot of people think that this is the
ultimate chance for the far right wing
in France.
The moments where the national front
with Marine Le Pen as its leader can get
the presidential office once and for
all,
if this was the case of Marine Le Pen,
who by the way is the daughter of Marine
Le Pen,
has promise that she will do everything
she can.
So you take a country out of the
European Union,
but not only that,
France is the second largest country in
continental Europe.
Victory for the extreme rights would be
a triumph for all far right parties.
Consonants
do.
Just wait one minute because the
question is really,
does Marine Le Pen have a real chance of
winning this election?
Is there anyone out there who could
possibly stop her?
Today?
We are going to answer all of these
questions and we're going to get to know
in depth history of the French extreme.
Write a story that includes wars,
ego clashes,
well playmates.
So let's get into it
and clap.
The French.
Extreme rights has to ideological
grandparents,
adult pit.
My ends theo a s as you know,
during World War Two,
the Germans invaded the north of France,
the south,
the so called free zone,
who's capital was vishy,
was governed by French politicians being
supported at the German national
socialism.
When the war ends in the new president
general Charles de Gaulle executed the
main officials from vishy.
But do wait one minute again,
because there were many people who
supported this collaborationist
government people even without having
political power,
it held the same principles,
ends the same ideals as the national
socialists for Nazi Germany.
Many of them were in the army up in 1961
the French.
So that's their most precious colony.
Algeria,
old,
a self determination referendum.
As you can imagine,
this was not great news for all of those
far right extremists inside the French
army.
This is how the OAS was born.
The oes was a terrorist group.
His main goal was to ends the Algeria
and attempt to the independence.
We are not terrorists.
Do you understand?
We have Patrick.
I would do what you used to the soldiers
who died fighting in Algeria and do the
3 million French citizens.
What?
What was it there?
So did they succeed?
Well actually no.
In 1962,
Algeria became a sovereign state.
And then the OAS change their goals and
trying to kill the French president
himself.
They thought that the goal was a traitor
to France.
Fortunately though,
in 1965,
the French police dismantled the last
cells of this group,
just like what happens after the end of
World War II,
they jailing the hardliners didn't mean
there were no people supporting the
general court.
Awesome.
The country of liberty,
equality and fraternity has a large
amounts of people who hated the Algerian
and to have for the Third Reich,
and this was the foundation that Joel
Marine Le Pen used to bills.
Ten years later,
the National Front's,
so you only talk about the war over and
over everyday we're reminded of what was
the war,
the persecution of the Jews,
the excessive behavior of the occupying
forces.
And so on.
The beginning of this policy was no easy
thing.
During the 19 seventies,
the National Front's would never get
more than five percent of the votes,
and Marie Le Pen himself suffered a
terrorist attack at his own house.
Now,
this though is when the really good pot
stocks in 1977,
that was the Le Pen family inherited
from a fellow support and entire palace.
It was the palace.
Soon this would become the unofficial
headquarters for the National Front,
or as we probably could just say the
lappin family.
Yes.
My friends with this policy,
everything does stay in family drama,
reorganized all those electoral
campaigns that need and the third
biggest political force in France at the
end of the 1980,
while his daughter Marine Le Pen was
following him and learning the secrets
as the art of politics in order to
become the leader that she is today.
Lisa,
his granddaughter,
Mary,
on the pen,
would follow him too,
and she is now an MD in French Polynesia
and a rising star in the national front.
Interestingly though,
even though his party congratulates in
as the champion of family values,
Le Pen's family is far from a happy one.
Yes,
yes.
I didn't know here visual politic.
We really don't like to gossip about
anyone,
but in this case,
it's kinds of absolutely necessary to
understand the political life.
As I said in the 19 eighties zone Marine
Le Pen,
who we will now called Le Pen senior,
was on fire in every election.
He was getting more and more votes than
the previous one.
It was during this time that he decided
to hiring journalists to write his own
biography,
and of course you know this random list
palace,
so can you guess what this journalist
did?
Well,
he probably can't unless you already
know he seduced Le Pen's wife.
Oh,
but it's not just that these lovers then
runaway from the palace,
and then months later,
Mrs Levin was on the cover of French
Playboy magazine,
and this is how the whole world
discovered the more sensible side of the
experience
right
now.
This caused a split in the family.
No matter how good the father was
dealing in the elections,
his daughter still agree with more and
more distant from him,
but the real turning point in the law
and family would come in the year 2002.
This was a year when France happened.
Presidential elections and for the first
time in history or Le Pen went to the
second round.
Now,
as you might know,
the French Alex oral system has two
routes.
When you're choosing presidents in the
first rounds,
they can choose from all of the
candidates,
however many that may be,
and in the second round you can only
vote for the two most successful
candidates in the first rounds,
well in 2002,
the ones who made it into the second
round was Jacques Chirac from the Center
Right Wing Party and Lapan senior from
the extreme
right
now you might be wondering how did it
happen to do it too,
right wing candidate.
All the new rules in France.
Well,
during the easiest Le Pen learned an
important lesson in politics.
The idea of the captain boats out.
I thought that this is going to find
some principles of the party attractive
no matter where they stand on the
political spectrum,
but ben stood for protectionism,
French companies,
but also for French workers.
Do you remember the America first thing
that trump was going on about?
Well,
it turns out that's not.
Trump's invention was used buying the
pen in the 19 nineties,
so incidentals and into industrial
cities,
like I'll say,
who used to be left wing strongholds
voted for the national front.
Yes,
and this is why in that second rounds,
boozy remains loyal to the social
democratic party,
had to swallow their pride and vote for
Chirac and the center reits candidates,
I mean anything was better than the
uprising of a racist,
extreme conservative.
Likely the Penn family learns a second
important lesson in politics.
It is not only important to be accepted
by your own voters,
you also can't be too scary to the other
people.
If your opposition are too frightened,
they might join forces to prevent you
from getting into that presidential
palace
versus Sean Murray versus Merry
Christmas was not a great time for the
family.
After 2000 and see,
Marine Le Pen started out internal
campaign against a father.
Now if again,
Jo Marie Le Pen was a politician that
ran for elections with statements like
this
to
be an authority always,
and we believe that in a household,
the best one to have this authority is
the mat.
Nonetheless,
Marine Le Pen was a women ready,
have authority and modernize a political
party that would honestly make windows
95 looked like a piece of state and
beyond software.
Now,
unlike the other marine supported gay
civil unions and was against the death
penalty,
even National Front voters could
appreciate these changes and this is why
in 2011 or the pen Jr took her father's
place as the party's leader,
but do not think that things were that
easy.
I wonder what motivated marine and her
deputy is in this offensive.
They have launched against me.
It's just that joint.
Just think about it when you've been the
founder and the leader of a French far
right political party for 39 years,
it's not going to be easy taking orders
from your daughter.
So even though today's y'all,
Marie Le Pen is the honorary president
of the National Front,
he also votes as an independence at the
European Parliament.
I campaigned not from a renal Le Pen,
but for Joan Marie Le Pen and I want 33
percent and guess this main supporter
inside of the family.
Surprise,
surprise.
Family business.
Again,
it says granddaughter,
married Le Pen who is starting her own
battle against her arms.
Murray,
he's a provocateur,
an nt conformist.
And it isn't always nice to hear.
Meanwhile,
marines moderation in combination with
the end of the crisis in France all
working way better than the radical
strategies have a fall back.
I consider Europe has made a mistake in
the past.
They should've started cooperation and
development relationships with Africa
this way they would have fixed the
people in their own countries.
In fact,
the latest holsters for this 2017
election give her close to 25 percent of
the vote.
This makes sense.
The first or second biggest candidates,
and in an election with five candidates,
25 percent is a big thing.
It is always certain that she will make
it into the second round,
but do consider that just because she is
less radical than her father.
This doesn't mean that marine is a
moderate.
In fact,
far from it,
they missed 144 points of our electoral
manifesto.
Lappin dreamier stands for closing
frontiers of massive deportations,
the exit of the European Union,
the return of the French currency,
the same economic views as Vladimir
Putin.
This is true,
but this is nothing new either.
All right,
so enough.
You're probably now wondering.
Well,
Cam lappin actually become the next
president of France,
so let's address this question with
another question.
Can Stop for years.
The center right wing in France,
Taliban,
good steal them,
but yes,
it is true that a big share of the
National Front's votes come from the
left wing,
but in a time of crisis,
family values and anti immigrant
sentiments are particularly attractive
to conservative voters.
So in 2016,
the big party of the center writes,
the Republicans chose a candidate.
We also put forward some of the
proposals that made famous viceman was
Francois.
So is the strategy working well?
Apparently not since finial became the
party's candidates,
the Republicans have been falling on the
polls and they are now fighting for
third position with the far right wing
party of Luke Menand,
shore corruption,
sex scandals,
and the fact that people prefer the
original to the copy.
This has caused failure and the center
right to fall into it,
but there is still hope.
The battle is not over.
There is still a man who could be ready
to stop.
Le Pen's hurricane.
His name is Emmanuel macron and he was
the finance minister during the
governments of Manwell vowels.
Alright,
so is Emmanuel macron a socialist?
Elmo macron is running in the elections
as an independent,
even manual vowels himself.
Didn't support him in public until
relatively recently.
So what does Emmanuel macron stand?
Basically he stands for the opposite of
Macron,
wants to ends the privileges and
subsidies that French companies guess he
wants to end the barriers that made it
impossible for the French youth to get a
job.
And of course he is against
discrimination based on race or religion
when it comes to the economy.
He wants to be a champion for deficit
reduction as fiscal responsibility.
Bam does.
If that was not enough,
one of his proposals is to forbid high
ranking officials,
do employee their own family in salina
be administration.
So as you can see is the antithesis of
Marine Le Pen and surprise surprise,
the latest polls actually indicate that
he is slightly more popular than Marine
Le Pen.
We'd like the 25 percent of the expected
and all of this despite being an
independence.
So he has a high chance of being the
person that Le Pen will face in the
second round,
maybe not because there is a last
variable that we must consider and
that's extension.
Even if macron has a lot of supporters,
they are simply not as motivated as
those from the Japan side.
So for example,
if during the second rounds,
the National Front could retain 90
percent of their boats and macron could
only retain 40 or 50 percent,
he would have great difficulty winning
the presence.
Yeah,
but I mean this is just our opinion and
visual politic and we would love to hear
yours.
Do you think macron can be in the pen in
France?
Are there any other candidates that
could make a surprise resurgence during
the election?
Please do leave us a comment below this
video and don't forget that we published
brand new videos every Monday and every
Thursday.
So do not forget to subscribe so you
don't miss any of those.
And if he did like this video,
please do give it a thumbs up below.
And as always,
I'll see you next time.
And don't forget to check out.
Reconsider a podcast about politics
where we don't do the thinking for you.
You can find us@reconsidermedia.com.
See you there.