It's known as the lucky
train,
amazing beaches,
a great deal of natural life spans,
many,
many natural resources.
This is Australia,
a surface paradise,
and they send it to the sport of
cricket.
For those who are unaware,
that's a British sport where there is
even a break for tea.
Australia is give us something special
and unique country.
Eighty percent of its plants and animals
don't exist anywhere else on the planet.
Everything is so different in Australia
compared to the rest of the world,
but even its characteristic animal,
the national symbol,
it doesn't even run or even fly.
It jumped.
Australia is a natural environment is
not only unique,
it's also rather terrifying.
Australia has more deadly things than
any other place in the wells.
For example,
all of the 10 most poisonous snakes in
the weld off from Australia.
Not enough evidence for you.
Well,
what about some other examples of the
deadly Australian ecosystem and have a
look at these four animals,
the funnel web,
spider box jellyfish,
the blue ringed octopus and the stone
fish.
They're all in Australia and they're the
deadliest of their kind.
Just be careful because,
well,
there's much,
much more
crocodiles that weighed more than 1500
kilograms sharks of all kinds and sizes,
and if animals don't scare you enough,
don't feel safe.
Yet there were many more natural dangers
of all kinds because this is a dry,
hot and aggressive climate.
How would that.
None of these things have stopped
Australia in any way from becoming a
dream,
the millions of people who dream of a
better future.
It's certainly logical.
I mean take a look at some of the
incredible places we can find in this
country.
This is the gold coast.
I'll tell you,
we are not only referring to regular
folks here who are heading to Australia
for a brighter future in the last few
years.
Australia has been like a magnet for
millionaires as well,
but the big question is why to find out.
I'll be honest with that.
We're going to have to leave the animals
aside and talk to some business
Australia.
Yeah,
a magnet for big fortune.
Everyday it gets easier to move around
the world.
Today.
We can reach almost any place in a
quick,
comfortable and affordable way for
further thanks to the Internet and all
kinds of new communication methods.
You can run a business from wherever you
want and just look at how things have
changed
just 50 years ago for a trip between
London and Sydney.
We have to make many stops on the way
and it never took less than three days.
Same trip can now be done in much less
time and a bit more than 20 hours on a
comfortable plain,
safe and with various films,
TV series and music.
You can arrive
because of this increase in the ease of
traveling communications,
wealthy business people have become more
demanding of their country,
of residence.
After all,
they can now easily choose where they
prefer to live without it affecting
their business.
It's not only attractive taxes that
affect the choice of where a wealthy
person lives.
They also want to live in places with
high standards of living where it's easy
to do business and whether a good
schools as well as safety in terms of
both physical security as well as
judicial safety.
The last meaning they can leave their
savings safely,
deposited somewhere safe in the
knowledge that it won't be seized by a
corrupt politician or they've had an
argument,
okay,
64 percent of Chinese millionaires have
either immigrated or plan to immigrate
taking their spending and their fortunes
with them
and Australia.
Wealth.
It has a lot to offer these
millionaires.
On the one hand,
it is the fifth most free economy in the
world.
It is very easy to do business that I'm.
There are plenty of opportunities for
business.
The justice system also works incredibly
well and it has a very competitive
financial system and regulations as a
general rule.
Plus on the other hand,
it's one of the countries with the
highest standard of living in the world
because there are a huge number of
quality services like hospitals,
universities,
and
cool.
In fact,
year after year,
Australia's big cities maintain the
highest positions in the international
rankings in terms of quality of life.
As an example,
Melbourne for six years in a row now has
led the quality of life rankings as
compiled by the economist.
This means it must be a pretty wonderful
place.
I'm sweating.
That wasn't enough.
The country recently created an open
door projects for people with
significant fortunes
in Australia.
Millionaires willing to invest about
three point $5,
million US dollars can obtain a
permanent residence card and if they
fall a little bit short,
if this three point $5,000,000 figure,
they can still get a lot of advantages
with $750,000.
Great
standards of living,
ease of doing business and open doors.
What do you think the results of all of
this has been?
Well,
that's pretty interesting.
In both 2015 and 2016,
Australia has been the country whether
most millionaires have moved to beating
out even the United States in 2006 in
particular.
$11,000 million as moved to Australia,
which is an unbelievable figure for a
country whose population is less than 25
million and honestly that might be the
best indicator of the unstoppable
Australian
economy.
Best version of the United States.
When you arrived in Australia,
some say that they feel they've arrived
and an improved version of the United
States.
That is to say in general,
the city's system and society in both
countries is quite similar.
Australia,
even as its own Washington DC,
a capital city built for and by the
politically powerful.
Now some might forget,
but the capital city of Australia is not
Sydney or Melbourne.
It's Canberra,
right?
The truth is you could mistake Australia
for America at first if it wasn't for
the fact that cars are on the wrong side
of the roads and there are statues of
Queen Victoria decorating the cities.
As an interesting aside,
it Australia is still technically a
monarchy and it's queen this Queen
Elizabeth Second.
Well,
the thing is that besides all of the
similarities,
Australia is a safer,
cleaner,
more modern,
more cosmopolitan,
more prosperous country,
and Australians are also richer than
American.
When Australians visit the US,
they see a country in decline.
Australian see the bad airports,
the infrastructure,
the poor,
the becker.
Now maybe you can understand why people
think Australia is something of an
improved USA.
Generally speaking,
international media doesn't pay a ton of
attention to Australia,
but this really shouldn't be the case
because this is a country that hasn't
seen an economic crisis in 26 years.
In fact,
the last time the country went through a
crisis,
Gorbachev was in power in the Soviet
Union.
No battery.
Yeah,
the phone that he had always thought of
you.
No financial crisis like crisis over raw
materials.
No unemployment's seemingly no problems
at all in Australia.
And so the question is now,
what's the result of all of this
prosperity with a population of just 24
million inhabitants,
it's economy is already as big as Russia
now.
It is also important to note that
Australia is very dependent on its raw
materials.
They make up more than half of its
exports.
20 19.
Australia will replace gutter as the
world's leading natural gas export.
So when the prices of raw material
started to fall,
it seems there's Australia would be
facing a situation similar to those
which occurred in Russia,
Brazil,
Ecuador,
Saudi Arabia,
et cetera.
It seemed as if the good times were
about to come to an end,
but the reality,
the reality is entirely different.
In Australia,
unlike almost every other producing
nation,
the crisis in raw materials didn't cause
any harm.
So what is it that makes Australia
almost invulnerable to any kinds of
crisis?
Well,
let's have a look.
The secret of success.
Lazy.
I regularly follow visual politic.
You already know that.
We like to say good policies,
good results,
but that is exactly what Australia has
done in the last few decades.
They've had reformance.
The changes weren't many,
so we'll just mention some of the most
important ones.
First,
the government decided to battle opening
up the economy.
International Trade,
removing most terrorists.
The country is today,
a from defender of free trade
agreements.
Exactly.
Seconds
in the early nineties,
the Labor is of poor.
Keating decided to start a retirement
system known as super annuation based on
capitalization,
so each worker saves and invest a part
of their salary to pay for their
retirements.
In this way,
the Australian system is similar to the
one in Chile.
The results are absolutely outstanding.
The program has allowed people to
generate large quantities of savings
which have been invested in the
productive economy.
Besides all this money saved has
launched the finance industry.
For example,
Australia is already one of the most
important markets for investment funds
and it isn't just that Australia has the
world's highest growth rate for finance
technology.
Third in 1995,
they started the national competition
policy,
the aim of which was to reduce state
interventionism in many sectors.
This program allowed for the elimination
of almost 20,000 rules and regulations
which restricted competition.
Also an ambitious program for
privatization and the elimination of
state monopolies was launched and you
want to know an example from this.
Well that would be quantified
today.
You're flying on a quad bike.
Yeah,
and three big major changes.
As in addition to that,
we also have budget stability in labor
flexibility.
Then so on and so forth.
And so what has been the result of all
of this?
Well,
that's 25 years without a recession and
economy with no unemployment as an
average salary of more than $5,000 a
month.
And that's not even mentioning the tons
of foreign investment.
Sounds pretty good,
right?
Well,
we did visual politic.
We will draw the conclusion that it is
wrong for a country to blame the price
of raw materials for a financial crisis.
They simply didn't do their homework.
And do you know who did do that?
Home work?
Wellbe?
Yeah,
that's Australia.
So what do you think?
Do you think that Australia is a great
destination for the wealthy?
Do you think that the country could be
to the 21st century?
What the USA wants to the 20th?
Let us know in the comments below.
We'd love to know what you think.
And as always,
if you enjoyed this video,
please do hit that like button below.
And don't forget to subscribe for brand
new videos every Monday and every
Thursday.
And as always I'll see you in the next
year.
And if you want to learn more about
politics and hear even more of my voice,
you can join us at reconsider media.
We have a podcast@reconsideredmedia.com
slash podcast.
See you there.