Totally before being fired on twitter at
Secretary of state,
rex Tillerson,
the former US diplomat,
has concluded his first tour of Latin
America was the first official trip a
senior officer from the trump
administration had taken to the region.
Though a few months ago in the summer of
2017 the vice president's himself,
Mike Pence had his own Latin American
talk in which he visited Panama,
Colombia,
Argentina,
and Chile.
I think we all know that the
relationship between the United States
and Latin America is very,
very,
should we say special.
And by special we mean not very good.
And I'm not just saying this because
there are about 60 million Hispanics
living in the United States,
but also because of historical
precedents,
commercial ties,
and many,
many security issues.
Without going any further,
one out of every four US trade dollars
ends up in this region.
However,
the vice presidents and the former
secretary of state's toilets left in
many with the feeling in the eyes of the
trump administration.
Latin America is more of a nuisance than
an opportunity,
and this might actually be softening the
blow.
Considering everything that trump has
said since he announced that he would
run four presidents,
when Mexico sends its people,
well,
they're not sending their best no more,
no more naps.
Alan Bray Dead Pedelec when we're going
to build the wall,
we have no choice.
We have no choice
to describe the relationship between the
United States and Latin America today.
We could say that the United States is
kind of like that friend who demands
loads of things from you.
But when the situations reversed,
they won't do anything for you.
A pretty good example of this is the
pretty surreal Mike Pence store.
It's all that had practically no
objectives and to which the vice
president seemed to be more concerned
with trying to prevent the insignificant
commercial relations between Chile and
North Korea,
or maybe trying to get the origin zines
to buy pork from his State,
Indiana.
He didn't seem to have much of a focus
on actual international relations
between the United States and Latin
America.
Uh,
I come from an agricultural state in the
United States.
I was governor of the state of Indiana
before I became vice president.
Uh,
and um,
I know the,
uh,
the quality of American pork.
You
know,
it was China,
Xi Jinping's China.
Well,
they're on the lookouts.
So in the video today,
we're going to see what he wants.
What does Donald Trump expects from mass
in America and also,
well,
what's happening with China.
But first,
let's look back at the history America
for North Americans,
1823,
the then president of the United States,
James Monroe,
launched what would later be known as
the Monroe Doctrine America for the
Americans or they,
with time,
this is become more like America for the
North Americans see this doctrine,
this policy defended the claim that the
European states had no right to
intervene in American affairs or in the
countries that were becoming independent
at the time from Spain.
At that time,
the U S was protecting Latin America and
defending non-intervention,
which sounds pretty good,
right?
Well,
just wait a moment here because that is
certainly a problem.
Well,
this doctrine led Washington's do
practically everything in Latin America.
We're a region that has since become
known as the u s his back yard.
Oh yes.
Since James Monro launched this
perspective,
the United States has set up,
governments has overthrown,
governments,
has financed gorillas,
has financed armies,
has bought politicians,
has negotiated with drug traffickers,
has managed to legitimize q to task and
has committed many more actions aimed at
depending on the time period,
either at fighting communism or
defending other interests such as some
big oil sector multinational now.
Yes,
of course.
Some good things have also been done,
especially in recent years when the
more,
let's say opaque relations gave way to a
strategy from Washington that focused
more on resolving internal conflict.
Yes.
Was the case for example with Bill
Clinton's Columbia plan or George Bush
is trade promotion strategy,
which led him to sign no less than 10
new free trade agreements with Latin
American countries and to even propose
for all of America to become a large
free trade area.
They even say relations between Latin
America and the United States.
They've always been very peculiar.
You see,
due to the Monroe doctrine,
Washington has always felt like a legal
guardian who can decide what's right,
what's wrong,
what's advisable,
and Watson not advisable.
However,
the results haven't been very positive.
[inaudible]
is it over again now since Donald Trump
entered the white house.
So let's see what the presidents of the
United States of Latin America wants,
what he expects and what we can expect.
What does Donald Trump want
now is not going to surprise anyone
watching this video that Donald Trump is
not exactly in Latin America's best
friend who seemingly has very little
concern for the region except Cuba,
Venezuela and above all,
well Mexico.
In fact,
trump has so little interest in Latin
America that one year into his
presidency at the time of making this
video,
he still hasn't appointed someone for
the Assistant Secretary of State for
Western Hispanic Affairs.
This is the person specifically
responsible for diplomacy with Latin
America and it's quite unusual that it
hasn't yet appointed anyone to this
position.
That is not to see that his lack of
interest hasn't made the region
something of a play thing for him.
Nor does it mean that he doesn't expect
anything from them.
Well,
I,
let me,
let me explain this.
Trump's first year has been marked with
insults to Mexico,
mostly due to his obsession with
building that wall.
Oh,
and he's also threatened to Columbia,
which is something we're going to get to
in a moment.
It may be through reimbursement,
but one way or the other,
Mexico will pay for the world.
That wall,
build that wall,
build that wall.
I love the Mexican people.
I have such a great relationship to make
sure I hire thousands people.
The Rich Mexicans,
they're great people.
Friends of mine,
they buy my apartments.
Ah,
well how about some more examples?
Now listen to this.
In 2017 as we saw here on visual
politics,
trump moved away from Obama's openness
towards Cuba without really proposing
any sort of alternative.
Also back in the worst customs of
Western diplomacy in Latin America.
He legitimized and supported the very
suspicious reelection of one Orlando
Hernandez in Honduras and most recently
in 2018 is government decided to suspend
these so called temporary protected
status for Nicaragua and Honduran
Haitian and above all Salvadoran
immigrants.
And listen because with this decision,
200,000
immigrants from El Salvador.
Yes,
200,000
we'll have to leave the United States or
simply become illegal immigrants.
We had hoped that if we worked hard,
paid our taxes and didn't get in
trouble,
will you be allowed to stay?
Veronica lacunas 39 a Salvadoran who has
two children born in the United States
and these are just a few examples.
The list is really rather long.
Perhaps that is why trump's popularity
in the region is so,
so low and when we say so,
so low,
we really mean it is just totally on the
floor.
I mean check it out.
In 2017 Gallup asked Lassen American
citizens for their opinion on president
trump.
Only 16% had a positive opinion.
The folks,
here's an important question.
The question that we really need to ask
ourselves is,
does all this offense does all this
poking in the,
I mean that trump doesn't want anything
from Latin America and the answer that
is not a tall,
his government is demanding several
things from the regions,
countries,
especially the following three
unconditional support for his foreign
policy,
including his policy on Venezuela,
seconds for people to renounce or curb
China's influence and third for them to
take the blame for everything.
Either by paying for the wall or by
assuming more responsibilities in the
fight against drug trafficking.
Now,
okay.
Except for China in the world,
the other demands could really be taken
as actually being pretty reasonable.
Do you know what the real problem is
here is
the trump administration never put any
alternatives on the table.
They don't seem very willing to give
anything in return and they do
everything under the,
you're either with me or against me
approach.
And the truth is that if we want Latin
America to change,
evolve to prosper,
it needs support and it needs
opportunities.
Like for example,
more trade opportunities.
That was another republican president.
George Bush has precise strategy and the
results were actually pretty good,
but okay.
Now you might be thinking,
well,
come on assignment.
Surely trump has also proposed some
positive things,
right.
Well,
I really think to answer that question,
we need to see how trump is treating the
u s is best allies in the room.
[inaudible]
brands
you can say without fear of being wrong,
but Colombia,
Honduras and Mexico have traditionally
been,
the u s is best allies in Latin America
and you know what?
With trump in the White House,
it's not really helping very much.
Check out the statements that trump made
by rex tillerson was on tour trying to
strengthen ties with the Latin America.
These countries are not our friends.
We think there our friends and we sent
the massive aid and I won't mention
names right now.
We send them massive aid and they're
pouring drugs into our country and
they're laughing at us.
Donald Trump,
yes,
trump.
He doesn't give out any names,
but there's little doubt.
He was referring to Mexico,
Colombia,
Honduras,
and brew in Mexico.
He mentioned the wall.
He mentioned the Nafta renegotiation.
There have been constant attacks since
trump announced his candidacy and do you
know how people feel about trump in
Mexico?
Will,
according to polls,
it's 1.6
points out of 10 does also take a look
now at Columbia,
the country that by far has historically
had the best relationship with the u s
yeah,
it might surprise you,
but Columbia was actually the only Latin
American country that sent troops to the
Korean War.
It also supported the United States and
the 2003 invasion of Iraq and this
country's policies.
It's pretty much always aligned with
Washington's interests.
These have been created policies towards
Cuba.
China.
Wow.
Well,
not even that's prevented from
threatened ms country by considering it
noncooperative with the fulfillment of
international requirements in the fight
against drug trafficking.
This is something that could have a
serious economic and political
consequences.
It isn't only treating an ally who's
trying to solve the problem in a rude
way.
It's also a great mistake.
He's sending a toxic message to the rest
of the region.
Even if you do what the u s asks,
if they disagree with part of your
strategy,
they will act against you.
Adam Isaacson coordinator up a
Washington Office for Latin American
affairs.
Yes,
it is true.
The coca production has rebounded in
Columbia and that the country hasn't
been able to beat the drug trafficking
that's threatening the country that has
suffered the most from the war on drugs,
threatening the only country that has
managed to improve the situation.
As I mean on top of that,
he's doing it without proposing any
alternative.
We've lost.
Our best leaders are best journalists,
are best judges,
are best police in the war on drugs.
Juan Manuel Santos,
President of Columbia and is regarding
Honduras and other great ally.
What we've already told you here on
visual politic about Juan Orlando
Hernandez is very probable q and even in
Argentina,
a country that is rapidly changing
something that Washington should
logically acts upon.
Well,
they're not even acting then.
Trump demands a lot from Latin America,
but he really isn't willing to give much
in return,
not even to the United States,
his best friends in the region,
and China knows it.
Right?
Does pursuit,
okay.
China and the Chinese influence in the
region is becoming a great obsession for
the United States.
Rex tillerson himself use the monroe
doctrine to see that the United States
has the right to block the interference
of another power in America.
But the question is,
who gave the United States government
that power in the first place?
Latin America does not need new imperial
powers that seek only to benefit their
own people.
Rex tillerson allow me to explain this.
Latin American countries have all the
rights in the wells to seek other
alliances,
other markets,
and other investments.
And if those are Chinese,
so the u s department of State should
ask itself is how is it possible that Xi
Jingping has visited the region more
times in the last five years?
Then the presidents of the United
States,
both Obama and trump
hold it.
China is willing to promote trade
agreements and investments while trump
is determines to punish Mexico,
build walls,
and restricts trade.
A great example of this is the shutting
down of the TPP,
the largest trade agreements in history,
which includes among other countries,
Mexico,
Peru,
and Chile.
See in the last Latin American and
Caribbean states community meeting,
China announced it would invest $250
billion in the region in the next
decade.
If the United States wants to maintain
its power and its influence and continue
to determine the political agenda,
perhaps it should include looking after
Latin America's interests in its
political strategy,
but now it's your turn.
On a scale from one to five,
how would you assess the USS influence
in Latin America?
Well,
you can leave your answer in the
comments below as well as in this survey
and I really hope you enjoyed this
video.
If you did,
please do hit that like button and don't
forget to subscribe to our channel for
brand new videos every Monday and every
Thursday.
Also,
don't forget to check it off.
Friends at the reconsider media
podcasts,
they provided the vocals.
In this episode that weren't not mine,
and as always,
thank you for watching.
When Mexico sends its people,
they're not sending their best no more,
not no more naps.
Alan Bray dead.
PEDALEC when we're going to build the
wall,
we have no choice.
We have no choice.