Here's the question,
anyone had a faker,
sk telecom fans?
Well,
those over 30 the slightest clue what
I'm talking about.
I'm talking about some of the most
famous players after the eeg of legends,
League of legends,
also known as lol,
due to its initials,
is one of the most successful video
games in the world.
Yes.
How'd that rise?
Many may think the video games aren't
simply a domestic form of entertainment
with either game we'd play as is home
alone or with our friends and that's
pretty much it writes well,
Dev view out nothing could be further
from the truth.
The surgeon will open its first use
sports stadium in Los Angeles next
month.
Yup.
That is really something that's
happening nowadays.
Video Games have become a mass sport
almost on the same level as football or
formula one,
giving you an idea only in 2017.
East sports that is electronic sports
moved more than one point $5,000,000,000
through sponsorships,
merchandising and investment.
Yeah.
Now that is still a little compared to
the $8,000,000,000.
The Formula One moves,
for example,
but it isn't bad if we consider that
this new mass sport isn't even 10 years
old.
To give you an idea,
the first league of Legends World
Championship was held in 2011 and had an
audience of about $200,000.
Seven years later,
in 2016,
more than 14 million people from around
the world saw the final match.
These figures are only a little bit
lower than the ones we could find for an
NBA final,
but not much lower.
Now,
league of legends broadcast even have
their own commentators in various
languages.
Where do you think sports are the most
popular?
Of course that would be an Asia.
In countries like China or South Korea,
their accounts for more than 60 percent
of video games audience,
unlike Formula One,
which never really took hold in this
part of the world.
East sports have really stuck and
logically this has led to an uproar in
the investor as well.
Intel,
HP announced record investment e-sports
industry.
However,
the Internet and new technologies have
always been the perfect breeding grounds
for generating financial bubbles that
explode in a rather big way.
We've all heard about the.com crisis at
the beginning of the 21st century or the
downtown companies like snapchat took.
So the question is,
are we really talking about a new sport
or is this simply just another bubble
kind of massport simply be created from
nothing just by investing money?
Well,
we're going to answer these questions in
today's video,
but first,
let's take a look at the history.
Who invented
Formula One in 2015 group of investors
go to liberty media,
but what Formula One you might be
wondering,
well,
how can someone buy a sport?
Well,
the truth is that Formula One,
in addition to being a sports
competition,
is also actually a after the second
world war with the cars democratization,
a massive public emerged who loved
seeing the fastest cars in the world and
his car manufacturers.
They were happy to participate in these
races.
Competitions gave them the perfect
excuse to test their latest engines.
To give you an idea of this formula,
one car can cost millions of dollars
even though it's never intended for the
consumer markets.
However,
the technology it uses ends up being
implemented in utilitarian cars,
for example,
disc brakes,
so active suspension innovations born in
formula throughout these years.
The only instate in job regulating and
stick teasing the competition rules was
the international automobile federation,
also known as the eye.
However,
the real business didn't emerge until
the seventies when this guy came along.
This is Bernie ecclestone something.
If the tuner of speed,
I Colston was the owner of a Formula One
team.
He immediately realized that this sport
was a money making machine,
but the business was neither in the
prizes nor in the car companies.
The real money was in selling tv
transmission rights around the wells.
Now,
what do you think Bernie did?
Hip well,
he partnered with the other teams,
went to the IAF headquarters and told
them either you give us transmission
rights so that we can manage them well.
We stopped running and your out of races
and that is how what we know today as
the Formula One group was born.
That is,
it's a sport that became the company
that is even listed on the New York
Stock Exchange.
In other words,
on the one hand we have the IAF which is
in charge of organizing the racism,
creating the regulations so that
everyone can meet on equal terms.
It was on the other hands,
the one who really has all the money as
the Formula One group,
and we're not just talking about a few
dollars here and 2011.
They made a profit of over one point
$5,000,000,000.
Hmm.
And when we talk about billions of
dollars,
it's.
It's easy to get lost in the figures and
not really know how much that is worth,
but put it this way,
the Burj Khalifa,
the tallest building in the world could
be built with that kind of money.
Now,
as you can imagine,
these two organizations that often
fighting and they do have a lot of legal
conflicts because they will.
Now you might be wondering,
well,
how does Formula One make any money?
Now pay attention here because this is
going to help us analyze e-sports,
veteran a moments.
Most of the money comes from
transmission rights and from the
payments that municipalities and
different governments make to host any
of the races in that cities.
Those two things alone account for 60
percent of the income.
The rest is made with companies
sponsorships.
That is advertising and merchandise
sales and so in other words,
the too long didn't read version is yes,
the company can create a big sport and
make billions of dollars from it,
from essentially nothing.
Now the question is,
can e-sports replicate this business
model?
Well,
let's dive into that right now.
Pixels to legends,
just like car racing,
video game competitions are as old as
video games themselves.
The first major tournament was held in
1972 at Stanford University.
More than 10,000 people gathered to see
the best space wall players.
It's baseball.
It was one of these old video games with
big pixels and eight bit music.
In those years.
Video Games hardly had multiplayer
systems and internet connections that he
existed,
so in other words,
in those times it was very haunting,
organize any competition that was really
worth seeing.
So just as in Formula One came about,
when most people started having cars in
east sports came when most people
started having high speed Internet
connections and you might be able to
guess the first country where
competitions were hell's.
Yep,
it was South Korea in 2006.
South Korea was the country with the
fastest Internet on the planet's ended.
That time,
half of the population had broadband
connections.
In other words,
this was the perfect breeding grounds
for the first big halo or starcraft
players to emerge.
And so how did these plants become
famous?
Well,
that's through streaming platforms such
as youtube or above will twitch.tv,
and that is essentially how east sports
fever broke out in South Korea.
Souls getting a new dedicated esports
stadium come March 2016.
Now.
You may be wondering who would be the
Bernie ecclestone of eastport and well
balanced is riot games.
This is the company that created the
most successful game of all time,
League of legends,
which was released in 2009.
We talking about a video game that seems
to have been made for competitions.
I mean check this out too,
that time.
Online games where,
how do we say it?
A bit rudimentary.
Of course there were titles like world
of warcraft,
which had fantastic graphics and a great
story,
but these were role playing game,
which one can play for hours and never
win and never lose.
Also,
you have to pay a monthly fee to pay and
not everyone can afford that.
However,
at League of legends is free,
has great graphics and an unbeatable
game.
Mode and games last for about an hour.
They have a winning and losing team in a
very short time.
This video game gained millions of
players around them.
They were connected by the Internet.
The teams that were created were
completely international.
For example,
at one of the best nine groups known as
origin,
has Spanish,
French and finished plans.
The truth is the by the year 2011,
they had a critical mass of users and to
celebrate it,
they went to an industry festival that
was being held in Sweden.
They had an audience and they place to
celebrate the championship,
allowing their players to share their
screens on youtube or twitch was enough
to offer a show on an international
scale,
and as we always say it,
as it was said,
so it was
done.
Championship reaches 900,000 viewers.
One thing was clear,
there was an audience he wanted to watch
matches from their favorite game on that
computer screens from the initial
900,000 spectators,
we now have surpassed more than 14
million and the players who are now
professionals travel around the wells on
athlete visas.
This means that from the institutional
point of view,
League of legends is now considered a
rightful sport and swear there's an
audience.
There are also companies willing to pay
for publicity.
Don't forget,
we're talking about video games.
Yeah,
a perfect environment to sell computers,
graphics,
cards,
screens,
or even high speed Internet connection.
It's every technology company has
recently decided to sponsor events.
As you can imagine,
that's where the gains come from as
there are also huge investors willing to
invest in this industry.
It's investment research highlights
three east stocks to watch.
It's clear east sports or a business
that is growing by leaps and bounds,
but how far can it go?
Good.
We'd be talking about the new Formula
One.
Well,
if you remember,
we mentioned that most of Formula One's
income comes from the rights sold to TV
network to now he's some broadcast
openly,
freely through online streaming
platforms.
Therefore,
there doesn't seem to be a big
television business here.
As on the other hand,
so far,
new governments or municipalities have
seemed willing to pay to host a
tournament.
In other words,
for me to one has a diversified business
with different income streams,
which means that even in times of
crisis,
the company continues to make an income.
At the moment it seems that the bulk of
esports income depends largely on their
sponsors and by definition sponsor based
businesses are on stable,
but above all,
the biggest problem with this type of
sports is variety.
There's only one formula one does that
mean one football,
but there are lots of esports and we
don't know which ones were lost and
which ones worked.
League of legends has achieved and
undeniable amounts of success,
but it was created in 2009.
I mean,
will it still be fashionable in another
10 years or will a new electronic sports
emerge that will pick up
that awesome.
No mistake.
The sports,
they're here to stay.
The question is which one is worth
investing in in the long run?
Of course,
these are all reasonable doubts for any
new industry and uncertain.
No circumstances do we want to
underestimate this phenomenon.
That's as we always say,
a visual politic.
Not Everything is as it seems and the
devil,
whether it's in the detail.
Having said that,
I'll leave you with this question.
Would you invest in an sports company
right now?
Do you think we're facing a new mass
sport that will generate millions of
dollars swelled and leave your onset in
the comments below,
and if you want to know more about
another emerging economic industry in
this case that have electric cars,
we tell you about that in this other
video where we look at the competition
between Tesla and BMW.
Also,
if you like this video,
please do hit that thumbs up button
below and don't forget to subscribe for
brand new videos just like this every
day of the week.
Also,
I'd like to thank our friends at the
reconsider media podcasts.
They provided the vocals in this episode
that we're not mine,
and as always,
thank you for watching and if you want
to learn more about politics and hear
even more of my love before you can join
us at reconsider media,
we have a podcast@reconsidermedia.com
slash podcast.
See you there.