Okay.
April,
2015 a historic meeting took place
between Raul Castro,
the president of Cuba,
and Barack Obama.
It was celebrated in Panama and it was
the first and bilateral meeting of the U
S and Cuban and presidents in 50 years,
four months,
Ellia booth leaders and announced they
would remake relations between the two
governments.
Today,
the United States of America is changing
its relationship with the people of
Cuba.
I'm dust.
They said they would do.
So it was done in just a short period of
time that he first changes were made and
relations between both countries started
to returns and normal.
Now he goes same like we see this a lot
on this channel,
but the arrival of Donald Trump to the
White House,
well,
they changed everything again,
the new presidents of the United States,
there's ordered that the u s steps back
from most of the changes that Obama
initiated with Cuba.
So the question might be,
why is he doing this?
What does he expect and what are the
consequences of this new policy?
We're going to look at all of these
questions in this video,
but before we do,
let's have a quick little caps.
The history of the relations between
these two countries.
Okay.
The embargo,
often
the so called Cuban revolution took
place against a Batista's dictatorship.
The new governments in the islands led
by Fidel Castro soon started to
nationalize every kind of capital good
and company Landon's,
hotels,
factories.
Well,
everything was up for grabs by the
governments.
So the Cuban revolution ended on the 1st
of January,
1959 and already buying may,
the government had begun a huge
expropriations all across the country.
Now our eyes,
you might probably be able to imagine
this is something that the u s did not
really take very well.
There were thousands of lawsuits filed
in the u s which had close relations
with Cuba at the time.
Further,
if this wasn't enough to upset the u s
the Soviet Union was already getting on
well with Fidel Castro
at this moment,
when as a penalty,
Washington passed the first trade
embargo against the island and in
embargo.
That's slowly grew stronger as the
relations between these countries were
getting worse.
Okay.
Backed off to the missile crisis of 1962
at Kennedy,
even limited to us,
traveled to Cuba since then.
Then with the exception of short periods
of battery relations under the
governments of Ford and Carter,
the various governments of the United
States of cabs of the embargo and the
policy of isolating Cuba economically,
we'll move Reagan.
Reagan
labeled the island as a sponsor of
terrorism and later Bill Clinton made
even more severe restrictions and the
embargo was put into law.
Since then,
traveling to and investing in Cuba or
doing business with the Cuban government
has been very limited for America.
Wow.
That is until Barack Obama came to
office
story 2008 fidel past power to his
brother Raul Castro.
That same year elections took place and
Obama said it was time to use a
different approach with Cuba.
It was time to improve diplomatic
relations between the two countries.
Obama didn't want to wait and shortly
after he arrived in the White House,
he softens some of the restrictions that
were in place on Cuba.
For example,
he allowed Cubans in the u s to send the
money to the islands and he started to
allow US citizens do travel to Cuba.
Many more things followed these fast
gestures.
During the years,
Obama was in office many restrictions
against Cuba.
Yes.
December of that year,
Raul Castro and Obama met in Panama.
Significant progress was being made.
Well,
I think what we have both concluded is
that we can disagree,
uh,
with a spirit of respect and civility
and that over time it is possible for us
to turn the page and develop a new
relationship between our two countries.
Anne's,
that is how to greater moments took
place in 2015 the embassy's reopens in
both countries and in March of 2016 Air
Force One lands then Havana for the
first time in history,
Cuba,
I dunno,
hosted a sitting American presidents
since 1920 [inaudible].
Okay.
See of isolation designed for the Cold
War made little sense in the 21st
century.
The embargo was only hurting the Cuban
people.
Instead of helping them,
it's time to lift the embargo.
It is time now for us to leave the past
behind.
It is time for us to look forward to the
future together.
When for Turo,
they Esperanza
policies towards Cuba.
We're taking over and even though the
embargo laws were technically still
enforced,
the Obama administration managed to find
legal loopholes to allow the relations
between these two countries to be
something close to normal.
When Obama left the White House,
Americans could travel freely to Cuban
immigrants,
could send unlimited money back to the
country.
American companies could invest in Cuba
and even planes of American companies
frequently landed at Jose Marti
international airports because the new
relationship,
well,
it was working,
but then Donald Trump became president
all over the United States.
And as we already mentioned,
everything changed
grump and Cuba.
On the 16th of June,
2017 trump decided to take this new
policy back and he did so in a
neighborhood of Miami called Little
Havana effective.
Immediately I am canceling the last
administration's completely one sided
deal with Cuba.
As soon as he finished his speech,
trump signed guidelines for his so
called new policy with Cuba.
But it's after any 50 year embargo with
the country etiquette hardly be
described as actually being new,
won't completely reverse Obama's
policies.
Many will be maintained,
for example,
the opening of embassies and the
commercial flights between the two
countries.
However,
from now on trips of Americans to Cuba,
we'll,
we'll be limited does it,
they won't be able to go individually
and any relationship with gay Sunday
holding grahib directed by the
governments,
which controls more than 50% of the
Cuban economy will be forbidden.
But don't think that trump has always
had this hard line attitude towards
Cuba.
Quite the opposite.
In fact,
in 1998 he tried to build a hotel on the
islands contradicting the embargo and
did the beginning of 2016 he supported
Obama's new policies towards the
country.
But here revision policy,
we think that trump's out attitude
towards Cuba.
Well,
it can be a mistake.
So let's have a look at exactly why
trump's mistake.
Let's make one thing really clear right
now.
The embargo against Cuba has been eight
total failure.
Yeah.
US embargo,
which is blocked all trade and
investment with Cuba for the past 55
years has not worked.
It is failed to isolate.
The Cuban government failed to regain
any nationalized property and succeeded
in giving an excuse to the Castro
government for its abuses and economic
mismanaged
more than 50 years.
The embargo has been completely useless.
It hasn't accomplished anything,
and on top of that to the Cuban
government has used it as an excuse to
justify their poor economic situation.
Wait just a second here because this is
not the end of it.
Not even close.
Reversing Obama's policies is a mistake
for several reasons.
Importantly,
improved relations with the u s of
Menton better security for the United
States.
Obama signed several important
cooperation agreements and since 2015
given authorities have given information
on drug and human trafficking to the u s
and it's,
on the other hand,
Russia and China have also set their
eyes on the island.
The game.
Russia says it may reopen Soviet era,
military bases,
Cuba
probably.
Imagine what a belief in national
security of the United States this would
be.
This is why making relations more
difficult means nothing more than
forcing the Cuban government to seek
better relations with Moscow or Beijing.
Not exactly a brilliant option for the u
s and there is so much more.
Trump's new policy will only damage to
the interests of many American companies
as well as put at risk,
the major changes that are taking place
on the islands.
How is Cuba changing
fins?
Raul Castro came to power.
He has admitted that Cuban a change of
direction and that the Cuban model
simply is not working.
Some people were saying that he wants to
emulate China,
be open to the world that maintain
control.
The truth is that up until now changes
have been scarce and slow,
but even so,
these changes could be felt and now the
Venezuela can no longer help the
islands.
These changes have become more and more
urgent.
So now let's have a look at what's been
happening since 2011 when reforms took
place.
Sims freelance entrepreneurship was made
a lot easier since 2011 the number of
self employed workers in Cuba is four
times larger.
It's Dave.
The number exceeds half a million
workers.
The government has also allowed private
farming for small farmers and
restaurants and small tourism businesses
growing and spreading across the
country.
The bottom is openness.
Well,
it certainly helps this process.
For example,
almost all private businesses in Cuba
are working off money coming in from
abroad.
Abby and b already has 22,000
apartments,
homes or rooms available in Cuba.
Further,
we shouldn't forget about less tangible
things like the exchange of ideas,
mutual knowledge,
and the strengthening of the private
sector.
Every dollar left in the hands of cab
drivers,
hotel workers,
waitresses and valleys.
It's a show of what awaits Cubans if
they reject socialism,
US Senator Rand Paul,
take a look at China and compare the
country as it is today to the country.
It was during Mao's time since the
country opened itself up to the wells.
Hundreds of millions of people have left
poverty behinds.
Yes,
China like Cuba,
it's still a terrible dictatorship is
thanks to that open policy the Chinese
have today more freedom as a better
standard of living than they've ever had
before.
The short of the matter is that the
embargo policy,
while it's fails and trump's insistence
in going back to this,
is North's going to achieve anything
that the weakening of security in the
United States lead to further poverty in
Cuba and prevent the changes that are
happening on the islands.
In February of 2018 at Castro was going
to leave power,
and this is not the moment for the u s
to take a step
that's in order to
define his decision.
And trump says he wants to defend human
rights,
which is nice.
Don't you think it's a bit hypocritical
to defend the Cuba's embargo while at
the same time he hugs the leaders of
Saudi Arabia?
I mean a human rights not important,
less important.
10 Republicans have also criticized this
course changed with Cuba
policy change that diminishes the
ability of Americans to travel freely to
Cuba is not in the best interests of the
United States or the Cuban people.
US Senator Jeff Flake.
Now we'd really love to know what you
think.
Please leave us your comments below and
feel free to answer the survey.
Should Donald Trump reverse Obama's
policies towards Cuba.
So I really hope you did enjoy this
video,
and please do hit,
like if you did,
and don't forget to subscribe if you
haven't already.
We've got brand new videos every Monday
and every Thursday,
and don't forget to check out our
friends at the reconsider media podcast
where they provided the vocals in this
episode that are not mine.
And there's always,
I'll see you in the next video,
right?
Oh Wow.
So Nice joke so much.