Here's a quick question and by now you
know the rules,
please don't google it or wikipedia it's
or whatever and the question is what do
you know about Armenia?
What do you really know about this
remote country located in the caucus's
region out?
Because Armenia has some very
interesting traits.
For example,
it was the first Christian country in
all of history.
It's a chess well power I didn't even
has its own alphabet is another thing
that you might not know about.
This country inside of the country is
not really sure how to say this,
but essentially there's another country
in that.
This country is the self constituted
republic of odd sack,
formerly known as an Al Gore Cara back.
You owe that rights we're talking about,
it's a republic that isn't recognized by
any other country in the world but which
proclaimed its independence in 1991 and
has its own governments' parliaments
constitution and even its own armed
forces.
You'll see except for a passport with
which they can travel the world.
They have everything of course,
this curious republic citizens,
I'm sort of [inaudible].
They all have an Armenian passports
because this country is a close ally of
Armenia.
You see,
during the Soviet period at this
territory was an odd blast and
autonomous province of the asthma,
Shani,
Soviet socialist republic,
but when the Soviet Union collapsed it
and the government decided that it
wanted to belong to Armenia,
which led to a long four year water
caused thousands of death.
Bye.
Oh,
interesting.
Side note here.
Have you ever noticed in history how
many wars have happened simply over
eight tiny piece of lambs?
Let's stay on topic for today.
Maybe that's something we'll talk about
in the future.
Now,
most would agree that Armenia has
absolutely everything required to dazzle
a politics.
Addicts as of course,
everything required for us to talk about
it right here on visual politic.
One comes re inside another one and
recent war in 2016 a huge diaspora,
a democratic revolution,
and even the potential to be a headache
for Mr Vladimir Putin himself.
So listen up.
Yeah,
with no see access,
a location surrounded by huge mountains
and less than 3 million inhabitants,
I believe you are,
that we can call Armenia a pretty remote
place.
Okay.
If
we had to briefly describe this country,
we would say that it's not far off from
the typical Hollywood portrayal of the
former Soviet republic.
Of course,
they want to like Hollywood.
They don't have a rebel military,
and they certainly don't have a desire
to return to communism.
But the truth is that this country has
many,
many problems.
See,
Armenia gained its independence in
September of 1991 and today,
27 years later,
unemployment surpasses 20% one in every
three citizens' lives in poverty.
Public debt has multiplied by four in
the last decade alone,
infrastructure is falling apart,
and on top of all of that,
they have a serious emigration.
Yes,
you heard that,
right?
Emigration,
you see,
it's estimated that there are about 12
million Armenians around the world,
but only 3 million of them actually live
in Armenia.
Therefore,
we're talking about one of the largest
diasporas in the entire world and only
one out of every five Armenians lives in
Armenia itself,
not,
it wasn't astonishing enough.
Every year on average,
40,000 Armenians leave the country and
in many cases they simply never return.
Worst of all,
things do not seem to be improving jack
out,
for example,
the evolution of foreign investments in
recent years,
but at this point you might be
wondering,
well,
why are things going quite so badly?
Well,
div you at one of the reasons is
certainly corruption ends.
The huge amounts of power that oligarchs
in the country possess.
You See,
in the last 20 years,
the Republican Armenian party,
Hey,
theoretically sends a rise in pro market
party.
That's really just a huge club of
oligarchs,
has tons of the country's politics into
a network of interests and privileges.
Let's put it another way.
For two entire decades,
if you wanted to do business in Armenia
joining this party,
it was almost a mandatory step and if
you were a foreign up dropping by wasn't
a bad idea or either.
However,
just hold on a moment here,
because in April of 2018 Armenian says,
well,
enough is enough.
And do you know what they did?
Well,
they held a revolution in the streets.
Check this out.
The revolution.
10 disastrous.
He has empowered after exhausting his
maximum number of mandates,
president's seg socks,
young tried to copy Putin's strategy and
get elected as prime minister
to do this.
He proposed a reform that basically
pasta president's main powers onto the
prime minister.
Say,
what do you think it happens at this
point?
It's all we talking about a smart
maneuver to stay in power or rape.
Leighton's mockery to all Armenians.
Well,
the have you,
uh,
it was very,
very clear to the people of this
country.
The presidents,
he was laughing at them.
He could rig the elections,
uses power at will and that's big
oligarchs use the government to get
rich.
But this,
this was too much off to 10 years of
presidents,
segs,
terrible managements.
This was beyond the joke and the
Armenians,
they did not accept it.
The 13th Nicole,
passion young,
a journalist and opposition deputy and
the Armenian parliaments could lead a
protest mobilization.
Yeah,
Si.
But at the beginning,
very few people join this protest,
but in a matter of days,
things changed.
A great deal.
On April the 16th for large groups of
students join the protest and four days
later on Friday,
April the 20th the movement had already
concentrated and Yara van,
the country's capital with tens of
thousands of people appearing.
Yeah.
The government's,
which up until then had seen the
demonstrations is a small nuisance,
began to get rather nervous.
What do you think they did at this
point?
Well,
they did what?
Tyron,
Steve,
they're rested the main leaders of these
completely peaceful demonstrations,
including their leader,
Nicholas Passion Yan,
they also announced that the police
would disperse the protests rallies by
force and without any consideration.
Yeah.
At this point,
you might think that,
well,
that was the end of the movement,
right?
Well,
in fact,
no,
just the opposite happens.
It was the point of no return from that
moment.
More than 200,000 people in a country.
A few of them,
3 million inhabitants took to the
capitol streets,
the country.
It was paralyzed work centers,
schools and universities.
They all closed.
The police faced with such a massive
concentration of people.
Well,
they decided to do absolutely nothing.
So all of this encouraged more and more
people to join in a completely peaceful
and really quite happy protest.
Finally,
Armenia citizens had stood up and said,
enough's enough.
The velvet revolution is underway.
And what was the results?
Wow.
Pm on Monday,
April the 23rd just 10 days after the
protests began,
the president announced his resignation.
A few weeks later,
our passion,
Yann himself,
the protests leader,
a journalist too.
In recent years,
it's suffered an attempted attack and
had been in prisons for confronting the
governments had now been appointed prime
minister.
Yes.
It was a pretty crazy few weeks from
opponents of prisoner and from prison up
to the governments.
All in just a few days.
Thing is why does society stabs up to
demand freedom,
democracy,
and justice?
It's kind of hard to stop them.
I mean he now has a chance to change its
course and to face the oligarchs and
ends the widespread corruption that's
been consuming the country.
We have
a new Armenia now where each investment
will be protected and no investment will
be threatened any longer and he called
Pacinian.
Tara for group is one of the largest
companies in the sugar trade,
but this company is forbidden to import
sugar to Armenia.
We can to allow them to do this as well
as allow other companies and we will
definitely it.
There should be no
monopolies in Armenia.
Nicole Pacinian,
Armenian prime minister,
let's hold on for just a moment because
it's certainly not going to be easy for
one because the Republican Party is
still controls congress and it's
representative of several ready status
that they won't resign or make it easy
for the new prime minister and that's an
old old as if that wasn't enough apart
from their own internal problems.
Armenia as two other important
challenges and to one of them is
Vladimir Putin's,
Russia,
Russia and usury threats.
Moscow has such a huge amount of control
over Armenia is economy,
defense and foreign policy.
Many analysts speak openly about the
kind of defacto occupation without
giving any further and the Armenian city
of [inaudible],
the Russian army has right next to the
Turkish border and important military
base with more than 5,000 soldiers,
Mig 29 aircrafts as 300 anti aircraft
missile system.
Yeah,
but it isn't just a military issue to a
large extent.
The country also depends on the
remittances sentence cut by more than 2
million Armenians who are currently
living in Russia.
I in addition,
the Russian giant is its main commercial
partner and completely controls their
energy supply.
I mean,
check this out.
What does crude in Armenia is something
unnatural?
It is next to Iran,
a major exporter of gas,
but it imports it's gas from Siberia as
a result of agreements that do little
more than legalize Armenia's occupation.
Indeed,
under the terms of those accords,
you're Yvonne can't make a deal with
Tehran and less Moscow.
Oh,
agrees.
Ruben [inaudible],
the editor of the Russian service of the
one in.am Internet portal.
The fact is that so far Vladimir Putin
has had very good relations with the
government and do you all know that
these kinds of revolutions,
they don't exactly thrilled Pearson,
so there's a warning on the table here.
Do not pay too much attention to the
seductive calls of the European Union of
the United States.
Certainly the 5,000 Russian soldiers
stationed in Armenia certainly help put
this message from Moscow across buts.
That is not all.
There is also another huge threat here.
Remember the republic of outs like that.
I mentioned her right at the beginning
of the video.
Well sorts of a protectorate of Armenia
in such way this Azerbaijan and
considers it to be an occupied
territory.
Indeed,
they've had no qualms about expressing
their intention to reconquer it and
tear.
It must be said,
the confrontations ons unusual.
Amazon even relatively recently in 2016
hard confrontations took place that four
days until Vladimir Putin demanded a
ceasefire,
it will be asleep.
The risk exists,
especially because Azerbaijan has oil
and gas that you,
that means money.
To give you an idea as a bit as John's
military budget is as big as the
Armenian governments in higher budgets.
So if one day Russia decides to wash its
hands,
Armenia could certainly get into a lot
of trouble.
Anyway.
That is how things stand in the country
today.
But now it's your turn.
Have you even heard of the Republic of
art sac?
Well,
leave your answer in the comments
section below as well as in this survey,
and I really hope you enjoyed this
video.
Please do hit that like button if he
did,
and don't forget to subscribe to our
channel for brand new videos.
Also,
don't forget to check out our friends at
the reconsider media podcast.
They provided the vocals in this episode
that are not mine,
and as always,
thank you for watching.
[inaudible].