Isn't her douse the trade war is one of
the hottest topics in international
politics,
payroll,
visual,
politic.
We've already spoken about the
consequences that this trade wall may
have,
which may already be having.
However we should explore requestion.
Many of you have already asked,
especially through our patrion page,
which is essential for analyzing this
entire matter.
Why does the United States have some
shot at launch?
Trade deficits,
indeed this gigantic deficits,
the past $550 billion dollars in 2017,
and most importantly,
how serious is it and how can it be
fixed?
While some of you might be thinking,
well,
that's easy,
there's a trade deficit because the
United States imports more than it
exports among other things because of
the evil unfair competition that has de
industrialized the country.
If we punish imports,
the trade deficit will decrease,
right?
I mean after all,
this is the stance of the White House
president trump.
Well,
just a moment here because things aren't
anywhere near as simple as this.
Listen up the easy equation
one,
choose,
magnify and report problem,
steps in place,
a number on the table that we can all
visualize.
Step three,
creates ends blaming enemy,
whether it's real or not,
it doesn't really matter.
Step four,
one,
every one of the consequences of this
problem and finally ends with a simple
and electoral remedy.
That is also false.
Folks,
these are the steps for creating a
populist political discourse,
a discourse that at the moment of truth
maybe worth absolutely nothing but will
certainly help you win elections.
Well,
that's exactly what the White House is
doing with the aim of winning votes.
They have created a political discourse
that so to speak,
is fundamentally based on eight,
three elements.
Equation,
but do not worry.
This has nothing to do with maths,
at least not entirely.
Seven's the trade deficit causes
terrible damage.
Seconds elements.
This damages due to the other countries,
unfair competition,
especially China and third,
the threat due to the other countries,
bad behavior and the US as industry and
power is falling apart.
However,
folks,
discourse is one thing and the reality
is quite different.
To magnify the problem,
Donald Trump's commercial advises us
again and again about the negative
impacts that this whole trade deficits
has on the North American economy today,
so they use the accounting entity that
you're seeing on the screen right now,
which is one of the formulas used to
calculate the GDP,
the US GDP equals consumption plus
investment plus public spending,
plus exports minus imports.
I mean there's really economics 101
here.
Well the fact is that seeing it this way
makes it look like the trade deficit is
causing a huge amount of damage to the U
s economy.
And of course if the difference between
exports and imports decreases,
then the GDP would increase prosperity
for everyone.
Easy,
right?
Well hold on a second because this all
implies simplifying things to the point
where any resemblance to reality is
purely coincidental.
So why do I say this?
Well,
that's because relations with the rest
of the world have a lot and I mean a lot
of influence on the other sections that
make up the GDP.
Are you listening
at the end of the day when a foreigner
invests in the United States?
So when US companies buy raw materials,
capital goods,
or intermediate goods,
the effects on the economy,
it's not exactly negative,
it's quite the opposite.
Actually.
If for example,
all these goods become expensive because
of tariffs,
then companies lose competitiveness.
Heroin,
visual politic.
We've already talked,
for example,
about how terrorists have caused Harley
Davidson to move its processes to Europe
in a similar way,
more expensive import products,
which also affects the retail sector.
So that in the end,
the relationship of this supposed trade
deficit with the GDP isn't as direct as
it might at first seem.
The second element of political
discourse that the White House uses is
that of unfair competition,
especially in the case of China.
And of course supposedly because of
Beijing's bat actions,
China's goods and services deficit alone
exceeds $300,000,000,000
per year.
And that's when from things,
well,
let's see if we decrease China's trade
deficit,
then problem solved,
right?
Well folks,
things,
they don't actually work that way
either.
First,
this unfair competition is at the very
least questionable.
China has been blamed for manipulating
its currency and that's just not really
true.
In fact,
it's actually the opposite.
In recent years,
the Chinese yuan has risen a lot against
the dollar and do you know what happened
to the trade deficit with China?
Went to Beijing,
didn't devalue its currency to export
more or they shot up?
Well,
in reality,
the US a trade deficit with East Asia in
terms of manufactured goods,
has been more or less constant since the
mid nineties.
What has changed is that what ones came
from Taiwan or Japan among others now
comes directly from China and it's
because it's a great assembly center and
that's precisely what fattens the US
trade deficit with China quite so much.
And regarding that last point is the one
about deindustrialization and loss of
competitiveness due to unfair
competition.
Well,
it isn't true either.
US exports,
which remains the second largest
exporter in the world are at record,
just like industrial production.
Check this out,
I'm sorry,
but China isn't devouring the American
economy.
Just a second then.
If trump's arguments aren't true about
the entire United States trade deficit,
why is that such an imbalance?
What are the real reasons for it?
Well,
listen to this,
the real reasons you may be surprised to
find out,
but what caused the US trade deficit
wasn't any country's unfair competition.
This time the fault is all at higher.
Yes,
leaving the theories that speak of evil
Chinese schemes to destroy the West
might be less exciting,
but I'm sorry.
It's just the way things are.
The commercial whole is due to the low
savings rate in the United States.
The United States dollar is a reserve
currency which makes it highly demanded
and I have a values and then there's the
huge amounts of capital that comes to
the United States every year from
abroad.
For example,
from China as we are going to see this
is what explains why the United States
spent more than 40 years.
We have a trade deficit without the
economy's suffering.
Forty years in a row can,
assuming more than it produces because
folks,
trump always talks about the trade
balance but never talks about the
financial balance and that's the trap.
$800,000,000,000
a year trade deficit with other nations
unaccepted.
They send the Mercedes,
they sent bmw,
they send everything
absolutely.
Last game
and economic law that the US president
seems to be unfamiliar with the balance
of payments which measures the monetary
transactions of a country with the
exterior is always in equilibrium in a
system of floating exchange rates like
the one that exists nowadays.
Allow me to explain that a bit further.
When there's a trade deficits,
it's basically compensated by capital or
financial account surpluses,
which more or less reflect the balance
between the capital that arrives in the
country and what leaves it.
That's the money that comes in and the
money that goes out.
A persistent current account surplus is
always balanced out by a capital account
deficit.
It's one of the eternal laws of
economics like gravity and physics.
Conrad poot sear a reporter at the real
deal.
Look at what happens precisely with the
United States balance of payment
s.
As you can
see,
the trade deficit is offset by surpluses
in the financial balances.
Now,
does this mean that a country can buy
whatever it wants abroad without limits?
Well,
no,
obviously not.
It can only important if it manages to
finance or for.
It's important.
We have capital that comes from abroad,
otherwise first its currency would
depreciate a lot,
say pure law of supply and demand is
high demand for foreign currency and
offer local currency,
and then eventually the foreign currency
reserves of the central bank would dry
up on leashing and exchange crisis.
This is something that in Latin America,
especially in Argentina,
is very well known.
Well.
All right,
so what happens in the U s case?
Well,
America is the greatest refuge for
capital on the entire planet.
Therefore,
every year,
huge amounts of capital and so the
country practically half of the world's
savings spent investing in this country,
either his loans direct foreign
investment all by buying shares on this,
etc.
Have you noticed,
for example,
the impressive run that the snp 500 has
had over the last nine years?
Well,
it's precisely that enormous capital
flow arriving every year to the United
States that allows americans to consume
more than they produce,
which despite in carrying commercial
deficits for more than 40 consecutive
years,
has led the country to practically
always find employments and record
levels of exports and industrial
production.
Considering tHat we can understand
things like this,
whether it's Japan in the 19 eighties,
Germany,
and the two thousands or China in recent
years,
countries that invest heavily in the New
York real estate market also tend to
have a massive trade surplus with the
United States.
Conrad puts sierra,
a reporter at the real deal.
Basically thanks to the capital that
comes from abroad to the United States
can afford to consume more than it
produces,
so in addition to exporting goods and
services,
the United States also export's
financial securities.
This is the key,
but wait,
does this need that?
The fiscal deficits combi reduced
actually not at all.
How to decrease the commercial
set.
As you can see,
sometimes things aren't as they seem at
fest.
Having a trade deficit doesn't have to
be bad.
After all,
the ultimate economic objective must be
to improve living conditions.
That is the ability to consume more and
the better goods and services.
Yes,
a bulky and continuing trade deficits.
It can have some drawbacks.
For example,
assumes more risk or risk that capital
will stop flowing towards the country,
which could lead to a huge crisis.
And for another,
it favors debt growth.
The country flooded with money from
abroad.
That means abundant and cheap money and
he doesn't want money.
So let's continue with the key question
here.
How can Donald Trump decrease the us
trade deficit?
Well,
there are mainly three options too that
we should set aside and it's one that's
highly recommend.
Those we did recommends would be either
agreeing to devalue the dollar and stop
it from being the hegemonic currency of
the world with the federal reserve.
So importance would be much more
expensive and nobody would want to take
their money to thiS couNtry or the u.
S could restrict the caPital coming from
abroad,
for example,
through taxes.
Of course,
that in the long run is also going to be
a disaster
because the other option,
the one that we'd recommend is consuming
less,
saving more favoring productive
investments.
That way fewer foreign lines would be
demanded and much more wealth would be
generated so that it's in percentage
terms over the gdp.
Trade deficits would be much smaller.
And to achieve this goal,
stopping the government's growing fiscal
hold would be a fantastic idea.
But trump,
despite what he's saying,
is going in the opposite direction,
it would also be a fantastic option to
allow american companies to fill the
nearly 6 million vacant jobs that the
north american economy suffers from
today by bringing in professionals from
abroad.
However,
protectionist policies don't work first
because all the other countries tend to
respond to tariffs with their own
tariffs,
which reduces imports,
but also exports and most importantly,
because the increased costs led by
terrorists make the United States and
less attractive country to invest in,
and that's in the longterm.
It's a really bad thing.
Perhaps folks,
the strongest proof that american
companies need to be open to the world
is found in the trump family itself.
See ivanka trump,
the president's daughter and white house
special advisor,
has just closed her clothing and
accessories brands.
Ivanka made this decision after
suffering a steep drop in sales and a
huge amount of criticism for some
alleged contradictions.
And do you know why she was criticized?
Well,
can you guess where she wants to making
products?
I mean,
surely in the United States rights.
Well,
no,
actually wrong.
The correct answer was China.
Most of our products are made in China
and also in countries like Vietnam and
Indonesia has ivanka trump has self been
an accomplice of the evil entities that
have been attacking the United States.
Well,
I'm just going to leave that.
That,
so I really hope you enjoyed the video.
Please do hit that like button if you
did and don't forget to subscribe for
brand new videos.
Polesafe.
Don't forget to check out our friends at
the reconsider media podcast.
He provided the vocals in this episode
that we're not mine falsely.
this channel is possible because of
patriarchy ends.
our patrons on the platform of
patriotic,
that's a lot of peas and another one is
please do consider joining them and
supporting our mission of providing
independent political coverage.
And as always,
thank you for watching.
$800,000,000,000
a year trade deficit with other nations.
Unacceptable.
They send the mercedes,
they sent bmws,
they send everything.
We tax them practically nothing.
We can't send them.