Does he know there is a country in South
America when most of its population are
of Indian origin and where the official
language is English.
Now,
if you don't know which country I'm
talking about,
don't worry because this is one of the
least known countries in the region,
and to be fair,
the media doesn't really pay that much
attention to it,
so really small as a country that the
media don't talk about very much.
Well,
that sounds like the perfect ingredients
for a visual politic.
Talking about Guyana that owns British
colony,
who didn't get independence until 1966.
Interestingly at the moment of
independence,
both the government's [inaudible]
popular opinion was generally in favor
of turning guy on it into a socialist
country.
It was this mindset which gave the
It's Pinto ask official name,
the Cooperative Republic of Guyana,
but let's focus on the country today.
Diana is one of the poorest countries in
South America and violence rates that
are some of the highest in the entire
region,
and that's saying a lot.
In fact,
if going on,
it is known for anything,
it would be for its place in the
international supply of cocaine.
Oh,
and also for having one of the highest
suicide rates in the world,
so not exactly brilliant things.
Now,
with all of this information,
you'd be forgiven for not being
optimistic about the future of this
Caribbean country,
but they may be about to get a lot
luckier.
Oh yeah.
Signs pointed to.
Guiana becoming an oil power for there's
only being this small republic with a
population of about 750,000
inhabitants has already got the
attention and dollars of multinational
companies such as Exxon or
that's
after several years exploring the area.
On January the 13th,
2017 things to powerful oil companies
announced the discovery of water they
think could be one of the most
significant oil and gas reserves found
decades.
Oil reserves have been found in deep
waters in the scene.
Menzel under the coastal waters of
Deanna early calculations estimate that
the amount of oil which can be exploited
in the country is no less than 4,000
million barrels and many experts from
this could be a much larger quantity,
so it seems that this country holds a
huge fortune just off it's shores.
That's the question really is how much
is this all really worth considering the
price of oil nowadays,
we're talking about roughly
$200,000,000,000,
so leaving other natural resources
asides and considering only petrol.
This would result in the equivalent of
$250,000
per citizen.
And it's important to note that the oil
reserves can be much bigger than the
early calculations in.
Yeah,
no,
it is true that oil exploitation is
expensive and requires enormous
investments,
but this could still be the first step
in a new era of prosperity 40 on it.
So far of the oil companies I've
mentioned Exxon mobile and has have
committed to investing $900,000,000
a year in Ghana over the next few years.
The government is investing to with
plans to start exporting oil in 20,
20.
This means Guiana,
it could be on the cusp of becoming one
of the greatest economic developments
that South America has ever.
Yes,
Ghana,
that poor violence country.
You could become the kinds of country
which other people in South America who
are unemployed might look at and think,
I want to change my life.
I once opportunities,
I want to go to Ghana.
Ghana could become that big hope for
many.
I'm employed South American people.
Nevertheless,
before they start packing a,
we have to say that it's not going to be
that easy.
The road ahead is going to be fraught
with difficulties.
Yeah,
with Venezuela,
much better.
The oil exploration is happening in
areas that have been claimed by
Venezuela and is the part they have
claimed is not exactly small Madora who
considers the region known as Guiana
asset.
[inaudible] burned to be vast and this
region represents more than 70 percent
of
surface,
so essentially Venezuela is claiming the
entire country as their own and as if
this wasn't bad enough and other area
which makes up seven percent of its
territory is claimed by their neighbors
in Suriname.
If their neighbors had their way,
Guiana would have been carved up and
split between them a long time ago.
The thing is this conflict over
territory seemed to have been forgotten
for years.
This was likely a consequence of the
good relations that the government's
kept with Cuba,
a country that holds a lot of influence
over this part of the world.
It was also likely because Venezuela
wanted the support of organizations such
as Caricom,
the Caribbean Community of which Guiana
is a member.
So now you might be wondering,
is Agi on a Caribbean country or is it a
South American country?
Well,
it's sort of both geographically
speaking,
the country is in South America,
but politically,
culturally and socially speaking.
Guiana is a Caribbean country.
In fact,
Guiana was one of the countries which
used to benefits from petro an
initiative by Hugo Chavez that we're
supplying cheap,
high quality oil to those countries
which were deemed France,
but it all changed when on May the 11th
of 2005,
the left wing governments of the
People's Progressive Party lost the
general election to a coalition headed
by their new president,
David granger.
A man who was closer to Washington and
who to end once and for all the claims
coming from
way less,
it was at that moment that the long
ignored conflict to defrost it and
things really started to heat up.
It's still carrying a monkey on its
back.
That monkey is the unbearable burden of
an oppressive and obnoxious Cleveland on
land and sea space.
Now,
the conflict is in the hands of the
United Nations,
but whatever the solution might be,
if there is any,
it's important to be aware of this
threat to the potential prosperous
future after gone.
Racial conflict.
Important risk is the recurrence.
Racial conflicts in Guyana,
which is a continuous presence in the
countries media.
Deanna is a complex country
demographically around 50 percent of its
population is of Indian origin,
while 40 percent is of African origin.
Those are two big groups who are not
exactly on the friendliest of terms.
In fact,
the black minority claims that for years
the Indian majority has obtained
privileges from the government and
always got that way.
This is triggered recurrence waves of
violence.
Luckily the situation seems to have
improved.
In fact is the winning coalition,
governments is quite multiracial.
There is still the possibility that
further internal conflict will flare up
in any case,
not only does this new governments have
an opportunity to overcome decades of
conflict,
it's once and for all,
but it's also being looked to to find
violence and corruption in the country,
something that Ganas certainly needs to
be one of the most corrupt countries in
the world according to Transparency
International.
So the new government has quite a few
major tasks ahead of them,
oil exploitation,
as well as the fight against corruption
and criminality and the country.
The thing is,
if they achieved their goals,
Guiana will attract great attention and
me become one of the richest countries
in South America,
but this will only be if they use their
resources well,
but the question is will that happen?
And it's certainly a big question.
So we've given you our opinion,
here are visual politics and now we'd
love to know what you think.
Do you think Guiana will successfully
take advantage of their newly discovered
oil and what position do you think
Venezuela should adopt?
As always,
leave your comments below and I do hope
that you found this video interesting.
If you did,
please do hit that like button below and
don't forget to subscribe to this
channel for brand new videos every
Monday and every Thursday,
and if you're looking for something else
to watch right now,
why not check out our video on why
Switzerland is quite so wealthy that you
can do that.
It's by taking,
let's say.
Yeah,
and as always,
I'll see you in the next year.
Yeah.