It's the world's largest population,
the second largest economy.
It has one of the largest multicurrency
reserves,
the second largest military budget,
the number one trade power globally,
but it's better known as the world's
factory.
These are just a few of the reasons that
China has become a superpower.
Now,
if you're a regular viewer of visual
politic,
you'll know that we've done several
videos on this country.
We've discussed it's foreign policy,
it's debt issues.
We've discussed how it's companies have
grown all around the world as well as
its political system.
We've discussed the Macau or Hong Kong.
Suffice to say,
we've talked a lot about
no
and we have done so because we believe
that nowadays it is impossible,
but as well as pretty inconvenient to
discuss international politics without
keeping in mind this huge global player
are there.
In all of those previous videos,
you could say that we've skipped a
really important question and that
question is really,
how powerful is China today?
Well,
the good news is that's exactly the
question we're going to be answering in
this video and we're going to do it from
three different perspectives,
military,
economic and political,
and look,
even though many people's date,
think of China as the second most
important global power.
Not everyone agrees with this,
not at all.
In fact,
some experts believe that when China
potential is carefully examined,
well,
it's not actually all that powerful,
but then again,
there are plenty of other experts.
You stated that Chinese power is growing
at an incredibly fast rate and that the
21st century is most certainly going to
be China's century.
Now,
before we get started,
we should establish one thing first and
that's what exactly do we mean by power?
Is it to have a lot of economic
resources and what about a big army or
maybe it's actually to do with natural
resources?
Well,
social scientists consider political
power to be found in leverage and
influence.
That is essentially saying the power is
the ability to shape and condition the
events and actions of others.
So the question now becomes,
what is China's power?
What do they have in order to leverage
and influence other countries?
Well,
as I said a moment ago,
in this video,
we're going to examine the three main
areas that most often deliver that
power,
and that's weapons,
economics and politics bands.
Well,
how about we kick things off with war
dragons strength?
Yeah.
It isn't exactly easy to quantify
anything military strength of a country.
It depends on several different factors.
You have to consider how well protected
the country is.
If its soldiers are well trained on how
modern it's arsenal is,
as well as a whole bunch of other
factors.
However,
despite these different factors,
we can still say the spending on defense
is usually the best way to measure the
military potential of a nation further.
When we analyze the money a country
spends on its army,
we also get some other relevant
information like how important is a
strong military?
It's the governments.
Sorry.
According to the official figures in
2016,
China spent around $146,000,000,000 on
defense,
but as you can probably imagine,
China's government is not a shiny
example of transparency in some of the
sources.
Indicate is that the number could be
closer to 226 billion anyway,
whichever number is correct.
We do know that China has multiplied
it's defense spending by five in the
last decade and it is today the second
largest spending country in the world
when it comes to defense spending,
trailing only behind the United States.
Of course,
five times though it's a significant
increase in such a short period of time.
However,
this hasn't been disproportionately
compared to the country's GDP.
Indeed spending has been closely related
to the economic growth of the country
having been kept within two percent of
the overall GDP.
That is not the end of it.
If we look at the public budget,
we can see how defense expenses have
dropped from 12 percent of the public
spending in 2001 to a listen more than
six percent in 2016.
And can you guess what that means?
Well,
it means that China has made less of an
effort when it comes to spending than
the US.
When you consider GDP and public
spending as reference points.
So take a look at this chart.
For instance,
we already know two things.
First,
the Chinese military spending will keep
growing at the same level of the economy
does,
which will gradually shrink that
difference with the US seconds.
We know that military spending is only a
small bird into the Chinese economy.
We could say it is a sustainable
amounts,
and if the government needed to reduce
it,
the governments could manage to do so
without too many problems.
However,
it's now important that we talk about
military capability because when it
comes to Chinese military power,
rob,
certain limitations,
the dragon lacks dryness potential to
you.
Operate military force outside of their
borders is actually pretty low.
Unlike the United States,
China does not have any military bases
abroad,
with the exception of Djibouti,
as we will see you later on.
It also doesn't have that many allies,
a verb already logistic network or
satellites for launch deployments.
That actually doesn't have much at all
and then you must consider that there
are also pretty inexperienced.
I mean it's been 40 years since the last
time Chinese troops engaged in.
That's what
does that mean that China is some sort
of paper tiger?
Well,
no,
absolutely not.
New resources are allowing Beijing to
make important changes and investments.
China's growing military potential has
changed the balance of forces in Asia
and the People's Liberation Army is now
capable of conducting operations on a
global scale.
China is making changes.
They have reduced their military by
300,000 soldiers since 2015 and so
focused on the military upgrades and
their ability to operate abroad.
The Chinese army opened its first for a
military base in July of 2017 in the
African country of Djibouti.
Then in 2012 trying to bolt it's first
aircraft carrier from Ukraine and in
2017 they completed their first to
domestic carry up with more to follow is
also investing in missiles and it's air
force has put into service.
It's new generation 20 stealth fighter.
Yes,
it is going to take decades at a minimum
for the Chinese army to come clips to
the American army,
but there is certainly no other country
out that with as much potential as
China,
we all better get used to having to deal
with China.
We're talking about global military
strategy,
the economic power.
There is no way to sustain any political
or military power without economic
capacity,
but there's more to it than that.
Economic power has its own great
potential to influence other governments
and large companies and this is what is
happening.
For instance,
with direct foreign investments,
which is both entering and leaving China
as a pure financial figure amount.
This is not actually very hydrus yes,
but year after year,
this figure has grown and grown.
In a previous visual politic video we
looked at is how in the last few years
Chinese companies have started to invest
money around the world in 2016,
excluding Hong Kong and Macau.
This amount was more than $180 million
dollars.
Thanks to this.
China is gaining influence,
especially in developing countries that
have seen quite the opportunity in this
Chinese,
yeah,
money and just
the same sort of thing with trades,
but he had trying to raise by far the
leading global power and we're not just
talking about Chinese exports here.
We're talking about imports a lot to pay
attention here because Chinese economic
growth has created a more prosperous
middle class everyday.
More than a hundred and 80,000 people
leave poverty behind and become a part
of the middle class that has enough
money to well spent and it's this view
is something that has caused many
multinationals to make China.
Then number one priority.
That is certainly the case of BMW where
one out of every four cars sold by this
company is sold in China.
A country where sales and about 50
percent larger than in the United
States,
but there's still more Asian assembly
lines occupying several countries.
For example,
Vietnam,
they produce one components while the
another is made in South Korea and later
they are all assembled in China.
Vi welds,
great production center in the Asia
Pacific region to hundreds of thousands
of jobs depend on trade with China,
but not everything looks so good.
There are problems too,
especially when it comes to technology,
design and innovation because well,
truth be told,
innovation and creativity usually get on
with dictatorships,
but still things are changing and
investment trade and multinationals are
all things that generate a lot of
influence in
growing political power.
That is political power.
It's often said that China lacks
leadership and further,
that's like the US,
which counseling solid allies all around
the world.
China is some sort of lone wolf.
Now,
this has been said for years,
but do keep in mind that this is all
beginning to change.
China has bet on increasing their
influence on global politics and is
doing that to defend interests that are
increasingly global.
Plan a strategy,
the Chinese are using that large
currency reserves to expand their
influence.
In the last decade alone,
Beijing has loaned money to several
governments and has invested all over
the world from Fiji to Madagascar,
and that is not the end of it.
They've also set up ambitious plans to
achieve their goals.
As an example,
the Asian infrastructure investment
bank,
a financial power controlled by China in
based in Beijing will reduce the
influence of institutions like the World
Bank,
the IMF or the Asian Development Bank.
All of them controlled by Washington to
some extent.
And how about some more examples?
Well,
there's the new silk roads,
the one road,
one belt,
the largest infrastructure project in
the world.
Then there is the China Investment
Corporation,
a sovereign funds that managers more
than $800,000,000,000 and invests in
companies all around the world.
And yes,
we didn't make a mistake there.
That is billion with a b.
So now you might be wondering,
How's China actually had any political
success with this strategy?
Well,
the answer is yes,
they have and that is well demonstrated
in the country of Greece.
China is developing enormous projects in
this country,
like the portal,
the Hellinikon,
they sort of Monaco in the heart,
the baffin.
What's the result of all this wild?
Last June,
Athens vetoed a resolution that condemns
the violation of rights in China and
it's not for the first time anyway.
China is still facing real challenges.
Perhaps the biggest of these is it's
aging population.
I mean,
just have a look at this.
Awesome.
Despite
this,
the influence of China and international
politics will grow quite a lot in the
next few years and China is already a
new superpower as well.
That's our opinion at visual politic and
now we'd love to know yours.
Do you think China is a superpower or
just a flash in the pan and do you think
China should be included in the
international community to a greater
extent?
Well,
as always,
you can leave your answer in the
comments below or in the survey,
and don't forget to hit that like
button.
If you enjoyed this video and subscribe
for new videos every Monday and
Thursday,
further,
do not forget to check it off.
Friends at the reconsider media
podcasts,
they provided the vocals in this video
that we're not mine,
and as always,
thank you for watching.