In the last few years,
there has been growing uncertainty and
concern over what's the future of jobs
will look like,
especially for those who are in
developed countries,
robotics,
Ai,
immigration,
international competition.
They are all hot topics.
Six,
according to some people,
we will have to get used to a future
where a job will be considered a luxury,
a world of unemployment on a massive
scale.
It'll be a world of higher inequality,
of poor working conditions,
and that's just for those who aren't
lucky enough to have it.
Job
is not the west of us.
Most of the people who are foreseen such
a critical situation also claimed this
and less major changes take place and we
try to slow down this frantic
developments.
Our wellbeing will be in serious danger,
certainly if there are not enough jobs,
wealth and production will concentrate
in a reduced but powerful oligarchy of
businessmen and companies.
And this leads to the question,
how will ordinary people make a living
who will pay taxes?
How can the welfare state possibly
survived for with so much
unemployment's?
It all sounds pretty dreary,
doesn't it?
Almost as if we're going to be facing a
terrible storm many year now.
This uncertainty,
it's made it easier for leaders like
Donald Trump or marine le pen,
among others to get a leg up in
politics.
Indeed.
Leaders who say that society is falling
apart and insist that they are the only
ones who can fix it.
Do you tend to do rather well?
Well,
if there is such a thing,
then the only thing we can do is fight
back and it is not just immigration
we're talking about here.
Oh No,
there is so,
so much more.
Amazon is doing great damage tax paying
retailers,
towns,
cities and states throughout the u.
s are being hurt.
Many jobs being lost at real.
Donald trump on twitter,
but hold on just a second because are we
really had such a dark and dreary
future?
Our robots are really going to take our
jobs and destroy the system as we know
it.
And is it true that unless we take
radical action,
we are in serious danger of losing our
jobs?
Well,
in order to answer these questions and
look at what lies beneath these
statements,
we have to pay close attention to what
is currently happening in the world we
live in and especially what is going on
in the greatest and most influential
power on earth.
Yes,
of course,
we're talking about the United States of
America,
the end of employment,
self driving cars,
self learning machinery,
factories without work as intelligent
robots,
less science fiction,
then more science facts every single
day.
And you know this technological wave.
It's just begun.
Nanotechnology,
biotechnology,
genetic engineering and robotics.
They seem to be changing the world as we
know it every day.
These technologies,
multiplying productivity and they can
even replace human work in a report to
the president from 2000 and Sixteen
Council of economic advisors in the
White House calculated that 83 percent
of jobs that were paid less than $20 per
hour would soon potentially be
automated.
In other words,
countries with a faster development in
robotics will be the first to suffer
from high sudden unemployment.
Millions and millions of people will
simply become unemployed,
but the question now has to be,
is this really what the future holds the
future?
I mean it's always uncertain,
but we can already see what's happening
today and compare that to what it's
going to be like in the future.
Robots,
they've already arrived and we can find
them everywhere in today's factories and
if we really dive into the figures,
we see that the evidence shows the exact
opposite of what we might expect.
So just take a look at this chart here.
The countries using the most robots,
other countries with the lowest rates of
unemployment as well.
This it has an explanation.
Sometimes we consider all the jobs that
are lost as a result of this process,
but we ignore the new jobs that are
being created as a result of all of this
automation,
new times,
new jobs.
Up until
now,
the industrial sector is the one when
most robots have been used.
In fact,
some companies like Ford already have
assembly lines made entirely out of
robots having no human workers at all.
Yet,
American industrial production is almost
as high as it has ever been,
and now you must be wondering,
well,
what happens to all the industrial jobs?
Well,
have a look at this.
That's right in the 19 forties,
one of every three jobs in America where
industrial jobs and now the number is
barely one in 12,
which is four times less.
So does this mean that there are no
employment opportunities in the United
States?
Well,
actually,
nothing's further from the truth.
Since the 19 forties,
the US has created more than 86 million
new jobs in the service industry.
This includes transport,
finance,
entertainment,
and so on and so forth.
As a matter of fact,
there has never been so many workers in
this country and while we are
specifically talking about robotics
here,
the impacts of any new technology,
it has a similar effect.
Blockbuster,
which was once the largest video and
video game rental company in America may
have vanished.
Putin exchange.
We have new companies like Netflix or
even youtube and these kinds of
companies.
They generate loads of jobs,
but this is not just happening in
America and it's not just happening with
robots or with video.
Consider the APP industry in Australia.
This new industry has already created
more than 113,000 jobs in one of the
wealthiest countries in the world.
I believe me,
this is not just an Australian
phenomenon in the United States and
deberry mind that this is a new sector
that has been born just a few years ago
with the iphone and it's already created
one point 5 million jobs.
Banks,
supermarkets,
insurance and software companies.
They all want to have their own app and
that means new jobs are being created
all of the time.
Further,
as productivity grows,
normal working hours,
they're reduced,
so thanks to technology will work hours,
which is another bit of great news.
I think for the next 30 years.
People only work four hours a day and
maybe four days a week.
My grandfather worked 16 hours a day in
the farmland and thought he was very
busy.
We work eight hours five days a week and
we think we are very busy.
Jack Ma and finally let's as a little
more detail,
some people like Bill Gates,
they've claimed the robots have taken
jobs that were previously done by
people.
Then therefore they should have to be
paying tax and you know what?
Well,
I'm not so sure about that.
I need robots.
They are just machines.
Simply the more machines and the more
technology we have,
the better we live.
Robots reduce costs and as a consequence
they reduced the price of goods and
this.
It allows consumers to work less and
buying more,
and this is why governments should boost
and encourage investment in technology,
but what is certainly true,
it's the society will have to prepare
for this automation process,
this technological change.
It is coming and it shouldn't be
stopped.
Stop globalization.
Have you who regularly follow up visual
policy will know that trump has
something of an obsession with China,
China,
China.
I love China all the time.
I Love Jack.
It's not just China.
In the last year,
trump is accused Canada,
Mexico,
Japan,
and even South Korea of unfair
competition.
He has also claimed that these countries
are destroying American jobs.
This is why trump wants to renegotiate
trade agreements,
empower protectionist policies,
and if needed,
set import tariffs in industries such as
the steel industry.
It wouldn't be the first president in
the US to pursue this kind of strategy.
We need look no further than that.
George W dot Bush and other Republicans
who set up import terrorists to steel
imports in 2002.
President Bush took some of the broadest
federal action in two decades to protect
a major American industry today,
imposing tariffs of up to 30 percent on
most types of steel imported into the
United States from Europe,
Asia,
and South America,
and truth be told the result,
it wasn't good.
Some studies have estimated that these
steel tariffs resulted in the loss of
more than 200,000 jobs.
Yep.
Not Policy lead to more unemployment's
less competition.
Argentina,
it's another great example.
Protectionism has had exactly the same
results.
That's of course,
last exports also means less drops,
but that's not the end of it.
Now,
it is true that in the last few decades,
industrial offshoring has caused us to
lose many jobs,
but in a way thanks to this,
countries like China have had an
opportunity to develop and Chinese
businesspeople are now eager to invest
in the United States,
seeing it as a safe place to make an
investment in 2016 Chinese companies
invested at $50,
billion dollars in the US and today
these companies have employed directly
and indirectly more than a hundred and
48,000 Americans.
That's nine times more than they were
employing in 2009.
That is indeed the case of this
businessman Mr Wang man who spent in
2014,
$700,000,000 restoring a factory that
General Motors had closed down.
Hi.
And it isn't just Chinese companies,
one in every five Americans is currently
working for foreign companies.
And remember,
as we said before,
never have been so many people working
in the United States.
So the story of globalization being
effected,
destroying our economies.
Well,
it seems like it's just that it's a
story.
Prints are stealing our jobs.
You will
note that this is one of the biggest
issues for people,
especially in the United States.
They're taking our jobs,
they're taking our manufacturing jobs,
they're taking our money,
they're killing us,
Donald Trump.
That is what trump has been saying,
but the reality is that the facts tell a
completely different story.
For instance,
in 2016,
the United States got six Nobel prizes
in science and economics.
All of them were awarded to immigrants.
People born in a different country that
now work at universities in the US and
immigrants.
They tend to be more inclined towards
entrepreneurship as well,
so even though immigration accounts for
50 percent of the workforce in America,
immigrants are involved in creating one
out of every three new companies in the
US,
and those companies are the ones that
are creating the most jobs.
And look,
there are two types of immigrants.
On the one hand,
we've got the illegal immigrants.
They usually work in more physical jobs
or the jobs Americans don't usually once
and on the other hands,
we have legal immigrants.
Half of these immigrants have higher
education.
This is a percentage far higher than
people born in the US.
This type of immigration,
it provides vital brainpower to a
country,
and this is something that countries
desperately meat.
They also have an entrepreneurial
spirits and many of them are responsible
for many successful projects.
Procter and gamble,
Goldman Sachs,
Yahoo,
Google,
Tesla,
att and t,
Intel,
Ebay,
IBM,
Citi Group,
ups,
Oracle,
Amazon,
or even apple or some of the many
companies founded or co founded by
immigrants or the children of
immigrants.
So hopefully you can see that the best
thing about immigration is that not only
does it not steal jobs from Americans,
it actually creates more jobs for them.
So there's a lot of legends when it
comes to predicting the future of our
lifestyles,
but the reality is that the facts simply
don't live up to the fear.
So there are a lot of legends when it
comes to predicting the future of our
lifestyles,
but the reality is that the facts,
they simply don't live up to the fear.
And this is our opinion here,
visual politic,
and now we'd love to know yours.
Aren't you afraid of being replaced by a
robot?
Do leave your answers in the comments
section below as well as in this survey,
and don't forget to subscribe to our
channel for brand new every Monday and
Thursday,
and also do not forget to check out our
friends at the reconsider media podcast.
They provided the vocals in this
episode,
but we're not mine,
and as always,
thanks for [inaudible].