We may not talk much about Indonesia,
but the truth is that this country
matters much more than you probably
think $250 million,
half of them under the age of 30 make up
Indonesia,
the most populous Muslim country on the
planet,
but Indonesia is also one of the most
complicated countries in the wells.
It's like,
allow me to explain.
Indonesia is a huge archipelago.
The consists of more than 17,000
islands covering more than 5,000
kilometers.
That's 3000 miles from end to end.
This is approximately the distance from
London to Afghanistan.
Based on this alone,
you can already imagine the enormous
variety of ethnicities,
cultures,
and languages that have founded this
country.
Also the huge social differences.
For instance,
while these citizens of Jakarta are
almost addicted to twitter,
a fifth of the population doesn't even
have access to electricity.
It didn't issues.
Diversity is not just geographic and
cultural.
Different groups are essentially living
at different points in human history all
at the same time.
Traveling from Jakarta to the Maluku
islands can seem like going back in
time.
Elizabeth [inaudible],
writer,
journalist,
and scientists,
and you can imagine how difficult it can
be to manage a country like this
country,
which by the way,
Barack Obama spent a good part of his
childhood in that right bomb.
His mother married an Indonesian citizen
in 1965 and two years later they moved
to Jakarta.
I feel great affection for the people
here and obviously I have a sister who's
half Indonesian.
My mother lived and worked here for a
long time and so the sights and the
sounds and the memories and all fueled
very familiar.
Barack Obama.
Alright,
okay.
Now some of you might be thinking,
but Simon,
I mean,
why should I care about Indonesia?
what's so special about this country?
Well,
Miss Eight,
despite all of its difficulties,
the Indonesian economy has grown a lot
in recent decades,
and the viewer,
even though it may surprise us,
Indonesia will soon become the largest
Muslim power on the planet and that has
lots and lots of social,
political and economic implications.
You can even notice how people have
changed their way of dressing.
The average age is around 29 to 30
years.
Those young people who have gone out
into the market who are better trained,
create an urban middle class with a huge
dynamism,
and this dynamism is what will change
this country.
Carlos gastone BBV,
a representative in Indonesia.
Well,
you can probably already imagined why we
should care more about Indonesia than we
do,
but before taking a closer look at
what's happening,
he has a bit of history.
Independence.
Stevens in Asia has had two main
protagonists and Suharto.
You see Indonesia is actually a fairly
new country.
It wasn't until 1999 that it gained its
independence from the Netherlands.
Yes.
You had that right.
Indonesia wasn't a British or French
colony.
It was a Dutch colony,
and don't think that gaining their
independence was easy.
Not at all.
Allow me to explain.
Sukarno was an important leader of the
resistance against colonial rule.
In 1927,
he founded the Indonesian Nationalist
Party under this slogan,
one nation,
Indonesia,
one people.
The Indonesian one language Bahasa,
Indonesia.
Mike.
Yeah.
Of course.
As you can imagine,
the Dutch authorities didn't like these
ideas at all,
so Sukarno was persecuted,
detained,
and finally forced into a kind of exile
in Sumatra.
Hey,
imprisonment,
dear viewer,
which saw him released in weld water.
You Buy Japanese troops.
When they occupied Indonesia,
the Japanese themselves joins the
Indonesian nationalists to control the
country
easily.
The fact is that two days off to Japan
surrendered in August of 1945,
it's economy declined.
Indonesia's independence a declaration
that wasn't recognized by the Dutch
authorities indeed far from that,
so they tried to regain power by force
began the Socorro's national revolution
that lasted for years.
Um,
which was very,
very bloody after the birth of the
Republican Indonesia,
we experienced a painful separation
process marked by terrible violence.
These are dark pages of art history,
burt calendars,
Dutch,
former minister of foreign affairs.
To give you an idea,
it is estimated that in just four years,
more than 100,000
Indonesians and 5,000
soldiers lost their lives.
And that is how finally in 1949,
after much much suffering reduction
authorities excepted underrecognized,
Indonesia's independent.
Yeah.
Dictators,
Indonesia,
achieving independent certainly didn't
mean that the country was free over the
following.
Eighteen years.
Economy led Indonesia in an increasingly
authoritarian way under a model that
became known as directed democracy,
and I swear every time you put an
adjective next to the term democracy
usually beads that something is anything
but democratic.
During this time,
all kinds of problems occurred,
the country,
it was really,
really poor.
The economy didn't work and there were
all kinds of rebellions and conflicts as
ethnic conflict,
self-determination,
a conflict with Malaysia and especially
with the Indonesian Communist Party,
first Communist Party and Asia by the
way,
which with China and the Soviet Union
supports became increasingly important
in the car.
True.
See,
Staccato wasn't considered a communist
leader,
but he was a rather socialist.
Nita who didn't mind getting close to
Mao's China and even received support
from the Soviet Union.
This was something that didn't prevent
the Indonesian communist party from
wanting to seize power at all costs.
Right
between all of this pushing and shoving
in 19,
65 and important happens,
call me.
C'Mon disconnected to the Communist
Party.
Prepared a who were interested in why.
Okay,
this events unleashed a brutal
repression against the communist party
that cost the lives of hundreds of
thousands of people and which the army
general Suharto greatly took advantage
of to seize power with support from the
United States.
During the following three decades.
The hotter ruled the country with an
iron fist.
With Washington support,
he launched some economic expansion
measures that were quite successful and
made their growth skyrockets.
However,
it was still a harsh dictatorship and
the state's violence,
political repression and corruption were
tremendously widespread.
So when at the end of the nineties,
the Asian crisis occurred,
the Indonesian economy will,
it collapsed.
The repeat lost 80 percent of its value
against the dollar and poverty
multiplied by four.
Faced with this disaster general
Suharto,
he was forced to leave after almost 50
years of independence and dictatorship
democracy in Indonesia,
I finally had a chance and finally,
after a lot of conflicts because in this
country conflicts that constants,
the first free elections were held in
2004.
Now,
it must be said,
of course,
that since the hottest Indonesia has
experienced a period of change,
political openness,
de-centralization as an economic policy
that is more open to the wells,
but even with all of this,
it is still very highly restricted band
in 2014,
Indonesia's current President Joko
Widodo popularly known as [inaudible]
and usually qualified as the Indonesian
Barack Obama won the elections.
Can we promise to liberalize the country
boost growth over seven percent per year
and lay the foundations for Indonesia to
become an economic and political power?
Indeed the largest Muslim power in the
world.
That moments,
my friends expectations west
skyrocketing the international media
spoke of Indonesia,
has the country of the few chat bots.
Wait just a minute because since then
some things changed so
enough.
Go Widodo President.
Between two worlds we know there's a
rival was a great revolution.
A great breath of fresh air,
if you will,
draw a week,
was the first non military or political
elites does in the country to take
power.
Social networks such as facebook,
twitter,
and youtube played an absolutely key
role and the truth is that the new
president started off his to make
Indonesia become a much more competitive
country on the right foot.
See arrived in power among other
measures.
Joker,
we greatly decrease.
Stands,
eliminated several subsidies and
allocated that money about $40,
billion dollars by the way,
to try and solve one of the country's
greatest problems.
Then lack of infrastructure.
Sure,
something that makes transporting goods
between the countries islands even more
expensive than importing a container
from Europe and not only that,
the president has also launched several
programs to decrease bureaucracy and
regulations,
which is another pretty big problem in
Indonesia.
Let me give you an example.
I mean,
check this out.
Indonesia's regulations and
bureaucracies are so strong that the.
For example,
if companies like Intertek,
Zara or h and m wants to open a new
store in Jakarta,
they can't do it directly.
They need a local franchise.
Yes,
it's more.
Many sectors are simply closed to
foreign investments and the government
has to assume a large part of the weight
it.
Construction companies are a nautical
industries,
shipyards and many communication
companies are still all state owned
company.
Yes,
it is.
The joker is also promoting opening
special economic tourism and industrial
areas and just launched a medical
insurance model that has covered more
than half of the population,
so right now I imagine it's all sounding
pretty darn good too.
You Weld if you just hold on a moment,
because despite everything,
these changes are slower than the
president promised and slower than they
need to be.
Therefore,
even though foreign investment has
grown,
the growth rate is much lower than
expected.
Of course,
this is not the biggest problem,
nor what will probably cost this
president,
his reelection.
Oh No.
The big problem is that in recent years
there have been outbreaks of religious
fundamentalism,
moderate Islamic power.
He is.
Indonesia has been presented as a kind
of model like mostly Muslim country that
recognize this religious freedom,
a country that is becoming increasingly
open to the world as where women
participate actively in political life.
Indonesia tradition of moderate Islam
frankly,
is an inspiration to the world and we
you and your people in your nation.
As in mind,
religion unifies it,
does not divide Mike Pence,
US,
vice president.
In fact,
this is how the Indonesian government
presents itself to the rest of the
world.
Indonesia is the world's third largest
democracy,
and we also have the world's largest
Muslim population is demonstrates that
democracy and Islam are not
incompatible.
Joko Widodo,
president of Indonesia.
However,
in recent years there has been a
significant increase in religious
radicalism.
This is something that organizations
like Amnesty International and Human
Rights Watch are denouncing,
and the truth is that they have every
reason to do so.
For example,
last year,
the Indonesian Leymah Council,
the largest religious authority in the
country,
decided to defend the belief that
Christians and other nonbelievers
shouldn't be able to hold political
positions in areas that were majority
Muslim,
which does pertain to the vast majority
of the country.
Only other hands.
The governor of Jakarta and close ally
of President Jokowi,
a Christian of Chinese ancestry,
known as a hawk has been condemned for
blast from eight by insinuating that
politics and religion should be
separate.
Great.
Recent years,
the Islamist parties discourse has
become a lot harsher.
For example,
in 2018,
they are proposing a change to the penal
code to prosecute relations outside of
marriage and between same sex couples
more harshly and even make cohabitation
of single couples illegal.
See Right now,
Indonesia is still a relatively moderate
country and most of its population
supports and open democracy and even
religious freedom,
but everything points to the probability
that in the 2019 election,
the Islamists will have a larger chance
of winning and it's clear that we'll
talking about a future power that can
give us many joys for many headaches.
See if the current reforms continue.
Indonesia will be a huge market.
For example,
it's estimated that by 2030,
the Indonesian middle class will consume
much more than Germany's middle class,
and if religious moderation winds its
influence in the Muslim world will be
much,
much stronger.
So we can only hope that Indonesia goes
down the right path,
but now it's your turn.
Do you think we should support
Indonesia's favoring?
Have a more moderate status?
Well,
leave your answer in the comments below
as well as in this survey and I really
hope you enjoyed this video.
Please do hit that like button if you
did and do not forget to subscribe to
our channel for brand new videos every
Monday and every Thursday.
Also,
don't forget to check it off.
Friends at the reconsider media
podcasts,
they provided the vocals in this episode
that weren't on mine and as always,
thank you for watching.