This is a great place to work.
This is what Donald Trump said,
well,
referring to the White House in early
March of 2018 hours before his chief
economic advisor,
Gary Cohn's resignation became public.
This is Gary Cohen's last meeting.
He's going to go out and make another
couple of hundred dollars,
million and
back
all the time.
This phrase,
would it have been specially,
wouldn't have called anybody's attention
after all the White House,
and I don't think this will surprise
anyone.
It's one of the most sought after places
to work in the world.
Having a job in the president's team
means power,
influence and recognition.
However way,
just the moments because we are
forgetting a very important detail and
that detail would be who the president
is and how he is.
Now you know this well in the trump
dictionary,
the term usually has no place.
It simply does not exist.
Don't believe me.
Well,
listen up in the west wing
in January of 2017,
the 23 most important people in the west
wing of the White House were sworn in.
That is the people who would make up the
team that would lie or closest to the
president,
the chief of staff,
press secretary,
National Security Advisor,
director of communications,
etc. Etc.
Etc.
That is all of those people that we
normally see next to the president's on
tv shows and movies.
Of coursE,
dev you have president trump isn't
president.
Bartlet and surviving and his
administration is becoming more
difficult than setting up a business in
nicolas maduro.
Venezuela.
Now,
waiT a minute,
maybe you don't know who president
josiah bartlet is.
Well,
maybe I haven't seen the west wing.
if that's the case and you like
politics,
which you probably do,
you're watching this channel.
Don't waste another minute and go check
out that show,
but let's stay on track here.
Let's get back to donald trump's white
house.
Can you guess how many of those 23
people who formed the president's
praetorian guard when his term began are
still in office to date?
Well,
out of those 23,
only nine are still in their post.
Sam's.
Many of those nine are on the chopping
block.
Okay,
so you might be thinking,
well,
maybe he didn't choose the right.
I mean anyone can make a mistake.
Well,
the problem is that that is not the
case.
A tall Katherine Dunn 10 per se,
researcher at the brookings institute,
one of the most important think tanks in
Washington is following the changes that
are taking place almost every week in
the president's executive office and
listen to it.
If we take all the appointed positions
into accounts and those you've been
replaced,
dismissed or resigned as well as the
people who worked for them in total
until now,
65 people have been passed of the
president's office.
That is a eight percenT turnoVer rate.
That means that in just over a year,
half of the people who were part of the
team and no longer in office,
yes,
an unprecedented rotation race,
the scandals,
disagreements with the president or
simply the oval office tenants,
mood swings have led to working in the
west wing becoming a high risk
profession.
TO give you an idea,
layoffs,
resignations,
and changes are happening at a speed
three times greater than in the obama
administration and two times greater
than in reagan's suit.
You still hold the record and we're
really not inflating this by just
talking about small posts.
In the last year,
trump has replaceD two press
secretaries,
two chiefs of staff to national security
advisors,
and five different people have been
appointed as director of communications
in this time,
Donald Trump has even fired as lawyers
and what's worse based on the available
information,
things seem to be heading in an even
worse direction.
For example,
the national security advisor,
general mcmaster hasn't just been fired
since everything points to the fact that
the general John Kelly has current chief
of staff will follow in his footsteps.
In a very short time,
trump has decided to remove his national
security advisor.
Donald trump chooses them,
and then he seems to change his mind
really quickly.
So with this scenario in mind,
so we can understand why many of us team
members,
based on what they confessed,
spends a great deal of time trying not
to provoke a presidents who gets angry
very,
very easily.
Now,
many people would probably imagine trump
walking the halls of the white house
saying to people that you have five,
but maybe this isn't actually that far
from the truth.
Yes,
it does seem as if trump took his
position on the apprentice to hot,
where he basically fired people every
week.
You're fired,
you're fired,
bradford,
you're fired.
Can I say it as a joke sometimes that
derek,
you're fired.
You're fired.
Eight matter yet,
he Better otherwise.
I'll say,
tom,
you're fired.
You're fired.
Devastating.
No business can handle this much less.
The government,
it's supposed to be about stability and
continuity.
That's just not in his lexicon.
William m daily,
former president barack obama's chief of
staff,
but all right,
so you might be wondering,
well,
what's really going on here?
Why are there so many changes?
Well,
there are many reasons.
So on the fence and leave due to
scandals such as the national security
advisor,
Michael Flynn or staff secretary,
rob porter,
who resigned after domestic abuse
allegations
today,
former national security advisor,
Michael Flynn,
appeared in federal court and pleaded
guilty to lying to the fbi about his
conversations with russia's ambassador
during the transition last december.
Staff secretary rob porter,
who announced his resignation yesterday
and then domestic abuse allegations is
now officially out.
This
was also bannon's case until August,
2017.
He was donald trump's right hand man in
his political career,
but not even that saved him known for is
highly nationalist position.
Steve bannon was named senior counselor
to the president and chief strategist of
the white house swell.
After a little over six months,
trump sided to kick him out.
In the end,
bannon stepped forward and submitted a
forced resignation.
Others such as the economic advisor runs
former goldman sachs executive gary
cohn,
or press secretary sean spicer,
left.
Because of that,
disagreements with the president's many
others.
Well,
they were directly fired.
Ten days on the job that makes anthony
scaramucci the shortest tenured
communications director in the history
of the white house.
Trump's personal assistant,
john mcentee,
fired over security issue.
Then there are other cases,
for example,
emma amanda goals here until December,
2017 was assistant to the president and
director of communications for the
office of public liaison.
See,
omarosa was basically known for
participating in television.
Reality shows,
one of which was the apprentice where
she met Donald Trump,
and thanks to that,
she became part of the president's team
when he arrived at the white house.
I think I've won every reality tv a war.
It's like reality star,
the year reality villain.
Best catfight,
most dramatic momeNt.
Most google moment.
I mean,
I was in a field that was driven by
ratings and you know what drives
ratings?
conflict.
Well,
in december of 2017,
she suddenly resigned stating that had
seen very strange things that had Made
her feel very uncomfortable and had
effected her emotionally.
Omarosa was fired three times on the
apprentice and this was the fourth time
we let her go.
And do you know what she did after
resigning?
Well,
nothing less than joining the celebrity.
Big brother show where she has been
entering all that she saw as a white
house employee,
haunted my tweet.
And eVery single day like what is he
going to tweak?
You would be worried about pens and
dream.
I'm christian,
I love jesus.
But he thinks jesus tells him to say
things like jesus.
I say that.
So apparently Donald Trump has an
amazing eye for recreating great job.
Really?
But okay.
Okay.
Now some of you might be thinking,
well,
yes simon.
The thing with is west wing team has
gotten a bit out of hand,
sparse at the governmental level,
things must be different,
right?
Well,
it doesn't actually seem.
So.
The cabiNet,
the cabinet,
the body that is made up of the main
positions of the us.
Government's hasn't been saved from the
trump earthquake either.
See,
in june of 2017,
the first meeting was held with the
entire cabinet.
At that time,
trump publicly stated that he had
assembled an extraordinary group of
talents to his government.
Well,
to say the least.
Things have changed since then.
There've been six cabinet rotations
that's more than George Bush had in his
two terms in office and it's more than
half the diploma had in a single year of
these exchanges incidentally for were
redundant dismissals or resignations
that have rains,
priebus,
tom price,
david shulkin,
the last time,
the most surreal of that being rex
tillerson,
the secretary of state,
and previously powerful ceo of exxon
mobile,
the largest oil company in the United
States,
rex tillerson,
dvo you might remember,
was fired through twitter.
Trump didn't even tell them in person.
In fact,
it's ruined that skipping the
president's orders,
John Kelly,
trump's chief of staff called tillison,
who was touring africa to tell him that
the president was going to kick him out
and that he needed to return to
Washington and consider resigning.
It isn't clear whether telus and didn't
want to,
didn't believe him or didn't have the
time,
but the fact is the trump fired him on
twitter.
Now,
rumors about who trump is going to find
next are growing like crazy.
then carson,
secretary of housing,
ron zinke,
secretary of the interior,
Scott Pruitt to director of the
environmental protection agency and the
powerful Jeff sessions,
the attorney general of the big
favorites for the next firing.
By the way,
the last of the attorney general jeff
sessions is being blamed by trump pinata
having halted the investigations on the
russian interference issue in the
presidential elections that led him to
the white house.
Trump is fed up.
He knoWs who the president is.
He knows he's the boss.
I mean,
what are they thinking?
How can the fbi or the justice
department to try to investigate him?
I mean,
how dare they independence will have
none of that.
Thank you very much and pay attention
here,
dear viewer,
because trump is a really forward
thinking guy.
That is why he is fired.
James comey or andrew macabe format fbI
directors,
and for that same reason he stated the
Robert Mueller,
the special counsel who's investigating
russia's interference in the elections
is next to be fired.
This is something that even made a
republican senator jeff flake from
Arizona publicly warned the presidents
without his possible dismissal.
Yep.
You heard that right?
You are begging the president not to
fire the special counsel.
Don't create a constitutional crisis.
Congress cannot preempt to such a firing
or only constitutional remedy is after
the fact through impeachment.
No one Wants that outcome.
Mr. President,
please don't go there.
Senator jeff flake wells,
if you have.
these are the reasons why working in the
trump administration is becoming less
and less attractive even for
republicans.
There isn't a huge appetite for many
republicans on the outside to explore
job opportunities in this
administration.
Ryan williams,
former spokesmen for mitt romney,
and by the way,
have you noticed the main consequences
of all of this?
I mean,
who's going to want to work in this
administration now?
I mean,
think about it.
If you had a good job,
if you had a good position,
would you risk everything's going to
work in the white house.
I mean you could be fired tomorrow and
that would be the ends of your
reputation and your career and maybe
you'd get fired by a tweet.
And the reality is that for many people,
they would just say no to working in the
white house.
And yes,
the obvious consequence of this is that
the trump administration might be
lacking in talent anyways.
If you are,
this is how things are in Washington.
And now consider that trump only been in
the white house for a single year.
But now it's your turn.
Who do you think's next up to be fired
in the white house swelled.
Leave your answer in the comments below
and I really hope you enjoy this video.
Please do hit like if you didn't,
don't forget to subscribe to our channel
for brand new videos every monday and
thursday.
And also don't forget to check out our
friends at the reconsider media
podcasts.
They provided the vocals in this episode
that we're not mine.
And as always,
thank you for watching.
Oh,
you bet.
Otherwise they'll say,
tom,
you're fired.
You're fired.