[inaudible]
many of you have written to us asking
for a video about what's going on in
Turkey and believe me,
the situation there is quite dangerous.
And in case you were wondering,
Nope,
this time Donald Trump is not to blame
for this.
In fact,
the u s sanctions are just the tip of
the iceberg here.
And this is an iceberg that could wreck
many ships.
And so when we say ships we really mean
European banks.
Just look at the map we're showing.
Yep.
Tuckey is a bridge between Europe and
Asia.
We're talking about a country with a
population as big as Germany,
a country where Europe has been
investing for decades,
companies,
factories,
and of course there are lots and lots of
loans.
One an example.
Well,
hey you are,
have you ever heard of bb?
Va is the second biggest bank in Spain?
Well,
Turkey is the third biggest market for
this bank.
In other words,
when the Turks Sneeze and lots of
Europeans end up with a Kohl's,
I'm scared enough yet.
Well listen up.
Turkey isn't important.
NATO member for America.
They have the biggest army in the
alliance and they are one of the few
countries with a Muslim majority and
secular constitution,
at least for now.
Yep.
You heard that rice we said so far,
but the truth is that the Turkish
president,
while he has not a big fan of secularism
or when there's something like the
antiquing Skywalker of politics,
he started out as the good guy in the
movie boss.
We all know that eventually it will fall
to the dark side.
In this case,
the dock side is a mix between a
religious fanaticism.
Well,
good old populism.
I don't want likes to portray himself as
the defender of the average man.
Those tax that live in rural areas like
Kanya.
I completely outside of the Glamor of
his stumble,
the tax that they don't have amazing
salaries and they maintain a traditional
lifestyle as well.
Who Do these people need to be protected
against?
Well,
of course that would be the western
conspiracy that wants to end Turkey.
This explains why it,
because this is so important for to
one's narrow
us impose sanctions and Turkish
officials over the paint American
pastor.
Nonetheless,
this is just the tip of the iceberg.
First of all,
the actual reason behind the US
sanctions is not the pastor that's the
military and sanctions with the Kurds in
Syria,
but that's another story for another
video.
The truth is Turkey's crisis has been
going on for three years already and
this isn't just a political crisis.
In fact,
the biggest problem is economics.
We're talking about a small scale of
Venezuela here,
right at the very gates of Europe.
But now the question is what is going on
in Turkey?
What happens in this country to cause
them to fall to the dark side of
economics and do we really have to be
scattered today?
We're going to answer all of these
questions,
but before we do,
as always,
let's take a look back at the huddle.
Strange Erdogan,
the savior,
so he is famous for Mary thinks,
seems Sophia Kebab sins inflation.
Since 1970 and until the year 2000
Turkey had sky high inflation rates,
many years,
they even surpass the 100% mark.
This means that from one year to the
next,
prices would double.
And what happens when you have so much
inflation and you live so close to
wealthy European countries?
Well,
you become a cheap labor.
Disneyland's companies like Renault of
Persia builds lots of factories in
Turkey.
But hold on a second because I can guess
when you're probably thinking right now,
you're probably thinking about,
okay Simon,
but isn't this actually good news for a
country?
Well,
yes and no.
At the same time.
For example,
in the 1960s Renno opens a factory in
Bursar,
a city in northern Turkey,
manufacturing cars in Bursar.
It was very cheap for rent.
I,
since the Turkish lira was devaluing
year after year,
Renno had to pay the lower and lower
salaries.
Okay?
Nonetheless,
when they got the money from selling
those cars of the era,
rarely think they kept it inside Turkey
of course,
and see they've Turkish money.
It was losing value so fast.
The smartest thing you could do with
your money was take it out of the
country as well,
fast as you possibly could.
This is why Turkey seemed doomed to
stagnation.
That was until the year 2003 that's the,
uh,
[inaudible] came to power.
His main goal was to keep inflation
below 10%.
It created a new car and see the Turkish
lira.
This was a currency far more stable than
the previous,
and as soon as inflation was enhance,
the Turkish economy is made a 180 degree
shift.
All of a sudden,
many European companies started
investing in Turkey.
This included banks.
One of them,
the Spanish bbb we mentioned previously
invested in this country,
big time.
In fact,
so much so that now Turkey is the third
largest market.
So in the two thousands Turkey,
it was in fashion rule of law ans
monetary stability.
Men,
the company has good reinvest in the
country.
So if less than 10 years,
your average Turkish work,
it went from making 800 US dollars a
month to making more than $1,200
it's a month.
Mother knew
that in those first oto in years and new
industries like tourism develops,
Turkey went from 13 million tourists to
39 million.
And what Turkish companies?
Well,
have you ever heard of Turkish Airlines
in the nineties Turkish Airlines was
just another carrier,
but since they can now reinvest that
profit,
they ended up becoming an aviation
juggernauts.
Now,
believe me,
this is not an isolated case.
If there's one great example of the
Turkish men are old and it has to be
yelled as holdings.
This company,
it started out as a family owned bakery
and now they've already bought European
brands like godiva chocolates or united
biscuits.
Today,
yielders holdings is the world's third
biggest company in the entire food
sector.
So in other words,
the Turkish economy,
it was absolutely on fire.
Zia Company who was on the line that
would really seem to care that one had
been to prison for being a part of a
radical group.
At the end of the day,
the country was still democratic.
Another one was the Arab rock star.
He was the chosen one.
He was the one who was going to bring
the Islamic wells.
That's the bright side.
Bags in Turkey wanted to be European.
They were just about to the Karma member
of the European Union as a fun fact in
2003 they even won the eurovision song
contest
last,
as you might know,
the negotiations to become a part of the
EU extended over a really long time.
So what happens?
Well,
over one lost his patients and he
essentially said,
oh,
what?
So I'm not cool enough to join your
club.
Well,
you know what?
I'm tired of being western.
I'm tired of a separation of powers.
I'm tired of secularism.
All of that.
It's now over.
Now is the time.
In the last five years,
things started to sour.
Third one first,
he was personally involved in many
corruption cases,
but worst of all was news like this
Istanbul,
Ataturk airport attack,
41 dead and more than 230 hurt
Dasha tax of brought Islamic terrorism
and insecurity to the streets of Turkey
and the damage to the tourism industry.
It was a media in just two years.
Tourism income has fallen by 25% and
this is especially worrying given the
tourism accounts for 13% of the Turkish
economy.
But that's not all foreign investment
has fallen by half.
And I,
you might be wondering,
well why?
Well there are two reasons for this.
The first one is the lack of a chance
that Turkey is going to become a part of
the European Union.
And the second one while I was out of
one himself.
Yes [inaudible] Islamic radicalism is
not just a danger politics wise.
It is also a danger for economics.
Ah,
he's earned a one calls,
interest rates the mother of all evil.
The lira slides
according to Ottawa,
the so called Economic Orthodoxy is a
Western invention that will destabilize
Turkey borrowing money with interesting.
It goes against Islam.
So he runs to the central bank and
forced them to lower the interest rates
and start printing money.
And what if the central bank and when he
refused and he said,
I just,
I just don't want to do that.
Well these are,
I don't want as well
central.
Yeah.
Thank can't take this independence and
set aside the signals given by the
president or to one speaking to
Bloomberg.
So in other words,
after the failed coup to tar of 2016 oh
one has finally fallen into the dark
side,
he thinks he can manage the economy at
his will and to every rational critic
against his economic policy is seen as a
western conspiracy that he even named
his son in law as the finance minister.
This new economic paradigm is not a free
markets or social democracy.
This is the new,
I don't want to nominate.
Do you mean
money to pay?
You feel spending wild,
you simply princess,
I'll Turkish companies complaining flood
the market with chief credit.
In less than two years,
Turkish banks have given more than $50
billion worth of loans and all of this
is with almost no interest.
The results,
well that's a crazy devaluation of the
Turkish lira 2014 the exchange rate
between the US dollar and the Turkish
lira was about 2.5
Liros to the dollar at the time of the
making of this video.
However,
the exchange rate,
is it more than six lyrice to the
dollar?
This means that the Turkish lira has
lost two thirds of its value compared to
four years ago.
It's also partially accounts for why
inflation rates have risen so high to
11.9%
in the end of 27
t
all right.
All right.
I don't want you to thinking I live in
boy.
9% doesn't sound so bad.
I mean in Argentina they have three
times that inflation is the truth is
that you need some time between a
devaluation and the rise in day to day
prices.
So who were the first ones suffering the
effects of this deflation?
Well,
those would be the companies that had
loans in foreign bank and there are more
than a few of them.
You really yielders holdings the food
industry bm off.
Well,
here you go.
Check this out.
Turkish owner of Godiva chocolate to
restructure,
six point $5 billion worth of debt
estimation.
Say that foreign debt from salvage
companies to surpass is $300 billion for
a lesser understanding.
This is the same amount of money spent
in all of the bailouts of Greece and
meanwhile the inflation rate is starting
to grow little by little this year,
2018 it's already reached 15% since all
the nongovernmental estimation saying
that at the beginning of 2019 it's going
to rise to 22%
yes,
Turkey's software and credit rating cut
deeper into junk as s and p seized
recession next year.
Add to this,
the sanctions imposed by Donald Trump.
We're going to talk about the reasons
behind the sanctions in another video,
but here we want to focus on the
economics because in the middle of all
of this,
there is another player with a lot the
loose and that's the European.
Yeah,
union.
Thanks like the Spanish Ppva and the
fringe and BNP of paradise or the
Italian unicredit.
As I've learned more than $190 billion
to Turkish companies so far,
BBV has already lost half of the value
of those investments,
so you can already imagine the big gap
that a Turkish collapse would leave so
far out.
Again has said that he won't ask for a
bailouts from the International Monetary
Fund and he will not raise capital
controls either.
But Kenny really stick to his words.
We just don't know here.
All we know is that both Qatar and China
have already promised to help for
Turkish economy,
but it is still too soon to tell what's
going to happen.
Yeah.
So now the question really goes to you.
Do you think Turkey will become the
European Venezuela?
Could this localized crisis creates a
bigger crisis all across Europe?
Could add one pull.
Everybody is the dark side.
Ah,
well please leave your answer in the
comment section below.
And as always,
don't forget to check out our friends or
the reconsider media podcast.
They provided the vocals in this episode
that were not mine.
Andrew,
remember that we published brand new
videos every week.
So do hit that subscribe button so you
won't miss out on a post.
And if you liked this video,
give us a thumbs up.
And as always,
I'll see you next time.
And if you want to learn more about
politics and hear more of my lovely
voice,
oh,
forget to check out the reconsidered
podcast@reconsidermedia.com
or we consider as a podcast that
challenges you to reconsider your views.
I providing context,
but we don't do the thinking for you.