Every time,
less than American government tries to
discuss foreign policy and development,
they ended up discussing regional
integration.
That is why we should understand the
three main common features of Latin
America,
football,
soccer for you Americans,
revolutions and the regional
organizations.
Seriously,
we're really not kidding here.
In the last few decades,
there have been so many regional
organizations that it is almost
impossible to know what goals each of
them have besides obviously being an
excuse for spending money on public
workers headquarters and traveling.
These are unison,
Mercosur,
Albert Caricom,
Sanilac Ld,
the Indian community seekers,
seller,
the Rio Group,
and of course the Organization of
American States,
and to be honest,
I'm probably not even mentioning all of
them there anyway.
Once you hear about all of these
organizations,
you might be thinking the Latin America
is the place where people get on with
each other.
The best.
A place where it's really easy to do
business among the different countries.
I'm where governments work together for
the common good in some sort of
wonderful paradise,
right?
When all the bad news is.
If you didn't guess that none of that is
true.
All of these organizations,
they were born with these really
wonderful home ideas,
but we could say they all really did
nothing for developments and economic
and political integration in Latin
America.
New institutions are created,
but it isn't clear what to do with the
previous ones.
It is an endless fight forward.
Carlos mood look just by all the
different processes of integration.
Trade is strangely low among these
different countries.
Those are important.
Yet the share of exports inside the
region.
It hasn't changed much and it has been
around 20 percent,
which is much lower than in other parts
of the world.
This is pretty strong evidence about how
artificial and unproductive these
organizations.
We'll see the details of this case
though.
The word disappointment or failure would
probably better describe Mercosur boss.
I can already tell you that it is very
possible that this lack of real
integration is the origin of some of the
most important problems that the region
is facing.
Turnell promise
in America is to view is it's a
fantastic region.
It's got great natural resources,
it has significant biodiversity and its
climate is very unimpressive.
Many people would say that the region is
one of the most beautiful on a,
the
economically speaking,
things on not looking so great despite
all of these magnificent resources and
ditch great potential,
the region has been left behind in terms
of economic growth.
Let's compare,
for example the current Richard's
country in Latin America and that would
be chilly.
So I think most people would agree here
that shit.
He's done a pretty good job in the last
few decades.
Right?
Well,
despite that apparent progress,
just have a look at this.
Oh No.
We have taken the richest country in
Latin America and have competitive to
South Korea,
which is not even the richest country in
eastern Asia.
Ben's weld.
The difference is pretty obvious.
In the sixties,
Chile was a poor country,
but was far richer than South Korea.
Yeah,
well things.
They're rather different.
Look at Argentina,
which was once the richest country in
Latin America with the exception of
Cuba,
but now we'll take a look at its
evolution when compared to Spain.
Well,
one of the causes for this lower growth,
my precisely be the low trade
integration and the access protectionism
and bureaucracy that the region has
always suffered from.
I mean there are loads of agreements,
there are tons of committees and forums
and all of that stuff,
but when the rubber hits the road,
it was really nothing there but do hold
on for just one second because a few
years ago a new integration project it
was put into place and this one is
actually completely different to the
rest.
Not only is it the first project with
real success in the region,
but it might also change the destiny of
Latin America forever and here we're
talking about the Pacific alliance civic
alliance,
April of 2011,
all friends,
Chile,
Columbia,
Mexico,
Peru formed the so called Pacific
alliance.
It's mission is to finally achieve and
integration,
so the goods capital and people can move
freely around the region.
All of this was put in place with the
idea that it would stimulate growth
development and competitiveness in these
economies.
Yes.
Teresa account for 55 percent of Latin
American exports.
This is not a romantic integration,
political integration.
It is a realistic integration before the
world and to the world.
Alan Garcia,
former president of Peru,
man,
so they did.
Even though there's still a lot of work
to be done since then development,
it's been really significant.
Six years.
These four countries,
they've removed 92 percent of customs
tariffs and they've set a deadline to
remove all of the rest as well.
Along with this,
they've simplified the bureaucracy of
customs and administration,
especially when it comes to rules about
the origin of goods.
This was previously a significant burden
on the region.
Alright.
All right,
so up until now,
if a Colombian producer used Peruvian
supplies,
he couldn't take advantage of the free
trade agreements between Columbia and
Mexico when selling his goods to Mexico,
which just crazy.
That's not the end of it.
Visa requirements,
they've also been eliminated,
so the movements of visitors has
actually doubled and then,
and this is very important,
there have been significant advances in
financial integration.
These four countries have created the m
I l a,
the American integrated market,
which is meant to be the largest stock
market in Latin.
Okay.
American
oldest,
more among other initiatives.
The countries in the alliance are
working together in order to be known in
international markets.
They have also started to share
embassies in African and Asian countries
and they have decided to negotiate
altogether for their free trade
agreements.
For example,
they've actually already started to do
this with New Zealand,
Australia,
Canada,
and Singapore.
Australia and New Zealand start trade
talks with Pacific alliance.
In other words,
these four countries are building step
by step,
a unique market which will be rather
significance.
We're talking about 240 million
consumers with a combined GDP,
which makes this alliance one of the
eight largest economies in the world.
Yeah.
This is an economy that represents 50
percent of all exports and more than 40
percent of all foreign investments in
Latin America.
We could say that if the Pacific
alliance keeps it up in a very short
time,
we might have to consider it the biggest
power in Latin America,
but in order to understand a bit better
the achievements that they've had in
only six years,
we should look at the other large group
in the region and that would be fall of
METCO.
Okay,
so it was created in 1991 by Brazil,
Argentina,
Uruguay,
and Paraguay with the intention of
creating one large integrated market.
Well,
these were ambitious goals,
but the advances,
we've been pretty damn modest.
And how about some evidence of this?
Well,
just have a look at this.
The trade among Mercosur members
represents today less than 30 percent of
the total trade of its members in 1995.
That was almost 20 percent.
Rather than encouraging trade between
its members,
we could say that Marcus has actually
weakened them in the last few years.
Microsoft has become some sort of
protectionist shield rather than
something which is working to integrate
these countries further.
Not exactly what they wanted in the
first place.
Group
is become little more than an antigo
talking shop,
but why isn't this working?
Well,
that's mainly because the countries,
they're not really very committed.
In theory,
Microsoft is a process of economic
integration,
but there are so many exceptions and
restrictions.
That's in the end.
There's no free movement of goods or
services.
Microsoft has become something which is
totally ineffective.
A good example can be found on the
border of Argentina and Uruguay.
In theory,
the goods should be able to move freely
between both countries.
However,
the reality is of the difference when
adding customs,
inspections and bureaucracy.
A truck from Uruguay,
Argentina could be delayed for more than
24 hours,
which is totally crazy when it's
supposed to not be delayed at all.
All of this has led to Uruguay,
formally asking,
do you become a member of the Pacific
alliance and there is more to this
story.
Still the political change in Argentina
and Brazil has led to both of their
governments.
Accepting that marcus,
or at least as it is understood today,
is almost completely worthless.
We'll never reach the common market.
The custom union is completely destroyed
and the free trade area is not working
either.
Mercosur isn't a dying state.
Danilo is story minister of Economy in
Uruguay.
This is why Macri has decided to become
closer to the Pacific alliance and look
the ties between both processes of
integration.
The real question becomes now will the
Pacific alliance creates a change in
America,
so if it does,
then that would be great news for the
entire region,
civic pumas.
Now of course,
the question that we have to ask is,
well,
why is the Pacific alliance on like any
of those other organizations,
the only one that seems to be working
well maybe this has to do with these so
called Pacific Pumas,
Chile,
Peru,
Columbia,
and Mexico.
These countries have been the most
dynamic economies in Latin America and
they share the same vision.
They all agree there's in order to grow
and develop,
they have to produce and do business
with the rest of the world,
and this is why according to the welds
bank,
these humans are the country where it is
easiest to do business or were more
trade agreements are signed with the
rest of the week.
Well anyway,
the Pacific Alliance represents one of
the best opportunities for Latin America
to be in a position to become the talk
of the town.
It wouldn't even be too much of a
stretch to say that we could be
witnessing the birth of a great economic
power,
but now it's your turn.
Do you think Latin America has to bet on
these processes of integration?
Well,
leave us your opinion in the comments
below as well as in this quick.
Paul also,
don't forget to subscribe to our channel
for brand new videos every Monday and
every Thursday.
Also,
do not forget to check out our friends
at the reconsider media podcast did.
They provided the vocals in this episode
that are not mine,
and as always,
thank you for awhile.