[inaudible].
Chechnya is an island of Islamic
fanaticism in the middle of Vladimir
Putin's Russia.
Yup.
You had that rights when it comes to me,
that congratulates itself on being the
spiritual shelter of the West.
The laws,
the bullock of Christiana.
See,
this is a country where you can find the
republic of Chechnya.
It's a positive Russia where it is
impossible to buy him.
Cut.
Oh yes.
Was I know what you're going to see.
I'm waiting an assignment that didn't
you just say the republic of Chechnya
didn't say that it was a part of Russia?
Well,
the truth is the Russian Federation is
territory wise,
the biggest country in the world,
and that means that their political
distribution,
it's really complicated.
The biggest parts of the country is
divided into the so called oblasts
switch up.
Similar to the states in the United
States of America.
These areas,
they have their own governor.
They have their own parliaments,
but they must respect the Russian
constitution as well as the Kremlin.
However,
there are other regions in Russia,
the so called republics that have way
more autonomy.
They have their own constitution.
They have their own language and they
could even have that own official.
One of these republics is the Crimean
republic and despite not being
recognized by America or by Europe,
it is controlled by Russia.
You've seen in theory,
Russian law guarantees a lot of autonomy
bots.
I say in theory like that because as you
know,
Vladimir Putin loves to keep this
country under tight control.
In fact,
almost all of the presidents of the
republics belonged to Putin's political
party and that would be united Russia.
Anytime one of those governors
challenges Putin,
even just the little things like this
happen
Tatarstan the last region to lose its
special status under Putin.
Nonetheless,
there is a real public that Putin does
not dare to bully.
Yup.
You had that ride.
Vladimir Putin,
the Chuck Norris of politics is afraid
sometimes to specifically when it comes
to Chechnya,
is
often unclear who rules whom.
Russian observers of the region
complained that Russian law and
authority stops at the Chechnyan border.
For example,
in Chechnya,
the hijab is promoted by the government.
Things like polygamy and even marriages
involving minors that are actually
tolerated and no restaurant.
Dez to open a daytime during Ramadan
season.
Nonetheless,
all of these things,
I'm nothing compared to what some
newspapers showed in April of 2017
Chechnya opens worlds first
concentration camp for homosexuals.
Yeah,
yeah.
Listen,
I know he picked it is not exactly the
biggest fan of lgbt rights,
but opening a gay concentration camp
sounds like it it too much even for him.
So the question to be made here is why
doesn't put some order into Chechnya?
What is the church and President Rams
and off secret to getting Putin that's
and let him do as he pleases.
Well today we are going to answer all of
those questions,
but before we do,
let's take a look back at the history.
Great.
The Sicily of the Caucasus for centuries
Czechian yet was ruled by big clams that
have power over specific areas.
Those clams named took home in the
church in language we're composed of
hundreds of smaller families.
The so called tip or a better
understanding.
This was pretty similar to the Sicilian
mafia system.
Everything stayed in the file.
Everything was done according to the
principles of religion.
In this case,
Sunni Islam,
I'm the same way.
The Sicilian mafia resisted all kinds of
invasions.
The Chechen took him system that
survived the saws and even the Soviet
Union.
Yeah,
it must be Soviets in public and Muslims
in private Chechnyan proverb and other
words during the Soviet era that were
two parallel systems that were running
at the same time,
all of a surface that was communism,
but under grounds there was a hierarchy
of Muslim clams and families.
This is why in the year 1991 when the
Soviet Union disappeared,
Chechens seize the opportunity and
declared the Chechen Republic of a
carrier.
This,
and I might ring a bell with you because
it appears in one of the call of duty
video games.
Now back then,
the presidents of the brand new Russian
Federation,
that was Boris Yeltsin,
and he replied to those rebels with
military Yeltsin,
declares emergency curfew and Chechen
region.
Nevertheless,
this state of emergency fails entirely.
The Russian army was incapable of
stopping the chapter and rentals and
they have to run back home.
But not only that,
during their retreats,
these separatist rebels seized Russian
weapons.
So for three long years,
the Kremlin puts up with Chechnya.
But in the year 1994 well,
things they changed.
Okay,
you can build a throne with band nets,
but it's difficult to sit on it,
Boris Yeltsin.
But do you remember what I told you
about the political system of Chechnya,
which was based on the took him clan
system?
Well,
the truth is these different clans
didn't really get on very well with each
other,
and this was the start of a civil war,
a civil war.
That's to rush eyes.
Where's the perfect opportunity to take
back control of the republic?
However,
a year later,
the Russian army had lost 6,000 soldiers
and poor Boris Yeltsin had to sign a
peace treaty with the separatists ends.
Pretty weak governments of Chechnya.
Meanwhile,
many Islamic terrorists from Saudi
Arabia and Afghanistan fled to Grozny.
The Chechen capitol to recruit new
members are failed states with a tribal
system where Islam is the official
religion.
That sounds like a pretty great market
for recruiting terrorists.
Well,
in other words,
all of this meant that it was just a
matter of time before another war again.
So this war,
it started in 1999 when a group of
Islamic rebels invaded a neighboring
Russian republic,
the Republic of Dagestan.
So if making trouble in their own
territory wasn't enough Chechens wanting
to attack other parts of Russia.
Now,
as you might imagine from this,
the Kremlin decided to send the troops
immediately,
but this time it was pretty different.
So why was this?
Well,
despite the fact Boris Yeltsin was the
president this time,
the prime minister was the one and only
the hero of visual politic.
And that would be Vladimir Putin.
Yeah.
Well,
Putin,
he actually,
when's their rents?
He found one of the separatists chiefs.
And that would be Ms. Dot.
[inaudible] cut a Rov.
So basically piecing when's this cutter
off guy and said,
all right dude,
look,
I'm going to show you a gold.
I'm going to give me as many weapons and
as much power as you need.
You could do whatever you want there in
Chechnya,
but that is only one condition.
No wars,
no terrorism.
All right.
And as we say here at visual policy egg
as it was sad,
well still it was done.
The wall,
it was over and catterall views all that
help from the Kremlin.
Do you destroy it?
The other warlords in the report,
and now you might be wondering,
well,
did all of this work really answer says
yes.
I'm sort of all say no.
Of course there were no more wars,
but many of those other warlords started
organizing terrorist attacks in other
areas of Russia,
including Moscow.
In the Moscow case,
a terrorist group kidnaps over 300
hostages in a theater.
Of those 300 civilians,
170 died.
In other words,
Putin's plan was far from perfect and
Kevin Authority was not taken for
granted.
In fact,
some years later he would die in another
terrorist attack in Grozny Allen's.
Well,
that was the moment when the main
character in all of this story comes
into the picture.
Instagram star runs out and catterall
succeeded.
His Father Empower Nan's.
He learned a valuable lesson.
If you want to start a dictatorship,
you better make it big.
We all talking about a country full of
warlords fighting each other.
Where al You doing one dash are
recruiting people who might challenge
cataracts power.
In other words,
he was not willing to let those weird
western fashions,
you know,
like democracy or human rights make him
look weak.
Besides here,
pten support.
He had wealth.
He had weapons.
What marketing possibly ask
form.
I owe my life to preach him.
If I ever forget this,
I am not a math.
When I went through a terribly hard time
in my life,
he helped.
He has the most saintly to Ramazan
[inaudible].
The truth.
Truth
is since kind of rope came to power
Chechen in other parts of Russia,
while they've disappeared,
but not only that,
I'll,
how are you doing Dash Mila's in stuff
disappearing to cater rob's police
chases them.
Expels them from the country with their
families and then bud's down the houses.
Yes,
this was not enough.
Cut Her off.
Soldiers offer themselves as volunteers
for the most dangerous missions in
Ukraine.
In fact,
in order to show his love for Putin rams
and candor of organize the military
parade at Cross knee football stadium,
thousands of soldiers were waving at the
Chechen presidents ready to die for him.
If Putin tells me to get my army
together,
I'm ready.
[inaudible] rough bus things.
Well,
they are not as sweet as they might
seem.
Actually with that military parade cadre
off was given two messages.
One was,
Hey Putin,
I'm your buddy,
but the other was,
hey Putin,
if you ever stopped being my buddy,
come and get me,
if you dare.
Yes,
DIV UA.
If flattening a Putin ever wanted to
confront his Chechen bestie,
it would be complicated to save the
League
spent on many signs that this could
actually happen.
In fact,
all of Kadar,
rob's political foes,
they've been murdered regardless of
where they work.
For journalists living in Moscow to
political opponents,
siding in some Petersburg,
they've all been kills like,
well,
what does this mean?
What it means.
The government of Grozny has its own kgb
situated all across the country and well
they're happy to use it anytime someone
Chechen or not get seen little bits
bothersome so it puts it more poetically
well piecing created rams and cat are
off and now his creation has become big
enough to look him in the eye.
This explains why I'm like other
presidents of Russian republics kind of
relevant dares to give his opinion on
international affairs and the creme and
they pretended they don't see those
horrific gay concentration camps.
Russia
backs,
Chechnya governments,
denials over killing a torture of gay
men.
Meanwhile,
Chechnya is getting wealthier and
wealthier thanks to Russia.
90% of their wealth comes direct from
money transfers from the Kremlin her
off.
He's built a republic where the cause of
his personality is always like a second
religion.
Just surpassed by Islam is instagram
accounts,
by the way,
has over 3 million followers,
which is twice as many as the church and
population.
And on this account you can see the
lifestyle of one of the craziest
dictators around,
and at the same time,
the only one that makes pewter to
phrase.
Now the question is,
will Vladimir Putin and ran Zahn
catterall ends up clashing?
Should the Kremlin tried to stop the
human rights violations in Chechnya?
Well,
please leave your answer in the comment
section below and also visit the
reconsider media podcast,
the podcast that provides,
yeah,
the vocals in this video,
but I'll not mine.
Also,
don't forget that we published brand new
videos every Monday and every Thursday.
So hit that subscribe button and you
will not miss a post.
And if you liked this video,
give it a thumbs up.
And as always,
I'll see you next time.
And if you want to learn more about
politics and hear even more of my love
the voice,
you can join us at reconsider media.
We have a podcast@reconsideredmedia.com
slash podcast.