[inaudible]
Hollywood's it's the world's most famous
neighborhoods spans.
Yes,
I said that.
Absolutely right.
Hollywood is a neighborhood.
It's not a city.
It's not even a village.
Hollywood is a district inside the city
of Los Angeles with a population of less
than 90,000
people.
Nonetheless,
here is where most of the movie industry
has concentrated.
Wait just a minute because I know what
you're going to say.
Come on.
Signer,
and I know better than this.
This isn't a tall tree.
The biggest movie production centered.
The world is Bollywood in India.
Well my dear viewers,
you up sort of right here,
but there is a pretty significant,
but now despite the fact that the Indian
movie industry makes more movies than
anyone of their income is tiny compared
to that of Hollywood,
I think just think about it.
How many Indian movies have you actually
seen?
I bet the answer to that is number or
lost and undone less.
Of course your Indian,
in which case,
hello,
dear Indian viewers.
Now with a few exceptions,
Bollywood movies are made to the
domestic market and the same goes for
Nigeria.
Nigeria is actually the second largest
movie producer in the world behind
Bollywood.
But I'm sure hardly any of you have
actually seen a film made in this
country and you are of course in
Nigerian,
in which case,
hello Nigerian viewers.
So when it comes to the raw economics of
it all,
Hollywood is undoubtedly the world's
movie capitol.
So now you might be wondering,
well,
Simon,
why are we talking about cinema here?
A visual politic.
Isn't this channel all about politics
and economics?
I mean,
what's the connection here?
Well,
actually there are a lot of connection.
First there is the fact that there is a
political reason why he's so much of the
movie world is centered in Hollywood and
the end of the day,
I mean,
why as Hollywood in Los Angeles and not
in New York or London or somewhere else
entirely.
Now,
many of you might think that California
has always been an important state in
the u s with innovative companies,
prestigious universities and celebrities
just walking down the street.
But the truth is that at the beginning
of the 20th century,
La had less of an 100,000
inhabitants.
In fact,
the first movie producers were born on
the other side of the country.
Then cities like New York or Chicago.
So the question we have to ask now is,
well,
why did they decide to move to la?
What does Hollywood have the Manhattan
doesn't?
And the most important question of all,
what does immigration have to do with
any of this?
Well today we are going to answer all of
those questions,
but before we do as usual,
let's take a look at the history art by
and for immigrants.
The first question of all when it has to
be who invented movies in the first
place?
The Lumiere brothers,
well,
not exactly what the Lumiere brothers
invented was the system to project films
onto a big screen.
But years before that the company of
Thomas Edison had already discovered a
system to record and play short movies
and this was called a kinetoscope.
It was a device where you would put a
coin into a slot and watch movies
through AP poll.
He is later.
This system would be improved so that
these short films could be projected
onto a big screen as well.
But the big difference between Edison
and the Lumiere brothers was that the
American businessmen knew that these
could make big time money.
Anything that won't sell,
I don't want to invent it.
Sale is proof of utility and utility is
success.
Thomas Alva Edison,
so while the Lumiere brothers showed off
their invention at scientific fairs,
Edison made a profit from it.
His business consisted of selling these
machines,
taking a royalty for their use and
supplying movie theaters with lots and
lots of films.
It just two decades,
Edison made more than 1,200
movies.
It's like now you might be wondering,
what kind of movies did Edison produce?
Well,
as bizarre,
more not as it possibly sounds as many
of these first films in history were
about women getting undressed,
but movies were bigger opportunity and
just a few years,
cities like New York and Chicago became
flooded with movie theaters.
The so called Nickelodeon's.
Here you find a great show at a lower
price in another theaters.
Plus,
since the movies were silent,
you didn't need to speak English to
understand them.
This means movies became the perfect
entertainments for all the immigrants
arriving to the lands of opportunity.
All of this,
it was happening in the first decade of
the 20th century men's while France,
since interestingly,
Denmark already were producing that own
movies.
No other country had a bigger audience
than America.
How is that Thomas Edison?
He wasn't able to see all of the
opportunities behind his invention.
At the end of the day,
he was the typical wasp and d despised
immigrants.
Of course,
he was happy to be money from them,
but he didn't really like them and so
now you might be asking,
well,
why didn't he invests money in improving
the quality of his films?
Well,
at the end of the day,
his company had a monopoly over the
production and distribution of the
films.
It's like he really didn't have any
incentive to
all those nickelodeon's paid royalties
to Edison's company and bought his films
without even looking at the titles are
plots.
At the end of the day,
nobody thought those German,
Italian or Hungarian immigrants would
appreciate the details.
Of course,
this was until this man you see on the
screen right now came along.
Of course I'm talking about call Lemley
Emily.
He was one of these German immigrants.
He worked at a nickelodeon in Chicago
business.
It was great,
but he was sick of paying so much money
if they that a sense movies.
So he asked himself the question wrong,
can just,
I make my own movies and as well,
yes,
he absolutely could.
I,
I'll say Lenley.
He knew other nickelodeon owners.
All of them were immigrants too,
as they knew the tastes and aspirations
of their audiences.
They knew that movies,
they could become something much more
than just cheap jokes and girls with not
very many clothes.
They could create stars like those seen
on Broadway.
Okay.
These cinema pioneers were the first
ones to include the actor's name on the
posters and in the credits this way,
many more artists were willing to work
for them.
Their films became famous among
immigrants who came.
They came from all over the worlds,
and this is why they named their company
universal.
Okay.
As you can imagine,
the success of this new company,
they didn't spot others to follow suit,
for instance,
and other Hungarian immigrants named
adults.
Zucker made another partnership with
other nickelodeon owners.
Zahn started another studio,
which was called paramount pictures,
southernly New York,
and in general,
the east coast became sort of the
primitive version of Hollywood.
The hold on for just a minute because
Thomas Edison,
well,
he was not willing to lose this battle.
Don't forget,
he had the fame,
the money,
am's,
the patterns.
So in less than five years,
Lemley and his partner's feast over 200
lawsuits.
The same happens with the rest of the
small studios and as well,
many of them went bankrupt.
Oh yeah.
This was a pretty bad side.
The movie studios is bad.
It was pretty much a golden era for
lawyers,
and if all of this was not enough,
Edison had enough power to force all of
the nickelodeons from New York and
Chicago to sign exclusivity contracts.
If they wanted Addison's technology,
it couldn't buy movies from his rivals.
Well,
this is the moment when our friend
called Lemley,
asked himself another important
question,
well,
why should they stay on the east coast?
Addison,
he was a powerful man in ds,
but it's influence didn't reach
everywhere.
There was a place far out of his reach
and that place it was California
birth of an industry.
In the end,
90 15 California,
there was the place to be thousands of
young immigrants.
The perfect audience for these would
arrive every year.
Houses and properties were cheaper than
anywhere else in America.
And as if this was not enough,
if the weather was pretty fantastic in
New York,
it rains a ray of the day.
So if you wanted to make movies,
you'd better have a studio and spend
thousands of dollars on lights.
In California,
there's plenty of sunshine all year
round,
so it's really easy to shoot outside.
This is why all those big studios from
New York and Chicago moved into a
neighborhood on the outskirts of Los
Angeles,
a small with less or more than 500
inhabitants.
And as you've probably guessed by now,
well that tiny place,
it was Hollywood,
but the story,
it doesn't end here.
You might now be wondering,
well,
how did California conquer audiences all
around the world?
I mean,
don't forget that back in the day that
United States,
it wasn't the big powerhouse that it
would become later.
And don't forget,
countries like France,
countries like Denmark,
they already had a well funded industry.
So why did Hollywood achieve so much
success and do it so quickly?
Well,
the answer lies in something called the
network effects,
and if you've been subscribed to this
channel for a while,
you should do that by the way,
then the chances aren't even know what
this thing is.
All those Hollywood studios attracted
the best investors and professionals
from all around the globe.
This explains why in 1915 Hollywood was
the setting for the first super
production in history,
the birth of a nation,
a cost around a hundred thousand dollars
at that time.
That's miscellanea.
By the way,
this movie,
it was extremely controversial because
essentially it portrayed the KKK as the
good guys,
but I mean,
that's an entire story for a different
day.
The truth is that in less than 10 years,
the population of Hollywood grew to more
than 30,000
inhabitants.
Most of them,
they were immigrants like Francisco
alias this span.
He came to Hollywood to work as a
production assistant.
Soon he realized he could translate the
titles of movies into Spanish this way,
the good export them to Spain and Latin
America,
other immigrants with other mother
tongues did the same,
and all of a sudden Hollywood movies
could be understood everywhere.
Oh,
but hold on just a second because I can
guess what you're thinking.
Well,
what happens to the movies when they
have sounds?
Well,
actually this was a crucial turning
points in the history of American
movies.
I blog now flows.
Let's have a quick look as an example.
During the times of Nazi Germany,
the government,
they're invested a fortune in
subsidizing German studios,
and of course those companies trying to
export their films to other countries
like Spain.
Spain mounted the dictatorship of
Francisco Franco was a close ally of the
Third Reich.
Nonetheless,
almost no Spanish movie theaters
projected a German movie.
That's why was this?
Well,
the reason is not as idealistic as you
might hope.
It was a pure technological reason.
German studios sent their movies in the
German language and they didn't have
good systems
out of my shell.
Hollywood studios instead had state of
the art methods for Darby plus.
Since they have such a high immigrant
population,
it was easier for them to find
translators and voice actors.
Some countries even had their own
offices in Spain,
so they sent the cellular Lloyd ready to
be replaced with the Spanish audio
track.
There you go.
Yeah.
They don't know about [inaudible].
In other words,
American movies were cheaper to
projections and those from any other
country.
How did this,
the peerless talent of those movie
geniuses like John Ford who came from
Ireland and Ernst Lubitsch who came from
Germany,
those were the ultimate weapons that
drove America to surpass any other
countries.
Movie Industry.
I sit at you liberty.
You pick it up.
Sorry.
Oh yes.
Hollywood was born.
Thanks to those who came from outside
America and Hollywood grew up thanks to
selling their movies to the people
outside.
If America at her,
everybody,
I'm just country kill crazy.
And Tina,
it's really important that I make it
aside in case you've never heard about
John Ford,
do yourself a favor and watch the man
who shot liberty valance.
It's the wonderful film and despite the
black and white,
it hasn't aged.
Show's over.
And now the question might be,
what happens after all of this?
How did Hollywood survive the censorship
and piracy that came later?
If you would like us to tell you that
story,
do let us know in the comments below,
we'd love to hear from you.
Meanwhile,
in this other video,
we tell you the story of how islands
became so rich.
So be sure to check that out.
And also do physics.
Our friends at the reconsider media
podcast,
they provided the vocals in this episode
that are not mine.
And of course,
don't forget that we publish brand new
videos every Monday and every Thursday.
It's so do you subscribe to this channel
so you don't miss any of those?
And if you liked this video,
give us a thumbs up.
And as always,
I'll see you in the next video.
And if you want to learn more about
politics and hear more,
my lovely voice,
don't forget to check out the reconsider
podcast@reconsidermedia.com
and we consider it as a podcast that
challenges you to reconsider your views
by providing context.
But we don't do the thinking.