We've already discussed it here on
visual politic margin.
Tina is a country where football is
practically a state religion ends.
We're not a single decade goes by
without at least one major economic
crisis.
For decades,
this country has been dominated by a
political model,
a kind of ideology,
a political current parent ism,
which is something like a mix of
nationalism,
protectionism and public spending.
Lab another job
in 2015,
and you governments arrived that have
Mauricio Macri with the mission of
rebuilding the country from the top to
the bottom.
Joel the same vineyard go there
in the 2017 legislative elections.
The Argentine people renewed that trust
in this process.
Basically they came to say,
well,
well done mackery.
So the question that has recently arisen
is,
well,
Ms Dot Argentina finally ready once and
for all for takeoff.
Well,
let's have a look at it.
Shall We?
On October the 22nd 2017 elections for
Congress and the senators were held in
Argentina.
The government in coalition can be a
moss,
has an overwhelming triumph with more
than 10 million votes.
They won 15 out of the 24 electoral
districts,
including the top five.
These are the most populated one spinal
surgeries,
providence,
Buenos Aires city,
Cordoba,
Santa Fe,
and Mendoza.
Something like that hasn't happened
since 1985
right
now,
after these elections.
Can Gay is close to having an absolute
majority,
which ensures the government's ability
to push their reform agenda forward.
No.
For this reason,
several analysts have stated that this
is the true beginning of term,
so after two years of power,
what does mackery done?
What hasn't been done,
and what are his intentions?
You're going to find the answers to all
of these questions in today's video,
but before we do that,
let's take a look back at the history
downfall.
Trigo.
Argentina was one of the richest
countries in the wells,
even richer than countries like Canada,
Australia,
France,
or even
Gemini.
Not only that,
when World War Two ended in 1945,
this country was along with the United
States,
one of the largest creditors in the
world,
and also one of the largest gold owners
on the entire planet at that time when
our salaries,
the Argentine capital was in full swing
and could even rival New York,
but of course having said all of that,
while he might not be wondering,
well,
what the hell happened to Argentina?
Even though things didn't look bad for
this country after the Second World War?
The truth is that something that was
already changed.
Great International Crisis of the 19
thirties affected this country a lot.
Argentina,
which was a huge agricultural exporter,
suffers and just had its first major
financial crisis,
and since that time,
all those years ago,
nothing has been the same.
Six began to intervene in every economic
and societal feels.
Finally,
in 1946,
what we could call it,
the definitive term where it began,
the governments of General Ferrell first
and then Ken or Juan Domingo,
Peron approved all kinds of rules and
laws more than 16,000
in fact,
which puts the economy under state
control,
which for example meant that things like
foreign trade isn't as creation or
competition,
wouldn't really be a priority instead of
policies such as import substitution,
nationalization ends,
launched state enterprises.
They became the order of the day.
This is how a 70 year downfall began,
which made Argentina become one of the
very few countries that has gone from a
developed country to a developing
country economic crisis.
Hyperinflation and payments suspension
has become very,
very common problems.
Talked about in the Argentinian media in
recent decades,
and this process culminated with
coaching tourism from Christina
Fernandez to cut snap man to ruin.
Tell two terms.
As president and Cristina Fernandez de
[inaudible] set up a model that could
simply be defined as uneconomical.
Yeah,
Argentina.
It was already pretty terrible at
business,
but Christina,
she took it a step further.
See,
in CFA is Argentina.
There were capital controls companies,
gonna repatriate their profits,
taxes on companies reached in comparable
proportions in Latin America.
There were lots of restrictions on
imports and the central bank was only
dedicated to making money in order to
finance the governor.
The model was so terribly uneconomic
that CFA at set up a lot of taxes on
exports.
Yes.
Who would really think of punishing
companies that are exporting,
selling to other countries.
It's pretty crazy indeed.
Going to celebrate what he saw.
A ton of posts get Tina independent
dealer Florida or something.
I can't do it,
but that isn't all with Christina at the
helm of the castle respond on the
Argentina Whitehouse.
This country became one of the most
protectionist in all of Latin America
and also a country where setting up
companies was incredibly difficult and
of course the results they were
immediate during his second term growth
was no.
The public deficits sort inflation rose
to 40 percent investment collapsed and
suddenly,
again,
nothing seemed to be.
This is how
in December of 2015,
the Argentinian people chose Mauricio
Macri,
former presidents of Boca junior as the
new president of Argentina.
Tito said he didn't see me in the door.
The end,
the color can dino.
Yeah.
Mauricio Macri is first year at leading
Argentina.
It wasn't easy.
Of course,
this was bound to happen because of the
terrible state that he inherited the
country and for example,
he reduced electricity and natural gas
subsidies,
but because reforms never have immediate
results,
things didn't look so great at the
beginning.
In 2016,
the country suffered a severe recession
with a GDP drop of two point six
percent.
Inflation also approached 40 percent
poverty.
Unemployment deficits and external debt
also increased.
In other words,
there were ample opportunities to
criticize mackerel.
I mean,
wasn't he the one who promised that
things were going to change?
Well,
as we said a minute ago,
reforms do not have immediate results,
but in the end those changes,
they do arrive in 2017.
The Argentine economy was finally
showing signs of improvement.
This year's growth may exceed three
percent in the appetite for investment
is already more than evidence.
Yep,
that's right.
It looks like Argentina maybe coming out
of that
tunnel.
Philadelphia
being these results have given macri the
great electoral victory that we've just
seen.
Now we come to the question of,
well,
what exactly did the president do?
Well,
basically he reduced all of the crazy
regulations and policies that have been
put in
place.
The new government,
it seemed to work reducing these because
in their eyes there was no time to lose.
As soon as he arrived,
he eliminated currency controls.
He allowed foreign investors to
repatriate their profits,
the eliminated the most incomprehensible
export taxes and reduce subsidies and
restrictions on imports and all of this
was with one clear objective,
Argentina,
to recover its productive economy.
Also,
and this is really important here,
mackery reached agreements with some of
the international investors that
Argentina hadn't paid in 2001 and with
whom it's still had judicial fights.
Tina reached an agreement with the
venture funds after 14 years of struggle
in total to cover all the debts with the
funds,
mccree offers $6,500,
million dollars.
This agreement implies a 25 percent.
Reduction.
On the other hand is the new
government's approved to kinds of fiscal
amnesty which brought to light new less
than a hundred and $17.
Billion Dollars.
Intelligent Indians had a broad and did
not declared,
but before you think this is a huge
scandal,
do you think about what would happen if
you were afraid that your savings could
be confiscated by the government?
Sometimes it's not just about not paying
taxes.
When states don't have legal security,
it's easy for money to simply disappear.
The fact is that with all these
measures,
macaroons,
government has managed to get much of
that money back to Argentina,
and since then there's been an influx of
money which has triggered things like
real estate sales,
car sales.
We are breaking records.
More than 700.
80,000
cars have been sold to this day and most
importantly trucks.
This means that production is moving.
Constructionist moving.
Mauricio Macri,
it looks like the engine,
quite literally it started again,
looks organ will invest $650,
million US dollars to modernize plants
in Argentina,
but
one question arises and that's
everything,
randy.
So exemplary is everything really so
perfect.
Well,
hold on a minute because the truth is
that until now the reforms have been
very,
very gradual than that and had a fairly
limited range,
something in spite of the electoral
results and all those calls to uncork
the champagne has alerted several
experts at the moment of truth.
So far he hasn't done much beyond
removing kitchener ism from power,
which isn't little,
even though he did say that these
elections are the endorsement for the
reforms.
We don't really know what they are,
what he wants to do.
Carlos Rodriguez,
Braun,
Argentina,
economist.
But why so much distrust?
Because despite the reforms we've seen,
it seems that this government is
struggling to overcome some of the
typical problems of Argentina's previous
governments.
For example,
public spending has not decreased.
It continues to rise and rise,
which has caused,
among other things,
foreign debt to soul by more than $50,
billion dollars since macri came to
power and that's not all taxes are
through the roof.
The central bank continues to finance
the government with new money as
according to the latest doing business
reports,
which the ease of doing business in the
country.
Argentina is still way down in 116th
place.
Now,
to be fair,
we can see the macro has pretty good
excuses.
First is that not much time has passed
and second is political position in
Congress in the Senate was very weak
now,
but after these last elections,
all of that is finally over reformist
agenda.
It seems that often has crushing
electoral trump.
President Macri has made it clear we are
entering a stage of permanent reformism.
Argentina doesn't have to stop.
It doesn't have to fear reforms because
to reform is to grow,
to evolve,
to progress the ratio mccree.
He certainly has a task out of him,
which is somewhat complicated.
Well,
what are his priorities?
fundamentally view at first,
it's something that is as popular as it
is necessary,
reducing public deficits and controlling
inflation which are ultimately related.
Then he's going to get Argentina back to
being a competitive and attractive
country in which to invest.
To achieve this,
it has promised to approve a tax reform
that reduces taxes on businesses and the
labor reform that facilitates hiring as
well as more free trade agreements.
Argentina and Chile signed the most
ambitious free trade agreement in 20
years.
Then pension,
educational,
and infrastructure reforms.
The next yes,
we can assess and say the macro has a
lot of work to do if you want us to meet
the high expectations that have been
placed
on him.
In any case,
it does seem as if a new political and
economic era has begun the entre.
Tina,
a good example is [inaudible] commitment
to reducing poverty by formalizing and
extending property to the most
disadvantaged.
Argentina delivers housing certificates
to one point 5 million people in slums.
Government will give them the documents
to access water and electricity legally.
By the way,
we will be discussing how to find
poverty in a future video.
Subscribe for now.
The question is,
will this country become great?
Once again,
if they manage to deepen their reforms
and take advantage of all their
opportunities,
it's not trans.
The lithium industry,
which we've discussed previously.
I have little doubt that this will be
the case and now we want to know what
you think will Argentina become a great
example for the rest of Latin America?
Do let us know in the comments below as
well as in this day and I really hope
that you enjoyed this video.
Please hit that like button if you did,
and don't forget to subscribe to our
channel for brand new videos every
Monday and Thursday button on the screen
as well as below me now.
Also,
do check out our friends at the
reconsider media podcasts.
They provided the vocals in this episode
that went on mine,
and as always,
thank you for watching.
Tito said he didn't think it put me in
the end.