Question,
can a poor country reasonably aspire to
become a high income one within a few
years?
Second question,
how much time would they really need?
And third question,
how would they do it?
These are some of the most common
questions that you send us pill on this
channel.
We've seen in various videos how several
countries have managed to change that
luck.
It's become locomotive swells of you.
In this video I want to tell you about a
very particular case.
I want to tell you about Poland's
because Poland's becoming something of a
new Germany.
Well,
listen up.
Here's a question for you,
Andy.
As always,
please do not google.
Which do you think is the city with the
most Polish inhabitants,
Warsaw and Krakow?
Well,
wrong.
Actually it would be Chicago.
2 million Polish people live in Chicago.
Yes.
We own really not getting here.
Give you a.
it's not been easy for polls.
During the Second World War,
Poland was the country that suffered the
most.
No less than one.
Out of every five poles,
that's almost 6 million people,
which is the conservative estimate by
the way,
lost their lives.
Then after that disaster,
they endured 44 years of a communist
governments who in addition to exerting
an enormous amount of political
repression also left them as a poor
country in 1989 when the system came to
an end,
Poland's per capita income was between
three and five times smaller than that
of developed countries such as Italy,
France,
or the United Kingdom,
but just hold on a second because things
they've really changed.
Portland's a country located halfway
between Paris and Moscow and has $40
million inhabitants completely changed
its model and since they've done this,
a very economy has grown by over four
percent every year.
Yeah.
All right,
so now you might be thinking,
did I just put too much emphasis on four
percent a year because it doesn't sound
that impressive.
This is.
Especially if you compare it to the
pretty crazy growth rates that you can
see in the Asian tigers for present kind
of sounds like a drake,
right?
Well folks,
if you are thinking that you are missing
a couple of important things,
details
is that we're talking about almost 25
years of uninterrupted economic growth
here.
Not even the great crisis of 2008 and
2009 really affected this country at
all.
We can say the ponens moving kind of
like a giant cargo ship.
It's not the fastest ship on the water
for sure,
but it has moved and incredible distance
another way young Polish people have
pretty much no idea what an economic
crisis is like.
The second detail is also very important
to it because I'm like,
what happens with the Asian Tigers?
Poland's has had this huge growth while
being a consolidated democracy and by
the way that really kind of dispels and
important myth here and that's that
countries need a strong hands in order
to grow.
Well anyway,
thanks to this grief,
Poland has had an amazing 25 years.
This country has gone from having
average salaries are between 10 to
15,000 American dollars per month to
having a panic capita income taking into
accounts each country's price
difference.
This in 2018 will be higher than that of
Greece,
Portugal and every Latin American
country,
and the reality is it's not really that
far behind Spain or Italy either.
Then goes into this point,
I think there's a question that we
really need to answer.
How did they achieve this?
Well,
listen up because that's what we're
going to talk about in today's video.
The end of an era,
34 years from 1945 to 1989,
the socialist state of the People's
Republic of Ireland,
the satellite country at the Soviet
Union was in power by the way,
to give you an idea of how great
Moscow's control was,
it said that when in 1950,
the Polish leader Bolus Law Barrett show
Joseph Stalin himself a draft of the
future Polish constitution,
that the leader of the Soviet Union made
dozens of corrections by hands,
which of course were taken into account
anyway.
The Polish regime was one of the least
harsh in the entire Soviet orbit.
For example,
most of the lands wasn't collectivize.
The Catholic Church was allowed to
function with relative freedom cans.
Even though political repression was
high,
it wasn't quite as intense as it was
another country.
Even though of course,
as in any good socialist country,
the state controlled almost everything,
and in 1989,
it's economy completely shattered.
Now,
thanks to all these small freedoms or
real political opposition emerge,
lead among others by lack of Valenzuela,
the leader of the Independent Solidarity
Union,
the thirst for union of all eastern
European country.
Thanks to this.
When the Soviet Union's power began to
crumble,
Poland's became the first country in
eastern Europe to set its political
transition in motion to completely
abandon communism and so on.
June the fourth,
19,
89,
the first relatively free elections were
held,
and with that it was no turning back
shock therapy.
Just a few months
after the first elections in September
of 19 nine,
the minister of Finance,
less egg bow Sarah of it sets a plan on
the table to shred the entire communist
fabric and to replace it with a
capitalist model.
Three months later,
this shock therapy as it's been known as
launched,
exerted a liberal program called shock
therapy.
The idea was either the patient improves
or dies from one day to the next.
Everything was liberalized in a very
rigid and centralized economy in which
prices and needs had nothing to do with
reality.
He called it the lunar economy.
Everything was fiction or pvh.
Nia Oshinsky,
Polish diplomat.
Suddenly everything changed.
Sure.
Prices were liberalized.
Controls were lifted,
people were able to set up private
businesses.
They stopped printing money.
The economy began to open up to the
world and the plan was launched to
privatized public enterprises within a
short time,
not even the polls could recognize
Poland's.
Also,
the government's had a very clear idea
about the future.
Ponant needed to get as far away from
Russia as possible and strengthen its
ties with the rest of Europe and the
United States.
So what was the result of all of this?
Well,
a few years later,
they joined the European Union and NATO.
Now,
what model do you think the country has
followed since
change?
Of course,
I've already told you plenty of times
the world is getting better.
Poverty is decreasing and countries are
getting rich yet,
but despite this belonging to the club
of rich countries is still a difficult
mission.
Even so,
everything points to Poland achieving
this within a very short amount of time.
Dev,
this country is becoming eastern
Europe's Germany.
See,
Poland has become an industrial power
house,
flooded with multinationals and like in
Germany,
it's smaller.
Medium sized companies have begun to
cross the border.
The results I'll since 1999,
it's foreign trade has multiplied by
more than 25 Polish exports amount to
almost $200,000,000,000 per year,
which represents more than 40 percent of
the country's GDP,
which is a seriously high.
Simply explains why Polish roads off
full of trucks.
Now you must be wondering,
well,
how are they achieving all of this?
What on earth is the key to their
success?
Well,
Dave,
you are taking notes at the Polish
recipe has four main ingredient to the
establishment of institutions that
attract a lot of foreign investments,
legal,
security,
property rights,
ease of setting up companies and
competition.
For example,
14 special economic zones have been
created where any interested company can
gain many advantages.
Second,
strict controls of public accounts.
Homelands.
Government is one of the most healthy in
the European Union.
Public debt,
for example,
is barely 50 percent of the GDP and
almost as importantly since 1989,
they have been set on fighting
inflation,
so no printing bills to finance the
government.
Basically the opposite of countries like
Argentina,
first quality education,
Yep.
You heard that rise.
Poland has managed to make their
educational system work and they've done
this without wasting huge amounts of
money.
It's rate of university students is
higher than the average of the European
Union.
Nine out of 10 young people complete
secondary education,
and according to international studies,
the Polish education system is one of
the 10 best,
not just in Europe,
but in the whole world and forth.
There's moderate taxes.
For example,
companies are taxed 19 percent while
smaller companies are taxed 15 and
income tax breaks down into two
brackets,
18 percent for the first 24,032 percent
for the rest.
And in addition,
because Poland is a fairly conservative
country,
families have even more advantages.
So if we take into account both personal
taxes and pension payments,
Poland is the fourth one,
cd country where families pay less
direct taxes,
right?
So it's with these four ingredients that
Poland has managed to become eastern
Europe's Gemini and exports and
industrial power with a healthy
governments can take quality of life
that just keeps on growing.
The best proof of this is perhaps that
within a few years the great power of
the east has gone from being a country
of immigrants to the country of
immigrants from a country of immigrants
to a country of immigrants.
In recent years,
if something has characterized the
Polish economy,
it's the simple availability of work.
Unemployment is approaching six percent
and many companies are beginning to have
a problem finding workers.
Initially,
foreign companies would only look for
highly experienced employees with
titles.
Now they take everyone and give them a
month training if necessary.
Roman and Lake entrepreneur and of
course if companies need a lot of
workers and can't find them,
I'll wages go up.
The average gross salary in the first
quarter of 2018 was seven point one
percent higher than in the same period.
In 2017.
Average gross salary exceeds $1,400 per
month with central statistics,
office of Poland.
And you know what this situation has led
to,
well,
first,
many young poles who until recently left
on master Richie European Union
countries deciding to stay.
I'm second.
In recent years,
more than 2 million Ukrainians have
settled in Poland,
especially young people looking for
better opportunities than the ones they
could find in their country of origin.
This means the Poland now has more
people arriving than leaving.
Now,
as we always say,
visual politic.
Not Everything is so great.
Portland is facing quite a serious aging
problem.
Ends the Lore Justice Party,
a very nationalist and very conservative
party,
won every recent election and now
controls the country some of their
decisions.
Of course,
the European Union threatened Poland's
with sanctions and even suspends their
rights as a member,
but that's something we're going to
address in a future video now.
It's your time.
Do you think ponens would be a good
example for Cuba or with the Chinese
model actually be better?
Well,
leave your answer in the comments
section below as well as in this survey
and I really hope you enjoyed that
video.
If you did,
please don't forget to subscribe to our
channel for brand new videos.
Also,
do not forget to check it off.
Friends and the reconsider media
podcasts.
They provided the vocals in this episode
and as always,
thank you for awhile.