Let's don't today's video with a
question.
Which country would you say is the US?
His biggest ally is a Canada.
Maybe it's the UK as well.
What about Israel?
Now,
this is not an easy question.
Zones are,
and it definitely depends on who you
asked.
Whether that is a country which has
improved.
It's aligns with the U.
s a great deal over the last few years.
It has improved enough that it is for
Republicans,
the best friend of the country,
its biggest ally more so than any other
country.
I know it's not Canada and the UK or
Israel.
It is Australia.
The country of Surf Kangaroos and the
Sydney Opera House.
Surprised.
Well you shouldn't be.
Australia is Devi.
You are the only country in the world to
have fought with the US in all of them.
Big Wars,
World War One,
World War II,
Korea,
Vietnam,
the Gulf War,
Afghanistan,
Iraq,
and now we'll see the operations against
isis for the bends.
Again,
we could almost say that Australia is to
the USA.
What these score is to Imovie and at
first might go unnoticed,
but remove that music and you can see
that it's really something that's going
to be missed on January the 28th,
2017,
and despite this old alliance,
Donald Trump decided to hang up the
phone on Malcolm Turnbull,
Australia's prime minister,
not just that though before we told him
to get lost and hung up on him at trump,
accused him of trying to export
terrorists,
do the United States,
and this was all just about a slight
disagreement that these two countries
had over 1000,
250 refugees,
but that's the story that we're going to
get into another day.
Yes,
this brief diplomatic tussle might not
seem like that much in the grand scheme
of things,
but it has had a lot of consequences.
Many Australians are left wondering if
it isn't time to start cooling off the
relationship with the United States.
Spike just listen.
Well naturally.
This is something we started wondering
as well.
It raises questions like how important
is Australia for the United States and
was it really sensible for trump to hang
up the phone on his greatest ally and
all kinds of consequences?
Is this going to have for him?
Well,
let's take a look.
Shall we time for Asia,
probably not news to you,
especially if you've been following this
channel for a while else has changed
ends.
Both the political and economic power
centers are moving quickly to Asia,
like 20,
20.
It is expected that more than half of
the world's economy and population will
be located in this continence and China
is emerging as a new superpower as well.
That's a fact.
I've been told now a map of the world
has looked pretty close to
why
from now on,
we're going to see things looking closer
and closer to this.
Yes,
as you
can see,
Europe is leaving the center of the Weld
Indians taking up a position in the
corner.
All right,
so that's a fun comparison,
but we come really denied that the
world's changing.
What the hell is that?
It's where you've been living this whole
time,
the 20th century.
It's going to be Asia's century
something.
We've discussed a bunch of visual
politic that is my former US president,
Barack Obama decided to bet strongly on
Asia and make this continent is top
priority for American diplomacy.
It was under these circumstances that
Australia became such a valuable
friends,
but how close is this friendship between
the US and Australia?
Well,
let's have a place to look.
Okay.
Big Alliance,
November of 2011,
Barack Obama and Australia's prime
minister at the time,
Julio Guillaune signing military
agreements,
which meant a new era for military
cooperation between these two countries.
We could always say that this new treaty
started a military friendship between
the US and Australia.
In fact,
let's take a look at the description.
The New York Times wrote about this
agreement agreement with Australia and
mounts the first longterm expansion of
the American military presence in the
Pacific since the end of the Vietnam War
bus.
Well,
what did this agreements,
what did it really mean?
Well,
for starters,
thanks to the treaty,
the US can deploy a floating force of up
to 2,500 soldiers in Australia.
These treats are from the Marine Corps
and they are able to quickly deploy it
in the event of any conflict,
but don't think that this is the end of
things.
Since the collaboration between these
two countries has grown and grown,
it has grown enough to become an
essential relationship for Washington.
It's not just the marines.
The United States wants to make
Australia the key home base for their
activities in both the Pacific and
Indian Ocean.
Now you're probably getting the idea the
US wants to have access to landing
strips situated in the north of the
country.
From here.
They want to be able to deploy B,
two and B,
52 bombers.
They also sent out a large naval base
near path for their enormous fleet of
nuclear aircraft carriers and nuclear
sub
marines
and there's more.
The United States is also trying to
locate and monitoring centers and
missile launch warning facilities that
to even once he rents parts of the Coco
islands in the Indian Ocean,
which an Australian sovereignty.
So you might now be thinking,
what do you need?
Why would the United States wants to
rent some random remote islands in the
Indian Ocean?
Well,
the answer is actually pretty clear.
The US wants to locate to their long
range surveillance aircrafts and armed
drones on the Coco Islands.
They also wanted to use this archipelago
as another deployment center for that
bombers in case of war,
but wait,
because there is still more,
the United States wants to improve the
integration between their army and the
Australian military so that the two
forces could work together whenever need
it.
Now,
if you don't exactly understand what the
results of this could be,
well,
do consider this in the last few years,
Australia has carried out a significant
renovation of them military equipment.
We're talking about purchase contracts
worth billions and billions of dollars
and among these there is quite a lot of
American material.
Take the controversial f 35 as an
example,
Australia has committed to buying 72
units,
which is going to cost $19,000,000,000.
This is a serious amount of cash and
it's.
We're talking about the country with a
little more than 24 million inhabitants.
It's like per person.
It's really a lot of money.
Alright,
so now you've got to be wondering why
Australia,
right?
Well that's for several reasons.
First because both countries are
culturally similar and as we've said
before,
they fought together and many times,
seconds it's because Australia's
geographical position is almost perfect.
It's situated between the Indian and the
Pacific oceans and it is close enough to
the hot spots in Asia that the US could
carry out attacks and deploy troops
there quickly and last but not least,
there's another important factor.
Australia is an important energy,
raw material and food suppliers or
Trynna,
so it depends again,
believes that in the event of a conflict
or tough tensions between the two
countries,
it would be convenient to have control
over Australia.
I'd say,
well,
what about the other side?
What do the Australians once they
basically understand that the US can
sort of be an insurance policy,
no way to ensure their own safety.
Some voices who disagree,
these voices,
they seem to be growing louder and
further.
Trump hasn't helped with his whole
hanging up the phone
thing.
That Chinese alternative
China.
It is by far the largest trade partner
for Australia.
It is the first destination for
Australia's exports.
It's the country of origin for many of
the immigrants coming to Australia and
besides that on more and more Chinese
people who visit the country every year
who have decided to study that anyway.
The Chinese mean a lot of money for the
Australian and well that has its
consequences.
A 2016 survey conducted by the Public
Policy Group Lowy Institute asked
respondents to identify the country that
was more important to Australia.
Forty three percent chose the United
States and 43 percent China in 2014,
48 percent had answered the United
States and only 37 percent had chosen
China,
New York Times and look
under 45 year olds clearly have opted
for China and almost half of the
country's population believed their
country should keep some distance from
trump's America book eating and
important Australian x prime minister,
for example,
is one of the personalities.
He thinks it would be best at trying to
improve relations with China and less
relations with the United States,
cooled down a bit and pay particular
attention to how he explains his.
The Society of artists is a better
society than the United States.
It's more even.
It's more fair.
We've had a 50 percent increase in real
incomes in the last 20 years.
Media in America has had zero zero for
now.
Australia has made some
kinds of gestures towards the Asian
giants.
As an example of when spanaway
Washington didn't like this at all,
the country decided to participate in
the Asian infrastructure.
Investment Bank and institution led by
China whose aim is to increase China's
influence in the country.
The Australian government itself has
made it clear that China is above all a
source for opportunities for the
country.
Luckily for trump though,
there are still many things that protect
his relationship with Australia,
American culture and the fear of the
Chinese.
Australia.
I'm the US all politically,
culturally and economically similar
countries.
They are so similar.
In fact,
it's an international level that it
could be argued that Australia is
nothing more than an extension of the
American lifestyle in Asia,
and the truth is that a lot of
Australians are pretty proud to be
considered
that way.
Whatever happens,
I will not tell my affection for the
American people and the best of American
culture that was not raised in America,
but I was raised in the American
century.
I have not yet ready to say goodbye Lisa
prior.
Furthermore,
the United States is still the largest
investor in Australia and investment.
If that exceeds $500,000,000,000.
Yes,
mostly the fact that China is still a
dictatorship is making Australia
suspicious.
Many simply don't trust Beijing's
intentions.
In fact,
the government has stopped and many
Chinese investments operations that
intended to buy land in Australia,
so we can't say that it kind of all of
indicates that the alliance with theu s
will continue,
but the Australians,
while there are very practical people
and they have made it clear that they
don't want to be affected by a future
hypothetical war of power between China
and the United States.
It's like,
well,
that's what we think here at visual
politic,
and now we'd love to know what you
think.
Do you think the United States will
despise trump,
uh,
carry out the projects they had planned
to do in Australia?
Or do you think China will achieve more
and more influence in the country?
Well,
most importantly,
how would you feel if trump hung up the
phone on your country's leader?
So if you did enjoy this video,
please do hit that like button.
And don't forget to subscribe below and
stay tuned for new videos.
We put them out twice a week.
Also check it off.
Friends at the reconsider media
podcasts.
They provided the vocals in this episode
that went online.
And as always,
thank you for watching.
What are your chances to get out of here
with that jacket on?