Here's a question for you.
How much does the U s actually pay for
its army and all the military operations
that they carry out day after day,
all over the
wow.
Well,
that's precisely what we're going to try
and answer in this video.
But there's no debate when it comes to
one thing.
And that's the,
they're military industry is one of the
most opaque,
most influential hands,
most powerful industries in the United
States.
It's,
well that's true for the United States
as it is for pretty much anywhere else
in the world too.
So I'm starting the question that I
posed to just a moment ago.
It means no more or no less than opening
a debate with a rather large
implications for,
in this case,
the bill.
And it could be hundreds of billions of
dollars.
So having given that wanting,
uh,
let's see what is happening within the
corridors of both the,
again and the Capitol talking about the
u s army is going to involve exorbitant
figures as well as a huge amount of
bureaucracy and political machinery.
So big amps,
so opaque is this institution that we
can practically talk about.
A parallel governor.
Yes.
In 2015 a report and made by the
Pentagon itself stated that they had to
pay tens of billions or pizza,
tens of billions of dollars every year
for extra costs caused by bad management
practices in the army.
Best Practices such as paying private
contractors,
more money than would be expected in a
competitive market.
We're going to be in peril because we're
spending dollars like it doesn't matter.
Robert L stine managing director
chartwell capital management and former
chairman of the defense business board,
and do you know think that it's only the
big military industrial companies,
those who produce fighters,
missiles,
and other military equipment?
Not at all.
In fact,
a good part of all of those billions
that have operated each year come from
activities such as accounting,
logistics,
or human resources.
You heard that,
right?
In fact,
the bureaucracy of the US armed forces
this super big,
that's it.
Employees,
no less than a million people.
Take a look at this graphic from the
Washington Post.
As you can see,
the u s army,
it has almost as many people in its
officer's doing administrative
activities as it does people who are
preparing for war or performing national
security tasks.
I had all of this,
of course,
it comes with an enormous costs.
Almost a quarter of the military budget
is invested in these types of tasks,
tasks,
that's all,
well,
let's say importance,
but I really,
a quarter of the money,
if you consider it another way,
all of this bureaucracy alone by itself,
counselors,
the third largest military budget in the
world,
which actually wouldn't be too far
behind the second biggest military
budget and that sort of China,
and that's not all according to a study
by the Department of Defense itself,
published in October,
2017 approximately one out of every five
installations that the again has do
nothing being synthy sit idle and they
could be closed with no military
consequences whatsoever.
And this would save millions of dollars
per year per each one.
But this is something that isn't really
quite supported by the politicians in
Washington.
Everything that has to do with the
Pentagon and the US Defense Department
involves talking about some gigantic,
hyper bureaucratic and very,
very expensive structures.
Well,
as we're going to see later in this
video,
all of this waste is very important in
the political debate,
but for now,
let's see how much money these military
adventures really costs the United
States.
Okay,
cost of war.
Does he know?
Just say says military adventures aren't
randy that strange if we count the Cold
War,
the United States has been at war since
homicide.
It's,
we all know it since the end of 2001 the
u s military has been involved in active
combat every year.
Syria operations in the Indian Ocean,
Africa,
Yemen,
and Eastern Europe and above all Iraq
and Afghanistan.
It doesn't look like it's ending anytime
soon.
So now with all of this going on all
around the world,
can you imagine how much this stuff
costs?
Well,
pay attention here because the numbers
are probably more scandalous than you
think.
Cool.
Before we get into these numbers,
let's mention a quick side note here.
One thing is the annual defense budgets
and another thing is the operating
budgets.
This means that when we hear about how
much the US spends on its army,
the cost of wars and military operations
themselves,
arms usually taken into account all the
factors there.
Since 2001 US taxpayers have spent just
in those military adventures and loan a
whopping one point $7 trillion,
one point $7 trillion by the way,
is more than Canada's GDP and almost as
much as Italy's put it another way in
today's dollars that is more than twice
what the Vietnam War costs or five times
that of the cost of the Korean War
bought DB Capitol Hill.
Because if you think this is a high
figure,
well wait just a minute because we
aren't done yet.
Cool
of the Iraq and Afghanistan wars for
example,
isn't over,
and I'm not referring only to the
military expenditures that or has,
but also to the costs that have already
occurred,
which the federal governments will have
to pay for in the future.
Of course costs
such as long term medical care for ex
combatants due to injuries produced in
combat expenses for veterans,
and of course the cost of the debts
incurred to finance the war in total
estimate states that these p was alone.
Again,
it ends up costing between four and $6
trillion.
That is just a vast amount of money to
get some idea of the real costs here.
This is the equivalent to all of the
military expenditure for all European
NATO countries for the next 15 to 23
years.
All of these military adventures,
they are a total financial,
yeah,
mess.
Well,
we think that countries should take a
look at these bills and be more prudent
in the future.
For example,
when one visits to the United States,
something that draws the attention is
the poor state of its infrastructure,
its roads,
its metro,
its railroads,
et cetera.
In fact,
infrastructure in the u s has the guns
to be a serious problem.
We spend trillions and trillions of
dollars outside of our nation,
but we can't build a road,
a highway,
a tunnel,
a bridge in our own nation and we watch
everything falling into district.
Yeah.
Well
with what the Iraq and Afghanistan wars
of costs,
the United States could have the best
infrastructure in the world.
Wow.
Pasta 30 years.
The American hat,
13 walls spanning 14 point $2 trillion.
What if the spread of proud of them
money on building up the infrastructure?
What if the money spin on the Middle
East,
middle west of the United States,
developing the industry there,
that could be changed a lot.
So it's not peep the other countries
stew jobs from your guys.
It is your strategy.
So far I think things are quite clear.
We have now seen how much Washington is
military adventures around the world if
cost the American people.
No,
I think it's going to be interesting to
see how much the federal government
really spends every year on the fence.
Hands.
I'm going to say that if you haven't
been surprised so far,
you probably are about to be
done.
Scott.
We dominate the sea.
We dominate the land and space
crew,
military expenditure.
Sure.
More or less than the US defense budget
is by far the largest in the wells.
Consider 2017 as an example.
In this year of $560 billion were spent
on the fence,
and of course we also have to add that
$60 billion for operating expenses.
This is approximately three times the
military expenditure of China,
or nine times the military expenditure
of Russia.
However,
these amounts don't,
dude,
all of the expenses that the military
well generates for the u s government.
Consider for example,
the cost of medical treatment for those
wounded in combat or the costs of
veteran expenses.
Have a quick look at this
scruff.
Yes.
As you can see,
if we take all of these expenses into
account that the armed forces expenses
rise above $900 billion par.
Yeah,
that's nearly a trillion dollars and we
still need to consider it national
security expenses like financing
intelligence agencies such as the CIA,
but even if we only take the department
of Defense and nuclear weapons budgets,
which is $620 billion,
we can see how the military efforts in
GDP terms is one of the largest in the
world.
However you want to look at those
numbers.
They are exorbitant,
but before we finish answering today's
question,
let's just wait for a moment because the
u s military dominance is somewhat less
impressive when we consider the
following factors.
First price difference.
That is you comms by the same things
with $1 in the u s as you can with $1 in
China.
If we correct this,
we would see that the u s military
expenditure would be equal to the sum of
China and Russia's military expenditure.
It's still an enormous amounts,
but it's not as impressive.
Pins and this is really important,
we have to consider how things have
changed in recent.
Yes,
allow me to explain her in constant
dollars.
That is adjusting for inflation.
Real defense expenditures have actually
fallen since 2010 by 25% this is
unquestionably the largest reduction in
decades and in a way,
this is what is great.
You're worrying many analysts and
politicians in Washington,
especially the Republican Party,
I understand we're in an election year.
I understand all that,
but how in the world do you refuse to
take up legislation that is only purpose
is to defend this nation,
which is under a shop.
We rely on these young men and women.
We rely on them to defend the nation and
now we won't even act to train,
equip,
pay,
and care for them.
Could it be that despite all the money
for the U S is spending today on
defense,
it's still isn't enough?
Well,
let's consider it.
Yes.
Waning power
since
fall of the Soviet Union.
Yeah,
yeah,
Yup.
That all of you.
Yeah.
You said
z consequent Dan's of the Cold War.
It could be expected that the size of
the United States armed forces has
decreased substantially.
We're talking about fewer submarines,
fewer aircraft carriers,
fewer bombers,
fewer soldiers,
et Cetera,
et cetera.
How has the new equipment has arrived
such as the aft 22 wraps or the b two
bomber,
the f 35 a new class of aircraft
carriers,
new cruisers,
and among other things,
high precision drones and miss
what all of this technological
innovation has had two consequences.
On the one hand it has increased the u s
military capabilities,
but on the other hand it has altered
equipments and operational costs and of
course as we've seen,
the budget has been decreasing in recent
years.
Years of underfunding have given us a
weakened force that despite the hard
work of our brave troops is ill equipped
to handle the missions.
We keep throwing at it.
Edwin j fullmer,
founder and president of the Heritage
Foundation do you to all of this,
the Republican Party,
and also it must be said,
a large part of the Democratic Party
seem to have something quite clear in
their minds.
The military budget must be increased.
Currently
the smallest army since 1940
our navy is at its smallest size.
Since 1917 I would send weapons.
You were crane.
The first thing we need to do to make
America stronger as a strength of our
military
as candidates for the presidency and
famous Arizona Senator John Mccain,
who incidentally is the chairman of the
Armed Services Committee of the
sentence,
is one of the politicians.
He was most committed to this issue and
has proposed raising the military
budgets to $800 billion.
They say that the current scas military
budget,
for example,
of course the accidents that the u s
navy has had in the Pacific,
US Navy relieves admiral in charge of
seventh fleet in wake of deadly disaster
at see,
this is as well as causing new and
emerging threats such as that if North
Korea or an increasingly strong China,
and as you can imagine,
dealing with these increasing threats is
not going to be
she
doing and modernizing the nuclear
arsenal that is,
and nuclear weapons bombers,
missiles,
and submarines is trump promised,
implies an investment in the next 30
years of more than one point $2
trillion.
However,
if you spend more than anyone else,
much more,
in fact,
and you all still note Belita,
shouldn't you perhaps be rethinking your
strategy should in the u s perhaps
modifying his role in some way so it's
not as involved in so many conflicts
around the world.
And further there's the question of
whether military expenditure,
it really helps national security or
does it really just help the arms
industry.
And it's important to note here that
that arms industry does generously
finance lobbyists and political
campaigns.
Well,
if he's hanging out the questions and
the answers that pretty much are your
penance,
but now it's your turn.
Do you think that the u s should
increase its military budgets?
Well,
leave y'all on.
Sit in the comment section below as well
as in this survey as I really hope you
enjoyed that video.
Please do hit that like button if you
did and do not forget to subscribe to
our channel for brand new videos every
Monday and Thursday.
And as always,
check it off.
Friends at the reconsider media
podcasts,
they provided the vocals in this episode
that were not mine.
And as always,
thank you for,
we currently have the smallest army
since our navies are the smallest size
since 1917 I would send weapons.
You were crane.
The first thing we need to do to make
America stronger as the strength of our
military.