Have you ever heard of bill?
Just online threats from Baghdad?
It seems probable that geography
students will seem to have to learn the
name of this capital city as well as its
new country,
and that would be a rocky Carter stock
the 25th of December this year.
What's the historical moments for the
more than 5 million Kurds who currently
live in this autonomous community in the
north of Iraq?
Well,
why was this?
that's because of after decades of
unfulfilled promises and ethnic
repression,
they have the opportunity to vote in a
referendum organized by the regional
governments of Kurdistan since 2005 and
according to the constitution of Iran,
Kurdistan is an autonomous region.
Despite it being an autonomous region,
though this place essentially works as
it's own almost independent country,
and the result of this was that the
population really wanted to be fully
independent.
The day of the referendum,
Kurds showed up on mass to the polling
stations.
Even the speakers of mosques encouraged
voters to go to the polls.
Well,
the final results showed the referendum
was a complete success.
More than seven out of every 10 Kurds
went to vote.
That's almost 3.1 million voters.
The victory.
Well,
it was overwhelming for those who
supported independence,
the movements it's obtained.
92.73% of the vote,
and you know what's what?
This triumph.
That's totally understandable because
we're talking about some of the most ill
treated people in history.
They will treat it despite the fact that
the Kurds are recording to many experts,
the most ancient people in this entire
region.
It is estimated that their culture,
their language,
their rituals,
essentially everything that could define
them have been in this part of the
world's upper Mesopotamia for more than
4,000 years.
In fact,
many of these experts consider the city
center of Erbil,
the capital as the oldest human
settlement to be continuously inhabited
on the planet.
In other words,
the Kurds Zam bolder than the Persians,
or indeed the Arabs.
However,
they have suffered from all kinds of
persecution.
See,
the total number of kids is it rounds at
30 million spread across mainly for
countries,
Turkey,
Iran,
Syria,
and Iraq.
Well in all of these places,
the Kurds have suffered the consequences
of nationalism,
which is trying to make them disappear
as a community.
They've tried to do ends their culture,
their language,
as well as trying to close down their
media outlets.
Between 1986 and 1989 Saddam Hussein
launched the amf full campaign and
estimation saw the between 50,002
180,000 Kurds died.
As a result,
as you might imagine,
this cannot easily be forgotten.
My grandfather had a good sense of
humor.
He used to say that he was born,
occurred in a free country.
Then the Ottomans arrived and said to my
grandfather,
your Ottoman,
at the fall of the Ottoman empire,
he became Turkish.
The church left and he became a gert.
Then the British arrived,
so my grandfather became a subject of
his Gracious Majesty.
The British invented Iraq,
so my grandfather became Iraqi,
but to his dying breath,
he was never proud of being Iraqi in air
or saline.
My father's rifle,
a childhood in Kurdistan.
Considering the history,
it's no surprise that the Kurds once,
once and for all to make the dream of
having their own state come true.
And if we add up the facts,
there's Iraqi had a stone is quite a
rich area in terms of oil and natural
gas as well as fresh water.
By the way,
we can understand even more why they
want independence.
So just some of,
cause they wanted that right and country
and say they held a referendum in order
to do that.
The referendum,
as we have said,
Kurdistan is almost an independent
country already.
They even have their own army of more
than 200,000 soldiers.
This army is called the Peshmerga and
they've,
by the way,
he'd been the main defense to Islamic
state in Iraq.
Do bear this in mind because the
governments of Kurdistan is a close ally
of Washington.
Indeed,
it may be their most loyal ally in the
region because of this,
the u s has trained,
financed and well armed their army.
So I'm indeed even save that the Kurds
are as pro American is the taxes.
So after many difficult years of intense
fighting against Islamic state,
it has been clear for the Kurds.
There are almost no advantages in
remaining in Iraq and the governments
have a bill took advantage of these
battles in order to integrate curd areas
into that political space.
For example,
there is the province of Coco who has a
majority of Kurds but was not within the
autonomous region of Kurdistan.
Go Cook is something of a crown jewel.
And one of the main reasons for the
conflict with the Iraqi government,
by the way,
as not hesitate to just send their
troops over to recover the settlements.
Iraqi forces sweep into Kirkuk checking
Kurdish independence drive.
So why is this territory so valuable?
Well,
that's because curt cook is the province
that contains the most Eileen Curtis
start.
In fact,
it's been estimated that around 10% of
all Iraqi oil reserves are concentrated
here in car cooked and nobody wants to
let
good
in 2007 a referendum.
It should have been conducted in order
to incorporate or not the autonomous
region of Kurdistan.
The voting in never took place.
So when the peshmerga occupying the city
in order to protect it from Islamic
state,
since the Iraqi army had literally run
away,
the curd governments had facto annexed
the territory.
So with these conditions and with the
constant negotiations between Baghdad
and beale men's with a growing
disconnect between both territories,
they eventually got the referendum.
This is the first time in history that
the people of Kurdistan will freely
decide their future.
After that,
we will start talks with Baghdad to
reach an agreement over borders,
water and oil.
Mister Barzani,
president of Iraqi Kurdistan,
now the governments of Iraq at post this
referendum in every way as a
constitutional court of Iraq,
even our Lord is parliaments asked for
many things,
including the withdrawal of
representation in our bill.
Lee bought a clothes and even army
deployments in Kirkuk.
There was also the prosecution of
organizers of the referendum,
and it's,
of course,
parliament tried their best to remain in
control of all of the oil.
But even with this kind of action by the
Iraqi government to the Kurds,
they didn't really care.
Okay.
That's the only logical because despite
the progress of the Iraqi army,
the risk for Kurdistan is probably not
in Iraq,
but rather with the international
community,
you see Turkey and Iran,
they don't even want to hear about an
independent Kurdistan.
That's because it might give the Kurds
in their territory is the idea that they
can replicate this success.
So lucky for instance,
there's been at war with the Kurds for
decades,
but that's a story for another day.
The thing is that these countries have
allied with Iraq in order to defy the
referendum.
Turkey's military has confirmed that
Turkey and Iraq will conduct a joint
military drills in Turkey along an area
bordering Iraq,
semi autonomous Kurdish region.
Iran's semiofficial,
I s n a news agency reported on Sunday
that the Supreme National Security
Council,
a closed Iranian airspace to the Iraqi
Kurdish area at the request of the
central government in Baghdad and
there's no way,
it's not just about the possibility of
conflicts after all,
this is likely to be the result of fear
tactics,
which are very usual in this kind of
situation and they rarely work.
By the way.
Remember Kurdistan is a close ally of
the USA and they haven't experienced and
well trained army?
No.
The bigger issue here might be that
Kurdistan they need then neighbors this
territory it's landlocked and as they
are very dependent on Turkey both in
order to export their oil,
Dan to import anything that they might
meet,
so a trade blockade,
it would be a serious threat for this
territory.
The KRG is economy depends on one
pipeline that sells oil to international
markets and that pipeline goes through
Turkey.
You shut down that pipeline,
you choke the Kurdish economy.
Bilal Wahab analysts at the Washington
Institute for Near East Policy Bounce
there is more to it than just their
neighbors.
Nobody wants any more tension with this
part of the world.
Internationally speaking,
the referendum didn't get much support.
The U S as opposed to it and Antonio
Guitars,
secretary general of the UN has
described it as dangerous and
potentially disruptive and today Israel
is the only country that supports
independence.
So this might mean the future is not
looking very good.
Right.
Well wait just a second because it's,
despite all of this,
it is very likely the Kurdistan will
achieve independence,
you know,
or later.
The reasons for a new country,
Iraqi Kurdistan,
it's got many issues.
However,
they have managed to become the region
that functions the best in Iraq.
They are the safest and wealthiest area.
I've been to Iraqi,
Kurdistan and number of times it's safer
than Kansas if you're coming from
Baghdad or muscle.
It's practically Switzerland.
Michael J totten American journalists.
Check this out.
In 2014 before the irs offensive,
this region was turning into the most
relevant financial and tourist spot in
Iraq and oasis.
Many businessmen,
both local and foreign skyscrapers,
moles and mentions where it's spreading
like mushrooms after the rain.
That was until Walbro broke out in Iraq
against the Islamic state.
Then most of this development,
it's empty.
You have to stop now,
often an awful few years of walk in 2017
the numbers at bouncing back.
And do you remember that this area is
oil rich?
Some estimations calculate the oil
reserves of Kurdistan at 45 billion
barrels,
but this into words,
Kurdistan would be among the 15 oil
richest countries on earth,
and this isn't a country with this or
more than 5 million inhabitants,
but there's still so much more it rugs.
Kurdistan is quite business friendly.
Indeed.
They like private initiatives.
Something uncommon in this part of the
globe.
The taxes are also attractive and
bureaucracy is not excessive either.
Unfortunately though there is still
plenty of corruption.
The Kurdistan government will do its
best to help the private sector and have
them invest here.
I invite all local and foreign investors
here to take advantage of our laws and
offers and invest Masoud Barzani,
president of Iraqi Kurdistan.
The thing is that this region has enough
going for it to make a Kurdistan,
a prosperous country.
Their first,
our lambs,
high levels of safety and natural
resources,
whether they're geographical location is
beneficial.
It's a place between Turkey,
Iran,
and Iraq.
But on top of all of that,
this new country,
it's only,
well there because people then,
especially Iraqi Kurds had been deported
attacks with chemical weapons and have
suffered all sorts of social engineering
in order to strangle their culture.
And now they have an opportunity to
build their own country for the rest of
us.
Could also benefits from a more
moderate,
prosperous and to free country than the
ones around it in the Middle East would
certainly be better for us.
So now we've got to consider the
problems in Iraqi Kurdistan.
I mean,
first of all,
oh,
they're ready.
Well,
yes,
absolutely.
But that's no excuse to not make this
new country happen first because these
problems exist now with them still being
a part of Iraq and seconds because they
are less serious than the ones in the
rest of the country.
So what about corruption?
Yes,
it's totally there.
And is there oil dependency also?
Yes.
And what about debt?
Well,
yes,
there is that too.
But this is totally normal in this part
of the wells because the rest of Iraq is
in a much worse situation.
Well anyway,
we just wished that bag Dan's a response
does not turn the situation into a
military conflicts.
That would be a terrible scenario for
everyone.
Indeed,
it would be a situation where political
interests prevail above the interests of
the people,
but now it's time for your opinion.
Do you support the idea of the
independence of Kurdistan?
Well,
do you leave your answer in the comments
below as well as in this survey and
don't forget to subscribe to our channel
for brand new videos every Monday and
Thursday.
Also,
do not forget to check out our friends
at the reconsider media podcast.
They provided the vocals in this episode
that were not mine and as always,
thank you for watching.
So you're still here still watching this
video.
Maybe you just let it run and you're not
actually there anymore.
Whatever the case,
if you're listening to this,
I think you should go check out my new
channel.
It's called biographics.
It is of notable historic figures as
well as present day people and give you
some examples.
We've got the queen of England,
Vladimir Air Putin.
There's just two people on the world
central.
It's got Ilan musk coming up,
Arnold Schwarzenegger,
we even the first serial killer,
h,
Hans,
maybe just hh homes.
We look at all sorts of people longer
formed about 20 minutes long diving into
the story of their lives in a similar
style to this.
It's biographics.
If you like this channel,
if you like my other stuff,
you're going to like this as well.
Biographics that is a link in the
description below.
Do go check it out and please do
subscribe.