For decades,
manufacturing companies dominated every
largest company ranking on the planet
because they weren't synonymous with
success and economic power.
Here is,
for example,
and I'm sure it's no surprise,
China's huge economic takeoff in recent
years.
I take over.
It has a lot to do with the
manufacturing industry.
Thanks to it.
So far.
In the 21st century,
the Asian giants is multiplied its
exports by 10 rising from just $257,
billions more than two point
$4,000,000,000,000.
That's why when we think about China,
about the Chinese economy,
it's very easy,
the images of a smoke filled country
full of huge dirty factories with
thousands and thousands of workers
making all kinds of junk for miserable
salaries to come to mind and you know
what?
To be honest,
when you first step into China for the
first time,
you realize that you probably weren't
wrong.
However,
just because this is the China,
we all know,
but it's no longer the only China.
Before we continue,
I got a question for you.
What would you say is the biggest video
game company in the world?
I'll listen up.
We've talked about it in several videos.
China is changing out full speed every
year.
Millions and millions of people leave
poverty behind to become part of the
middle class.
However,
today we're going to focus on a slightly
different aspects on one of the sectors
that's changing the most.
Something that may be quite surprising
to many of you.
I'm talking about China's digital
revolution.
Yep.
You heard that right?
China,
the country of cheap stuff is quickly
becoming a technological giants,
and the truth is that in terms of the
digital terrain,
in many ways it's even ahead of the
western powers.
Don't believe me.
Well,
let's take a look for example of what's
happening with economy.
Just a decade ago,
China's share and the global ecommerce
market was less than one percent.
Today,
almost half 42 percent of all ECOMMERCE
transactions on the planet come from
China.
To give you an idea of what this means,
it's estimated that China's ecommerce
market is already greater than those of
France,
Germany,
the United Kingdom,
Japan,
and the U.
s combined surprised.
Well,
you shouldn't be.
China's digital economy is growing at
four speeds,
and I'm not exaggerating here.
According to the China Academy of
Information and communications
technology,
you have already agreed to it in the
Ministry of Industry and Information
Technology,
the digital economy,
you could already account for 30 percent
of the entire Chinese economy because
it's not just about ecommerce.
The number of Internet users in China
exceeds 700 million people more than the
Internet users in the European Union and
the United States.
Yeah,
yeah.
I know they have many more inhabitants
and in fact the internet expansion rate
is still lower in China than in Europe
or the United States,
but just think about that market sites
that is used magnets years.
All the 700 million people is a lot of
people and yeah,
it's true.
You may have all heard about the great
firewall with which the Chinese
government sends us a lot of services
and websites such as Google,
facebook,
or youtube
issue.
Yes.
Unfortunately,
that firewall does exist and yes,
unfortunately the Chinese government
exerts see huge amounts of censorship on
the information that Chinese citizens
can access,
but despite this,
the Internet is the Internet,
so it's not all that surprising to
realize that the use of vpn networks to
bypass government control rates is not
exactly low in China and besides
everything that isn't,
politics does kind of work with enough
freedom.
In fact,
the Beijing government itself promotes
the development of the Internet and
digital economy as a national priority.
Okay,
so the truth is that the Chinese are
very receptive,
almost passionate about the new digital
world.
For example,
in China,
more than half of all events tickets are
sold through digital channels.
And what's more surprising,
it's estimated that more than 45 percent
of all retailers sell over the Internet.
And other good example can be found in
the fintech sector.
That is financial technology services.
So listen to them.
According
the consulting firm I research in 2016,
mobile payments in China were worth
about five point $5,000,000,000,000,
approximately 50 times the United
States,
$112,000,000,000
market.
Now,
this isn't just about Fintech,
not adult,
the truth is that China has begun to
play a part in almost every sector.
It's very unlikely that in the upcoming
years,
many of the greatest digital and
technological innovations will be born
right here in China,
but just a second because don't think
that this is just some vision of the
future.
It's actually happening right now,
almost one in three Unicorns,
which is what startups valued at more
than a billion dollars on known as his
Chinese one in three in the entire
world.
We're talking about more than 75
companies like the ones you're seeing on
the screen now.
Now you may not have heard of many of
them,
but actually now that I think about it,
you probably haven't heard of most of
them,
but folks,
they all have something in common.
All of these companies are worth more
than a billion American dollars and
they're all Chinese.
These companies are all expected to play
a strong role in the world of
technology.
Okay.
To give you an idea of the type of
company we're talking about,
we'll mention the company on this list
that most of you probably know.
I'm about Dji,
the world's leader in commercial
drainages.
Maybe you know the spark that now the
care,
the Mavic pro.
Well,
it's the company that makes those things
along with them,
of course,
is the group of big players,
Alibaba,
tencent,
Baidu,
me,
Huawei,
et Cetera,
et cetera.
Yeah,
we could say that silicon valley has a
new and powerful.
Right,
so allow me to repeat the question that
I asked at the beginning of the video.
What would you say is the biggest video
game company in the world?
Maybe a French company,
maybe a company located in Silicon
Valley?
Nope,
none of that.
The largest video game company in the
world is ten cent Nasoni non intended.
Not Microsoft,
but tencent.
You see,
even though the company's main business
has nothing to do with video games,
the company is best known for we chat.
This company makes more than
$16,000,000,000
worth of video games each year and
controls more than 10 percent of the
world wide video game industry.
Right.
Have you ever heard of League of Legends
Clash Royale or candy crush?
Well,
to some extent they're controlled by
this Chinese company surprised.
Well,
you shouldn't be.
Perhaps the best example we can find.
The digital and technological revolution
that China is undergoing exists in what
is already known as the Silicon Delta.
Check this out the Pearl River Delta,
the Pearl River Delta has become one of
the most important economic poles on the
planet here,
and we can find some of the engines that
explained the impressive growth of this
region of the world has had in recent
decades.
Among others.
The delta contains places like Hong
Kong,
Macau,
Fascia and Guangzhou,
and Shenzhen.
While it's precisely Shen Zen's case
that can explain what's happening in
this part of the world.
See,
Shenzen is a city of more than 12
million people whose economy has just
surpassed that of Hong Kong.
What
just three decades ago was no more than
a fishing village has become a global
technology epicenter.
To give you an idea of what we're
talking about every single year this
city registers more international
Peyton's than France or the United
Kingdom.
For example,
ten cent was born here,
the company that owns we chat,
the leading messaging application in
China and which you can do practically
everything with in this application.
You can even find real time thermal maps
that show you how busy or shopping
center is at that very moment.
Just 30 years ago,
this Pearl River,
Delta megacity was a mere fishing
village now home to up to 15 million
people.
It hopes to become a tech nirvana for
the world's hardware startups.
The fact is,
this is 1979 when Shen Zen became the
first special economic zone of China.
The city's economy has grown as an
annual average rate of around 22 percent
today as development in growth are
mainly led by digital and technology
companies.
It's companies like royal that aspires
to become the world's leader in folding
touchscreens.
Something that's considered
indispensable for the future of
communications.
Because folks,
you can already see it and you China is
emerging.
We're going to have to get used to more
and more innovations coming from this
country and of course that's a good
thing.
Silicon Valley needs some competition
and that means that in the next few
years,
the pace of technological development
will accelerate more and more.
By the way,
in a future video,
we're actually going to have a long talk
about Alibaba.
Subscribe for Vat,
but now it's your turn.
Do you think shen zen will soon overtake
Silicon Valley as the engine of global
innovation?
I'll leave your answer in the comments
below as well as in this survey and I
really hope you enjoyed this video.
Please do hit that like button if you
did and don't forget to subscribe for
brand new videos.
Don't forget to check it off.
Friends and reconsider media as well.
They provided the vocals in this episode
that we're not mine.
Also,
this channel,
as always as possible because of
patriots fans,
our patrons on that platform,
please do consider joining them and
supporting our mission of providing
independent political coverage,
and as always,
I'll see you in the next week.