We can't hide it here,
a visual politic.
We Love Asia,
man,
that's poorly because we believe that
the world sends him is already on this
continent,
but in the last few decades,
one country has stood out of that crowd
and that's country,
whether it's China
for its huge size and the speed of which
this country is growing.
China deserves to be given the chief
role in this super production that is
changing our harness,
but wait just a second,
let's not rush into this whole thing.
China,
it's certainly not perfect.
Indeed.
The country has some pretty major
problems.
On the 23rd of May,
2017,
Moody's,
one of the three agencies in charge of
rating the solvency and risk of
financial products downgraded the rating
of China's debt and this is the first
reduction Moody's has made on China's
debt in 27 years.
Okay.
Now I know what you're thinking.
Moody's really raising agencies in
general.
I mean they rarely seem to get it right
and yeah,
while it is true,
it is also one of the only things that
we have to judge.
This sort of thing is still
overwhelmingly rely on standard and
Poor's Moody's and Fitch when deciding
whether to buy bonds,
the three issue more than 95 percent of
global bond ratings.
The thing is,
do you view as China has faced two major
threats in the last few years,
less growth and much,
much more debt.
In fact,
this has even led to unimportant
question Cam China go back
crops.
China's great growth.
If we had a time machine and the
opportunity to travel back to Mao's
China,
the country we would find would be
completely different to the one that we
find today.
There wouldn't be any skyscrapers,
any malls.
In fact,
there really wouldn't be much of
anything in the 19 seventies.
China was a mainly agricultural country
and it was extremely painful.
A few years often now had died and man
known as Dung Xiaoping came to power.
He realized that communism,
well,
it really hadn't worked.
It's all immediately put into practice a
set of measures that would change China
for rather these reforms and be changed.
The China has gone through since they're
actually going to be the subject of an
upcoming visual politic video,
so please don't forget to subscribe to
this channel right now.
All right,
done that well.
That's carry on for now.
It's important to you.
Remember something done.
Joe Ping was a turning point for China.
Since then,
China has undergone the greatest
economic revolution in the history of
mankind.
The last three decades.
China has managed to take $500 people
out of poverty
and to become the largest industrial and
trading power on the planet.
In other words,
if we ask any Chinese person about his
or her living standards,
the answer will be now is infinitely
better than it was before.
Please don't get me wrong,
there is still a lot of poverty in
China,
but compared to how it was,
it's a whole lot better today,
but as long as I was saying earlier,
it's certainly not all roses and there
are some serious clouds on the horizon,
a system addicted to debt.
I'll be quick look at this chart which
shows what happens.
Do you Chinese debt in the last few
years?
As you can see,
it goes up and up and up,
and I mean,
well,
that's a seriously steep line on the
other hands.
Look closely at what has happened is do
Chinese economic growth.
As you can see.
Well this Charles,
it's headed in the opposite direction,
so in other words,
in China the economy is declining and
the debt wouldn't stop rising.
Look,
gross terms.
The Chinese debt as multiplying by four
since 2017.
Yeah,
Chinese debt now equals more than 260
percent of the GDP and many analysts
consider this number to be especially
high for a country that has yet to
become one of the richest in the world.
Well,
most of the debt is actually the
responsibility of Chinese company.
Yes.
Well,
the thing is that is a silver lining,
but there is also a significant negative
side and that is an.
All this international expansion needs
money and swell and the great deal of it
as well.
Much of the debt has financed the
expansion of Chinese companies.
They have also paid well for this kind
of nonsense
throughout China.
There are hundreds of cities that have
almost everything one needs for modern
urban lifestyle,
high rise apartment complexes,
developed waterfronts skyscrapers and
even public art.
Everything that is except one major
factor
people so you can get some idea of the
size of all of it has been built in
China in the last few years.
Hey,
attention to the following number.
In just three years,
China is used more concrete than the
United States used in the entire 20th
century and as I said,
everything absolutely everything has
been paid for with debt.
So now we come to a really important
question.
What the hell has happened in this
country to cause it to get into quite so
much debt,
trainees,
governments,
forward
flight
the last few decades.
If you could say that Chinese people
were good at one thing,
well it would be saving money.
This is especially true if the oldest
Chinese citizens,
they work and they save ends weld.
That is pretty much all they do.
So thanks to all of that advert.
China has high investment rates,
but don't be fooled.
What has happened in the last few years,
it has nothing to do with this
intelligence to know what has happened
is we need to go back to 2008 at that
time,
all developed countries and we're going
through a major financial crisis and you
can probably imagine how this affected
China's exports,
which are the engine that keeps driving
China forward.
The truth is that at that time,
the Chinese government was terrifying,
that the country would be affected by
the national crisis,
so in order to prevent it,
they came up with an idea.
The economic system had to be
transformed and they had two beds on
domestic demands.
When it comes through in the mouth of a
politician that's domestic demands thing
almost always means they are planning to
start overspending and swelling.
That's exactly what Beijing did.
The Chinese government started a
colossal program of extra public
spending of 4 trillion UN.
About $600,000,000,000 meant to be used
for building all kinds of
infrastructure,
high speed trains,
underground trains,
highways,
houses,
offices,
Cetera,
box.
They went further than that.
The Chinese government's thoughts and
that government overspending wasn't
enough.
So they had to encourage the companies
to do the same.
So the question was how could they do
that?
Well,
they decided to use a traditional
remedy,
2008,
trying to also started one of the most
expansive monetary policies ever known.
The authorities lowered interest rates
and banks gave money loans to everyone
who asks for them.
They practically establish an open bar
of cheap lumps.
In three years.
The price of housing was an average of
two point four times more expensive to
an apartments which costs $100,000.
Three years before would now be worth
$240,000.
What was the result of all of this?
Well,
companies started to make all kinds of
investments.
They build ghost towns bought our
companies all over the world and engaged
in all kinds of projects.
These are gone.
Whatever crazy,
risky projects they felt like after all
this central bank was pretty much giving
money away.
Reduction in key industries is damaging
both China's economic sustainability and
foreign trade relations.
Obviously many of these projects have
never been profitable,
so the companies can't give the money
back.
So what did they do that?
Well,
they simply asked for new loans to pay
back the old ones and the snowboard kept
rolling and it's getting bigger and
bigger and this is how the Chinese
economy became addicted to debt and now
I've probably got an idea of what you're
thinking.
Stupid private companies,
right?
Well,
not exactly.
More than half of the bank debt in China
consists of loans from state owned banks
to state owned enterprises.
Wait just a second because there is so
much more
Chinese banks,
a weapon of mass.
We've
already seen how China is currently
going,
a debt overdose,
but as if this wasn't enough,
there is another danger hiding in the
bushes back in the shadows.
Banks face certain limitations on the
amount of money they can loan,
but Chinese banks have managed to skip
these controls and in a way these banks
have just copied what American banks
were doing with them.
Mortgages.
Let me explain.
Instead of just giving loans,
they set up off balance companies that
issued the debt that the banks then
bought,
and these surprise surprise,
when you look at the banks accounts are
not listed as loans that are rather as
other investments.
It's actually a pretty smart workaround,
right?
Well,
it is estimated.
The Chinese banks have hidden woven
$2,000,000,000,000 and it has a
straightforward consequence.
Chinese banks can be way less solvent
than their official numbers might
indicate and besides much of this debt
is opaque,
so the actual Chinese desk could be
much,
much higher.
The vast spread of off balance
activities and bank investment actually
means a risk of hidden loans which could
threaten China's financial security,
shrunk fully in ex president of
trainers,
banking regulatory commission and
weights because there's more a growing
number of non bank financial firms also
market their own wealth management
products and invest the money with
little disclosure of where the money
goes.
That's right in the last few years.
Those companies at which get money from
people to make investments that are
risky and as opaque as become more and
more popular as well.
Why is that?
Well,
it's obviously because they're going to
get higher rates of return with those
investments.
The thing is that this craving for loans
has caused quite a bit of indigestion.
This is a risk that the government is
admitted and it has tried to limit
company loans,
but since there are a lot of unsold
ghost towns,
empty houses and bankruptcy,
real estate agencies,
the government has told the banks in the
last few years to give away loans as if
there was no tomorrow because,
well,
the family debt level is still so low
that economists note that China's
mortgage loans increased by 35 percent
in 2016 and now you might be beginning
to see why some analysts a warning that
if they don't stop this debt vortex,
China could become a new Japan,
a country that has been in crisis since
the 1980.
There is still more because now we know
why she jinping and China need
globalization quite so much.
Air companies need foreign markets to
deal with all of the debt that they have
issues.
Boston,
not everything is all doom and gloom in
the future.
Well,
it's still to come in China.
The savings rates are still high,
high enough,
the foreign capital to arrive in the
country.
That's.
That is a risk and Moody's has given the
first warning.
Now it's the time that the government to
start working to make reforms,
and now,
well,
we'd love to know your thoughts.
You can tell us what you think in this
survey as well as in the comments below
this video.
What do you think will happen in China?
Do you think that stagnation?
We'll turn it into a new Japan or do you
think there'll be new reforms which will
open China even more to the West?
Well,
I do really hope that you enjoyed that
video and if you did,
please do hit that like button and don't
forget to subscribe if you haven't
already.
Brand new videos are uploaded every
Monday and every Thursday and do not
forget to track it all.
Friends at the reconsider media
podcasts,
they provided the vocals in this episode
that are not mine,
and as always,
I'll see you in the next video.
Okay.