Why are some countries rich and others
pour?
I mean,
it sounds like an easy question,
but nothing could be further from the
truth.
There in fact is the origin of wealth is
one of the key issues.
If north of the most important issue in
political debates,
they're three and a half million more
women living in poverty today,
the one that president took office.
We don't have to live like this.
I want to give middleclass families and
folks who were striving to give the
middle class some leaf,
all the poor countries poor because
there are rich countries.
Do the richest countries have any
special geographical characteristics
that determine their success?
Oh,
natural resources for source of wealth,
ah,
their inhabitants smarter or most
importantly of all,
is there some limited amount of wealth
that we simply have to distribute?
What does,
if you,
if the answer to all of those questions
was a yes,
then we could say that our luckiest set
and we simply can't change it.
If we're rich,
great,
and if we're poor,
apparently there are only two paths.
Either we quits or we put our trust in
some sorts of Messianic leader who
promises us some kinds of revolution.
Of course,
these revolutions,
well,
they almost always ends up making things
much worse.
[inaudible] Rico said,
I know,
but just all during my mind,
I actually think that this approach is
missing something melt.
Honestly,
I think it's missing rather,
and lots of things.
Obviously folks,
many factors determine whether a country
is rich or whether it is porn,
and in this video we're going to focus
on one of the factors.
In fact,
probably one of the most important
issues of all,
we'll will do so by taking a look at the
history of the entire American
continent.
So listen up America versus America.
Okay.
America one consonance,
two very different realities.
Some countries are very rich and others
very poor.
For example,
check out Canada's park capita income,
even taking a price difference into
account.
It is five times that of El Salvador or
Ecuador.
Then consider the fact that the per
capita income in the U S is four times
higher than it is in Columbia.
Yes,
it's true.
And there's also a group of countries
that we could describe in relative terms
as sort of middle class.
We've got Chili and Panama.
The income is three times that of
Bolivia and almost double that of Peru.
Okay.
Broadly speaking,
of the 1 billion people living in the
America is approximately 40% lift in
some of the richest countries in the
world,
mainly the United States and Canada.
Meanwhile,
the other 60% of Americans live in
countries that are either very poor or
are still developing and of course faced
with this panorama.
The question is,
why on earth is there such a contrast
between for two great North American
powers under the rest of the consonants
or even why are the countries located at
both ends of the continents?
January richer?
Well,
just check out this map.
The countries that are painted with a
darker color,
Richard.
Okay.
However,
it may be easier to notice the enormous
difference writes on the board of that.
You're seeing donald trump's favorite
border,
of course,
the one between the United States and
Mexico on the north side of the border.
We do have the u s one of the wealthiest
countries in the world.
I come three where in general its
inhabitants are much richer and it's
much safer and they live longer lives
than those on the southern side of the
border.
Those who live in Mexico,
in fact one crosses the border and
suddenly everything changes.
Right.
Bye.
Why such a difference?
Well,
because at the end of the day we're
talking about territories that have a
very similar population and its natural
resources.
Don't forget that much of California,
Texas and New Mexico,
some of these states,
which by the way are the most prosperous
and innovative in the United States when
Mexican at the beginning of the 19th
century.
Okay.
Yeah.
And the people that you manage to cross
from south of the border to the north
have quite high employment and
entrepreneurship rates.
So of course we're not talking about
racial or religious motives.
Yeah.
Then why on earth does this huge
contrast exist between the north and the
south of the border?
Well,
you might be thinking right now that
obviously it's because they've had worse
governments and worse politicians,
but I mean,
where did that come from?
Did almost all the countries south of
the u s Mexico border just simply have
this sort of bad luck?
Is that not another factor involved?
Well,
listen up here,
different destinations Devi,
you are to continue in the video today,
we really need to take a small trip.
We need to go back to the year 1600
imagine there are two brothers,
John and his pizza who,
or a balanced,
we embark on the American adventure from
some European pause.
However,
due to fate,
they ended up on different books.
Okay?
One of the brothers,
John left in such a fortune in Mexico,
while pizza got on a ship that was
heading farther north to what later
became known as New England's and today
corresponds to the states.
If New Hampshire,
Connecticut,
Massachusetts,
Vermont,
Maine,
and Rhode Island.
Okay?
And you might be picking it up now,
but this is indeed one of the richest
areas in the United States.
Now,
the question is,
if you'd been in these two brothers
places,
which ship would you have preferred?
The one that was going to Mexico or the
one that was to New England's to Boston?
Well,
viewer,
for those of you who answered Boston,
I think you should rather reconsider
your decision at the time.
Things they couldn't have been more
different.
You see,
John,
he arrived in Mexico City,
a city full of monuments in new
buildings,
a city that had nothing to envy from
European cities,
but that's how I'm,
Mexico was part of the vice royalty of
new Spain,
an area of expensive governance that was
full of wonders,
cultivated fields,
ancient civilization ruins large cities,
et Cetera,
et cetera.
But Peta,
he arrived in a cold,
desolate,
unpopulated area,
a place without infrastructure where
mere survival was something of a
challenge.
It was a place where real hunger and
true cold,
we're raging.
Actually the Spanish conquerors didn't
move further north because there was no
wealth to extract that
chose North America.
Not because it was attractive,
but because it was all that was
available,
but desirable parts of the Americas
where the indigenous population to
exploit was plentiful and where the gold
and silver mines were located had
already been occupied.
The English got the leftovers,
Darren,
Asimo,
Lou and James Robinson.
Why nations fail
in New England,
one how to work very hard just to
survive in the south.
However things they were difference,
there were many natural riches.
The climate's was much better for
agriculture and so there was a large
local population used by the Spanish
conquistadores to do endless hours of
work in exchange for practically
nothing.
The fact is that all of these resources,
man,
so that many of those who arrived didn't
have to work in order to survive,
and not only that,
many of the institutions that existed in
old Europe could be easily replicated.
These were institutions like the
aristocracy and bureaucracy.
That is the officials or the royal
favors,
which were privileges granted by the
state and to which benefits is only a
select few.
These include things like commercial
monopolies,
land distribution,
mining,
exploitation,
et cetera.
That way.
That's all by Lisel.
On the one hand,
a culture was born in which work and
entrepreneurship.
We're not perceived as the best way to
prospect.
Instead,
people just needed to make good
connections with those who were in
power.
I mean,
why risk investing when you can just
hold out your hand for a handout and
then on the other hands in elite class
was formed by people who lived based on
the resources that others extracted.
They lived through privileges,
forced exploitation of the natives,
lans,
distribution,
concessions,
public revenues,
taxes,
et cetera.
This was an elite class by the way,
which based on the standards of the time
lived at full speed,
which meant having to extract more and
more resources from the others.
This meant that this elite group that's
controlled the economic resources not
only to,
didn't have to worry about investing,
innovating or taking risks,
they actually placed obstacles for other
people and give you this culture.
It didn't disappear with independence.
It simply remains consolidating some of
the most remarkable characteristics of
Latin America and elite class with a lot
of wealth that is based on obtaining
wrens overlords,
a lot of bureaucracy,
and they shattered social elevator.
Meanwhile,
in the north,
things were going completely
differently.
The survival
unlike was happens in the south of the
north,
had no resources and no indigenous
population to exploit it,
so there was no other option,
but to work hard,
invest and innovate in order to improve
the standard of living.
Yeah.
Thus the social climate and the
institutions that were developed were
very,
very different.
Physical hard work was well regarded and
not only that,
because since these territories were
very poor and practically depopulated,
they had a lot of political and economic
autonomy.
Actually at first,
the British crown didn't really care
much about these colonies.
They were more concerned about what was
happening in other parts of the empire
where things were more lucrative.
In fact,
it was only when these colonies begins a
prosper that the crown that started to
pay attention to them.
This means that the crown began to
establish political and economic
controls as well as introduced taxes.
And as we all know,
the settlers didn't take that lying
down.
Yeah.
Okay.
See,
it's often said that the u s war of
independence was a fight to obtain
freedom.
However many of the incentives that led
them to fight it more to do with
maintaining the freedom,
but they were already used to and which
they were no longer willing to give up
once they obtained their independence.
They worried a lot about making sure
that neither of their liberties nor that
entrepreneurial capacities were at risk.
But some of you might be thinking right
now,
well Simon,
hold on a minute because the offer
guessing about slavery.
Well,
actually I'm not because the slave
states,
they weren't actually the richest
slavery enriched a few at the great
expense of others.
Of course,
if instead we talked about two companies
instead of two brothers in the long
term,
it would have been much better to invest
in the one in Boston.
The keys to development.
They don't lie in the natural resources
of a country or in the exploitation of
anyone.
They lie in ingenuity,
entrepreneurial spirit,
and in work.
That's why when politicians make this
process difficult,
for example,
with taxes,
a strong state,
lots of bureaucracy or privileges for
their friends,
the results that are always really bad
in a way,
it's similar to what happens with the
natural resources.
They can help,
but they aren't enough to generate real
wealth because they're all very rich.
Countries that hardly have any natural
resources like Japan or Singapore and
others with many resources but are
incredibly poor like Venezuela.
Ingenuity,
work and capital are more important than
any natural resource.
Good.
The good news
here is that poverty,
it's not,
and you can't escape it.
Trajectories such as those seen in
countries like Chile or Panama or in
recent decades showing with that things
absolutely can change,
but always the,
and do you think we'll soon see an
economic takeoff in Latin America?
Well,
leave your answer in the comments below
as well as in this survey.
And I also really hope you enjoyed this
video.
Please do hit that like of us than if
you did.
And don't forget to subscribe to this
channel for brand new videos.
I'll say,
don't forget to check it off.
Friends at the reconsider media
podcasts,
they provided the vocals in this episode
though.
Why not mine?
And as always,
thank you for watching.
Okay.