[inaudible]
Israel does not have the world's biggest
army bus.
It is the most effective.
Think about it,
we are talking about the country with
less than 9 million inhabitants.
Nonetheless,
they have won wars against countries 10
times bigger.
For example,
during the six days war,
Israel confronted a coalition that
included Egypt,
Syria and Jordan.
These countries put together sums up to
more than 130 million people and they
sent over 240,000 soldiers twice as many
as the Israeli army debt.
In other words,
no one would expect a victory for
Israel.
That history was rather difference in
just six days of the Israeli defense
forces also known as IDF wiped out their
enemies and yes,
I know where you're going to say now the
Israelis have the best technology and
weaponry,
right?
Well,
that is true now,
but it wasn't back then.
For instance,
in 1973 during the Yom Kippur war,
Israel's weapons where as modern as
those of their main rivals,
Syria.
In fact,
the IDF had some combat jets
manufactured in the 1950s the famous a
four Skyhawk.
However,
the Syrians,
they had state of the art anti aircraft
to isles.
They were given to the Soviets just five
years before.
And you won that wall.
Yeah,
it was Israel.
All right.
All right,
so I can hear something you're saying
no.
Oh,
come on.
Sign.
But Israel has the sport of America.
That's a really big help.
And yes,
at this point you are right.
Israel is the country that receives the
most help from Uncle Sam.
But do you know of any other country who
buys the best weaponry from America?
Well,
that would be Saudi Arabia.
The Saudi's have an army as big and as
modern as the Israeli one.
But if you've been subscribed to visual
politic for a while and you already know
that the big failure of the Saudi army
was fighting guerrilla warriors,
namely those who see rebels from Yemen.
In other words,
neither the technology nor the
American's support are enough to explain
why the Israeli army is such a fearful.
Yeah.
So the question of the day is why is the
Israeli army so powerful?
What are the key elements explaining
such military success?
Well,
today we are going to tell you the five
key facts that explain this fast
decision making.
Every almay is based on hierarchy and
authority,
right?
Well,
some of them,
they're more flexible than others.
In this other video,
we explained how the Saudi army and has
a bigger sense of hierarchy and the
officials don't have much power to make
their own decisions.
The same goes with other Arabic
countries like Syria or Egypt.
It's like,
here is an example.
Imagine a Syrian unit defending a
position.
Let's say the headquarters have been
destroyed before the soldiers in the
front line are aware of it.
That's
if they have to follow the normal
procedure.
They will have to wait until someone
gives them an order during this time,
they don't know if they should retreat,
strike back,
or coordinate with other military units.
All right,
so now you might be wondering,
well,
why are Arab armies so centralized?
No,
don't forget the,
most of these countries aren't
dictatorships or absolute monarchies.
If you are a higher and you want your
army to be under control in order to
micromanage every little decision in
order to prevent acute attack,
he is rainy.
Ami is way different from that.
Let's look back to our previous example.
In this case,
the is rainy commander on the front
line.
Would it need to wait for orders?
He has a degree of his own decision
making power so he can react immediately
and seize opportunities.
In fact,
this is pretty normal in almost all
western armies.
The big planning is centralized,
but the execution is decentralized.
This way the organization is more
flexible and can react more right
quickly.
Unlike the western countries,
Israel has something unique in that
culture.
We all talking about a pretty unknown
fact about this country.
Yes,
it is a very,
very important one.
Israel is the least hierarchical country
on the planet and you can feel this in
every aspect of their culture inside of
an Israeli company.
It's pretty normal for an average worker
to have a discussion with his boss
debate site a common thing and there is
a pretty small sense of authority.
Actually in the 1970s of Dutch
anthropologist named Geert Hofstetter
studied the power relationships in
different countries.
Over the course of six years,
he surveyed ibm workers in different
offices around the globe.
This is how the power distance index was
born,
and among all those countries,
Israel has the lowest power distance.
While the Arab countries like Egypt or
Saudi Arabia rank among the highest.
In other words,
Israeli citizens are educated in
flexibility more than any other nation.
Yeah,
internal cohesion in Israel military
service is mandatory for every citizen
regardless of their social condition or
that gender.
Both men and women,
rich and poor start from the very
awesome.
Well,
actually this is not entirely true
because the ultra orthodox Jews don't
need to do military service and neither
does Israel's Palestinian population,
but the rest of Israel citizens must
serve in the military and fall into a
meritocratic scheme.
This means everyone must follow the same
rules in order to be promoted,
and this is not as common as you might
think.
For instance,
during World War II,
the aristocrats grants who joined the
British army started with higher
positions and the peasants and the
working class.
As of course,
it's such elitism,
it tends to destroy an army's morale and
make it harder for it to function.
For example,
the Saudi army consists of both civil
sevenths ams,
members of the royal family.
As hierarchy matters a lot.
The son of the Saudi prince will be a
soldier,
and as you can imagine,
this classist structure has negative
consequences.
Combat
morale.
In the,
in 1973 Israel forced the Egyptian and
the Syrian army at the same time.
As we said at the beginning,
back then,
Israel was not the technological
powerhouse that it is today.
Syrians had those antiaircraft guns,
the Sdu hundreds that we mentioned
before,
and during the first days,
those anti aircraft missiles destroyed a
lot of Israeli combat jets,
Israel answer retreat.
Nonetheless,
Uncle Sam was here to help.
The White House sends a package of
weapons so they could neutralize the Sdu
hundreds and the radars,
things like flags that could confuse the
smart missiles that would guide it by
temperature this way.
The Israeli struck back and in a short
amount of time they finished off the
Syrian defenses as well.
Guess what happened next?
Well,
the loss of those Arab soldiers scared
of being wiped out from the air.
Well,
they defected.
If you look at the picture on the
screen,
you will see seven Syrian tanks.
They are not moving,
but not one of them is destroyed.
Well,
it means that the soldiers that were
inside of those tanks,
they decided to run away.
Defection is a common problem when
morale is low,
and this is a common problem for Arab
army
s
Syrian troops defect to southern Turkish
province of Hottie.
Think about it.
If you aren't an Israeli soldier or an
American one,
you know you must be loyal to your
country,
but Arab soldiers have too many ethnic,
national,
and religious identity.
Imagine you are a Syrian soldiers and at
the same time you are occurs or you
belong to the Muslim Brotherhood.
Both groups aren't chased by the Syrian
government so well.
Who were your loyalty?
Of course the army pays your bills,
but when your life is a risk and
everything is lost,
when what's more important?
Your salary,
life,
no matter your wealth and your
technology.
If your soldiers are not strongly
motivated,
you've already lost ans the Israelis,
they know that better than anyone.
Capitol old tanks place their engines on
the backside,
but why is this?
Because usually the rocket center on the
front side,
Angie wants your tank to keep working
even after being hit.
This is why all the models from the
German leopards do the Russian tea
nineties keep that engine's in the back.
Nonetheless,
the Israeli army doesn't value the
vehicle as much as their soldiers.
This is why the Israeli mccarver is the
only one of its kinds of,
that has the engine's in the front.
This
way,
a rocket will destroy the tank,
but it will protect the soldiers.
Putting aside the ethics,
Israel has a really small population.
This means that they can't allow
themselves to lose too many soldiers.
This is why they receive much more
intense training with real bullets and
better equipment.
And don't forget that this is the
country where craft mudguard one,
it's the most advanced martial arts was
born.
You can also see this human capital
doctrine reflected in their intelligence
service.
The massage,
it is considered one of the best in the
entire world.
Wow.
One day you happen to travel to Israel
and you should know that they will take
your phone number and other data because
they know information is power.
Yep.
All right.
I know what you want to hit.
Now,
you came to this video because you
wanted to hear about state of the art
weaponry,
Rice.
Well,
Hey,
you have this made in Israel during the
1980 it's the Israeli government wanted
a secret weapon,
a weapon no one had ever heard of until
recently.
So they met our local manufacturer or
company called Rafael.
Do you design a very special vehicle?
The so called para.
This is a vehicle that looks like a
tank,
but in fact,
as a tank hunter weapon with a big
rocket launch chat,
if you know about weapons,
you know there's a big difference.
Tank weaponry has to reach a distance of
between two and four kilometers.
Perrier rockets can travel and distance
of 30 so imagine the situation.
The enemies would take satellite
pictures to see the Israeli weaponry.
And as they would see a lot of normal
tax based on this,
they would turn their strategy,
but then surprise,
surprise those tanks on not tanks and
bars.
In fact,
something with a much,
much bigger,
right?
Sure.
The decades this para was one of the
most mysterious weapons if the Israeli
army and their main strength was that no
one knew anything about them.
So now the question is how come Israel
makes it's own secret weapons and other
countries don't?
Well,
the answer is that in Israel there are a
lot of rocket science companies that
give it a worldclass defense industry.
So a while ago we did a video about
Israeli startups.
Well.
In the 1980s the Israeli government
created a special program which was
called a yells map.
This program consisted of 10 hedge funds
with both private and government money
in them.
Those funds helps to create a lot of
tech companies and you know what the
favorite industry for those brand new
startups was?
Well,
of course it was the military industry.
At the end of the day,
the army,
it was a rich and reliable clients.
All of a sudden,
dozens of weapons manufacturers were
born companies that created customized
products that met the exact needs of the
Israeli army at every
moment.
Iron don't defense system to the Merkaba
tanks or the parade we mentioned before.
Now you might be wondering what happens
in the other countries.
Well,
let's first consider Saudi Arabia.
As you note,
the sound of your economy.
It's got a problem.
It relies heavily on the oil industry.
Of course,
thanks to the dinosaur juice.
The Saudis have become a rich and they
can pay for the third biggest army in
the world,
only surpassed by China and America.
Expensive is not a synonym for good.
The Saudi army buys their tanks from the
USA ends.
Those are customized for the needs of
the American army.
Like does that makes it harder to have a
secret weapon because everyone knows
what you bought on the international
market.
All right,
so I probably know what you're thinking.
Now.
It seems that we're really talking up
the Israelis rice,
but do you make no mistake,
the Israeli army certainly has its weak
points.
In fact,
there is an organization that could make
their life even harder,
but that's something we're going to talk
about in another video.
Nope.
The question for you is who do you think
can defeat the Israeli army and what do
you think their main weak point saw?
What?
Please leave your answers in the
comments section below.
Meanwhile,
please visit our friends at the
reconsider media podcasts.
They provided the vocals in this episode
that are not mine.
Also,
do not forget that we published brand
new videos every single week,
so do not forget to subscribe and you
won't miss a single post.
And if you liked this video,
please do give it a thumbs up.
And as always,
I'll see you next time.
And if you want to learn more about
politics and hear even more of my love
the voice,
you can join us at reconsider media.
We have a podcast@reconsidermedia.com
slash podcast.