Hong Kong is one of those places that
probably needs no introduction because
you already know will have is situated
in the south of China.
Hong Kong is a lively bustling city with
a great deal of contrasts
in Hong Kong.
It isn't surprising to see ancient
Lori's running alongside luxury cars.
You'll also see ruins buildings right
next to fancy modern skyscrapers and
you'll see top notch restaurants next to
street food cars.
They all do have one thing in common.
They occupy tiny spaces.
This is true whether the location is a
high ends mold or just a traditional
storefronts.
Whatever business you operate in Hong
Kong,
the most is made of every single square
meter.
Hong Kong was one of the biggest
miracles of the 20th century.
In fact,
it was the model Milton Friedman himself
looked at in order to prove his pro free
trade thesis.
Free market really is obliged to come.
World Water You,
Hong Kong's population.
It was around 600,000
people.
It has an income equivalent to about a
quarter of the United Kingdom's 60 years
later and the population now exceeds 7
million people and the per capita income
is almost equal to the UK.
When purchasing power is considered,
its GDP is much larger than the one in
the UK.
Okay.
Sixty years.
Hong Kong has not only become the fourth
most significant financial center in the
world and one of the 10 most important
markets,
but it has also become a shell sap and
millions of Chinese citizens through
escapes the poverty and violence of
Mao's China.
With all the economic development is
economic freedom is something that you
can really feel in the air in Hong Kong.
Now,
Hong Kong cannot exactly be considered a
free paradise,
but nowadays it can be considered the
freest economy in the world and the
fourth easiest place to do business in
the world.
Anyway,
the kings are Hong Kong's economic
development is going to be discussed in
a future video,
but today we're going to focus on the
politics of Hong Kong and the threats
against its institutional structure
which might even compromise its future
economic development.
And to do so,
we're gonna have to start by looking at
the great paradox that China is facing,
the paradox which has become something
of a hallmark for the country.
Ongoing Kong
was a British colony until 1997 when the
city integrated into China.
Again,
it's something that hadn't happened
since the 19th century.
China was and today remains a
dictatorship,
lacking respect for human rights and
having very few civil liberties.
This forced the governments in London
and Beijing to negotiate a solution.
The citizens of Hong Kong didn't want to
lose that fundamental rights,
and London simply couldn't tolerate the
Chinese applying their authoritarians of
city
negotiations.
In 1984,
they reached an agreement known as the
Sino British joint declaration,
which established for 50 years after the
integration,
Hong Kong would have a different
political system than the one in
mainland China.
This meant that after 1997,
Hong Kong became a special
administrative region where these so
called basic law replies.
This is a lot of the grants,
its citizens' rights and freedoms that
would be unimaginable in any other place
in China with the exception of Macau
which was integrated into China
following the same model,
the citizens in Hong Kong have freedom
of speech,
freedom of the press,
freedom of publication,
freedom of Assembly and association,
and it's even freedom of demonstration.
Further,
Hong Kong has its own currency,
its own immigration policy and customs
policy,
its own police and even has its own
courts.
So at first things went really well.
Following this policy and the economic
growth we mentioned earlier,
certainly did help the citizens cap that
reign free status.
They could apply their own policies and
Hong Kong became the natural entrance
for foreign investment into
China
for a few years.
Things started to get rather worse.
The basic law we mentioned a moment ago
acknowledges civil rights but not civil
democracy.
In fact,
China has control over the parliaments
and the city's executive power.
So how did they do this?
Well,
first in Hong Kong,
only half of the MPS are chosen through
the popular vote.
The other half were chosen by a closed
group formed of entrepreneurs and
institutions close to China
now watching Jolyon separatists arguing
for independence from China.
They were excluded from the chamber for
using offensive language.
There is the head of the executive
branch,
and that's the prime minister who was
chosen by a committee of 1000,
200 people involved or Linkedin,
one way or another to the communist
party.
In addition to that,
all public officials must take an oath
of allegiance and commitments to China.
Because of this,
there's an argument to be made that some
of these positions are actually in
legitimate.
Finally,
the Basic Law states that the autonomy
of Hong Kong is subordinate to Chinese
people's congrats,
special administrative region of the
People's Republic of China.
However,
the trees,
he demanded that from 2017,
the executive chief hat to be chosen by
popular vote,
and this leads us to the part of the
story.
When China started to break their word
over and over again,
the 31st
of August,
2014,
the national congress in Beijing started
the electoral reform,
which would choose the government chief
in this special region,
and here was the surprise,
yes,
Beijing did acknowledge that this should
be chosen by popular vote,
but they could only choose between two
or three who had been previously
selected by the Communist Party.
Yes.
Some surprisingly,
the Chinese do have a rather different
idea of democracy,
so over the next few days the people
really started rising up first.
These were protests by students,
some of them as young as 17 years old.
Can you explain to a young educated
students who grew up with full access to
the Internet and the media that they are
actually going to have to live under a
Chinese dictatorship after all
and 2017,
I believe that will be more
demonstrations and protests,
especially under the interface of
Beijing government,
is just proved the failure of one
country,
two system
reaction to the authorities to these
first strikes and mobilizations wasn't
very friendly.
They decided to use force,
but the results,
it was the opposite of what they were
expecting.
Instead of containing the protests,
more and more people took to the
streets,
moved by the fear of having to remain
under the rule of Beijing in a short
time,
a huge demonstration developed in the
center of Hong Kong.
I did many of the organizations occupy
central and scholar Ism,
not only me,
oh well,
let's go home until feel we awake at
bluff.
Police started using tear gas and pepper
spray to control the protesters,
and the population started using towels,
mosques,
and umbrellas to mitigate the effect of
the gas.
For this reason,
the protests actually became known as
the umbrella.
You should.
The occupation
of central Hong Kong lasted for 79 days
and since then the conflict has
continued with some spontaneous
outbreaks and young people getting more
radical and not just demanding
democracy,
but demanding independence from China.
This is something,
by the way,
that China has said that they absolutely
will not tolerate under any
circumstances,
even if they have to use military force.
As an interesting aside,
hey,
by the way,
China has recently kidnapped five
librarians in Hong Kong for spreading
ideas against Chinese control of the
city.
I was visiting my girlfriend in the
mainland and I was stopped by two
officials at the border.
They took me to a police fan where there
were dozens of policemen waiting up to
you.
Then I was taken to the police station
in Schengen when I was held in the
prisoners compound and interrogated
largely
because of these protests.
The September 2016 elections were
celebrated as many of the protests
leaders were chosen as mps.
There are antibodies using pro
independence positions have opened up
the conflict door again since September
two,
mps have already been expelled from
their offices under pressure for
maintenance
China,
and as I mentioned earlier in this
video,
civil rights are only protected in Hong
Kong until 20,
47 and it seems that every day China's
involvement in the city grows and grows
and this does come with a price.
Potential investors in China through
Hong Kong starting to perceive a risk.
This is probably one of the why
Singapore has experienced such strong
growth in the last few years,
so that's what we think,
but what do you think?
Do you think the citizens in Hong Kong
should fight for their freedom?
Do you think China will eventually
completely controlled Hong Kong?
Do let us know in the comments below,
we'd love to hear from you,
and if you liked this video,
do click that like button below.
If you haven't done so yet,
please do subscribe to our channel for
brand new videos every Monday and every
Thursday,
and as always I'll see you in the next
week.