Imagine that you could buy stocks in
your uncle's farm and guess I know that
assumes that your uncle has a farm.
Let's say it's a small farm,
it's got some cows,
etc. And you can buy stocks from his
company,
something you would do on the stock
market,
just like you deal with big companies
like apple,
exxon,
or chevron thing.
I'm crAzy.
Well,
actually I'm not at all and at the end
of this video you're going to see
exactly where I'm coming from.
Let's say you want to start a company,
a traditional company.
Let's stick to the example of California
that's going to produce milk and other
dairy products.
What is the first thing that you need?
Well,
of course that's going to be money.
You need money to buy the property.
The facilities as well as the all
important was so where can you get the
money to do this?
Well,
the first option of course is going to
be to go to the bank,
but this has a whole bunch of issues.
The first one is that if it wasn't risky
enough to start your own company,
having a loan makes it even more risky.
You could end up bankrupt and in debt.
Besides then there's the whole thing
that the bank have might actually not
give you that loan.
If you've ever tried to get a loan start
company,
you know exactly what I'm talking about.
It's pretty hard to convince a banker to
lend you any money.
So let's.
First of all,
disregard of a bank option.
The next alternative is a venture
capitalist.
You know those guys out in silicon
valley.
These people were the loads of cash and
a willingness to invest in young talents
just like you.
I mean who knows,
maybe a small farm might become the next
industry been off,
but then you run into the problem that
you probably don't know any venture
capitalists,
especially if you're somewhere like in
the middle of India.
so there's no banks,
there's new venture capitalists,
but maybe a parents are rich,
but if they're not,
well I guess that's not any help.
So just hold on for a minute because I
think I have an idea what if you could
already entered the stock market,
you know,
something like wall street where general
motors and mcdonald's operate the good
thing and now the stock market is,
you don't need to know a millionaire to
get funding.
There aren't thousands of small
investors out there who buy stocks every
day.
So let's say you divide your company
into 10,000 stocks in each of them has
an initial price of $10 and people no
matter where they live can buy those
shares.
Say maybe there's a guy in Kansas who
buys one stock in the zero women in
France.
He buys 10 this way with no contacts and
no bank loans.
You can get the funding you need.
You just need a good idea and a bit of
hard work,
right?
Well
hold on a second.
Didn't get too excited.
There's a pretty major problem here.
For instance,
if you want to get into the New York
stock exchange,
your company,
it should have already made at least
$10,000,000 in the last three years.
And that's just the beginning.
There are lots and lots of regulations
that you have to meet.
well,
this is the situation that the guys from
hako sky agricultural company we're in,
they lived in Russia and they wanted to
start a cow farm and they had no money
so.
Well,
what do you think they did?
Well?
Check it out.
back to coco skier agricultural company
plans to launch an ico named milk coin
to fund a dairy farm.
Yep.
You heard that right?
These farmers launch their own
cryptocurrency.
It's basically their own version of
bitcoin.
They advertised it on their website and
launched the offer of these new coins.
This is what we call an initial coin
offering or ico.
So now you might be wondering,
well,
why would I buy another cryptocurrency
bitcoin enough?
Now you might just think that you're
just buying some sort of virtual coin
here,
but the reality is you're actually
buying stocks and you're doing it
without going through the traditional
stock markets.
But at the end of this video,
I'm going to tell you what happens with
this company,
but the fact is they're not the only
example.
Forty eight percent of those were
successful last year,
but startups still managEd to raise five
point $6,000,000,000.
Yes,
if you have.
That appears to be a brand new way of
getting money to start a company and
it's available for everybody right now,
but hold on just a minute because not
everything is a beautiful and as you can
imagine,
these icrs seem like a scam as paradise.
So the question is can we really trust
this brand new way of starting companies
and what does Switzerland and have to do
with all of this today?
We're going to answer all of these
questions,
but before we do as usual,
let's take a look back at the history
coins versus tokens.
In the year 2013,
everyone in the tech industry was
already pretty aware of bitcoin in
silicon valley.
They were celebrating all kinds of
events and talking about the future of
this currency.
Yeah.
In one of them,
that was a man called j dot r with it.
This man had a very funny idea.
He said we could create alternative
currencies that using the same
technology as bitcoin would have
different rules and how are you going to
pay all the itv,
but he would design all of this.
They asked him,
he said that instead of looking for a
venture capitalist,
he could sell some notes,
what we call a token that will be
exchanged for coins,
swamps.
They were created,
and this is how the first initial Coin
offering was created,
but before
we continue,
many of you might be wondering,
well,
what exactly is a token?
Well,
tokens are any elements that can be
changed in a blockchain.
Cryptocurrencies are one kind of token,
but there are many more.
On the one hand,
we have those that give a right to its
owner.
For instance,
those notes that you could exchange for
brand new currencies when they are
created.
On the other hand,
we have the tokens that are based on an
asset.
This would be the case,
so if the stocks at the russian farmers
having one of their tokens means having
a share of their company visit initial
public offering of tokens became
fashionable in the year 2014.
So why was that?
What exactly happens In this year?
Well,
that was the year when the second most
famous cryptocurrency was created.
The decentralized platform that might
displace today's institutions.
Unlike bitcoin,
we all know who is behind a theory.
This is a company that offers way more
than a cryptocurrency.
They also offer a system so other people
can create their own cryptocurrency
isn't in their own tokens.
For example.
Do you remember this other video where I
told you about how a spanish bank is
using blockchains,
give corporate loans?
Well,
if theory in is the platform that they
use,
we are only talking about spanish banks
here.
The theory has made it really easy for
lots of people to start creating
different financial products on
chain
theory and rush has been unleashed.
Isis ceos are in fashion in the tech
investment world.
Since then,
lots of companies are getting financed
this way.
For example,
serum labs,
a swiss company that is about to launch
their own smartphone,
this company has got more than a hundred
and $18,000,000 thanks to one of the
most successful ice a's in history,
and of course there are all kinds of
internet companies that have been born
with this system,
but just hold on a second because not
everything is so great.
Ico is they've got no regulation
whatsoever,
so you can certainly imagine there are
some problems.
How to create an ico scam in five simple
steps.
Now you might be wondering,
well,
what's the difference between an ico and
a website like kickstarter?
Well,
that's actually pretty easy to onset.
If you support some kickstarter project,
you can't sell any shares on an ico.
You can buy a token or a coin and if it
rises higher and market value,
you can sell it to another investor.
The only problem is that here there is
no financial police or fcc running
against the bad guys.
So yes,
there were plenty of people who thought
they could get rich really quick and
then ended up losing a ton of money.
For example,
saved ride was a german company that
wanted to make a cryptocurrency based
credit card.
It has all the buzzwords to make
speculators happy and everything seemed
great.
The technology Was there and it was very
disruptive.
They got $50,000,000 to launch it,
so once they got their money,
what do you think happens?
Well,
they just disappeared and since there
was no public register whatsoever,
it's almost impossible to find the
owner.
I'm sure you've all seen the ads onlIne
for coins and tokens and things that
promise a whole ton of profits.
I mean for a better understanding,
even the ceo of a theory and butter like
butter and recognized that most of the
ico is a scam.
As you can imagine.
Governments have already started to act.
China has banned ics.
America seems to be following a similar
path.
Other countries like Estonia said that
it's okay to invest in.
Ico is for everyone except estonian
citizens,
so they're essentially saying something
like,
oh yeah,
man,
you can totally scam anyone you like,
just not my own citizens.
Cool.
Nonetheless,
there is one country that has found an
intermediate solution.
They weren't banned.
Ico is,
but they will not let them go
unregulated as they are today.
And what country am I talking about?
Well,
let me give you a clear.
It's probably the channel we've talked
to most about here on visual politic
already knows.
Well,
yes,
of course.
We're talking about sir,
when the krypto nation.
During that video we made about
Switzerland there we talked about kansan
called zog,
which has the lowest taxes in the car.
Well guess what?
The theory and has its headquarters.
Having the biggest cryptocurrency
company in your country means that you
also have the biggest experts on the
mass of that.
So most of the ico is,
are done on swift service.
And of course the swiss government soon
realize that,
uh,
with or without scams,
this was a multi million dollar.
The street
wants to be the world capital of
cryptocurrency.
Four of the 10 biggest initial coin
offerings last year.
We're in Switzerland more than any other
country.
This is why some swiss municipalities
let the citizens pay taxes or even fines
with cryptocurrencies as having less
than 30,000 inhabitants is already the
home of 400 blockchain based companies
and the regional government is already
doing trials.
To use this technology to organize
referendums,
you probably already know that
referendums and direct democracy are
essential in the swiss political system,
so well now they want to do it with
blockchain and of course Switzerland
wants to become the pioneer in ico
regulations too.
This financial authority releases ico
specific regulatory guidelines.
For example,
any company that wants to make an ico in
Switzerland,
we'll have to do it through a swiss
company.
This means they will have to regIster,
then have to give their name and
physical address.
This way it will be easier to chase
terrorists,
knockers or scammers.
As you can imagine,
these regulations,
well,
they're starting to work and many
companies have already gone to other tax
havens like the cayman islands,
which offer a complete doggy dog
environments where you can essentially
do whatever you want.
This is the short term price you have to
pay in order to have a stable
environment.
We're talking about a wells that still
needs a lot of work before it becomes a
mature market.
One thing is for sure it has pLenty of
possibilities.
Many scams,
lots of money laundering and some easy
money to be made.
So the swiss way seems to be the
smartest far yes and new technology has
come.
It is risky,
but it has many possibilities to instead
of banning us or letting it run
completely free,
the best option is to regulate it.
This way we take the good and to avoid
the bad,
by the way,
going all the way back to our russian
friends,
the ones you wanted to finance their
farm with cryptocurrency.
Well,
we've got some bad news
it for you
originally since milk coin raised only
two percent of the soft cap.
We're giving back all funds that we
received.
We will start the return on the 21st of
November.
Huge thanks to our backers.
Now the question becomes,
do you think other countries will follow
the swiss example?
It is clear that we still need more time
for the ico market to grow and become
mature,
but do you think it can be the
capitalist revolution that will open the
entry barriers to starting a company?
Please welcome.
Leave the onset in the comment section
below and do visit our friends from
reconsider media,
the podcast that provided the vocals in
this episode that we're not mine,
and don't forget that we publish brand
new videos like this one every week,
so hit that subscribe button and the
bell icon so you don't miss any posts
and if you want to,
you can support us on patrion and as
always,
I'll see you next time
and if you want to learn more about
politics and hear even more of my love
before you can join us at reconsider
media.
We have a podcast@reconsideredmedia.com
sLash podcast.