Luxembourg is the only country in the
world is prime minister is openly gay.
We're talking about one of them is
tolerance,
open-minded societies on the planet.
In fact,
they have a population of around 500,000
inhabitants and 40 percent of them are
immigrants.
In other words,
Luxembourg is the smallest country in
the European Union,
but the one with the biggest share of
immigrants nonetheless,
what made Luxenberg famous can be
summarized in just one word.
And that word is money.
Yes.
Do you have.
You have the grants actually of
Luxembourg is one of the three
wealthiest countries on earth here.
The minimum wage is around 2000 euros a
month.
No,
that's not average wage.
That's the minimum wage.
The normal wage in Luxembourg.
5,000 euros a month for comparison.
Luxembourgish people have a GDP per
capita twice as big as that of
Australians or the dangers.
Alright.
But just hold on for a second because
that is a little trick in this figure.
You see almost half of the work is in
this country actually live outside of
it.
Everyday around 160,000 people commute
to this country.
And then go back to their homes in
Germany,
France,
or Belgium.
In other words,
they create wealth in the country,
but they don't live that.
This is why when we divide Luxembourg's
GDB among their population,
we get such an enormous number,
even with these statistical deviations,
no one can deny that Luxembourg is kind
of a country for many ins and this
explains why it's capital.
Luxembourg city is among these cities in
the world with the highest quality of
life.
Many of you might think that this can
all be explained because Luxembourg is a
fiscal haven,
but the truth is that other countries
like Malaysia and Cyprus also have low
taxes,
but they are not even half as rich as
Luxembourg.
So the big question here is what does
Luxembourg happens that makes them so
incredibly wealthy?
What did they do in this country to
enjoy such a fantastic quality of life
life today?
Well,
we are going to answer that very
question,
but before we do,
let's take a look back at the history.
The kings of steel by the rag and 15,
the Grand Duchy of Luxembourg became an
independent country.
And I say independence because none of
its neighbors really recognized its
independence.
France and Germany used to be back then
for for control over the dap sheet on
several occasions.
In fact,
despite their government's desire for
independence,
the territory of Luxembourg was owned by
King William the third of the
Netherlands.
During these years,
Luxembourg was far from being a wealthy
country.
Most of its citizens survived thanks to
agriculture and iron mining back then,
one in every five people from Luxembourg
was emigrating to America.
Nonetheless,
living between two rival countries like
France and Russia had its advantages
too.
You see,
during this time,
Germany didn't exist as a country.
Instead,
there were a lot of republics,
kingdoms and Dutchies united under a
confederation.
If you want to know what a confederation
is,
well click on this video.
The truth is all the German states
traded among themselves that basically
created a special free trade zone,
which they called the silver,
right?
All right,
so in 1942,
Luxembourg became a member of the
zollverein.
And since that point history,
what?
It would never be the same again.
As I said before,
poor Luxembourg was based on two main
industries,
agriculture and iron mining,
and remember here,
these are the times of the industrial
revolution,
still was needed for,
well,
basically everything.
It was used in everything from machines
to buildings and Luxembourgish citizens
while they were sitting on top of a pile
of iron,
but not only that,
we're talking about a tiny country
placed in the intersection between
France,
Germany,
and Belgium.
In other words,
it was the perfect points.
Have a railroad so they could send the
iron to all three countries.
All of a sudden,
Luxembourg became ground zero for all of
these trade routes as well as one of the
biggest steel providers on the planet.
In fact,
many of those New York skyscrapers were
built with beams made in this country.
This is why the biggest steel companies
are luxembourgish.
The biggest of them all.
Arcelor.
Mittal is one that you might have even
heard about and financial newspapers,
and although as in just a few decades,
Luxembourg gone to the same level as its
neighbors,
but still it was not the economic dmf
what it is today.
They still need to
special sauce.
That special sauce was this
29?
This is the year when Luxembourg past
the holding goal bonds.
Wait just a minute here because you
might be wondering,
well,
what's corporate holding all about?
Well,
let's take a cookie cutter as an
example.
On the one hand,
Coca Cola isn't beverage brand,
but on the other hand that is the Coca
Cola company.
This is a big conglomerate that contains
other companies like Faenza Schweppes or
Coca Cola,
the beverage brand.
Okay,
so this big conglomerates is called a
holding corporation that owns the
company,
his insight it alcohol subsidiary
companies.
These subsidiaries can be in different
countries and all the guys who produce
and distribute the drinks.
However,
the role of the holding company is
mainly to manage the property of these
other subsidiary companies.
All right,
so this 19,
29 law,
it's offered amazingly good tax
conditions to those holding companies.
Basically they paid around one percent
tap.
These were the 19 thirties and back then
there wasn't as many holding companies
as there are today.
Johnson,
remember,
those were the years when Coca Cola was
starting to expand to other markets,
so Luxembourg was doing great,
but they still want the drawing where
they are today.
In other words,
Luxembourg was growing but not that much
more than other countries.
Yes.
Nonetheless,
the seventies were other times when
American companies conquered the
European and Asian markets that finally
had some money to spend on consumer
goods.
During these years,
many of the big corporations we know
today were born.
In other words,
a lot of holding sprang up and their
profits came from all around the
planets.
So where did they decide to set up their
headquarters?
Well,
since they could choose anywhere they
wanted to,
they went to the places with the best
fiscal conditions.
Luxembourg has everything they want,
says a whole lot more.
You see,
by the 19 sixties and seventies,
the country already had a big banking
industry.
The best lawyers,
accountants and economists were living
there ready to help those big companies
in order to take advantage of those
business friendly laws.
And this is how this little country
glance into their silver decades.
Yes.
Do you believe what you see the economy
of Luxembourg became two times bigger in
less than six years compared to this.
China or Singapore is great rate.
It's kind of a joke and yes,
you heard that right?
I did say before silver decade,
because all of this growth was nothing
compared to what was to come.
Think about it.
We are already talking about the two
thousands,
the age of the online business.
Boom.
These brand new corporate juggernauts
operated all over the world,
had dozens of subsidiary companies in
every country are not concentrated in
any specific location because they sold
every year.
In other words,
these tech companies were made some of
Luxembourg,
so if you've got this country,
it was already astoundingly rich and
could have grown more well,
do you think?
Twice
amazing,
isn't it?
I don't know if you noticed this,
but in just five years,
Luxembourg's GDP per capita,
I went from 50,000 US dollars,
which is already a lost over $100,000
when you live in the country where the
GDP per capita of over $100,000
can fill the old swimming pool with
champagne.
In fact,
the Audi a three is the third best
selling car in
and yes.
Well,
they probably do know what you're
thinking right now.
You think that this country has made its
fortune by companies avoid paying taxes,
right?
Well beyond,
sir.
It's a little bit more complicated than
that.
You see the facts that are holding
corporation is located in Luxembourg,
uh,
does not mean that its subsidiary
companies don't pay taxes elsewhere.
For instance,
Amazon has its headquarters in
Luxembourg.
Nonetheless,
it's British subsidiary that is the
company that sells products and managers
and logistics in this country still has
to pay taxes in the UK,
or at least that is the theory.
In fact,
the reality is way different school lux
leaks.
So let's get back to our Amazon example.
As we said,
the profits of his British subsidiary
are taxed in the UK rice.
Well,
the question that then comes up is,
what if they don't have any profits
whatsoever?
Imagine that right after they pay taxes,
Amazon UK gets a big loan,
a big loan with a really high interest
rates so high in fact,
that the company takes losses and who
lends them that money?
Exactly.
Well,
of course,
that would be Amazon Holdings in
Luxembourg.
This weight,
these subsidiary companies have almost
no profits.
One way or another,
they managed to send them money to the
Luxembourg brunch and that's what you
said before in Luxembourg.
Taxes are really low for companies.
Of course,
this is perfectly legal bus.
In 2009 during the financial crisis,
the American governments realized the
huge amounts of money they were losing
with all of these big companies moving
overseas.
That's why today I'm announcing a set of
proposals to crack down on illegal
overseas tax evasion,
close loopholes and make it more
profitable for companies to create jobs
here in the United States.
Since then,
other governments have also followed in
Obama's steps.
Now,
don't forget,
Luxembourg is one of the European
Union's founding members.
His name is the other club.
Members were angry and willing to lay on
a lot of political pressure,
but the biggest crisis for this country
came in the year 2014.
This was the time when a group of
accountants released a ton of private
data for these big corporations.
Thanks
so called Lux leaks.
We could all see the tax evasion
strategies employed by thousands of
different companies.
Now,
do you remember what I told you about
loans between different subsidiary
companies within a holding.
Well,
here is another way of improving the
deal.
You see all these big companies hire big
consulting firms so they can help them
with their accounting consulting firms
like pricewaterhouse coopers with a big
customer portfolio in Luxembourg.
That enough power to sit down with the
prime minister back then,
John Golan,
Jamaica,
and arrange a special tax deal.
No current spotlight after Luxembourg.
Tax Revelations,
the leaked documents demonstrate tax
arrangements negotiated by price
waterhouse coopers.
As you could imagine,
the release of the luxleaks was a total
game changer.
In fact,
this year,
2017 Luxembourg past a brand's new
fiscal reform and probably many of these
arrangements are going to have to
change,
but hold on just a minute here because
this doesn't mean that is going to stop
being a rich place.
In fact,
the opposite is probably true.
Despite this political turbulence,
the country group at a rate of four
point two percent last year,
this is way faster than almost any other
country in Europe having so many
savings.
Luxembourg has invested in many other
industries.
Now,
of course,
they have steel.
They have their bank suddenly also have
space.
Yes.
Burgs bent on space.
Industry shows early signs of success.
Yep.
You heard that right?
In fact,
Luxembourg in the United States of the
first countries to pass laws regulating
space mining,
and this tiny country is expected to
become the Silicon Valley of the
aerospace industry.
This explains partly some of the details
of the 2017 fiscal reform.
Of course,
the government of Luxembourg doesn't
want to help big corporations avoid
taxes.
At least this is what they say
officially.
Instead,
they have reduced taxes for smaller
companies and are actively trying to
improve conditions in order to encourage
more tech startups.
But this is a subject for another video
question for you is do you think we're
gonna?
See another moment of skyrocketing
growth in Luxembourg economy.
Well,
this country truly become a world leader
in the aerospace industry.
Well,
please leave your answer in the comment
section below.
We'd love to hear from you.
Meanwhile,
if you want to know more about to see if
a wealthy country click on this video to
hear more about Qatar and also do not
forget to visit our friends at the
reconsider media podcasts.
They provided the vocals in this episode
that we're not mine and don't forget too
that we've published brand new videos
every week on Mondays and Thursdays,
so hit that subscribe button and give us
a thumbs up and as always,
I'll see you next time
and if you want to learn more about
politics and hear more of my lovely
voice,
don't forget to check out the reconsider
podcast@reconsidermedia.com.
We consider as a podcast that challenges
you to reconsider your abuse by
providing context,
but we don't do the thinking.