On this channel,
we talk about politics.
Are you prepared to accept the truth?
Because that's what I'm going to tell
these people are out to make your lives
a living hell.
You are fake news,
okay?
Okay,
but not this kind of politics.
In this channel,
we want to know the why of politics and
the why of economics.
When the whole world needs your oil,
you have all of the deal making power.
We want to understand why some countries
are poor.
How did the government destroy the
economy in such a short amount of time
and how good politics can make good
countries.
Switzerland has one of the world's best
political systems and we believe that
this is the reason that they are
successful and to understand how the
world is changing.
In other words,
Estonia has invented a brands new
concepts,
the concept of liquid citizenship.
In fact,
this has nothing to do with the politics
that you see in the traditional media.
It's real.
It's informative,
it's visual or politic,
and welcome to our channel.