Which about a launch list,
small countries which are more
successful,
these questions may seem silly,
but if you are,
I guarantee you they are not
well that is gaining more and more
countries,
so obviously countries,
they are becoming smaller.
Since 1950.
Our wealth has gone from having about 60
countries to having more than 200.
So this may lead to a few questions.
I'll smaller countries,
a good or a bad thing.
Are they more viable in some way?
While these are the questions that we're
going to answer in this video,
but first a quick comment when we're
talking about small countries,
so we need countries where the
population of fewer than 10 million
inhabitants,
this includes Hong Kong and Macau
because even though they are a part of
China,
they have their own laws,
they have their own courts and customs,
et Cetera.
This is a law that grants its citizens'
rights and freedoms that would be
unimaginable in any other place in China
with the exception of Macau,
which was integrated into China
following the same model.
So having several of that,
let's proceed to the key issue.
What is happening with these small
countries,
and this is actually a really important
issue in international politics,
we all knew that a good deal of
political conflicts have to do with
precisely this with many territories
wanting to declare themselves
independent hands become new countries.
Some examples are Scotland's Catalonia
and go to start
in the small.
There's no doubt here.
Smaller countries don't usually play a
large role in international news.
They aren't really involved in major
conflicts.
They don't participate in major decision
making processes and truthfully that
political news is not usually that well
known,
but this is all pretty normal.
We all know the presidents of the United
States or France or Russia,
who cares about the rules of countries
like Ireland,
Denmark or Taiwan.
Yes.
Now it's true on visual politic.
We tend to talk about them,
but it's not really that common out
there in the room.
Real wealth,
despite all of this.
The truth is that in the last 30 years,
if something has characterized smaller
countries,
is that they do things a lot better than
large countries.
In fact,
whenever ranking is published about the
richest countries,
the most innovative,
most competitive,
happiest,
safest,
all of these things,
small countries almost always occupied
most of the top positions.
Hands,
yeah.
It's usually when we read these rankings
that we kind of noticed there exist and
we probably ask ourselves,
well,
I want to do.
They do it.
You see,
if we take for example,
the ranking of the richest countries in
the world,
that is the countries with the highest
GDP per capita.
We find this among the 10 richest
countries.
Nine of them are smaller countries by
the way,
out of those nine countries,
eight half less than 6 million
inhabitants.
That is,
they are much smaller than some cities
like Dallas,
Philadelphia,
or Toronto.
She's the top 25 countries.
Things they change a bit,
but not that much.
Out of the top 25 richest countries in
the world,
17,
all small
countries
take price differences into account.
That is if we take the GDP per capita
pad with purchasing power,
the fact,
so even more shockingly one sided in
that case,
14 of the richest territories in the
welds are all talking about really,
really different countries.
There have a high population density
like Singapore,
others have a really low,
unlike Finland's some also have more
natural resources like Qatar and others
have practically nothing like ours.
Art more agricultural and others are
more financial.
Some are large and territory and others
are not.
That is to say there is an absolutely
huge variety,
but they all have one thing in common
and that's very few in
who told you
about countries like Iceland,
New Zealand,
Luxembourg,
Norway,
Ireland,
Denmark,
Singapore,
Austria,
Switzerland and Finland.
Here and in 2014 and 2015.
Two studies published by the Credit
Suisse research units corroborated this
exact situation.
He studies found that small countries
tend to be richer and more egalitarian
and more socially advanced.
In fact,
on average,
they invest a lot more in things like
their education
health.
That wasn't enough.
Small countries tend to have more lawful
accounts,
have less debt,
less deficits,
and even fewer taxes.
Even if we look at their financial
markets or stock exchanges.
For example,
we will see it in the last decades.
Smaller countries markets have performed
the best.
Have a look at this chart,
so now I'm probably going to voice the
question that all of you are thinking in
your mind is right now on that swell.
How on earth is this happening?
Well to success,
yes.
Do small countries work better than
large ones on big countries spaced out
larger markets,
more business opportunities,
and a greater ability to take advantage
of economies of scale.
So what's failing here,
and just before we get into it,
I do want to say that I am excluding tax
havens here because that's not really
fat.
Nivo.
Finland's Austria,
Denmark,
or New Zealand for example,
can be considered under any
circumstances.
Tax Haven.
What is the explanation here?
Well,
as we usually say visual politic,
that's never a single cause,
but we can see that these countries,
prosperity comes largely from that own
weakness.
Yeah,
yeah.
You heard that right?
So these small countries are involved in
more international trade,
not only sell,
but also to buy the products they need a
small country,
obviously they can't produce everything
they need.
Also,
they are more exposed to competition and
the swings of the international
financial market,
yes,
forces them to be more prudent with
their accounts to keep themselves
competitive kinds.
Of course,
since they can't afford them to avoid
the implementation of protectionist
policies.
In fact,
want to take a look at another data
point seat 21 out of 25 of the most
globalized countries.
That is countries that are most open to
the movements of goods people and
capital our small country,
yes.
Own Hands.
If we want to see how these countries
economy and his company competitiveness
work,
we only need to take a look at,
for example,
the weld banks doing business index,
which as you know,
classifies countries based on that ease
of doing business.
The latest doing business 2018,
which the World Bank published on
October the 31st 2017 is also dominated
by small countries.
New Zealand,
Singapore,
Denmark,
and Hong Kong.
Occupied four of the top five places and
among the top 25 countries in the world
for doing business 16,
a small countries and there's something
even more important.
See,
small countries tend to have much less
bureaucracy first because they don't
need so many political structures or at
least it's hard to justify them seconds
because citizens tend to be more aware
of the costs involved and third,
because they simply can't.
The role of this is that small
countries,
they tend to be more flexible,
more competitive,
and less bureaucratic.
Before some of you might be thinking
right now,
well Simon couldn't small countries beat
Richard because they were created
enriched zones and Richard territory.
Well,
the honest truth of that is simply no
okay.
Of Islands,
and there's the case of Singapore,
for example,
which just a few decades ago were quite
poor countries and so on nowadays to
have the richest countries in the world.
Another good example is the old republic
of
a vacuum.
Proof of separation.
In 1993,
Czechoslovakia decided to divide into
two smaller countries,
the Czech Republic and
the vacuum
that time both countries which used to
form Czechoslovakia,
suffered the effects of the Soviet
Union's Fullan's underwent a severe
transition.
However,
despite this the check side,
we're still much richer than the slave
act.
In fact
is the Vacchio.
The park,
as their income was only 65 percent of
unemployment rates were almost five
times higher,
and the Slovak Republic,
it depended too much on the money that
came as interregional solidarity from
the richest parts of the country.
That is the
awesome,
well
since they separated in 1993,
both countries have done quite well.
They successfully transitioned from a
communist model to a capitalist model
and have both grown considerably more
than,
for example,
Germany.
Now out of these two countries,
the one that has progressed the most has
been Slovakia.
Yes,
having to organize itself while having
to compete actually favored the poorest.
You can see the clear convergence that
has occurred between both countries and
the following crop.
We'll explain everything about this in
an upcoming video.
We're done.
We just want to have one last note here.
The new world configuration.
Globalization has led to countries with
a large population no longer having the
upper hand and it's not just that.
The truth is that in this world,
fostering traits such as
competitiveness,
openness and adaptability are becoming
increasingly important and for the time
being divvied small countries seem to be
even more efficient at this and not just
small countries,
but even cities.
Yeah,
you heard me right there and I'll.
Wells big cities have become the most
important economic growth
drivers just includes
London,
New York City,
Hong Kong,
Singapore,
Macau cities that playing an
increasingly important role in our
world.
The economy of Jakarta,
for example,
grows twice as much as Indonesia as
economy.
New York's GDP is twice that of Sweden
and the countries that have the highest
percentage of the population living in
cities tend to be richer.
So that leaves me wondering,
based on that information,
shouldn't we all have that on smaller
decentralized states for even give
cities some measure of independence?
I'll just leave that thought,
right?
Yeah,
of course.
None of this compares to the influence
that the development of supernational
organizations have to address from
terrorism to caring for the environment,
but now it's your turn.
What do you think is better wells with
several small countries or a weld with
just a few launch one?
Leave your answer in the comment section
below as well as in this survey,
and I do really hope you enjoyed this
video.
Please do hit that like button below if
you did and do not forget to subscribe
to our channel for brand new videos
every Monday and every Thursday and
don't forget to check out our friends at
the reconsider media podcasts.
They provided the vocals in this
episode,
but we're not mine and as always,
thanks for awhile.