One thing is very clear,
Vladimir Putin is one of the most
controversial politicians in the world.
He is vitalized by some and hated by
others,
but what is for sure is that Putin's
period in office is making its mark on
international politics.
The truth is that the government has
achieved little in terms of economic and
social matters under his leadership.
His popularity among Russians remains
really high today.
In this video,
we're going to analyze why Putin is
quite popular in Russia,
so this,
this Spanish saying that says after the
storm that comes the calm.
Well,
when it comes to Russia,
this is exactly what happens after going
through a tough crisis in the last few
years due to the fall in oil prices as
well as the sanctions received from the
international community for occupying
Crimea.
The government has been pretty blunt,
but difficult times have passed.
Ams.
The Russian economy is back,
but is it really,
I mean,
where's the evidence to really back this
up and tell me,
what do you think Russian grief is
expected to be in 2017?
Twelve percent maybe nine,
five,
three,
two?
Nope.
Well,
it's actually predicted to be one
percent
month after month.
The Russian economy keeps growing.
For 2017,
we're expecting a growth of one percent
or even more Igor Shuvalov
that sure doesn't look like a lot and
that's bearing in mind that Russia is
not exactly a rich country to begin
with,
and to be honest,
that one percent is only if we believe
the statistics of the Russian
government's,
which well,
more and more analysts considered to be
rather fictitious.
The truth is that even though everything
seems to indicate that the Russian
economy is more stable for last few
years,
have not exactly been easy for the
Russians.
According to the Russian social security
institutes in the year 2016 alone,
Russian citizens suffered from the
biggest loss in purchasing power.
That means real income since the 19
nineties.
Not a good
thing.
The crisis and the depreciation of the
ruble,
the Russian currency has led to this
country with $145 million inhabitants,
tabet GDP that's similar to that of
Australia,
which only has a population of $23
million.
And what's even worse is that for now it
doesn't look like the situation is going
to improve.
So here we come to the great Russian
anomaly evidence,
which shows that this country is very
different from any other,
neither the crisis and all these
terrible economic conditions have
damaged the national popularity of
Vladimir Putin.
In fact,
Putin's popularity is today higher than
it's pretty much ever been.
According to polls from the Levada
Center,
Putin's approval rating among the
Russian population is almost 80 percent.
I'll have a look at it.
This
now.
You might be wondering how is this even
possible?
Why is this man immune to such a crisis?
Well,
let's have a look at just what is
happening.
The protective father,
when the Russian
economy is pretty much mandatory to talk
about oil and raw materials,
and here are two pieces of information
so you can get some idea of just how
dependent on Russia is on these
resources
before the fall.
And the prices of crude oil,
oil and natural gas meant a lot to the
Russian economy.
Seventy percent of the country's exports
and more than 50 percent of all income
of the Russian government came from
these two commodities.
And take a look at the evolution of the
price of oil during the years.
Peter has been in office.
So anyway.
Well Putin,
he was incredibly lucky right after he
reached out the price of oil,
which should remained stable around $20
a barrel for the last 10 years,
started to increase quickly and of
course this is an amazing flow of money
coming into the country just so you can
get an idea of how significant this was.
The share the government contributed to
the economy rose from 35 percent to 70
percent.
All of a sudden prosperity came to the
entire nation.
There were cranes everywhere.
Skyscrapers started to appear as if they
were mushrooms after the rain and the
standard of living for Russians went up
and up and up.
Yeah.
So it is true that Putin's
authoritarianism could be felt right
from the very beginning,
but I mean say what you ucas.
The money was flowing.
Okay,
so we could say that there was this sort
of agreements between Russian society
leader in exchange for not asking you
about civil liberties or corruption.
The government gave prosperity and
stability to the citizens.
In a way Putin became some sort of
protective father to the nation.
A tough,
capable father who was able to take care
of his children has always.
The problem is that these situations are
fragile.
Know government's not even Putin's as
the capacity of achieving this
prosperity all on its higher.
Yeah.
With such high oil prices,
Putin didn't conduct any reforms in
Russia.
I mean,
what would really be the point ends up
because of that.
When the price of oil starts to go down
in the summer of 2014,
the economy of Russia followed the same
pattern and it is here that we come to
the most interesting part of this story.
None of these things affected Putin's
popularity.
The Russian president knew,
for want of a better word,
how to recycle his earliest strategy.
If at the beginning he was the guardian
of prosperity,
now he would become the leader who would
recover the previous great influenced
that mother Russia use to have
nationalist
fervor.
Sorry if Russia's economy wasn't having
the best moments.
Well,
he had to look for another source of
popularity and Putin,
well,
he knew where to find it.
For 500 years.
Russia's foreign policy was all about
expanding its influenced since the times
of only when the terrible around the
14th century,
Russia expanded its territory on average
80 square kilometers a day until it
became by far the largest country on
earth dance well as the most powerful.
However,
after the fall of the Soviet Union,
the influence of Russia on the world
collapse.
Puson made a new promise and it could be
summarized like this,
be a prosperous country and the economic
situation may be bad,
but I bladimir poutine will recover
Russia's influence in the world.
You may not be your wealthy people.
Bless you.
Our nation will be strong in order to
make this strategy work.
Some things on unnecessary.
The first of them is to praise
nationalist sentiments,
and this means well.
Russia,
and more.
Russia
bladimir unveiled a statue of medieval
namesake who united Russian land.
Well,
either way following these same ideals,
all the recurring adverts of new
invincible weapons,
incredibly powerful ones which will
guarantee you Russia gains great status
and global supremacy.
First of all,
though,
an important question is going to be
whether the Russian governments can
actually afford these weapons.
The second necessary thing is rather
more sinister and that's going to be for
Russia to find an enemy.
This enemy is something that can push
Russians towards a common goal.
Let me explain that a little further.
Russia,
they need a threats.
They need an aggressive.
They need something for the Russians to
unite against,
and in order to achieve that content
requires an aggressive foreign policy.
I see
the Ukrainian crisis,
the accusations against NATO and the
occupation of Crimea.
All examples that have made Putin's
popularity rise again in the alleys.
If the Russians,
Putin is taking Russia back to its
previous grants.
Yes,
second strategy,
you can explain the busy schedule of
rough and diplomacy.
In the last few years,
they may not have much money that Moscow
is everywhere,
Ukraine,
Syria and North Africa,
and hey,
to be honest,
the sanctions the international
community have imposed on Russia had
kind of the opposite effect that was
intended.
They have been seen by the Russians as
humiliating and if they've had any
effects,
he was to consolidate popular support
for Vladimir Putin.
Seventy five,
four percent of Russians consider the
sanctions to be an intention to weaken
and humiliate Russia.
Only five percent.
Think of them as an instrument to stop
the conflict in Ukraine,
Levada center
and last of all for Putin.
It is unnecessary for him to consolidate
to the image of a strong determined
leader,
almost a national hero something of a
savior,
if you will.
There is no Russia today if there is no
Putin,
sorry.
These are the keys and understanding why
Vladimir Putin has been able to keep an
even increases popularity.
He is no longer the guardian of
prosperity,
but the leader who will regain the power
that Russia ones had crony capitalism.
Another decisiveness at Sydney
considered is that Putin's governments
also survivors because he has been able
to create a network of powerful
oligarchs around him who have gotten
rich thanks to the resources of the
Russian state governments aids launch
state contracts and things in its
commitments to replace imports have all
benefited.
These oligarchs,
former judo partner awarded contract to
build Russian bridge to Crimea.
It'll cost more than $3,000,000,000
besides speak to it as a backup plan.
In case things go awry,
he can privatized or more accurately
just give states companies away to these
oligarchs who will use that power and
money to further Putin's interests.
The Russian president has made it clear
that nobody strategic investors will be
allowed to participate in
privatizations,
and that means only investors who have
been selected by the Russian
government's iron fist.
Oh,
Ron's.
Lest we forget the repression,
political repression and the repression
of minorities.
That seems to be kind of a fetish for
dictators and potential dictators.
I mean,
just take a look at the last report from
Amnesty International on human rights in
Russia.
It's pretty sad.
Restrictions on right to freedom of
expression,
association and Peaceful Assembly
increased in 2016.
Well,
now we all know the ingredients that
explains Putin's popularity,
nationalism,
oligarchs,
censorship,
and political repression.
Putin has promised the people that they
will become powerful again in exchange
for that unconditional loyalty.
However,
despite all of this posturing,
it does seem kind of unlikely that
Russia is going to be able to seriously
competes with either China or the US in
the media and in the long run,
but that's our opinion here,
visual politic,
and as always,
we'd love to know what you think.
Do you think Putin will be successful in
giving Russia rids old power back?
What would you prefer?
National Power Bowl,
maybe wellbeing,
prosperity,
and freedom.
We definitely know what weird ones,
but we'd like to know what you would
like.
Drop us a comment below this video.
Let us know your thoughts and well,
if you enjoy this video,
please do give it a thumbs up below and
do not forget to subscribe.
We put our brand new videos every Monday
and every Thursday,
and please don't forget to check out our
friends at the reconsider media podcast
who provided the voice in this video
that isn't mine,
and as always I'll see you in the next
step.