Democracy,
it's a tricky concept now.
Yes,
we all agree that people must have a say
on governmental decisions,
but on the other hands were kind of
scared to see what happens when the
citizens are manipulated by a populist
politician.
This is why direct democracy and
referendums are quite so controversial.
In theory it seems like a great idea,
so I'll ask the voters directionally
about the very laws that affect them,
but what happens when we actually put
something like this into practice?
Yes.
Well,
occasionally you do get a rather nasty
surprise,
but not always.
Indeed,
there is one country that needed direct
democracy,
a cornerstone of that political system,
no war.
Despite what you might think.
We are not talking about Switzerland
here this time we're talking about
liquidity
shine.
All right.
I know.
I mean,
why should you care about such a small
country?
Well,
look,
Lichtenstein,
it has a population of less than 38,000
inhabitants,
but despite their size,
their political system is one of a kind.
Despite being a constitutional monarchy,
most of the political decisions in this
principality done through referendums.
This includes economic policy.
Social spending and even citizenship,
yes,
that is right.
If you wanted to become a lichtenstein
or your neighbors get to choose whether
to accept or reject you through a
popular vote.
Even the right to self determination can
be guaranteed by referendum.
This means that any of the 11
municipalities in sight of Lichtenstein
can hold a popular vote to decide
whether they want to stay in the country
or become an independent nation or
sounds pretty crazy,
right?
Well,
it certainly seems to have served
Lichtenstein incredibly well along with
Qatar.
Lichtenstein is the wealthiest country
on the planet,
at least when it comes to GDP per capita
at purchasing power parity.
This country is also known for its
political stability.
It's rule of law and its business
friendly policies and well at this point
in the video you might be beginning to
wonder,
well,
how is all of this possible?
How can you manage the guarantees such a
stable political system when people can
vote in any crazy law they want simply
with a referendum?
Well,
this is what we were wondering here at
visual politic to and to figure out the
answer to this question.
We decided that the best thing was to go
to the country and last,
so we did just that.
A Gal is a village with no more than
2000 inhabitants that technically it
could become an independent sovereign
country if it wanted to,
so we wanted to find out exactly how
that would happen.
So we spoke with the mayor of the town.
Great.
Thank you for joining us today.
I appreciate you taking the time to meet
with us and just answer a few a few
questions.
If we could start off,
if I could ask,
what is the legal way for the town of
regale could separate from the country
of Lichtenstein and how could,
how could regale hold a self
referendums?
Does he facetune Dank part?
It's very does to be focused on.
Then now her very smugly say,
does he say dish?
I was making the seat somehow taken say
punked room.
Yeah,
deceased tank,
but we had food and survive that Suki
hertich lunchtime leaking shine.
Eastern client owned a escaped came and
good wound.
To me.
I can type austism for boondoggles,
so shaken
and as far as far as I can see here,
we've been in Lichtenstein for a couple
of days.
The prince is very well respected here,
isn't it?
Yeah.
Uh,
the first is to actually any respects
persona owned via seen doc be counted
toward Houston House just recently in
Lichtenstein.
Andrea Dane can the first tower we see
owning his students.
A start over helped me to see Owen.
And when does he start?
Sean oft to go to get common,
some beige.
Bill Boehm to bay St Louis,
the OPS team for the rights to give food
to at rallies rights,
wilted on neat by threaten dim on the BS
in Tobago.
Klauber positive.
Our we act on the is not nearby.
Prince Hans,
Adam.
The second is the wealthiest monique in
all of Europe with a net worth of more
than 4 billion American dollars.
But make no mistake here.
His wealth doesn't come from his
political role,
but instead from his business career,
he is the owner of the lgbt banking
group.
One of the biggest asset management
firms.
Europe.
He inherited the principality in 1989
and you can say that he is the father of
the direct democracy system here in
Lichtenstein.
In his book the state in the third
millennium.
He outlined a way to implement this
system in a larger country and well,
this is what we wanted to talk to him
about yesterday and Highness.
Thank you once again for being here.
I really appreciate taking time to talk
to us and inviting us to your home.
What,
what do you mean?
It's a really broad question,
but what do you mean by the state as a
service provider?
I think the state should really
concentrate on those jobs,
uh,
which the state can do better than
private industry or a better than the
local communities.
And for me,
it also important when a,
uh,
proposals,
changes of the,
uh,
of the constitution to all also
introduced a right of self determination
at every village in leakage.
Dan Has the right to leave the standard
principality,
if they think that they get a better
offer from another country or if they
can make more money,
uh,
or lower taxation or God knows what,
if they become independent.
And that was for me also important,
you know,
also for my successes and for the
politician to really to deliver very
good service on low cost and therefore
low cost with low taxation.
Do you think that
lower cost is driven by competition?
Yeah.
Between the,
my understanding is the local
governments have of Lichtenstein is,
you know,
they have a lot of self determination.
They're also competing with each other.
Is that,
could you,
could you tell me a little how that
works?
Yeah,
the different.
We have 11 villages,
basically a,
they compete on,
on,
on taxation.
Uh,
they compete on the way how they offer
the infrastructure.
For instance,
give building sites to some industry
knows what.
So there is a certain competition
services or whatever.
So.
So they compete on this issues
basically.
So if I was a Vichtenstein Ian and I was
living here and I was looking at 11
different villages,
I feel,
you know,
again,
relating to my experience,
you know,
I,
I basically have like one country where
I grew up so I'm always going to relate
things to the UK.
But I think about it if I,
if I,
I grew up in a village called
headquarters and if like I guess in the
next village over town or Canterbury or
whatever,
I get pretty much the same deal is,
it's not going to be any different,
you know,
whether I'm working for someone or
starting a business or applying to the
government for a permit to do something,
it's always going to be the same.
But here in Lichtenstein fi I can look
at what the different villages are
offering and make a decision.
So religious said,
oh,
we have now enough manufacturing
industry all,
uh,
also enough foreignness.
It was also quite an issue because if
you attract being the service,
the service instead of manufacturing
industry with it,
you attract also workforce also from
outside.
Because we cannot provide all the
workforce here.
Not the specialist and so on.
So basically,
so there was no resistance.
No,
we have to stop and others took up the
chances and uh,
we're able to attract a manufacturing or
service industries and therefore get
more income for the village and then off
of,
oh,
lower taxation or build a new road or a
new school or a renovated church or God
knows whatever ideas they had.
This works fantastically here,
but in a country as large as the United
States,
the UK,
Spain.
Do you think this,
is that right?
To self sovereignty and that right?
That works so well here in a small
country.
Do you think they can work in,
in the constitution of,
of a,
of a much larger country?
Yes.
I think,
yes,
I've seen it in Switzerland.
They have it,
they have this direct democracy,
they have this decentralization
sometimes depending on the can't on down
to the small villages.
I've seen it to a certain degree also in
United States,
of course they're from state to state.
It's a little bit different.
Uh,
but that influenced me very much and
thought that's basically a good system
and a to give the people some say
because usually,
especially in a very centralized states,
uh,
as a politician or has a monarch or a
monitor,
a ga or president or prime minister,
it takes so long until you realize that
there's a problem and with that problems
pop up and suddenly you'll see,
oh,
I didn't realize that they suddenly have
an initiative being locally being on a
statewide level.
And then you can solve those problems
bunch earlier
and Lichtenstein for reference about
40,000
people.
So you go out there,
you can gather these things.
It's interesting because I feel this
should be something if I can get a
thousand of my friends together and then
put something forward and then
parliament have to discuss it.
And if it's quite a smart idea of a
constitutional change at 1,500
could happen,
which,
you know,
Primo Fasc,
you think this is going to be less
stable,
right?
You know,
the immediate thought that comes into
the mind because anyone can change this
right away.
But this doesn't happen here and it
doesn't seem to happen in other places
that have a similar thing.
Why do you think that is?
Because many of those things are on the
local
basis and you have people who are in
favor of it against it and so all those
things are much more discussed within
the population,
within the voting with the voters,
and I think that has turned out to be an
advantage,
edited the stability.
If I look at Switzerland,
for instance,
nevertheless I think that we have even a
vest assist in this was the possibility
of a veto power,
but the reigning prince,
just to clarify the Swiss system,
they also have a similar system of
direct democracy,
but obviously in a prince two visa,
it's now before continuing with this
interview where you wanted to get in
touch with some politicians from
parliaments.
The Flyer list,
the party is the most critical voice
inside of Lichtenstein's political
system
only has bonds actually used just sweet
to power.
In 1961,
it was a hunting law.
I have no idea,
but it goes a little baby then,
but it was about the hunting lawyers and
she didn't like that and he didn't
signed the,
the law and that was it.
He doesn't even have to say why he
doesn't sign.
It just doesn't sign.
And since then it hasn't really been
necessary.
Of course,
a threat to have to,
to make use of the Meta powers of course
has an effect on the working soft
department.
So you have to get over,
you have to reach a consensus.
It in Indiana.
I thought that it will be worthwhile to
keep,
uh,
the veto power of the reigning prince
except for an initiative.
The people want to abolish the monarchy
because I saw that sometimes you had in
Switzerland votes,
which were perhaps not in the long term
interest of the country,
of the people,
the reigning prince.
We think in generations.
We had 15 or 20 years ago,
we had discussions about this dualism
system and people wanted more power,
but at the end there was a,
there was a referendum and 65 percent of
the people said,
no,
let's keep it like it is.
You could argue that democracy should
overrule the Monitor Archaic System,
but it's the other way around at the
moment.
And that has been decided by the people
referendums they often are,
you know,
with Brexit,
it was like you just had the people who
wanted to leave calling the people who
wanted to stay calling the people who
wanted to leave.
And it was kind of this ongoing theme in
relations to that.
Um,
how do you think,
you know,
in a country that has so many
referendums that people can make
informed decisions
at two things which we have to take.
You have to take into account before you
introduce it.
One is that you have to start on the
local basis that people read,
really,
uh,
get trained indoors,
kind of direct democracy referendums.
Initiative said,
saw where they can see what's the effect
of a stupid decision on the village.
And the city,
whatever,
so that they're seeing is,
is,
is one aspect.
The other aspect is that you will have
to inform the people quite a lot we have
in the law and also Switzerland that you
as a Jew did to inform,
give the order information to have
enough time for people to,
uh,
before vote,
discussions and so on,
so that,
that's very important and you have to
hand out all the information and neutral
basis.
I wanted to ask about that because it
seems often the information at least
I've seen is handed out by whichever
newspaper you tend to subscribe to a how
does that,
how is that neutral information
disseminated to the population
government?
All the village administration,
if it's just on the local vote,
um,
has to hand out the information and
neutral information where both sides
can,
uh,
put this information.
There's a,
then they can also put their own view
into there.
So that's handed out to all the voters
so they can look it up.
They organize meetings and so on.
So before such a vote,
it's really.
That seems people are well informed.
Yeah.
Those,
I don't know,
whenever I tend to read stuff written by
government,
it's as an,
I think of myself as reasonably
intelligence and I read some of this
stuff,
but I'm like,
uh,
like it's governments can be verbose and
they're not perhaps the best at writing
things in an easy to understand way.
Is this information presented in a way
that,
you know,
it doesn't require a degree to
understand.
It's kind of like his how it is for the
every man
in your own interest.
If you read in a stupid way or the
highway which nobody understands is
going to be rejected,
right?
The people writing this,
of course you have to check that the,
the right correct way and you can appeal
to the,
to,
to court.
So if there's wrong information in,
there was cool.
Separation of powers now,
right
as I mentioned,
Lichtenstein by by various measures,
the highest GDP per capita in the world.
So very,
very wealthy country and we've been
walking around and it's reflected in
beautifully clean streets.
Just a lovely looking place.
But it wasn't always like this was it,
it was,
it was quite different.
So,
uh,
I think I read kind of agrarian was the
time.
Can you tell me a little bit about,
about the history of,
of Lichtenstein,
kind of before,
you know,
it's,
it's relatively recent economic success,
what will know from my predecessor
around 1700 bought the governing the
rights of those.
There were two counties in the holy
Roman Empire.
It was basically have a road bike
exercise because you voted to the
emperor.
And so for him to get more influence in
the holy Roman Empire as a prince of the
holy Roman Empire,
a he bold those voting rights because it
was very poor.
And,
and the families who were raining then
went bankrupt.
He could have cross support by his huge
estates.
It was no problem.
Uh,
those,
uh,
two counties and put them together,
made the principality,
artificial.
So if he,
he buys the lands because the possession
of the land is what gives him the voting
rights.
Not traded the procession of the lag,
but it was the reigning powers over the
land.
Okay.
So the land will still be partly in
private ownership.
That was separated.
It was some kind of private who bought
some counties have accounts here who
went bankrupt and to pay for the.
For the people who vote,
they owed money.
Then there was a court in the holy Roman
Empire where they just sort of
auctioning off the governing rights and
my free says a 17 century laws,
very rich,
and he paid the highest price for that.
So it wasn't.
In a way it was still private lands
ownership.
It was.
He was buying the governing rights or
you for what is today?
Lichtenstein?
Yes.
Nobody was really interested here in the
land.
The first one to move here to finish,
that was my father in 1938 and the first
of all to wizard what one of his answers
to the predecessor bought.
He came there,
I think when the railway was built
throughout Australia,
sometimes in the middle of the 19th
century,
so
hundreds of now I could go visit.
It's not that I've purchased.
What's that?
They?
Of course,
they always.
They nominate someone to represent them
and they paid for the people.
They introduced reforms.
They paid for dedication of people.
One of the first countries to introduce
a bonus free educational educational on
a statewide basis.
So yeah,
we'll try to develop it.
Yeah.
So it,
it existed at that point in your,
you said your father was the first one
to move here.
What,
why?
What changed is,
was it around the time of the war or
whatever?
Of course it,
what?
Basically the family lived on the huge
estates,
what is now the Czech Republic and all
the palace in Vienna,
whole summer states in Australia still.
Uh,
but then,
uh,
when,
Hitler,
uh,
took over Australia,
well,
didn't know what would happen with
lifting and when the German troops
marched into Austria by a father who was
not yet during prince,
his,
his great uncle was married to a Jewish,
a barrow nes family was very much anti
Nazi for
see what the married to a baron.
It's probably not best friends.
The randy prints flat to Czechoslovakia
over the boulder.
And my father drove his car,
met the German troops marching towards a
Vienna and try to stabilize it here.
Yeah.
Luckily he succeeded that,
uh,
we were not the next.
There was a small,
uh,
there was a small attempt of a coup
d'etat he unleashed when Nazi party,
uh,
when my father,
I think in 1938 just before the outbreak
of World War Two,
the small,
not Nazi party by the support of some
Nazi people outside,
I seem to governor have to roll and fall
back or southern Germany support that.
They tried to make a mark on the dots
like the march on Rome,
but to do cheer.
Wow.
Was a bad copy.
Bold boat.
Yeah.
But then the people heard about it stuff
because you couldn't keep it secret.
Uh,
so people came together.
The farmers at that time,
you know,
with all the instruments there,
hydrocodone forks and all the lawsuits
on this around the country.
Wow.
I failed.
Fascinating.
Your father was,
was here and he established what exists
today,
essentially.
That's right when the reigning princes
came to visit before they build a villa
up here.
Uh,
but they came with settlement.
It was only built in the second half of
the 19th century when the first came to
visit.
Uh,
but then the people wanted to have the
costal,
uh,
which was before a museum adapted so
that it will be residents or three
prints and this is where we are and
that's where we are
now.
Most people think that Lichtenstein just
became rich because of that low taxes
and their secret banking laws.
But this couldn't be further from
reality.
Now,
of course the financial sector does play
a big role here,
but in fact the industrial sector is the
biggest economic power in Lichtenstein.
Have you heard of the company Hilti or
Ivr called Viva dense?
Well,
if you haven't heard of that latter one,
the next time you go into the dentist,
have a look at the brands of tools they
use,
most likely they were made in
Lichtenstein
to hitting system of the company that is
still in the Buckingham Palace.
I,
I'm guessing that they updated it from
this version already,
but yes,
the Buckingham Palace is heated by a
heating system out of leakage Stein.
So we were,
we were kind of talking and we,
we spoke with other people as well about
the employment situation in licked
strikes.
It's about 40,000
people in the country,
but a lot of people come from around two
to work here kind of as a commute.
Right.
Lichtenstein actually has more.
I'm working places.
Then we have inhabitants.
So we have roughly 38,000
inhabitants and 39,000
chops.
That means we are heavily dependent on
commuters that come into the country
each day.
I think it's about 20,000
people that come here each day.
And what are these people typically
doing?
Um,
most of them work in the industries in
like a 40 biggest companies like Hilti,
like the evil Claude or the to some
crooked presta
related to the economy of Lichtenstein.
And you know,
I appreciate the history.
Things I didn't,
didn't even know after doing the
research role of this.
Um,
what,
what kind of drove the change from the
Agrarian Lichtenstein from I suppose,
how it was before your father arrived in
and set things up here to Lichtenstein
as it is today because while it was at
60 or 70 years,
it's,
in a way,
that seems like a lot of time.
It's and not a lot of time for such a
dramatic transformation.
I think there are several factors which
were important are one factor was
already in the 19th century when one of
my predecessors introduced a general
schooling career,
one of the first states to introduce it,
I think worldwide a thing in Europe
because on thought because it was a poor
country relying on the subsidies of the
reigning prints.
So at least we should educate the people
so they can find a job outside of Stan
if they don't find one.
Insight.
One kept the uh,
taxation as low as possible.
So to attract business one was then able
to make a way of Allah.
The customers treat you with the Austin
Hungarian Empire that opened up the big
market before for the local market.
Hopeless,
small too small.
So with access to this large market or
one could attract a Swiss textile
industry.
Yeah,
because it's a across the border,
but next to it.
But there was a free trade with that.
Otherwise they would have had to pay
taxes.
It's,
I'm just thinking of the similarities
with today,
kind of how in the past it was,
we're a very small country.
We want to trade with Austria,
Hungary,
and now it's like European Union in a
way,
a similar thing.
You have your small country and we,
we saw a healthy,
the tool manufacturers,
the dental stuff,
of course,
a low taxation,
which is something we'll discuss in a
bit.
People I think often have these,
these notions where they're like,
they think of something and they're
like,
why is the place rich and Switzerland
rather than the Lichtenstein as an
example,
low taxes.
Right.
But the reality is that it's often more
than that,
whether it's education of an education.
Yeah.
And then also access to the markets.
If you don't have access to market.
We couldn't even feed our own people.
They were dependent on subsidies,
better any prints,
and of course it became better.
Result really was fine with anger an
empire and then after it collapsed.
Luckily we got the same three d with
Switzerland and I was able to push
through thanks to the Eric Democracy,
the European economic market,
because there was a lot of resistance,
a government and parliament and would
not have gotten through that.
But with direct democracy I was able to
put it into to a popular vote.
So I brought this.
We have several advantages here in
Lichtenstein.
One is that the taxes are not too high.
The other is we are actually in the
middle of Europe.
Well,
you've seen the distance since you're.
You're everywhere within no time,
right?
We're staying in Switzerland while we're
here in Lichtenstein,
just over the border,
as you were mentioning the people
commuting from Austria and Germany,
so race in the middle.
We are also located in two different
economic areas at the same time,
so we have very easy access to the Swiss
economic area and.
But we're also part of the European
economic area.
Right,
right next door to the EU,
right next door to Switzerland.
And we have both.
We have contracts that makes it very
easy.
So if you like,
for example,
if you have an insurance company and it
is based in Lichtenstein,
you just need one office to work in
Switzerland and in the EU.
Well if you don't have it in
Lichtenstein and then you need two
separate offices,
I think that the removal of the secret
banking that was who was here before.
Do you think that.
Do you think that affected
Lichtenstein's economy much?
What it reduced for short terms a tax
income against my more pessimistic look
at it,
I was very much in favor of opening it
up because it exposes so much criticism
of those banks or the financial
industry.
They recovered after two,
three years perhaps also because they
always said,
oh,
we're not going to be able to apportion
this begging secrecy,
which was introduced sometime before
world war two,
but Swiss and so on.
So that that's changing though.
You will have really two,
two,
if you want to survive in the long term
as a bank or in the financial industry,
you will have to offer good service for
people who are willing to pay also that
taxes in their home country.
I think that's another thing that
that I picked up on was with these
smaller states,
you can really focus on,
you know,
instead of like you say,
the reality is this is the way the
world's going.
People need to be open with their
finances.
This is how it's going to,
how it's going to be,
and then you could switch to a focus on
let's do really good banking.
Let's be really excellent banks.
Let's not be generic.
Giant Bank won't pick up the phone on
Saturday morning,
so you,
that's be really good at this.
Which is important.
Do you think that's another one of the
reasons why you know Lichtenstein is an
economy has done so well because you can
focus on doing things really rather
than.
I think so,
yes.
I think it was the education system.
It was low taxation.
It was the realization that you would
only be able to survive in a small,
a small country in an economy with no
whole market.
You had to compete on the world markets
to survive and nobody's going to protect
you.
The government cannot afford to support
one of our larger manufacturing
companies that we read.
We just,
then we would have to raise taxes and
there will be immediately,
uh,
an initiative but the people in the
popular vote.
Why,
why should we pay more taxes to support
Mr Archbold,
Mr Hill,
Mr Mayor,
Mr.
whatever Mueller.
This is why like your system,
because I feel this sometimes happens in
other countries.
Maybe my is.
We didn't really get to say it's like A.
Yeah,
we,
um,
we just gave them loads of money because
they were in trouble.
Um,
Le Pen,
trump,
UKIP.
Why now do you,
do you have an opinion on why?
Why do you think this is happening now?
We see changes in the whole system of
indirect democracy.
People get more detached.
Everything has become more complicated.
You have globalization.
There's not so much possibility to
decide only for your state.
All that makes people very unhappy and
therefore populism easy solutions that
people never really had looked much and
why this law or that law like
Switzerland or here,
there was also in Switzerland,
populist movements to certain degree on,
on immigration,
but that quietened down when it will
solve more or less and here divorce,
but not much and that I think is
something that has somehow tried me for
quite some time.
Those states who are,
in my opinion to certainly over
centralized an ultra filling anymore the
duties which are expected from the
people and that creates populism and,
and,
and easy.
So you and things like this and I think
I've seen a lot of easy solutions.
The appeal of easy solution,
is it a solution?
And very often they're catastrophists.
Yes.
Narrowly avoided sometimes.
Do you think increasing globalization,
you know,
maybe really is going to lead to more of
this.
Do you think this is something we're
going to see continue?
Do you think this is
kind of a something we're going to see
fade away as people perhaps realize
that,
you know,
once we've elected a populous,
they're not all they're cracked up to
be,
it's,
I don't think it's going to fade away
because globalization is going to
increase,
uh,
you really think you have to adapt to
this new situation and really know their
ordination state and social state told
the people that we are going to produce
heaven here on earth and that doesn't
turn out like that.
And so there's resentment on that and
people have the feeling that the people
up there,
the adult contact anymore with us,
they're detached,
they're just looking for their own
position,
they own money and that creates this
kind of populism.
And uh,
and that's,
I think,
a danger for democracy and that worries
me.
That's one of the reasons why I wrote my
book.
I just want to say it's been a real
pleasure to,
to ask you this.
Have you given me your thoughts and
everything.
It's been a pleasure.
It was an interesting discussion for me.
Tall glass.
Thank you very much.
Thank you.
Now,
as we often say here,
official policy of not everything is
perfect and despite the success of
Lichtenstein's model,
there are still many questions.
Is it legitimate that the head of state
is not chosen by his citizens?
Could this system really be implemented
in big nations?
Well,
now it's your turn.
Please do leave your answer in the
comment section below.
We'd love to hear from you and perhaps
many of you right now,
you're hungry for a little bit more.
Well,
if that is the case,
we do have a bonus for you.
You can watch the entire interview with
the prince and it has many,
many more questions in it's in that
video.
We talk about history of the war on
drugs and of course immigration.
Yeah,
especially the rich people moved in
before we put those restrictions because
of the low taxation,
they would buy nice houses and Nice
building places where as the local paper
couldn't afford it.
Now this video is only going to be
available to our patrion supporters,
and if you do want to become a support
that and get that bonus material,
please do check out our patrion page.
We really appreciate it for less than
the price of a cup of coffee per month,
you can help us to continue this project
called visual politic and also make it
bigger and more ambitious,
and as I mentioned,
you will also get access to the whole
Prince Hans Adam interview as well as
other exclusive content that we're going
to be publishing in the future.
So please do check that out.
There's a link in the description below
and also if you like this video,
please do give it a thumbs up and as
always I'll see you in the next one.