Brazil is the country of the future,
but it seems like we've been hearing
that for a long time lately though.
We've had a lots of other countries,
corruption scandals,
the economic crisis this is going
through or the street violence in cities
like Rio de Janeiro bond.
There is something even more important
about this country.
Something that doesn't appear very much
in the media.
Yeah.
Brazil is the most expensive country in
all of South America.
Yep.
You heard that,
right?
If you go shopping in a city like Sao
Paulo or Rio de Janeiro,
you'd better be ready to clean out your
wallet because it will be as expensive
as New York or London.
The Brazilians even have a name for
this.
They call it customer Brazil.
This is the special charge you have to
pay for living in the country of Samba.
So let's look at an example.
The Big Mac Burger that you buy from
Mcdonald's.
If you've been subscribed to visual
politics for a long time,
you already know that the economists use
something called the Big Mac index to
measure the cost of living in a country
double in Switzerland.
One of the wealthiest countries in the
world,
the big Mac costs a whopping six point
seven,
$5.
Then we have Peru,
a poorer country where the Burger and
costs $3 and twenty three cents.
Fair enough,
right?
Well,
in Brazil,
the big Mac,
it costs $5 and ten cents.
It's more expensive than in Denmark,
the UK or Canada,
according to the ex parte astound.com
website.
Sao Paulo is the most expensive city in
South America with prices as high as
Houston,
Texas,
Berlin,
or Germany.
And now you might want to give them the
high cost of living.
How high a Brazilian salaries,
all the wealthier save and Colombians.
Chileans.
Well,
absolutely not.
The average wage in Brazil is less than
$600 a month.
Argentinians and Chileans are actually
better off in this regard.
So the real question here is why is
Brazil so expensive?
One of the reasons why a middle income
country has the prices of a wealthy one.
Well,
today we are going to answer this
question and believe me,
there's also partly explains the
Brazilian crisis too.
So let's dive in.
Isolated economy.
Many of you might think of Brazil as a
country opens a free trade,
right?
Well,
at the end of the date,
many foreign companies like mastercard
or Barclays have a strong presence in
this country.
Nonetheless,
Brazil has the highest tariffs in South
America.
So what does this mean?
Well,
imagine we have a cell phone
manufacturer in America or in,
they wanted to sell on the Brazilian
market.
Since our product is made abroad,
we must sell it with a special tax that
could reach up to 35 percent of its
market price.
As you can imagine,
this type of policy has a pretty big
impact on everyday life.
Contento
exits.
Brazilian market due to high tariffs.
Yes.
Heard that right.
During those years,
Brazilians,
he wanted to buy a we or an intended des
had to travel to Uruguay in order to
find one.
Interestingly,
this was a great advantage for
Nintendo's biggest rivals,
especially Microsoft and the Xbox,
and you know why?
Well,
Microsoft has a factory in Brazil where
the xbox one is made.
This means they don't have to import it
and therefore it doesn't have those high
tariffs and yes,
I know what you're thinking.
High tariffs are cool because they
forced companies to build factories in
your country and employ your citizens.
Right?
Well,
think twice that when Microsoft opens
that Brazilian factory,
they still need to import all the
machines and materials needed to
manufacture that xbox one.
This can be plastic semiconductors,
robots.
Many of these things are made somewhere
else and if they are made somewhere
else,
they still have these special tariffs
and you can guess who pays for these
extra costs.
Of course,
it's the consumer.
This explains why so many products
manufactured in Brazil,
also expensive.
Want an example?
Take the Volkswagen Golf in Mexico City.
This car costs around 15,000 US dollars
in Sao Paulo.
It costs 25,000 US dollars.
All of this,
despite the fact that this specific
model of automobile is many factored in
Sao Paulo,
but wait a minute because this is not
the only thing that explains this.
Customer Brazil or what the Brazilians
used to refer to this incredibly high
cost of living cousteau.
Let's imagine someone doing soy
agriculture in the state of power in the
north of this country.
If he wants to send this side is all
power,
he must carry it on trucks through the
highway,
be all one six,
three.
This highway has over a thousand
kilometers and a hundred of its on.
Not even paved.
A simple rainy day is enough to keep
those trucks stuck in the mud,
and this is just one example.
In fact in Brazil has some of the worst
infrastructure in the world.
Even India has better roads,
so to make a comparison,
any xymogen American farmer sells $100
in,
so he has to spend $9 on transportation.
The same farmer in Brazil,
I'd have to pay $25 since they have no
good roads.
Brazilians have to invest in expensive
trucks that break down quickly and make
the cost even more expensive.
And of course all of this means higher
and higher prices for Brazilian
customers.
But now you might be wondering,
well,
why is the Brazilian governments are
reluctant to pay for infrastructure?
But at the end of the day,
Brazil has state of the art engineering
companies,
companies like the automatic.
It's great.
He happened to be someone watching from
a South American country.
Well,
this name probably rings a bell for you
or direct was the biggest engineering
and construction company in the region,
and I do say was here because they had
the biggest corruption scandal in the
history of the continent and as
naturally with the future of the firm
isn't looking pretty dim.
But this story does explain well why
Brazil has such poor infrastructure
because at the end of the day,
part of the money goes towards bribes
and corruption.
But normally that's when the Brazilian
government wanted to modernize their
country world.
What did they do?
Yeah,
well,
they decided to host the Olympic Games
and the FIFA World Cup.
So today,
Brazilian cities can congratulate
themselves for having the most beautiful
sports arenas with high end technology
and luxurious decoration today,
taking a walk in the center of Sao
Paolo,
or it feels like being in a Scifi movie,
but outside of this metropolis,
the railroads or abandons the highways
are unpaved and several neighborhoods
don't have a single bus line that
connects them with the city center.
Woeful infrastructure costs the economy
as much as $48,
billion US dollars per year.
Now,
of course this affects the prices for
Brazilian consumers,
but also for worldwide consumers who
wants to buy and Brazilian goods.
But that is something we're actually
going to address in a future video
because now the question really becomes
how can someone who makes $600 bucks a
month spend 25 bucks on pizza as an
average restaurant in Sao Paolo?
Well,
I am going to tell you how
ready
the hallway for decades,
Brazil had some of the highest inflation
in the wells during the 19 eighties and
nineties,
they had more than 6,000 percent
inflation.
This means if you had a bear as a Rio de
Janeiro bar in 1980,
you would pay 100 femoral.
The terra was the Brazilian currency
back.
Then one year later,
that same beer would cost 600,000
arrows.
As you can imagine,
hyperinflation created unique consumer
behavior
that was quite different from the rest
of the world in order to survive.
Resilience,
ships got used to selling with
installments and it's.
This is still a thing today.
If you go to any Brazilian shop,
you can see that next to the prices said
something like 10 x,
12 x or 20 x.
This number means that you can pay for
this product on 10,
12 or 20 installments.
In other words,
question many Brazilians ask themselves
is not whether this TV,
your this suit is more or less
expensive,
but if they can pay for it during the
next two years,
and as you can imagine when you buy
something in installments,
it is far more extensive.
On the screen,
we're showing you a smartphone on a
Brazilian ecommerce website.
If you bought a ones,
it costs 632 you race,
which is equivalent to $202 at the
moment.
We need this video nonetheless.
If you buy it with installments,
it costs 217 US dollars,
which is a seven percent increase.
So as you can imagine,
your average Brazilian is in debt all
the time.
Ninety percent of Brazilians in
installment
debt,
but
wait just a minute because is not the
worst of it.
In the last year,
something has happened in Brazil that is
done to custody Brazil into a real nice
matt ready
card.
How at the beginning of the two
thousands,
Brazil,
it was the perfect market for foreign
banks.
Big Financial firms like Santander or
credit suisse started investing in the
country.
And don't forget,
we're talking about a $200 million
person country that was on the rise here
where prices were high and people are
used to paying for things in
installments and other words.
Brazil.
It was a paradise for selling credit
cards since 2005 Brazil's credit card
market has grown at a 20 percent plus
rate and yeah.
Yep,
yeah,
2012 Brazilians had an average of two
credit cards per person and they really
knew how to use them.
Brazil was the country with the most
credit payments across all of South
America.
Nonetheless,
that happiness,
it didn't last very super default and
credit cards has reached 27 percent in
April 2012 in the very same year,
2012,
the alarm started to sound in all those
Brazilian banks.
The country was in the middle of a
crisis with rising unemployment and
declining salaries and that made it hard
for Brazilians.
Do pay back that debt.
So what happens when a bank is afraid of
getting into falses?
Well,
as the interest,
great
residents have to pay 414 percent
interest on their credit cards.
So you mentioned you use your credit
card to buy a TV screen.
The costs you a thousand US dollars,
you pay for it in 12 installments.
Well,
at the end of the day,
counting the interest rates and the
credit card,
the TV costs around 5,000 US dollars.
Pretty impressive,
isn't it?
And don't forget that the average wage
in present is less than $600 a month.
In other words,
no matter the antipoverty measures taken
by the government,
most Brazilians struggling to survive
and west of all,
since they call it,
saves money,
losing a job and be a real tragedy for
many,
almost
relation in Rio de Janeiro increases 150
percent in three years.
Yes.
Yeah.
Is the question now,
can Brazil get over the situation?
Who could possibly reformed this
country?
Well,
we'd love to know what you think so
please leave your answer in the comments
section below.
Also,
do not forget to check it off.
Friends at the reconsider media
podcasts,
they provided the vocals in this episode
that weren't on mine.
Also,
I've got a new channel.
It's called biographics.
We do biographies of notable people from
history as well as the present day.
You can find a link to that in the
description below,
and also don't forget that here,
a visual politic.
We published brand new videos every
week,
so please do subscribe and you will not
miss a post.
Also,
if you liked this video,
give us a thumbs up and there's always,
I'll see you next time and if you want
to learn more about politics and hear
even more of my lovely voice,
you can join us at reconsider media.
We have a podcast@reconsideredmedia.com
slash podcast.