[inaudible]
it's hard to put a sign.
Two thoughts when thinking about Africa.
The first is the thing that Africa is a
continent forever sentence do poverty,
illness,
starvation and tragedy and the loss of
tragedy.
So the Africa is often thought of as a
somewhat compact territory web.
Everything is connected to westernize.
Africa can look more like a country than
a consonance with many feedings or
realize the colossal size on this
continent.
Africa is as big as Europe,
the US,
India,
China and Argentina combined.
So now you can imagine the deluge
felicity,
that this huge territory must contain in
2010 if the economist referred to Africa
as the consonants without hope buses as
can often happen,
things rapidly changed in Africa since
the start of the 21st century.
Africa that has experienced a
significant boost,
especially in the poorest countries on
the continent with the exception of
South Africa.
The countries of sub Saharan Africa
achieved annual growth rates of 6.2%
while comparison that is twice the
growth rates of countries in Latin
America during the same time period in
2015 five of the 10 economies that grew
the most in the world.
Where in Africa,
these are the Ivory Coast,
Ethiopia,
Tanzania,
Rwanda,
and the Democratic Republic of Congo.
The growth rate of these countries
exceeded 7%
Democratic Republic of Congo is been
ranked among the top 10 countries for
reforms in the world.
For example,
in 2014 there are already nearly 7,000
enterprises that have been created.
Although the growth figures were a bit
smaller,
the situation remains similar in the
year 2016 all of this growth has led to
some really significant social
consequences.
So let's have a look at some of these.
Foreign life expectancy has increased
significantly over the last eight years
and child mortality figures and those
dying from starvation has been cut in
half.
To sum up extreme poverty,
you still affect 58% of the population
in 1990 900 now it is decreased to just
35% it is still true that more than 420
million people are still suffering from
extreme poverty in Africa,
which is tragic.
There's fortunately the future is
looking brighter than ever.
Right?
Another thing is also certain Africa is
going to have a major global role over
the coming decades and it's middleclass
or consumer class is the fastest growing
in the world.
The fact is Africa is no longer an
emerging.
It is here now.
Africa is being urbanized quickly which
allows for both the provision of public
services and also economies of scale.
In the near future.
We are going to find as many of the
world's biggest cities are on this call.
Smith
who knows Lagos,
Nairobi or accurate money to become the
new Shanghai in just a few short
decades.
For example,
the tallest skyscraper in Africa for
Haas Tower is currently being built in
Nairobi in Acra,
the capitalist of Ghana.
Six malls have been built in only six
years and while that might not seem like
a lot when you consider that there was
only one mall in the entire city before
those six new ones were built,
it seems like a little bit more foreign
investments has also grown strongly in
the last few years and it's half of
these investments operating areas they'd
have nothing to do with Africa's natural
resources.
This is important because many of the
countries in Africa are trying to
develop industries outside of raw
materials,
so they are depending less on these
natural resources.
These economies are known as the African
lions,
the African lions.
These African lions include Kenya,
Uganda,
Tanzania,
Mozambique and Zambia.
These other countries in Africa that are
developing the fastest.
Now we're going to discuss each of them
in detail in upcoming videos,
but today we're just going to focus on
three of them.
Russel Rwanda,
this is a small country with a
population of only 12 million people and
it doesn't have any coastline.
It is still a poor country but it is
registered and almost 9% annual growth
since the year 2001 and importantly this
country has no oil or other important
natural resources.
So the big question is,
well how did they do it?
This has actually been mostly down.
So you supporting business creation.
This is why Rwanda is the second easiest
country to do business in in sub Saharan
Africa according to the world's bank
doing business report.
So the question you might be asking is
this is a coincidence and we have visual
politic,
we really don't think so.
We are know what example looking at
under the 50th their 50th if we got word
organized,
if we other way with it and you put
everything that's needed and to the
world are connected.
The portable growth.
Now thanks to all of this,
nearly all children have primary
education and as a 98% of its people
already have access to health care.
As a consequence,
child mortality has been reduced by 60%
had to aids and malaria have also seen
significant reductions.
Further Rwanda,
President Paul Kagame,
he claims to be a disciple of Lee Kuan
Yew,
the legendary leader of Singapore.
Here we're going to be discussing in an
upcoming episode,
so don't forget to subscribe if you
haven't already,
so you will get notified of our bats.
And also Wayne miss out on any of our
other videos,
if you up yet
is a much larger country with a
population of nearly 100 million people
in Ethiopia.
Around 20 million people still have
nutritional problems and that is not the
only problem they have.
The government's also become more
authoritarian recently.
However,
things aren't changing fast.
And today,
Ethiopia's Capitol Adis Abba is always
pursuing significant construction
projects.
In fact,
about a year ago at us,
out of the bar opens the first modern
tram system in all of sub Saharan
Africa.
And to be honest,
they deserve it.
Ethiopia is a country which has grown
significantly in the last 10 years.
It's economy as multiplied by a factor
of five in this period and it's GDP has
grown by over 10% every year.
Yeah.
Now you might be asking,
well,
how did they do it?
Well,
they were simply trying to be more
attractive to investors and then
neighboring countries.
In doing so,
the country has established at two main
priorities.
One achieved stable macro economics and
to establish attractive taxation,
for example,
and in boards of technological equipment
such as machinery,
does not have any important charge that
other companies don't have to pay any
tax in their first five years,
which is pretty cool.
Nice.
We couldn't do this video without
mentioning Botswana,
the country which recently celebrated in
2016 at the 50th anniversary of its
independence.
What's one APP has been the greatest
economic success story in all of Africa?
In fact,
it is even one of the most successful
worldwide at the time of Botswana's
independence in the year 1966 it was one
of the poorest countries on the planet
on top of that,
and so the country has suffered severe
droughts and does suffered from the
second largest aids epidemic in the
world.
In spite of all these obstacles,
the country,
it has experienced developments,
so significance,
but it's GDP in purchasing power parity
is equivalent to two countries such as
Columbia,
Brazil,
or Thailand's.
This is obviously considering the
different levels of prices among these
countries.
Si.
Yeah,
the key to success and can be found in
the strength of its national
institutions that healthy public
finances and above all the country's
legal certainty.
In fact,
in the last CPI corruption perception
index,
Botswana was ranked in 31st position.
This is a better position than countries
like Spain,
Israel,
or Taiwan,
rule of law,
regulatory reform,
good governance,
all those things matter even more
because people should be able to start a
business and ship their goods without
having to pay a bribe or hire somebody
whose cousin.
But now,
how about some more surprising facts
about Africa?
You should know that this continent is
already home.
It's a 400 companies with a turnover of
more than a billion dollars a year.
So it really does seem that the ends of
Africa being a totally poor consonant is
coming to an end.
Furthermore in Africa we can also find
Nollywood is the second largest film
industry in terms of films produced in
the world.
Only 2,500
films less than Bollywood.
Further in Nigeria alone,
the film industry employees around a
million workers.
Now for just one final surprise,
Africa is the wells leader in online
banking and mobile phone payments.
Yes,
you probably weren't expecting that,
but it is absolutely true today many
farmers share information through SMS
and in the string silvery ones it is
popular to use safe motos,
which is like a Rwandan version of Uber,
except there's a small difference.
Instead of using cars,
they use motorcycles because there are
very few cars available.
So the thing about Africa is that it is
changing incredibly fast,
but the truth is that there are still
many challenges and difficulties that
the continent is going to face.
A hat,
for example,
consolidating the rule of law,
reducing poverty and improving their
infrastructure.
And of course they supports in ends once
and for all to all those terrible
dictatorships in countries like Angola,
Eritrea or Equatorial Guinea.
However,
everything does seem to indicate that
the future of Africa is brighter than it
has ever been.
So I hope you found that video
interesting,
and we would love to know what you
think.
Do you think that Africa is going to
become a major player in the coming
decades?
Do let us know in the comments below?
We'd love to read them and know what you
guys think.
Also,
do click the like button below this
video if you enjoy this.
And don't forget to subscribe for brand
new videos every Monday and every
Thursday,
and I'll see you in the next
[inaudible].