In the last few decades,
Israel has become one of the most
important technological powers in the
world and they're using it with a little
more than 8 million inhabitants.
This country has more than 4,000
tech companies,
Cisco,
paypal,
Google,
facebook,
apple and Intel are only some of the
many companies that develop new products
in Israel.
How did such a small island study island
country become one of the world's
innovation leaders?
Well,
we're going to answer that question.
In today's
video
is one of the most controversial
countries in the world ends in truth.
It's pretty difficult to talk about it
without having to revert a was religion
and various political conflicts.
However,
in this video we're going to try it and
we're going to try and shed some lights
on a very different side of this country
because they.
You are.
In the last few decades,
Israel has become one of the world's
greatest technological powers,
and this is something pretty surprising.
As we mentioned,
Israel has over 4,000
tech based companies and ace of the
largest 500 companies in the wells have
subsidiaries here oriented towards
research and innovation.
In fact,
Tel Aviv right off to silicon valley is
the most important technological center
in the world may seem impossible given
its size.
Israel is the country in the world with
the third most companies listed on the
Nasdaq.
This is only behind is the United States
and China.
Israel.
More companies are listed on this market
than Spain,
Italy,
France,
Germany,
and the Netherlands all put together.
So how about some specific examples?
Well,
here,
they all,
at the time of this video going out,
most of the next iphone is hardware is
being developed in Israel.
Further,
many of Google's innovations are made in
Israel.
Bands Intel,
the world's leader in microchips who's
most of its success to the innovations
of it's Israeli subsidiary,
which by the way has 11,000
workers and is one of the largest
companies in the entire country and
leaving Microsoft has been considered a
semi Israeli radiation.
Funny.
It is a hub of innovation with top notch
computer science,
academic institutes and revolutionary
technologies.
Hey Belt,
IBM,
Cisco,
Amazon,
facebook.
These are the companies that we use
everyday who's technology relies a lot
on r and d that is done in Israel.
This actually makes up more than 12
percent of its national GDP and half of
its exports.
Alright,
so now you might be wondering how did
they achieved such success?
Now,
cultural factors are usually considered
here,
but today we want to focus on three
political keys that were essential in
this process.
Use My,
the 19 eighties in Israel are remembered
as a terrible decade,
especially from the economic
perspective.
Back then the country was going through
a tough crisis.
Inflation between 1980 and 1985 exceeded
100 percent every year.
Deficits and public debts were an almost
unbearable financial burden on the
economy in general.
People felt handcuffed due to excessive
state intervention.
To a large extent,
Israel was very dependent on the help
coming from different parts of the wells
and even though the situation started to
stabilize by the end of the eighties,
right at that time,
there was a massive arrival of Jewish
people from different parts of the
Soviet Union in very little time.
800,000
new people arrived in the country that
now don't forget to put some perspective
on this number in relative terms that
would be like 70 million immigrants
arriving in the United States and now
the question for Israel was fairly
clear,
how could they generate jobs for so many
people in such a depressed economy?
Israel's only option was to reinvent
itself.
The government tried to encourage the
new canvas to create companies with
subsidies that would promote the work of
on trapping nurse,
but they seen realize that this method
didn't results in very prosperous
companies.
Immigrants who had no experience in
management and they lacked commercial
knowledge and they rarely got any
financing.
I mean,
after all,
he would want to invest their money in a
turbulent country like Israel.
And this is when the government realized
that the key was to pass on attracting
international venture capital that isn't
money used for new ideas and new
companies.
In order to do so,
they came up with the Osmo program,
thanks to yours map.
The government created 10 funds of
venture capital and allocated $100,
million dollars to be used under these
conditions.
Each Fund's capable of levying 12
million private investors would receive
8 million in public investments.
In exchange the government would keep 40
percent of the property,
but in case the investment was
successful,
the inventus could get these shares from
the government just by giving the
government's money back with the small
interest rate,
so in 10 years,
all the funds that came to Israel at
that time,
lazy about 15 million billion dollar
which will invested into local
companies.
So if things worked well,
the profits would be mainly for the
investors and if things didn't work so
well,
the government,
which Sharon the losses.
Now,
this might seem unfair,
but the truth is that the public
investment was relatively small lands.
Also the government expected to get the
losses back from the new taxes generated
by these new companies and all of the
jobs that they would create.
The idea was to fire things up and then
continue to reap the ongoing benefits.
Since then,
most public programs in Israel have
followed this same system and the truth
is the results.
They couldn't have been any better.
International money started to arrive.
There was funding for almost any idea,
and in the first eight years alone,
the number of funds rose from 20 to 513.
As a result,
Israel today has one of the best
ecosystems fall entrepreneurial capital
in the world and according to the last
one,
cd data and the investment available for
new companies exceeds $150 per person
per year.
To make a comparison of that figure.
In Spain,
it's only about three point $5,
which is a solid 40 times less.
The key in this process is that venture
capital doesn't just bring money with
this money also comes expertise and
contacts
immigration
that Israel is the country which has bet
on immigration.
The next one out of every three citizens
has been born abroad.
Hands nine out of 10 are either
immigrants or the children or the
grandchildren of immigrants.
This is an impressive migratory number
that explains the growth of its
population from 800,000
inhabitants in 1948,
more than 8 million today.
In this latest round of immigration,
nearly 50 French Jews arrived at Tel
Aviv's Ben Gurion airport,
so in little more than 60 years,
the population has multiplied by 10.
Israel is in fact say political and
historical exception because their
founding documents,
so to speak,
it's constitution expresses the need to
have an open integration policy.
Let's examine the law of return,
which is still enforced today and was
created in 1950.
Three Jew has the right to come to this
country as an older law of return.
Article One,
and I don't get this wrong,
this is not a minor issue.
Immigration has contributed to the
economic miracle as much as any other
facts that no,
no matter what populous politicians say,
whose aim is often just to get votes.
The wealthiest nations on usually the
ones with more immigrants among other
reasons,
it's usually because immigrants have
higher rates of entrepreneurship and
also because immigrants helped boost
international trade,
especially with their countries of
origin.
By the way,
if you are interested about the
immigration,
I'm going to link over to some videos
about that that we've put together at
the end of this video.
Education quality
of Israeli education is almost a
national hallmark in 1918,
30 years before the founding of the
state of Israel,
Jewish specialist founded the Hebrew
University of Jerusalem,
Israel today as one of the highest rates
of people with college degrees and the
country.
It has a lot of success with fusion
companies slash universities.
Finance for Israeli universities relies
mainly on projects financed by private
companies,
so there are reasons for universities to
collaborate with them further,
they have achieved the best rate of
business creation.
In the Oec d,
knowledge transfer is a central.
This is taking the university and
professional world closer together.
God,
everything went well,
so so far we've seen the main keys to
success,
but that all other influential factors,
for example,
there is the Jewish Chutzpah,
a tendency to question everything.
Something that is key in Jewish culture.
The military service is also a
surprising and important thing is it
helps social mobilization.
Forcing young people from different
social classes to interact,
hey,
well,
compulsory military service isn't
exactly great.
It does have some positive effects in
this case.
Now we could also discuss,
for example,
and that's y'all yahoo's reforms of
2003,
which were essential to Israel's
success,
but I think it's better to leave that
for a future video,
but the thing is,
thanks to all of what we've discussed
today since the 19 eighties,
Israel has doubled its population.
Multiply the number of jobs by four and
grown by an annual average rate of four
percent.
Today.
It's GDP per capita is higher than other
countries like Spain or Italy.
So what do you think will Israel
consolidate itself as the leading
technological power in the world?
Could its model will be repeated for
other countries?
Let us know what you think in the
comments below your and hey,
if you did like this video,
be sure to hit that like button below
and don't forget to subscribe for brand
new videos every Monday and every
Thursday band.
As always,
thank you for watching and I'll see you
in the next week and if you want to
learn more about politics and hear even
more of my lovely voice,
you can join us at reconsider media.
We have a podcast@reconsidermedia.com
slash podcast.