I'm going to start today off with a
question because I want to know when is
the last time you bought a music cd like
this one.
In fact,
this.
This is naturally a music cd.
This is a CD that my Internet provider
sent me to set up my router seriously
for the millennials watching this video,
compact disc was a thing that had songs
on it.
Yup.
Before the Internet era,
if you wanted to listen to music,
you actually have to buy it.
There was this thing,
good,
a record shop and there was a cd or a
cassette tape and these things can cost
up to $30.
I know,
I know.
It all seems pretty bizarre these days
going to a physical store to purchase
music in less than 20 years,
record sales have almost disappeared in
the year.
2,000.
More than 900 million cds were sold in
America alone.
Eighteen years later,
this number has dropped to 90 million.
That's less than a 10th of what it used
to be.
The reason of course is internet
downloads.
Platforms like napster,
email and torrance have completely
changed the industry,
and of course you might think in this
situation,
record labels must be going totally
bankrupt,
right?
Well,
I mean actually the opposite is true.
University
music group turned over an average of 17
point $5,000,000 per day in 2017 as the
company's annual sales hit record highs
topping $6,000,000,000,
and this is just one example.
Other music companies like Sony,
music or Warner are in a similar
situation,
absolutely record profits sands in case
you were wondering,
the answer is no.
Streaming platforms like Pandora,
Deezer,
and of course spotify are not enough to
explain this phenomenon.
For example,
Taylor swift is one of the world's most
famous artists.
Injury now hardly even makes $400,000 a
year from spotify listens.
Now,
this might seem like a lot,
but believe me,
it is absolute pennies compared with the
mega money that Michael Jackson made
from the sales of thriller.
So why are record labels making so much
money?
How could they even survive all the
illegal internet downloads and file
sharing platforms like napster and
email?
Well,
today we're going to answer these
questions,
but before we do,
let's take a look back at the history,
creative destruction in the.
In 1935,
the Union of American musicians
published this statement are multiplied
and duplicated by the thousands and then
sold to and used in places where
otherwise musicians would be employed.
According to this union,
more than 8,000 professional musicians
that lost their jobs because of the
so-called jukeboxes.
A box for those who don't know is a big
record plant,
sits in a bar or restaurant so you can
insert a coin and choose a song that you
want
by the end.
Nineteen 35,
more than 135,000 machines like this one
was sold throughout the United States,
but at the same time that those 8,000
traditional musicians were taken out of
business,
Benny Goodman was signing a million
dollar contract with a label called RCA
victor.
The business model of the music industry
had already changed forever.
Prior to this,
musicians lived off the money they made
from concerts.
In fact,
the first music records swept used as
advertising for the life performances,
but now 90 percent of their income was
coming from record sales.
This is a process which we call creative
destruction,
but this was more of an economic shift.
The way we listened to music changed
forever as well.
All of a sudden,
some local music genre started being
enjoyed nationwide,
for example,
of jazz music was a typical genre in New
Orleans,
but it ended up expanding all over
America and not only that,
this also changed the way that we
understood music.
Think about it before we could record
music,
musicians could only do live
performances.
That maximum audience was just a few
hundred people.
Suddenly radios and records allowed them
to reach millions and this way it made a
whole lot more money is how a new genre
was created,
a musical style made for radio,
and that's of course rock and roll.
This is a style of music that originated
in America and ended up expanding to all
parts of the West from Los Angeles to
Berlin rock stars.
We're no longer just simple artists.
They were engines inside of a complex
machine,
the record label,
paying for marketing campaigns,
organized massive concerts,
and even negotiated advertising deals
for them and meanwhile the Rockstar gave
the whole industry a young,
fresh face
is why wild about is like Elvis and the
Beatles became millionaires.
The big companies.
It just got bigger and bigger.
Since then,
music was not just listened to all
across the developed world.
A record like Michael Jackson's thriller
could sell more than 66 million copies
in a brand new market that stretched
from La to Tokyo.
By the in 1999 in the music industry had
reached its ceiling.
Well,
there's $1,200 million records had been
sold.
The business was bigger than the GDP of
a country like the Dominican Republic.
And what happens when an industry
generates so much money?
Well,
the big guys start eating the smaller
for a better understanding.
In that moment,
78 percent of the industry was
concentrated in just five big
multinationals.
And then when the music industry was the
ultimate moneymaking machine,
something rather surprising habits.
Remember that thing I said about
creative destruction?
Well,
if there's one good example of positive
distraction,
it's napster.
Napster was the first software that
allowed users to download songs in MP
three format in a fast free and of
course illegal way from one day to the
next.
Those records that could cost $30 could
be found for free online,
and as you can see on this chart,
this was the beginning of the end.
Even though napster lost a case in the
courts,
it was already too late.
The music business had already changed
forever.
At the end of the day,
why would you buy something if you can
get it for
great,
but just hold on a minute here because I
haven't looked at the chart again,
if you pay attention,
you'll see that despite a dramatic
decline in record sales,
the profit for company is like universal
music group hasn't actually changed that
much.
Why?
Well,
let's explain that right now.
Size matters drillers.
8,000 musicians that lost their jobs in
1935.
Well,
in the year 2000,
something similar happened.
Universal music,
fod,
4,000 people practically overnight.
This was 34 percent of their staff at
this point,
record sales were almost 90 percent of
their income and those sales,
they were falling by 20 percent.
Yeah,
often.
and this moment is when the executives
of the big record labels started singing
the same old tune that we've been
talking about over and over again in
this video,
and of course creative destruction if
they wanted to survive that to make a
180 degree shift to the company,
they had to stop being a record label
and start becoming a music label.
Oh,
okay.
But you know,
what does that actually mean?
Well,
let's have a look at the example of
universal music reading.
The first step for creative destruction
is of course destruction.
In the past decade of the 21st century,
universal got rid of everything that was
not making it any money.
What was that?
Well,
that would be the record.
Manufacturing factories,
they sold as many of those things as
possible.
And what's next up in creative
destruction?
Well,
of course,
that's creativity with all the money
they got from selling the factories.
Universal bought all the music labels
they possibly could.
The main goal was to expand them,
use a catalog as much as possible,
which explains news like this,
universal music group purchases,
Emi music label group will acquire
catalogs of the Beatles.
Pink Floyd,
radiohead and more so what happens after
some creative destruction like this?
Well tastes to musical genres.
They changed.
For example,
we have k pop with songs like gangnam
style
genre in South Korea.
That's ended up expanding to the rest of
the wells.
Yep.
Of Us in the 19 thirties,
the music industry was limited to the
United States then in the eighties and
it expanded throughout the West.
Now in the two thousands,
music is a 100 percent global industry
and companies like universal have bought
labels in every market.
You could have
university.
Oh,
music science.
Ten cent deal for China expands music
group to relaunch emi records in.
Yeah.
Bursal buys majority stake in Kenyan
label ai records and now you might
wonder,
okay,
but no matter how many labels you have
by,
if people don't buy music anymore,
you're income's going to fold
inevitably.
Alright.
Well,
yeah.
Yeah.
You are right.
In fact,
the music industry today is nothing but
a shadow of what it used to be so well.
What's the difference?
Well,
now,
despite the cake being smaller,
oh,
way less people using,
as you can see on the chart,
72 percent of the industry is covered by
three big multinationals,
universal,
Sony,
music and Warner,
and yes now is when we start talking
about spotify,
as we said before,
spotify gives various or money to the
artists.
1 million listens only means about
$7,000,
but when you have the rights of 25
percent of the music produced in the
world,
even if you make one point zero,
$0 per listen,
you're still become a million app today.
Record sales,
they've gone from being 90 percent of
the industry's profits to just $25
and streaming music represents six out
of every $10 entering the music
industry.
Of course,
this is great news for multinational
corporations which make more and more
money that as you can imagine,
this is not so good news for the
musicians.
It's harder and harder to make money
with music and this is why you need to
be extremely popular to make any money
out of this.
On the other hand,
those three big labels aren't willing to
risk what they have by experimenting
with new formulas,
but always a minute because this is not
so bad.
If you've been following the news and
the music industry lately,
you'll probably see that there's a bit
more room for some creative destruction.
Now let's artists bypass labels and
upload their own music.
Yes,
do you is if you have a bands,
you can now upload your songs directly
to spotify and get your royalties
without a middleman way,
and by the way,
if you do make good music and you want
some free advertising,
do send us.
He had demos to info@visualpolitic.net
and we can play it in the background of
some of our videos.
Of course.
Do you remember to add a link to your
youtube channel?
Meanwhile,
the big question now is will we
witnessed the advent of a new creative
destruction process in the music
industry?
While please leave your answer in the
comments section below.
Also do visit reconsider media.com,
the podcast that provided the vocals in
this episode,
but we're not mine.
And don't forget we publish a brand new
videos every week.
So subscribe to this channel and hit the
bell button so you won't miss any posts.
And if you liked this video,
give us a thumbs up and as always we'll
see you next time.
And if you want to learn more about
politics and hear more of my lovely
voice,
don't forget to check out the
reconsidered
podcast@reconsidermedia.com.
And we consider it as a podcast that
challenges you to reconsider your
reviews by providing context.
But we don't do the thinking.