We might not notice it,
but the weld is changing really,
really fun.
Austin
biotechnology,
robotics,
nanotechnology,
every day somewhere on some discovery is
being made.
Discoveries that will make our lines
longer,
more comfortable and generally just much
better.
We could always say,
dear viewer,
that we are on board or high speed train
bounds for the future.
John,
that already companies in existence
today,
which look like they could have come
straight out of a science fiction movie.
Would you like some examples?
Well then are you familiar with Oregon?
Novo?
It's a truly incredible company.
It's listed on the Nasdaq and did
business is no less than the bioprinting
of tissues to implant into the human
body and thus eliminating the need for
organ transplants.
Can you imagine printing and liver.
It's truly remarkable.
Stop.
What about the company?
Modern meadow.
This startup's aim is to produce leather
and meet without having to kill any
animals.
They want to reduce that own stakes in
the lab and then take them to the bowl.
Oh,
okay.
The question is though,
would you eat it?
So how about another example of a heard
of Illumina?
It's the largest company dedicated to
DNA sequencing in the wealth among other
targets.
They are trying to detect cancer before
any of the symptoms appear.
It's almost unbelievable,
isn't it?
Yes.
Well,
these are only three of hundreds of
companies which are literally building
the future today.
Well,
you know what?
Organ Printing,
DNA sequencing,
that's not really the best part.
The best part is the end of poverty is
getting closer every day and the reality
is that it's already right around the
corner.
And listen,
we're not just talking about extreme
poverty here on the contrary,
current realities like hunger or not
being able to eat meat or not having
access to healthcare or even not being
able to go on holiday aren't going to be
rare and very infrequent in the near
future.
And it's blowing near future.
We mean this is going to be a reality
and probably just a few years.
Alright.
Alright,
so now some of you must be thinking,
Simon's finally lost it.
It's all down here for visual politic
from here.
Well,
no,
actually I haven't lost my mind.
In fact,
hit with all of you as witnesses.
I am willing to bet you that's in the
next year,
we will experience the best period of
prosperity in the history of mankind and
I'm certainly not the only one who
shares this opinion.
Listen to what Warren Buffett,
the investment genius has to say about
it,
or how about Barack Obama as well.
If you had a choice of when to be born
and you didn't know ahead of time who
you were going to be,
what nationality,
whether you were male or female,
what religion,
but you said when in human history be
the best time to
be born.
The time would be now while I'm here to
tell you even more,
this wave of prosperity will bring
opportunities we've never even thought
of before.
Alright.
But for the skeptics era,
the numbers.
Yes.
Tonight at the,
by the end of 2016,
three point 2 billion people are already
going to be in the middle class and two
each year,
more than 140 million people will make
it into this select club.
It is as if every year a group of people
the size of the population of Mexico.
Oh,
leaving poverty behind.
Notice that this process is accelerating
and it's expected that by 20,
20,
that's just three years from the time of
this video coming out,
most of the world's population will
belong to the middle class.
This growth in the middle class will
mean that the poor will finally be in
Rsa.
Before I continue,
I am sure you might be wondering how
exactly do you define middle class?
Since income levels vary from country to
country.
When we talk about middle class,
what we're talking about is people who
can afford to have a very diverse people
who can face and cover unexpected
expenses as well as education and people
who can buy an automobile.
These people,
they might not be rich,
but they definitely are poor anymore and
this is a brand new thing in the history
of men
pies.
Now they have an idea of how things are
changing today.
Let's have a look at the historical
perspective.
When the Polian was fighting everyone in
Europe,
only 2 million people could be
considered middle class.
That is less than half of the population
of Singapore today.
A pretty tough situation for the vast
majority of people who were living at
that time,
well since then,
150 years have passed,
but it wasn't until the 19 seventies,
but the number of people in the middle
class passed the 1 billion people today.
The number is about 3 billion by 20,
21 is expected to reach for Binyam ends.
As I mentioned,
the process.
It's getting faster and faster every
single day.
And this nice middle class,
they are going to make an impressive
entrance.
Don't believe me.
And as we have these billions of people
in lodging into a global middle class,
they need to be fed.
They need to be housed,
they need power,
they need transport,
uh,
they want to,
they want to travel and see the world.
So there are tremendous opportunities
for an expansion of economic activity to
meet their needs.
Yes,
versiti you're looking at right now is
Hanoi,
which is the capital of Vietnam.
If the country in the world where
capitalism is actually most liked,
that's according to a recent study from
the Pew Research Center.
Seems like we're in the west.
Might have some catching up to do.
In fact,
the majority of this new middle class,
they're coming from Asia,
almost nine out of every 10 new people.
They make it to the middle class and
live in Asia.
The continent of the economic boons and
the growing epicenter of power on earth.
You just have to take a look at
countries like the Philippines or
Thailand in just a few years.
These countries,
middle classes will be as big as those
in the UK,
France and Italy.
Yes,
they will remain poorer countries,
but the growth of the middle class,
it's still very impressive.
Bots do you want to know how things are
really changing?
Well,
this is Jakarta.
Well that means for the companies,
but that's something we're going to get
into later,
but out of all these countries,
one is making a particularly big
difference and that's China who's middle
class has absolutely exploded according
to estimations by Mckinsey analysts.
If in five years this isn't,
the homes of people were to create,
say the Chinese Republic of middle class
citizens,
this country would be the third most
populated country in the world.
No bad a sorry if he wants to know what
these changes really mean.
Take a look at Truong quizzing the most
populated city in China
because of the growth of the middle
class.
These people now have money available to
buy all kinds of products,
clothing and like tronics cars and of
course travel,
and now you can probably understand why
the countries in Asia,
especially China,
are so important for multinational
companies.
Canada's largest online ride hailing
platform dd two things that it's
received.
One billion US dollars from us tech
giants,
apple pay
close attention to this data because
it's probably interesting if you're
starting a business,
it is estimated that the spending growth
of the Chinese in the next four years
alone will exceed what the British or
German spent.
Sorry,
refute our visual politic.
Friends are the company you might want
to think about investigating the Asian
market because many opportunities will
appear in the next few years.
Consequences
of this,
I'm just an opportunity to make money
and do more business.
Probably the most important consequences
of this middle class expansion is that
we will live in a happier world.
Let me explain.
You've probably heard the phrase money
doesn't make you happy.
Well,
actually,
according to recent research,
this is not entirely true.
In 2010 Angus Deaton and Daniel Conaman
booster winners of the Nobel Prize in
economics presented a paper which proved
that up to the figure of $75,000 a year,
happiness and income with very closely
related,
meaning more income equals more
happiness up to $5,000 a year.
I mean,
this makes sense.
We have more money.
You don't have to worry about making it
to the end of the month,
paying your bills and not having enough
to eat as well as not being able to take
your family to the doctor and etc. Etc.
So according to thEse two academics,
the expansion of the middle class is
leading to a happier world.
But wait just a minute because there is
more.
More middle claSs means more educated
people.
This means more researchers and more
entrepreneurs,
more ideas,
more innovation.
Man's therefore more progress.
Well today in China that are more
college students have any in the United
States.
Remember the companies that we saw at
the beginning of this video,
well,
soon enough,
there are going to be plenty more of
those.
Now.
You may be wondering,
is this all really is wonderful as we're
describing a visual politic?
How come people such as Donald Trump and
le pen are so popular then?
Well,
this middle class boom is not happening
in all parts of the world.
Therefore it's really important.
We understand that if western economies
aren't working perfectly,
are having problems,
they should take responsibility for it
and stop blaming it on other countries.
There are plenty of opportunities in the
global economy and now is the time to
adapt and sees them,
but now I can probably guess what your
thinking is.
All of this group really sustainable
ways.
All of this progress and development
destroy the environment so cause other
such problems.
Well,
that's not exactly clear.
It's true that in theory,
more middle class means more spending
and therefore more consumerism and more
pressure on natural resources,
etc. But that awesome things to consider
first more middle class also means more
people in big cities and the consumerism
here is usually more sustainable.
Transport is the most evidence.
Example,
my public transport is frequent in large
cities.
It is rare in small places.
More middle class also means faster
demographic transition,
so more women's study and work and say
the population tends to shrink as well
and above all more middle class means,
as we said before,
more ideas and more innovation and among
these things are often ideas which allow
more sustainable consumerism.
So however we want to approach this
situation and although that is certainly
a lot of room for advancement and
improvement,
we think that this really is a time in
history when we should all be feeling
rather positive,
but that's our opinion at visual
politic.
Ams.
Now we would like to know what you
think.
Do you Believe we are moving towards a
better world?
Do you think that asia can be a land of
opportunity for businesses?
well,
do let us know in the comments below.
We would love to hear your thoughts.
And if you enjoyed this video,
please do hit that thumbs up button
below.
And don't forget to subscribe for brand
new videos every monday and every
thursday.
And as always,
I'll see you in the next video.