[inaudible].
They were visual politic when not
exactly massive fans of Donald Trump.
As viewers of our Spanish language
channel,
we'll note particularly however,
there is one area where we must admit
the Donald Trump is absolutely correct.
If you want to be a citizen of Mexico,
you and let's assume you're a perfect
person,
okay?
You want to be,
you could not become a citizen of
Mexico.
It's the hardest place just about in the
country,
in the world to become a citizen.
In this case,
Donald Trump is telling the truth.
Mexico has an immigration policy that is
way more restrictive than the American
one.
To understand this Pesa in 2015 the
Mexican government is kicked out of its
country.
100,000
foreign is one.
It's the neighbor to the north kicks out
of 300 thousands okay,
so actually on the face of things,
it looks as if the u s deports more
people than Mexico.
Rice,
I mean 300,000
versus 100,000
but you really must think about this in
relative terms,
but one Mexico's population is three
times smaller than the United States and
it's also a far less attractive
destination for immigrant.
That's it.
We can say that the Mexican authorities
deport nearly everyone who crosses into
the country through their southern
border with the leaves and Guatemala is
that is the deport all of the people who
decide to stay in Mexico rather than
heading further north to the United
States.
In fact,
while America has an immigrant
population of 14% which is by the way
average in terms of developed countries,
Mexico has an immigrant population on
just one.
In fact,
well the Mexican presidents on Recap
Pinion,
yet always saying this to Donald Trump,
we'll make you or Nesta,
Mexicans living in us are honest,
hardworking people.
They are good people.
They respect family,
they respect their communities and they
deserve respect,
will make you medicine and respectful.
They told us 48% of the Mexican
population holds a negative or very
negative opinion about immigrants from
Central America.
In fact,
in 2016 a Mexican newspaper called La,
Yana published the following,
yes
to the border wall,
but in the south of Mexico,
the problems between the u s and Mexico
can be solved by building a border like
the one proposed by Donald Trump,
but in the south so we can keep illegal
aliens out of Central American.
It's so rather interesting.
Right,
and that's why in today's visual politic
video,
were you going to be looking in to
Mexico's immigration policy?
Why?
Why does
Mexico Deport Central American
immigrants?
The first thing that we need to
understand before talking about
immigration to is their geographical
location.
What's imagine that you live in
Nicaragua and you want to move to the
United States.
Let's also say that you have no money to
purchase a plane tickets.
In this case,
the only way for you to get from
Nicaragua to the United States is by
land,
and that means going through Mexico.
Currently,
the biggest flow of immigrants in the
world is from Central America to the
United States.
And and 15 alone,
over 22 million people made this trip.
It's an extremely dangerous journey on
roads that are in terrible condition as
immigrants also passed through some
incredibly violent areas.
And don't forget Mexican states like
chip pass ski area.
When a lower the hotspots for drug
trafficking,
they suffer all kinds of abuses,
extortion,
kidnapping,
human trafficking,
drug trafficking,
human and sexual slavery.
Right.
Do you understand this best when some of
the immigrants arrive in the south of
Mexico and they have to continue that
journey to the US on the reef of a
train?
This train has become known as the beast
or the death train,
and it's not hard to figure out why.
With Amenia key,
this is why some immigrants' decide to
stay in Mexico.
This situation was the perfect excuse
for the Mexican government to pass it,
the lady to properly RCR or population
law.
This was passed in the mid 1970s the law
was Paulie put in place in order to
restrict the flow of immigrants to the
country in order to avoid human
trafficking and abuse.
So this sounds like a well intentioned
law.
So what exactly was the problem?
Well,
what's it first appeared to be something
good for foreigners.
It quickly became hell for them.
And now you might be wondering what
exactly made this law quite so bad for
immigrants.
Well,
quite simply,
it gave the government the power to
expel foreigners or reasons as ludicrous
as this one,
the secretary can the knife 40 nurse and
trans to the country or change the
quality or characteristics of the
migration in order to keep at
demographic balance and otherwise Mexico
only once immigrants from wealthy
countries.
And if possible,
it's better if this skin is white as
well.
What's the result of all this?
Well,
it turns out that seven out of every 10
immigrants to Mexico off from the United
States.
And what about the rest of them?
What about that other three wells,
they're mostly from Spain.
In fact in Mexican has twice as many
Spaniards living in it does it?
Does Guatemala.
Now this wouldn't exactly be a big
surprise except for the fact of the
Guatemala shares a border with Mexico
and Spain is thousands of miles away
across in,
Yup.
This is not all Mexico has an equal
number of German immigrants as it does
Peruvians.
So if you come from Europe or the United
States,
you're going to have no problem getting
a visa for Mexico.
Lee,
your helping to improve that demographic
balance.
But if you happen to be from Peru,
wants to live in the country of Robert
Rodriguez,
well good luck to the Mexican
governments.
You on nothing more than a demographic
rats.
Hold on for a second because there's
more according to the previous and he
mentions law.
Being an immigrant in Mexico is a
felony.
This means that at any moments of
federal agents can request your
documentation and if you don't have the
documentation,
you can be forced to leave.
Country ends pay a fine of two months
average salary in Mexico.
Okay.
Okay,
so now you might be thinking,
well,
every country gets to determine its own
immigration policy,
right?
Well that's absolutely right and until
2010 no other governments complains
about Mexico's immigration policy in
2010 something happens that embarrassed
the entire night.
Patient,
governor Jan Brewer on Friday signed the
states immigration bill in low.
It is considered to be among the
toughest legislation in the nation.
As ironic as it sounds,
that rezone a law which was meant to
stop immigrants from Mexico,
was a copy of that same Mexican law
birds.
Actually in practice it was slightly
less extreme.
For example,
while Arizona's government considers it
to be a felony to be an illegal
immigrants,
it doesn't really matter because Arizona
State's law doesn't apply to the federal
government,
so the reality was the federal police
could do nothing.
Nevertheless,
vis law caught the attention of the
world's media and the president of bank
then Philippe cals around didn't remain
silence doll that gets the same brain
[inaudible] collection,
criminalizes immigration,
social phenomenon and economic
phenomena.
Every load that penalizes it opening up
the door for intolerance and
discrimination as well.
There you have it since then,
day diction.
Reason next to the word hypocrisy have
started including a picture of Philippe
Calderon wrong and quickly following
this statement came the world's
reaction.
The Mexican government were forced to
change to that population law that we
mentioned.
This meant that immigration to Mexico
wasn't no longer eight felony was do
hold on that for just one second because
that is not the end of us.
Boring.
Yes,
it is true.
The Mexico changed its immigration law,
but it didn't diesel entirely.
Remember when I said to the Mexican
federal police can request the
documentation of any person at any time.
Well,
that is still happening today.
Today in the United States,
the authorities need to suspect you of
committing a crime.
If they want to ask you the
documentation,
this means is over and easy for them to
stop you on the street and to rescue for
being then legal immigrants.
Meanwhile,
down in Mexico,
this is happening every single day adds
of this.
The limited control over the country
have over their own police force and you
get stories like this.
Escape
deportation migrants often pay bribes to
inm agents of between and $300 and of
course the mass deportations of Central
American immigrants remain exactly the
same.
But do you really think that Mexico is
the only place where this is happening?
Because the answer is absolutely not.
Now.
Normally when we talk about immigration,
we're normally talking about people who
are living in a poor country,
moving to a rich country.
[inaudible]
there's,
there's in 2015 over 80 million people
moved from one poor country to a another
poor country.
They were just moving to a poor country
that is slightly better off than that
original country.
As an example,
every year thousands of people move from
Bangladesh to India and the authorities
don't exactly welcomed them with open
arms.
Just consider what Narendra Modi sets
the Indian presidents when he was
running for office.
You can write it down after Mexico
[inaudible] these Bangladeshis better be
prepared with their backs packed.
This is really a big difference when
compared to the immigrant friendly
policies of countries like Canada or New
Zealand,
which by the way are some of the
wealthiest countries in the world.
This is just our opinion here at the
visual politic and we would love to know
what you think.
Do you think that Europe and the United
States should follow examples set by
countries like Mexico and India,
or follow the examples of countries like
Canada and New Zealand?
Let us know in the comments section
below this video.
We'd love to know what you think.
Also,
if you enjoyed this video,
please do click that like button below
and don't forget to subscribe for brand
new videos every Monday and every
Thursday,
and I'll see you it
[inaudible].