Imagine this situation,
you live in London and you want to buy a
house in San Francisco,
the house costs one point $3 million.
It's what comes in first,
your payments or the handover of the
keys.
If you happen to pay first,
you might fall into a scam.
Maybe the house doesn't really exist or
it's not owned by the person that you
contact us.
Don't forget that you can live a really
long way away from that.
You never met the person who's selling
the house and believe me,
you're not the first person or the last
is going to lose money through an online
scam like this.
Ridiculous as it sounds,
this is actually one of the most
complicated problems that exists in
economics and that's trust.
But I know what you're thinking.
You click this video expecting something
about blockchain,
about cryptocurrencies and bitcoin.
What does all of this I have to deal
with that.
Well,
I'll tell you,
yeah.
Nowadays we've all heard of bitcoin and
I'm sure many of you know of some other
cryptocurrencies as well,
like a theory.
I'm light coin or riddle if you've dug
deeper into this matter and you might
also have heard about another term and
that's blockchain for many.
This crypto currency world is the
ultimate revolution that's going to end
governments and banks.
For others it's just another financial
bubble.
This will make it easier for criminals
and terrorists to hide their money from
the police.
Unfortunately the reality is way more
boring than this bitcoin exchange
reaches deal with Barclays for UK
transactions but all is on just a
second.
If you felt cryptic currencies,
but just a strategy to avoid taxes.
I've got some news for you.
This municipality
of [inaudible] is going to let residents
pay their taxes in bitcoin.
It's mayor has announced,
sorry,
let's start from the beginning.
Shall We?
Blockchain?
Blockchain is a technology.
It just like virtual reality or peer to
peer file sharing is a technology.
As with every technology you can use it
for any different things and one of them
is cryptocurrencies and one of these
cryptocurrencies,
bitcoin and as with many technologies
you can use it for many different
things.
One of them is cryptocurrencies and one
of those cryptocurrencies is bitcoin.
But it's not the only one.
Many people think that these new coins
will substitute legal money that is
dollars,
euros,
or any other currency,
but it doesn't have to be that way.
In fact,
cryptocurrencies can do many other
things and today we're going to have a
look at some of them.
But now the real question is what is
blockchain all about?
What is it used for?
And most importantly why,
uh,
banks starting to use it.
Do they were going to answer all of
these questions,
but before we do,
let's take a look back at their history.
What is blockchain used for?
Look,
bitcoin was born in 2009 nonetheless,
the technology that it's based on,
the blockchain was all the way back in
1991 so let's see how it works without
even mentioning the word.
Yep.
Ahead.
Body.
We want to do this well because it's
important to understand the blockchain
can be used for many other things.
And since this is a complicated matter,
I asked one sec,
one of the hosts of the Spanish visual
politic channel to show it to you by
drawing,
which is something he can do and I sadly
cannot.
All right,
so let me take you back to the example
of the house in San Francisco.
The one that costs one point $3 million.
In order to buy it,
you have to sign a contract with the
owner,
but how do you know that he or she is
going to meet that agreement?
How do you know that the house exists if
you've never seen it?
In reality,
usually we have a trusted third party,
like a notary verifiers.
This notary will verify the house
exists.
Since that you're talking to the real
owner who is willing to hand over the
keys when he gets the money.
This is the way that any traditional
contract works and it has many problems.
First having many parties means that
there's lots of waiting time and lots of
fees,
but there's an even worse problem here
if someone hacked the computer of one of
those third parties so you could modify
the terms of the contract.
This means traditional contracts on not
as safe as they seem,
and this is where the lock chain enters
the picture.
In this case,
instead of using a traditional contract,
we could use a so called smart contract.
Is that a little bit of software that
executes automatically when something
happens?
In this case,
you could leave your one point $3
million in a special account.
So there's the moment when you open up a
new door of your house as sensible,
notice your presence and boom,
the smart contract will take your 1.3
million bucks from that special accounts
and send it to the seller in case the
key doesn't work because you've been
tricked,
then the contract would not execute.
All right,
so all of this sounds pretty great,
but who is going to validate any of
this?
Well,
in this case,
we don't actually need that parties or
middlemen.
There's may need for notaries
whatsoever.
In this case,
we have a network.
This is a crappy is a company that
offers a real estate sales
internationally through blockchain.
Well,
in this case,
all the sellers and buyers inside of
this platform would be nodes of the
network.
And so now you might be wondering,
so I just want to address it really
quickly.
No company has paid us to do this video.
We just used the example of this
company.
So we can give a real life example.
It makes it more tangible and hopefully
more enjoyable.
So while the great innovation of
blockchain is that it's users will
always have a copy of the contract.
So all of them can be a point of
verification.
And in case one copy does not match the
copy of another node system,
we'll consider this to be fought.
But yeah,
but not only that,
this contract will always be stored and
what we call a block.
Okay.
And this book at the same time will be
stored in a chain of blocks.
This is why we call this system
blockchain.
So if a hacker wants to modify our
contract,
he would have to get into all of the
computers from the members of our
blockchain all at the same time.
As you can imagine,
this is way harder than getting into one
computer and no matter how secure that
computer is,
and now you might be wondering,
so anytime I start using some blockchain
service,
will they have all the registers and
transactions that have been done in
Sinus?
And the answer is,
well,
yeah.
In fact,
if you want to have a bitcoin,
you should download all of the
blockchain,
which is now over 160 gigabytes
and now I can get many of you saying,
well come on sign.
And that's not true.
I've got a bit coin while there's a nice
enough to download 160 gigabytes or
stuff.
Well actually of course you do.
In your case for you or what you have is
actually a light coin.
This means that another person
downloaded those 160 gigabytes and now
that person is letting you use bitcoin
through his or has server.
This said,
blockchain is starting to be used for
all kinds of things as you have already
seen.
Some companies offer real estate deals
with smart contracts,
but there are many,
many other applications.
You can even have a website hosting with
blockchain so then he can hear it.
US inside of a network would have the
data,
other companies offer medical record
storage,
et Cetera,
but okay,
we've already told you what blockchain
is all about.
Now there is a second part and that is,
well what do banks have to do with all
of this and that's something we're going
to look at,
right?
Survival
of the fittest.
If there is one thing that generates all
kinds of gossip and mixed signals and
conspiracy theories,
it's crypto currencies.
You just need to google the name of any
famous company followed by the word
crypto currency and you've got some
blogs that claims that this farm wants
to get its own crypto coin or the
opposite or both things.
At the same time,
there's information.
Noise is so pervasive that it is almost
impossible to separate the wheat from
the chaff and this is also a heads up
for you guys.
He might want to start investing in this
industry.
Watch out.
I'm not telling you,
not to you,
but be careful because there is a lot of
hype and this is why to do this video.
We talked straight to the sources so
that we could corroborate that this is
true.
Dbva an intro.
We'll make the world's first blockchain
based corporate loan.
In this case,
Indra is a Spanish engineering company
and bb Va is a large Spanish bank.
The idea is pretty similar to what we
said about the house in San Francisco
and this case bb va signs a contract
with Indra and to all the members inside
of the blockchain will have a copy of
the same.
So what's the advantage of all this?
Well,
it would prevent internal corruption.
Some people might want to exaggerate the
cost of some building in order to get
her money into their pockets,
but if they have a smart and everybody
has a copy of this,
then they can track every transaction.
This means that both the company and the
bank are protecting themselves from the
iron workers,
but we are only talking about loans
here.
As we said before,
blockchain can be used for many other
things and apparently Spanish banks,
they want to pioneer this.
Here's another example.
Sorry
Tom Dare to launch the first blockchain
base.
International money transfer service.
In this case we are talking again about
a reducing verification times.
You see anytime you make an
international money transfer,
you have lots of intermediary banks.
For instance,
if you want to send $1,000 to a friend
in Germany or somebody has to verify
that you have $1,000 less and your
friend has $1,000 more after this,
the problems from the currency exchange
and you have lots of intermediaries that
need to be in contact and verify every
step of the process.
Companies like a ripple used blockchain
to do this.
In a matter of seconds,
and this is why it Santown death will
now stop making international transfers
from one day to the other.
In fact,
both Santander and bb va has been
investing in cryptocurrency companies
for years.
Main European banks have all been part
of blockchain platforms for years from
we trade to the Spanish Alaska area.
But how big of future do these projects
have?
You simply don't know,
but clearly there's an interest from
traditional banks to not miss out on
these kinds of new technologies.
And now I know what you might be
thinking.
So far we've just talked about faster
transactions and safe a contract.
It's nothing super exciting,
right?
So where is that revolution that some
people are talking about?
Well,
believe me,
there is certainly a potential
revolution here,
but we're going to talk about that in
the coming week.
Send me
him.
Don't forget to subscribe to visual
politic and click on the bell icon so
you don't miss any of our posts.
And that was your,
so far we talked about banks using
blockchain technology.
What about cryptocurrencies?
Yeah,
Barclay's,
yes,
indeed.
Barclays is offering services in
Bitcoin,
but will they use it as a normal thing?
Well,
we see all kinds of new services,
thanks to cryptocurrencies.
Well,
please leave your answer in the comments
section below and also don't forget to
visit our friends at the reconsider
media podcast.
They provided the vocals in this episode
that were not mine.
It if you like this video,
please do give us a thumbs up.
As always,
I'll see you next time and if you want
to learn more about politics and hear
even more of my lovely voice,
you can join us at reconsider media.
We have a podcast@reconsideredmedia.com
slash podcast.