And the reason is the exposure of the
Panama papers in the paradise papers,
if once again,
but tax havens on the public opinion
radar in the last two years,
criticism of these places has multiplied
all throughout the wells,
politicians,
businessmen,
soccer players,
singers,
or simply investors and savers.
Many people transfer part of their
fortunes to these places supposedly to
pay fewer taxes.
That's why many critics states that if
it weren't for these millionaire
paradise,
the 2008 financial crisis would have
been less of a crisis.
We're told that without these paradises,
governments wouldn't have to make so
many cuts with all pay fewer taxes,
and ultimately it would make things much
better.
Well,
the question now is how true is all of
this?
All tax havens rarely so bad for the
general welfare of the population?
Well,
let's check it out.
The first thing we need to be clear
about is what a tax haven is.
A tax haven is nothing more than a
jurisdiction with low taxes,
high legal security,
and an extreme amounts of protection of
the savers privacy.
This is very important because cutting
taxes isn't enough to turn a territory
into a tax haven,
not at all.
You see,
the international investors and savers
who use these jurisdictions really want
to protect their assets.
That's why they not only demands low
taxes,
but also legal security that is in
addition to low taxes.
They want to ensure that their assets
are safe from any kinds of robbery,
nationalization confiscation,
corruption,
inflation,
etc.
Therefore,
what's common to all tax havens even
more than low taxes isn't legal safety.
They're all the cayman islands,
Switzerland,
Singapore,
Hong Kong,
cypress,
jersey,
ends,
bermuda.
All of these jurisdictions that we
recognize as important financial centers
in that characterized by their high
legal safety say this,
essentially know that the government's
not going to take all of their money.
It's precisely this combination of low
taxes and high legal security that makes
these territories receive so much
capital from around the world and to
grow at rates and much higher than in
other countries and though operating in
these places isn't illegal in itself,
despite what the media might suggest
appearing in the paradise papers are in
the Panama papers.
It doesn't necessarily mean that you've
committed a crime.
In fact,
most of the names on these lists of
those entirely innocent people,
people like alex krivaline,
shakira,
whose assets have a legal origin and to
use tax havens to minimize their tax
bills within the bounds of the law.
This may seem more or less immoral,
but it's perfectly legal.
Another very important detail which we
usually forget is that these tax havens
are a refuge for millions of citizens.
You have the misfortune of being in
authoritarian and extractive country.
we all know that there are many
countries in the world where the most
basic human rights on guarantees or wow
authoritarian governments arbitrarily
decide who to repress or persecuted that
is.
Many investors don't seek protection
just for lower taxes.
They also escaping political,
ideological,
and religious.
I think for example,
of political dissidence in Russia or
Venezuela or families who are threatened
by kidnapping in Mexico or entrepreneurs
that come from countries with few
guarantees like Zimbabwe or better
reduce,
well,
they all benefit from being able to
access jurisdictions that guarantee the
safety,
that tax havens
because it's also a matter of justice.
And then we do explain it,
most people think it's an aberration,
when some states present messages and
it's from leaving the country as happens
with the berlin wall,
what we should also probably think it's
an aberration when states preventing
their citizens from taking their savings
out of the country and depositing it in
a more protective foreign jurisdiction.
That is of course,
if they're doing it in compliance with
the law.
In any case,
the truth is that both the media and
politicians greatly exaggerate the
Consequences that these tax havens half
on our economies.
So let's check it out.
A very exaggerated
roll.
Too many polIticians and journalists tax
havens are greatly responsible for all
of the ells we suffer,
such as the third world governments
budget cuts,
inequality,
and under development.
ThiS is what the organization,
oxfam argues.
For example,
I check this out.
The current global inequality crisis has
a clear ally in tax havens.
These jurisdictions represent the black
hole through the development
opportunities,
uh,
millions of people around the world
fall.
Well,
first of all,
we must state that oxfam is definition
of a tax.
Haven is a bit lax in their opinion.
A tax haven is any country that has very
low taxes,
especially for foreign investments.
This definition includes countries like
the Netherlands and Luxembourg,
which of course they received such a
qualification from the european
commission,
the european parliament,
or the oec deep,
but all right,
even with this definition,
let's see how important those tax havens
really off.
Say,
let's take the case of Spain,
a european union country with a high
average income that has many economic
problems as well as high taxes.
Well,
based on their government's own data,
Spain invested 40 point nine,
$1,
billion euros overseas in 2016 of this
total.
Nine point five,
4 billion ended up in what?
Oxfam mccall's tax havens.
Nine point five,
$4 million is less than five percent of
everything.
Spanish people invested in the entire
world,
including Spain during that year.
So really the reality is that the
relevance of these tax savings isn't
quite as great as it's made out to be.
In fact,
the highest place the world heritage of
tax havens at about seven point
$6,000,000,000,000.
And that might seem like a huge number,
but when you look at it from a global
perspective,
it's actually quite small,
so we might not like it,
but the truth is that tax havens can
hardly be responsible for the big
problems that many critics say they are.
But that's not all here.
Let's return to Spain situation.
80 seven percent of the spanish
investments that went to oxfam's tax
havens in 2016 were concentrated in
Ireland,
the Netherlands and Luxembourg.
We're talking about a bit over
$8,000,000
out.
Well,
in that same year,
these three countries invested over
$12,000,000,000
into Spain.
As you can see,
tax havens not only do two d capitalize,
the business fabric of a country is
fiscally uncompetitive as Spain.
In fact,
it's quite the opposite.
These tax havens of helped capitalize
the week spanish economy.
Luxembourg is the country that invest
the most in Spain,
in factorieS,
buildings,
farms,
employment,
but it isn't public,
but private money most comes from
companies and savings vehicles
established in the country.
Javier,
gee,
your in economics journalist in it'll
competency are.
But Having said that,
let's look at another key question.
How much revenue did governments lose
result of tax havens?
Is it true that without them there would
have been no cuts during the crisis?
Well,
let's see.
Story of the milKmaid.
We've seen one of the most common
criticisms tax havens yet is that if we
hadn't had such unfair competition,
governments wouldn't have had to make
budget cuts as a result of the 2008
financial crisis.
But is it true?
Well,
let's get baCk to our spanish case
again.
As you know,
this is one of the countries that
suffered the most from the recession.
Well,
according to data from the spanish
ministry of economy,
the investment accumulated in oxfam
defined tax savings year after year
announced an $80 million dollars.
Well,
if all of that money had been
accumulated in Spain,
instead of tax havens,
the extra income that the spanish state
would have received would have been
approximately one to one point 5 billion
euros.
Again,
it sounds like quite a bit of money,
but I promise you it's a really
minuscule amount in the overall scheme
of
thanks.
Give you an idea about that.
It's about zero point one percent of the
spanish gdp and less than point five
percent of all taxes collected.
In other words,
it has a very limited impact and if
instead of Spain we took a look at
what's happening in the rest of the
world,
the situation is pretty similar.
In fact,
even if we take the highest estimates of
the tax Justice network,
which is the source that's usually used
to denounce tax havens,
we'll see.
They show a global collection loss of
about $200,000,000,000,
which is Barely one percent of all the
tax revenues of the world's governments.
No.
The truth is that contrary to what's
usually claimed,
a tax havens aren't to be blamed for the
cuts,
nor do they force us to pay more taxes
or really harm our economies.
We mAy not like it much,
but it's just the thing.
No.
In 1980 islands was actually poor than
Spain today.
Thanks to these policies,
that's the second richest country in the
eurozone.
To improve the general welfare,
we need more companies,
not more politicians and not more public
spending.
The problems that countries with
economic difficulties face don't usually
come from tax havens,
ms from the politicians,
but now is your time.
Do you think that tax havens should be
persecuted?
Please leave your answer in the comments
below as well as in this survey and I
really hope you enjoyed this video.
Please do hit that like button if you
did and don't forget to subscribe for
brand new videos.
Also,
don't forget the jacket.
Our friends at the reconsider media
podcast,
they provided the bogles in this
episode,
but we're not mine.
Also this channel as possible because of
patrion and our patrons on that platform
to use,
consider joining them and supporting our
mission of providing independent
political coverage.
And as always,
I'll see you in the next day.
Yes.