It's the second most populated country
on earth.
Seventh biggest economy.
Yeah.
One of the 10 biggest military budgets
in the world and is a nuclear power.
India is a stranger in political terms.
If I were to ask you,
who's the prime minister of India,
could you tell me?
No.
I am aware that many of you will
actually know this,
especially if you're watching this video
from India,
but if you don't know who the prime
minister of India is,
don't worry because.
Well,
that happens a lot
on the 26th of May,
2014 after an absolute majority,
which had not been seen in 30 years.
Narendra Modi became the prime minister
of India.
Moody's mission,
whether it was clear boost growth
investments,
and to create millions of jobs in
conclusion,
turn India into a superpower capable of
competing with China on an economic,
political,
and military level.
Gene Kim,
how todd?
You know India because you're a politic
view is,
is something all on eternal promise.
It's always that country that seems to
be the next one that's going to take
off,
but it never really does.
Where you can see that this is
definitely the case.
If we take a look at India's GDP and
compare it to that of China,
they seem quite different economic
development in the last few decades,
so with Moody's victory expectations
all,
once again,
high end,
India has again become the talk of the
town.
Moody is repeating over and over again.
The 21st century is going to be India's
century.
Well,
before we get into all of that,
let's take a look at boody himself.
Oh,
he's Narendra Modi,
vegetarian,
single ends,
a yoga enthusiast,
Modi escapes the traditional politician
profile.
He comes from a family of limited means
and when he was a child,
used to help his father sell tea in a
train station.
This has helped him and the sympathy of
many poor people in the country.
They see him as an example of a rags to
riches story and shows that rags to
riches in India can sometimes work.
His political ideology has always been
very attached to Hinduism and he is not
always taken a moderate approach.
In fact,
before getting involved with the BJP
party,
he was involved with the rfs as potty.
The RSS Party isn't extreme rights
policy that had Mahatma Gandhi's
assassin as one of its members for 13
years,
between 2011 and 2014.
Moody was the regional Prime Minister in
the state of good Gerard Gerard.
It's 65 million inhabitants has become
numb to Moody's leadership,
India's greatest economic driver with an
annual growth rate of 10 percent.
It's like these impressive figures.
Social Welfare has also greatly
improved.
Almost every home has access to the
plumbing,
electricity,
and preschool education.
While the general election in India was
taking place,
moody promised to replicate what he'd
done in his state in the rest of India.
Furthermore,
he promised to do this in just 10 years,
which is only two political terms,
Lauren Nigga,
we did look by his dish arms,
arms,
shit,
abuse,
because I've magical Niggas don't
niggas.
This is because for Moody,
the Year Twenty,
22 is a landmark.
Yeah.
It's the 75th anniversary of India's
independence.
The country will also support us,
China as the world's most populous
country.
Reaching a population of one point 6
billion people,
Moody says that by the year 20,
22,
it's going to be clear that the 21st
century is India
century.
This is certainly not going to be easy,
especially in a country where the
population is growing by 28 people every
minute.
Yes,
measure problem.
Now India has many problems,
but three,
do you stand out as particularly
important?
The first is that India is a
bureaucrat's paradise.
In fact,
if bureaucracy was the key to
prosperity,
India would probably be the most
prosperous country in the world.
Unfortunately though bureaucracy instead
of encouraging business actually
prevents it.
John Cody has blamed the Indian
bureaucracy for putting roadblocks in
the group of Indian economy.
According to the doing business report
from the wells bank,
which estimates how easy it is to do
business in India occupies the 130th
position each step of the way to
establishing a business in India takes a
ton of documents and then the taxes are
not only high.
Not that anyone really pays them,
but they are also a nightmare to sort
out,
for example,
on not only different taxes in each
individual state,
but there are sometimes different taxes
for each individual product or different
models of the same product.
This is something that commonly happens
with vehicles and it is a real nice
math.
Anyone to work out
Katina with the hand or they buddy nick
lingered further.
DSM among public workers has reached
such a critical state that some
hospitals have been forced to closed
temporarily because of the lack of
staff.
The second big problem is that
regulations in the marketplace make it
so complicated that the market is barely
able to function on the borders between
different states.
You'll find trucks that are just cuing
to cross the border.
Not a few people say that it's actually
easier to import something from abroad
than it is to get something from another
state.
Further,
there is the terrible state of the
country's infrastructure as well.
Estimated that half of the country's
harvest goes to waste every year because
of these delays.
And the third big problem is that
corruption is a big issue in Indian
society.
As a quick example of this,
it is estimated that 50 percent of all
money that the government gives for
welfare either ends up in the hands of
corrupt politicians or middlemen.
And so this is the country for Moody,
is having to deal with
government policies.
Some have suggested it has not yet taken
place.
However,
the truth is is that the government has
achieved some notable advances.
For example,
we could highlight the following in
order to reduce bureaucracy.
The government has created a committee
with the purpose of determining which
rules and regulations are obsolete and
should be eliminated.
So far they've done away with more than
1700 of these rules.
Moody has eliminated many restrictions
on foreign investments is past the first
bankruptcy law.
And to set up a powerful planet to make
India a destination for business
is also set forth an ambitious plan for
better financial inclusion.
This plan has a pretty unpronounceable
name,
so I'm just going to show it on the
screen now.
And this plan has basically allowed for
people to have a bank account for the
first time,
the number of people who've taken this
up,
it's about $200 million.
And this basically means that that
welfare money that is coming from the
government,
it doesn't have to go through any
middlemen further.
The government has also put forth a plan
to simplify a very complicated tax
system.
Having a flat sales tax at the national
level.
There's also
announced that they're going to be
spending a lot of money on
infrastructure with a hundred and
$30,000,000,000 being spent on rail by
2020.
So again this year,
our plan is to really connect a lot of
these small towns and cities to the main
national highway and,
and the target or the government is to
construct 10,000 kilometers of road
every year.
But these aside,
Moody's most risky moves so far happens
in November of 2016 mbs cash crisis.
In order to fight corruption,
India suddenly made the countries
501,000 rupee notes illegal.
These represented 85 percent of all of
our cash in India.
A country that is really a cash based
economy,
the goal was to find dirty money and
punish it when the owners came into the
bank to switch out that 500 and the
phenols and notes for ones in the new
design.
However,
the plan was an utter disaster.
The government didn't have enough cash
to replace the money that people wanted
to exchange.
Further,
the country's atfs weren't working
properly because the new currency was a
different shape to the old currency and
the ATM is hadn't been adjusted.
I don't know what to do.
People here have no money to buy my
products so I can't buy stock from the
market either.
It's the end of my business.
This was a botched operation that left
the country moneyless and caused
significant damage to the economy.
Sales fell in November.
By more than 30 percent.
Many businesses simply weren't able to
pay workers,
and many business transactions have to
be canceled.
Some studies estimate that the total
damage was two points of India's GDP.
This would mean for the bank note switch
cost India.
$50,000,000,000 ends.
Unfortunately,
the poorest in the country were the
hardest hit.
Then the government tried to save,
but it was all part of some big plans
who encourage people to use more
electronic money,
a politician foreign policy agenda.
Now this is the field where the prime
minister has really excelled.
In his first year alone,
he visited my new team members
that he's only been in power for a short
amount of time,
that he has a treatment,
some notable advances.
The Pakistan treaty has improved India,
Pakistan,
one relationship.
It's a relationship with China,
has started dealing with some economic
and commercial issues.
At a joint press conference,
President Xi Jinping announced 20
billion US dollars worth of investment
in India's infrastructure in five years.
However,
without any doubt,
the greatest strength of Moody's
political agenda has been his approach
to the United States.
The chemistry between Obama and Moody
has been quite significant and their
encounters have been frequent and
friendly.
They have both even published an article
altogether in the Washington.
What we really need to ask now is we'll
moody achieve his goals.
That I'll certainly a great deal of
challenges that he is going to have to
overcome.
For example,
it's been made clear to the prime
minister just how tricky it is,
but the limits on bureaucracy further
moody has avoided many essential reforms
such as ending India's labor regulation,
which has mentioned that four out of
every five jobs in the country are on
the gray market.
Moody claims to be an admirer of Lee
Kuan Yew.
Singapore's ex prime minister Modi
doesn't seem to have the same drive or
determination to transform India's
model.
So this is just our opinion here,
revisional politic,
and we would love to know what you
think.
Do you think that the 21st century is
going to be India Century?
Do you think that Modi is going to
achieve all that he has set out to
achieve?
Do let us know in the comments below?
We'd love to hear from you.
Also,
please do give this video a thumbs up if
you enjoyed it and don't forget to
subscribe a brand new videos every
Monday and Thursday,
and as always I'll see you next
[inaudible].