The world's best country if you don't
want to be alone.
This country has half the population of
the United States,
but concentrated in an area the size of
Illinois.
It is the most densely populated country
on the planet.
It's also been one of the fastest
growing countries in the last few
decades.
In less than 20 years,
Bangladesh has cut poverty in half.
Avi Leader in textile manufacturing only
surpassed by China.
In fact,
I'm pretty sure your shirt,
your trousers or something else you're
wearing right now was made bath.
Let's wait a minute because it is still
too soon to open the bottle of
champagne.
Yes.
Bangladesh grows faster,
but still to date,
13 percent of their population lives on
less than $2 a day and that's 20 million
people add to this.
The fact that Islam is the main religion
in the country and you get headlines
like this one
activity increased in Bangladesh in
2016.
I made global fall and attacks dislike
the fact that Bangladesh has a secular
constitution.
Adulterous women are stoned to death in
some regions and 80 percent of the
population agrees with changing the
legislation.
So that it meets the principles of
Sharia law.
Meanwhile,
despite the radicalization of some
citizens,
the prime minister shake of Ciena is a
woman and the opposition leader,
a leader is also a woman.
So the situation that is far from quiet,
especially given that in the next year,
2018 Bangladesh will hold elections that
might be crucial for the future of the
country.
Questions that we find ourselves asking,
oh well Ken Bangladesh become an Islamic
republic.
And why do we think Bangladesh is a
demographic time bomb?
Well,
today we are going to answer these
questions,
but before we do that,
let's take a look back out the history.
One Country to families and 1947,
the British empire,
let's the Indian colonies become
independence.
The parts were Hindu,
isn't was the main religion became what
today is known as
dm
with an Islamic majority became
Pakistan,
but things are not as simple as they
seem.
The listening pause ended up divided
into two parts.
As you can see on the screen now,
India was in the middle and to the left
and right there was Pakistan with a
political system.
Based on sharia law,
2,200 kilometers divided,
these two paths that belonged to the
same states,
and as you can imagine,
this just didn't work very well.
In fact,
putting aside the fact that they have
the same religion,
these two paths,
while they had nothing in common,
they didn't even speak the same
language.
Western Pakistanis
despise the eastern Pakistanis,
also known as the Bengalis and wanted to
have their own country.
So in 1971,
the liberation war starting estimation
say that somewhere between 300,000 and 3
million civilians died in the sport,
but as a result of brand new country,
I was born and this was the People's
Republic of Bangladesh.
This is also how Mujtaba Rahman,
or as they know him,
Bunka Bonduelle became the first
president since Pakistan was an Islamic
country,
and Bangladesh hated Pakistan badly.
Bangor then do you designed the
constitution that was completely
secular.
In fact,
they followed the ideological fashion of
the time or the so called Arab
socialism.
This wasn't ideological cocktail that
combines authoritarian leaders,
a centralized economy and secularism.
Wait,
just a minute here because it really
wasn't that easy for years later,
Bangor bands zoo and this whole family
died and acute atar made by those who
supported Pakistan.
You rule during the liberation war,
only his two daughters survived.
One of them shake a Siena is the current
prime minister,
but let's look back at that cue to top
after two years of political stability
in the influence of the CIA General Zia
Rahman became the man in China.
Sure
that his most controversial decisions
was to give amnesty to the pro
Pakistani.
Therefore Islam as soldiers who killed
Banga Bantu.
This is how the big ideological divide
was created in Bangladesh.
On the one hand,
we have the family and the political
party of General Ramen.
The BNP or Bangladesh National Party,
they are a conservative coalition with a
strong presence among isn't Mr parties,
some of those who participated in the
cute Atar.
In 1975 became members of the BNP party.
On the other hand,
we have the party of Bangor Bansi,
the circled Awami League.
They are considered socialist and
secular.
Romans rule the country for four years.
Then of course,
then another cute Atar,
Bangladesh was ruled by the military
until 1991 when democracy came back to
the country,
but hold on a minute again here,
because the Bangladesh way,
if democracy is pretty far from
democratic tree to women since 1991,
these two political parties had two main
leaders.
On the BNP side,
we have Kalita Zen,
the widow desire ramen.
On the army side there is shake Asina,
the daughter of Ngabantu.
Since then,
elections have been a fight between two
women.
This alternate empower every five years.
Neither one of them can win the
elections consistently.
In fact,
elections in Bangladesh,
absolutely.
Hello,
the opposition party organizers,
violence protests and paralyzing strikes
that damage to the country,
but in 2006 well
things they changed back then.
The Awami League,
leds by shake Asina disagreed with the
way that they organize the elections.
This was pretty business as usual,
but this time the military tried to make
a cute.
It's odd,
but some audit in the country like they
had in the 19 eighties elections had to
be postponed for two years and finally
sheet casinos won the elections.
In that moment,
I learned a lesson.
The important thing is not winning the
office.
Keeping
not.
Remember when I told you the general
robin gave amnesty to those.
You've killed Banga Bendu 40 years
before.
Well,
his daughter shake Kasina had a pretty
good memory and she took those memories
from the past and decided to do
something about those Islamists.
He might challenge power.
Those who participated in the 1975 at a
time executes leader of largest Islamist
party.
If this wasn't enough,
she broke up.
Uh,
one of the biggest political traditions
in Bangladesh.
Usually during an election,
the parliaments would create a neutral
governments in order to guarantee a
clean and fair process was not willing
to leave power.
The opposition boycotted the elections
and to Siena one with 79 percent of the
vote.
When ash ruling party wins after
boycotted vote.
I don't have the words now in 2017.
Shake a scene or is the strongest leader
in Bangladesh's history,
and this is no little thing if we
remember that this is a country of more
than 160 million inhabitants.
So the question is now,
is there anyone who can match a scene as
power?
Well,
the answer is actually yes.
Graphic bomb,
as we said at the beginning of the 20
million Bangladeshi citizens live in
extreme poverty.
They are young and extremely religious.
In other words,
they are the perfect market for a
radical Islamist movements.
And Yeah,
I know you might be saying right now,
but.
Well,
Simon did not say that Bangladesh is one
of the fastest growing countries.
Well,
yes I did.
And this is exactly why there's 20
million poor citizens
problem.
Yes,
and if you want to start the populist
revolution never go to an extremely poor
country.
In fact,
most of the radical movements appear
when countries are starting to grow or
stepping out of a crisis.
This is your window of opportunity.
That is the moment when the worst off
citizens can feel jealous of those who
are getting wealthier and wealthier.
Those $20 million impoverished citizens
are imperfect targets for radicalization
and it can be a real threats to our
country stability.
This is why it terrorist attacks have
been getting more and more frequent in
Bangladesh since 2013.
The victims are bloggers who claim to be
atheists and trying to spread secularism
in the country.
That's the real wakeup call that came
in.
Two Thousand and 16 long letter should
attack isis.
Gunmen killed at least 22 people in the
hostage crisis at Daca restaurant since
then shake us.
INA has been trying to stop terrorism.
Nonetheless,
as I said in 2018 elections will be held
and the government is trying to gain
support from that religious population.
This is why it has seen isn't letting
Saudi Arabia invest $1,000,000,000 into
the building of 160 mosques throughout
the country.
At the same time,
she is making it harder for women's who
inherits money and also making it easier
for young girls to marry much older.
Yeah.
Amen.
It doesn't stop there and Islamic
propaganda group because half is that he
Islam send their agenda with political
suggestions.
Do you have governments,
for instance,
they wanted the religious teachings
given a radical mosques to be considered
at the same level as any academic
institution and against the odds shake
Hasina has accepted that as well as
other proposals from the radicals.
Don't forget that she and her party are
the ones that stands for secular values
against a more traditional approach from
the BNP party.
So this leads us to the big question
here.
Do you think Bangladesh is at risk of
becoming a de facto Islamic republic,
or is this just a political game?
Sheik Hasina to strengthen her power
before the elections?
Well,
you can leave your answer in the
comments section below and please do
also visit our friends at the reconsider
media podcast.
You can find it@reconsidermedia.com or
they provided the vocals in this video
that are not mine.
Also check out my new channel
biographics.
We do biographies of notable people from
history as well as the present day.
Find a link to that in the description
below.
New Videos here as well every Monday and
Thursday.
So I subscribed to visual politics so
you won't miss anything and as always,
thank you for watching and if you want
to learn more about politics and hear
even more of my lovely voice,
you can join us at reconsider media.
We have a podcast@reconsideredmedia.com
slash podcast.
See you there.