Is this someone controlling capitalism
behind the scenes?
You've heard about the Reptilians,
the Rothschild family,
even George Soros.
This is one player with much more power
than any of these guys and nobody's ever
told you about them.
That of course is the government of
Norway.
Yep.
No way is more than just a very,
very rich country.
It's governments can have a real sway on
international businesses.
Think I've gotten enough swell at the
end of this video.
You are absolutely going to see where
I'm coming from.
No way is the only country on the planet
where say tannic black metal songs are
on the billboard shots.
Yes.
My idea of you,
if you ever travel to this country and
turn up your radio,
you might find yourself not listening to
Taylor swift,
but instead bands like kroger off man or
little meister and that famous hit
titled My ass.
Ah,
so yes,
there might be something a little odd
going on with the music in this country,
but Norway is one of the richest
countries on the planet's thing in the
same league as Ireland and Switzerland,
but not only that,
they're also.
One of the most egalitarian,
this means that the difference between
the rich and the poor is fairness.
Awesome.
That welfare state is big.
That taxes are high and their lifestyle
is good,
but I'm betting yet already probably
know this.
What you probably don't know is that
noise influence on the international
economy is way bigger than it looks.
Yes,
Norway is behind the scenes of one of
the biggest corporations on the planet,
but
seriously,
don't leave this video right now.
I know what you're thinking and.
No,
no,
no.
This video is most definitely not a
crossover with Alex Jones use no way.
As a population of less than 5 million
inhabitants,
New York City has more people
nonetheless.
These 5 million people have big shares
in the welds.
Major corporations.
Yep.
You heard that right?
The government of Norway has its own
hedge fund and they are among the main
shareholders in a lot of companies like
apple,
facebook,
and Tesla knowing might not have a big
tree,
but they have an army of money ready to
influence the world's economy.
So the question now is,
well,
why is Norway so rich and powerful?
How to do it now at this point?
Yeah,
probably all thinking the same thing and
that is probably oil and you are
actually kind of right.
Norway is one of the world's largest oil
producers,
but they actually have nothing to do
with the other oil rich countries.
I mean,
just look at this picture.
You can see the skylines of Riyadh.
Saudi Arabia
conversation
looks like a Scifi city of the future.
These skyscrapers,
modern buildings and blends.
You have lights.
Now we'll take a look at this picture of
Oslo,
the capital of
Norway.
I probably see the difference right now.
If you've been following visual politic
for a long time,
you already know that having oil is not
the same as being rich.
In fact,
as you can see on this,
Josh,
Norwegian crude oil is twice as
expensive to extract a Saudi
for a better understanding.
Most of the Norwegian oil comes from the
North Sea and these oil beds,
if she had with other countries like the
United Kingdom,
however noise,
taking the most advantage of that oil
wealth.
Oh,
okay.
Okay.
And I know what you're probably thinking
right now.
Oh,
this is another visual politic video
where Simon tells us how wonderful it is
and how rich Norway God by privatizing
companies,
right rice.
Well,
actually this time the story is
different.
Norway is actually a great example of
state capitalism.
So now you might be wondering,
well,
what exactly is state capitalism?
Why is no way so rich and powerful?
11 answer the question,
Simon,
and what does it mean for a government
to invest in the stock market?
Well,
do not worry because today we're going
to answer these questions,
but as always before we do that,
let's have a look back at the history,
the Dutch disease.
So I do need to be honest here because
Norway is never exactly been a poor
country,
but it wasn't exactly always a wealthy
one either.
In the 19 fifties.
Norwegians enjoyed a lifestyle similar
to that of the French.
This means wealthier than the Spaniards,
but poorer than this Swedish neighbors.
And of course the Americans.
Back then,
nobody expected Norway to have oil,
but well,
things change dramatically.
Nineteen 59 and that moment shell
started respecting in the North Sea
shells in oil company.
In the Netherlands,
and they were looking for potential oil
beds in the shores of that
country.
One day,
boom.
They found little gas sources and
whenever that is gas and oil,
so they kept up their exploration and
this is how one of the biggest oil field
in the world was discovered.
An oilfield situated under British
Norwegian waters.
During the 19 sixties,
Sharon got drilling licenses in those
two countries years later in 1972,
the Norwegian government founded its own
oil company.
Stat oil,
fresh.
You're married.
Then you start on this.
This is how the North Sea oil boom
started.
During the 19 seventies,
money flew into this country.
In just three years,
Norwegians doubled their GDP per capita.
All of a sudden the Norwegian dream and
working in the dinosaur juice industry,
I mean,
who really wants to go fishing for
salmon when you can make a lot of money
working with and gas right now,
it all might be sounding pretty
fantastic to you.
Rice.
Well actually it's not.
In fact this phenomenon,
the.
It has a name,
they call it the Dutch disease or the
cost of natural resources.
Basically anytime the country finds oil
and its economy goes nuts,
the government couldn't waste piles of
money while still lowering taxes,
citizens,
they want to work in the oil industry
because it's the most profitable.
Well,
what happens next few years you were
coming in.
Just one thing.
Dinosaur,
Jason,
when you depend so much on a single
product,
a small change in the market price puts
the whole country on the verge of
bankruptcy.
This is exactly what's happened in
Venezuela and what could happen in other
countries like Saudi Arabia or Bahrain,
this.
This was the big difference between
Norway and the United Kingdom.
Both countries have labor governments,
but their policies couldn't be more
different.
In the year 1976,
the UK was in the middle of one of their
worst financial crises.
The government couldn't wait to squeeze
that oil wealth for all.
It was worth Norway.
However,
they had a more stable situation and
they could wait so well.
What does this mean?
Well,
first the government put very strict
industry regulations in place.
Plus,
50 percent of those are eggs had to be
in the hands of the state owned oil
company.
On the other hand,
foreign companies have to pay a 78
percent tax on the profits and that's
not at all.
No Way.
Put a limit on oil production.
Just look at ms dot.
Yeah,
yeah.
You can see whether UK kickstarted that
production.
At the end of the 19 seventies,
the British were already producing more
than a million and a half barrels a day
while Norway was still doing a third of
that during the eighties during the
Margaret Thatcher administration,
the UK kept pumping oil like there was
no tomorrow while Norway was still
pretty much relaxed about the
production.
So what did they achieve by doing this?
Norway was keeping the productive
economy focused on oil,
but just wait a minute because there's
another big difference
you see during the eighties,
Thatcher private domains to British
Petroleum.
Norway's governments by contrast kept
control of start on even today,
display the company changing its name
from [inaudible] to Ecuador.
That state still owns 67 percent of the
fun.
Okay,
so now you might be thinking,
well,
oh my God,
so wait,
noise a socialist country,
but just hold on a second because the
Norwegian economic system,
it's actually kind of similar to that of
China and this is what experts are
calling state capitalism.
This means that the state controls a
good share of the economy,
but it behaves like a big private
company.
So what does that mean?
Well,
check this out.
The hedge fund country.
Now before we continue,
I should make an aside here because this
beautiful romantic and sweet melody or
hearing right now is the music of end of
it.
A black metal band that's from not from
Norway.
They're actually from Columbia that it
sounds just like a Norwegian bands and
they sent us their music for this video.
If you want to hear more of them,
we haven't linked to their channel in
the description,
the light.
All right,
back to our stories.
Do you remember the two pictures I
showed you at the beginning of this
video?
Well,
the countries like Saudi Arabia,
they used their impressive or wealth to
live like a hip hop artist on a Friday
night.
However,
the different Norwegian administrations,
both labor and conservative have
measured every last penny they've spent.
And so what does this mean?
Well,
that oil wealth and went into a piggy
bank,
and this is how we go to the year,
1990 in this year,
Norwegian parliament,
they realize three things.
One,
they have a lot of savings to all market
prices go up and down and they cannot
control that.
And three,
the best thing they can do is diversify
their economy as well.
How could they do that?
Well,
how about investing in the stock?
Gotcha.
I have.
So as we say here,
a visual politics.
So it was that insert was done.
This is how the government pension fund
of Norway also known as the oil fund was
created.
This is a hedge fund controlled by the
Norwegian Central Bank as they might be
thinking,
well,
oh yeah,
but what's so impressive about that,
I mean there are other countries,
but sovereign wealth funds China,
there's Australia,
there's the United Arab Emirates.
And yes,
that is true,
but this is one of the biggest of them
all.
We're talking about more than a trillion
American dollars.
This means that if we divide up this
fund by the entire Norwegian population,
each citizen has more than $200,000
invested in stocks,
but this is not the end of the story.
According to the law,
nobody can touch that money for any
public spending.
This means that the government can only
use the benefits of the fund,
but never the capital.
And believe me,
we are not talking about a small amount
of money.
Yeah,
Norway's sovereign wealth fund made
$130,000,000,000
in one year.
Also,
according to the law,
they cannot invest in their local
economy only in foreign companies.
This is why today,
Norway holds one point five percent of
all of the stocks existing in the entire
world.
Now,
of course,
some years are better than others and
according to many analysts,
the management of the fund is overly
conservative and it doesn't make as much
money as they could,
but the truth is,
Norway doesn't just use this for
diversification.
They all fund is also a political
weapon.
Norway's 900,
$5 billion dollar oil fund flexes its
shareholder muscles,
world's largest sovereign wealth fund,
opposed 6,700
company resolutions.
Last year,
for example,
every year the Norwegian central bank
pushes a blacklist with companies that
they don't invest in for ethical
reasons.
This includes weapons manufacturers,
tobacco producers and firms involved in
corruption scandals,
but this is just the beginning.
You see,
having stocks of a publicly traded
company gives you the right to
participate in the shareholder's
meetings.
You can vote on corporate decisions and
even suggest topics for discussion.
The more stocks you have,
the more important you are in those
meetings.
Is an example.
This past summer 2018,
facebook started in new algorithms to
filter fake news.
They also started to take the wage gap
seriously.
These two decisions,
all the outcome of a shareholder meeting
and guess you added those topics in the
meeting schedule.
Well,
yeah,
it was.
No Way.
And the same also happens with other
companies.
Norway's Fund backs activists bid at
alphabet meeting.
As you know,
Alphabet is the conglomerate that owns
Google and Youtube.
A small group of shells is wanted google
to refine the fake news filter and
having the support of Norway's Fund
helps them at win very crucial votes.
The same thing happens with apple.
In this case,
Norway is the eighth biggest shareholder
with more than 9 billion US dollars
invested and they aren't exactly silent
in the shareholder meetings in general,
Norway is pushing some of the world's
biggest companies to change their
corporate policies on many different
fronts.
Of course,
there's the gender gap that that's not
the only one.
Part of the Norwegian ideology focuses
on this
two
Norway sovereign fund to focus on high
executive pay.
In many ways,
big multinational executives make a big
sign of aries despite the company losing
money.
We saw this several times during the
financial crisis.
As you can imagine,
shareholders of these companies are not
exactly happy with this,
but it's hard to speak out when you only
hold a small number of shares in the
company,
and this is where Norway comes in,
is it's a loudspeaker for smaller
investors,
many countries trying to control the
world within militaries,
other countries trying to sway foreign
governments with diplomacy.
Norway expands their power through
influence on the biggest global
companies,
and this is the Norwegian conspiracy,
but meanwhile Norwegian citizens can
sleep at night knowing that even if oil
prices go down,
they have their futures guaranteed,
and now it's your turn.
Do you think it's a good idea for a
whole country to invest in the stock
market?
Do you think that the Norwegian
influences good for global capitalism?
What do you think it's bad?
Well,
please leave your answer in the comment
section below.
Also,
don't forget to visit reconsider
media.com.
They're the podcast that provided the
voices in this episode that we're not
buying and as always,
do not forget.
We published brand new videos every
week,
so subscribe to this channel and hit
that bell button so you won't miss out
on any future posts and if you like
this video,
give it a thumbs up and as always I'll
see you next time and if you want to
learn more about politics and hear more
of mine,
lovely voice,
don't forget to check out the reconsider
podcast@reconsidermedia.com.
And we consider as a podcast that
challenges you to reconsider your
reviews by providing context,
but we don't do the thinking.
Yeah.