Funny.
It's [inaudible] has become the biggest
threat to the euro zone.
Why is this?
Well,
that's what we're going to tell you in
this video.
[inaudible]
the cradle of the West,
the place of pastor pizza and pop.
You like coffee making techniques like
the Cappuccino,
ristretto and espresso.
It's all in SLA,
but in addition to this,
it's really,
it has become quite a headache for
Europe's leaders.
No ones are,
I mean,
we're talking about a giant of the could
turn into a true titanic.
Okay?
We're talking about an economic and
financial crisis that could make greases
crisis look like child's play.
See,
it's only currently has the eighth
largest economy in the world,
but this country isn't growing.
It's banking system has loads of
problems and it is.
Governments is hugely in debt.
In fact,
this is at least public debt already
surpasses 130% of its GDP,
which means that even though it has the
fourth largest economy in the European
Union off to Germany,
the United Kingdom and France,
it also has the largest public debt
stock.
This amounts to more than two point $5
trillion.
The Italian public debt folks is twice
the size of the entire Mexican economy.
I'd almost four times the size of the
Swiss economy and that's if you didn't
figure out is a lot of it.
Money
Prolo doesn't even begin to end that the
Italian economy is hardly growing.
In fact,
it hasn't managed to get back to its pre
2008 crisis levels.
Unemployment,
it's a pass is 10% and youth
unemployment lies at around 40%
total of this.
We need to add the fact that year after
year,
public debt continues to rise and it
won't stop growing.
The country has a very big population
with an agent problem and above all,
the European Central Bank,
which in recent years has been Italy's
largest public debt purchaser could soon
stop doing that.
European Central Bank says it's massive
bond buying program will likely end in
December.
All of that said,
we can easily understand news like this.
Italy is pushing Europe to the brink of
another economic crisis.
The Italian crisis that is making the EU
tremble worsens.
All right.
Is there something you might not be
wondering?
Well,
yes,
Simon,
I get it,
but this is hardly new.
It's at,
he's been a problem for ages.
Why we spotlighting it now?
Well,
I'm going to tell you government a step
back after months of uncertainty,
a new government finally gained power in
June of 2018 and we're not talking about
just any governor
that's
led by the new prime minister just sat
by [inaudible].
We're talking about a government formed
by the euro skeptic and antisystem
movement,
fivestars ends by La Liga and extremely
far right wing party.
This new coalition arrived with a very
clear idea in mind.
It's at least sovereignty would again be
in room and not in Brussels,
which in most cases wouldn't mean
anything except a higher expense.
Well,
the fact is that as you know,
the countries that belonged to the euro
zone,
that is those that share the same
currency agree on certain goals with the
European authorities as well as on some
maximum public deficit levels and on a
path of these deficits have to follow
over the years.
All of this is done to maintain their
stability and solvency and thus reduce
the risk of crisis.
Well,
the new Italian government does not like
this one yet.
Deficit path,
I mean,
come on now.
You're not going to tell me how to spend
my money.
Europe,
and this is more or less what the new
government must have fought because one
of the first things they did was present
a budget proposal in September for a
public deficits that is substantially
larger than the one they committed to in
Brussels.
And that is when the earthquake happens,
it'll eat,
defies the European Union and increases
their deficits.
2.4%
of GDP and you have government wanting
to spend money that they,
and he's got a public debt problem and
now they want to ask for a higher dance.
Well I'm seeing is believing because
folks 2.4%
might sound low,
but if we take the facts that the
Italian economy is forecasted to not
grow more than 1% in the upcoming years
into accounts,
then things really do change because
that 2.4%
now means that with every year that
passes,
Italy will become less solvent.
That is,
it will be even less able to pay off its
debts.
So do you know what came of this
dialogue between the new euro skeptic
governments in Brussels?
Well,
since just on says new governments
orientation was exposed,
the 10 year Italian bonds profitability
sorted by more than 90% that is
investors now understand that there's a
very high risk and therefore they
require a higher profitability if
they're going to lend them money.
Obviously this means that every time the
Italian government issues debt,
it has to include higher interest.
Cleans that up to the year 2020 it's
only we'll have to face debt maturities
of almost $600 billion and a balance.
Of course it'll have to request again
from the markets along with the deficits
that it has accumulated.
Until then,
this amounts to more than $700 billion,
which is an insane number.
Well,
it hit investors ask for more
profitability.
Interests will be higher and so will the
public deficits and if in addition,
the European central bank stops buying
debt,
it could mean even higher interest rates
to the point that this spiral cup at the
Italian government's on the ropes and
then its banks as fault,
they own a good part of it are these dat
also.
It doesn't really seem likely that they
will be able to withstand a new
recession.
Italy's banks stumble into a new crisis
and of course that's not all Italy is
Greece.
It's huge size cause me the spread of
that financial crisis throughout the
entire euro zone.
That's why the new Italian government's
policies have led to so much concern.
Italy is a time on the could simply
explode at any moment.
That's why it doesn't seem likely that
the European Central,
we'll stop funding the party.
The only reason Italy isn't already
rated junk is because the readings
agencies assume the ECB will step in to
prevent a default.
In that sense,
Italian bonds are actually German bonds.
John Rubino.
The question now is,
well,
how long can the situation last,
but now that we know what's happening,
the question that remains is how did we
get to this point?
Well,
listen,
origin of the problem,
awesome.
Long ago we dedicated to video to you
how Italy arrived at the situation.
We can basically summarize it as a lack
of competitiveness.
Yes,
Italian politicians really didn't care
about the economy while for well changed
at full speed.
Italy punished companies with extremely
high taxes and lots of regulations and
that's what all the states kept hiring
more and more officials and spending
money without really caring about the
results.
For example,
any one in five young Italians gets a
university degree or race.
That's almost half of the ovc d average
as of course,
if you aren't educating your youth and
forget about being competitive,
well,
what else can you expect?
If that weren't enough by adopting the
euro,
Italian politicians can no longer use
one of their favorite tricks,
devaluing the currency.
So this folks,
this is what explains the dark news that
we occasionally see in the media.
As you can probably see the situation,
it's all rather complicated.
And here are visual politic.
We're going to try and keep up with all
the events.
But now as your time,
do you think that the Italian government
should break with Brussels?
Well,
leave your answer in the comments below
as well as in this survey and I really
hope you enjoyed this video.
Please do pit that lightbox.
And if you did,
and don't forget to subscribe for brand
new videos.
Also,
don't forget to check it off.
Friends at the reconsider media podcast,
they provided the vocals in this episode
that we're not mine and also this
channel.
It's possible because of patron and our
patrons on that platform.
Please do consider joining them and
supporting our mission of providing
independent political coverage.
As always,
I'll see you in the day.