So somebody who is of this channel often
ask us why we're the channel called
visual politic.
We make videos about companies,
for example,
we've already talked about Amazon into
text and Tessa among many others.
Well,
we do this for two fundamental reasons.
Now,
if the first one is that we see politics
in a broad sense,
and this means that we can talk about
politics without considering economic
and social issues.
Of course I day I think we can deny the
huge influence that big companies play
on our lives.
Second
only we know that many of you love these
kinds of videos.
So we keep making them and you know,
well,
we like these kinds of videos too.
So here we are.
So in this video we're gonna have a
pretty interesting combination.
We've got the company of BMW and the
countries of Germany and China.
As we mentioned here,
a visual holistic Germany is the mother
factory of the wells.
It's the place where machines and the
things that go into the other things
that other countries produce,
manufacture
shit.
Of course,
of all of the industries,
the automobile industry is without a
doubt the most famous and also the most
peculiar,
we all know that brands like Mercedes,
BMW,
Volkswagen,
Porsche,
opal,
and Audi are all jokes because Germany
isn't any one of the largest copper
producers in the wells.
It is also considered the cradle of the
first cop.
Yes,
you heard that right?
Seen 85 a German engineer called Karl
Benz trying to place a combustion engine
into a three wheels.
Chariots.
This was known as the bend patent motor
wagon atoms.
It was able to reach an astounding
seeing.
You'd all 16 Colombo
does now
25 units were manufactured and in one of
them,
Bertha Benz,
Cole's wife needs what is considered the
first contract in history for a distance
of actually 94 kilometers,
which isn't bad.
Now that something you might be thinking
about right now,
and that's the,
well back then the were no petrol
stations.
So how exactly did Bertha Benz refuel?
Well,
she did this by buying a petroleum
derivative in pharmacies called AESOP.
That's right.
We could say that pharmacies where the
first gas stations in history,
but of course that's not the reason why
cars in Germany are quite so important.
See,
because more machines are always needed.
The automotive industry to viewer is one
of the most productive and most
capitalized so well what better place to
manufacture them than Germany,
the country of machines.
However,
despite all of this,
let's just say that in recent times the
German automotive industry as the
European automotive industry in general
hasn't been the most popular danger of
extinction.
Yeah.
In recent times that has been a
widespread feeling that the traditional
automotive industry,
and especially as we said,
European manufacturers will be the big
losers of the upcoming electric car and
autonomous car revenue.
You should
want one of those old companies when we
have fresh and innovative companies like
Tesla.
Now this is something we've actually
talked about on this channel not so long
ago,
despite never having made any money in
producing very few cars,
tesla has a market value for it is as
large as that of BMW and which is far
superior to companies such as Renno or
Persia.
So how is this possible?
Well,
as we saw basically because many
investors consider this in a few years,
Tesla will literally take over the
markets.
[inaudible] the viewer is where
questions began to arise.
We'll the electric car transition really
be that quick.
A European manufacturer is too late to
join this resolution.
Well,
I don't know what you think,
but some information at least does not
seem to support these ideas.
According to a recent study from the Ifo
Institute,
Europe owns almost half of all patents
related to the electric car leading the
world ranking and being well ahead of
countries such as Japan,
23% and the United States 18% Yvonne
Martin,
president and Chief Investment Officer
of my Guyana's value
[inaudible].
Now let's assume that Elon musk is right
and tesla managers to overcome all of
the problems that currently affects it.
For example,
the production of the model three and
thus fulfills his most ambitious
forecast managing to sell 2 million cars
in 2022 this means that he would have to
multiply his production capacity and not
to buy two or by five but by 20 in just
over four years,
one in that same year at least 110
million vehicles are expected to be
produced in the world.
[inaudible]
when we consider these strong growth of
the middle class in emerging markets,
I would actually be on a far greater
vehicle production than that,
but let's just be prudent and stick with
that number.
Out of those 110 million cost,
no more than 20% are expected to be
electric cars or even just plug in
hybrids.
So what exactly does that mean?
Well,
what it means is in the best case
scenario for Tessa would have a market
share in the industry of less than 2%
and 9% in the electric car
[inaudible].
We can say that the cards that not even
dealt yet and so that even if Tesla's
best forecasts on mass,
then we'll still be many companies in
the market.
Companies such as BMW,
he ended up here
is one of the great icons in German
industry,
robust,
luxurious,
technologically advanced cars who
doesn't want to be honest.
How about you?
In line of the past 10 years,
this brand has been the world's leader
in premium costs and the truth is that
this is pretty interesting.
He,
this company besides owning bmw also
owns mini and Rolls Royce and at the
time of publishing this video has a
market value that is very similar to
that of Tesla at about 50 billion
donuts.
This both companies have many,
many differences.
While in 2016 Elon Musk's company
managed to sell 76,000 cause while
losing $770 million,
the German company sold 2.3 6 million
calls.
And how they profit after tax of more
than $7 billion.
Okay.
All right,
so now I know what many of you are
probably thinking,
wait a minute,
Simon,
this isn't a fair competition and Tesla
is currently investing in research and
the developing new technologies.
What BMW makes the same cause they've
been making forever.
Well it isn't actually quite like that.
Let me explain.
In 2016 for example,
the gem and grief invested more than $5
billion in research and development.
Meanwhile,
tests,
his investment was funny of time,
smaller,
slightly less than $1 billion.
And of course a lot of that BMW
investment money is going to developing
electric and autonomous models w to
spend $237 million on battery cell
center.
And that's not all.
Okay,
so here's a question for you and please
do not give a listen sheet.
Which company,
BMW or Tesla do you think is going to
sell more electric cars in 2017 now,
many of you are probably batting on
Tesla right now by a lot,
right?
Well wait just a second because the
truth is that taking both electric cars
and the plug in hybrids into accounts,
both companies are actually very close.
Now.
It does look like Tesla is going to win
this race with a few weeks left in 2017
but it's seriously close.
In fact,
both companies are expected to close
2017 sales with approximately a hundred
thousand electric cars.
Salt,
yes.
Okay,
so I'm sure some of you are going to
argue,
but Tesla has stored a lot of it's model
three cars,
which in principle translates into sales
for the next few years.
Model three will be new territory for
CEO,
Elon Musk and Tesla as a company.
The sedan has already received at least
400,000 preorders.
That is true,
but the German brand also hopes to
improve it.
Yeah,
it's numbers in short,
short,
as we always say here,
a visual politic.
The future is by definition I'm Satin
Tesla.
It could be a great company,
but it's not going to be the only one.
The truth is the by selling almost as
many electric cars is Tesla by investing
five times more in r and d and by owning
a cumulative profit of more than $30
billion in the last five years,
I think we can say that BMW is at least
a very important competitor.
In fact,
it is surprising that both company's
market value is practically the same
considering that expectations for one so
much higher than they offer the other.
This is especially when we consider that
in recent years,
BMW has become a major and very
important player in the Chinese market.
Okay,
great.
Chinese market
since
2007 and despite the international
economic crisis,
the BMW group has managed in less than
10 years to increase the number of cars
it's making from 1.5 million in 2007 to
2.3 7 million in 2016 and of course that
translates into more income and also
mop.
BMW is nets benefits.
That is the money that's left for the
company after taxes has more than
doubled in this period of time.
Check out this graph,
that graph,
we could see that things have gone
rather wealthy
company.
One of the pieces that has greatly aided
this progress is actually China.
Take a look at how the market has it.
And then 16 I managed to sell half a
million cars out of which 300 thousands
were manufactured in China itself
through a partnership with a local
company and 200,000 were importers,
mostly from factories that the company
has in Germany.
Other way
it's one out of every four cars sold by
the BMW group is already in China.
Uh,
markets where the automobile out will
surge in the upcoming years along with
its middle class.
Well,
the fact is the,
beyond any comparison with Tesla,
BMW is Chinese adventure shows us a
couple of things.
The first is that far from what is
usually said,
China could be a great source of
opportunities and wealth.
It's something which incidentally we've
been mentioning all the visual politic
for quite a lot
time.
Yeah.
18 million Chinese people join the
middle class and this has very clear,
obvious consequences on their ability to
Spanish.
Secondly,
it is very common to hear politicians of
all backgrounds arguing,
but in order to export more,
the currency needs to be devalued.
Well,
Germany in fact,
they say quite the opposite.
What is required isn't a cheap currency.
It's competitiveness and a good product.
Yup.
That is something we are going to talk
about another time and now it's your
turn.
If you have to choose which company
would you bet on?
Would it be tesla or would it be bmw at
the end of the day?
As we've seen both having very similar
market value.
So please do leave your answer in the
comments section as well as in this
survey and I really hope you enjoyed the
video.
Please hit that like button if you did
and do not forget to subscribe to our
channel for brand new videos every
Monday and Thursday and also checking
our friends at the reconsider media
podcast.
They provided the vocals in this
episode,
but we're not mine and as always,
thank you for watching.