Japan a country that brags about two
things.
The first is the used underwear vending
machines,
which yes,
you really can find on the streets,
and the second is the immigration rates,
which is by far the lowest in the
developed world for comparison in the
United States.
The immigrant population is about 14
percent.
Canada and New Zealand's have 20 and 25
percent respectively.
And then this Japan with an immigration
population of less than two percent.
What's the reason for this?
Well,
quite simply it's they're very
restrictive immigration system.
This makes Japan something of a dream
country for politicians like Donald
Trump or marine le pen.
If there is one word that could define
the current political debate,
that word would be immigration.
In Europe,
countries are arguing about what to do
with refugees and it seems the
politicians across the board seemed to
think that immigration is a problem that
needs to be stopped.
Immigration has fallen under this
government and we've cut net migration
by a third.
Anyone who illegally crosses the border
will be detained until they are removed
out of our country and back to the
country from which they came.
Since I took office,
we've deployed more border agents and
technology to our southern border than
ever before,
so then Japan is a perfect example of
what our country would look like without
really many immigrants at all,
and so now you might be wondering what
exactly does that mean for Japan's
economy?
Do they really save money because they
don't have to spend on social policies
for immigrants further deep Japanese
work as enjoy a higher standard of life
because they don't have to compete for
jobs with foreign workers.
Hands on this episode of visual politics
going to be answering those questions.
Before we get into all of that,
we need to have a close look at Japan's
immigration law.
Yeah,
country one culture,
one race.
This statement was said by the man who
was the prime minister of Japan in the
mid 19 eighties.
Viceman was Yasuhiro Naca.
The Statesman's clearly summarizes the
immigration policy of Japan.
Basically there are two ways to get into
the land of the rising sun.
One is where they work contracts and the
other is with a tourist visa.
If a company wants to hire you from
overseas,
you will need a work visa and the only
possible way that you can get that visa
is do you have a university degree or
have some specific skills that are
practically impossible to find in the
Japanese labor markets,
so if you are just to construction
worker,
you are never going to get a work permit
for Japan.
That is,
unless you use this other program
on Japan,
didn't have a lot to accept workers from
other Asian countries like Vietnam or
Philippines.
They graded the so called technical
internal training program.
This in summary is sort of like being an
intern in Japan,
except you get about half the salary.
There's a Japanese in turn would get not
only that,
but with this technical internal
training program,
your boss has even allowed to hold onto
your passport and access your bank
accounts.
More worryingly than that.
Since they started this program,
thousands of Asian immigrants have
simply disappeared.
For
when the Union Representative I spoke
with me,
she said that my attitude was bad and
that if I continue to have this heavy
dude,
if my actions continued her friend,
we'll hire a hitman to kill channel.
So well,
what if you ended up with a tourist
visa?
Well,
in that case you can stand the country
for a year and a half as long as you can
prove that you are studying Japanese.
Once that initial time has passed,
you need to get hired by a company.
This could lead to you getting a work
visa,
but do watch out here because unlike in
the United States or certain European
countries,
this work visa stipulates what your
profession is.
So for example,
if you get that work visa saying that
you are a chef,
then you could only work in a
restaurant.
If you break this rule and do some sort
of other work,
then the government will not renew your
visa.
There is only one really effective way
for a foreign.
So you make a living in Japan,
the most part thing to get the was like
the easiest thing to live here is
marrying a Japanese person.
Now I heard you can understand why in a
country with over 127 million
inhabitants,
I need 2 million of them are immigrants,
but what consequences does this have on
the daily lives of Japanese citizens?
He's a Japanese pensions.
Japan is the oldest country in the
world,
not because of that long history,
but because of the actual physical age
of their population.
In fact estimation save.
It's in the next 90 years,
they're going to lose about 44 million
people from their population,
which is about the entire population of
Canada and now this wouldn't be a
problem if it wasn't for these social
security system.
As you probably know the pen.
As you know,
the pension system in most countries in
the world works in the following way.
The people who are working today are the
ones who are paying the pensions of the
people who are retired today.
As the workforce gets smaller and
smaller night,
year after year,
the number of people paying those
pensions is getting smaller.
Further on the other side of things,
more and more people are retiring who
are drawing more ends,
more social security,
and this leads to problems like this.
Yes,
social security contributions cover only
60 percent of these benefits,
the remaining 40 trillion jen comes from
taxes or more precisely public deficits
way.
The music you're hearing in this video
is from the Spanish band Mescalina if
you like it and want to check out more
of their stuff and do you look in the
description box?
Why pay attention to this mosque?
Japan has the highest public debt of any
country in the world.
Their current debt level is more than
double the GDP and to their fiscal
deficits.
The difference between the income and
this spending is higher than the one in
the United States.
In other words,
if Angela Merkel where to go to Japan,
she had probably get very,
very angry.
So like now you might be wondering,
well,
what does all of this have to do with
integration?
Well,
the answer is a lot.
You see,
we've all heard about how expensive it
is to integrate immigrants.
You have to pay for social programs,
integration courses,
etc. Etc.
But no onE really talks about how much
are you native citizens costs.
Yup.
For an example,
an american Born citizen costs the
government $150,000 by the time age 16,
and this is only for education and
health care depending on the state that
that person lives in.
You minds have to add in other expenses,
but the government sees all of this as
an investment because when that person
stops paying taxes,
they're going to get that money back.
On the other hand,
let's take an example of a vietnamese
immigrants to Japan.
He comes to the country when he is old
enough to start whacking his education
and healthcare was already paid for by
the vehicle average of two years.
That'd be in the knees.
Immigrants is going to find a job.
Now,
of course,
that might be a low page one and you
might pay just a little tax,
but the japanese government didn't have
to invest any money in,
so in other words,
immigrant,
so free cash,
but the government,
since Japan has so few immigrants,
they are losing out on this easy influx
of cash.
this is why in the middle of a fiscal
crisis in 2015,
the japanese prime minister shinzo are.
They made the following amount under
pressure to accept more immigrants as
workforce shrinks.
But despite what it looks like,
this is not japan's biggest problem.
Japan has seen the last 20 years go by
with no economic growth.
This is what experts have goals the last
decades and it has a lot to do with
immigration as well.
Create that.
It stopped innovating.
We all want to enter in Japan as a
country of technology and innovation.
The country where companies like
nintendo,
sony,
toshiba,
where they will
on line.
So the reality is these companies are
really old.
Nintendo was founded in 18,
89,
and so I always said it was created in
1937.
Actually.
Can anybody name any japanese companies
that were created in the 21st century?
You probably couldn't,
but on the other hand,
you could probably name five to 10
american companies that were formed
during the same.
It started at 52 percent of all new
silicon valley companies between 1995
and 2005.
The entrepreneurial rates among
immigrant populations is two to three
times higher than natives,
and this is a trend that you find in
every country.
For instance,
one of the founders of google,
sanjay brinn was born in moscow.
The cofounder of whatsapp was born in.
Yeah,
just about silicon valley startups.
Just take a walk around your
neighborhood and you'll see hundreds of
chinese doors,
mexican restaurants,
and all other kinds of small businesses
created by immigrants and it does make
complete sense that immigrants will have
an entrepreneurial spirit.
At the end of the day,
though,
you seem leave their home country on
risk takers.
Not only that,
immigrants bring with them their culture
to a new country,
which helps them.
In thinking outside of the.
Let's take a look.
There's another example.
Charles feldman was a german immigrants.
Do New York city in the 19th century.
Soon he realized that the work is in the
city,
needed some sort of food that can be
cooked and sold on the streets,
but that's when he decided to import
sausages from his home country and
that's when the hot dog was born.
TodaY this meal feeds millions of people
from all around the planets and this.
This is just one example.
There are thousands upon thousands more
in short,
when cultures mixed new ideas and
methodologies are created.
This is what business people call
innovation and this.
This is the special sauce that makes
companies and countries
well,
what's going on in Japan?
I'm surprisingly,
Japan has the lowest entrepreneurial
rate in the developed world.
Just seven percent oF the population
decides to start a business by
comparison and countries like Canada and
New Zealand.
That percentage is about 10 percent.
The japanese dream isn't to start your
own business.
It's to get hot by one that already
exists.
You know those big companies that we
previously mentioned,
like sony and sheba,
companies that have the same corporate
and work structure that they had in the
19 eighties traditional japanese
electronic power houses such as sharp
and sony having kurt huge losses and
shed thousands of jobs,
well competitors,
apple and sAmsung have continued to
increase their market shares,
lazy like football or what american
schools soccer like keep up with the
world cup or the us championships.
Twenty years ago there were at least two
japanese companies sponsoring these
events in 2016.
The european cup had no japanese
sponsors and no matter where you look,
japanese companies are struggling to
compete with the european american
indian,
chinese companies,
and the reason is not a lack of money.
It's a lack of innovation.
And this explains why japan's economy
has been so frozen over the last few
days.
This is having a major impact on the
millions of Japan citizens in order to
keep productivity up.
Japanese workers have the longest
working hours and the shortest holidays
of any developed nation.
Meanwhile,
they still have the same salaries that
the pattern.
So that is our opinion here,
a visual politic,
and now we would love to know yours.
Do you think Japan should open its doors
to immigrants or do you think other
countries should follow japan's example
and close their doors to immigrants?
Use the comment section below to let us
know.
Also,
if you enjoyed this video,
please do give us a thumbs up below.
And don't forget to subscribe for brand
new videos every monday and thursday.
And I'll see you next time
for.