Francis,
probably the only country that makes the
Americans look humble.
The Ego of the French is so colossal
that it doesn't even fit within its own
country's borders,
which explains why the French spends the
19th century colonizing other countries.
Almost half of Africa was a French
colony as I bet you could probably guess
now.
The most widely spoken language in
Subsaharan Africa.
Yep.
That would be French,
but not only that,
you will probably heard that Latin
America is the United States,
his back yard rice.
Well,
we could say the Africa is kind of like
the backyard of the French.
For example,
in 2011,
France led every military operation
against Gaddafi.
Francois Salons,
government sent troops to defend the
president of the Central African
Republic.
While at the same time,
French soldiers were also fighting
Islamic terrorists in Mali.
Basically,
the French army has been present in
virtually every African armed conflict
prompts even actually controls the
currency that many African countries
use.
In other words,
even though African countries gained
independence from from decades ago,
it still maintains a strong influence on
their governments.
You can call it soft power,
you can call it diplomacy.
Oh,
you could simply call it colonialism.
Two point nine,
and I probably know what many of you are
thinking right now.
France has got to be getting rich off.
It's two point.
Oh,
African colonies,
right?
Well actually nothing could be further
from the truth.
Yeah.
The last 10 years,
for instance,
trade with Africa has dropped from 10 to
four point seven percent
had that right.
Even though from dominates African
politics,
its economy is an entirely different
story.
In fact,
often centuries of colonialism and
neocolonialism African countries have
barely evolved.
Hardly any new companies have emerged
due to French investments and meanwhile
francis spending billions of euros every
year to maintain its influence over the
continent even though ultimately it
barely gets any benefit at all.
Bus.
I,
as you can guess who's reaping all of
the benefits from this collaboration
with Africa?
Yep,
of course.
We will be talking about China.
Companies and Africa need each other
like never before.
For the last 10 years,
Chinese investment has changed the
skyline of almost all African cities.
Some countries like Ethiopia,
at becoming industrial powers,
especially in the textile sac,
sac,
Chinese companies aren't only taking
advantage of the cheap labor,
they've also found a new market to sell
that product to.
Chinese mobiles are sweeping across
Africa and is more and more people are
learning Chinese.
In other words,
while France sends soldiers,
China sends businessmen and it looks
like it's actually working out pretty
well for them.
So the question remains,
why is France failed to capitalize on
its influence in Africa and what can the
new French President Emmanuel macron do
to improve the situation today?
Well,
we're going to answer this question,
but before we do,
let's take a look at the history.
Disadvantages of paternalism.
Those of you who've been following
visual politic for awhile know that
after World War Two,
every African country became independent
from its colonizers.
Make no mistake,
not every colonizer behave the same way.
For example,
Spain had two colonies in Africa,
Sahara and Equatorial Guinea.
So when these new countries decided to
become independent,
the Spanish government's reaction was
pretty much weight.
We have colonies in Africa and then they
pretty much just let them go because
they had enough to worry about back
home.
Something similar happens with they
invaded Ethiopia during miscellaneous
time and weren't in a position to resist
any decolonization.
However,
from sue was very different,
so at that time the French president was
this guy,
Charles,
to goal to goal was how can we define
it?
He was kind of Donald Trump,
but a little bit more politically smart.
CanNot Be France without its greatness.
Charleston
cool.
Now on the one hand,
Charles de Gaulle had pretty much no
choice but to allow its African colonies
to become independence.
Maintaining colonies is really expensive
and from Santa focus on rebuilding
itself,
but as you can imagine,
a government with so much ego wasn't
going to give up.
It's old possessions from skeptics.
Ami in all of its former colonies.
Sands from the Elysee Palace decided to
support everyone of the political elites
that had begun governing these new
African countries.
For example,
in 1964,
the French army,
it's supported acu in Gabon.
Since then,
the country was governed by Oma bongos.
Dictatorship.
For more than 40 years and you supplied
all the weapons,
well of course it would be France and
resigned and gambling and follows French
foreign policy to the and is its main
uranium supplier.
As you probably know,
France is one of the countries with the
most nuclear power plants in the whole
world.
Well,
the Uranian they use it comes almost
entirely from gambling and of course
they get it at a favorable price.
Gabon was out.
France is like a car without a driver.
France without Gabon is like a car with
no fuel,
well more Bunco,
president of Gabon for 42 years
and the same goes for other countries
such as the Ivory Coast who's president
was also placed by France in 2011.
The previous presidents left the palace
under cannon shots and guests.
He was pulling the trigger of those
canons.
Well,
yes,
it would be French soldiers and
resigned.
The Ivory Coast is Francis made coffee
and cocoa supplier.
French influence in the region is so
complete.
There's even the currency they use is
controlled by froms,
so called CFA franc is the currency
being used in 15 of west African
countries such as Mali,
Burkina Faso and Ivory Coast,
and it turns out that the central bank
that issues this currency is required to
keep at least half of its foreign
currency reserves in the French treasury
and since its creation,
the CFA franc has been linked to the
French currency.
He used to be the French franc and now
it's the euro.
This means that when the euro rises or
falls,
the CFA franc follow.
Wait a moment because there's some fine
print here and now find brands is the
productive economy.
In other words,
France has been running,
it's former colonies policies for
decades,
but these countries have remained just
as poor as when they were independence
with the exception of the Ivory Coast.
The French influenced countries in
Africa tend to have underdeveloped
agricultural and virtually stagnant
economies.
No French company has bothered to open
factories in Africa and the money that
came from the Elisa was invested in
weapons or extracting natural resources
after all who wants to do business in
Africa?
Well,
you probably already know the answer to
that.
China,
Africa,
we've told you a thousand times.
Aaron Fisher,
politic.
China is Africa's main trading.
These China grew economically like
there's no tomorrow and when one starts
grabbing one needs resources.
So far,
nothing new because unlike France or
many other Western power,
China realize that Africa was more than
mines and oil fields.
I believe Africa is going to become the
next manufacturer.
Flow,
photo work and poverty will not be a
destiny and millions of people you
Africa will escape poverty.
Thank you all.
The woman you just heard is Helen.
Hi.
And she's a Chinese businesswoman.
That company is Gian and it makes shoes
for big brands.
If you have gas or Calvin Klein shoes,
it's very likely that they were made by
this company and I bet you can't guess
where it's biggest factor is.
Well,
it's actually located not in China,
but in Addis Ababa.
Ethiopia is capital.
Let me
think about it.
In the nineties,
China was the Mecca of cheap labor,
every large American or European
company,
which that of its factories in cities
such as Shenzhen or Guangzhou,
so,
but as the country grew salaries group
two,
and it's by the year 2011,
Helen,
hi.
Realized that if she wanted to cut costs
in terms of salaries,
she needed to find another country and
that country was Ethiopia once more.
Helen,
hi.
Wasn't traveling alone.
She had the Chinese government support
which address the Ethiopian political
elites and told them,
look guys,
if you just let us do things our way,
we can cover the country with factories,
with money,
jobs,
and as we often say,
visual politic as it will said.
So it was done.
Industrial Park is already operational
and Ethiopia wants it to become a
manufacturing hub,
but we're not just talking about
Ethiopia here.
There are Chinese factories in many
other countries twice.
It is a company that manufactures
ceramic tiles and it's main plant is on
the outskirts of Nairobi in Kenya,
and we can also find new industrial
parks and other countries like Ghana.
Even though Chinese companies are
supported by the governments,
we're mostly talking about private
investments here and I probably can
guess what you're thinking right now
that these companies are making cheap
things so they can sell them.
So rich countries,
Rice.
Well actually not really.
For example,
Star Times is a company in Tanzania made
with Chinese capital and it provides
cable television since they reached the
market.
Cable TV prices have dropped by 95.
Thanks.
That more than $10 million Africans can
enjoy a service.
That was a luxury and the same is going
on with telecom.
Companies like Huawei have flooded the
market with cheap mobile phones.
In fact,
nowadays the same amount of Kenyans use
mobile phones as Europeans and of course
to connect all these industrial centers,
the Chinese government has spared no
expense.
Do you?
To the new Silk Road we talked about
previously,
the so called one belt,
one road project that Xi Jinping
launched.
Well,
the same thing is happening in Africa
and we're talking about thousands of
kilometers of railroads and roads that
have changed the landscape of several
areas of the continent.
In other words,
unlike France,
China hasn't tried to colonize Africa,
but instead has turns them into business
partners and thanks to that they have
managed and more money and more
influence.
Fucious institutes are raising
generations of pro Chinese mandarin
speakers throughout Africa and now
you're wondering,
well,
what conference do about this?
Are they just going to sit by while
China and gulfs the market?
Well,
we'll see common interests.
It probably won't surprise you to learn
that a large number of African countries
aren't exactly legal safety paradises
that have a lot of respect for the law.
We're often talking about dictatorships
out.
Others,
I'll simply failed states that can
barely contain the fights of various
tribes.
That means setting up a factory in a
country like Gavin is much more
complicated than setting one up.
For example,
in a place like the United States,
it isn't
enough to buy land and get a permit.
You need to have government contracts.
That means in these cases,
diplomacy plays a fundamental role.
Or in the how I told you that froms
controls its former colonies governments
with an iron fist.
Well,
you can imagine the rest of the story.
Yeah.
French companies must go on the
offensive and fight to the growing
influence of rival China for a stake in
Africa's increasingly competitive
markets.
For instance,
minister pro Muscovy chief said on
Saturday,
as you can imagine,
if France doesn't want China to invest
in its former colonies,
it has enough tools to prevent it and
that's why Chinese money has banny
reached these countries.
Of course Beijing has paid for some
projects in countries like the Ivory
Coast and Ghana,
and there's little in comparison to
Ethiopia or Kenya.
However,
things could start to change.
The new French President Emmanuel Macron
has promised to turn the African
situation around and it looks like it's
already started.
Revives Francis Partnership with China
in Africa.
As mccrone said at the press conference,
China has the money and we have the
knowledge of the region.
In other words,
France would be willing to allow the
African politicians they control except
Chinese investments in return that
require a piece of the pie.
Of course,
this news is from January 2018,
so there's still a lot to do before we
can see how this agreement turns out.
So now the question becomes,
do you think France will change its
policy,
consenting Africa and started treating
its former colonies?
Is trading partners or will they just
continue to exchange nice sweats?
Well,
leave your answer in the comments
section below.
Meanwhile,
if you want to know how Africa is
leaving poverty behind,
please do click on this other video and
don't forget to visit our friends at
reconsider immediate.
I'll call them.
They provided the vocals in this episode
that we're not mine and remember that we
published brand new videos every week,
so hit that subscribe button and you
won't miss a single post.
Also,
if you like this video,
give us thumbs up.
As always.
I'll see you next time
and if you want to learn more about
politics and hear even more of my love,
the course,
you can join us at reconsider media.
We have a podcast@reconsideredmedia.com
slash podcast.