In September of 2017,
Puerto Rico suffered it's most
significant natural disaster in the last
100 years.
The impacts of Hurricane Maria,
a huge category for cycling a category
five at its strongest with wind gusts of
over 155 miles per hour and torrential
rain wreaks havoc on this islands.
The destruction,
it was enormous.
Thousands of houses were destroyed in
the entire Puerto Rican electricity
network collapsed.
The islands was quite literally engulfed
in darkness.
As you can imagine,
the economic damage was enormous.
To give you an idea today,
the reconstruction costs have risen to
around $100,000,000,000 and that's not
at all.
Seven months later,
thousands of businesses remain closed
and blackouts,
I'll still quite frequent.
However,
if you are just wasting because
Hurricane Maria,
myself,
the whole story,
he says that the island's problems began
a really long time ago.
Pressing Rico,
they've been suffering a severe economic
crisis and the population exodus for
more than 10 years and exit is so great
that it threatens the island's very
survival.
See officer declaring bankruptcy in May
of 2017.
The situation has become so critical
that the islands government is
considering moving thousands of
prisoners do private prisons in the
United States,
so why is this?
Well,
the islands government is even having
problems with financing it's own
penitentiary system and renting spots in
places like Texas or Florida is actually
proving to be.
Yeah.
Now,
hold on just a moment here.
I mean prisoners to the United States.
It sounds kind of weird,
but you absolutely heard it right.
Do not forget the Puerto Rico is a part
of the United States.
It's not a state,
but it's kind of a free associated
state.
When we left,
when we also love Puerto Rico,
it has to back and
of course by being a part of the United
States,
having a tropical climate,
a rich history,
and it's beautiful white sand beaches on
which by the way,
Captain Jack Sparrow had some of his
most famous exploits.
We might think that Puerto Rico has
everything required to be one of the
most prosperous places in the world.
Well,
the reality is not so much.
The truth is rarely rather difference.
Here's a question for you.
Where do you think most Puerto Rican
slip?
I mean it sounds like a bit of a silly
question,
but it isn't because the answer,
it's not Puerto Rico.
The escape.
Yes,
but first Puerto Rico may look like a
paradise.
Good weather,
beautiful beaches,
wonderful music.
However,
the island has a huge problem.
Every year.
Thousands and thousands of Puerto Rican
leave the islands.
See Puerto Rican been US citizens since
1917.
They are Americans and they can move
freely around that country.
Well,
according to data from the Pew Research
Center,
during the last decades,
more than 500,000 Puerto Ricans have
left Puerto Rico to move to the
consonants,
to places like Texas,
Florida and New York and Pennsylvania.
Half a million people isn't absolutely
huge number for an island that has just
over 3 million inhabitants seen in
another way.
Not only in the last 10 years,
one of every seven inhabitants has left
Puerto Rico.
Rather.
The question I just asked,
why do you think most pressure eakins
lived?
While the answer is that since 2006,
there are more Puerto Ricans living in
the continental United States than there
are on the island specifically more than
5 million compared to just over three.
We were watching a real live demographic
and population collapse on a monumental
scale.
Limestone and independent migration
researcher and economist at the US
Agriculture Department and things,
well,
they could get much,
much worse,
but the islands are in government expect
just in 2018 for another 200,000 people
to leave the islands.
This means that Puerto Rico will lose
about six percent of its population in a
single year.
Sorry
if you thought this process,
this accident was already severe.
Well,
the consequences of Hurricane Maria,
they found the accelerated as different
estimates,
both from the governments and from
private consultants expect another half
million Puerto Rican to pack their bags
and move to the consonants in the next
five years.
I'm very attached to my island and my
preference is to stay here,
but I have to think about what's best
for my son,
Victor Domingo's,
a 39 year old mortgage banker to the
Washington Post.
As you may imagine,
Centra flights.
We'll have very serious consequences for
the island,
especially because most of those who are
leaving a young infants,
it is estimated that half of all
immigrants,
of all people who leave the islands are
under 24 years of age,
so what's the result of all of this?
Well,
in the next decade,
Puerto Rico is population will decrease
to two point 5 million people.
That is to say in the next decade,
Puerto Rico will lose 800,000
inhabitants,
25 percent of its population,
and if another natural disaster,
another hurricane,
for example,
the cars or if the island fails to
recover from the severe crisis that's
going through the reality,
it could be even worse.
I mean,
can you imagine what this will mean for
the island's economy?
Who's going to pay?
It's huge debt.
Who's going to pay for its pension?
Well,
I think at this point in the video we
need to ask a question,
why does so many Puerto Ricans leave the
islands?
These statistics seem to be similar to
that of a country going through a war.
So what's going on?
Well,
listen to this very long crisis.
If we take a look at the data,
the explanation seems very clear.
Almost half of Puerto Rican is living on
the islands are considered poor by US
standards.
The average family income is $20,000,
which is slightly less than half of the
average income of Mississippi.
The poorest state in the continental
United States.
Yes.
Well that's not all the islands.
Government is bankrupt and it is a huge
public desk.
Seventy dollars,
billion dollars and another
$50,000,000,000 in payment commitments.
Like for example,
it's pensions or we're talking about an
islands of just over 3 million
inhabitants.
So that's really an insane amounts of
money.
It means that an average family would
have to devote six years of their salary
to pay off the public debt.
So now you might be able to understand
why Puerto Rico is known as the grease
of the Caribbean,
and if you think this is the worst of
it,
when you're absolutely right,
is that there's hardly any work in
Puerto Rico.
In fact,
the island has the lowest activity rates
in the United States.
Only four out of every 10 adults
actively looking for work.
And if we don't come with the people who
don't have a job in the public sector,
who salaries come out.
So if the taxes,
the people who work in the private
sector provide the results,
it's pretty alarming.
Less than a quarter of the island's
inhabitants work in the private sector.
Bye.
Wait,
one of Puerto Rico's great problems is
precisely this.
Public employees and officials see
almost one out of every four jobs on the
island corresponds to the governments.
And that's not the worst part.
Did you know that many of these public
employees have the right to retire at
the age of 50,
which is 15 years earlier than in the
rest of the United States.
And if you want things to get even more
terrifying,
you can also keep in mind is that given
the high percentage of young people
leaving,
the island's population is aging very,
very quickly.
In other words,
if things don't change,
Puerto Rico will enter a very,
very difficult situation.
But okay.
I'm sure at this point in the video
you're wondering,
well,
how on earth can the island get out of
this mess?
Is that really a way out for Puerto
Rico?
Well,
that's how it look
how to get out of this.
It's often
said that those who don't learn from
history are condemned to repeat it,
and indeed this might happen in Puerto
Rico when we talk about how local
politicians see the future,
we find some good things,
but also some not so good things.
Puerto Rico has gone bankrupt.
That's the facts.
And if they continue like this,
the government could push the islands
into the abyss.
So for one public spending has to be
cost.
They have to stop the drainage.
That has caused such a huge amount of
public
debt.
Principal,
the new government,
Ricardo Rosales is working on this.
In fact,
he's committed to decreasing the
government's size by a lot.
The volume is how he wants to do it,
isn't exactly clear indeed is not really
clear if there's a real political will
to correct the islands.
Massive problem.
The Puerto Rico has to turn its economic
policy around and set some serious plans
in motion in order to attract
investments.
This is because Puerto Rico needs
decisive measures.
It needs real reforms and not just
cosmetically changes.
A few things have been done in recent
years.
For example,
they are trying to defend Puerto Rico
into what kinds of financial center,
the guarantees anonymity to
international investors work,
but there's still a really long way to
go.
Now,
before we end today's video,
we still have to ask a very important
question.
How on Earth did Puerto Rico get to this
point?
Well,
one reason was that local government
spent huge amounts of money to hire us.
We saw many public workers and to fund
expensive projects that didn't give the
island anything other than more
debt.
Reason has a lot to do with influence
from the United States,
but that's something we're going to tell
you about in an upcoming video.
For now,
it's your turn because I want to ask a
question of you.
Do you think the pressure Rico should
continue to belong to the United States?
So do you think they should seek to
become an independent country?
Well,
you can leave your answer in the
comments below as well as in this day,
and I really hope you enjoyed that
video.
Please do hit like if you did and don't
forget to subscribe to our channel for
brand new videos every Monday and
Thursday.
Also,
don't forget to check out our friends at
the reconsider media podcasts.
They provided the vocals in this episode
that we're not mine,
and as always,
thank you for watching
what we left with.