Right,
lights,
slot machines,
poker,
blackjack,
all of all mine,
so probably interests traveled to
London,
Vegas,
sin.
It's the place that everyone thinks of
when they think of gambling as well.
That's because it's the world's capital
of gambling,
right?
Well,
actually it is not because the world's
leading capital of gambling is by no
means Las Vegas.
It's Macau.
Macau is an autonomous city located in
the south of China,
very close to Hong Kong.
In fact,
it's so close to Hong Kong,
but the fastest way to get to Macau from
Hong Kong is by a fast ferry.
It takes about an hour.
Macau is a very curious city.
On the one hand,
it's a small slice of Portugal inside
the very chaotic Asian southwest.
On the other hand,
it's place where skyscrapers and bowls,
modern architecture of very easy to do
fine
landscape is dominated by an enormous
skyscraper skyscraper with colorful
crystals in the sheep of Lotus flowers.
This building is the Grand Lisboa.
Above all,
the Macau is something of a messy city.
It's all rather ramshackle and full of
tiny little street
was the last colonial European city in
Asia and it remained a colonial city
until very recent times for centuries.
It was a part of Portugal that was until
the end of 1999 when it was finally
integrated with China.
At this point it was set up in China as
a special administrative region.
This essentially allows for the one
country,
but two systems set up these two cities,
Macau and Hong Kong,
even though they are a part of China,
keep their own legislation with certain
limitations and they also have their own
customs caught currency and political
institutions.
In practical terms,
they really work as if they are a
different country from China.
Interestingly in Macau,
Portuguese is still an official language
which normally an issue.
Ilene with Zoe and we will give the MCO.
Well really mcconnell could be more
considered a gambling theme part rather
than a city.
Every year Macau receives over 30
million tourists.
This makes this tiny piece of land is
one of the most visited places in the
world.
So why is this?
You might be asking.
Well,
that's because it's the only place in
the whole of China where gambling is
permitted.
Thanks this,
since there's integration with China or
up until 2014,
the region has enjoyed one of the
fastest periods of economic growth in
history.
In a little over 10 years,
GDP has multiplied by 10 going from
$5,000,000,000
to 55 billion.
Now.
There was a very key moments in this
growth phase and that was when mccowen
gave the gambling free reign.
It was at this very moment so that huge
multinational gambling companies moved
in to establish themselves in Macau and
this changed the identity forever.
There's something about the Asian
culture where gaming is acceptable as a
form of entertainment and so that is a
major driver of the success I think that
you've seen here and clearly in
Singapore today.
The city is known as Chinese last Vegas
for its high concentration of casinos at
dear view is about is something of a
ridiculous name because gambling in
Macau is a way,
way bigger deal than in Las Vegas.
In the cows.
Forty plus casinos in 2015.
Over $29,000,000,000
was invoiced,
which for some perspective is five times
that of last year,
Vegas
in 2013,
it reached the astonishing amount of
$45,000,000,000,
which for a comparison is almost the
same as the entire amounts of money that
franz receives from its entire tourism
industry.
It really is pretty amazing gambling
lights.
Luxury shops,
sends well still more lights.
That is Macau's,
new identity.
My cows casinos
now on every time you think of gambling,
do not think of a Monte Carlo or Las
Vegas,
but do think of Macau and there is
absolutely no slowing down.
Three new mega casinos.
The result of multimillion dollar
investments that have opened in the last
12 months.
For example,
at the end of 2015,
these studio city development opens.
This is a huge hotel casino complex with
a Hollywood atmosphere.
Interestingly,
it's opening saw the production of a
short 15 minute film which had a
production budget of $70 million
dollars,
which is a record by the way.
The film was directed by Martin Scorsese
and had lead roles played by Robert De
Niro,
Leonardo Dicaprio,
and Brad Pitt,
which leaves us wondering what possible
hotel opening good editorial.
This part,
Lee,
in August 2016,
the wind palace opened its doors.
This is a luxurious hotel with 1,700
Greens,
which cost about four point 2 billion
USD.
You just hotel to open.
At the time of writing was the
Parisians.
This is a masterpiece created bind for
last Vegas Sands Company,
which is owned by wealthy invest.
If Sheldon Adelson.
This
hotel is essentially a city in itself
with free thousand rooms,
a waterpark and even its own half scare
life for
tower.
Oh yes.
The openings do continue.
The next opening is going to be the 13,
which is billed as the most expensive
hotel in the world.
Some of the rooms in this hotel are
going to cost between 50 and a hundred
thousand dollars night and know that is
not a mistake.
On the plus side,
guests are going to have the use of 30
rolls royces burst at the cost of 50 to
$100,000
a night.
They should probably be be giving you a
Rolls Royce along with these new hotels.
Casinos,
some of the most legendary in Macau
currently are the Galaxy Grand Lisboa,
the city of dreams,
the Venetian,
the mgm,
as well as many more.
If Mcconnell keeps this up,
the Strip in Las Vegas is soon going to
look like the work of an amateur
profit sharing in the cow more than
yeah,
80 percent of governmental income comes
from these casinos ends.
The money is so abundant that every year
Macau has a significant budget.
Surplus Mcconnell is completely
unfamiliar with the idea of a deficit,
and as you can probably imagine from
this,
taxes are rather low.
So now you might be wondering what
exactly does the government do with such
a huge surplus every year?
Well,
a part of it is invested in
infrastructure,
but an entire third of it is wait for it
paid to Macau Macau's citizens as a
dividend.
Yes.
Again,
we are not making a mistake here since
2008,
all of the city's inhabitants have
received a portion of the income from
the casinos.
For example,
in 2016,
the dividend was a thousand dollars per
citizen.
This means that for a family of four,
they are getting a check for $4,000
every single year,
which isn't exactly bad and this is not
the only benefit that the citizens get
from the casinos.
Every one in four jobs in Macau is in
the casino industry,
so low taxes,
high employment rates,
and dividends paid out from the casinos.
It all seems like a pretty sweet deal.
However,
not everything is sunshine and rainbows
and yeah,
lollipops,
crises in Macau,
most tourists,
Macau,
around two thirds coming from
continental China.
This means that the economy over the
region is highly dependent on China's,
and if that wasn't enough,
she shipping the president of China,
started a war against public work at
corruption in 2015.
After that time,
the economy of Macau collapsed.
Chinese President Xi Jinping has been
cleaning house on the mainland,
including cracking down on those.
Trying to take money out of the country
illegally and that's making some high
rollers.
Very wary about spending big in Macau
in a single year.
The gambling income over the city fell
by 40 percent.
This led to the economy of Macau losing
more than 20 percent of its GDP.
The corrupts public workers in China had
gotten use to the idea of going to
Macau.
They could easily spend their money,
do some gambling,
attended red carpet like events and
while they're there,
probably do some laundry.
Have the money for it generally,
and I decided there will be no
investigation.
Now if you'll excuse me,
I'll go away
now.
It's not as if the whole industry
depends on them,
but as in the Chinese economic slow down
and to the new controls established by
the Chinese government as many of these
vip so you used to go to Macau,
have simply stopped doing so.
Now this is going to continue for a
little while at least,
and it's causing problems from the cow
because half of their economy relies on
thanks to numerous investments,
a good state of public finance,
and is the advantage of being such an
important tourist cluster.
These social and economic effects have
been limited,
so the government's keeps a comfortable
surplus.
The unemployment rate is one point eight
percent and his family incomes have not
suffered violence.
One thing is absolutely true.
As Xi Jinping said on his last visit to
the city,
it is time for diversification and the
governments has already presented a plan
to tackle
Columbus
based on family tourism,
health,
tourism,
finance,
and the technological industry.
In the next few years,
the economy has already started to
bounce back.
If the government's plans do become a
reality,
Macau might become some sort of 21st
century Monaco in the next few years.
The city's mistake was to put all of its
eggs in one basket and not diversifying.
They didn't make it easy for companies
to form and they didn't make it easy for
outside investors to come in.
This is something that also happened in
Atlantic city with serious consequences,
but that's something we're going to be
looking at in a future video.
So what do you think about Macau?
Let us know in the comments below.
Also,
if you want to see more videos about
Asia like this one,
do you click that like button below and
don't forget to subscribe for brand new
videos every Monday and Thursday and
we'll see you next time.
But the cookbook or watching the
floorman shift forces are watching.
The casino manager was watching the
shift bosses.
I'm watching the casino manager and the
eye in the sky.
Watching yourself.