The country with the highest density of
famous musicians put our capital in the
entire world.
Ireland is a country with less than 5
million inhabitants.
Even Boston has a larger population,
but as small as the population maybe
Ireland is the cradle of well known
music like any of the cranberries,
and of course Bano for view.
See,
there is another thing that makes
Ireland's famous as well,
and that's the.
It's the second wealthiest country in
the eurozone.
Further Irish people have more money
than the British or even the Swiss,
and this is surprising given the just 30
years ago,
Ireland was as poor as Greece.
Yep.
You heard that right back then,
one in every five Irish university
students were emigrating to other
countries.
Today,
there are more people with Irish blood
living in the US or Australia than there
are in Ireland
self
nonetheless.
Now this country is home to some of the
world's leading technological companies.
Firms like apple or Google have their
tax headquarters that many of you might
be thinking now that that simply because
of the low taxes there right now,
of course it is absolutely true that
Ireland does offer good fiscal
conditions for companies,
but other countries like the Republic of
Liberia or the seashells also offer
pretty low corporate taxes and then not
even half as rich as ours.
The question here is,
what have they done to grow so fast?
How is it that even after the financial
crisis,
Ireland remains wealthier than
Switzerland?
Did I?
We're going to answer this question,
but first as usual,
we're going to take a look at the
history.
The poorest of the wealthiest
islands was born in 1922 years,
but before that the whole island was
part of the British crown.
I ended the relationship well.
It wasn't exactly great for the English
politicians.
Island was a lens of Catholic peasants
who were unwilling to work and devoted
to having lots and lots of children.
This explains why after they got their
independence,
the New Republic of Ireland is cut.
All of that ties with London.
Well,
actually it wasn't just London,
they closed off their relationships with
the rest of the world as well.
Even during World War Two,
they were the only English speaking
country that captain neutral,
but not only that,
the different Irish governments closed
their gates to international trade.
They even put a ban on foreign as owning
or investing in local companies.
So now the question is,
what was the outcome of all of these
policies?
Well,
he knows that that would be a brutal
economic crisis.
Fortunately enough,
because Irish people spoke English,
they could easily move to the United
States.
We're not talking about adventure just a
few decades.
The Irish population reduced by half,
and of course the national industry
never grew as it was expected to think
about it in such a small country,
it is impossible to find the tools and
resources needed to build factories and
machines.
There just isn't enough industry.
They needed to import them,
but because
the government put so many fairs and
barriers to foreign trade,
it was pretty hard to get the material
needed to start a new company.
This was in 1957.
The governments of Shawn Thomas Kelly
made islands town or one 80 on that
trade policy.
This is how they went from not buying
anything that's opening their gates to
the entire world.
Right after that,
they signed a free trade agreement with
the UK and a decade later they would
enter the European community,
which later came to be called the
European Union,
but hold on just a minute.
My Dad,
Libertarians,
he might be watching this video,
just hold back here and things,
the them for a moment because this
openness to free trade was not exactly
as good as expected.
Think about it.
For decades,
Ireland was closed for business.
I had nationalized many of their
companies.
When a company knows that they have no
rivals in the market,
share is guaranteed by the government.
They have very little reason to improve.
This explains,
for instance why in 1988 people in the
city of Cork,
which is in the southern part of
Ireland,
had so many electricity breakdowns and
brownouts,
they're wiring network hadn't been
replaced for decades.
The same happened in many other
industries.
All of a sudden the Irish economy
allowed people to buy goods abroad,
new products,
more competitive products.
They appeared in the market.
So now you're probably wondering what
happened to those local producers?
Well,
unsurprisingly they disappeared.
Ends with thousands of people just lost
their jobs.
In 1987 islands reached and unemployment
rate up seventeen cents.
Once again,
the Irish youth started packing up and
moving.
Yeah.
Then following visual politics for some
assignment,
you'll probably know that integration
isn't really much of a problem for our
country.
Can you guess what the real issue is?
Well,
actually it's exactly the opposite.
The migration we need to consider is who
was leaving audience,
but it was the university students and
it was those people with higher skills.
This cause what is known as a brand,
but believe me,
there's more than this in order to
attract the multinational corporations,
the government,
lower taxes,
and of course this strategy worked out
well.
Firms like Intel,
apple,
Microsoft,
they chose Ireland as the place for
their European headquarters.
So now you might be wondering why.
What's the problem with this?
This sounds great.
Well,
they essentially just opens up a tiny
office with an accountant.
This means that their contribution to
the country's wealth was actually funny.
Paul,
if
this was not enough,
the same government that put the red
carpet out the companies was also
raising income tax on it citizens.
Some people ended up paying 60 percent
in tax from their salaries,
and if this was not enough,
Irish legislation did not make it easy
to hire people.
So now considering the situation,
jobs are disappearing,
local companies are going bankrupt.
Government spending is on the rise and
thousands of Irish people just leaving
the country.
In 1988,
the Economist magazine published this.
Yeah,
of the rich.
Poor Ireland behaved as though it was
rich.
Now it must pay the price.
All right?
All right.
All right,
so that's the bad stuff covered.
Now,
how did they step out of the scenario?
Well,
let me tell you a story.
The Celtic Tiger roars.
It was the in 1987 and Charles Hall,
he had won the elections in Ireland as a
country on the edge of collapse.
Mansi realized something.
You can't open your economic system
without first modernizing it.
Of course companies like oracle or HP,
what happened to be an islands and pay
less taxes than they were paying in the
us,
but where are they willing to?
I've been a research center.
We're a factory that would employ a
thousand people we have who isn't and
why?
Well,
first they would have to deal with the
labor laws,
which were a bureaucratic nightmare.
Not only that,
what you said about the 60 percent
income tax.
This means that no matter how high the
salaries for the worker were,
a fairly large chunk of that is still
going to the governor.
Highly skilled professionals would
rather just moved to the United States.
So the first policy implemented by Jorge
was to deal with trade unions and the
company's salaries would grow at the
same rate as the economy was on the
other hands.
He lowered income taxes this way.
What has ended up making more money,
even if the wages were the same and this
soon started generating right salts.
Packard like slipped plant is to employ
2000 people by the year.
2,000
in a short amount of all of those
multinational companies that it opens
their fiscal headquarters on,
Irish soil started owning that own
factories and offices.
Meanwhile,
unemployment,
it was going down,
wages were on the rise and even the
government collected more money,
but not only that,
this deal with the unions and theocratic
simplification helped create all new
company.
Have you ever played with
Ron at both the t shirt at prime,
arc drunk and Guinness?
Well,
all of these companies expanded
internationally during those years.
This explains why the Irish economy grew
as much as the Chinese economy during
the 19 nineties suddenly addresses in
Dublin would offer champagne to their
customers.
Some people even flying to New York to
do shopping on the weekends.
These were the years of the Celtic Tiger
and at that point,
the economist decided to dedicate
another article a decade ago,
Irish and comes with less than two
thirds of British incomes.
Last year by one measure,
they had surpassed British incomes that
hold on just a moment because not
everything is so perfect.
Of course,
during those 15 years,
salaries doubles,
but that optimism drove banks to offer
mortgages to nearly is encouraged,
ridiculous spending in those years were
even companies that rented helicopters
for children to have their first
communion in the.
Yeah,
and this led to a financial crisis that
we are going to cover that in another
video.
If you don't want to miss that video,
please do not forget to subscribe to
this channel.
Meanwhile,
you might want to watch another video
where we explain why London is actually
growing faster than New York City.
You can click here to
now.
The question is,
do you think that the Irish model could
help other countries like Greece or
perhaps India?
Do you think poor countries could
benefit from attracting foreign
investments?
You can leave your arms for us in the
comments below.
We would love to read it,
and if he did like this video,
please do give us a thumbs up below and
as always I'll see you in the next one.
And if you want to learn more about
politics and hear even more of my lovely
voice,
you can join us at reconsider media.
We have a podcast@reconsidermedia.com
slash podcast.
See you there.