Doesn't seem that lately a lot of movies
have been shot in London.
One example is bridget Jones's baby,
a movie from the Bridget Jones's soccer,
which I might've seen just look at the
skyscrapers in the backgrounds of that
movie.
Those were simply not there in the first
movie of the saga.
In fact,
London skyline has changed dramatically
in the last 10 years alone,
and this is pretty surprising because
we're not talking about an emerging
economies like China or
actually
the overall economy in the UK as an all
performance that well over the last few
years.
However,
the London is another world entirely
today.
It is one of the four fastest growing
capitals on the planet almost growing at
the same level as Dubai.
Their population has increased by 50
percent in the last few decades,
particularly odd on a continental Europe
where all countries are seeing overall
population decline.
Instead,
London has 3 million more inhabitants
and not only that,
but in the finance wells,
London is now more important than New
York City itself.
So now you might be wondering what
exactly has happened in London that has
caused this massive success?
Well,
that's the question we're going to be
answering in today is visual politic
video ration.
The United Kingdom has always been a
country of immigrants and the London was
always the main destination.
Nonetheless,
in the last decade,
immigration has apps and the sky
rocketed after Poland's became a member
of the European Union in 2004.
I lots of polls easily moved from Poland
to London because there was no visa
required.
The same happens when Bulgaria,
Romania became part of the European
Union in 2007.
This created a whole new influx of
immigrants adding to those already there
from India and Pakistan.
These European immigrants typically have
higher education and university degrees.
In fact,
today in London has a one point 7
million highly skilled workers.
While New York has one point 6 million
immigrants are not only working the jobs
that British people don't want to do
anymore.
Instead they are coming to the country
and starting their own businesses or
getting hired in the high tech sector.
But Tom started his marketing business
four years after arriving from Warsaw.
He now employs six people and four of
them are British.
That's companies are far more than just
job creating machines or economic growth
engines.
The fact that London has more educated
people means more bars,
more exhibitions,
more culture.
In summary,
it has more of all the things that make
a city look cool.
For example,
well,
where's the best known Peruvian
restaurants outside of Peru?
Well,
according to all of the gastronomical
guides,
it's restaurant called civic j,
which of course is located in London.
This is how London has created a
virtuous cycle that has attracted more
and more people.
This is why in 2000 inmates,
after the financial crisis hits many
Spaniards,
Portuguese and Italians,
who wanted to leave their countries,
saw London as the main destination.
It was more than just a good place to
find a job.
It was a cool place.
The myths,
this is something that economists school
the network effect.
The more people and companies that you
have,
the easier it is to attract highly
skilled immigrants.
Today,
a new generation of coders,
bankers,
and financial wizards are remaking,
is extraordinary place.
Interestingly,
since 2010 over 1000 startups have been
created in London every single year,
but hold on a moment because there's
more.
Oh,
city of London.
All the skyscrapers that you see here
are concentrated in a single area.
This is an area and not bigger than a
square mile.
And it is known as the city of London or
just with the city?
Yes.
On the one hand we do have London and
then also on the other hand we have the
city of London.
You have London essentially works like
it's own country within the United
Kingdom.
Yes.
Now we normally say for Britain is made
up of four nations,
England,
Wales,
Scotland and Northern Ireland,
but really this is not exactly true.
In fact,
we should really add a fifth one and
this is the city of London.
The city has its own laws and has its
own
mayor.
The city is the financial center of
Great Britain.
About 7,000
people live in this city,
but each day 300,000
come to work and its banks,
brokerage firms and insurance companies.
London's mayor is the man we're showing
on the screen now.
His name is Sidique Khan,
but the city of London has its own Lord,
mayor,
and his name is Jeffrey months events.
One of the characteristics over the
city,
also known as the square mile,
is the during elections,
both citizens and companies have the
right to vote.
For example,
a Unilever has its headquarters in the
square mile.
Therefore when elections come,
Unilever is allowed to.
Okay,
so now you might be wondering,
does Unilever get the same voting power
as a smaller company?
Well,
the answer is no.
There's a number of votes a company
gets.
Depends on how many people say
employment in the city.
By the way,
the music that is accompanying this
video that you were listening to right
now is by a band called the forgotten
voice.
There a pop rock bands from to you sent
us that music to use in this video.
And if you like it and you would like to
hear more from them,
it please do.
Check out the links in the description
below.
All right,
so now you might be wondering whether
the city of London is a fiscal haven and
the answer is no.
All across the UK taxes off,
fairly similar to what is true is that
the square mile does have more business
friendly policies than the rest of the
UK,
for instance,
that the development laws are much more
free and open than the rest of the
country and this is why they're all more
skyscrapers bought when it comes to
taxes.
They are not a haven whatsoever,
but it's.
Hold on just a minute because the city
does play a really important role.
This is because the main task of the
Lord mayor is do traveled around the
world and promote London as a great
place for doing
business.
Mayor of the city of London,
Alderman Alan Yarrow is believe that
business delegation to Indonesia,
helping to make sure London and the UK
remained the regional partner of choice
when it comes to financial and
professional services.
So you went away.
You can say that London has its own
marketing departments,
showcasing all of the benefits of doing
business there to the rest of the world
business
concentration.
The US economy is divided among
different cities.
For example,
politics is centered in Washington DC.
Finance is in New York City.
Entertainment is in Los Angeles,
and technology is centered in San
Francisco.
The same happens in Germany where you
have cities like Berlin,
Frankfurt,
and Munich,
andover.
In Spain you have Barcelona,
correct.
On the other hands,
Britain has London as well,
just London.
The other larger cities are far less
important to the country's economy.
In fact,
London generates every one in five
pounds.
In the British economy.
In this city,
you will find all of the major
government institutions,
the banks,
the technological center,
the fashion center,
et Cetera.
While the amount of tax generated in
London increased by 25 percent in real
terms between 2005 and 2015,
Manchester's fax intake by only one
percent.
Well,
Birmingham,
Glasgow and leads also significant
decreases in their vaccine take and the
tool of this,
we should add another really important
element and that's English.
As you probably know,
the UK has had a rather good
relationship with the United States,
well at least for the past two
centuries,
even though there is no trade agreements
between the two countries.
They do have a lot of history in common
and importantly they speak the same
language.
List
fact that the United Kingdom
is currently a part of the European
Union and so you can see why London has
become the gateway for American
companies who want to do business in
Europe.
What London does,
it is the capital of the euro and that
means that 70 percent of forex trading
and all sorts of other over the counter
derivatives,
all sorts of fancy stuff gets done
through London.
Although the UK is not in the euro,
so there's a very difficult set of
negotiations coming up.
But now the obvious and big question is
going to be how is brexit going to
affect London's growth?
One thing is very clear and that's the.
Well,
the majority of the British population
once it the UK,
to leave the European Union,
London wasn't very much.
These are our thoughts here at visual
politic and we would love to know your
so you use the comments section below to
let us know what you think and don't
forget to thumbs up this video and
subscribe because we put our brand new
videos every Monday and every Thursday.
And as always,
if you'd like to dig deeper into this
topic,
please do check out the links in the
description below and I'll see you next
[inaudible].