I've gotten a stone is a difficult
country then many aspects,
difficult honestly doesn't really cover
it.
I've gotten a stone is a very
mountainous country.
Almost three quarters of its surface is
covered by mountains and peaks that in
many cases exceed 20,000 feet.
Cause then you can probably imagine just
how difficult communications are among
the different regions of this country as
if this was not enough.
It's also a landlocked and it's mostly
Erin's place.
In fact,
deserts are not unusual at all in
Afghanistan
stop.
So despite a few valleys,
it's national landscape is mainly
composed of red and yellow tones.
But geography is not the worst part of
this country and neither is a task.
Climate conditions not at all.
In fact,
poverty,
corruption and especially fundamentalism
and violence,
all the worst parts of this place.
Afghanistan's if you are above all as a
country.
Yeah.
1978 the sour revolution,
a communist space revolution took place
when you're later in 1979 the Soviet
army invaded the country to consolidate
the communist government
since
send the people have not known what
peace means,
but before,
to be honest,
the situation,
it wasn't really good either.
Afghanistan was his ends probably will
be for a long time,
one of the poorest countries on earth.
It's also got one of the hardest and
most hostile living conditions,
especially for women
countries.
Six out of every 10 people don't know
how to read or rice.
Almost half of its population doesn't
have access to drinking water and it's
difficult to find a single family which
hasn't been devastated by war and
violence.
We can safely say that if someone was
able to choose where they were to be
born,
no one would ever choose Afghanistan.
The last grade conflicts,
which still persists to this day,
it burst onto the global stage in
October of 2001 when the president of
the United States at the time,
George W.
Bush decided to invade.
Afghanistan has a response to nine 11 at
that time,
Afghanistan was led by the Taliban,
a radical religious political group,
which protected members of al Qaeda,
including a solid bin London
on my orders.
The United States military has begun
strikes against al Qaeda terrorist
training camps and military
installations of the Taliban regime in
Afghanistan.
The invasion,
it was fast.
The Taliban simply weren't an obstacle
for the massive American war machine.
16 years and three presidents later
though,
and it has been named by many as the
longest war in US history.
It's already longer than the war in
Vietnam.
I believe it's on,
not the u s that aren't winning that
one.
What's happening?
long years of conflict,
occupation and hundreds of billions of
dollars later,
and it would seem logical to think that
the u s and NATO could have managed to
have the situation under control and
Afghanistan would be close to reaching
peace,
right?
Well,
nothing is further from reality.
The truth is that with each day that
goes by,
the Taliban regain grounds.
Just take a look at this map from the
Washington Post.
The colored areas are the ones
controlled by the talent.
Bye.
Um,
well this map shows the situation at the
beginning of 2017 but today things are
even worse because as we just said,
the Taliban are regaining ground almost
everyday day.
Recent estimates show that the
governments of cabal us and NATO control
less than 60% of the territory and the
next map is going to show him even more
Taliban controlled and regions.
Yes,
can government controls just 57% of its
territory you s watchdog set,
but the loss of control by the Afghan
government seems nuts.
The U S it shouldn't be just seen as a
territorial losses,
but also an economic loss for example.
It's really important that we ask
ourselves,
how can the Taliban,
it finance their activity,
where do all of their resources come
from?
Well,
basically that would be from heroin
production.
As you might know,
Afghanistan is the biggest opm produce
it in the whales and this opm,
well that's the raw ingredients that is
used in heroin.
And listen,
Afghanistan is not just the world's
biggest producer.
It controls between 80 and 90% of opium
production globally
believe
boom,
comes from Papa Savas,
some different,
the most popular plant among the Afghan
opium farm.
Sure
country.
Most of the population lives off farm
say that most of the Afghan economy
relies on two fields.
That's international soldiers,
opm.
In fact,
there's little more to their economy
than that.
So for quite a while,
the Taliban have controls the opium
production in this country,
but now they also have realized that
they can produce the heroin themselves,
which is a much more profitable activity
as well.
That's exactly what they do.
Doing everything they harvest is duly
processed inside the country.
They received more revenue if they
processed the opening before it has left
the country.
William Brownfield,
US Assistant Secretary for drugs and law
enforcement estimate is to show that the
town of man could be raising about,
yeah,
$3 billion every year from this.
And that's despite all the money that
the u s has wasted trying to stop these
activities.
And after this,
as you can see from this chart,
hasn't been at all.
Despite all the efforts made by the u s
opium production remains at very high
levels.
As a consequence of having all of these
resources,
the Taliban,
they're managing,
do you sustain a war that is not just
allowing them to regain ground,
but there's also plunged the country
into violence and worst of all is that
future predictions.
They're not very good.
The Taliban are getting stronger.
The government is on the retreat.
They're losing ground to the Taliban day
by day.
Abdul Jabbar Carmen,
I retired general.
Listen to this.
Taliban army has increased from between
2000 to 10,000 soldiers in 2005 to more
than 60,000 today.
But at this point,
the question was to become,
why is the u s losing this war?
Or at least why aren't they winning the
Afghan trap?
The United States has tried many
different strategies in Afghanistan,
but it seems that nothing is working.
In fact,
generally speaking,
this quite a lot of pessimism over this
conflict.
This is not just a matter of more or
less soldiers.
When Barack Obama was a candidate for
president,
he repeated all the time that
Afghanistan was a war.
They need to win.
We did not finish the job against al
Qaeda in Afghanistan.
We did not develop new capabilities to
defeat a new enemy or launch a
comprehensive strategy to dry up the
terrorist base of support.
We did not reaffirm our basic values or
secure our homeland.
It's time to turn the page.
When I am president,
we will wage war.
That has to be what Barack Obama,
when he enrolled me into the White House
and he deployed 100,000 soldiers and
another 40,000 from NATO.
Even so nothing changed.
Many experts say that.
The problem is that President Obama
insisted all the time on an exit plan
with a Pruett,
withdrawal,
a calendar,
which is sort of like saying to the
Taliban,
hey look,
you know,
don't worry about any of this.
It's all temporary.
But beyond that,
although the soldiers from the
international coalition gains grounds,
they couldn't gain influence.
And now the question is,
why is that?
Well,
first of all,
we're talking about a tribal country
with a culture of consolidated violence.
It's not easy for international trips to
gain people's trust and be able to
distinguish civilians from enemies or
even just know what's happening on the
grounds.
The cultural leave is absolutely huge
and having suffered so many years of
violence means that the Taliban,
yeah,
plenty of experience.
On the other hand,
there's the corruption and the lack of
credibility in the local governments.
We can safely say that the Afghan
government has a total lack of
institutions,
which can provide anything to the Afghan
people.
And while there are very few that do
exist,
they are extremely corrupt.
In fact,
this is one of the most corrupt
countries on earth.
Ordinary Afghans don't like the Taliban,
but they disliked the Afghan government.
Even more.
People don't die for an army.
They die for a country.
And who wants to die for the current
Afghan government?
Dexter Filkins,
New Yorker reporter.
With all of this considered and also
adding in the fear of the Taliban.
It's easy to understand is why every
month almost 4,000 soldiers and
policemen desert to the government of
qubole.
Further,
we have to say that the strategy,
the u s is taken with the Afghan
government,
the politics and the institutions.
It hasn't worked.
Washington hasn't even made the Afghan
military able to function with the
exception of the special forces,
which is formed of 17,000 elite
soldiers.
They are the only ones who are really
fighting the Taliban.
Barack Obama understood that the war in
Afghanistan with something that the
Afghan people should carry out though
the u s would be the one paying the
bills.
Today,
I signed a historic agreement between
the United States and Afghanistan that
defines a new kind of relationship
between our countries,
a future in which Afghans are
responsible for the security of their
nation among all the problems.
We also have two eyes in one Pakistan
who was being accused of providing
support to the Taliban and to an economy
which doesn't work at all.
And then there's three,
a lot of concealed interests.
For example,
have you thought about what interests
Beijing to Ron or Moscow having this
war?
One thing is clear,
it's countries don't want Afghanistan to
be an American colony because of all of
this.
After 16 years of war,
the battle,
it continues,
but now that the oval office,
there's a new president,
Donald Trump,
a huge mistake.
Trump has been saying for years that the
war in Afghanistan is a huge mistake and
that the u s has to get out of that.
He said it's of course three his
favorite communication medium and that
would be twitter.
He repeated it to gain and the gain in
2011 2012 2013 all the way until his
2016 cameras
pain.
When will we stop wasting our money on
rebuilding Afghanistan?
We must rebuild our country first.
It's time to get out of Afghanistan.
We're building roads in schools for
people that hate us.
It's not in our national interest.
Do not allow our very stupid leaders to
sign a deal that keeps us in Afghanistan
through 2024 with all costs by USA.
Make America Great.
Now Obama is keeping our soldiers in
Afghanistan for at least another year.
He is losing two wars simultaneously
and it's not just twitter.
Trump insisted again and again and
again,
but Afghanistan was a mistake.
Have a look at this.
Afghanistan is a total and complete
disaster.
What are we doing?
Get out of Afghanistan.
We've wasted billions and billions of
dollars and more importantly,
thousands and thousands of lives
brands.
Of course in the presidential campaign.
He promised he will get the US out of
Afghanistan if elected.
Well,
now that he's president as well,
things they seem to be rather
difference.
Trump's new position.
Okay.
On the 21st of August in the military
base of four to Meijer in Virginia,
trump explained his brand new strategy
as well.
Let's just say that everything has been
saying for years when it came to nothing
trumps new strategy.
It's so similar to a bombers that it's
really quite difficult to differentiate
them.
Trump announced more troops but not that
many more.
Basically the contingents will increase
from 12,000 to about 16,000 the training
of the Afghan military and the fight
against terrorism will become a
priority.
More money will be spent.
Corruption will be battles and there
will be more pressure on Pakistan.
So in other words,
more of the same and nothing that the US
hasn't done before.
The main differences from Obama's
strategy though are twofold.
First,
there won't be a withdrawal calendar.
I'm second from seems not to be
interested in building Afghan
institutions.
In fact,
with the budget cuts on the State
Department's,
trump seems to rely more on arms them on
politics and it's not clear what trump
tends to do with 16,000 soldiers that
Obama couldn't do with 140 thousands how
he thinks he can stabilize the country
without solid and reliable institutions,
which could gain local people's trust
and allow for some economic development.
I mean,
the average age in Afghanistan is around
18 years old,
which is an incredibly young population
and this youth nowadays can't work.
It doesn't have any future apart from
what the Taliban can offer them.
If qubole or Washington or not able to
build a framework of opportunities for
these people,
the end of violence will be very far
away.
So the question must be,
it's Donald Trump aware of this.
It's going to be only America first
America first,
sorry,
16 years with an $800 billion in
thousands and thousands of military and
civilian losses later in the United
States.
It's still bogged down in what many call
the Afghan trap.
And the truth is that trump doesn't seem
to propose anything difference without
institutions.
And with Al's a multilateral
willingness,
which must include Afghanistan's
neighbors like China,
it seems very hard to believe that
weapons are going to be enough.
And now it's your turn.
What do you think the US should do in
Afghanistan?
It's a pretty big question.
You can leave us your opinion in the
comments below and don't forget to
subscribe to our channel for brand new
videos every Monday and Thursday.
Also,
please do check it off.
Friends at the reconsider media
podcasts,
they provided the vocals in this episode
that we're not mine and is a ways
thank you for watching.
My original instinct was to pull out,
and historically,
I like following my instincts,
but all my life,
I've heard that decisions are much
different when you sit behind the desk
in the Oval Office.
In other words,
when you're president of the United
States.