New Zealand's is a remarkable country
with little more than four and a half
million inhabitants in a surface area of
268,000
square kilometers.
It is a little bit smaller than Japan or
Italy.
It is located in the South Pacific and
we could say it in New Zealand is fall
from,
well literally everything because even
though it feels like it's right near
Australia by looking at the map,
these new countries are separated by
more than 1000,
600 kilometers.
Absent that closest.
This is why we can find that endemic
species such as the Kiwi and non-flying,
nocturnal birds.
Being such an isolated country,
New Zealand has managed to become the
following,
a rather unique model.
One of the countries in the welds
enjoying is one of the highest standards
of living.
In this first video,
we're going to tell you about some of
the most striking keys to New Zealand's
success.
There is an entrepreneur comments or
feeling if you wish,
which takes place over and over again.
Every time someone is asked about New
Zealand's after a visit,
they all sing it as a country of
congeniality and his quality of life,
that country that everyone seems to want
to go back to you.
I'm happy to say categorically that I
have found no other country that aligns
more with my view of the future.
The New Zealand Peter Teal,
so if something is for sure,
it is that New Zealand is above all a
welcoming integrating country.
So how about we look at a piece of
evidence for that?
Well,
do you consider this one out of four of
New Zealand's inhabitants has been
abroad and here sign language is
considered an official language.
This isn't certainly have plenty of
reasons to be happy and more than
satisfied.
Further New Zealand is one of the top
five safest countries in the world.
Its economy is the third freest on the
entire planet and according to the doing
business ranking,
it is the number one country in the
world when it comes to the ease of doing
business.
Yep.
You heard that right?
New Zealand dethrone Singapore as
easiest place to do business.
Both for this.
It's not the end of our story today,
not even close.
New Zealand is also considered the least
corrupt country in the world along with
Denmark.
Employment rates here are higher than
the average and the OACD,
and it has excellent educational,
sanitary and cultural systems.
In other words,
New Zealand is both an economic and
social success story,
but leaving all of that aside.
In this video,
we're going to focus on one of the most
distinctive keys to its success,
and that's the countryside.
New Zealand of land a farm using is the
only developed country where the primary
sector has become more relevant in the
last three decades.
This sector represents today almost
seven percent of the country's economy
see
highlights.
Just quite how much of this is consider
the fact that primary sector is just one
point six percent of the economy of the
European Union.
Four Times less than New Zealand's even
Spain who's primary sector represents,
so there's are more than two percent of
its economy and is considered.
The Orchard of Europe looks pretty
ridiculous when compared to the country
that we're discussing today.
There is simply no equivalence in the
entire world.
For example,
milk and dairy here are the largest
exports from New Zealand.
In fact,
if we add goofy primary sector to the
Agri food industry,
these two represent 60 percent of the
nation's trade exports.
I really thought this could be possible
that the countryside could be the main
economic engine in the country with one
of the best welfare systems and
standards of living on the entire
planet.
So it is quite simply rather amazing.
The agricultural competition here is so
high that they even managed to achieve
this without having to rely on
governmental subsidies.
Consider the difference.
Yeah.
The European Union grants agriculture
and livestock subsidies worth around 21
percent of total
production.
The European Union has foreseen that
they will have to give 55 billion US
dollars in farming support between the
years 2014 and 20,
and don't be thinking that the American
system is any difference now.
All right,
so in North America it subsidies are a
bit lower than they are in the EU,
but they all still around eight percent
of all agricultural production.
Well,
that's a loss.
Now,
New Zealand does have some government
subsidies,
but they aren't just zero point nine
percent of production,
which is 23 times less than the European
Union and to almost 10 times less than
the United States.
Not Bad,
right?
Besides,
if this wasn't enough,
New Zealand spending is mostly bound for
investments and innovation as you can
seeing thanks to save a great deal,
but this hasn't always been the case.
Roger nomics and the New Zealand or
farming
Lucia
in the early 19 eighties,
almost 40 percent of farming income came
from government subsidies at the time
the national economy.
It was the archetype of protectionism
and the system.
Well,
we didn't exactly work the economy over
the country.
It was going through a tough crisis.
The public
deficit was enormous.
Almost 10 percent of the national GDP.
There was double digit inflation.
The external debt and unemployment kept
rising and the economy was in a state of
Texas
nation.
Now,
in 1984,
the economics minister of the recently
elected Labor governments,
Roger Douglas,
started and ambitious reform program
known as Roger Nomix in this program.
At many areas of the economy were
liberalized and this included the
primary sector and these changes took
place almost overnight.
Price controls were eliminated and most
farming subsidies were removed.
Furthermore,
in order to fight inflation,
the government decided to raise interest
rates.
This was really unpopular and farmers
were angry since they'd gone into debt.
In previous years.
It was the perfect storm income falls,
debt interest spending increases,
and there was a fall in the price of
lands.
As you can imagine,
this change wasn't easy and it all
seemed to indicate a future disaster.
However,
the country soon felt the benefits of
putting an end to subsidization.
The income fully encouraged farmers to
look the innovations capable of raising
the levels of production.
They introduce new crops,
improve the quality of their current
crops,
and used more ecological farming
methods.
They simply have to find a way to stand
out from the crowd.
On the other hand,
they began to be very careful about cost
and it wasn't just about maximizing the
production of subsidized products.
They had to improve the value chain,
adapt to consumers and reduced costs.
Let's consider an example.
Subsidizing fertilizers.
Had resulted in the careless use of them
when there were no more subsidies for
these fertilizers,
the use of fertilizers fell without
affecting production.
Farmers learns to only use them whenever
necessary,
which helps with the cost of production,
but also helps the environment.
The same happens with other things and
this created a more efficient and
sustainable agricultural system when we
consider the new crops and products that
New Zealand started producing.
Theory is probably no better example
than that of the wine industry.
The space dedicated to two vineyards has
almost tripled in the last decade,
and New Zealand wine has become known
around the world.
More over with the goal of finding new
revenue sources.
The rural population started to develop
additional businesses like rural tourism
or elaborate agrifood products,
both closely relying on environmental
preservation and a highly valued brands.
This meant that the farmers started to
commit to the protection of the
environment.
Now has realized that preservation of
the ecosystem was also profitable in
economic terms.
The results of this well,
it was an incredible revolution.
In the end,
only 800 interests,
one percent of all of them had to close
down and in the next 20 years after
1986,
the production in this sector grew by 40
percent.
Pay Close attention to that figure.
Since the removal of subsidies,
the primary sector has grown more than
the rest of the economy.
Nineteen 86 and 2006.
The primary sector had sustained growth
of five point nine percent per year.
New Zealand
really has thrived after the removal of
subsidies,
along with this internalization is also
key and let them Use Zealand's
countryside competitively export more
than 90 percent of its production.
And in addition to all of that,
it's all incredibly environmentally
friendly.
So I mean,
what else could we possibly ask for New
Zealand Dfu up?
It's the perfect example of how bad
policies and subsidization can damage
innovation,
diversification,
and productivity,
while at the same time creating a burden
for the public economy.
This is exactly what is happening with
the CIP,
the European protectionist agricultural
policy,
which costs around $50,
billion euros every single year.
On the contrary,
New Zealand shows that by doing things
right,
it is not only possible to save a lot of
money,
but at the same time it's possible for
rural areas to improve substantially.
New Zealand has absolutely proven that
farming can prosper without public aid
and while New Zealand is trying to
double that falling exports by 20,
25 for the rest of the country's.
I'll still involved in the debate around
subsidization,
but that's our opinion here at Fisher
politic and we'd love to know what you
think.
Do you think the countryside will die
without public aid,
New Zealand's success?
Could it be replicated somewhere else?
Well,
we'd love to know what you think.
Please let us know in the comments below
and if you enjoyed the video,
please do hit that like button and also
subscribed to brand new videos twice a
week.
Also,
do check out our friends at the
reconsider media podcasts.
They provided the vocals in this
episode,
that one on mine,
and as always,
thank you for.