[inaudible]
Thursday,
December 28 2017 the year was bound to
ams and the world gets ready to welcome
2018 like every year.
Newsrooms are practically on pause and
Tony talk about three basic topics reuse
on 2017 predictions of what 2018 may
bring and to news about how the arrival
of the New Year we'll be celebrated in
nitty every corner of it.
The wells,
however you have,
you are thirsty to some of the 28th when
the year seemed to be over.
This news came out,
numerous protests and demonstrations
began to emerge throughout Iran.
It all began in the city of Masada.
Historic,
she knows pilgrimage site,
the hometown of the supreme leader,
Ayatollah common aim,
and it's one of the bastions of the
regime.
Well,
surprisingly it was here in this Islamic
Revolution Sanctuary for the first
antigovernment protests emerged.
Some demonstrations spread quickly
throughout the country,
resulting in more than 20 deaths and
over a thousand detainees.
But that's that time when everything was
beginning.
Many people wondered if we were
witnessing the birth of a new kind of
Persian spring.
The president of the United States.
Donald Trump seem to suggest that Iran
is failing at every level despite the
terrible deal made with them by the
Obama administration.
The great Iranian people had been
repressed for many years.
They are hungry for food and for freedom
along with human rights.
The wealth of a ram is being looted.
Time for Change Butts.
Just the moments if we really witnessed
an incipient Persians spring,
have we rarely seen the powerful
ayatollah's regime wobble?
Well,
no,
we haven't.
Not imminently at least you'll see what
I mean.
And just a moment.
However,
not being at the beginning of a Persian
spring doesn't mean that Iran isn't
undergoing events that are very
important to the country's future.
Hands by extension,
important to the future of the Middle
East.
So the viewer here we have three key
questions.
First,
why do these protests occur?
What would their cause seconds who lit
this entire movement spark?
And third,
what can we expect?
Will these events have any effects on
Iran?
Well,
let's answer these three questions and
see why all of these movements show us
how the Islamic Revolution in Iran,
the totalitarian regime that now
controls the country is facing rapid
erosion fires,
causes,
as we've seen in previous videos here on
visual politic,
Iran is one of the countries with the
most natural resources in the world.
It has the fourth largest oil reserves,
the second largest natural gas reserves
as their copper,
iron,
zinc,
uranium,
and silver deposits among many other
resources are also among the largest in
the world,
and that's not all.
If that one's enough,
it also has a relatively young as well
educated population.
For example,
every year almost 5 million young people
attend university.
In principle,
it seems like this country,
you should have an easy time getting
things to go well for us,
however,
despite this,
it's economy is a disaster.
Okay?
Employment shortage in Iran,
especially for the youngest who suffer
unemployment rates of 40% inflation is
also in the double digits.
The currency has suffered notable
depreciation and the government has been
forced to cut several social benefit.
This all clashes head on with the huge
expectations generated from the 2015
nuclear agreements.
See,
there was widespread hope that this
government would be a turning point for
the country's economy.
Investments would begin to arrive in
world markets would reopen to do
business with Iran.
President Rohani himself supported this
thesis and the truth is since the
agreement was signed,
things they have improved.
Since many of the sanctions were lifted
in 2016 not all of them,
though the United States actually still
maintained several oil production has
increased by 20% public accounts have
improved and the growth rate has sought
to almost 7%
these changes haven't been enough among
other things because the Iranian
economy,
it has more holes than Swiss cheese.
See,
corruption is very widespread.
A good section of the economy is in the
hands of corporations that are linked to
politicians,
religious foundations,
and the powerful revolution regard,
and they of course receive all kinds of
privileges.
It isn't fair that a lot of Iranian
suffer,
while a large part of the budget is
allocated to Islamic organizations whose
functions we don't know that well,
poverty takes over everything.
Even people's religion Mussa of retired
person and participate in the protest
rallies in Tehran.
In fact,
it is estimated that it's a bit more
than 20% of the economy belongs to what
we might consider the purely private
sector.
Yup.
Really only 20% c doing business in Iran
is really,
really complicated.
Seeing the world's banks doing business
ranking,
which measures how easy it is to do
business in a country ranked Iran in
position 124 as if we take a look at the
economic freedom index.
The results are even worse.
They occupy the 155th place and well
Iran,
it isn't even a World Trade Organization
member and it maintains average tariffs
of approximately 25%
I did that.
When's enough?
The government spends huge results is
abroad,
can Syria,
Lebanon,
Iraq and Yemen for example,
which in addition to spending a loss of
Iran scas money fuels the investment
community's panic.
Just think about it for a moment.
Who is willing to their savings in a
country like Iran?
I mean,
don't tell me that's not just a little
bit scary.
The main problem comes from the
revolutions export ideology and from
supporting the Shiite groups from
Lebanon to Yemen.
The system spends money on these
campaigns without taking the needs of
the people into account far Mars,
last student and activist.
Of course,
the results of this disastrous motto
falls on the shoulders of Iran citizens,
especially its youngest,
and this is important to it because it
is estimated that around 50% of the
country's population is less than 30
years old.
Now we know what sparked this protest,
but is behind all of this.
Who organized the first rallies?
Could it actually have been the United
States as the Toronto regime denounced?
Could it have been a well organized and
well prepared?
It's political opposition.
Well,
let's see that.
Listen,
I've hit because you might be surprised.
The instigator.
At first they were as usual,
several interpretations about what was
happening and one of them was the theory
that a popular revolution could be
starting a very particular Persian
spring.
However,
do you view,
it was soon clear that some pieces did
not seem to fit at all.
See,
on the one hand is protest,
it's exploded in some of the most
controlled and most talkative cities in
the country.
On the other hands on,
like for example,
the so called 2009 green revolution this
time the main role did not fall on the
middle classes,
which tend to be more secular and
reformist,
but curiously on the poorer conservative
causes.
And so on top of that,
the first protest of messages were aimed
mainly at the president's isn't clear
who has organized these demonstrations,
but most slogans were against raw honey.
How mom had,
he is as ours,
editor in chief c even though elections
are held in Iran to choose the
president,
candidates are ultimately chosen by the
supreme leader.
The ayatollah who at the moment of truth
has the last word.
This is why he's the supreme leader.
While the fact is the president of
Rouhani,
honey is let's say a reformist and a
soft hearted political leader of course,
as much of a reformist and softhearted
vertical leader as we could expect in a
regime like Iran.
And while he may not have reached every
expectation,
he did take some steps towards a certain
amount of openness in the country.
Under Mr raw honey,
strict Islamic rules have been somewhat
relaxed,
concerts have been allowed,
and the morals police are largely off
the streets.
Illegal parties that usually no longer
rated,
although there have been exceptions.
So if what you're demanding are more
reforms and more freedom,
attacking the most reformist president
would seem,
at the very least rather curious,
don't you think?
Well,
as you might imagine,
this does have an explanation.
The powerful revolution regards main
chief himself,
Muhammed Ali Jafari made it very clear
at first,
the instigators leader was none other
than the former president Ahmadinejad
himself.
That's right.
Ultra conservative groups organized the
first protests to erode the reformists
political capitol bird of course,
in a country where 50% of the population
is less than 30 whether it's widespread
frustration.
And above all smartphones and Internet
access.
It's not a surprise that the contagion
spread very quickly within hours.
The calls to protest spread through
social networks and communication
applications such as telegram,
the most popular application and the
country.
Suddenly spontaneous protests broke out
all over the car.
I'm sure
of course,
complaints about the economic situation
we're seeing joins by demands for
freedom.
Yes,
we could really save the all of this got
rather out of hands for the ultra
conservative.
Of course the government didn't take
long to reactions.
Use the force.
We can all imagine a dictatorship like
this has detentions,
considerable threats,
and even capital punishment due to
rebellion,
freeze in connection with foreign
intelligence services or began as for
the recent days,
developments in the country and it means
have been united to create problems for
the Islamic system by using various
means including money,
weapons,
politics and security apparatus
Ayatollah Khomeini,
their response was so big that the
government has just announced a
prohibition on teaching English in
primary schools supposedly to avoid
cultural invasion.
As you can imagine,
all of this stops the protests.
However,
even though we aren't facing a Persian
and spraying,
the fact is that all these events showed
several of the totalitarian regimes
weaknesses,
yes,
have a failed revolution since the
Islamic Revolution took place back in
1979 the wrong government has made a lot
of efforts to achieve a strong national
identity built on religion.
See,
according to the Iranian news agency,
there are more than one and a half
million.
Yes,
one and a half million clerics teaching
the Koran and promoting Islamic
principles in schools and in all kinds
of educational institutions.
However,
despite all these efforts,
Iranian society,
which as we saw is very,
very young,
is becoming increasingly secular and
increasingly dissatisfied with a country
model.
If that lies far from their way of
thinking.
As you can imagine,
the Internet has played a key role in
all of it.
Yes.
Well,
if we add the regimes inability to
generate opportunities for all these
young people to all of this,
it isn't unreasonable to think that we
will witness a very fast erosion of this
country's political pillars in the next
few years.
Mind,
do you?
This is harder to imagine in Saudi
Arabia,
and even then,
we are beginning to see it with the
changes that Crown Prince Mohammed bin
Salman is introducing.
Well,
they Raelian society is much more open,
much more secular,
independent of religion and better
formed.
So,
well,
we'll just have to wait and see.
But now it's your turn.
Do you think that the ayatollah's regime
will be able to contain such a changing
force where we begin to see changes in
Iran?
Well,
leave your answer in the comments below.
as in this survey,
can I really hope you enjoyed this
video?
If you did,
please do hit that like button below.
And don't forget,
we put our brand new videos every Monday
and every Thursday,
and please do check it off.
Friends at the reconsider media podcast.
They provided the vocals in this
episode,
but we're not mine.
And there's a ways,
thank you for what.