Is to currencies.
What tinder is,
taps.
Everybody loves to criticize it,
but at the end of the day,
a lot of people wouldn't expect to use
it.
Totally do.
I'm sure many of you have heard
economists and experts have all kinds
making predictions about the ends of the
single European currency
thing Germany could do for Europe is to
quit the single currency,
but it won't.
Larry Elliott for the Guardian Euro,
is it patently flawed construct,
which it's architects knew at the time
of its creation,
George Soros.
Nevertheless,
the reality is way different.
In fact,
the euro is the second most common
worldwide reserve currency and at the
end of the video today,
you're going to see how it might not be
far from being the first and at this
point you might be thinking,
but the u s dollars fast.
There's absolutely no way that's going
anywhere,
but maybe I'm right.
Look,
one third of international trade uses
the euro as its exchange currency.
Twenty percent of the reserve currencies
from central banks are denominated in
euros and many other countries also
issue debt in this currency,
but this is not the end of the story.
If you follow visual politic every week,
you already know that Donald trump is
putting lots of terrorists on
international trade.
So what does that mean?
Well,
think about it.
If Americans are going to buy less stuff
abroad,
there will be fewer dollars in
circulation.
And then you've got to think about who's
signing free trade deals with seemingly
everyone,
and of course that's the European Union.
They've already passed a treaty with
Canada,
the so-called seater,
but this is not the only one.
In the last two years,
Europe has reduced terrorists with
Japan,
Mexico,
and many other countries.
In other words,
the more Europeans by abroad,
the more euros there will be in
circulation.
This means that could be a moment where
instead of having one hegemonic reserve
currency,
we might have two US dollar and the
euro,
so I can probably guess what you're
thinking right now.
I mean,
what good does this really do anyone?
Is it actually useful for the Europeans
to have the euro as their currency?
Well,
yeah,
and at the same time,
no.
If you're watching this from a country
and you have a company,
well having the euro as the world's
reserve currency,
it's not going to help you,
but if
you're working for a European
governments,
boy,
you're probably feeling really lucky.
If there's a big demand for euros,
the European Central Bank will have a
bigger margins of prince money without
devaluing it.
Anyway,
we actually talked about this in our
video about the dollar.
If you haven't seen that one yet,
you'll find a link in the description
below.
Check it out after watching this one.
Now the big question is why is the euro
more popular than any other currency?
For example,
why the euro and why not the Chinese
yuan and why are so many economists
critical of the Europe?
Well,
today we're going to answer these
questions,
but before we do,
as we always do,
let's take a look back at the history
central crisis.
During the seventies,
European countries were happy to trade
with each other,
although there was no European Union
back then.
There was something very similar and
that was the common market.
Nonetheless,
there was a problem.
Each country had its own national
currency at each currency works in a
different way.
For example,
the German market was strong and stable,
but the Italian lira was devaluing every
other day.
You mentioned the situation,
you work in a German bank and do you
lend a million layers?
Do An Italian company at the moment that
you lend at a million layers is worth a
thousand German marks,
but when it's time for that Italian
company to give you the money back,
the lira has been devalued.
So even if you get a million lawyers
back when you exchanged Clo who
currency,
you only get about 900 German marks,
not exactly business brilliance.
Alright,
so in order to avoid this European
politicians,
they met together in a room,
and I'm really not making this up.
Apparently they decided to try something
called verse snake in the tunnel.
So here's the snake is kind of a
metaphor for currency fluctuations
because currencies go up and down,
like apparently a snake,
it goes up and down.
So if you don't want the snake to go
crazy,
you make a tunnel and put the snake in
the tunnel.
That way the currency doesn't fluctuate.
Look for any possible excuse for this
sort of analogy was that it was the 19
seventies.
Bob Marley was alive.
Bell bottoms with trendy.
It was just a really different time.
Alright,
so importantly,
did this snake in the tunnel agreement
work?
Well?
Now your dividends during the 19
eighties,
European currencies went up and down
like a drunk snake in a very wide
tunnel.
Trying to continue that terrible
seventies metaphor.
This is why decades later European
politicians met again in another room.
This time it was 1992 ads.
They had moved on from the ridiculous
names of the 19 seventies and they
decided to call it the Maastricht
treaty.
And then this one they got really
serious and said,
let's not fool around with any more
snakes than any more tunnels.
That was weird.
It was the seventies.
Let's just,
let's make a currency that everyone can
use.
There'll be no more exchange rates,
there'll be no more fluctuations that we
no more bullshit that we had to deal
with before.
Alright,
everyone sound good and then essentially
Great Britain post lands up in is like,
guys,
I don't,
I don't.
I don't want to end with that.
I really liked my pound sterling and
everyone else in the room was basically
Geico yourself for doing this anyway,
and this is how a three step process to
create a single currency started.
In 1999,
all the stock market started listing in
euros and later on European citizens
started using the new coins for their
daily traits.
Today we've all gotten used to hearing
about the euro like any other normal
currency,
but make no mistake.
Back then,
it was an unprecedented financial
experiments and this is how the first
critics came to be
exemplifies situation unfavorable to a
common currency.
It is composed of separate nations,
speaking different languages with
different customs and having citizens
feeling far greater loyalty and
attachment to their own country than to
a common market or to the idea of
Europe.
Milton Friedman and I am.
One's a.
what's the problem?
We're the single currency unless easy.
If we have a single currency,
that German bank we talked about before,
we'll have no problems sending money to
an Italian or a green company,
so.
Well,
what happens then?
since there's no currency risk of German
banks,
you have a lot of money lender to poorer
Italian,
Greek and Spanish companies.
All of a sudden,
rich countries have started to invest in
poor countries like there is no tomorrow
and yet.
Yeah,
I can probably guess what you're
thinking right now.
What's the problem with all of this?
It sounds pretty great.
Well,
the problem comes with the crisis.
Banks must take bigger losses on Greek
loans,
says German finance minister.
Basically the southern European
economies that poor a weekend when
there's a crisis,
their companies are the first ones to go
bankrupt,
so if companies can't pay their debts
back,
the banks can go bankrupt too,
and this is what we call the risk of
contagion.
This explains why during the 2008
crisis,
so many politicians and economists
suggested abandoning the euro.
One of them talked about the creation of
two different years,
one for the wealthy countries who are
solid and stable and another kind of
shitty year for the poorer countries and
that kind of week a year a,
they'd just be happy to evaluate as they
want.
Nonetheless,
today the euro,
it's still alive and kicking and it
wasn't split into two different parts.
So why was this?
Well,
let's roll into the next section.
The chaos critics are rice.
The European Central Bank,
also known as the ECB is a modern day
tower of Babel.
It works similarly to a country's
government.
The current president is a man named
Mario Draghi,
and the executive board is something
like the executive power,
but there's also a legislative power and
that's the governing council.
This is where you have representatives
from all of the eurozone countries.
This one from Spain,
this one from France,
Germany,
Slovenia,
well,
all the countries that have the euro as
their currency,
these guys that the real decision
makers,
they decide whether to raise or lower
interest rates or prince more or less
money,
but before they do,
they have to reach an agreement and this
is where the problems really start.
The southern European countries,
they want to print more money,
but the northern neighbors,
they don't.
Since they can't come to an agreement,
it's almost impossible to make drastic
decision.
Now this is all true and the problem is,
well actually where is the problem?
I mean,
where is the problem in having a
currency that cannot be devalued because
those who are in charge of printing is
don't agree with each other.
I mean,
isn't this actually a strength?
We've talked about this hundreds of
times on visual politic.
The best currency is the strongest one.
If the value of your money doesn't
change,
there is low inflation and you can do
your shopping without being afraid of
losing all your money.
You could also,
if you wanted to start a tech company,
because you know you can invest long
term,
so now you might be wondering,
well Simon is the euro actually that
stable?
Well,
have a look at this
shops
here you can see a comparison between
the monetary supply,
the so-called m two,
if the ECB and the American Federal
Reserve.
Can you see how they go hand in hand in
less than 20 years,
the euro has become as solid as the
American dollar.
In fact,
Europeans have already forgotten what
infection even is for a better
understanding.
The American Federal Reserve has two
main goals,
keeping inflation low and keeping
unemployment low as well.
European Central Bank instead has just
one goal on their agenda and that's
monetary stability and so far all
they've achieved it.
So yeah,
we can see that the euro is as solid and
abundant as the US dollar,
but the question is now,
could it be even more solid and even
more abundance?
And the short answer is yeah.
Today the eurozone has around $320
million inhabitants.
That's almost the same as the United
States,
but despite the European economy being
smaller than the American one,
the euro zone can increase as long as
new countries joining.
Yeah,
the last 10 years,
six new countries have adopted the euro
as their currency and despite the fact
that the political climate is not
currently very much in favor of it,
Poland or the Nordic countries might end
up joining the euro at some point as
well.
This wasn't enough.
There are many other currencies that are
linked to the array.
Do you remember in a previous video we
talked about French colonies in Africa.
In that video we said how countries like
the Ivory Coast and Senegal have a
common currency called the CFA franc.
This currency is actually linked to the
euro and we're talking about more than a
hundred and 50 million people in
emerging economies here.
In other words,
with so many people using euros in their
daily lives,
there are enough coins out there to make
it easy for any company to get their
hands on them.
As an now you might be thinking,
well,
yes,
I'm in.
A lot of people do use the euro,
no doubt,
but you know who else has a lot of users
that Chinese yuan.
This is also known as the renminbi and
it's becoming more and more fashionable
these days.
Well,
so why are we using euros instead of
Renminbi is well,
that's
the laws of the UN.
Well,
you're absolutely right.
China is full of a lot of people who are
using this currency for that day.
You transactions.
This means high demand for this currency
and lots of notes and lots of coins in
circulation.
At first glance,
this should be enough for the nuance,
become an international reserve
currency,
but there is a problem.
Put 15,000 United States dollars and you
will personal cap on overseas bank card
withdrawals.
Yeah.
That ride.
China does not want us to leave the
country.
This is why they put lots of capital
controls in place.
In other words,
finding new ones in the international
markets.
It's not an easy job.
In fact,
China wants to avoid Chinese businessman
taking money out of the country.
Hence,
the Chinese People's Bank has lots and
lots of restrictions and as you can
imagine in a dictatorship like that
Chinese one,
it's hard to believe in the independence
of their central bank.
In other words,
if she needed to,
he could simply changed the rules and
just stopped printing as much money as
he wants it.
Don't believe me.
Well,
the political system doesn't affect the
currency.
If you do,
you should probably watch a video on
Turkey.
They all see what happens when you mix
authoritarianism and economic crisis and
it's not good for now though,
it's your turn.
Do you think the euro can become as
important as the dollar or maybe we see
a brand new crisis destroying the
European single currency.
Please leave your answer in the comment
section below and also visit the
reconsider media website.
They all the podcasts that provided the
vocals in this episode that weren't
mine,
and don't forget we published brand new
videos every week,
so hit that subscribe button and click
the bell icon so you'll always receive a
notification when we publish a new video
and if you liked this episode,
give it a thumbs up.
Share it
friends.
I was always.
I'll see you in the next episode and if
you want to learn more about politics
and hear even more of my voice,
you can join us at reconsider media.
We have a podcast@reconsideredmedia.com
slash podcast.
See you there.