[inaudible]
one of the most surprising things about
Japan,
and there are many surprising things is
quite how safe it is.
[inaudible] Japan is one of the few
countries in the world where you can
leave an iphone 10 and a coffee shop and
the only thing you've got to worry about
is dropping by the next day to get it.
Because to view it is only certain that
your recently released brand new iphone
10 will be there waiting for you at the
next
stay.
I'm not even exaggerating here.
Also,
Japan is a beautiful country with
amazing sites where everything seems to
be exactly where it should be.
As you know,
this is not a travel channel in this
video is indeed not sponsored by Japan's
Ministry of Tourism.
So let us get right to the point yet.
Recently we will find out that emperor
hito has decided to abdicate.
The Emperor of Japan will step down on
April 30th,
2019 the first application by a Japanese
monarch in two centuries.
Well,
see,
this emperor came to the throne almost
30 years ago in 1989 just when the great
Japanese crisis again.
So No.
In Japan,
the emperor has no power.
So I can hito wasn't responsible,
but don't say that.
Can't be just coincidence and bad luck.
We can practically say that it was off
to Iquitos arrival that 30 years of
stagnation began,
and in this video we're going to see
what happens,
what caused this great crisis and why
the German economic model has managed to
defeat the Japanese model.
But first,
have you or let's have a small history.
Lesson.
Goals exists and Germany are two very
interesting countries with a lot in
common,
and it's also many differences off to
the Second World War.
Both countries were literally in ruins.
They had lost not only the
infrastructure,
but also an entire generation.
However,
despite this,
between the 1950s in the 1970s both
countries experienced such a powerful
take off that in those two decades they
not only managed to recover bus become
two of the largest economies in the
world as well as two of the richest
country.
In fact,
even though it might seem incredible,
it's a day for years,
it was speculated that Japan could
surpass even the United States as the
world's largest economy and oh,
how things have changed says that
between 1955 and 1973 Japan grew at an
average rate of 9% a year and between
1973 and 1990 above 4% these are really,
truly incredible rates and Germany
didn't stay behind just as an average
growth rate of 7% for almost 30 years.
Countries
where at full throttle,
their factories works tirelessly.
There was no unemployment and it's both
Germans and the Japanese saved and
invested their money all over the world.
Suddenly Japanese and German companies
became famous.
World was very important,
especially for Japan,
a country that lives constantly under
nature's threat.
Sorry,
it's being a very mountainous country.
Japan suffers from all kinds of natural
disasters,
earthquakes,
cyclin tsunamis,
et Cetera,
et cetera.
Bye Bye.
In a future visual politic video,
hit subscribe.
Wait,
going to tell you all about how these
two economic miracles took place.
Well.
The fact is that in 1989 this entire
economic takeoff stops.
It came to an end and gave way to what
is known as the great Japanese
stagnation.
Forget Greece.
Japan has the world's real economic
time.
Buck Christopher Matthews,
an axios reporter.
I'm pretty convinced this isn't news to
you as it isn't strange to hear people
talk about Japan along with the word
crisis.
Since I can recall,
Japan has been the country of eternal
crisis,
the country that has one good year for
every three bad ones.
In fact,
nowadays we can easily declared Germany
v winner in the growth rates that both
countries maintained for decades today.
Germany,
which has also gone through some bad
times in recent decades,
is richer,
has healthier public accounts,
is more competitive internationally and
has higher weight.
Yeah.
Yes.
No idea of Japan situation.
I think we can use to very revealing
facts first in Japan,
real wages,
which take into account inflation are
lower today than salaries.
Back in 1990 which was 30 years ago,
seconds,
the Japanese government's public debt is
the highest in the world.
250% of GDP.
Yes,
we didn't screw that up.
That is really the debt.
So do you feel,
you might be wondering,
well what the hell happens?
What made the German models so much
better than the Japanese?
Well,
obviously there are lots of reasons,
but we believe that three of them are by
far the most important.
So we're going to take a look at them,
right?
No
problematic model.
Okay.
First we can save that.
There was a big difference between Japan
and Japanese developments,
the country of the rising sun opposite
to protect a large industrial
conglomerates of [inaudible].
They can read,
so to speak,
holdings the do practically everything
that is,
they have companies for all kinds of
things,
cause planes,
tires,
even toothpaste.
Everything is manufactured by the same
holding company whose companies support
each other by and sell products between
themselves and even have their own banks
to finance themselves.
So what's the problem this?
Well,
these large conglomerates tended to be
very bureaucratic and not very flexible.
Yeah.
So decision making was a very difficult
and slow process,
but the Japanese government decided to
compensate them for all of these
disadvantages and to didn't hesitate to
give the Keiretsu all kinds of
advantages and privileges.
For example,
Japan central bank finance them
generously at abnormally low rates
through specific programs.
However,
the results,
they were not
good.
See these large groups became very
influential in the country's politics.
They also had many problems because of
course when one of these conglomerates
companies did badly,
it was extremely easy for them to infect
the rest.
They were also in a lot of debt and they
even limited common
tissue.
I mean how can one compete with such
groups if they are also protected by the
government and to have all kinds of
privileges.
It's a pretty hard thing to ask.
On the other hands.
In Germany the political commitments was
completely different and focused on
creating a very competitive market with
small and medium sized company,
all that large industrial ribs in
Germany.
Well of course there are and that's a
good thing as long as they don't,
depends on the government or receive
privileges that impede competition.
So while Germany's companies thrive to
Japan's and large conglomerates have had
many problems and most of disappeared or
broken down at some point,
but that's not all discount policy
is Japanese politicians thought that in
order to export more,
devaluing the currency from time to time
was not a bad thing.
However,
in 1985 the real problems began.
See as a result of all these currency
wars,
the United States gained a fairly large
external deficits and because Washington
politicians of the time,
as they do now didn't like it,
they forced the so called plaza record
and agreements between the United
States,
Japan,
Germany,
France,
and the United Kingdom to depreciate the
dollar to decrease the trade deficits.
As you can imagine,
this was a huge blow to the Japanese
industry who was used to competing with
a little bit of help and then the
government is sank its interest rates
and began boosting credit like there was
no tomorrow
[inaudible]
the result of this,
well that was a huge debt spiral.
Banks distributing money like crazy and
a massive bubble in the real estate and
financial markets.
And you know what happened next?
Well in 1990 this entire house of cards
began to collapse in Germany.
However,
as we also saw here at visual politics,
but governments opposite to maintain a
strong mark that currency at the time,
which on one hand forced companies to
compete in productivity and innovation,
but on the other allowed them to buy
foreign technology and machines under
better terms.
But dear viewer,
there is still a third ends determinant.
Different
walked
within themselves.
Japan
is the most elderly country in the
world,
just over 25% of its population.
That is everyone in for Japanese people
are over 65 and for every hour that
passes,
the country's population drops by 50
people.
The Japanese government expects the
country's population to fall below 100
million people by the year 2050 and of
course the more elderly citizens there
are,
the less young people there are in the
liver,
the population.
This has clear consequences for one more
public spending on pensions and
healthcare and for another less
labor.
Many other countries have this problem,
but Japan's case is by far the most
serious.
And this isn't by chance at all.
Japanese companies.
I've compensated for all of the problems
caused by the bad policies that we
talked about in this video.
They forced their employees to work
longer hours than in other developed
countries,
which obviously it leaves very little
time to think about starting a family
and what's more,
what some countries like Germany have
favored the arrival of immigrants who
tend to have higher population growth
rates.
Japan has closed its doors.
In fact,
when international organizations tell
Japan that they have to open their
borders to immigration to face the aging
problem,
the Japanese government's has even said
this in Japan's finance minister tells
elderly they should hurry up and die to
help reduce countries rising welfare
bill,
sorry.
These are the fundamental causes that
have led Japan to live in continuous
crisis and the courses that have made
the German model clearly better than the
Japanese one.
So now over to you,
do you think that Japan will be able to
overcome this period of stagnation and
seemingly permanent crisis?
Well,
leave your answer in the comments below
as well as in this survey.
And I also really hope you enjoyed this
video.
Please do hit that like button if you
did,
and don't forget to subscribe to our
channel for brand new videos every
Monday and Thursday.
Also,
do not forget to check it off.
Friends at the reconsider media podcasts
that they provided the vocals in this
episode,
but we're not mine and as always,
thank you for watching.