[inaudible].
They're all team types of companies.
Those that sell a product to a customer
and those where the customer is the
product.
Tinder belongs to the second group.
Why would you choose tinder before any
other dating app?
No,
all the answers.
That's pretty simple.
It's because it's full of users.
This means that the real product,
it is not a website or a service.
Do you have you on tinder,
the product is you,
and here is where the big question comes
in.
How would you start a dating app?
I mean,
imagine you and your friends decide to
start a company like tinder.
Well,
the first thing you need is lots of
people using it,
right?
But these men and women then are going
to use it if they don't see a lot of
other men and women using it.
You see where I'm coming from here?
This is why tinder with over 200 million
users is one of the most surprising
successes in business history.
So how did they get started?
What did they do better than their
competitors?
Well today we're going to answer this
question and in order to do so,
we're going to ask one of the biggest
experts in the industry,
and that's Mark Brooks,
who's the president of idea,
a group that represents the biggest
dating apps on the planet.
He has spent more than 25 years in the
online love industry and he's also the
brains behind many of the dating sites
that you probably know
Hello Simon and the hell is all of
visual politics subscribers.
As you said,
the key to being successful with a
dating service is as we call it,
having a critical mass of activity.
This means having enough active users,
so on average one out of five messages
get an answer.
How'd you get there?
This is where economics strategy and
math comes into play and you might be
wondering,
why are we talking about this on visual
politics?
What does tinder have to do with all of
the things we usually cover on this
channel?
Well,
actually a lot.
Listen up in this survey,
one out of five heterosexual couples in
America got to know each other through a
dating site.
In the case of same sex couples,
this figure is more than 70% in other
words,
dating online has changed our society
and this,
this is also politics nonetheless,
despite what it looks like,
the online dating industry,
there's still a virgin industry.
In total.
We make around $5 billion a year around
the world,
which isn't that much really relative to
other industries.
For example,
the underwear industry has more than 10
times bigger than the online.
Personal is industry.
Yup.
You heard that right?
We're talking about an industry where
making a profit is seldom easy.
Besides that,
there's a hyper concentrated industry.
Basically,
most of the dating sites,
including tinder,
belong to the very same group match
group.
This is a Nasdaq listed company that has
smashed or required most of the
competitors at this stage,
but still the middle
question is how did the tinder creators
managed to such a successful app?
What kind of lessons can we learn from
tinder that could be applied to other
kinds of businesses?
Well today we're going to answer these
questions,
but before we do,
let's take a look back at the history.
The love,
the Haemus.
I know,
I know it won't come as a surprise if I
tell you that dating sites are as old as
the Internet itself for a better
understanding in the year 1991 Tim ben
is,
he created the first website in history,
well three years later,
the first dating site,
whether personals was launched.
And as you can imagine we all just
talking about finding your significant
other at the time.
Other sides like adult friend finder
where created to
nonetheless,
most of these websites were pretty
rudimentary back then.
Nobody talked about user experience or
complex algorithms were personal.
So there's just an online version of the
good old classified ads that you had an
newspapers,
but you could search more quickly and
send messages to the contacts,
which was huge.
And overall the biggest problem was they
had very few users.
Hmm.
And most of the cases you would create a
profile and find just a few geeks today.
But all of this changed with the advent
of match.com match.
The comb was the real game changer that
make no mistake,
they didn't have an especially good
algorithm or a better user experience.
In fact,
their asset was just one word.
Money match.com started out with just a
small improvement over the classified
ads in newspapers,
but they realize the future was online
during the early years.
They tried different formulas for the
turning point came in the year 1999 that
was the year when I see a multinational
Bolton mashed or calm for $50 million
and believe me,
that was enough money to do great
things.
All of a sudden this company could
invest heavily in advertising and this
advertising budget,
let them get to that critical mass
sooner than anybody else,
but not only that.
match.com was the first one to import
the concepts of the white label to the
dating world.
So what made match.com so unique?
Well,
they had technology to improve online
dating,
but what did they need while they needed
more users and who had the most users
back then?
While that would be msn.com remember old
Microsoft and messenger?
Well,
back then this was the most used
messaging software on the planet.
They were having to offer a brand new
dating service to their users and this
is why msn personals was nothing but the
match.com engine with another logo
with this aggressive strategy manager
come close,
similar deals with other Internet
juggernauts like Yahoo.
And this is how in so little time they
smashed the competitors.
In fact,
today,
this company is so big,
it's listed on the Nasdaq index and they
represent one fifth of the entire
industry.
Yeah.
[inaudible]
I ain't know what you now thinking.
Who could compete with such a ban off at
the end of the day with so much money
for advertising and the power to close
the best business deals?
Who could come out from under that
shadow?
Well,
believe me,
the battle,
it had only just started
despite mashed up calm being such a big
company,
the service was pretty lame.
It is true.
They had lots of users,
but a minority of people found a natural
match.
This explained why the retention rates
were so low.
In fact,
people signed up into metro con and they
left after just three months.
Most what does satisfied
this left a big vacuum for a better
competitor with a better strategy.
And the winning strategy was we do
promise and over deliver.
Imagine we start a business to make
money.
The logical move would be to get paid
for the service.
Right?
Well it doesn't actually have to be that
way.
The founders of plenty of fish.
A proofing.
Yeah.
2003 this website was the first one to
offer their services completely for
free.
So how did they make money?
Well,
the answer that's kind of obvious.
It's bad advertising.
Many of you will not be surprised with
this,
but back in the time this was a
revolutionary idea being based on ads.
Plenty of fish was heavily incentivized
to make sure the users would spend a lot
of time on the site.
The longer they use the service,
the more ads they would see.
But this is not
the end of the story.
The strategy of plenty of fish could not
be more counter intuitive.
So here's a question.
Let's say that you're starting your own
dating site.
What kind of pictures would you put it
on the front page?
Would you pick ugly or beautiful people?
Would you use an attractive,
elegant web design or a very simple and
sketchy one?
Well,
my guess is you'd go for beautiful
people in a smart design,
right?
Well,
actually plenty of fish did the
opposite.
Their motto was happy are those with no
expectations because they will never be
disappointed.
In other words,
under promise and over deliver.
In order to avoid the website taking
forever to download.
Plenty of fish wander to use low res
pictures.
There's men are very unattractive
design.
They made sure where their users that
they wouldn't find top models,
but they'd find normal people,
real people,
even their orange made clear that they
didn't want to lie to anybody.
Plenty of fish,
simple free,
and it works.
This model was so disruptive that they
soon found imitators.
Other websites like purdue followed in
their footsteps.
And guess what happens when plenty of
fish became successful?
Well match.com the ban off of the
industry does not like competitors,
so they made them an offer they couldn't
refuse.
Basically they did a buy them for what
the company was worth,
but by the amounts of money,
match.com was losing by having them as
competitors and well,
it was a lot of money,
but many of you might believe that with
such a solid business model and as a
part of match.com nobody could take on
plenty of fish rice.
Well you aren't wrong ones again.
Tindering outside of the box.
Yep.
It's true.
Fancier fish seems like the perfect
website.
Millions of users,
simple design,
happy customers.
But there was a problem.
It didn't work on mobile phones and as
if this wasn't enough and everything was
proud of the fact that they were using
plenty of fish.
Now I know this is probably going to
surprise the millennials watching this
video,
but until recently,
the online dating industry was kind of a
pretty shameful pastime.
And the last thing that you'd confessed
to your friends,
and this is when the tinder founders
came in ready to change the rules of the
game forever.
Tinder was the first dating APP design
that we've fully mobile first.
No computers or laptops,
just cell phones.
And how do you think they got what that
critical mass of users?
Well,
you might think that being an internet
app,
they use online ads to promote
themselves.
Right.
So the opposite was true.
Okay.
The strategy of tinder was 100% offline
instead of ads or big marketing
campaigns.
The tinder founders organized parties at
American universities more.
Exactly the coolest fraternities and
sororities.
If you wanted to attend to the most
glamorous parties,
you had to download the APP to your
mobile phone and it wasn't sold as a
dating APP.
In fact,
it was a game.
the goal of the 10 to founders was not
to sell true level of significant
others.
The motto was,
we are playing tinder.
Let's play and see who is the most
popular in the party would have put it
on their own terms.
Let's see who gets the biggest share of
life.
The idea of competing for popularity was
nothing new.
Mother websites like hot or not offered
people the chance to upload their
pictures so others could rank them from
zero to 10 but tins are made everything
simpler.
It wasn't about ranking,
but instead it was a matter of yes or no
or in tinder towns swipe right or swipe
left
often does real success can be explained
with the theories at the so called
behavioral economist.
Authors like Daniel Conaman talk about
two kinds of behavior,
some of the basics
in NATO operations functions that we
have such as perceiving things,
having emotional reactions to things.
All this is system one.
We don't choose what just happens to us.
The so called system one or intuitive
fast decision making and the so called
system to all logical and slow decision
making.
By limiting the range of choices,
we can easily approach people's emotions
easier.
So tend to dumb down decision making to
the purest emotional element element.
In other words,
mobile first design,
gamification and perfect expansion
strategy made at tinder,
the most loved APP in American
universities.
Instead of hiding it,
people told everybody they were using it
and at the end of the day it wasn't
dating.
It was a game.
They were playing tinder,
and guess what happens after tinder
achieved so much success.
Exactly.
Again,
match.com the lovebam off bought them.
In other words,
most of the dating apps today,
a part of the very same group,
and this is why we can still say the
story doesn't end here after 25 years,
the dating app industry is still taking
baby steps and this is because it's one
of the few businesses where people
success is punished instead of rewarded.
Think about it.
What would be the best app for dating?
Of course,
the one that lets you find your
significant other,
right?
Nonetheless,
if you find your match on tinder,
the next thing you'll do is leave the
APP.
This way the company stops making money,
which is crazy.
In other words,
the incentive for a dating app is quite
broken.
If they can help you find your true
love,
then you're off never to return.
In economic terms,
this means the dating app market is far
from mature.
There's still a lot of space for new
players.
For example,
one of the tinder craze has left the
company after a sexual harassment
lawsuit.
She created her own app called the
bumble.
This APP is completely innovative
because here women are the ones who must
send the first message.
Okay.
And of course there's also facebook.
Yep.
You heard me right?
Facebook has already announced they
would have launched their own dating
site.
They have the information that Melville
users and the money to make a 180 degree
shift to an industry that despite having
millions of users,
makes them less than $5 billion a year.
Wow.
So now it's your turn.
Do you think facebook will be a rival
for tinder or match.com do you think
online dating will become the preferred
way of finding your significant other?
Well,
please leave your answer in the comment
section below.
And if you want to hear more about this
industry,
you can follow me at my blog.
Online is watch.com there you will find
interviews with the industry leaders,
news and true insight on the dating
industry.
Also don't forget that we published
brand new videos every week.
So subscribe to visual politic and you
won't miss any posts.
And if you like this video,
please give us a thumbs up.
And as always,
I'll see you next time.
One,
learn more about politics and hear more
of my lovely voice.
Don't forget to checkout the reconsider
podcast at reconsider media diet.