Amazing is the only rock dance with
their own private jets.
And do you know who the pilot of that
pilot jet might be?
Well,
yes.
That's none other than the lead singer
Bruce Dickenson.
And listen,
there are not many people who deserve
more admiration than Mr Dickinson.
If it wasn't enough to be one of the
most successful heavy metal singers in
history,
he's also an experienced commercial
pilot,
a radio host,
a writer,
an ownership into.
I'm the CEO of one of the most
innovative aviation companies in the
wells.
As you know.
Might be wondering,
well,
why are we talking about Bruce Dickinson
on visual politic?
I mean,
what does iron maiden have to do with
politics at all?
Well,
let me
tell you,
maiden singer Bruce Dickinson's,
Cardiff aviation signs on to manage
national carrier for Djibouti Palsy.
If Aviation is a company that provides
maintenance to airline companies,
we could say that iron maiden has landed
in Djibouti,
but in this case they didn't come to
perform.
They came to sell airplanes,
train the pilots and design a system so
the Djibouti can have its own airlines.
But just wait a minute because this is
the really important thing here.
You might think that the airlines have a
country like judy owns a big deal,
right?
I mean,
we're talking about a really poor
country located in the Horn of Africa
with a population of less than a million
inhabitants.
Oh,
I thought,
what if I told you the debussy has a big
chance of becoming the next Dubai.
What if Bruce Dickinson is actually one
of the first vision reason to decide to
invest in this country?
Think about it while you look at this
map.
Here it is true,
but now this is the Suez Canal and this
is the Red Sea.
Any oil tanker who wants to go from Abu
Dhabi to Europe must pass through here.
All of those Chinese mobile phones sold
in the UK,
travel through this area.
We don't have 10 ships that sail the
planet are passing in front of the
Djiboutian coasts.
But make no mistake,
this is not a quiet region.
In fact,
the opposite is true.
Remember the Somali pirates?
Well,
this is Somalia and this other thing is
called [inaudible] and it's not a chill
place either and this other thing you
see on the map,
this is called Yemen and it's in the
middle of a civil war.
It turns out your booties,
the only peaceful country in the entire
room.
Now,
hold on a minute once again because they
still more here.
Now,
if you've been following this channel
for a long time,
you should already know,
but Ethiopia is one of the fastest
growing countries on the planet.
They are becoming a textile superpower
and they have more than 90 million
inhabitants.
And guess what else?
Ethiopia has got no coast.
This means whenever they want to sell
their tax dollars,
they have to do so through the Djibouti
port and yes,
I can probably guess what you're
thinking right now.
Are we really talking about a new
Singapore or Dubai or is the something
missing here?
I mean maybe you might be thinking now
what should I be like Bruce Dickinson
and invest in?
Well,
today we are going to answer all of
those questions,
but before do as always,
let's take a look back at the history,
location,
location.
I'll do everything I just said about,
but some of you might be thinking right
now.
I mean,
why have I never heard of this country
before?
Well,
the answer to that lies in their
history,
which is not really very different from
that.
Yes,
in the year 1977,
after a peaceful referendum,
Djibouti became the latest country to
gain independence from their French
colonizers and just as it happens in
similar cases too,
but he became a one party dictate until
the 19 nineties,
Mr Hassan Goulet apted on and other
members of his tribe controlled the fate
of this country.
Sponsoring members of the opposition
became a common practice and the ruling
party got really,
really rich off the profits from the
port.
Now you could say that back then,
GBC was a textbook example of a gate
keeper state.
You see in such poor countries,
the whole economy is dependent on just
one thing.
In the case of editorial Guinea for
instance,
that thing is oil.
In the case of Jersey,
well that would be it's port.
Since the dictators have no money to pay
a big army to control the whole country,
they must focus all of their oppressive
powers in the area where the money is
located,
so Djibouti port was completely secured
while the rest of the country was in
total chaos.
There were murders on the streets that
was rape.
There were all kinds of other horrific
crimes.
Now,
as you can probably imagine,
this is not the ideal situation to
create companies or to track any sort of
foreign investments now that in fact
that in the nineties as civil war
started between the governments and the
opposition parties and tribes and it's
all not exactly a recipe for success
as well.
This is where the first difference
between Djibouti and the rest of their
neighbor countries comes in.
The way the government's solved their
problem was surprising to everybody.
Basically,
after years of bloody fighting and
thousands of killings on both sides of
the battle,
Mr went to the other party,
the so called fronts for the restoration
of unity and democracy and essentially
said to them,
they're dudes.
Okay,
get a grip.
There is money for everyone here.
Why can't we share it all and just stop
fighting each other and this.
This is how to.
But you got its first unity government,
a government that combines most of the
local political party.
Yes.
Now there is still political opposition
in Djibouti though,
but they can really not even meet
campaigns and navy signed that on
presidential elections.
They are essentially causes.
This explains why Amazon ads laser has
his nephew the late when the elections
with outcomes close to 100 percent of
the vote.
So yes,
it's not exactly a leaving democracy
bus.
This is just the beginning.
Despite the internal fights by the year
2011,
but it was still a very corrupt country
with a very weak position.
I mean,
think about it.
We're talking about a really small
country,
less than 1 million inhabitants placed
in the middle of one of the most violent
regions on the planet.
I mean Somalia,
which is virtually anarchy where
different tribes that constantly at each
other's throat span.
Then on the other side,
we have Eritrea a dictatorship that
makes North Korea looked like Sweden and
in the south of course this Ethiopia,
the biggest regional power and one who
had any moments would be happy to invade
your booty so they can have a coastline.
So in summary,
they were far from being in a peaceful
situation,
but then when everything seemed to be
against them,
history decided to give the country a
marvelous break.
Our enemy is a radical network of
terrorists and every government that
supports them,
all of a sudden America with George W
dot Bush as their president declared war
on terrorism and this meant sending
troops to all the areas where our cells,
what presence,
which includes of course with a Horn of
Africa and is there any better place for
building military basis than shebooty.
It has a peerless location and to
governments that corrupt as it is,
congratulates itself for being stable
and having no ties with terrorist
groups.
Now,
do you remember when I told you that the
Red Sea is extremely dangerous for
merchant ships?
You know all the pirates and stuff?
Well,
from the camp lemon airbase,
American troops can chase those Somali
pirates and not only the Americans can
do this in 10 years.
The list of countries who have installed
military bases in Djibouti,
it's pretty much never ending.
We can indeed find French,
Italian and Spanish troops that indeed
the only place where Japan has a
military base abroad is turbidity and as
you might be able to imagine with so
many wells powers having a military
presence here,
China,
well,
this is where China comes into the
picture.
Job
Opens first overseas base in Djibouti,
ends.
Of course,
in such a poor in small country,
having so many foreign armies is a
fantastic deal.
I mean,
think about it.
All of these soldiers,
they need food to eat,
they have to shop,
and they also need to have some fun.
This means lots of jobs,
lots of money for the entire country and
on top of all that,
it's always the biggest problem Djibouti
had for investments
with
so many military bases in the country,
only an insane best and would dare to
invade them.
In fact,
there are few places in Africa that are
safer than shebooty nowadays,
add to this,
the perfect situation for international
trade routes,
and you can easily understand why this
country has been growing at a five
percent annual rate since the day
American troops,
but that boots on the ground,
as you might've guessed.
No,
not everything is perfectly wonderful.
Hip spiked this growth.
Djibouti still has an unemployment rate
higher than 50 percent.
Yep.
You heard that right?
One out of two Djibouti eons.
No stable job.
In other words,
these are lines that Bruce Dickinson
helps creative just sending soldiers and
people from ngos that traveled to places
like Somalia or Ethiopia.
That's just wait a minute here because
the times they're certainly changing in
this country,
man and his vision.
Remember this name?
Alias Mosa Dowell a.
Now you might be thinking,
well,
he's the new president rice.
Well,
no,
certainly not to,
but has kept the same president for the
past 20 years.
This man,
well,
he's the minister of Economy and
finance,
but in this case,
the finance minister is even more famous
than the president.
We needed to plan over a longer period.
We accept that we will probably not be
able to achieve all of our objectives
during the current administration.
The Vision Twenty,
35 clearly sets out the aspirations of
the president and his government.
Les.
Yes,
Musar Darwalla.
Now,
if you've been following visual politic
for awhile,
this vision 20 slash 35 thing will
probably remind you of something.
Do you remember this video where I told
you about Rwanda's road out of poverty?
This vision 20,
35 is a carbon copy of Rwanda's plants.
In many aspects,
the gbt governments wants their ports to
have state of the art technology just
like those of Singapore and Dubai for
this while they need money,
but not only that,
Aa also knows there's.
In order to make the economy work,
you need to diversify as if a country
only relies on one single industry.
A small crisis could easily be the
country's downfold.
That again,
if you want to diversify your economy,
you still need money and you need a
business friendly environments and
corruption and lack of rule of law up
seldom.
Friends have businesses,
kinds of foreign investments,
and in these areas,
Djibouti,
while they get a gold medal,
for example,
despite the poor being the main economic
driver in this country,
nobody can see the accounting books.
This means many governments officials
are getting rich or without anyone
knowing.
If this was not enough,
part of the local legislation is based
on sharia law.
Nobody can even protest this fact
because Djibouti is among the 10
countries with the lowest freedom of
speech in the entire world.
In just 2016,
the government sent three BBC
journalists to jail because they wanted
to talk about election fraud.
Now,
as you can imagine,
this is certainly hurting the country's
opportunities and what's worse?
Well,
it's almost impossible to change the
system.
At the end of the day.
The ruling class is already making
enough money from the port and the
rents.
They guess from all of those foreign
army
feather.
They also have enough security that
makes them not afraid of a popular
uprising.
In other words,
if Dalloway the finance minister,
wanted to change the political system,
and as he says in his vision 20,
35 paper and prove the governance over
the country,
he has an impossible job,
right?
Well,
dear viewer,
well sometimes miracles,
they do happen.
Jody breaks ground on massive Chinese
backed free trade zone.
In other words,
if you've gone,
Shane's the whole political system in
the entire country,
just change a little part of it.
In this special economic zone,
everyone can buy property and build
without having to wait months and months
to get government permission.
This makes it harder for governments.
Officials who wants to take bribes.
Now,
on the other hand is all of the
regulations are going to follow Chinese
law.
Essentially.
This is a little short of a tiny little
shenzen in the middle of a country.
The agreement calls for the zone to
handle $7,000,000,000
worth of trade,
or within two years,
Judi will create a unified customer
system with trainer establish a trade
center and set up a currency clearance.
Well,
what can we expect now?
the idea of making special economic
zones is certainly nothing new and it's
been proven to work many times.
In fact,
this is the system that let Dubai become
the metropolis that it is today.
The idea is that when you have a special
economic zone,
both the citizens and the political
leads can see firsthand what happens
when you have transparent laws and a
good framework for companies to follow.
If this experiment works,
politicians will be more willing to
implement real changes in the rest of
the country.
All right,
so in summary,
we have an African country where
security is granted by foreign armies
and he was starting to apply serious
reforms.
We have a country with the perfect
location in science to become a
financial and logistical sensor in one
of the busiest areas on the planets.
So it seems that Mr Dickinson has found
a virgin paradise for investments.
Doesn't it?
Well,
hold on just a second because this does
not enjoy.
Beauty is going to become a freedom and
human rights haven.
I mean at the end of the day,
neither China nor does by.
Oh really?
Such havens either.
But this can be at least the beginning
of the end for poverty in this region.
So the question now is,
what do you think these positive
predictions do you think they'll become
true?
Is this a good time to invest in
Djibouti or is this going to amount to
nothing more than just hopeful
predictions?
Well,
do leave your answer in the comments
section below.
And if you want to know why do you buy
as say,
rich?
Well check out this video.
Here's a spoiler.
It has nothing to do with oil.
Also,
do you know if it gets,
check it off,
friends and the reconsider media
podcast,
the podcast that provided the voices in
this video that are not mine,
and don't forget we published brand new
videos every Monday and every Thursday,
so hit that subscribe button and you
won't miss a single posts.
And if you liked this video,
give us thumbs up.
As always,
I'll see you next time.
And if you want to learn more about
politics and hear even more of my lovely
voice,
you can join us at reconsider media.
We have a podcast@reconsideredmedia.com
slash podcast.
See you.