Venezuela is undergoing some of its
worst moments.
This disaster is so huge that what was
once one of the largest and most
powerful oil companies in the world,
PDVSA is now practically bankrupt and
has more problems including extracting
the oil.
So how does the oil company with the
largest reserves in the world have
problems extracting?
Yes.
Well that's what we're going to talk
about in today's video,
folks.
I think we all probably know it's
Venezuela is undergoing a true
catastrophe and not only an economic
one,
it is above all a humanitarian
catastrophe.
It's such a huge disaster that in recent
years it has caused between three and 4
million Venezuelans to flee the country.
That's more than one in every 10
inhabitants.
And the truth is we're not really
surprised by this.
Si,
according to the latest statistics,
80 at 7% of the population that's nearly
nine out of every 10 Venezuelans are
poor.
And on top of that,
most of Venezuela's population,
60% isn't only poor.
They live in extreme poverty.
Not only that,
Venezuela is burning down according to
data from the Venezuelan social
conflict.
Observe a treat in 2017 almost 10,000
protests were registered throughout the
country.
More than 27 per day.
And what's even worse than this?
Well,
according to information from Attorney
General Luis Ortega,
since 2015 the police,
the national guard,
the army as the different intelligence
services have killed more than 8,000
people.
Of course,
most of them were opposes to the right
Jesus Christ.
Hunger,
violence,
repression,
everything indicates that Venezuela will
soon undergo a refugee crisis of
colossal dimensions because let's be
clear their view,
and let's be honest,
things they're not looking good.
You see,
for years the Bolivarian Revolution of
Chavez,
Maduro and company has a great ally and
there we're not too worried about Cuba
or Russia or any other country.
As a matter of fact,
we're talking about oil.
The black gold that financed the
revolution for a long time,
the huge income,
this raw material brought,
financed all of the regimes,
policies,
ends.
They didn't really care about the
consequences.
So,
I mean,
factories were closing,
foreign investment was fleeing the
country,
but it didn't matter because while they
have loads and loads of money from all
of that oil,
but all of that,
well it's about to end.
Yup.
Venezuela does have a lot of oil,
but one thing is having oil and another
thing is being able to exploit set oil.
Did you know that Pdvsa the national our
is practically about to collapse.
Well,
listen,
up the fall of pedevesa petroleum of
Venezuela,
PDVSA was created by government decree
in 1976 do you integrate all the oil
assets that the state had nationalized
this company soon became a world class
colossus as you know.
Why?
Well,
among other things,
because this company has the largest
reserves on the planet as when we say
large,
we mean large.
There are more than 300 billion barrels
of oil certified here more than the
reserves of Saudi Arabia,
the Emirates,
Russia,
or any other oil power.
Now,
yes,
it is true and we have set it on this
channel before.
Venezuelan oil doesn't have the highest
quality,
but that doesn't really matter.
We're talking about a huge amount of
resources,
almost 20% of the world's noon
herbs,
and the fact is that this company paid
evasive peaks in production in 1998 a
year before Hugo Chavez came to power,
at which time the company was extracting
three and a half million barrels per
day.
Since then,
things have changed a lot.
By the year of Hugo Chavez death in 2013
production had decreased by 1 million
barrels per day day.
So could it be that Hugo Chavez bothered
area and government didn't like oil?
Could it all be part of a twisted,
bland,
do diversify Venezuelan economy?
Well,
in fact,
it's quite the opposite.
If he had known me,
do you want me [inaudible] petroleum
Hugo Chavez to increase production to 5
million barrels?
The problem was that they simply weren't
able to do it.
But if you think that that command,
his results were bad,
you haven't seen anything.
Yes,
because since Nicolas Maduro came to
power,
production has sunk to 1.8
million barrels.
That means like while countries like the
United States of doubles their
production,
Venezuela produces half as much oil has
when the revolution began.
So hardly a fantastic success.
And if you think that that's the worst
of it,
get prepared.
Do you think again,
because the future is looking a lot more
bleak.
So at this point in the video,
you might be wondering,
well,
what on earth is going on with paid a
visa?
The keys of a disaster for toll.
Okay,
databases.
History.
Divya has been the story of a disaster
for tolls.
The best example of that,
the Power wanna refining complex,
which consists of three crude oil
refineries and just one of the three
largest complexes of its kind in the
entire world.
For years it was Venezuela's industrial
pride,
the crown duel,
if you will.
However,
today it barely operates at 15% capacity
and all kinds of accidents tend to
happen.
Well,
why is this?
There's no maintenance.
They sucked everything they could from
pedevesa without investing,
there's nothing left to squeeze.
Publishes Pedis Plant Operator,
and this is certainly not an
extraordinary case at the end of
October.
Also in the [inaudible] refining complex
and why refineries spills over 200,000
gallons of gasoline into the bay a few
days later,
another refinery in the complex,
the card on refinery itself to fire that
fireman could barely contain because
they didn't even have the foam to fight
the flame.
Yeah,
long and on and on it goes because the
truth is that most of the old companies
facilities are in terrible condition.
So how do you think that they reached
this point?
You see,
the Chavez government always saw paid a
vase,
a as I kind of dairy cow from which they
could get all the resources they needed
for the revolution.
The problem is that the oil industry,
it requires lots and lots of
investments,
and these are investments that the
Venezuelan government simply did not
want to make.
Even with that fact,
it's still indebted the company to the
Brim.
And by the way,
do you know how indebted this company is
today?
Well,
listen to this,
we're not talking about one or 5
billion.
We're talking about 90 billion American
dollars.
A fortune so big that Venezuela could
have even bought multinationals like
Goldman Sachs,
Nike or semen
is just an insane amount of debt.
But do you think there's a that's going
on?
Well,
not even close.
They also use the company to plug in
place and hire thousands and thousands
of supporters,
friends and family members around which
paid a visa,
lost even more resources.
And if that wasn't enough,
the Chavez regime also placed unskilled
and inexperienced personnel in
management positions while dismissing
and driving away thousands and thousands
of experienced employees because of that
political beliefs.
Yes,
this is how pdvsa ran out of money and
ran out of human resources.
And now with all of this information,
we can really understand why oil
production is dropping in Venezuela.
And of course the consequences of all of
this.
Well,
they're terrible for the country.
The consequences
oil is essential for the Venezuelan
economy,
especially because there's no other
industry left standing.
That dependence on oil is so great that
it generates 95% of all foreign currency
profits in dollars and these currencies,
div Ua,
I won't finish.
Swayla needs to be able to import food
medicine,
gasoline.
Yes,
indeed.
When I swayla still today has to import
gasoline as well.
There's pretty much everything else,
but of course there's oil production
keeps plummeting.
The country is able to import less
thing.
Yeah,
and you know what?
Since Venezuela is producing nothing
fantastic,
we import everything.
The dwindling oil money is no longer
enough to pay all the bills.
But of course,
as you will know,
when you spend more money than you make,
money goes away.
And that's precisely what's happening to
Venezuela,
which according to some calculations,
valley has $10 billion in foreign
reserves,
which is that lowest number in 40 years.
This means that when the money is gone,
they won't be able to import anything
else than what they can buy with the
money they make from the oil,
which she is decreasing.
So you're probably beginning to see the
problem.
Yeah.
Previously talked about on visual
politic.
I'm Nicolas Maduro,
has government has tried to buy time by
resorting to international markets to
issue desk has pretty scandalous rates,
sometimes as high as 40% obviously issue
in debt with implicit rates of 40% can
only mean future ruin ends.
In any case,
that's actually no longer a possibility.
In fact,
both of the Venezuelan government and
Pedevesa are incurring defaults that is
a on not paying that debt.
I said Pete downgrades seven sovereign
Venezuelan bonds to the default level
and other they attempted was that of the
Chinese rescue and the Chinese answers
and place more than $23 billion in loans
on the table.
Everything has a limit and they are no
longer willing to continue giving more
money and getting nothing in return.
Let me just check this out.
The Chinese oil companies seen OPEC
sue's pit of Essa for unpaid debts.
The situation,
dear viewer,
is so desperate that the Cuban
government has decided to seize the 49%
that paid a visa held in a Cuban
refinery is compensation for that unpaid
debts.
Yep.
Yeah,
that right.
Not even Cuba trusts the maduro regime
and it was all of this that led to the
latest Chavista events for Petro.
Yep.
Venezuelan,
crypto currency.
As we've seen with everyday that passes,
the Venezuelan government has less
access to foreign currency,
which is obviously a huge problem
because without a foreign currency they
can't import,
but based on this problem and idea came
up,
cryptocurrency is in fashion,
so why not launch their own
cryptocurrency?
While they did and they called it the
petro
not good enough.
They're not going to be good for the
older.
Maybe your mountain tell too,
because
course the petro is a very particular
currency among other things because it's
controlled by Maduro is governments
under these conditions.
Let me ask you a question.
Would you be willing to invest a single
euro or a single dollar into this new
crypto currency?
In other words,
would you put your money in the hands of
the Venezuelan government?
Well,
you can bet that I would and not even a
single penny and precisely because no
one in their right mind would do such a
thing.
The Venezuelan government as hat due
back.
This particular cryptocurrency with oil
that is each petro will be guaranteed by
a barrel of oil from the Venezuelan oil
reserves preserves.
That of course are still undergrounds in
this way.
If he petros value as apparently linked
to the value of this raw material
[inaudible] and you can get fairly Paco
[inaudible].
Does that sound any better?
Well hold on for either because we
cannot forget a detail,
a very,
very important detail.
They are reserves are of course under
the control of the government.
As I wonder,
do you really think that this government
is going to exploit those reserves and
even if they did,
do you think that really back the petro
and what about the support rates?
We didn't,
the resources generated some DB spends,
wouldn't they impose restrictions or
regulations that would benefit?
Yeah.
Them.
Why take the risk of investing in
Petros?
And by the way,
another important point here that petro,
it's not convertible.
That is to say even though it is
supposedly backed by oil barrels,
you can never exchange it for the barrel
or any title that proves a right over
those barrels.
The Petros a cryptocurrency that isn't
crypto,
that it's backed by reserves that aren't
reserves.
It's going only be monetized or the
production that is collapsing and issued
by a government that is in default and
has no dollars.
Francisco Menotti,
professor at the rice universities,
Baker Institute in Houston,
folks,
the battery doesn't seem to be anything
more than a last ditch.
Attempts to gain time and try to obtain
the greatest possible number of dollars
by taking advantage of the popularity of
cryptocurrencies and perhaps of capitol
laundering because well,
who would put their dollars on the
table?
Fact is that if this crypto it doesn't
work in,
that does look like the most plausible
scenario Madora his regime.
Well only have three options.
First,
accept some kind of internal revolts and
leave power one way or another,
which seems very difficult.
Second views and even tougher hands and
condemn Venezuela to even greater
humanitarian disaster or third,
try to get the Chinese and Russians to
by the country's national resources on
mass hands.
By all means trust that refineries,
that oil and maybe other raw materials.
That is to say they would essentially
become a sort of colony by selling at a
loss each and every one of their crown
jewels so that the regimes are leads,
can continue to enjoy their standard of
living.
So now today,
Nicolas Maduro in company,
they're still in power and it hardly
seems likely the Venezuela is going to
have a better future,
but now it's your sound.
Would you be willing to exchange your
money for that?
Trey's well leave your answer in the
comments below as well as in this survey
and is,
I really do hope you enjoyed this video.
Please do hit like if you did and don't
forget to subscribe to our channel for
brand new videos just like this every
Monday and every Thursday.
Also don't forget to check it off.
Friends at the reconsider media podcast.
They provided the vocals in this episode
that were not mine,
and as always,
thank you for watching.
Well.