Just before we get into the video today,
do you want to say that I recently
started a new channel,
it's called biographics.
We do long form,
20 minutes ish biographies of people
from history as well as the present day
politicians,
but a whole lot else.
Please check out the link in the
striction below and if you'd like
biographics please subscribe anyway.
Well,
everybody has their eyes on North Korea,
not their nuclear programs.
Still worries those in the White House.
That is the nuclear program of the
Islamic Republic of Iran.
This country has such a bad reputation
that when we talk about it,
it can feel like we're talking about one
of those places that only exists in the
movies,
one of those countries dominated by evil
leaders who dream of destroying the
world.
Well,
that might actually be some truth to
this,
but definitely not as much as some
seemed thing.
In fact,
Iran is not the most religious.
It's not the most authoritarian and it's
not even the most hostile place towards
women in this part of the world because
we have Saudi Arabia,
which is far,
far worse.
Dev,
you have,
Iran is a country of contradictions,
a country whose government claims to
work under a democratic system,
but at the same time everything is under
the control of one man.
Yeah.
That man would be allie harmony,
the supremes.
At first glance,
he isn't as scary as its predecessor
Ruhollah Khomeini,
who was scary.
Just have look at the truth is how many
econ stand anything modern for him?
Modality might as well have come from
Satan himself except for nuclear
technology,
of course,
explains why in the past few years
around has been famous for two things.
Number one,
being one of the country's alongside
China,
where the most people are executed every
year and number two,
wanting to build their own nuclear bomb.
However,
unlike what has happened with the North
Korean crisis,
the US and Iran,
they did reach an agreement.
Yeah.
In 2015,
President Obama led the joint
comprehensive plan of action and
agreements to prevent Iran from
obtaining a nuclear bomb as an agreement
to this many of considered to be one of
the greatest achievements in all the
foreign policy.
It's now more than 50 years since
President Kennedy stood before the
American people and said,
let us never negotiate out of fear,
but let us never fear to negotiate.
Although to Fab all signs seem to point
to the conclusion that this agreement
has not kept either party.
Saturday presidents of the United States
now,
Donald Trump is pretty clear about his
opinion on the deal ever since he was a
candidate.
He has described it as the worst
agreement ever negotiated during his
campaign.
Trump has vowed on many,
many occasions that his top priority
would be to put an end to such a
catastrophic agreements.
I've been doing deals for a long time,
been making lots
of wonderful deals,
great deals.
That's what I do.
Never ever,
ever in my life have I seen any
transaction so incompetently negotiated
as our deal with Iran.
And do you think that this was the
typical campaign message that every
politician repeats over and over again,
but then soon forgets about?
Well,
once the election has finished,
in his first speech at the UN assembly,
trump repeated it loud and clear.
The Iran deal was one of the worst and
most one sided transaction the United
States has ever entered into.
Frankly that deal is an embarrassment to
the United States and I don't think
you've heard the last of it.
Believe me,
they haven't done so.
Yes,
but it is true that both the president
sands,
many other members of the Republican
Party load,
yes,
absolutely low disagreements and they do
so because among other things
agreements,
we're also signed with North Korea.
This is a good deal for the United
States.
North Korea will freeze and then
dismantle its nuclear program.
South Korea and our other allies will be
better protected and well,
these agreements,
they didn't work at all except for
allowing [inaudible] to lay hands on the
bomb.
Well,
now you might be wondering why exactly
is it such a controversial agreements?
Well,
we're going to look at that in a bit.
Before we do.
Let's take a look at the context in
which it was signed.
Iran,
a budding superpower.
So during the Cold War it is said that
the Russians were so obsessed that they
saw a Chinese man behind every tree.
Something similar might not actually be
happening between it wrong and the USA,
since the Islamic revolution of command
I in 1979 in Iran has become one of
Washington's worst enemies.
It is accused of being the first sponsor
of radical and anti American groups like
Hezbollah,
Hamas or the Taliban.
Not to mention their support of the
Syrian regime under the Shah,
Al Assad,
but there is more to this.
Washington knows very well that Iran,
it's not just any country.
Iran is absolutely huge.
It's got $8,
million inhabitants and one of the
greatest amounts of mineral wealth on
and hey,
it's not just about oil and natural gas
here,
but it's also got other minerals like
copper,
iron,
zinc,
uranium,
silver,
etc.
Yes,
we do all know that oil and natural gas
spelled that particularly important and
that is why I now want to ask you a
question.
What is the biggest fear of manY
analysts in Washington?
Well,
that is the sum of Iraq and Iran.
So let me explain both countries and
neighbors ever majority shia ruled and
influence of tehran or baghdad has
skyrocketed in the last few years.
Yes,
we add up the oil reserves of both
countries for the amount is one of the
largest in the world.
It's larger than Saudi Arabia.
It's larger than Venezuela,
so coordinated international politics
between these two countries would result
in a superpower which is outside the
control of Washington with almost a
hundred and 20 million people that's not
mentioning all of those other natural
resources.
This quite simply would be an incredible
amount of influence,
so then what would happen if Iran got a
hold of a nuclear bomb?
Now,
on the one hand,
it would certainly consolidate its role
as an international suva power as well
as its influence over its allies like
Iraq,
but on the other hand,
it would also trigger an arms race with
Saudi Arabia and the emirates countries
that have already said they won't be
left behind.
If tiran managers to get a nuclear bomb.
The results of all this,
well,
that's pretty obvious.
It's tension,
it's risk of proliferation,
it's risk of nuclear disaster.
That's also a loss of american leverage
in the area.
It goes without saying,
but seeing such radical governments in
possession of such powerful weapons also
doesn't make anyone feel particularly
safe.
Well,
that was the situation when the
agreement was reached back in 2015,
the deal
years.
The United States is trying to stop the
nuclear program with financial
penalties,
but these were pretty useless.
Didn't they harm the economy in Iran?
Well,
absolutely,
but they did nothing to stop their
nuclear program.
Finally,
on november the 14th of July,
2015,
the nuclear deal was signed an agreement
with a clear target to prevent
proliferation and make sure Iran only
uses nuclear technology for peaceful
purposes.
However,
since then the deal,
it has suffered harsh attacks.
We're going to have a look at some of
the reasons cited by critics of this
agreement,
but first I think now is a good time to
think about the circumstances under
which this agreement was signed and the
first thing we need to note is that the
nuclear program in Iran is very,
very advanced.
AccordIng to us intelligence.
If the agreement was to be broken,
Iran could develop its first nuclear
bomb in a matter of months.
This is the way it is today,
2017,
and it was even true back in 2015 when
the iranian program was working at it's
fullest capacity.
That is why I want to take a moment to
think about three possible outcomes
here,
more agreements or Iran with nuclear
capability,
so stopping the nuclear program with
military intervention.
It would not have been an easy task.
It would have resulted in many victims.
The costs for the us would have been
prohibitive and the us.
We've had to keep a military
intervention in the middle east for
decades to compare.
It is estimated that this would be the
Iraq war multiplied by five because I
mean it's one thing to destroy
infrastructure and it's a very different
thing to eliminate the knowledge that a
country has to make nuclear bombs.
Obama kneW that the situation was
totally impossible.
What he wanted was to get away from the
middle east and not get into any more
trouble in this region because it's been
something of a chronic nightmare for the
United States.
Sure.
On the other hand is not doing anything.
Would've meant that Iran,
we've gotten their new toy and as we
have seen,
it would have resulted in an arms race
in the region,
which Washington didn't want either.
So an agreement,
it was the only option left.
I mean,
we make a deal and everyone's happy,
right?
Just wait there for a second.
Because despite that many experts,
especially republicans,
don't even want to hear about this pact.
Bad deal.
Obama broke every rule of negotiation.
We get an agreement,
a very questionable value.
If I am elected president on the very
first day in office,
I Will rip to shreds this catastrophic
iranian nuclear deal.
The iranians have been given a blank
check basically by,
uh,
by depressing the United States.
I think it will just warhawks determined
to impose their ideas by forced,
well,
maybe there are some like that.
But the truth is,
they all say the points they say when
they arise,
that the u s already signed many
agreements with North Korea and pyong
yang never kept its weren't which is
wide.
North korean is now in nuclear power.
They are convinced that Iran will do the
same and there is no better evidence
than the fact that Iran has not stopped
their ballistic missile program.
Iran is boosting its missile
capabilities in order to increase the
accuracy,
precision and range Iran will not stop
its missile projects
and this program,
what has being developed with North
Korea and technology.
So it seems clear which way deal with
Iran will go.
We cannot let a murderous regime
continue these destabilizing activities
while building dangerous missiles and we
cannot abide by an agreement if it
provides cover for the eventual
construction of a nuclear program.
The science,
since the bank does a limited duration,
Iran could still put itself in a
position to get its arsenal.
The moment the deal is over and it could
be armed within a matter of months.
However,
as we have seen the alternatives,
they're really not any better is that
Iran doesn't necessarily need to go the
way of North Korea.
You're on
benefits of the agreement.
I'm pretty sure many of you are thinking
that comparing North Korea and Iran is
easy after all,
both countries are radical
dictatorships,
right?
Well,
I mean not really to be.
Third things that quite a bit different.
Iranian society is much more open minded
than north korean society.
In Iran there is a well formed middle
class.
There are political debates and things
like having a smartphone and access to
the internet.
It's really quite common.
In fact,
most Iranians,
especially the younger generation,
clearly pro agreements,
you see,
it's not just a matter of international
politics,
it's also a matter of quantity of life.
The penalties is put in place by the
international community.
They were very damagIng for her in 2013
when presidents ahmadinejad the main
defender of the agreements left power
the economy of Iran.
It waS devastated.
For an investment vanished.
The unemployment rate skyrocketed.
Inflation grew to around 40 percent and
the expectations for improvements,
it's high.
In short,
it was a complete mess,
but thanks to the agreement that
penalties started to disappear and since
then aisle exports of triples.
I mean Iraq is not North Korea.
They need the trade on the economic
advantages that disagreement is.
Yeah.
Joint comprehensive plan of action will
produce the comprehensive lifting of all
un security council sanctions as well as
multilateral and national sanctions
related to iran's nuclear program,
including steps on access in areas of
trade,
technology,
finance,
and energy.
The hope for obama's administration was
that with a more prosperous and trade
open Iran,
the younger,
more openminded generation would be
allowed to take power in a few years.
However,
those who opposed the agreements argue
it's necessary to be more demanding with
roland because otherwise it will
eventually become another North Korea,
a new nuclear power.
Anyway,
it's not an easy situation is you can
see,
but truth be told,
I think it would be a mistake to think
that any pact is bad until proven
otherwise.
Having to run under pressure might be a
good strategy,
but let's be careful not to go too far,
but we could all lose.
Well,
now it's your turn.
If you were the president of the United
States,
what do you think you would do with
Iran,
which you make a deal,
but leave your answer in the comments
below as well as in this survey and I do
really hope that you enjoyed this video.
If you did,
please do not forget to subscribe to our
channel for brand new videos every
monday and every thurSday and don't
forget to check out our friends at the
reconsider media podcasts.
They provided the vocals in this episode
that we're not mine as well.
If you're looking for something else to
watch,
please do check out my brand new channel
biographics.
There's a link in the description below
and as always,
thank you for watching.