There's a country that always,
always,
always appears in the headlines of
international newspapers,
and it's for two main reasons why one of
them soccer and the other is economic
crisis.
The problem,
my friends lately,
these headlines on having more to do
with crises on the football,
I am of course talking about Argentina.
Yeah.
It's hard to say,
but Argentina is a country that is as
allergic to reforms as it is addicted to
crises.
When everything seemed to be going well,
2018 suddenly became very,
very complicated.
So much so that we're ECO Macra,
he's governments has been forced to to
ask for a bailout from the international
monetary funds.
So now you might be thinking really a
bailout Argentina again.
Well,
yes,
you heard it right.
Argentina,
the country of tango is back on the
ropes,
so listen up.
Okay.
April and May of 2018 haven't exactly
been great months for Argentina.
Okay.
That condition and
[inaudible]. [inaudible]
[inaudible].
That's who we ended up.
Sandy [inaudible] are the basis the
American,
yeah,
thanks.
And just a few weeks of pay.
So it was depreciated by 20% going from
an exchange rate of one US dollar for 20
pesos to an exchange rate of $1 getting
you 25 pesos.
You know what?
There's not exactly surprising since the
beginning of 2018 Argentina's currency
has depreciated by at 25% and if we
extended that time frame to five years,
could you guess how much the peso has
depreciated since then?
Well,
the reality is that it's been an
absolutely brutal 80% appreciation.
Make no mistake as though the plummeting
exchange rate isn't the problem.
It's the consequence
you see,
you Argentina's real problem lies in its
addiction to public spending.
And I'm not saying the public spending
is slightly higher than they can afford
here after they have such high public
spending that Argentina simply has no
ability to afford it.
Okay?
In the last 57 years,
we spent 53 years with the state
spending more than it collects.
That is with the fiscal deficits.
And during those 53 years,
we had four huge crises.
Now we're fighting to avoid a fifth one,
Jose Luis,
Bert and Argentine
economist.
But I know what you might be thinking
right now.
You're probably thinking,
Simon,
what the hell does public spending have
to do with the pcs depreciation?
Well,
actually much more than you'd think.
So let's go through it step by step.
Argentina is facing eight triple time
bomb.
It has a huge external deficits,
a huge public deficits,
and $250 billion of external desk.
Of course,
as you can imagine,
both the deficits and the dads have to
be paid.
Here's where that first big problem
appears.
He is,
and he is a protectionism,
devaluations,
hyper regulation,
and very high taxes.
Indeed,
Argentina is one of the countries with
the highest business taxes on the entire
planet.
Now,
all of this has stopped.
The industry ends,
the Argentine economy in general,
from being competitive.
It's also caused capitalists.
Do you flee the country long ago in such
a refuge somewhere else?
I mean,
it's a little sounds pretty logical,
right?
And so what's the result of this?
Well,
since there's no money at home,
Argentina has become very dependent on
foreign financing.
According to the Institute of
International Finance,
most almost 64% of Argentina's state and
corporate debt is denominated in dollars
and other foreign currency.
That's why both the volume of central
bank reserves and the exchange rate of
very,
very important.
Yeah,
of course,
on the one hand,
they need to pay for imports and deal
with debt payments,
but since Argentina has a negative
external balance,
that is,
it consumes more dollars than it gets.
It needs someone to lend them those
dollars.
It needs investors to bring money into
the country
and my friends,
if investors don't lend that money
because they don't trust the country,
then Argentina has a problem,
a really big problem.
On the other hands,
if the peso depreciates,
then obviously it loses value in folks.
Let's be honest,
nobody wants to have their savings in a
currency that the is so cool.
Okay,
sorry.
Well,
what do you do in that situation?
essentially what you do is you rush to
exchange all of your pieces for a
stronger and more stable currency and
well,
that's exactly what the population are
doing and that is causing the currency
to collapse.
Even further,
and of course that leaves two reserves
being consumed even faster,
but all right,
having said that,
let's take a look at that.
Yeah.
See,
both Nesta catch now ran the specialty.
Cristina Fernandez de Kartchner,
the two previous presidents of
Argentina,
they like to spend quite freely.
When they came to power in 2002 public
spending was equivalent to 23% of GDP
when they left,
when it was more like 40% now you might
be wondering,
well,
what did they do with all the money?
Well,
basically they hired public employees to
win votes and multiplied subsidies.
No,
in only 13 years,
public employment sought by 60% to give
you an idea of how extreme this was
today,
35% of employees in Argentina work for
the government.
Hopefully they're gonna share this.
[inaudible],
[inaudible], [inaudible]
select libido basis or Rochelle.
Okay,
get this in seven provinces in the
country,
there are more public workers,
then there are private.
It really is a crazy situation.
It's given that the government didn't
have enough money to pay for all of this
year after year,
they continue to register a huge public
deficits.
Now,
as you might know,
the coach and has couldn't go to the
international markets first because
they're investors didn't trust them in
seconds because the country was already
in the fall.
Okay.
He's wonderful.
He,
Naomi Luna,
a [inaudible] [inaudible]
[inaudible] [inaudible]
[inaudible] [inaudible] [inaudible]
oh,
nice.
Nine.
Of course,
if you don't pay your investors,
obviously the investors don't lend you
any more money.
All right,
so what do you think they did then?
Yeah,
they used every populist politicians
favorite machine,
the money printing machine.
They simply printed new pesos to pay
that public expenditure vasant and
establishing your currency camp,
which meant and limiting the amounts of
money there's Argentinians could take
out of the country.
So they wouldn't be,
Thomas said dwindling reserves.
And the question is,
what happens when these policies
continue?
Well,
inflation,
the soul is due to all the new stays in
circulation and foreign investors of
course do not want to come near you.
And so there was in these circumstances
that Mauricio Macri came to power
the mockery plants.
Mauricio Macri came to the Castle
Rosado.
He had a plan to implement reforms
little by little that were commonly
known as gradualism,
but eight to implement [inaudible]
economic [inaudible], [inaudible]
[inaudible],
[inaudible], [inaudible]
and the truth is they've actually been
quite successful.
The business climate has improved.
Some subsidies have been reduced and in
a way they regained the international
investors trust out of all the hard
things they needed to do if they've only
done the easiest ones.
What they haven't achieved in more than
two years of governing has been
decreasing the public deficits
flushing
in spite of having access to the
financial markets,
the options on government has continued
to prince bills to maintain that public
expenditure out of course means more
inflation.
This chart shows how the money is
growing.
That is how the Central Bank of the
Republic of Argentina continues to issue
more and more pesos.
Good.
All right.
Now you might be wondering,
well,
it wasn't Mauricio Macri that duty was
supposed to change things.
Well,
Gary was,
but slowly see this all has an
explanation.
Yeah.
Factories team's idea was to carry out
reforms and little by little to attract
investments and make the Argentine
economy grow.
If the economy grew,
the government would raise more money
and would not have to make cuts.
Meanwhile,
little by little,
as they regains the international
markets trust,
they would be able to issue a debt and
is thus reduce the need to print bills
in this way.
Within a few years,
Argentina would you got rid of that
deficits,
limit inflation and would start to grow
again.
It's an accurate,
of course would maintainers political
capital to continue winning elections.
It all sounds like a pretty great plant
rice.
Yeah.
Well,
so far things have actually kind of gone
his plans,
but just hold on a moment because things
have now changed and it's mainly for two
reasons.
Fast.
After two and a half years in power,
it's hard to understand how the public
deficits,
inflation and taxes continue to
skyrocket.
Gradualism how's it become something
like racing and arthritic at all and
seconds because the Federal Reserve of
the United States has begun to raise
interest rates C for public debt in the
United States,
the 10 year bond is already yielding 3%
okay.
Out of course,
many investors now asked themselves if
the u s desk,
which is supposedly the less risky
assets,
gives me a reasonable return.
Why on earth would I keep lending money
to Argentina?
Wow,
I see no changes.
Yeah,
well that's exactly what it is because
many people who were interested in
investing in Argentina to turn away from
it,
and for this reason,
macaroons,
governments has decided to resort to the
international monetary funds to obtain a
credit line with which to face the debt
maturities of the upcoming months and
the future.
Can you remember what would happen if a
new default occurred before the 2019
elections?
You see,
everything has to do with the
government's behaviour and if you think
about it for a moment,
it's actually very sensible.
The patients once held for Argentina,
it's gone.
What investors and Argentine savers find
themselves saying is fine.
If you want to spend more than you can
go right ahead,
but just don't do it with my money.
Yeah,
and this is north of me in regards of
public spending,
but many other reforms that make it
easier to do business.
And this,
it brings up a key question.
Is it time to abandon gradualism
aggressive therapies or gradualism
nope.
Flakes making reforms is never an easy
task,
but I think it's time for the castle
Rosado that's the Argentinian version of
the White House to osc itself.
A question shouldn't leave.
Perhaps try employing more aggressive
measures.
Well,
you know what?
First let's take a look at the
historical evidence.
Which do you think has worked better?
Gradualism a con step by step change or
aggressive therapy?
Hey,
we can see a good example of huge
transformations in the former countries
of the Soviet orbit.
When the communist model collapsed in
1989 many countries employed drastic
changes almost overnight while others,
obs,
there's four more gradual measures.
Now's the best results.
It was the ones that made the most
good
trees,
assumptions,
Estonia,
Latvia,
Lithuania,
Poland,
and the Czech Republic opposite for a
more drastic change that is making
reforms as quickly as possible.
Yeah,
it was pretty hot at the beginning,
but soon they began to grow and they
achieved all kinds of investments to
such an extent that today these
countries which were mostly poor in 1989
have a higher standard of living than
Portugal or any Latin American country.
On the other hand is though you see what
plying gradual reforms,
countries such as Ukraine,
Romania,
Tajikistan,
ends,
Armenia,
well,
let's just say things haven't gone so
well either an economic or social tams.
Anyway,
if I x,
this is a decision that macri is
government has to make.
It has to decide whether to take
advantage of the IMF,
some money to carry out strong reforms
once and for all or continue with grand
jury will listen it and let's be clear.
If Argentina doesn't fix its public debt
and stopped printing bills,
the future does not look good.
Borrowing money is in good governance.
Good governance is creating basic
reforms.
In Argentina.
There's an elephant Tine,
gigantic hypertrophied state that needs
to be slimmed down.
They need to cut public spending.
Jame Bailey,
in addition,
the model simply doesn't work.
The Argentine government has never spent
so much,
and despite that it's been decades since
there was so much poverty and so much
violence.
But we'll mastery listener.
Well,
I need the future will tell,
but now it's your turn.
What do you think?
Should they continue with the gradual
reforms or is it time for a faster
change while leave your answer in the
comments below as well as in this
survey,
and I know this was a bit of a dense
subjects,
but I hope with this video we were able
to shed some light on us and I really
have keep did enjoy the video.
So please do pit that like button if you
did.
And don't forget to subscribe to our
channel for brand new videos every
Monday and every Thursday.
Also,
don't forget to check it off.
Friends at the reconsider media podcast
who provided the vocals in this episode
that we're not mine.
And as always,
thank you for watching.