Run out of these one of the most
innovative companies on the planet,
and yet it also manages to be one of the
most hated.
Yeah,
yeah.
We've all heard of companies like tesla
or hyperbole,
but.
But let's be honest,
it's going to be years before those
companies actually change lives.
If they ever,
dear ron and I have created a revolution
or ready and I'm not worried about
European.
Ron has sway.
You can be felt worldwide,
but on the other side of things,
it's hard to find someone who doesn't
hate this ally.
This is partly due to the efforts of its
CEO,
Michael O'leary.
He seems to have worked really hard to
become the man you love to hate with
quotes like this one,
but we need fewer people queuing to go
to the toilet.
How do you get fewer people queuing to
go to the toilet,
charge them for it,
or how about this one?
Nobody wants to sit beside a really fat
that's on board.
We have been frankly astonished at the
number of customers who don't only want
to tax people,
but torture them.
Well,
it's actually another reason people hate
ron already.
If you've been following this channel,
all my others,
you might already know that I live in
Prague,
in the Czech Republic.
Now,
why Paul is on this channel,
they live over in Madrid,
in Spain and until there's a very month,
the cost of a flight to go from here in
Prague to Madrid,
cost about 250 American dollars,
but this year,
well Ryan and I came down and they
managed to offer Prague to Madrid routes
for about $90.
And what did the other airlines do in
response to this?
Well,
they were also forced to lower their
prices and this didn't just happen
between Progam Madrid.
This happened all across Europe.
Anywhere Ryan out operates the rest of
it's competitors.
Hats put down their prices in order to
remain competitive.
This meant lower profits or even
potential bankrupt.
Let's see.
Just to have a look at British Airways
in the year 2000,
they carried over 46 million passengers,
but just eight years later they didn't
even carry 33 million.
And of course,
those big airlines like British Airways
or Lufthansa or Iberia,
they spent a fortune buying ads in the
media and well,
because it was ad buy,
they want the love of journalists sand.
Well,
you know,
you didn't have much love from
journalists.
Well that would be ryanair because they
never really bought any apps.
Well,
despite this bad reputation,
there are only a few companies that can
claim to have changed an entire industry
the way that Ryan did.
And as I said before,
this is not only a European thing,
Ryan air effects can be felt around the
wells except perhaps in Latin America.
So the first question we have to ask
here is,
how did Ryan ever changed the world?
Why do regions like Latin America need a
company like this?
Most important of all,
how does Ryan App managed to author
these ludicrously low prices?
Well,
today we are going to answer all those
questions,
but first let's take a look back at the
history.
Why is Ryan Air so cheap?
Back in the 19 eighties and Madrid
salons in flight cost the equivalent of
$700 back then in Spain.
This was the average monthly wage.
Everyone understood that flying well.
It was a luxury.
I mean at the end of the day,
planes,
they're really expensive and there
wasn't really anything anyone could do.
Nevertheless,
the reason why flights with that
expensive actually had little to do with
the technology and just had much more to
do with politics.
Yes,
this really is true because back then
average,
they will based on agreements between
governments.
For instance,
the French government and the American
one,
they had a deal,
so only French and American airlines
could fly between Paris and New York
City.
The same happens with the rest of the
European countries.
Airlines.
They had essentially a monopoly over the
roots that they operate,
so there really was no incentive for
them to lower fares because they could
simply make a fortune selling $700
tickets.
Back then it was really only British and
Irish people.
You could enjoy it,
Ryan as lower fares,
but then in April of 19,
97 things,
they changed for
any technically qualified airline in the
European Union.
Plus,
Norway and Iceland will be able to run
services inside any other country.
All of a sudden,
all these European carriers,
they could compete against each other.
They didn't really know how.
This is why they are heavily invested in
advertising and more luxuries.
They make that a food more comfortable
seats and even gave corporate gifts to
passengers.
Ronna instead,
they.
That's on a totally different strategy.
Airlines are asking how they can put up
barriers.
We are asking how we could get rid of
them
saying this in 1997,
it was totally crazy.
Of course there were already on the
budget guidelines like the American
Airlines,
southwest,
but runner,
they wanted to go even further.
This is why they found new ways to
reduce the costs to an absolute minimum.
For example,
the landing cost depended partly on the
of the town lines,
paid to the airports landing.
It's Brussels central lab is costly,
but 60 kilometers south,
if there is Charlotte Roy airports which
offers way lower landing fees simply by
choosing to fly to that airport.
Ryan at,
they saved another cost saving policy,
was utilizing the same athlete model for
all of the roots and this airplane.
It was the Boeing seven,
three,
seven other companies like Lufthansa,
they worked with over 14 different types
of airplanes.
This means they needed 14 maintenance
technicians.
Each of them are specialized on a
different model of aircraft.
Ronna instead,
they could do the same with just a few
experts.
This means that while Lufthansa needed
hours between flights,
do maintenance checks,
Ryanair needed half that time,
and of course after this,
the rest of the extra costs that they
saved during the flights do you want to
use on the airplane?
Well,
that's extra.
Do you want to carry on baggage that's
extra to you.
Want to choose your seats every year,
Ron and finds new ways to reduce costs.
For instance,
a few years ago on the backs of their
seats,
they started posting adverts,
but the real turning points in this
company came in the year 2000.
This was the time when Michael O'leary
made a decision that changed the entire
industry for
bye.
The travel agents take the out and shoot
them.
What have they done for passengers over
the last years in the year?
2,000 runner was the first company to
create a website where you could book
tickets online.
Prior to that it was impossible to buy
your own plane ticket unless you lived
close to the airport.
So travel agents,
they were a pretty essential middleman.
And of course these travel agents,
they've charged commissions and these
conditions went up to 30 percent now in
stats passengers could just go to the
website to find the cheapest flights.
And then bias,
do they.
This is completely normal,
but back then it was a revolution and
they put lots of travel agents,
business with all of this.
By the year 2010,
Ron,
eh could offer tickets for an average
price of 40 US dollars.
I mean,
that's cheap,
but it's pretty ridiculous when you
consider these $700 to get the we were
talking about before.
All right?
All right.
So now you might be wondering,
why aren't we saying cheap flights,
uh,
such a revolution.
Think about it.
Since Ryanair extended its business in
Europe,
the amount of passengers has tripled.
Pay attention to the chart here because
we're talking about much more than
tourism here.
Okay,
thanks to cheap flights.
Students exchange programs have
multiplied by five since 2007.
In fact,
if you are watching this video from
anywhere in Europe,
you might have studied abroad with an
erasmus programme or have a friend do
did,
and the same goes for labor mobility,
which has tripled in a decade.
It would be hard to measure all the
small businesses that have been born
thanks to cheap flights.
They can even allow the most modest
freelancer to find clients and another.
Okay.
I'm sorry,
hold on for just a minute because
there's another detail that we must keep
in mindset.
If you look carefully,
you will see that while flying has
increased in Europe,
Latin America seems to be immune to
those changes and didn't like to say
that the air effects it was worldwide.
I mean,
well what happens in Latin America,
the Ryanair effect.
I know what you're thinking.
Ronnette just operates in Europe.
I mean,
how could they have such a big influence
on the rest of the wells?
Well,
I'll let you draw your own conclusions.
Take Airasia.
They were an airline owned by the
Malaysian government at the beginning of
the two thousands that you want on the
verge of bankruptcy.
Then in 2011,
the Malaysian businessmen,
Tony Fernandez bought it and followed
the Ryanair model that it started to
work in Europe and Asia.
They adopted the slogan and now everyone
can fly and they offered to the first
low cost flights on the continents.
Suddenly Corolla the important Macau
could be done for less than $90.
It happened Europe,
Asia then
sold the birth of many other low cost
airlines from lion era of Indonesia to
Cebu Pacific and the Philippines.
Even a country as poor and as big as
India has seen it,
the amount of passengers triple in just
10 years.
Hold on again for just a minute because
there's still that pulse of the planet
which seems immune to the Ryan Air
Effects and this area as we mentioned,
whether it's Latin America for example,
a cheap flight between Bogota or in
Colombia and Mexico City costs $460.
John's compare that with the $86 that
you could pay going from quality
important Taipei,
and in case you want to check the
distance,
both are more or less than
dot,
and the same goes if you want to go from
Libor and Peru to La Paz in Bolivia.
This is a three hour flight and it costs
$600 and yes,
this is more than the average monthly
wage in most Latin American countries.
So now you might be wondering why is it
so damn expensive to fly in Latin
America?
Why don't they have some Ryanair like
company?
The answer lies again in politics.
In other words,
legislation in the region has made it
impossible for a company to appear.
If an airline wants to work in Brazil,
they need to have at least 20 percent of
their capital owned by resilience and
two years ago this percentage,
it was even higher.
This is why it went avianca re,
Colombian carrier wanted to open two
markets in the country.
The government forced them to start a
brand new company with their
headquarters in Brazil.
Thus Avianca runs Avianca,
Brazil,
all two entirely different companies.
Despite the fact that they do belong to
the same group that Brazil,
that'll be any country that protects
their analysis.
Year 2016,
Argentenians wanted to fly.
I could only choose between two
companies.
Argentina,
Lat am a private carrier and outer your
lineage.
Argentina's a state owned airline for
decades that Christina Fernandez,
the administration made sure no other
airline could compete with these
airlines,
and the same goes for the airports,
the that could cut costs.
It's thanks to you taking off and
landing at airports.
Well,
this is possibly in Europe because one
out of every four airport,
some managed by a marriage between the
government and private companies.
Thanks to this airports must compete
with each other by offering better
services and love affairs.
It's not by chance that half of European
air traffic comes from private airports.
Latin America though it's a different
story.
Most of their airports are managed
solely by the governments.
If there is no competition,
they simply have no interest in reducing
fats.
And other words Brian Enter is failed to
have an effect on this region because of
politics and well.
What are the consequences of this?
Well,
despite the fact that there's many Latin
American countries have grown
economically in the past few years,
flying is still a privilege for the
rich.
This is my vision.
I've been to the mountaintop.
I've seen the lights.
Now the question becomes,
do you think Latin America should
liberalize its aspects?
Do you think that everyone could benefit
from a company like Ron out operating in
his own country?
Well,
please do it.
Leave your answers in the comments
section below because we'd love to hear
from you.
Meanwhile,
if you want to know how Ireland stepped
out of poverty and became the powerhouse
that it is today,
well do you click on this video?
Also do visit reconsider media.com,
the podcast that provided the vocals in
this video that are not mine,
and as always I'll see you in the next
video
and if you want to learn more about
politics and hear more of my lovely
voice,
don't forget to check out.
Reconsider podcast@reconsidermedia.com.
We consider as a podcast that challenges
you to reconsider your views by
providing context,
but we don't do the thinking.