Heroin,
visual politic,
we've already made several videos about
how Venezuela is going through its
toughest times,
however we still need to address one of
the most serious consequences of the
Bolivarian Revolution is gigantic
failure and there's no debate here.
Venezuela is adrift with every day that
passes life in this country.
It just becomes harder and harder with
some of the highest violence,
poverty and inflation indices in the
worlds and with a growing drug
trafficking and organized crime
industry.
Many,
many Venezuelans condo find any
alternative to putting some space
between themselves and their homelands.
That is even behind the country that's
falling apart.
Ministry,
Latina,
so Seattle bullied the Tara.
Well,
if you were in a situation like this,
would any of you have any hope?
I mean,
I would certainly try to escape and
that's exactly what more and more
Venezuelans are doing,
especially the youngest ones.
Now,
some of you might be wondering,
well,
okay Simon,
but how big is this problem?
In reality,
what you see,
according to the UN's calculations from
2014 to June of 2018,
around at two point 3 million
Venezuelans left their country and these
numbers,
they're not gonna.
Stop from growing anytime soon.
See when total of one I see.
Let me see.
Hold on the door for them.
In other words,
the Bolivarian Revolution has caused the
greatest exodus in the history of Latin
America,
so listen up.
The exodus,
societies are entities in constant
movement throughout history,
migration has been continuous,
whether economic or for political
reasons,
to find better opportunities to escape
from a threat or simply to escape bad
living conditions.
People are continually moving from one
place to another,
not that
however,
an exodus is something quite different.
The term exodus refers to the mass
immigration of people who are forced to
leave the place where they live.
That is to say it isn't about people who
dream of a better life,
but people who have to leave in order to
survive.
In general,
throughout history,
the most common causes have been
political,
racial,
or religious.
Perhaps the most common type of exodus
throughout history has been that bite
people forced to leave their homes
because another stronger group took over
and expelled them.
Violence.
For example,
there's the exodus of the Armenian
people in Nineteen 15 when hundreds of
thousands of people were forced to
escape from the Turkish empire,
a process that became known as the
Armenian genocide.
I know the case would be bass of the
tens of thousands of Republicans who
faced the threat of reprisal,
torture,
and condemnation of all kinds from the
frank [inaudible] and were forced to
leave Spain the end of the Spanish civil
war or what happens in the second world
war or with the fight for independence
in African and Asian countries in the 19
sixties.
Well,
in all times we've had two very clear
examples.
The first was a product of the Syrian
civil war,
which since its beginning in 2011,
has driven millions of people to move
inside and outside of its borders.
The second case is that a Venezuelan,
then everything indicates that it's
exodus will end up being much,
much bigger than serious at this moment.
The migration of Venezuelans should be
described as a forced migration as it's
not planned.
It's for survival.
Beatrice Borgess,
executive director of the Justice and
Peace Center in Venezuela because folks,
we need to understand what's happening
here,
understand that the hundreds of
thousands of Venezuelans who are
escaping,
they don't do it for pleasure,
they do it out of necessity,
and unlike the examples we've covered
here,
the Venezuelan exodus isn't the result
of a war or the occupation of a foreign
force,
but have the hunger fear and the misery
caused by the Bolivarian Revolution.
You see,
according to the mass living condition
survey in 2018,
87 percent of Venezuelans living poverty
and more than 60 percent in extreme
poverty.
These are sub Saharan African numbers.
Yes.
The paradox is that this humanitarian
catastrophe is happening in one of the
most important oil powers in the world.
Folks,
the situation,
it's beginning to get real serious.
For example,
due to a lack of medicine and health
equipment within the country,
diseases such as measles,
tuberculosis,
and malaria.
Diseases that have been eradicated in
the country haven't only reemerged in
some cases they've become real
epidemics,
ends what's more,
there are more than 100,000 HIV AIDS
patients at risk due to a lack of access
to necessary medication.
United Nations Office for the
Coordination of human affairs,
and of course this lack of medicine has
lethal consequences for the population,
but that's not all.
Venezuela is experiencing such a huge
production and supply problem that it's
becoming increasingly difficult to
acquire basic food products.
For example,
the can of tuna can cost more than a
minimum wage salary.
That athletics explains why according to
data from the United Nations where ideas
Datto,
Qbo and the rest of the regime,
John's a growing fat lobster dinners
around one and a half million
Venezuelans are currently suffering from
malnutrition and then there's the
violence issue,
which is also no joke.
Homicide statistics for example,
are out levels typical of a country in a
civil war.
Check this out and then there's of
course robberies,
losing extortion,
and all the other crimes that have made
this country a very dangerous place to
live and the Bolivarian Place.
They don't help listen
more than percent
of the crimes.
In July,
we're committed by police officials,
Venezuelan observatory of violence,
so faced with this scenario,
we can't be surprised that just in the
last three years,
2 million Venezuelans have left the
country by sea and land
that's
surely you've all seen the huge rows of
Venezuelans walking step by step towards
the border because most of those who
flee on foot or sometimes take buses,
calls,
mules,
but lately many have begun simply
walking to Columbia,
Brazil,
and Ecuador first and then maybe from
that of hurry,
Chile or Argentina.
Of course,
this is not an easy trip.
The journey is hard not only because of
how tiring it isn't because of what they
leave behind families,
friends in their homes,
but in many cases,
these refugees fall victim to
fraudsters,
thieves until the nefarious characters.
Fortunately so far,
the other Latin American countries have
shown great solidarity and have allowed
almost unrestricted entry to the
hundreds of thousands of Venezuelans.
However,
this could all change.
Receiving so many people at once isn't
always easy,
especially if the recipients on exactly
rich countries,
huge pressure
folks.
It's true,
some Latin American countries are
beginning to feel a lot of pressure.
The Venezuelan exodus is so great.
Then in some cases they're facing
serious capacity problems.
For example,
in the border stage of Reimer in Brazil,
the number of Venezuelans attending
medical centers has increased from 700
in 2014 to more than 50,000 in 2017 just
in the first three months of 2018.
The number reached over 45,000 every day
around seven to 800 Venezuelans cross
the border and that's creating a lot of
trouble for their vaccination and
organization.
Michel Temer,
president of Brazil in Columbia,
the number of Venezuelans already
exceeds 1 million people.
In Peru,
there are more than $400,000 in Ecuador.
It's almost a quarter of a million.
The way this is so big that in 2018,
so far more than 4,000 Venezuelans have
arrived in Ecuador every day.
Of course,
many of them go onto other countries,
countries like Chile,
which in the first six months between
January and June received almost 150,000
Venezuelans.
All of this is causing the most effected
countries to begin establishing some
measures to reduce this huge flow of
people.
The Brazilian government,
for example,
has announced the deployment of the
military at the border and just stated
that it will consider establishing
quotas that is a maximum number of
people who can enter the country for
their past Ecuador and Peru have begun
to demand the presentation of passports.
And why is that?
Well,
that's because possible.
It's not exactly easy to obtain and
Nicolas Maduro,
Venezuela because for one,
there's a bureaucratic labyrinth and
also the simple facts that the
government lacks.
The paper needed to actually print.
Oh,
and then there's little say the Fang
that because many officials do great
business by selling possibles on the
black market where a simple
possibilities,
official price is only about the
equivalent of twenty cents can cost
between $705,500 depending on how
quickly you need us or how much money
the buyer has
the new face or face to own new.
And for those who are lucky enough to
already have a passport when it expires,
they can extend its validity for two
more years with a stamp because they
won't get another passport.
But even so,
getting that stamp,
unless you go through the black market,
can take up to three months
chocolate
anyway,
that's the way things are for the first
time.
Last in America is facing a serious
problem with its borders and it's not an
easy problem.
On the one hand,
you can't prevent Venezuelans from
coming in.
It's a humanitarian issue and there's
still a huge margin of refugees to
citizens,
but it's evidence that if things go on
like this,
more and more people will try to escape
the country.
And that's quite a challenge here.
Every Latin American country needs to
work in a coordinated manner and receive
support from the international
community.
Of course,
to be fatty acid and solidarity shown by
many of the regions countries has been
extraordinary.
It's been an incredible example of that
in unity.
And by the way,
one final note here isn't really common.
Venezuelans who were leaving in recent
years,
many Venezuelans who made a fortune
during the bolivarian revolution,
dark period as well as the families of
many high ranking officials if also
left,
and of course they've done it with a
full wallet.
Former ministers of Chavez hit 2 billion
euros and on Dora the opulent landing of
Venezuelan millionaires in Spain,
a dozen businessman and former top
officials,
some of them detained for corruption,
have invested tens of millions in luxury
real estate and hunting ranches.
These are known as Bala Chicos and we're
going to try and do a video about them
in the future,
but for now it's your turn.
Do you think that the international
community should help the Venezuelan
people more?
Well,
leave your answer in the comments below
as well as in this survey and I really
hope you enjoyed this video.
Please do hit like if you did and don't
forget to subscribe for brand new
videos.
Also,
don't forget to track it.
Our friends at the reconsider media
podcasts,
they provided the vocals in this episode
that went on mine.
Also.
This channel is made possible because of
patriot and our patrons on that platform
to use.
Do you consider joining them and
supporting our mission of providing
independent political coverage,
and as always,
I'll see you in the next video.