[inaudible],
Venezuelan,
as long game of thrones,
we all want to know how it's going to
ends,
but at the same time we all know that
we're going to be disappointed with the
ending and this is exactly what are we
going to be talking about today.
Many of you have the same question in
mind.
How can the Venezuelan crisis and yeah,
we are talking about one of the biggest
financial and humanitarian catastrophes
in modern history in just 10 years
they've gone from exporting oil to
exporting refugees,
but you already knew this.
We've got several videos here on visual
politic that cover this very issue.
Of course,
Venezuela is not the only country that
has gone completely bankrupt.
You also have the example of Nicaragua
during the 1980s Nicaragua suffered from
hyperinflation,
scarcity of resources and extreme
poverty as well,
but in that case there was a clear
alternative to power and it was easy to
figure out what could happen there.
Venezuela instead is a big time mystery.
Think about it.
The Venezuelan president,
Nicolas Maduro is up against the wall.
As we said in this video.
He even came up with his own
cryptocurrency,
the petro as a desperate attempt to get
some foreign currency.
If things keep going this way,
he won't even have the money to pay the
army.
That keeps them empower.
But this is not the worst problem.
The real mystery of oven is wheeler is
who is the alternative is they're really
somebody who can substitute Maduro's
rule,
somebody with enough political capital
to change things in this country and
it's hard to say.
So far summary,
it is almost impossible to understand is
the current political situation in
Venezuela.
And then this is why we wanted to talk
to one of the world's largest experts in
political transitions and you might
wonder,
well,
who are we talking about here in a story
in from a think tank and economist
maybe?
Well,
we've got someone way better if I'm
headed up was the finance minister of
the Czech Republic during the first
years after the fall of communism.
He is one of the architects of the Czech
Republic as it exists today,
but this is not the end of the story.
After having a remarkable political
career,
he started a business in South America.
This means he knows this region as well
as the palm of his hands.
And with that said,
let me introduce you to him.
Hello to all the visual poetic
subscribers.
All right,
Simon,
it's just impossible to imagine what
could actually happen in ministry.
But
today we are going to draw three
different or things show scenarios based
on the recent history.
So today's question is what can happen
in Venezuela?
What potential scenarios can we foresee
in this country?
We're going to answer these questions,
but before we do,
let's take a look back at the history.
Correct
way out.
Remember this name [inaudible] Slav.
Javiel few people have had more
influence on the history of a country
than him.
He must lizard be achieved.
Yeah,
it looks basically the Czech Republic.
We know today the Czech Republic Web,
I happen to live is what it is.
Thanks to Vat,
Slav Harwell and believe me,
this is a big success story for a
democratic transition.
While other countries like Russia or
Ukraine are still poor and unequal
societies,
the Czech Republic is prosperous,
modern.
And surprisingly egalitarian,
they have low unemployment,
a thriving middle class and it's the
political rights of any other European
country that well,
how did they get?
Yeah,
until the year 1,989
checks lift the mosquito control
government under the dictatorship of
good stuff.
Gustafason things like going abroad on
vacation or forbidden or very difficult.
If you wanted to rent a house or flat,
you will need a special permits is with
achy years.
Yeah.
Countries like bullet this fine.
Having to communist regime David A.
Little bit more open in effect manage
checks even though it's trying to cross
the Polish border so they could buy
books.
It pigeon in Czechoslovakia.
It's time
nonetheless.
Everything changed at the end of the
1980s
you,
us though we never had the
hyperinflation to heaven.
Banish valid today.
We did suffer scar seats.
Did you want to buy a car?
You had to have faith for years onto the
state.
Urgh factory would send your basic
things like bananas but a luxury.
It was impossible to find in most of the
shops,
maybe with exception of Christmas.
The same happened with most of the
fruits and vegetables,
meats at many different other products
add to this.
The fact that the Soviet Union couldn't
send money to that allies anymore.
So with no foreign support in the
bankrupt economy,
it's normal to have all kinds of
protests.
Of course,
that first police suppress the protests
against hossack.
Raul,
of course,
on the first stage,
Balistreri brands,
the protest a cane Zulu sat through.
But what happens when all of a sudden
you have more than 250,000
people in the streets of Brac?
You gotta be crazy to start shooting
quarter of million beads.
Nicolas Maduro,
the Czechoslovakia and government
understood that the best thing they
could do with step down from power in a
peaceful fashion,
thanks to this Gustaf who sank it got
his golden retirement and the check
revolution was known as the velvet
revolution because no blood was spilled.
Nonetheless,
as I said at the beginning,
the key to this process was the
prominent figure of Vaslav Harville.
He was a famous writer back then,
and so he managed to capitalize on all
of the political unrest.
Sure.
And love will overcome lies and hate.
True Fuss.
Love Harvard Bachelor.
Hello,
we'll slot schooler known before and
with all the tribulation came up,
but he had all the elements to become a
good leader.
The question now is,
is that any Venezuelan vaults love
Harwell,
maybe somebody we don't know that could
emerge as a charismatic leader able to
change everything.
The answer is,
unfortunately that we don't know and
this is why we should talk about the
more pessimistic scenario manian way
out.
What happens when a dictator doesn't
want to leave power,
even if the situation is getting out of
hand.
I'm telling you right now,
it's nothing good.
We've said it before here.
A visual politic,
despite how it looks,
being an authoritarian ruler is a risky
job.
Glass Churches,
school is the best proof of this.
You know,
choking.
Get both of them.
The most brutal dictators we ever had.
[inaudible]
I like Nicolas Maduro equal ass jokes.
He didn't even care about pretending to
organize elections.
It was a system based on the cult of
personality,
but you know when the economy goes
south,
even Europe's most authoritarians
dictator has problems.
Just like the rest of the communist
countries.
At the end of the 1980s Romania was at
the edge of bankruptcy in some regions.
They even had kids with malnutrition.
Nonetheless,
on December the 25th 1989 after giving a
massive speech,
the citizens went from clapping their
hands to booing him in a matter of
seconds.
Days later,
the Romanian equivalent of Kim Jong Uhmm
was executed by his people.
Aye.
Beyond nuts talking about a revolution
against the regime.
He was not even killed by county
humanist activists.
In fact,
vouchers school was executed by the
members of his own party.
It was kind of injuring Gudetama,
the moderate faction of the Romanian
Communist Party do to control of the
Romanian government.
In the case of Venezuela,
this good be a faction of his own
governments or the army.
Of course,
it doesn't have to finish the execution
of anybody.
They could just kick him out of the
country and you could end up living in a
mansion and any other nation that would
accept him.
It wouldn't be the first time this has
happened and it certainly won't be the
last but just like in Romania,
the changes in government would it be
pure lip service,
different faces but at the same values,
the same policies although perhaps a
little more moderate.
Well at this school year to do these
Romania,
he's not a special example of the
transition but at least now we have a
stable carpentry with some economic
movement and growth and the reason I was
extreme poverty anymore and there are
opportunities in the for of future form
and I do now have to make a a serious
and important decides.
I want to be really clear about this.
We're not wishing any personal harm on
Nicolas Maduro or anyone from his
government here are visual politic.
We would never advocate for any kind of
violence in this video.
We're simply exploring potential
scenarios that might or might not happen
based on previous occurrences and that
really is all that said.
This Romanian way out doesn't seem
likely to happen either.
That is why we will focus on the latest
possible scenario.
Something that might sound at surreal,
but everything seems to be possible in
fairness way
a country for sale that Chinese way out.
In this other video,
we explained to you why China is the
only strong ally left of Venezuela.
The truth is that China has lens more
than $60 billion to Madurai as
governments.
Much of this credit comes in what we
call oil loans.
There's means China gives money to
Venezuela and Venezuela instead of
giving back.
Hard currency gives oil barrels,
and this makes sense,
right?
If there was something abundance in this
country,
that would certainly be it's dinosaur
juice.
In fact,
they have the world's biggest reserves,
so it seems to be a pretty good deal for
the Douro.
Right?
Well,
that is a problem here because as you
know,
the Venezuelan oil company PDVSA has a
big crisis too.
It is more expensive to drill and
extract oil in Venezuela than in any
other country,
including Norway and Canada.
This explains why p Dvsa can no longer
extract that own resources.
This company is producing of just 43% of
their capacity and it's getting lower
and lower.
Oh,
many Chinese investors are losing their
patients.
Don't forget,
we are not only talking about
[inaudible] being government here.
There are many private companies
involved here,
companies that both have an Israeli in
debt bonds or firms that hidden stake on
of an Israelian industry.
This is why we can find use languages
trying to see no peck,
sue's Venezuela in sign of fraying
relations.
So the question now,
the real question is what would happen
in Venezuela if they can't give back
those Chinese loans?
Well,
a default is unlikely.
China is paying for the military and the
police of Maduro.
This means that at any moment they could
simply shut down the government.
So what could they do instead?
Well,
they could seize pdv essay properties
and these might have viewers are the
crown jewels of this coming,
trey,
Brian,
you bet.
We are saying,
but it is a board of managers could do
the necessary font so the company can go
back to work normally.
Okay?
Today if you DVSA assets are worth $230
billion,
Maduro owes Xi Jingping more than $60
billion.
In other words,
Beijing could be entitled to seize a
forth of PTV essays,
assets,
and don't forget that pdv essay is the
biggest,
if not the only company in Venezuela.
Don't forget here that their dinosaur
juice is 97% of their export,
say only lean.
PDV I say is sort of the same as owning
Venezuela as a whole.
Well,
I didn't bring simple,
Oh,
this would be good for good use for
veneers,
but it would immobilize because Maduro's
government.
Yeah,
the words,
it would be like selling Jehovah
mcconnachie to the Chinese universities.
Okay.
All right,
so I know what you're all thinking right
now.
You're probably thinking,
come on Simon,
this is science fiction.
It can't actually happen.
Well,
let me tell you that there are already
signs that something like this could
happen.
Just look at the news published in Shane
Choir News,
as you probably guessed by the name
shake.
One News is a Chinese news sites that
follows Tszujing pings views have a look
at this.
Judo creates Venezuela's first petro
special economic zone.
Anytime China wants to do big business
with a poorer country,
the first thing they do is create a
special economic zone,
an area with special laws based on
Chinese regulations and low taxes for
business.
But in this case,
this could even go further.
We're not talking about investing in a
country or doing business.
We are talking about buying the backbone
of the Bolivarian Revolution here.
Without pd Vsa,
Maduro is like a hip hop artist without
the bling bling chains.
So if you can control the economy of the
country,
including the way that it gets its
finances,
couldn't we say that you've sort of
already bought it?
Well,
this is what could end up happening in
Venezuela.
It will be one of the first times in
history where our whole nation is sold.
Perfect.
Again,
this is really hard to conceive,
but as I've already said,
everything is possible in Venezuela,
but now,
well it's your 10 which of these three
scenarios is more to happen or do you
think we'll see a mixture of all of
them?
These won't leave your answer in the
comments section below.
It has been a pleasure to be here with
you guys.
If you wants to keep in touch with me,
you can find me on twitter at the wine
bar.
She you soon.
Maybe
also,
please don't forget to check it our
patrion on page so you can support this
project.
And if you like this video,
please do subscribe to this channel so
you won't miss any posts.
Sense.
There's always,
I'll see you next time
and if you want to learn more about
politics and hear even more of my lovely
voice,
you can join us at reconsider media.
We have a podcast@reconsideredmedia.com
slash podcast see you there.