Located in the Persian Gulf because
Howard is a country with an area of a
little more than 10,000 square
kilometers,
just to give you some idea of just how
small that is.
Nearly 40 times smaller than California,
so when this country got its
independence from the UK in Nineteen 71
guitar was a faraway,
hostile and very,
very poor place.
As a matter of fact,
it was one of the poorest territories of
the United Kingdom and well that kind of
made a lot of sense.
The Guitar Peninsula is a place where
temperatures can reach 50 degrees
Celsius in summer.
It's almost completely covered by desert
and it was certainly one of the most
uninhabitable places on earth,
but it didn't stay that way forever.
And today guitar is the richest country
on the planet.
Well,
that's right to the citizens of this
tiny nation.
Enjoy a per capita income of more than
$125,000,
which is almost three times the income
in France.
And to follow your time is that found in
really.
This is a country which was almost
uninhabited.
A country third could hardly survive on
it's fishing industry,
and today it looks something like
scrooge mcduck safe
governments,
government investments and properties
all around the world,
the birthplace of Alpha zero,
the most important Arabic media company.
Well then there was Doha,
the capital,
which is a sea of skyscrapers and
luxurious cars,
a mix of Monaco in vegas,
but without the alcohol and gambling,
there's no room for simplicity.
Everything is sumptuous,
huge and sparkling in Doha on how
Sausalito conflict areas reporter gets,
has gone from being a dark shelter for
what harvest preachers and has become a
watch.
People might consider the most open
country in the Middle East.
This is of course excluding Dubai birds.
As you might know,
Dubai is an emirate and not actually a
country something Doha.
We can find international universities
or the Falls Church city,
a complex of Protestant Orthodox and
Catholic churches like the Church of our
lady rosary million dollar Catholic
Church,
which seats 2,700 is located in the
southern outskirts of the city on land
donated by seek Hamad bin Khalifa.
Funny Qatar's emir.
So now the question of course has to be
how did Qatar achieve this remarkable
transformation?
Well,
let's take a look at
that.
The
LNG blessing,
liquefied natural gas.
In other videos we have discussed the
keys as to why some countries are so
rich,
but in this case it is much simpler and
it can be summarized.
Blink two things.
Oh,
bands.
More importantly,
natural gas,
a massive,
massive amounts of natural gas.
That really is pretty much it.
If you'll just voice it will just hold
on a second because it's actually quite
an interesting story
already.
The fields they were found in the 19
forties and by the 19 sixties,
exploitation was already consolidators
and things in the poor country of Qatar
changed,
but not really that much.
The thing is that it wasn't until the
beginning of the 19 seventies that shell
founds the biggest treasure of this
country and that would be the north
fields,
which is the largest gas field in the
world
at that time.
Well,
natural gas,
it just wasn't that profitable.
You see at the time gasket only be
transported through gas pipes and guitar
was far from places where this gas could
be used.
Even Shell,
well,
they soon forgot about it,
but well things they were really about
to change in 1996,
the older male,
bin Khalifa,
al tiny,
who abdicated in 2013 staged acute atar
while his father was in Switzerland.
This Amir reached our with a clear idea
and that was the future of guitar was in
gas.
They simply had to exploit their huge
gasfields man so well.
He did just that.
The new mayor decided to invest in an
undeveloped Andrew rare technology.
This technology,
it's liquefaction,
which is the ability to carry natural
gas in its liquid form so that it can be
transported in large ships as if it was
oil.
In order to do this,
the gas needed to cool down and be kept
at a temperature of minus 161 degrees
Celsius,
which is minus 258 degrees Fahrenheit.
Now this is something that is pretty
inconvenient to do
so well.
I could tell they decided to invest
enormous quantities of resources in
order to boost the development of this
technology so that it can be used on a
massive scale.
Because of that as investments.
Guitar is now the world's largest
exporter of LNG.
With this technology,
guitar is able to export its enormous
gas supplies to the rest of the world.
In fact,
last year,
three quarters of guitars,
gas went to Asian countries like China,
India,
South Korea,
and Japan as well.
There's more because the industrial
complex that guitar has developed is so
big,
so large scale that the country has
managed to have the cheapest costs of
extraction and liquefaction in the
entire world.
To illustrate this,
a 10 career,
LNG is four times cheaper and guitar
than it is in the United States and
this,
well,
that's the secret of this small and
wealthy country.
But this,
you know,
there's only a part of the equation.
I mean,
not only does the country have to
exploit the resources they have,
but they also need to use that money to
generate other money or they're going to
end up like Angola or Venezuela.
So besides this innovative process,
guitar has some other keys to their
success,
star power,
some
odd bin.
Kalief Jatani reached power in 1995.
Things they have changed significantly
and is 18 years leading the country
Qatar's population.
It's multiplied by while at the same
time it's become the richest country on
it.
Yeah,
the older mayor,
he's got plenty of reasons to feel proud
of himself.
But let's move on from this because it
started to generate a lot of economic
resources and the question now is,
well,
what are they doing with this money well
spent would it may look like they've
actually mostly invested it both
nationally and internationally.
It's hard.
They've created the Qatar Investment
Authority,
which is a huge funds to invest money
all around the world.
It is known as guitars power because
they have in their hands more than
$330,000,000,000.
And when you consider that the
population of guitar is less than 3
million people,
but if those 3 million people,
only 300,000 citizens,
well you can do the math.
This fund,
it has made significant real estate
investments all over the world.
A big part of the city belongs to Qatar
and including offices,
hotels,
apartments and swell.
In the United States,
guitar was in 2016.
The fourth largest office investor in
the country in Manhattan alone.
This fund is invested $5,000,000,000 in
the last two years and they're not just
investing in real estate.
This funds also has major shares in many
multinationals.
It gets on this,
for instance,
one of the largest shareholders of
companies like Volkswagen,
Iberdrola,
Barclays Bank,
tiffany and co Shell,
or even the judge,
rough snaps the oil company of the
Russian governments.
In the image I'm about to show you,
you can see how much foreign investment
has increased as the production of gas
and oil has grown
pants.
It's not just international investments
here.
They're also investing lots of resources
inside the country.
Tens of billions has been spent on
highways,
ports,
airports,
research centers,
financial centers,
etc. Etc.
So you might bE asking now,
what's the goal of all of this?
Well,
that is to be able to in the future,
replace the income they get from island
gas,
with income from all of these
investments versus you know what?
The moment when the gas business runs
out is still too far away to really be a
problem.
No analysts who can say when demand for
gas,
we'll wait for oil.
There are people who See peak demand
demanded 20,
30 others in 20,
42,
but for gas demand is constantly
growing.
This idea they have of investing rather
than spending the money from natural
resources might be at one of the most
important differences between Qatar and
other countries who are also rich in
natural resources.
Most of them,
they find it too easy to spend the
money.
Today.
Man's not think too much about the
future effective independent
when someones
been kelly for our tiny reached power.
He also had another thing in mind,
Qatar.
It had to gain international influence.
You see,
for years,
guitar was controlled.
A de facto bike.
Saudi arabia under the new amir just
couldn't forget about iraq's invasion of
Kuwait.
If gasol wanted to survive,
they needed to claim their identity and
gain international influence.
Otherwise any conflict with radar could
compromise the independence of the
country besides well natural gas,
it could pay the bills now,
sorry,
in 2003 when Saudi Arabia or requested
that the u s take american troops out of
that country guitar,
didn't hesitate to offer itself as a
destination for those trips.
They didn't even blink when it came to
spending about $8,000,000,000 to build
the military bases that were needed.
Yes,
brawling based 20 miles southwest of the
qatari capital of doha is home to some
11,000 us military personnel.
Indeed,
it could be said that Qatar has taken
out a very comprehensive insurance
policy and then we have the founding of
al jazeera.
this has the objective of obtaining
global influence bands.
Well,
they succeeded and this is something we
actually covered in a previous video
that you should definitely check out.
They also developed a foreign policy
driving towards international influence
blockade.
All this political strategy made both
the United Arab Emirates and Saudi
Arabia very angry and in june of 2017,
they announced a blockade accusing Qatar
of supporting fundamentalist groups and
terrorists,
and when it comes to Saudi Arabia,
we could definitely call this a case of
the pot calling the kettle black.
Now,
it is true that Qatar has some dark
secrets.
I mean it is an absolute monarchy after
all,
but the country is a good ally for the
west,
especially the United States,
and it's also one of the most open
countries in the region.
The truth is that the boycotts,
it had a different target to cut down
guitars,
strategy of international influence,
and to essentially put them back in that
place.
However,
the blockade,
well,
it's been a total failure.
First results position is not that
strong.
Very few countries have supported us,
not even Kuwait or in mind.
Also,
Qatar has developed to better
relationships with Turkey bands.
Even Iran console has simply proved that
they are strong enough to weather the
storm.
And finally it's really important that
we didn't make something clear.
There aren't plenty of gray areas in
Qatar labor conditions that are more
consistent with the ones of have a poor
country,
the situation of women in the country
and the lack of a democracy.
Furthermore,
the system needs to prove that it can
work without the government because
unlike dubai,
the lead has been taken by public
initiative,
not private,
and this is one of the reasons why dubai
is still above khatami in pretty much
all aspects,
but I am.
And it would it be fair to not
acknowledge what they're doing right,
like they're saving capacity.
That productive investments,
um,
is there openness?
And While that's our opinion here at
visual politic and now we would love to
know what you think,
who do you think will win the battle of
the countries in the persian gulf,
saudi,
or maybe Qatar?
Well,
let us know your answer in the comments
below as well as in this survey.
And also don't forget to subscribe to
our channel for brand new videos every
monday and every thursday.
Also,
don't forget to check out our friends at
the reconsider media podcasts.
They provided the vocals in this episode
that are not mine,
and as always I'll thank you for
watching.