[inaudible]
in this video,
we are going to take a look at the
career of one of the most surprising and
controversial figures of the century.
The figure is Mikhail Saakashvili.
Wait a second,
you don't know him.
Well,
imagine a person who is capable of being
one of the best allies of Washington and
at the same time one of the greatest
enemies of flatten map Putin.
He was president of one country,
a candidate to preside over another and
today beat doesn't even have a
nationality.
This is a man how politician worthy of
starring and his very own political
thriller.
In fact,
I would imagine they probably wouldn't
be surprising to see a netflix original
produced about this guy
[inaudible].
This is today's character for visual
politic.
It is Mikhail Saakashvili.
Maybe a
be shoved the governor.
What does it start our story?
We need to go back to maybe the 30th
2015 but that's a petro Poroshenko.
The president of Ukraine appointed may
coming Elsa Cash Villi as the governor
of the province of a Dessa.
With it
position Misha was given Ukrainian
nationality.
However,
to becoming Ukrainian citizen,
he had to give up citizenship from his
home country,
Georgia,
the country he had led US president
between 2004 and 2013
yes.
Addition to the Ukrainian government was
quite the treat for the media band.
Well,
that's only logical.
You see at that time your crane was
going through a really tense situation
after the circled maidan revolution and
the fall of pro Russian President Viktor
Yanukovych.
That was almost a feeling of civil war
in Ukraine,
a war between Kiev supporters and
supporters of Moscow,
and Odessa was one of the most pro
Russian provinces.
So you can imagine the picture of the
foreign ex presidents and not just any
ex president,
but what of Putin's worst enemies
appointed as the governor of a,
this event was hugely discussed in all
the national media as well as the
international press,
the president of Ukraine,
who was,
by the way,
in old friends and fellow college
students of meshes,
Petro Poroshenko.
Describe to Misha as the man who makes
possible the impossible,
pretty flattering,
right at that time,
their friendship when it seemed
bulletproof.
Well,
the mission of the new governor was to
stabilize a dessa grounds power to Kiev,
chase corruption,
and sets the groundwork for the region
to prosper in order to carry it all out
to make sure.
Brought in many of his former
collaborators from Georgia.
He also hired many young professionals
to be thought to be corruption free like
Yulia and Mary chef's got an activist
who became famous here on Youtube.
But with the video,
I am a Ukrainian.
Misha also brought in some people from
Putin's opposition in Russia,
like the Russian activist,
Maria guider who was appointed vice
governor.
No.
Yes.
That was a lot to do and it had to be
done fast,
so wow.
As it was sad.
So it was done.
One
See,
took the Odessa governorship.
The new governor started a thorough
investigation to find and punish corrupt
public workers.
He changed most of the high level
positions in the public administration.
He's simplified the process for creating
companies and introduced independent
controls and even liberated public
beaches that had been illegally occupied
so that once again Adesa citizens joy
them.
Hold on a second tier because Misha has
a strange work methodology and it is as
effective as it is controversial.
If anything doesn't work properly and
does corrupt,
he just dismantles it.
He fires all the workers and he sets it
up again.
He did the same during his time in
office in Georgia with the traffic
police anti threatened to do it again
with the Odessa port,
the largest commercial port in Ukraine,
well known for bribes and payments to
customs officers.
You need to fire them all.
We have 130 new people.
They are young,
new and trained and the old ones are
hopeless.
He Calls Saakashvili in the end though
here and you have to follow some of the
customs officers so that the corruption
would stop.
Consider this.
A number of businessmen noted that
bribes at the port really had stopped in
recent months,
mainly because people were scared of
becoming the next victim of one of
soccer stability is public
anticorruption tirades rates.
Shawn Walker,
correspondent of the Guardian with all
these changes and with the help of me,
she has contacts.
ADESA started to receive help from the
USA and since we should didn't trust the
police,
the first thing he did was establish an
independent police force to fight
corruption.
One
has a police force that was organized
and trained by the FBI and the
California Highway Patrol,
so it looks like everything was going
pretty good.
Right.
Well just hold on a second because both
sac is really and his team soon realized
that it was going to be much,
much harder than they anticipated.
The problem was that Odessa was not a
battlefield of Kiev supporters versus
pro Russians,
but it was a battlefield between the
rule of law and an oligarchy that has
dominated Ukraine at,
since it's independence kingdom of all
the guards,
more and more experts have said,
so your cranes biggest problem is not a
Russia.
It is the oligarchy corruption in
Ukraine is so embedded that we could
almost say it is a sort of feudal
country where the nobility or of course
these mighty oligarchy
thanks.
They
control the,
the political power,
the administration,
even the media,
almost nothing escapes that power which
is consolidated both by money and by
fear.
Then level of impunity is almost
absolute police,
government judges that all a part of the
game.
Things have been this way since you
crane got its independence,
but since the maidan revolution,
it's all got a whole lot worse after the
fall of the pro Russian president vixy
you knock a bitch and with the civil
conflict to the country was going
through the new government felt
incapable of trusting the army,
all the police.
Since both institutions were corrupt,
they were disorganized and they were
badly equipped.
That is why he made a decision.
He appointed several oligarchs is
governors of some of the most vulnerable
regions in the country.
These oligarchs paid for that own
private armies and with nice incentives,
the police followed their orders as
well.
Earning a sum for the heads of every
separatist.
Yeah,
but as I told you,
the government essentially placed the
mafia directly in charge of several
governorships.
Oh,
that was the case for e Hok.
Hello Boyski who was appointed governor
of Denise [inaudible].
I'm sorry if I'm screwing the
pronunciation up on that.
This took like 17 takes.
This region is one of the most important
in the country.
Economically speaking.
So yes,
this is the Ukraine Mikhail Saccos
philly was dealing with.
There was not a single state enterprise
in Ukraine that has not been usurped by
one clan or another.
I verus Abramovic.
Yes,
former minister of economy and trade of
Ukraine.
As you can imagine,
all these oligarchs did not welcome
Misha or his reform agenda.
Indeed,
once he was even kicked out of an
interview when he suggested all of these
mafia members have to be sent to prison,
that the media is also the property of
the oligarchy.
The thing is Misha soon started to work
to fight and ultimately ends the
situation.
I will do whatever it takes for complete
victory to read new crane of this filth
of this corrupt scum which capitalize on
the blood of our soldiers whose only
motivation in life is to fill its own
pockets,
strengthen its own clan and bleed
Ukraine dry,
Mikhail Saakashvili and so he did Misha.
It started to publicly report all kinds
of influence,
peddling favorable treatment and
privileges.
On one occasion he even came on national
television and reported the details that
they corrupt scheme of the airlines
owned by column Boyski and oligarch.
You'd nearly obtained a monopoly on
national flights.
The public reports ended the situation
and took many of the people involved to
course.
Let's,
as you can imagine,
Mr Colin [inaudible] didn't take it
well.
He promised to get his revenge and
here's what he said about satish
civilian public.
When a dog without a muscle bite
someone,
we need to punish both the dog and more
importantly the owner.
He Horror Calamos Ski.
Now,
Dino thing that all Meesha did was
report the oligarchs.
Not at all.
Okay,
train crash Saakashvili is reforms in
Odessa didn't complete the work.
Many of them were stops and sabotage by
the government in Kiev.
This wasn't just the audio gox.
You see,
corruption was so commonplace that it
was difficult to tell the difference
between the Mafia and the authority.
Nisha,
he didn't think twice the government
became his target.
Many analysts claim that this new war
against the government had a hidden
agenda to take a leap.
International politics.
Well,
maybe,
but the thing is,
he did it.
He started by reporting the corruption
of the very prime minister.
Our any Yatsenyuk man's many ministers
followed this.
Evil included his own friends.
The president's Petro Poroshenko,
the person who had placed him in a Dasa.
What difference for Ukrainians does it
make who will treat them like dirt
Poroshenko or you're kind of itch?
What difference?
Who will steal from them?
Mikhail Saakashvili,
the friendship that didn't last long as
we have seen Poroshenko appointed meesha
governor in May of 2015 in just a year.
The battle it,
yeah.
Gone.
Finally in November,
2016 at resigned as governor and began
his own political party.
The M N F I hadn't see soon gains more
than 20,000 members.
Yup.
The former Georgian presidents now
wanted to lead Ukraine and his own
words.
Yes,
fine.
To turn this disaster of a country into
a complete European super.
Yeah.
Am I now be wondering about the
responsive Poroshenko ans the government
to this campaign and pay close attention
here in July,
2017 Poroshenko took advantage of the
fact that there's a,
Misha was in the USA and he revoked his
Ukrainian citizenship.
All of a sudden,
Mikhail Saakashvili was a stateless
person.
Now if thing that stopped him,
you are absolutely wrong.
Look,
when his nationality,
it was taken away.
Misha,
he simply moved opponents and we have to
say,
Michelle is a well loved guy in eastern
Europe.
In fact,
many countries offered him citizenship,
but nope bishop,
he was determined to go back to Ukraine
as well.
That's exactly what he did.
Despite the warnings of the government
to give on September the 10th surrounded
by a supportive crowd.
Michelle crossed the border on foot
between Poland and Ukraine.
The images of his confrontation with the
border guards.
Well,
they're quite
nice.
What do you think is up to now that he's
back despite his irregular situation?
Nisha,
he's campaigning around the country,
but all of that said there is still an
important question.
Why out [inaudible] Philly,
the Saakashvili Revolution in 2003
Michelle at a popular uprising against
the corrupt George and political system
of Eduard Shevardnadze and then what is
known as the Rose Revolution.
He even made it to the Georgian
parliament.
Elections were held mans as the
successful revolutions.
Nida Saakashvili easily beat the rest.
The reform process that started there
was a fierce fight against corruption
and a tough policy towards Moscow.
That came to be a model for the former
Soviet countries.
Plus we are going to discuss these
matters as well as the dark and less
glamorous side of Saakashvili in a
future video right here at visual
politics.
So do subscribe,
but for now it's your turn.
Do you think Misha will ends up leading
new crane?
Well,
please do leave your answers in the
comments below as well as in this survey
and do not forget to subscribe for brand
new videos every Monday and every
Thursday and please do check it.
Our friends at the reconsider media
podcasts,
they provided the vocals in this episode
that were not mine trans.
Well,
if you're looking for something else to
watch right now,
please do check out my brand new
channel.
Biographics we do biographies in the
longer form there,
about 20 minutes each of notable people
from history and the present day,
politicians and others.
So go check it out.
Link in the description below,
and as always,
thank you for.