Many of you have asked for this video,
and I'll be honest,
we're not very surprised,
the Republic of China better known as
Taiwan has some of the most strange and
controversial political and diplomatic
situations in the entire world.
So let me explain.
At the time of publishing this video,
Taiwan has only received formal
recognition from 20 of the world's
countries and some of these countries,
well,
they're pretty small,
like the Vatican Tuvalu in Swaziland
fight all of this.
Taiwan has managed to become one of the
richest and freest countries on the
planet.
It has a well equipped army and it is
one of these spear heads over the United
States in Southeast Asia.
Before we really get into it,
let's take a look back and see where it
began.
The great Chinese separation,
the situation Taiwan finds itself in has
its origin in the Chinese civil war,
which took place between 1927 and 1949
war between the conservative forces.
The Chinese Nationalist Party led by
Chiang Kai Shek and the forces of the
Communist Party of Nazi Tome on December
the 10th,
1949.
The last setting,
Chengdu fell into the hands of the
nationalists.
The war had ended and the communists and
gotten their way shortly before Chang do
fell that they,
in carrying the nationalist leader
Chiang Kai Shek,
left bound for Taiwan.
The last province under national list
control z didn't go alone.
Check 2 million more people,
took shelter in Taiwan along with the
survivors of the nationalist army.
Since then ends,
even though mal tried to take the
islands back,
Taiwan has received support from the
United States.
The US continued recognizing the
governments over the island as the
legitimate government of China up until
1979.
As a curious note here,
Taiwan is the only country other than
the US that is continually operated the
youtube spy plane.
Their mission was to monitor Mao's
China.
The CIA itself was actually in charge of
conducting these operations.
Nope.
About
1979.
It's a really important date.
At this time,
the United States was trying to build
trust with Beijing.
This was in order to create some sort of
a double envelopment against the Soviet
Union.
We actually talked about this in a
previous video and I'll leave a link to
that in the description.
Well,
the thing is,
in 1979,
the presidents of the United States,
Jimmy Carter,
decided to establish diplomatic
relations with Beijing and mass meant
that they had to stop recognizing the
government of the Republic of China.
That is the government based in Taipei.
You see Taiwan that never declared its
independence for years.
The government based in Taipei,
captain,
considering itself as the legitimate
government of all of China as of course
the country.
You can only have diplomatically
speaking one government and yes,
this is how the one China started and
today this is supported by Washington
Adams.
Most countries around the world.
This is a change by the way,
the course Taiwan to lose its place in
the UN as well as other important
international organizations,
but it is true that the United States,
we're still committed to the security of
Taiwan.
That same year,
in 1979,
the American Congress passed the Taiwan
Relations Act.
This was documents that among other
things,
reserve the option for the US to ensure
the security and defense of the islands
and since that act was passed for us
when it's done,
just that,
but as I was saying at the beginning of
this video,
none of these things have kept Taiwan
from being the star of one of the
greatest stories of the economic and
social success,
big roar of the tiger,
fifties,
Taiwan.
It was a very poor place that had a
pretty rudimentary economy where their
exports were basically really basic
things like rice and sugar.
So the question at that time was,
how are we going to develop such a port
islands while the Taiwanese government
thought the best way to achieve success
was to ensure that businesses on the
island could sell their products all
over the world?
This was considered to be the best way
to open up the island to the world and
even encouraged savings.
Yeah.
Am I seeing counter intuitive,
but actually this action does encourage
people to save because in order to
invest,
you first need to get the resources that
are necessary to do so and well.
That's exactly what they did.
The governments of the islands soon
started to eliminate almost all import
restrictions.
This meant the businesses could get all
the products they required to set up
their businesses and assembly lines
without being stung by import fees.
This is sort of similar to what it's
this culture of saving attitude,
the legal certainty of the country and
so encouraged further investments world.
Soon enough,
Taiwanese companies began appearing like
mushrooms after the rain,
as they exploded all kinds of products.
The rest of them,
tad industrial products,
we're already 90 percent of the
country's exports and they were growing
an average of 30 percent per year.
Yeah,
they sold all kinds of things to the
world,
toys,
radios,
bike,
socks,
just about everything.
And of course,
as you can imagine with that sort of
situation that the per capita income
didn't stop growing in just 30 years.
It multiplied by F
fine
with that.
A new Asian tiger was born.
Now
don't a anything that this was an easy
process.
I mean,
Taiwan didn't even have a democracy
until the 19 nineties,
but once they've got their freedom,
the Taiwanese people,
they held onto it tightly.
Let's have a look at some example.
Is Today considered the 11 freest
economy in the world in Asia?
Only Hong Kong and Singapore rank best
that it's a rich country with quite a
high standard of living and it is one of
the countries that has a significant
number of civil liberties and in fact
Taiwan,
they're about to make history.
Yeah.
Taiwan court rules in favor of same sex
marriage in historic first for an Asian
country
who as you can see compared with
continental China,
well,
there really is no comparison in terms
of per capita income.
The Taiwanese onto day three times
richer than the Chinese.
They are much more free,
but in spite of all of this good stuff,
there are still some clouds on the
horizon,
clouds in the Taiwanese sky.
The truth is this,
in the last few years,
the country has been going through a few
things.
Salaries have been frozen for years and
didn't see thousand and 15.
The country went through a small
recessions since then.
Economic growth,
well,
it's been very slow and now be rather
obvious.
Question is what exactly is happening?
Well,
there are several ingredients to this
rather bitter recipe,
which is threatening the future.
Yeah.
This is competition from new emerging
markets like China,
Indonesia,
Vietnam,
also the brain drain and the aging
population and the cliffs to broken
pension system.
The latter of the pension system is the
problem vertebra by far concerns the
government of the most.
Look for years,
the pensions of public workers.
They were inflated for political
reasons.
They did this in order to get votes.
Adams well,
it became really,
really expensive.
Public pensions whipped so inflated that
they are now threatening the stability
of the entire system.
Taiwanese
workers earn about 1300 US dollars per
month on average,
but retired high school teachers receive
a whopping average pension of 2,250 US
dollars per month.
As you well know,
bad policies turnouts to be expensive.
Let's consider some of the other
problems to continue our.
For the next ingredients in our bitter
recipe would be what is called the 40 40
issue.
It's like the Taiwanese economy.
It's very dependent on the electronic
industry as well as commerce in China,
no
goods or 40 percent of all of their
export,
and China is the destination of almost
40 percent of Taiwan's export,
so now you might be wondering,
well,
what exactly is the problem with that?
Well,
this dependence on electronics and China
means that when the electronics industry
or China isn't doing well,
economically,
Taiwan suffers too,
and that's precisely what has happened
over the last few years,
but wait,
because we're not done yet.
Above all,
that is a political problem which has
affected the country severely and has
caused for an investment in Taiwan to be
significantly lower than that of the
countries nearby and so well,
what's the problem that?
Well,
foreign investors are afraid of China.
The Chinese threat.
This is by far the biggest problem that
Taiwan is facing.
Humans of Beijing is determining to
regain sovereignty over the islands and
it's made a public declaration on the
data that states two things.
First of all,
it will happen before 20,
49,
the 100th anniversary of the People's
Republic of China,
and secondly that they are willing to
use force if Taiwan tries to declare its
independence.
So let me dig into that.
A little Taiwan could be considered an
independent country from pretty much
every perspective.
The island has its own presidents whose
democratically elected by the way,
it has its own laws.
It has its own army.
However,
Beijing isn't going to accept formal
independence the most they are willing
to give.
Taiwan temporarily is a status similar
to that of Hong Kong,
and this is pretty serious because among
other things,
most Taiwanese don't feel that their
identity is paint.
No
citizens of a free country,
which has been independent for almost 70
years.
In fact,
in 2014 when the previous government
solve Taiwan tried to approach Beijing
to develop a trade agreements,
but Taiwanese people started a
revolution which eventually became known
as the sunflower revolution.
Hundreds of young people protested with
the motto.
Taiwan is not.
Sale
was exactly under this atmosphere of
economic and political frustration that
in 2016,
the Democratic Progressive Policy,
a party whose foundations were mainly
pro independence,
one that the legislative and
presidential election citing wing,
not the closest politician to Beijing
that became the first female presidents
of Tyler
one,
even though the economy was the most
crucial factor,
Beijing didn't like this election at
all.
They disapproved of it so much that they
decided to start harassing Taiwan again
in 2017 and up to now,
Chinese tourism to Taiwan has been
reduced by 40 percent.
Beijing has convinced to countries,
Panama and Sao Tome and Principe to stop
recognizing Taiwan and it is blocking
the presence of the island in many
international forums.
For now,
there has been no economic retaliation,
but the island knew that they could be
in for a Sivia below.
This is why one of the priorities of the
new government is to open up to as many
new markets as possible as soon as
possible.
So now you might be wondering where is
the US and all of this.
I mean,
this is a visual politic video.
After all,
and we've been a little light on the US
so far,
so where are they?
Well,
for now,
their support seems to remain in tact.
In fact,
trump's administration is already
approved.
A weapon sale to Taiwan went off at one
point $5,000,000,000.
Trump administration approves first arms
sale to Taiwan,
and on top of all that,
the powerful Senate Arms Services
Committee in the United States and navy
ships to use Taiwanese ports,
and they did so with a majority of votes
from both the democratic and the
Republican parties in both chambers
finally approved that decision.
You can bet to the Beijing,
they're going to be pretty annoyed.
Oh,
what is Washington's objective yet?
Well,
that would be to try and prevent Beijing
from even thinking about a military
invasion of Taiwan and that's pretty
much it for now.
Here are visual.
Politic wiggins.
Keep a close eye on Taiwan as the
situation develops,
but now it's your turn.
What do you think the future of Taiwan
will hold?
Well,
you can leave us your opinion in the
comments below as well as in this survey
and I really hope you enjoyed this video
and if you did,
please do hit that like button and don't
forget to subscribe if you haven't
already for brand new videos every
Monday and every Thursday cans.
Don't forget to check.
I'll be reconsidered.
Media podcasts did.
They provided the vocals in this episode
that are not mine,
and as always I'll see you in the next
week.