Forty five years,
it's been 45 years since China and
Australia established diplomatic
relations.
Since then,
things have changed a lot.
Shawna was founded in 1949 with this,
with these words,
John Wall run man's punchy life that
Chinese people have stood up.
It was an assertion of sovereignty.
It was an assertion of pride and we
stand up and so we say hourly.
I run Manzanar,
Eli,
the Australian people stand up
through
all these years.
Both countries have maintained one of
the most fruitful,
controversial and interesting
relationships in the world are
relationship based on stories about
money,
spies,
accusations,
infidelities,
and many,
many conflicting interests because in
all honesty,
if we're talking about a relationship
between two people instead of two
countries,
we have a great script for an Alaskan
American Tele Novella.
Obviously this swell,
this is visual politics,
so let's get right to the point,
shall we.
Today,
China is Australia's main commercial
partner.
That purchases represents about a third
of all Australian exports,
eight times more than exports to the
United States.
In 2015,
China and Australia signed a free trade
agreements and today their trade
relations exceed a hundred and
$55,000,000,000
per year,
and not only that,
China is also becoming an incredibly
important investor in Australia.
I couldn't freak where one in 20 people
or Chinese among them,
many millionaires who decided to find a
safer place with more guarantees for
their assets and their lives,
such as the scale of trade that
financial markets have long been of the
view that the Australian dollar is one
of the best proxies for bets on China
itself.
James Laurenson,
deputy director of the Australia China
relations institute.
Of course,
this all has its consequences.
We already talked about it here on
visual politic.
Australia has broken records and does
not have a national crisis for almost 30
years.
Sounds pretty amazing.
Rise.
One of the great Chinese takeoff had a
lot to do with all of this success.
Therefore,
it's easy to understand why when the
lowery institute's and important thing
tank in the country asked Australians
last year,
which relationship was more important to
them?
The one with the United States or the
one with China and the result,
but it was a tie.
This is despite the fact that relations
within North American friends very close
indeed.
However,
in spite of this romance,
the fact is for thousand and 17 was not
a year of love for Australia and China.
Check out what Bob Carr,
former minister for foreign affairs of
Australia set on the subject this year.
Australia declared rhetorical war on
China.
The words being used by Australian
leaders are the harshest anytime since
diplomatic relations commenced in 1972
with the exception of comments at the
time of the Tiananmen crackdown.
The Tony's harsher than that of any
other US ally,
including Japan.
As you can see,
2017 was a very difficult year for both
countries relations.
So much so that a survey by the global
times,
one of China's most popular newspapers
examines the Australia,
was the most hostile country to China in
2017.
And the truth is that with trump in the
White House,
those are really big words because we
can't continue to allow China to rape
our country.
And that's what they're doing.
It's the greatest theft in the history
of the world.
So what the hell has happened?
What has led to so much dissension
between Canberra and Beijing?
Well,
that A.
Look at that,
shall we?
The storm.
Oh,
first 2017,
seems like it'd be a good year for China
and Australia.
Economic relations wouldn't stop
growing.
Trump's shedding off his best diplomatic
skills hung up on the Australian prime
minister,
Malcolm Turnbull himself further sinking
his popularity in this area of the
world.
We had a good telephone call,
a very cool,
and the Australian government's even
publicly supported China,
replacing the United States as a main
member of the fails TPP,
the Pacific free trade agreements.
We could almost say those in telanovela
terms.
Love was about to triumph.
However,
the good times didn't last long and
everything started to go wrong about
halfway through the year and it went
really wrong.
Yes,
they have had clashes before,
but nothing really major in recent
years.
The Australian government has followed a
strategy that basically it consisted of
trying to balance that position between
Beijing and Washington.
To
don't make matters,
it was all Beijing and insecurity and
defense matters.
It was a Washington.
We already mentioned on visual politic
that Republicans consider Australia to
be the US is best ally and so should be.
Australia is the only country that has
intervened in every major us walk and
for years the military relations have
been so tight that Australia has become
for us as spearhead in this area of the
world.
Awesome.
The Australian prime minister himself is
trimmed as great appreciation for the
United States saying the peace and
stability of a region has been enabled
by consistent us global leadership.
While that leadership would not have
been possible without the hard power of
fleets and armies,
its greatest potency has come from the
values we embodies.
Through all the twists and turns of
history,
the United States has stood for the
values on which it's great.
Republic was founded,
freedom,
democracy,
and the rule of law.
Malcolm Turnbull.
Let's get back to the Chinese matter.
See,
these words were pronounced on June the
second 2017.
That was the first time in Australian
prime.
Minister spoke so clearly in favor of
Washington in a speech which was also
full of warnings to China.
Such a dark view of our future would see
China isolating those who stand in
opposition to or are not aligned with
its interests.
And then just eight days later the media
storm broke out.
It says espionage and foreign
interference against Australian interest
is extensive.
Several news organizations reported on a
single story.
The Australian intelligence agency was
making very serious warnings about the
Chinese government's intentions to
influence Australian politics through
various means,
including purchasing politicians,
journalists,
and scientists.
All these surveillance and intimidation
of citizens belonging to the Chinese
community in Australia.
The scans it was unleashed suddenly
knew,
started to emerge on the collaboration
Australian universities and scientists
with Chinese military contractors for
former politicians.
It's not chance the former Trade
Minister Andrew Rob,
who now works for companies controlled
by the Chinese government in exchange
for juicy salaries,
but amount to hundreds of thousands of
dollars.
Yes,
of course.
The Australian security services,
fear of Chinese espionage certainly
isn't new.
Various Australian governments have been
blocking Chinese corporate operations
for years,
and so I've also banned companies such
as quite way from participating in
deploying a national broadband network.
This is all precisely because of a fear
of espionage or excessive Chinese
influence.
However,
despite everything,
controversy and tension had never gone
this far,
but reports have suggested that the
Chinese Communist Party has been working
to covertly interfere with our media or
universities and even the decisions.
Elected representatives right here in
this building in the parliament.
Malcolm,
on December the twelfth,
2017,
Sam Dastyari,
Labor Party senator and one of the most
promising political figures in the
country was forced to resign because of
his ties to China.
I said earlier in the statement that I
am a patriotic Australian.
I meant that with all my heart and I
leave the Senate with nothing but good
thoughts for our country and for our
people.
Among other things,
he was accused of receiving money in
exchange for speeches that favored the
Chinese government's interests and even
have alerting a Chinese businessman
linked to the communist party that he
could be being investigated by
Australia's intelligence agencies and
that his phone could be tapped well.
Scientists collaborating with Chinese
military contractors,
university in filtration,
paying journalists,
buying politicians.
These accusations had been running since
the beginning of June.
The Australian government announced it
publicly and began modifying its
legislation on espionage,
treason,
immigration,
and on financing political parties and
this dvr.
It looks like it's only just the
beginning.
It is no secret that China is very
active in intelligence activities
directed against us.
The consequences of these cooling
political relations can be seen.
For example,
in foreign policy,
we can clearly say that in 2017,
Australia has been favoring the United
States like never before,
but don't think that this position has
been unanimous among the political class
or at all.
In fact,
the government doesn't seem to
understand the economic importance of
the relationship with China or the
strategic issues involved.
We're putting all of our faith and our
relationship with China through the
foreign policy lens of the US,
Paul Keating,
Australian former prime minister,
and you know what,
given the circumstances,
I think that this entire database on the
position Australia should take regarding
China is quite understanding.
On the one hand,
many critics affirmed that there isn't
enough evidence of the Chinese
interference that the government
denounces some even say that this is all
a political operation fed by Washington
now on the other is breaking with China
or at least being this forceful with the
Beijing government isn't exactly easy
for Australia,
and now you might be asking,
well,
why is this?
Well,
check this out.
China defends itself.
Israel,
this entire political crisis.
China has been very strong.
Of course they have denied all
accusations and have even said that this
entire campaign is based on racial
prejudice and anti Chinese paranoia.
This paranoia they've claimed is turning
into clear hostility towards the Chinese
community in Australia itself.
Chinese diplomats warn students in
Australia to stay alert to safety risks
after spate of attacks.
Yes,
these types of messages may seem
exaggerated,
especially because the truth is that
beyond a few posters in one university
or another,
there seems to be no evidence of this
acclaimed danger,
but although this claim shows us how
things off,
it's also kind of a warning because
clearly it isn't good publicity.
Allow me to explain myself.
Yet,
Chinese students account for four out of
every 10 foreign students in Australian
universities and they spend
$18,000,000,000
in the country every single year.
It seems that Xi Jinping's governments
wants to make it very clear that it is
willing,
if necessary,
to play in economic terms as a pressure
measure.
This is something that by the way,
they have used recently with both South
Korea and Taiwan
and
we are only talking about students here,
but also about tourists and investors.
For example,
in recent years,
the luxury sector has experienced a huge
economic boom in Australia and you know
why?
Well,
listen to this,
students,
tourists and Chinese residents in
Australia are responsible for up to two
thirds of all luxury retail sales in
Sydney and Melbourne and had as another
example.
China's direct investments in Australia
of multiplies not by 10 by 20,
but by 32 inches,
nine years,
so as you can see,
slowing down this entire process could
translate into a lot and that is a lot
of pain for the Australian economy,
but dear viewer,
that is simply the way things are.
So far,
the Australian government remains
faithful to its close relationship with
Washington.
The United States seems to have secured
an alliance that is essential for their
interests in this area of the world and
for that military industry.
In recent years,
Australia became one of the U.
s is best customers,
and in the next decade they expect to
spend more than a hundred billion
dollars.
Renewing their armed forces were
American contractors have a big
advantage.
However,
there all more than a few people then
it's by people here.
I need politicians,
businessmen,
and citizens to Australia to remain
neutral and protect its national
security without having to make so many
public accusations.
So now the question becomes,
well,
how is this story going to end?
Well,
one of the most fruitful relationships
in recent years be at risk.
Well,
when the time is going to tell,
but now it's your turn.
Where do you think Australian politics
should turn?
Do leave us your answer in the comments
below as well as in this survey as I
really hope you enjoyed this video.
If you did,
please do hit that like button below and
do not forget to subscribe to this
channel for brand new videos every
Monday and every Thursday.
Also,
don't forget to check it off.
Friends at the reconsider media
podcasts.
They provided the vocals in this
episode,
but we're not mine and as always,
thank you for.
And so we say at our yard run Manzano,
Eli,
the Australian people stand up.
It is no secret that China is very
active in intelligence activities
directed against us.