Welcome to course six as zero,
nine,
nine artificial general intelligence.
We will explore the nature of
intelligence from as much as possible.
An engineering perspective.
You will hear many voices.
My voice will be that of an engineer.
Our mission is to engineer intelligence.
The mit motto is mined in hand.
What that means is we want to explore
the fundamental science of what makes an
intelligent system,
the core concepts behind our
understanding of what is intelligence,
but we always want to ground it in the
creation of intelligence systems.
We always want to be in the now in today
in understanding how today we can build
artificial intelligence systems that can
make for a better world that is the core
for us here at Mit,
first and foremost,
where scientists and engineers,
our goal is to engineer intelligence.
We want to provide with this approach a
balanced to the very important but
overrepresented view of artificial
general intelligence.
That black box reasoning view,
where the idea is,
once we know how to create a human level
intelligence system,
how will society be impacted?
Will robots take over and kill everyone?
Will we achieve a utopia that will
remove the need to do any of the messy
jobs that will make us all extremely
happy?
Those kinds of beautiful philosophical
concepts are interesting to explore,
but that's not what we're interested in
doing.
I believe that from an engineering
perspective,
we want to focus on the black box of
Agi,
start to build insights and intuitions
about how we create systems that
approach human level intelligence.
I believe we're very far away from
creating anything resembling human level
intelligence.
However,
the dimension of the metric behind the
ward far may not be time in time,
perhaps through a few breakthroughs may
be even one breakthrough.
Everything can change,
but as we stand now,
our current methods as we will explore
from the various ideas and approaches
and the guest speakers coming here,
uh,
over the next two weeks and beyond,
our best understanding,
our best intuition insights are not yet
at the level of reaching without a major
leap and breakthrough and paradigm shift
towards human level intelligence.
So it's not constructive to consider the
impact of artificial intelligence to
consider questions of safety and ethics.
Fundamental,
extremely important questions,
we it's not constructive to consider
those questions without also deeply
considering the black box of the actual
methods of artificial intelligence,
human level,
artificial intelligence,
and that's what I see.
What I hope this course can be,
its first iteration,
it's first exploratory attempt to try to
look at different approaches of how we
can engineer intelligence.
That's the role of mit is tradition of
mine in hand is to consider the big
picture,
the future impact of society 10,
20,
30,
40 years out,
but fundamentally grounded in what kind
of methods do we have today and what are
the limitations and possibilities of
achieving that.
The black box of Agi and in the future
impact on society of creating artificial
intelligence systems that get become
increasingly more intelligent.
The fundamental disagreement lies in the
fact the very core of that black box,
which is how hard is it to build an Agi
system?
How hard is it to create a human level
artificial intelligence system?
That's the open question for all of us,
from,
from Josh Tenenbaum to Andrea carpathy
to folks some open ai to Boston
dynamics,
the brilliant leaders in various fields
of artificial intelligence that will
come here.
That's the open question.
How hard is.
It has been a lot of incredibly
impressive results in deep learning in
neuroscience and computational cognitive
science in robotics,
but how far are we still to go to the
Agi?
That's the fundamental question that we
need to explore before we consider the
questions,
the future impact on society.
And the goal for this class is to build
intuition.
One,
talk at a time,
a project at a time build intuition
about where we stand,
about what the limitations of current
approaches are.
How can we close the gap?
A Nice meme that I caught on twitter
recently of a,
the difference between the engineering
approach at the very simplest of a
google intern typing a for loop that
just does a grid search on parameters
for neural network.
Uh,
and on the right is the way media would
report this for loop the Google ai
created its own baby ai.
I think it's easy for us to go one way
or the other,
but we'd like to do both.
Our first goal is to avoid the pitfalls
of black box thinking of the futurism
thinking that results in hype,
that's detached from scientific
engineering,
understanding of what the actual systems
are doing.
That's what the media often reports.
That's what some of our speakers will
explore in a rigorous way.
It's still an important topic to
explore.
Ray Kurzweil on Wednesday.
We'll look at.
We'll explore this topic next week
talking about Ai Safety and autonomous
weapons systems.
We'll explore this topic that future
impact 10,
20 years out.
How do we design systems today that
would lead to safe systems tomorrow.
Still very important,
but the reality is a lot of us need to
put a lot more emphasis on the left,
on the for loops,
on creating these systems at the same
time.
The second goal of what we're trying to
do here is not emphasize the silliness,
the simplicity,
the naive basic nature of this four loop
and the same way as was the process in
creating nuclear weapons before,
during World War Two.
The idea that as an engineer,
as a scientist,
that I am just the scientist is also a
flawed way of thinking.
We have to consider the big picture
impact the near term negative
consequences that are preventable,
the low hanging fruit,
the that can be prevented through that
engineering process.
We have to do both and in this
engineering approach we always have to
be cautious that just because we don't
understand,
we're just because we our intuition,
our best understanding of the
capabilities of modern systems that
learn to act in this world seem limited,
seem far from human level intelligence.
Our ability to learn and represent
common sense reasoning seems limited.
The exponential potentially exponential.
It's could be argued and he will.
A growth of technology of these ideas
means that just around the corner is a
singularity is a breakthrough idea that
will change everything.
We have to be cautious of that.
Moreover,
we have to be cautious of the fact that
every decade over the past century,
our adoption of new technologies has
gotten faster and faster.
The rate at which a new technology from
its birth to its wide mass adoption has
shortened and shortened and shortened.
That means that new idea,
the moment it drops into the world can
have widespread effects overnight,
so as an I think the in in the
engineering approach is fundamentally
cynical on artificial general
intelligence because every aspect of it
is so difficult.
We have to always remember that
overnight.
Everything can change through this
question of beginning to approach from a
deep learning perspective,
from deeper enforcement learning from
brain simulation,
complex cognitive science from
computational neuroscience,
from cognitive architecture,
some robotics from a legal perspective
and autonomous weapons systems.
As we begin to approach these questions,
we need to start to build intuition.
How far away are we from creating
intelligence systems?
The singularity here is that spark,
that moment when we're truly surprised
by the intelligence of the systems we
create.
I'd like to visualize it by the,
by the certain analogy that we're in
this dark room looking for a light
switch with no knowledge of where the
lights,
which is.
There's going to be people that say,
well,
it's a small rooms are all small.
We're right there and say anywhere.
We'll be able to find it anytime time.
The reality is we know very little so we
have to stumble around,
feel our way around to build the
intuition of far,
far away.
We really are.
And many will.
Speakers here,
we'll talk about how we define
intelligence,
how we can begin to see intelligence.
What are the fundamental impacts of
creating intelligence systems?
I'd like to sort of see the positive
reason for this little class and for
these efforts that have fascinated
people throughout the century of trying
to create intelligence systems is that
there is something about human beings
that want that craze to explore,
to uncover the mysteries of the
universe.
Fundamental in itself,
a desire to uncover the mysteries of the
universe,
not for a purpose,
and there's often an underlying purpose
of money,
of greed,
of,
uh,
the,
power craving for power and so on.
But there's seems to be an underlying
desire to explore.
Nice little book,
an exploration,
a very short introduction by Stewart
Weaver.
He says,
for all the different forums that takes
in different historical periods for for
all the worthy and unworthy motives that
lie behind it.
Exploration travel for the sake of
discovery and adventure is a human
compulsion,
a human obsession even.
It is defining element of a distinctly
human identity and it will never arrest
at any frontier,
whether terrestrial or extraterrestrial.
From 325 BC.
He with a long,
7,500
mile journey
on the ocean to explore the Arctic,
to Christopher Columbus and his flawed
harshly criticize the modern
scholarshipped trip that ultimately pave
the way,
didn't discover,
paved the way to colonization of the
Americas,
to the Darwin trip,
the voyage of the Beagle.
Whilst this planet has gone,
cycling on according to the fixed law of
gravity from so simple,
a beginning,
endless forms most beautiful and most
wonderful have been and are being
evolved to the first venture into space
by Urunga,
Guardian,
first human in space in 1961.
What he said over the radio is,
the earth is blue.
It is amazing this.
These are the words that I think drive
our exploration in the sciences and the
engineering and today in ai from the
first walk on the moon and now the
desire to colonize Mars and beyond.
That's where I see this desire to create
intelligence systems,
talking about the positive and negative
impact of ai on society.
Talking about the business case so the
jobs lost,
jobs gained,
jobs,
created diseases cured the autonomous
vehicles,
the ethical questions,
the safety of autonomous weapons,
of the misuse of ai in the financial
markets.
Underneath it all,
and there are people,
many people have spoken about this.
What drives myself and many in the
community is a desire to explore,
to uncover the mystery of the universe
and that hope that you join me in that
very effort with speakers that come here
in the next two weeks and beyond.
The website for the course is Agi that
mit did you.
I am a part of an amazing team,
many of whom you know Agi at Mit.
That edu is the email.
We're on slack.
Deep Dash Mit does slack up for
registered at Mit students.
It created account on the website and
submit five new links and vote on 10 to
vote Ai,
which is an aggregator of information
and material we've put together for the
topic of Agi and submit a entry to one
of the competitions,
one of the three competitions projects
that we have in this course and the
projects are dream vision.
I'll go over them in a little bit.
Dream Vision,
Angele ethical car,
and the aggregator of material.
Vote Ai.
We have guest speakers,
incredible guest speakers.
I will go over them today and as before
with the deep learning for self driving
cars course,
we have shirts and they're free for in
person,
for people that attend in person for the
last lecture,
most likely or you can order them
online.
Okay.
Dream vision will take the Google g
dream idea.
We explore the idea of creativity where
Einstein's view of intelligence,
the mark of intelligence is creativity.
This idea is something we explore by
using neural networks and interesting
ways to visualize what the network see
and in so doing,
create beautiful visualizations in time
through video.
So taking the ideas of deep dream and
combining them together with multiple
video streams to mix,
dream and reality,
and the competition is through
mechanical Turk was set up a competition
of who produces the most beautiful
visualization will provide code to
generate this visualization and ideas of
how you can make it more and more
beautiful and how to submit it to the
competition.
Angel,
the artificial neural generator of
emotion and language is a different
twist on the turing test where we don't
use words,
we only use emotions to speak expression
of those emotions and we create.
We use an age a,
a,
a face customizable with 26 muscles.
All of which can be controlled or
controlled with an Lstm we use in your
network to train the generation of
emotion
and the competition in you.
Submitting the code to the competition
is you get 10 seconds to impress with
the these expressions of emotion,
the viewer.
It's Ab testing.
Your goal is to impress the viewer
enough to where they choose your agent
versus another agent,
and those that are most loved agents,
most loved will be the ones that are
declared winners in a twist.
We will add human beings into this mix,
so we've created a system that maps are
human faces,
myself and the Ta's to where we
ourselves enter an outcome in the
competition and try to convince you to
keep us as your friend.
That's the turing test.
Okay.
Ethical car building in the ideas of the
trolley problem and the moral machine
done here in the media lab.
They incredible,
interesting work.
We take a machine learning approach to
it and take what we've developed,
the deep reinforcement learning
competition for a six zero,
nine for the deep traffic and we add
pedestrians into it to cast stochastic
irrational,
unpredictable pedestrians,
and we add human life to the loss
function where there's a tradeoff
between getting from point a to point b.
So in deep traffic,
the deeper enforcement learning
competition,
the goal was to go as fast as possible.
Here it's up to you to decide what you,
what your agents goal is.
There's a parade of front tradeoff
between getting from point a to point B
as fast as possible and hurting
pedestrians.
This is not a ethical question.
It's an engineering question and it's a
serious one because fundamentally in
creating autonomous vehicles that
function in this world,
we want them to get from point a to
point B as quickly as possible.
The United States government insurance
companies put a price tag on human life.
We put that power in your hands in
designing these agents to ask the
question of a,
how can we create machine learning
systems where the objective function,
the loss function has human life as part
of it and vote ai is an aggregator of
different links,
different articles,
papers,
videos on the topic of artificial
general intelligence where people vote
on a vote,
quality articles up and down and choose
on the sentiment of positive and
negative.
We'd like to explore the different ways
to the different arguments for and
against artificial general intelligence.
There is an incredible list of speakers
the best in their disciplines from Josh
Tenenbaum,
Ghana,
mit to ray Kurzweil at Google,
to Lisa Feldman,
Barrett and nature Bensky from
northeastern university,
Andre Carpathy,
Steven Wolf from Richard Moise,
Mark Reiber,
ltss giver,
and myself,
Josh Tenenbaum.
Tomorrow I'd like to go through each of
these speakers and talk about the
perspectives they bring that to try to
try to see the approach,
the ideas they bring to the table.
They're not,
in most cases interested in the
discussion of the future impact on
society without grounding it into the
expertise,
into the actual engineering,
into creating these intelligence
systems.
So Josh is a computation and cognitive
science expert.
Professor Faculty here at Mit.
He will talk about how we can create
common sense understanding systems that
see a world of physical objects and
their interactions and our own
possibilities to act,
interact with others,
the intuitive physics.
How do we build into systems the
intuitive physics of the world more than
just the deep learning memorization
engines that take patterns and learn
through supervised way to map those
patterns to classification.
Actually begin to understand the
intuitive common sense physics of the
world and learn rapid model based
learning.
Learn from nothing,
learned from very little,
just like we do as children,
just like we do as human being
successfully,
often only need one example to learn a
concept.
How do we create systems that learn from
very few,
sometimes a single example and integrate
ideas from various disciplines,
of course,
from neural networks,
but also probabilistic generative models
and symbol processing architectures.
It's gonna be incredible of course,
from a,
from a different area of the world.
Uh,
another incredible thinker,
intellectual speaker is Ray Kurzweil.
He'll be here on Wednesday at 1:00
PM and he will do a whirlwind discussion
of where we stand with intelligence,
creating intelligence systems,
how we see natural intelligence,
our own human intelligence,
how we define it,
how we understand it,
and how that transfers to the increasing
exponential growth of development,
of artificial general intelligence.
Something I'm very excited about
is Lisa Feldman Barrett coming here on
Thursday.
She's written a book,
I believe,
how emotions are made.
He argues that emotions are created,
that there is a distinction,
there is a detachment between what we
feel in our bodies,
the physical state of our bodies,
and the expression of emotion from,
from body to the contextually grounded
to the face expressing that emotion,
which means now why is this a person who
is a psychology person in a
fundamentally engineer and computer
science topic like Agi?
Because if emotions are created and the
way she argues and she'll systematically
break it down,
that means we're learning societal.
As human beings,
we're learning societal norms of how to
express emotion.
The idea of emotional intelligence has
learned,
which means we can have machines learn
this idea.
It's a machine learn just like it's a
human learning problem.
It's some machine learning problem in a
little bit of a twist.
She asked that instead of giving a talk,
I have a conversation with her so
there's going to be a little bit
challenging and fun and,
uh,
she's great looking forward to it and
we'll explore different ways that we can
get emotion expressed through video,
through audio,
through the project.
The Angel Project that I mentioned.
So there's has been worked and
reenacting intelligence,
so a well reenacting mapping face to
face mapping different emotions on video
that was previously recorded.
So if you can imagine that means we can
take emotions that we've created,
the kind of emotion creation we've been
discussing and remap it on previous
video.
That's one way to see intelligence is
taking raw human data that we already
have and mapping new computer generated
the the,
the underlying fundamentals of human,
but the surface appearance,
the representation of emotion,
visual or auditory is generated by
computer.
It could be in the embodied form like
with Sophia,
so different if you take a long time for
to context and jealousy and it might be
possible than any.
The more ethical,
a good partnership.
Very important to note for those
captivated by Sophia in the press or
have seen these videos.
Sophia is an art exhibit.
She's not a strong natural language
processing system.
This is not an agi system,
but it's a beautiful visualization of
embodying of.
It's a beautiful visualization of how
easy it is to trick us human beings.
That there is intelligence,
an underlying something that the
emotional expression,
the physical embodiment and the
emotional expression that has that has
some degree of humor that has some
degree of wit and intelligence is enough
to captivate us,
so that's an argument for not creating
intelligence from scratch,
but having machines at the very surface,
the display of that emotion,
the generation,
the mapping of the visual and the
auditory elements were underneath.
It is really trivial technology that's
fundamentally relying on humans.
Like in Sophia's case and in the
simplest form,
we remove all elements of shit.
How should I say,
attractive appearance from a,
from an agent.
We really keep it to the simplest
muscles aspect,
characteristics of the face and see with
26 muscles controlled by a neural
network through time,
so recurrent neural network.
I was tm.
How can we explore the generation of
emotion?
Can we get this thing,
and this is an open question for us too.
We just created the system.
We don't know if we can.
Can we get it to make us feel something,
make us feel something.
By watching it express its feelings,
can it become human before our eyes can
now learn to back competing against
other agents?
Ab testing on Turk.
I'm mechanical Turk.
Can the winters be very convincing to
make us feel entertained?
Pity,
love.
Maybe some of you will fall in love with
Angela here,
mate Devenski.
On Friday we'll talk about cognitive
modeling architectures,
so you will speak about the cognitive
modeling aspect.
Can have a a Ma.
Can we model cognition in some kind of
systematic way to try to build intuition
of Hok?
Complicated cognition is Andrea
[inaudible],
famous for being the state of the art
human on the image net challenge,
the representative,
the 95 percent accuracy performance
among other things he's also famous for
is now a tesla.
He will talk about
the role,
the limitations,
the possibilities of deep learning.
We'll talk,
as I have spoken about in the past few
weeks and throughout about our
misunderstanding or are flawed intuition
about what are the difficult and what
are the easy problems in deep learning
and the power of the representational
learning,
the ability of neural networks to form
deeper and deeper representations that
the underlying raw data that ultimately
forms that takes complex information
that's hard to make sense of and a
converted into useful actionable
knowledge
that is from a certain Lens in a certain
certain Lens and a certain problem space
can be clearly defined as understanding
of the complex information understanding
is ultimately taking complex information
and reducing it to a simple essential
elements,
representational learning and the
trivial case here in drawing a having to
draw a straight line to separate the
blue and the red curves.
That's impossible to do in a in a Nigel
input space on the left.
What the act of learning is for deep
neural networks in this formulation is
to construct the topology under which
there exists a straight line to
accurately classify blue versus red.
That's the problem,
and for a simple blue and red line,
it seems trivial here,
but this works in the general case for
arbitrary input spaces for arbitrary,
nonlinear,
highly dimensional input spaces and the
ability to automatically learn features
too,
to learn hierarchical representations of
the raw sensory data means that you
could do a lot more with data,
which means you can expand further and
further and further to create
intelligence systems that,
uh,
operate successfully with real world
data.
That's what representation learning
means.
That deep learning allows because the
arbitrary number of features that can be
automatically determined,
you can learn a lot of things about a
pretty complex world.
Unfortunately,
there needs to be a lot of supervised
data.
There still needs to be a lot of human
input.
Andre and others,
Josh will talk about the difference
between our human brain are biological
and neural network and the artificial
neural network,
the full human brain with 100 billion
neurons,
1000 trillion synapses and the biggest
neural networks out there,
the artificial neural networks having
much smaller,
$60,
million synapses for resident at 1:52.
The biggest difference,
the parameter is the human brain being
several orders of magnitude more
synapses.
That topology being much more complex,
chaotic,
the asynchronous nature of the human
brain and the learning algorithm of
artificial neural networks is trivial
and constrained with backpropagation is
essentially an optimization function
over a,
over a clearly defined last function
from the output to the,
uh,
to the input using backpropagation to
teach,
to adjust the waist on that network.
The learning algorithm for our human
brain is most of the unknown,
but it's certainly much more complicated
than backpropagation.
The power consumption.
The human brain is a lot more efficient
than artificial neural networks.
And there's a very kind of artificial,
a trivial supervised learning process
for training artificial neural networks.
You have to have a training stage and
you have to have an evaluation stage and
once the network is trained,
there's no clear way to continue
training it or there's,
there's a lot of ways,
but they're inefficient.
It's not designed to do online learning,
uh,
naturally to always be learning is
designed to be,
to learn and then be applied.
Obviously our human brains are always
learning,
but the beautiful,
fascinating thing is that they're both
distributed computation systems on a
large scale,
so it's not a,
uh,
there's,
it doesn't ultimately boil down to a
single compute unit.
The computation is distributed.
The backpropagation learning process
distributed can be paralyzed in a GPU,
massively parallelized.
The underlying computational unit of a
neuron is trivial,
but can be stacked together to form
forward neural networks,
recurrent neural networks to represent
both spacial information with images and
temporal information with a audio
speech,
text sequences of images and video and
so on.
Mapping from one to one,
one to many,
many to one,
so the mapping,
any kind of structure vector and time
data as an input to any kind of
classification,
regression sequences,
captioning,
video,
audio as output,
learning in the general sense,
but in a domain that's precisely defined
for the supervised training process.
We can think of the in deep learning
case.
You can think of the supervised methods
where humans have to annotate the data
as memorization of the data.
We can think of the exciting new and
growing field of semi supervised
learning when most of the data through
off through generative adversarial
networks or through significant data
augmentation,
clever data augmentation,
most of it is done automatically.
The annotation process or through
simulation and then reinforcement
learning where most of the,
uh,
most of the labels are extremely sparse
and come rarely.
And so the system has to figure out how
to operate in the world with very little
human input,
very little human data.
We can think of that as reasoning
because you take very little information
from our teachers,
the humans and transfer it across,
generalize it across a to reason about
the world.
And finally,
uh,
unsupervised learning,
the excitement of the community that
promise,
the hope.
You could think of that as understanding
because ultimately it's taking data with
very little or no human input.
And for me representations that that
data is how we think of understanding,
requiring,
making sense of the world without strict
input of how to make sense of the world.
The kind of process of discovering
information,
maybe discovering new ideas,
new ways to simplify the world to
represent the world that you can do new
things with it.
The new is the key element there.
Understanding and uh,
Andrea and Eylea and others will talk
about the certainly the past,
but the future of deep learning.
Whereas going to go is it over hyped,
under hyped?
What is the future?
Will the compute of CPU GPU as six
continue with the breakthroughs,
the Moore's law and its various forms of
massive parallelization continue and the
large data sets with tens of millions of
images grow to billions and trillions.
Will the algorithms improve?
Is there a groundbreaking idea that's
still coming with,
uh,
with Geoff Hinton's?
Capsule networks is a fundamental
architectural changes in your networks
that we can come up with that will
change everything,
that will ease the learning process.
They'll make the learning process more
efficient or will be able to represent
higher and higher orders of information
is such that you can transfer knowledge
between domains and the software
architectures that support intensive
Florida Pi Torch.
Uh,
I would say the last year and this year
will be the year of deep learning
frameworks.
So will,
those will certainly keep coming in
their various forms and the financial
backing is growing and growing the open
challenges for deep learning.
Really a lot of this course is kind of
connected to deep learning because
that's where a lot of the recent
breakthroughs that inspire us to think
about intelligence systems come from.
But the challenges are many,
the,
the need,
the ability to transfer between
different domains as in reinforcement
learning and robotics.
The need for huge data and an efficient
learning.
Uh,
we're,
we're still need supervised data.
Uh,
inability to learn in an unsupervised
way is a huge problem and not fully
automated learning.
There's still a degree,
a significant degree of hyper parameter
tuning necessary with the reward
functions.
The loss functions are ultimately
defined by humans and therefore are
deeply flawed.
When we released those systems into the
real world where there is no ground
truth for the testing set and the goal
isn't achieving a class,
a high classification on a trivial,
a image classification,
localization detection problem,
but rather to have an autonomous vehicle
that doesn't kill pedestrians or an
industrial robot that operates in
jointly with other human beings and all
the edge cases that come up.
How does deep learning methods,
how to machine learning methods
generalize over the edge cases,
the weird stuff that happens in the real
world?
Those are all the problems there.
Stephen Wolfram will be here on Monday
evening at 7:00
PM,
has done a lot of amazing things,
I would say is very interesting from his
recent interest in knowledge based
programming.
Wolfram Alpha I think is the fuel for
most middle school and high school
students.
Now,
for the first time taking calculus I
pray,
probably go to Wolfram Alpha to answer
their own questions,
but more seriously,
there is a,
a deep connected graph of knowledge as
being built there with the wool from
wool,
from Alpha and wool from language that
still will explore in terms of language
and interesting thing.
He was part of the team on arrival that,
uh,
worked on the language.
If for those of you are familiar to
arrival where a alien species spoke with
us,
US humans through a very interesting,
beautiful,
complicated language and he was brought
in as a representative human to
interpret that language just like in the
movie,
who's represent that in real life.
And you use the skills that him and his
son Christopher used to analyze this
language.
Very interesting.
That process is extremely interesting.
I hope he talks about it and his
background with Mathematica and a new
kind of science.
The sort of another set of ideas that
have inspired people in terms of
creating intelligence systems is the
idea that from very simple things,
very simple rules,
extremely complex patterns can emerge.
His work with cellular Automata did just
that take an extremely simple
mathematical constructs here with
cellular Automata.
These are,
these are grids of computational units
that switch on and off and some kind of
predefined way and only operate locally
based on their local neighborhood and
somehow based on different kinds of
rules,
different patterns emerge.
Here's the three dimensional cellular
automata with a simple rule starting
with nothing with a single cell.
They grow and really interesting,
complex ways.
This emergent complexity is inspiring.
It's the same kind of thing that
inspires us about neural networks that
you can take a simple computational unit
and when combined together in arbitrary
ways can form complex representations.
That's also very interesting.
You can see knowledge from a knowledge
perspective.
You could see knowledge formation in the
same kind of way.
Simplicity at a mass distributed scale,
resulting complexity.
Next Tuesday,
Richard,
noise from article 36 coming all the way
from UK for us.
We'll talk about it works with
autonomous weapons systems,
works with also a nuclear weapons,
but primarily autonomous weapon systems
and concern legal policy and
technological aspects of banning these
weapons.
There's been a lot of agreement about
the safety hazards of autonomous systems
that make decisions to kill a human
being.
Mara Criber,
CEO,
Boston Dynamics,
previously long time ago,
faculty here at Mit,
we'll talk about.
We'll bring robots and talked to us
about his work of robots in the real
world as a,
doing a lot of exciting stuff with
humanoid robotics at 80 kinds of robots
operating on legs.
Uh,
it's incredible work,
extremely exciting and gets to explore
the idea of how difficult it is to build
these robots systems that operate in the
real world,
uh,
from both the Qa control aspect and from
the way the final result is perceived by
our society.
It's very interesting to see when
intelligence in robotics is embodied and
then taking in by us and what that
inspires.
Fear,
excitement,
hope,
concern,
and all of the above.
Les is a expert in many aspects of
machine learning.
Is the cofounder of open Ai.
Talk about there different aspects of
game playing that they've recently been
exploring by using deeper enforcement,
learning to play arcade games
and d on the deep mind side,
using deep reinforcement learning to
beat the best in the world that the game
of go in 2017.
The big fascinating breakthrough
achieved by that team with Alphago,
zero training and agent that through
self play playing itself,
not an expert games so truly from
scratch,
learning to beat the best in the world,
including the previous iteration of
Alphago.
We'll explore what aspects of the stack
of intelligent robotics systems
intelligent agents can be learned in
this way.
So deep learning,
the memorization,
the supervised learning memorization
approach.
It looks at the sensor data feature
extraction representation,
learning aspect of this,
taking the sensor data from camera,
a lidar audio,
extracting the features for me,
higher order of representations and on
those representations.
Learning to actually accomplish some
kind of classification regression task,
figuring out based on the representation
what is going on in the raw sensory data
and then combining that data together to
reason about it and finally in the
robotic domains,
taking it all together as with humanoid,
robotics,
industrial robotics,
autonomous vehicles taking altogether
and actually acting in this world where
the effectors and the open question is,
how much of this ai stack can be
learned?
That's something for us to discuss,
to think about.
The eylea will touch on with deeper
enforcement learning.
We can certainly learn representations
and perform classifications.
They are better than human I damaged
classification,
image,
net and segmentation tasks
and the excitement of deep learning is
what's highlighted there in the red box
can be done end to ends.
Raw sensory data out to the knowledge,
to the output,
to the classification.
Can we begin to reason is the open
question with the knowledge based
programming that Stephen Wolfman,
we'll talk about.
Can we begin to take these automatically
generated high order representations and
combine them together to form knowledge
basis,
to form a aggregate grass of ideas that
can then be used the reason
and can we then combine them together to
act in the world for whether in
simulation with arcade games or
simulation of autonomous vehicles or box
systems are actually in the physical
world with robots moving about that end
to end from raw sensory data to action
be learned.
That's the open question for for
artificial general intelligence for this
class.
Can this entire process be end to end?
Can we build systems and how do we do it
that achieve this process end to end in
the same way that humans do.
We're born in this raw sensory
environment,
taking in very little information and
learn to operate successfully an
arbitrary constraints,
arbitrary goals,
and to do so.
We have lectures,
we have three projects and we have guest
speakers from various disciplines.
I hope that all these voices will be
heard and will feed a conversation about
artificial intelligence and it's
positive and it's concerning effects in
society and how do we move forward from
an engineering approach.
The topics will be deep learning,
deep reinforcement learning,
cognitive modeling,
competition,
cognitive science,
emotion creation,
knowledge based programming,
ai safety with autonomous weapons
systems and personal robotics with human
centered artificial intelligence.
That's for the first two weeks of this
class.
That's the part where if you're actually
registered students,
that's where you need to submit the
project.
That's when we all meet here every,
every night with an incredible speakers,
but this will continue.
We're already have several speakers
scheduled the next couple of months yet
to be announced,
but they're incredible and we have
conversations on video.
We'll have new projects.
I hope this continues throughout 2018 on
the topics of Ai Ethics and bias.
There's a lot of incredible work in a
way know of a speaker.
There are coming on the topic of how do
we create artificial intelligence
systems that are do not discriminate,
did not form the kind of biases that US
humans do in this world that are
operating under social norms,
but our reasoning beyond the flawed
aspects of those social norms with bias,
creativity as well.
The project of dream vision and beyond.
There's so much exciting work qa and
using machine learning methods to create
beautiful art and music,
a brain stimulation,
neuroscience,
computation,
neuroscience.
Shockingly,
in the first two weeks we don't have a
computation neuroscience speaker,
which is a fascinating perspective.
Brain simulation or neuroscience in
general.
Computation neuroscience is a
fascinating approach from the from the
mark of actual brain work to get the
perspective of how our brain works and
how we can create something that mimics,
that resembles the fundamentals of what
makes our brain intelligent.
And finally the turing test.
The traditional definite shouldn't have
intelligence defined by Alan Turing was
grounded in natural language processing
and creating chat bots that impress us,
that amaze us and trick us into thinking
they're human.
We will have a project and a speaker on
natural language processing in March
that I like to thank you for coming
today and look forward to seeing your
submissions for the three projects.
Thank you very much.