The following is a conversation
with Serratia of all.
He's an educator and entertainer,
a rapper, and an entrepreneur.
He's the founder of school of Ai,
which is an online education platform
and community that makes topics and data
science, machine learning,
AI accessible to everyone.
He's one of the most unique, eccentric
and creative educators on the Internet,
constantly innovating and reinventing
himself. Many people love them,
some people don't.
But the inspiring thing about Sarraj is
that he doesn't let the critic stopped
them. He just learns from
the criticism and improves.
You should go to his youtube channel
and subscribe for many accessible
introductory videos and AI.
Unlike cause youtube videos,
this conversation was a relaxed low
key chat about his personal story,
his process,
and his vision.
This conversation is part or
the artificial intelligence
podcasts. If you enjoy,
subscribe on Youtube,
iTunes,
or simply connect with me on Twitter at
[inaudible] Friedman, spelledF , r I, d.
And now here's my conversation with Siraj,
Jay z or Kanye,
Kanye.
Anybody better than Kanye in terms of
producing music in terms of the full
package,
I mean her as a full package,
probably Kendrick Lamar.
Okay.
You're one of the most unapologetically
unique personalities in the Ai Community.
So I want to talk to you today a little
bit less about AI and a little bit more
about what I think inspires thousands
of people if not more about you Raj,
which is the lack of fear and
trying something different.
Even if you fail and you
openly and publicly are
searching for yourself and try
to define who you are as an individual,
as a person.
And I think the way you're doing that
openly sort of online in video form and
trying crazy things going all out in the
most confident way of scene is pretty
inspiring.
And it,
I think too many people in this world
in general are just afraid to do that,
to be fragile,
to put themselves out there,
especially the internet, especially
youtube. In the face of criticism,
scrutiny. So many people love
you, are inspired by you,
but some people criticize
you. Um, looking at,
uh,
you machine learning subreddit,
how do you take such criticism,
especially when you put so much of
yourself in the content that you put out?
When I first started it definitely hurt.
I would post pretty much all my videos
to reiterate what you said. Yes.
In the machine learning sub
reddit, but generally, yeah,
it was mostly negative feedback
and um, yeah, I mean it,
it legitimately hurt,
but I think what got me to
keep going despite that was
that I felt like this field,
the techniques, um, in AI
were more significant than me.
It's not about me. Like I can be the
gesture, you know, I can be the joker,
I can be that martyr that people can
make fun of as long as people get it,
that this is a very important technology
and we can use it to make huge impacts
in society. As long as people get that,
I don't care what people say about me.
Over time I've become more and more
numb to the haters. We're at this point,
I feel like pretty much
like oblivious finally.
Well hold on a second. So
that, that's a beautiful thing.
It's about the idea that you're trying
to spread about the sort of inspire and
just open the eyes and the door to people
that don't know anything about machine
learning. Get them into
it, get them excited,
whether you're young or old or whatever.
But you're also trying to find yourself
like all of us are and doing it pretty
publicly. So in that sense, criticism,
I know criticism hurts
me a lot when people,
cause I am trying to put myself out there
and I'm putting my ugly face and voice
that I hate listening to out there.
And it hurts when somebody says,
this guy's an idiot that that doesn't,
you're saying at this point it
gets better. It gets better.
It does get better because if you
keep putting out value to society,
eventually you'll have
more lovers than haters.
And the lovers just outweigh the haters.
Okay.
So your trajectory up to this point,
it's been, let's say unconventional.
You've pretty much made your way,
uh,
your own way and ignored
what others have said.
Or at least you know,
the,
the folks who may be pushed you to
go towards the more conventional way.
And you've been pretty honest about it.
So let's, let's go to the beginning.
Tell me where you grew up.
I was born in Houston, Houston,
Texas. My parents are from India.
I was born in,
obviously in Houston.
Spent 18 years there before I
moved to New York for college.
Right. Columbia. But Columbia, what's
it like growing up? I mean, is it,
uh,
so I grew up in Jewish parents.
There's a lot of pressure to
do certain kinds of things,
right. And doctor, lawyer,
scientist.
Uh,
what were your parents doing and what
were they pushing you into doing?
So Jewish in Indian
parents are pretty similar.
I've learned that after having gone to
Columbia, met a lot of Jewish people,
may a lot of Jewish friends in
San Francisco as well in and La.
So there were similar in that they're like
scientists, engineer, lawyer, you know,
you need to marry, marry a good
Indian girl or Jewish girl, you know,
just to point out the
similarity yet again. But, um,
it was very much conservative.
Do what you're told,
don't question things too much, get
a stable job and uh, go to a really,
really good school because we're
not going to pay for your college.
So you need to really get a full
ride to Columbia or some good school,
which I did. So that thankful
he pulled that off. So
what was your value system?
What, uh, what do you, what,
what did you find gave you meaning
and you're in the early days?
I, so one of the interesting
things is you've grown a lot.
You've developed a lie, you've evolved
a lot. It's clear from just your path.
Uh,
I,
I've read that you've changed your name
and then gone back and you struggle with
your identity and some
very interesting ways.
But let's start at the sort of the
beginning who were trying to be, how,
how we try to fit in.
So growing up in Houston,
which was not inside of a city,
but it was more like the farm
lands, it's like majority, you know,
Caucasian white people.
And, um, yeah, I was like,
we were the only Indian
family in the area.
So I felt kind of like
an outsider growing up.
So that, that, that feeling of being,
feeling a little alienated
from other people,
I think that helped my creativity and to
be able to look at things from both an
insiders and an outsider's perspective,
and to put those two perspectives together
to create some new idea or thought or
path forward. I definitely felt alienated
and in my, what I was trying to be in,
what I was trying to do was to fit in.
So what that meant in the context
of Houston and Texas was like,
I want it to be more,
let's just say white anglicised,
American, white, Christian. You know,
those values that everybody around me
held that my family didn't necessarily
hold.
I want it to be more like that.
So I wanted to be loved and liked.
What point
did you change your name? You try changing
your name to become more England size.
When I was 18, so right when I got my
letter to Columbia, the acceptance letter,
I legally changed it
against my parents' wishes.
And in fact they offered me money not
to change it. Um, you told them? Yeah,
the discussion and we had this discussion,
like I'm changing my name to
Jason Scott rebel because, uh,
I feel like it would be easier just to,
for everything to,
for whatever reason I felt like that,
like that at the time.
And to get a job to get accepted
by people too, you know,
um, do a bunch of things. So I
did it and when I got to Columbia,
that's what I, the name I went by. Um,
but just to like put things into even
even more extreme perspective that I don't
think I've said before. Not only
did I change my name, but I like,
I wore green contacts and I dyed my hair
a little brown and I told people that I
was, um, you know, half Brazilian.
I really didn't like my ancestry,
my ethnicity,
and uh, I just felt like I
want it to be something else.
I'm going to reinvent myself.
So that could be like more,
I mean this is the coolest theme that
continues with you is really interesting.
Did you have a vision of that?
Of being half Brazilian or was
this a off the cuff I had a vision.
So like you're,
you have like Steve Jobs,
you have an intention behind that person.
You see yourself as,
yeah. Yeah. More I think more social
cause I was pretty introverted
in high school, more popular,
more liked and a funner,
a better dancer.
And
how did it feel being that, you know,
that's a big step just going to college,
leaving parents, parents behind. What did
it feel like to a show up in New York?
It was super exciting.
The first two,
three months,
we're super exciting and new and people
I felt pretty accepted and that's not
because I was, you know, looking back
half Brazilian or whatever. I just,
I'd never known
what a culture like
Columbia could be like. I,
I'd never been in that kind of scenario
where everyone's pretty, you know,
educated and has a more worldly view,
you know,
to,
to give you one example,
in my public high school and I went
to a pretty good public high schools,
giant public high school feeder school
for a lot of people in the area.
I remember in our history class senior
year, the teacher asks a question,
is anyone watching the g 20 summit
or know what that is? You're,
are you familiar with the judgment?
And so,
and my class was like IB
international baccalaureate,
which is kind of like a piece,
like an advance.
It's like the advanced program
of that public high school.
So it was like the smartest kids in
the high school. Nobody accepted me,
raise my hand because no one.
And that's when I realized like does no
one care about what's happening outside
of the u s you know,
but whereas in Colombia,
everybody knew obviously what that was.
And so that was cool.
So I did feel more accepted.
It's not because I don't think it was
because I had changed my name or anything,
but I had to learn that. So I changed
it back. By the way, I changed my back.
My name legally backs your name Sir Roger
Hall, which is my original name. Yeah.
One of that happen pretty quickly.
Oh,
it happened four years later.
So when I moved to San
Francisco after I left Colombia.
Was that with intention behind it as well?
Well
that was intention.
I had a startup at the time called lucid
robotics and we were building a seven
degree of freedom autonomous robot to
help older people with als to pick things
up off the floor, controlled by an iPad
via remote, you know, camera vision,
object detection, touch the object.
And then autonomous grasping.
This is like 2014. So I was like
deep learning wasn't like really,
um,
feasible for on device.
Would you use deep learning?
No, of course. Yeah, you
would have a robotic arm. Uh,
for autonomous. I mean
opening, I had the, uh,
the grasping demo,
which was cool simulation,
a version of DRL, which was kind of
right, but for product, if you want
to go product, most, uh,
most industrial robotics,
most manipulation is not going to use RL,
at least from what I've seen.
I mean,
not Pieter Abbeel is trying to get,
trying to start applying our own that
space. But you look at Boston Dynamics,
he look at, uh, uh, was Rodney
Brooks is rethink robotics.
There's no RL insight.
It's interesting.
If you waited a little longer and see
how a deep learning version of that would
have worked out, you ever
think about getting back into
the startup world? I mean,
you're in a startup now in a sense
that you're creating your own,
whatever you want to call it, whether
it's a youtube channel or a media empire,
it's somewhere in between, right? The hope
is to create an accredited university,
accredited university.
So what do you think is broken or is not
broken about the university education
system too expensive as money, money.
What about the actual experience?
Say it was all free.
Say it was all the same.
Do you think you think
you can be improved upon?
So you've been teaching a lot of very
large number of people through uh,
through online,
through video forum.
Do you think that's more
effective as audacity model?
What's Sebastian through and as
explored and you have explored,
do you think there is a,
it's more effective than
a classroom education?
I do think it's more effective,
but there are still people who are going
to want to get a bachelor's degree.
Like, you know, certificates
have their place, right?
Bootcamps training programs,
they all have their place.
But the idea of a four year degree
isn't going away anytime soon.
So that needs to be upgraded to Internet
status and that needs to be made free
and to have that same
student support quality.
And I'm talking about the full spectrum
of student support and not just um,
support for a specific module of a course,
but mental health,
like the full spectrum of what a school
like MIT provides needs to be made
freely available online.
Is that where school of Ai Fits
in? Yeah, it's just school.
The guys building a global large
community of people. Right.
So you think that's,
there's a future in which school of AI
gets accredited status where you can get
degrees and so on. That's,
that's my, that's my dream.
I've heard,
you mentioned somewhere,
I read mentioned somewhere that you
want to essentially be a movie star,
right?
In that kind of swim in that realm.
Is that still a dream of yours to exist
in some kind of a height and status and
realm of movie stars?
So definitely when I started there
was a need for external validation.
It wasn't all internal like, oh, I
educated them, I feel good. It was also,
I want to loved by the
audience and I wanted to,
and I felt like by becoming famous,
that would be something that I could feel.
And I felt like, you know, I've
been doing this for three years now,
which is not that long, but three years
now I feel validated externally by now.
Like why now? I'm good. So, so
why do I want to be movie stars?
So the reason I mentioned that is it's
not for more, um, external validation,
like my name on the billboards. Like I'm,
I'm good. Like if I stay this famous,
but I can continue to do this goal of
getting like a accredited, you know,
university, I will be happy. And like
having, you know, a few close friends,
you know, living in La, I'm good. Like
I don't need to be more famous anymore.
Like I, I felt it. Why do I want to be
a movie star? So let me correct you.
I did want to be in a movie earlier,
but now what it is is I want to either
have a Netflix show or just join the
mainstream in some ways. So I can
propagate this message to the youth,
which is the future of Ai.
So to give you one example,
last week I was at a party at a club
in La called Dalilah's and Drake's dad
shows up and Drake is there as
well. And like, I didn't even know.
He strikes out and we were
like chatting and I was like,
and then like one guy was
like, hey, hey you Indian. I
was like, yeah. He's like, hi,
you cool. I was like, wow, that's all it
takes. But like they were like a crew,
like they all knew each other.
A bunch of rappers,
Atlanta Mbos are pulling up SUVs and
I'm sitting here trying to whisper sweet
nothings about data and algorithms into
the ears of these rappers because if and
Jaden Smith, the reason I went there
is because I heard a rap, Jaden Smith,
he's will Smith's son.
He made a rap called Calabasas
freestyle and this is so nerdy.
I know exactly the time marker
at the two 45 minute mark,
he mentioned the word neural net
and the full line was that's what the
neural net will become when the AI is
sentient.
And so that's when I saw hope because
Jane not 2 million views on that music
video. The youth listen to
Jayden and hip hop has, you know,
just their past rock music as the number
one listened to genre in the United
States. I did not know that. And that's
similar to something as powerful.
That's powerful. So if I can
be, I don't need to be the guy,
I don't need to be the rapper like I was
just doing it because no one else was
doing it.
If I can be the advisor to the guy,
like I'm trying to get this stuff into
the ears of these influential mainstream
rappers in and if not
that's not going to work.
Then I'll try Netflix show like something
like something's radical needs to
happen to get people who care about
like totally not unrelated topics like
fashion and music and art
and beauty culture news and
focus it on data literacy.
Technical literacy because that's
where the jobs of the future are.
And that's how we're going to
stay competitive as a country.
But I have a global view.
So every country and everybody needs to
be competitive and impacting society.
So like we really got to bring this
down to the Kim Kardashian level.
I like this a data literacy.
You know,
the Kardashians are several orders
of magnitude more famous than any AI
researcher, almost any scientists
in the world. And so it's,
it's nice that you're thinking basically
how to break any aspect of this into
the mainstream,
into the real mainstream.
And it sounds like you're not
constrained to anyone medium or anyone.
Path is basically anything and you're
just creating all kinds of crazy things to
try to get there. So where
did rap come from? You uh,
you started making rap videos,
you have rap videos.
I bought a bunch of different topics.
Pretty good rhymes,
but it is nevertheless about AI,
which is hard to do. It's not,
it's like a, it's a difficult dance
you're playing, right? Cause, uh,
cause rap is,
you can educate me more,
but there's a rap is more
about not giving a damn.
So not caring and in a certain
there's a coolness to just like,
uh,
not giving a damn about anything and
in your apps or is that kind of you are
giving a damn about
something and it's pretty uh,
sort of technical and scientific, which
currently has a weight of being nerdy,
so it's not cool. So you're
basically going up hill. Yeah.
So what,
what inspired you?
What made you brave enough to
put out the first one? Actually
that's a good question.
And the people at the youtube space,
we're like laughing and also looking
at each other. Like what does he do?
Talk to you about?
Cause I made at the youtube space
as a part of this creator camp.
The first one alone la.
Yeah. In La a long time ago.
Like three years ago when I first
started, well, produce, it's well written.
I mean the whole thing. So you didn't
just, it wasn't like off the cuff,
it was well done. So he said, okay.
So let's take me through the genesis.
Like what were your thoughts?
What were your hopes?
What was your vision for it?
I've always liked my favorite subject
growing up in school as much as technology
is, that wasn't really a subject
growing up in school was English,
like wordplay and how to communicate and
put words together for maximum impact.
And I've always had,
um, when I, when, when,
whenever I was studying for tests or
anything like mnemonic devices like rhymes
helped me memorize things.
So what's the perfect
medium for rhyming rap?
The perfect medium that is also
relevant to youth, the youth. So yeah,
just putting together,
you know,
like how can I simplify all of neural
network architecture into like two lines
of English input times away, add a bias,
activate. Obviously there's more to it.
Yeah. But it's easy. Remember it
rhymes and then you add a beat to it.
And there there's your, there's your way
of studying and once you're out a test,
you're in a test,
you can just remember it much easier.
So it's a pneumonic device.
So I felt like that was my,
um, drive. And I was thinking,
well, if I, if I would like it,
I guess I made the bet that
there are other people who would
do this as well because I would always
make wraps just in my head about,
you know,
gps or like robots.
Like I'd make songs and I
know he's like super weird,
but also like I'm also
used to being weird. I'm,
I'm used to being abnormal and not normal.
And I think part of it was like
having a chip on my shoulder of like,
I'm going to bring my abnormal reality
into the mainstream and change culture
because I've got nothing
to lose and I've got,
I'll only be here for like a hundred years
and like, let's just see what happens.
So the thing is, you
know, that rep got, again,
a lot of love, but it also got, you know,
like the usual haters, right? Right.
Because you are really making yourself
fragile. You'd try and do something,
you know from your perspective from the,
you're been in society,
you're not supposed to do that.
Right.
So you're totally doing what you're not
supposed to be doing. And a as weird.
And so people are reacting in that way.
So what was your feeling like because
you did more and they've gotten better.
Yeah, they keep getting
better. That's the point. I'm,
I'm approximate the day when nobody
says cringey on the top comments.
I will be happy we're getting
there. I'm getting there. Yeah.
Like every time it gets better.
Like I take all that feedback.
Like I also know that people who are
commenting, cause I'm like uh, uh,
a comment analysis machine. I read
everything. I read all that data,
I look at audience retention,
I look at the jokes that I made a at
that point and see did it go up or down
based on that. And I've, it's
all a big feedback loop. You
know, for me, you look at
criticism,
what,
what do you in that in the full context
you're able to see the criticism is just
one person saying a thing, one
another data point, another data.
Well you know, like my latest music video
I've spent the most money on for sure,
but I spent 10 k, 10 k on it
and it's all done. Thank you.
So production value, way better than
ever before. Lyrical VA value that. Um,
the, the, the musical value,
the beat best I've ever done,
the lyrical valued now that's
where I know I need to work on.
So it's like I'm moving up
all these metrics and I know
what to work on the next
source. Like lyrically, I tried to fit
an entire AI lecture into this last,
I did fit an entire
electric into the last Rep.
Now I know that it doesn't have
to be an entire AI lecture.
It's more about how it sounds and,
and people will pick out like one line.
Yeah,
they're not gonna memorize the entire
thing. They'll pick out one line.
And so you really got to focus on
making that one line both impactful,
educational and easy to remember.
A catchy and then the rest can just kind
of be filler and like Yo, yeah, yeah.
Whatever.
What about, have you tried thinking
of going like the na's route,
like a gong less produced,
more like using a dark
room with a mic versus,
there's like, there's a bunch of, I mean,
it looks like a rap video. You recent one,
like, you know those girls and there's
a, it's well produced. Thanks. Have you,
have you thought about just doing
like, I dunno, yeah, Nas on Mike.
That's a great song. I Love Nas in, I,
I right now I find too much fun
making the youtube videos, like, yeah.
And I'm also like,
I feel compelled to do it
for all of this year. Um, but
when I reach a certain metric,
I will,
I might look into that.
Do you have a number in your head?
They chasing? I do have a number.
You want to share that number? 1
million? It's arbitrary. Oh, yeah, yeah,
yeah. I know. It's awkward for me if
people don't know you have, I mean,
you're approaching 600,000
subscribers. Yeah. I mean,
is there a, you're probably one of
the most popular youtube channels, uh,
of on a technical topic. Well, that's not
true. There's, um, there's a number file,
computer files, uh, three ground.
Yeah. Uh, but you're in that I'm
up there. Yeah. Here in Europe.
You certainly the only one
wrapping, I mean the, one of
the cool things while you,
like I said,
keep harboring on this
cause it's inspiring to me I
think is inspiring to a lot
of people is that you're chasing,
you're not,
you're not trying to fit into anything.
You're, you're trying to be trying,
you are unique and you try to
be yourself essentially. Yup.
As you try to become more who
you are and becoming unique,
discovering that you're,
that sound,
that voice,
who do you find yourself becoming?
How have you changed in the three years
that you've been working on your channel?
Not In terms of content, but in terms of
who you are when you look in the mirror.
I think I've become more humble,
more patient,
more patient for sure.
More patient with people that I
work with or tend to work with
more empathetic,
kinder and
that's more patient, more empathetic,
kinder. Those are the big three.
What, what, did you have a temper
before? No, I didn't have a temper.
I had, uh, I,
I wasn't very patient with
like to work with people.
That's how I worked by myself for so long
cause I wanted to move so fast and he
always had to be like my way.
It's not like I was like angry if
someone that I just said, all right,
we're not gonna work together.
Thank you.
So like I look back at like you'd ask
city, I'm like, oh, I could have nicer.
I always have to have in my way.
They were trying for sure. Good team,
good people. Yeah. You
[inaudible] is a good team.
Uh, so yeah, working with others,
you know, it's tough to create,
especially when you're perfection,
especially when you do the kind
of output the you're doing.
It's hard to create with others.
So have you found,
you said you've gotten better at it.
Have you found a magic formula,
but how you're able to collaborate
with somebody else or, um,
is it mostly, is, is most of
the content, most of the idea,
most of the core of what you're
doing still just you on Mike.
I have compromised a little bit
like I know how to compromise now.
It's not just always my way.
It's for the greater good like educating
people and as long as we're all on that,
you know, we all have the same
goal. Like we can work together.
You want to give me an example?
Yeah.
Sort of working with someone who
wants to fund my movement,
you know, with his,
with his own funds and we
have, you know, it was,
it was kind of hard to like work together
at first because we came at things
from such different angles.
Like I have a specialty and
that's social media velocity.
I can make content really
fast and he has an angle,
which is academic rigor and creating a,
being able to create a very rigorous
curriculum that can be analyzed and tested
by authorities.
And just like trying to combine those two.
It's been hard as rough, but like,
and it's been only like a month now,
but like it's working out.
Let's talk about that. The rate of
which you output content is incredible.
It's pretty rich. And, um, you know,
there's a lot going on in the videos.
There's a lot of content,
but in terms of rigor,
sometimes your videos can lack rigor,
right? Just because you're so focused.
I mean,
at least from my perspective,
you can maybe speak to it is still
focused on the creative art of it,
that sometimes,
uh,
that's probably what your creative
processes like is more, uh,
treating it like a rap video
versus sort of dealed school, uh,
lecture. Yeah. So, uh, do,
do you ever think about that?
Do you ever consider slowing down,
uh, or even slowing down here?
I'll give you two examples. So one is
sort of the angel rang, which you can,
I could never see a Sarraj doing an ain't
drink style video where it's just like
you a very plain, you know,
nothing really going on.
Or have you ever considered
taking, you know what? I'm
sorry. Three blue one brown,
is it three? Yeah, three blue
on Brown, you know, taking,
he takes sometimes over a month,
right to do one video.
Have you ever considered doing that?
I've considered it,
but I am a now a slave to the youtube
algorithm and I have a certain subscriber
growth that I wanted to continue and it
would be quite a risk to take some time
away from that.
And other youtubers have faced similar
issues and it's part of the reason why so
many top youtubers are burning out because
the algorithm kind of doesn't allow
you to take a break.
Like either you keep submitting content
at the pace you have or will stop
sending new subscribers
your way. Hmm. Not that,
I mean it's a valid question like,
you know, why not just do that?
But I think I don't want to risk that
is one risk. I don't want to take,
like I'm on a very steady
growth trajectory right now.
The videos work well enough. I want to
improve them at the rate that I am. Yes.
I could slow down, make less and
increase the quality even more.
But I think I'm really going to try
to do both quality and quantity.
You maybe you can split because
I actually don't know this stuff
at all. Uh, some of it just seems
like a, what does it, alchemy, yeah,
the youtube game is so much a part of
my existence, my life, my dopamine,
my reward signals are so attuned
to views and likes and comments.
Interesting that I can't imagine
not doing this. Yeah. You know,
I'm sure after I hit a million, like
I'm going to be like, whew, all right,
time to stop. And then it's like,
what, what else do I do now? But like,
I really am gonna you know,
I'm always going to be
educating storytelling about
AI and data and technology
is just like, what is the next
medium after youtube? I don't know.
Like you said Netflix or
something like Netflix would
be sick. Yeah. Yeah. Netflix,
if you're watching, you know, with,
you know who it is right here. Uh,
do you think you could walk away
from Youtube for, uh, six months?
Uh, I wonder ultimately for your
happiness, for your wellbeing,
for your success as an
educator and sort of,
I'm a person that's putting
a AI into the stratosphere,
trying to make a famous,
what's the best move?
What do you think is the best move
was the 2018 is about rap videos.
So this year is like focus on youtube
into almost entirely and like,
you know, trying to figure out the, the,
the not just not focusing on youtube as
a medium of distribution but in general
focus on increasing the academic rigor
of my content as well to you know,
trying to develop this university.
Yeah.
Focus afterwards is um,
try to get, yeah, like a Netflix
show I think would be ideal.
Let's talk some specifics. Uh, who's the
target audience? The youtube channel.
So it could be a young people who
don't have any programming or a machine
learning experience could be programmers
who just don't have any machine
learning experience.
It could be research sceneries
or as a deep mind open Ai.
So people who are like actively
publishing in Europe and so on.
Who Do you have in mind when
you're making the videos?
So that keeps evolving.
When I started it was like I wanted the
developer market of which there were at
the time, three years ago,
10 million developers. So,
and most of them are
concentrated on get hub, right.
So and now get hub has a 29
million registered accounts.
So it's grown a lot. But at the
time before I started out, you know,
I had a shroom trip to admit that publicly
where I was like crying my eyes out.
I was with some random Tinder date and
I just had this revelation like looking
up at the sky. She was like, I
was like, I've got to do this.
No one else is going to do
this as I've got to do this.
Cause trims kind of give you this
ancient truth. We can talk about that.
I'm read this book by Michael Pollan
on psychedelics. Really Great Book,
author of Omnivore's dilemma.
To get back to this though,
so the goal when I started the youtube
channel was to win the hearts and minds
of developers everywhere. Yeah. And I've
learned a bit of that game at Tulio,
which was my last job because
I was a developer educator.
So I learned that you know how to do this.
So I kind of applied that at scale and
I feel like I did that more or less,
maybe two years in,
I kinda of Sorta to saturate that market.
Obviously I don't have
10 million subscribers,
but I saturated the market of developers
who are also interested in video
content and are also interested in me.
So that, and so that's when I was like,
okay, now I'm not just
developers, but people, um,
develop not just developers who, AI
developers or like programming developers,
but like other types of engineers.
So people generally in stem,
science, technology, engineering,
mathematics. Now I feel like,
and especially having lived in La for
now four months and like kind of seeing
what the scene is like outside
of the Silicon Valley bubble.
It's like people who don't code
at all and don't care. So, but,
but they are interested in technology.
They have some interest in
technology broadly. That's my,
that's what my target audiences, you
know, those are the kind of things,
but listen to podcasts actually,
you know,
it's like there's just curious
about ideas. They don't want to.
So probably no math or no, actually you
know people love number file, right?
Yeah,
and I'm pretty sure a very
large percentage of them
don't understand most of
what's being talked about. Yeah. Like
at a, at a core mathematical level,
but what they're enjoying is the,
the seeming beauty of how
everything just fits together. Yeah.
Being explained and they just enjoy that.
That there is a law structure
to the universe. What does that,
do you have an understanding why
people are into a number of file?
I do have an understanding.
It's not what you would think.
I do have an understanding of very data
driven understanding as a creator who
looks at my analytics and looks
at my audiences demographics.
A lot of people want an
Avatar that looks like them.
A lot of people are like the sound of
a person and how it makes them feel.
It's not even about the
content, it's about, it's about
the intonation, it's about
the medium that they're using.
Like sometimes just having a pen and
paper while not as efficient as say some
online tool. Sometimes just like seeing
that and seeing the market board.
That's enough for them.
So Daniel Shiffman is one example
of a creator who does as well.
A friend of mine, the coding
train on Youtube, great channel.
But other than like those things he does,
he's a really good storyteller or they
are really, really good storytellers.
And that's what it comes down to.
Like grant three blue one brown is a
coherent story from start to finish. No,
no matter how long the content is,
it has a start,
middle and end and people like that that
the sequential aspect of that as you've
all Noah Harari said in his book as
you've probably read, we are storytellers.
We think we imagined we dream,
we remember in stories.
So as long as we can
wrap math into a story,
we can get more people interested in it.
And in terms of like getting to this
audience who doesn't care about code,
I'm never going to stop
talking about math.
Math is the value that I bring to society.
I know that from a data driven approach,
right? As long as math is prevalent.
Cause that's the thing that I
can bring that not everybody,
not every rapper in
whatever can bring math.
I can talk about math and I can make
it cool. So it's going to be math,
like don't work with Dick
Talks about chess, right?
Yeah, exactly. I think it will take
me in chess. Popular. They did.
I'm sure it's a math and AI in technically
I was gonna stick with you for a
while.
Yeah, absolutely.
Absolutely. And to be honest,
I'm feeling disillusioned
with differentiable blocks
as the future and SGD like
stochastic gradient descent as the future
of Ai. But I'm sure a lot of people do.
Yeah. You know, it's, it's amazing.
And obviously it's doing
a much of amazing things,
but it's not the future of Agi. So,
but for now I'm sticking with that.
You're going to have like angry,
frustrated reps about the state
of a neural networks today.
It's almost like a, so like Tupac rapping
about like the problems, you know,
racial problems in society.
You'd be rapping like a Jeff Hinton,
the backpropagation.
Okay.
That'd be sick. That's a great idea. See,
I'm not the only one who's going to be
a ramper about Ai. Exactly. Yeah. Yeah.
Quoting, hinting at the beginning
and then like dropping a beat.
Well, if you need any guitar tracks,
uh, I'd love that lamb down. Okay.
So, uh, how's your process of creating
two videos changed over the years?
What's that process like? I think it's
fascinating for a lot of people who, uh,
who are educators.
I know that a lot of people are
quite terrible and making videos. Uh,
and uh, you're quite good and, and
the, the whole production of it.
So what's that process been like?
What's it converged to and what advice
do you have on how to do it well,
so I no longer do it all myself.
I have a team now. Awesome. Yeah.
I haven't edited her and an animator
who help and so I'll kind of lay out the
idea, the story, the
concepts. I'll write it.
I write every word like I'm never
going to have someone write for me.
To me that's the most disingenuous,
dishonest thing you could do is to have
someone else write the words that you
speak. Not to call anybody
in particular, but,
but so, so I'll, I'll write it, I'll
write the script and then there,
and then I'll also tell them like what
the animation should look like and what
the assets are going to be.
I'll also make the memes, um,
but the editor will kind of stitch things
together and the animator will at the
animations.
How do you,
the editor,
how do you put your vision
into their head and share that?
Is that part of the sacrifice of the
collaboration that you talk about?
Yeah. Yeah. So when I first started,
there were certain little things that I
could do because I was editing them that
and because my turnaround is so fast
as well, that I could just do, um,
and my editor could do that as well.
It's just the turnaround is so fast that,
but he's getting better and we've worked
together for maybe eight months now and
he's reliable and he's getting
better. So, but yeah, like you know,
when it comes to like
take this equation's,
split it up and like take these variables.
Obviously you need some
domain knowledge there.
So you just got to find a really great
editor and turn them into a unicorn
by giving them a domain
knowledge through experience. Uh,
what's it mean to be a unicorn?
A Unicorn isn't a person who's
really good at editing and AI.
Oh, I see. So you're almost
educating them. Yeah. And the, wow.
So you're growing all together. Is
this in person or remote? Remote.
He can do a remote too.
Yeah.
What's the hardest part of the whole
process for you from start to finish?
Is it the idea stage? The
writing. The script is shooting,
like standing in front
of a camera and saying,
do you have to ramp up for it?
We've got to ramp up. You got to turn,
turn my swag on, turn the energy level.
Is that a lot of energy in those videos?
So what, uh, what's that process like?
How many takes you,
you know,
I want you to videos some youtube
recently made me feel a lot better.
Actually, because sometimes I'll do like,
like even for an Intro, like for uh,
for this conversation, I'll do an intro
for like a minute about you. Right, right.
And I'll probably do three takes of it.
Yeah.
And I used to feel bad about that
cause I, I screwed up, you know,
but I saw some youtube would do like
40 takes of like a three minute video,
like some crazy number.
Do you find yourself doing having to do
a lot of takes because you have really
complex material, like give a lot
of different storylines flowing?
Yeah,
I do. I do. I do several
takes for sure. Uh,
it's rare that I can do it all in
one take. Usually like, you know,
maybe somewhere to 30 seconds to two
minutes and I'll mess up and they'll have
to restart from that point.
And Yeah.
Yeah. Just you use a use a teleprompter
or do you use, do you remember?
I use a teleprompter. Yeah. Just getting
into like Stephen King details here.
How do you write out a script?
You just take like a
loose notes or do you go
by word word by word?
So it's kind of an essay.
It's an essay. I'm writing essays
every week, like three essays.
If I were to take all my
scripts that I made up till now,
they would be like five books
worth of Innosight. Yeah. As books.
Do you remember a time when
you took way too long in a video?
Like it was way harder than
you thought you anticipated?
And do you remember what
that video might be?
Huh? Neuro ordinary differential
equations. The nips paper.
The neuro,
sorry.
No rips paper that a cause that
the actual optimization step with the
three integrals, I still didn't know
fully get it. That's a good question.
Actually. When you do a video,
especially some of the trickier
concepts, do you, I mean,
they're difficult to fully get,
even if you teach a course,
even if teach of course,
multiple times on a topic,
you learn something new every
time you find yourself. I mean,
Jewish degree, do you try to fully get a
topic before you're doing a video on it?
How much do I know it when I say it?
I've really gotten better at
this over the years. Like so, um,
I remember like the first year there was
one video. What was deep mines thing?
It was like the DNC, the differential
neural computer. Honestly, I've,
I felt like I knew 50% of that
when I made that video like that.
That was crazy. I don't know if you ever
looked into this architecture. Yeah.
Now I like at least 90,
90% understand it.
Do you uh, have a goal when you add
memes or humor? Keep People's attention?
You know what,
one of the interesting things
you mentioned and maybe
you can dig into a little
bit. You have like a, an analog, like
a data analytics view of this thing.
I do. So like audience retention.
Yeah. So Do, I'm sure you have like a,
almost like a sixth sense now of what
things get an audience to keep their eyes
on, on. Of course you probably always
learning and nobody really knows.
Like how do you mean
no,
what worked and what didn't.
If I retention drops at a certain point,
whatever I said or showed or displayed,
they're not good. If it increased,
that's good. That's good. And you start
to build it up and you can monitor that.
Yeah.
So what kind of things
have you learned? If you
can, if you can simplify
into words, what are people, um,
I mean you already mentioned like certain
ways of talking that people just find
appealing. This is the type of video
where people like whisper into the mic,
I need to look contagious tomorrow. Yes,
I'm on. Great. What the heck is that?
It creeped me out. Gen Z loves
this younger than me. Yeah.
It's just like a relaxing, you know,
it's like one form of this, you know,
different types of love and
affection that we all need.
This is like more of the intimacy.
It fulfills a need,
a very human need of like
being close with someone.
Obviously with Vr we can increase that,
but it's one step of wow, I've never,
so I've looked into it for just like a
few minutes and never as a really nice
explanation of it. That makes so
much sense. The whispering brings us,
it does a feeling of closeness to it
even more so than just listening to the
person directly as powerful. So you get,
so stuff like that, what have you learned?
What people connect and they want
to keep watching relevancy matters.
So you want your jokes should matter.
Your meme should be relevant. Your
you got to stay with the Times
you gotta be in pop culture.
You gotta be watching Pewdie Pie and
bunch of other popular creators and know
where the pulse is in terms of pop
culture and be able to relate AI to it.
And so that's a fulltime job.
How hard is it creating the memes? You
know, it comes, it becomes second nature.
Now that I make them, I used to just
Google them and like find relevant,
like Lstm meme,
find one.
Now I actually write them myself and
so there I have more control. Yeah,
she's better and they're
funnier as well. Yeah, I and I,
and you can't use 2018 memes like memes
or are changing now the Pekichu meme is
in,
but like watch it go out next month.
It's like things I care about
that nobody knows. But like I'm,
I'm really into mammalogy and
like you and Ilan Musk, so you're,
yeah. Yeah. Apparently he's into it.
Have you noticed changes
in the Youtube in um,
in youtube was a medium since he started.
He said,
we get you a month by month.
I mean a lot is changing right
from Manas monetization to uh,
just the number of people that are
producing content to the algorithm behind
youtube.
The have you actually,
because you have your finger to the pulse,
have you noticed substantive
changes they can speak to? Uh,
definitely not enough creator
support. Definitely. I mean,
I could complain about Youtube all day,
so it's mostly complaints is mostly
not been in the positive direction.
He would say no, I love Youtube because
they've given me a platform I could,
I wouldn't be,
you know,
I wouldn't have the influence that I
do be able to reach to many people.
I do as I do without youtube. So I
deeply appreciate youtube. In fact,
I'm going to, I'm a contractor,
like I get youtube ad revenue.
I met in a way I worked for youtube,
so they're great.
However they could be better.
And I've seen that happen to other
creators and everybody has their list of
complaints.
For me specifically,
one that I would say is
like better resources for
educators and they're working
on, and I know, but it could be better.
Are they transparent with the algorithm,
you know? No. Do you think they should be?
Wow. I think they should
be, but it wouldn't.
They couldn't be because it
would break their business model.
They need a new business model
that wasn't entirely ad based. Uh,
so people will start to try
to manipulate it. Exactly.
So somebody who was starting a youtube
channel now with zero subscribers,
you have close to 600,000.
You're trying to do a million by the
end of the year. He has dual. So I know,
you know, I I, I think 800 k's doable.
But by February or March for sure.
March for sure of next year.
1 million. 1 million. Yeah. Do
people know you're aiming for this?
I think some people do. I don't really
try to talk about it too much. I mean,
people love that kind of cause they
love to help that, right? Yeah. It's,
it's cool to have goals
like that. I think, uh,
people love to help you
strive for that kind of thing.
1 million is a really cool number,
especially for an AI channel. So yeah. Uh,
I think I'm one of the
subscribers, so thank you. I'm
a subscriber to you as well.
Awesome. So you, uh,
so what advice would you give to
somebody just starting out today?
Zero zero subscribers or
maybe advice to yourself.
You're starting out then icology, do it.
What kind of content would you create?
What have you learned if you
time traveled to the beginning?
Just try out different types of videos,
like trial,
just to craziest most random ideas,
as many as you can,
and then look at the data and
reiterate with what works,
what a topic in deep learning or AI do
you see is at least in the beginning,
you've connected with beginners a lot.
What,
what topic do they struggle with
the most? Like, what's the thing,
what's the entry point that
people struggle with and
how do you recommend they
overcome it? Well, it
always tends to be the math.
So usually anything having to
do with either linear Algebra,
calculus,
probability theory or statistics,
the four pillars of deep learning,
those are the four.
So how would you,
what would you recommend they
do to overcome? At this point,
there exists free content from many
resources on the web for all of these
things. It doesn't exist together
as a cohesive curriculum,
like basically everything you need.
But it does exist across different
courses on different platforms.
And so what I've done is I've created
like medic curriculums on get hub that I
promote with youtube.
And then they like curriculums consisting
of different courses which other
people have done as well.
And so that's kind of acting as a
pathway for people without a path.
So I can provide path as a service
learning path as a service.
Well, we'll put what a
topic, if you can look back,
was the hardest for you to put together
a video about [inaudible] technically
for you. I mean, you mentioned
you, you mentioned some,
but sort of something that
you get to learn a lot for or maybe you
grew a lot from in doing quantum machine
learning. I hadn't seen that one from
you. Cool. Yeah, I did it with d wave.
That was pretty, uh, interesting.
Started me down the rabbit hole of
quantum mechanics and I still don't
understand it. There's a whole
movement of a, I know that MIT,
this quantum machine learning people, I
still, I don't, I don't know anything.
So I do know about quantum mechanics.
I don't know nothing about quantum
computing or quantum machine hunting.
Certainly don't, is that, is
that something you're excited
about? What's, you know,
quantum computing in general?
Is that something you're
excited about? Absolutely.
Absolutely.
There's,
there's a lot of promising research
happening right now at MIT and other
institutions specifically for speeding
up a matrix matrix multiplications on
quantum resistors. What
you, I guess you would,
you call him cubits. Yep. But, um,
that's really cool
because if we can do that,
I don't even need gps anymore.
But variational auto encoder sends me
very popular with the quantum community.
And simulated annealing, but there
needs to be more problems that are,
it's applied to, but graph problems
basically like in graph theory,
traffic optimization, traffic traffic,
like optimization is one that, you know,
they did with Volkswagen.
So Volkswagen actually paid
them for this and it worked.
But interesting.
So there's actual applications that,
is that a real world applications of this.
See what topic in AI with top,
again,
computing is most exciting to you today.
I really liked the idea of
AI applied to healthcare,
specifically genetic enhancement.
Hmm.
And brain enhancement and thinking
and taking the idea of Alphago,
of thinking in an alien way and combining
that with human intelligence to create
an intelligence that is greater
than the sum of its parts.
What do you mean alien way?
So outside of the capabilities
of the human brain kind of. Yeah.
So like move 37 the move that
shock least Sudo in that it was,
it seemed like a bad move at first, but
it turned out to be a better move. Right.
And so this went against the grain of
2000 plus years of human theory and to go,
you know, what, what, what
moves should be played.
So this was an alien way of
thinking that was not only alien,
it was alien and better. Right? So those
two together is a unique benefit of AI.
So when we combine that, what does
the AI deep, what does the AI,
human deep blue moment,
what does that look like?
And I think it's going to be in
something related to healthcare,
probably drug discovery in the next
five years. If I were to make a bet,
well that that is one of the things
that where you could really transform
society. That's really interesting
that you thinking about that.
Who in deep learning community do you
look up to sort of this researchers is
somebody that maybe early on inspired
you or continues to inspires you?
I know you mentioned Trask um,
a few other really good bloggers,
but is there somebody a,
the stands out besides those folks?
Yes. Oriol Vin Y'alls. Yeah,
at deep mind. He's so cool.
Neural conversational model.
All of this work in sequence.
The sequence modeling and just Alpha
Star and Alpha fall and basically
everything. Cool. I, you mentioned that
the road by Cormac Mccarthy
is one of your favorite books.
It takes place in a post
apocalyptic America. So a,
if human civilization destroys itself,
do you think AI will be part
of that destruction? Yeah,
but not in the way that it's going
to make decisions for itself and uh,
consciously decide that humans need
to be this steroid and then, you know,
do whatever it takes,
it's going to be in the way that a human
or a group of humans decides to exploit
other humans using AI and
they do something nefarious
that involves some kind of
your biochemical attack or propaganda
as an empowering tool for destruction
that humans are doing anyway.
So empowering the evil that is inside
us humans. Yeah. But are you, uh,
you've taught a bunch of topics and
AI, right? Do you have a concern,
existential threats or any kind of
threats of AI in the near term or the long
term? Is this something you think about?
Is that something that concerns you?
Is it does some percent of
the population general public,
at least the those, you know Sam
Harris, even Ilan mosque and so on.
Yeah. I definitely felt when
I first started like that,
the existential threat was
that AI was too concentrated.
The knowledge of AI was too concentrated
and the best way to get a desperate,
as Elon Musk has said and he
quoted Lord Acton on this,
was to ensure that all of that power is
centralized, so spreading the education,
the knowledge of Ai, that data
to the compute, the algorithms.
That has been my goal so far to prevent
that existential threat in terms of
an AI,
consciously deciding human humanity needs
to be wiped out and then being able to
execute that. I don't feel
it's, I just really don't,
I guess you could say his faith. I have
faith that that's not going to happen.
It's going to be, if
it, if it does happen,
it's going to be because of humans and
then we decide to do something. Right.
Yeah. I share your, the
centralized controls, one of the,
we assume as form tribes and those traps
can be destructive in that same way we
need to distribute the
control of Ai Algorithm.
So no one tribe gets to,
uh, is to monopolize it. So,
uh,
what
kind of educator,
artist human being would you like
to grow to be in the next 10 years?
What do you think that
trajectory looks like?
You mentioned focusing on youtube
this year may be something,
who knows what something like
Netflix in the coming years,
but if you look 10 years from now,
what do you see yourself as?
Well, I have some ideas on
that. It's just I'm not,
I don't have the authority,
I'm saying this out loud,
but it's what goes on my head.
I don't yet have the authority to put
that out there into human consciousness,
like a fashion line that uses technology
and learning technologies specifically
to adapt to its user.
A quick a fashion line for engineers by
engineers. Huh? Wow. Yeah, that'd be sick.
Right? So one step at a time here
before I build this media empire.
But it's all about education in the end.
You know,
we're trying to make these
things cool and relevant.
So these are just mediums.
They're all different.
Keys of the piano of there are different
instruments in the orchestra of
education and some of these instruments
haven't been utilized before yet in the
way that they should be.
Like Netflix, like music,
hip hop music specifically and fashion
even can be a tool for education.
Just that relevancy to get
into vogue and you know,
these magazines that puts it into
their head into human consciousness,
but fashion, art, music, fashion,
music after Netflix, fashion line,
uh, maybe an album. And uh,
then I mean obviously like a book as well.
And then just content in
different forms of content,
creating content around storytelling,
around technology
and then maybe even a product.
And if I do a product that's going
to be something related to genetic
enhancement, um, or you know,
maybe some kind of APP for the brain
computer interface that is being developed
by a friend of mine.
Listen, you're one of the most
unique and ambitious people I know,
which is why I wanted to
talk to you today. And, uh,
I think I speak for the
rest of the world that, uh,
except all the haters that, uh, we
can't wait to see what you do next.
Thanks so much for talking
today, man. Thank you Lex.