Today we have Josh Tenenbaum,
he's a professor here at mit leading the
computational cognitive science group
among many other topics and cognition
and intelligence.
He is fascinated with the question of
how human beings learn so much from so
little and how these insights can lead
to build ai systems that are much more
efficient learning from data.
So please give Josh a warm welcome.
Thank you.
All right.
Thank you very much.
Thanks for having me.
Excited to be part of what looks like
really quite a very impressive lineup,
especially starting after today and it's
I think quite a great opportunity to get
to see perspectives on artificial
intelligence from many of the leaders in
industry and other entities working on
this great quest.
So I'm going to talk to you about some
of the work that we do in our group,
but also I'm going to try to give a
broader perspective,
reflective of a number of mit faculty,
especially those who are affiliated with
the center for brains,
minds and machines.
So you can see up there on my
affiliation academically,
I'm part of brain and cognitive science
or course nine.
I'm also part of resale,
but I'm also part of the center for
brains,
minds and machines,
which is an NSF funded center science
and Technology Center,
which really stands for the bridge
between the science and the engineering
of intelligence.
It literally straddles Vassar Street and
that we have see sale and bcs members.
We also have partners at Harvard and
other academic institutions and again,
what we stand for.
I want to try to convey some of the
specific things we're doing in the
center and where we want to go with a
vision that really is about jointly
pursuing the science,
the basic science of how intelligence
arises in the human mind and brain and
also the engineering enterprise of how
to build something increasingly like
human intelligence in machines and we
deeply believe that these two projects
have something to do with each other and
our best pursued jointly.
Now it's a really exciting time to be
doing anything related to intelligence
or certainly to ai for all the reasons
that brought you all here.
I don't have to tell you this.
We have all these ways in which ai is
kind of.
Finally here we finally live in the era
of something like real practical ai or
for those who've been around for awhile
and have seen some of the rises and
falls,
you know,
ai is back in a big way,
but from my perspective,
and I think maybe this reflects why we
distinguish what we might call Agi from
Ai,
we don't really have any real ai.
Basically we have what I like to call ai
technologies,
which are systems that do things we used
to think that only humans could do and
now we have machines that do them often
quite well,
maybe even better than any human who's
ever lived.
Right?
Like a machine that plays go,
but none of these systems I would say
are truly intelligent.
None of them have anything like common
sense.
None of them have anything like the
flexible general purpose intelligence
that each of you might use to learn
every one of these skills or tasks.
Right?
Each of these systems had to be built by
large teams of engineers working
together often for a number of years.
I'd often at great cost to somebody
who's willing to pay for it and each of
them just does one thing.
So alphago might beat the world's best,
but it can't drive to the match or even
tell you that.
Go what go is,
I can't even tell you the go is a game
because it doesn't even know what a game
is.
Right?
So what's missing?
Why?
What is it that makes every one of your
brains,
maybe you can't beat,
you know,
the world's best in go,
but any one of you can get behind the
wheel of a car.
I think of this because my daughter is
going to turn 16 tomorrow if she lived
in California,
she'd have a driver's license.
It's a little bit down the line for us
here in Massachusetts.
But um,
you know,
she didn't have to be specially
engineered by a billion dollar startups
and you know,
she got really into chess recently and
now she's taught herself chest by
playing just a handful of games
basically.
Um,
and she can do any one of these
activities at any one of us can.
So what is it?
What's the,
what makes up the difference?
Well,
there's many things,
right?
Um,
I'll talk about the focus for us and our
research and a lot of us,
again,
in CBMM is summarized here.
Um,
what,
what drives the success is right now in
ai,
especially in industry.
Okay.
And all of these ai technologies is
many,
many things,
but what,
what,
where the progress has been made most
recently and what's getting most of the
attention is of course deep learning,
but other kinds of machine learning
technologies which essentially represent
the maturation of a decades long effort
to solve the problem of pattern
recognition.
That means taking data and finding
patterns in the data that tells you
something you care about,
like how to label a class or how to
predict some other signal.
Okay.
Um,
and pattern recognition is great.
It's an important part of intelligence
and it's reasonable to say that deep
learning as a technology has really made
great strides on pattern recognition and
maybe even,
you know,
has coming close to solving the problems
with pattern recognition.
But intelligence is about many other
things.
Intelligence about a lot more in
particular.
It's about modeling the world and think
about all the activities that a human
does from all over the world that that
go beyond just say,
recognizing patterns in data,
but actually trying to explain and
understand what we see,
for instance,
okay.
Or to be able to imagine things that
we've never seen that never seen,
maybe even very different from anything
we've ever seen,
but we want to see and then two,
to set those as goals to make plans and
solve problems needed to make those
things real or thinking about learning.
Again,
some kinds of learning can be thought of
as pattern recognition if you're
learning sufficient statistics or
weights and a neural net that are used
for those purposes,
but many activities of learning are
about building out new models,
right?
Either refining,
reusing and proving old bottles or
actually building fundamentally new
models as you've experienced more of the
world.
And then think about sharing our models,
communicating our models to others,
modeling their models,
learning from them.
All of these activities of modeling.
These are at the heart of human
intelligence and it requires a much
broader set of tools.
So I want to talk about the ways that
we're studying these activities of
modeling the world and something in a
pretty nontechnical way about what are
the kinds of tools that allow us to
capture these abilities.
Now I think it's.
I want to be very honest upfront and to
say this is just the beginning of a
story,
right?
When you look at deep learning
successes,
that itself is a story that goes back
decades.
I'll say a little bit about that history
in a minute,
but where we are now is just looking
forward to a future when we might be
able to capture these abilities at a
really mature engineering scale and I
would say we are far from being able to
capture the all the ways in which humans
richly flexibly,
quickly build models of the world at the
kind of scale that say silicon valley
wants either big tech companies like
Google or Microsoft or IBM or facebook
or small startups.
Right?
We can get there and I think what I want
to talk to you about here is one route
for trying to get there and this is the
route that CBMM stands for,
the idea that by reverse engineering how
intelligence works in the human mind and
brain that will give us a route to
engineering these abilities in machines.
When we say reverse engineering,
we're talking about science,
but doing science like engineers.
This is our fundamental principle that
if we approach cognitive science and
neuroscience like an engineer,
where so the output of our science isn't
just a description of the brain or the
mind in words,
but in the same terms that an engineer
would use to build an intelligent
system,
then that will be both the basis for a
much more rigorous and deep,
the insightful science,
but also direct translation of those
insights into engineering applications.
Now I said before I talk a little about
history,
um,
what I mean by that is this,
again,
if,
if part of what brought you here as deep
learning,
and I know even if you've never heard of
deep learning before,
which I'm sure is unlikely you saw some,
you know,
a good spectrum of that in the,
in the overview session,
uh,
last night.
Okay.
Um,
it's really interesting and important to
look back on the history of where did
techniques for deep learning come from
or reinforcement learning.
Those are the two tools in the,
in the current machine learning arsenal
that are getting the most attention,
things like backpropagation or end to
end,
stochastic gradient descent or temporal
difference learning or cue learning.
Here's a few papers from the literature.
May,
you know,
maybe some of you have read these
original papers.
Here's,
here's the original paper by Romel
heart,
Hinton and colleagues in which they
introduced the backpropagation algorithm
for training multilayer,
perceptrons,
right?
Multilayer neural networks.
Here's the original perceptron paper by
Rosenblatt,
which introduced the one layer version
of that architecture and the basic
perceptron learning algorithm.
Here's the first paper on sort of the
temporal difference learning method for
reinforcement learning from Sutton and
bartow.
Here's the original bolt machine paper
also by Hinton and colleagues,
which you know again is a,
those who don't know that architecture
can give a kind of probabilistic
undirected multilayer perceptron,
um,
or for example,
before the Lstm is if you know about
current recurrent neural network
architecture earlier,
as much simpler versions of the same
idea were proposed by Jeff Ellman and
his simple recurrent networks.
The reason I want to put up the original
papers here is for you to look at both
when they were published,
where they were published.
So if you look at the dates,
you'll see papers going back to the
eighties,
but even the sixties or even the 19
fifties,
and look at where they were published.
Most of them were published in
psychology journals.
So the journal psychological review,
if you don't know it,
is like the leading journal of
theoretical psychology and mathematical
psychology or cognitive science.
The Journal of the cognitive science
society or the back prop paper was
published in nature,
which is a general interest science
journal.
But by people who are mostly affiliated
with the Institute for Cognitive Science
in San Diego,
so what you see here is already a long
history of scientists thinking like
engineers,
these are people who are in psychology
or cognitive science departments and
publishing in those places,
but by formalizing even very basic
insights about how humans might learn or
how,
you know,
brains might learn in the right kind of
math that led to,
of course,
progress on the science side,
but it led to all the engineering that
we see now.
It wasn't sufficient,
right?
We needed,
we needed,
of course,
lots of innovations and advances in
computing hardware and software systems,
right?
But this is where the basic,
the basic math came from and it came
from doing science like an engineer.
So what I want to talk about and our
vision is what is the future of this
look like?
If we were to look 50 years into the
future,
what would we be looking back on now?
Or you know,
over this timescale.
Well,
here's a,
here's a longterm research roadmap that
reflects some of my ambitions and some
of our centers goals and many others to
right.
We'd like to be able to address basic
questions,
fundamental questions of what it is to
be and to think like a human questions
for example,
of consciousness or meaning and language
or real learning,
right?
Questions like,
um,
you know,
even beyond the individual at questions
of culture or creativity.
Those are our big ideas up there.
And for each of these there are basic
scientific questions,
right?
How do we become aware of the world and
ourselves in.
It starts with perception,
but it really turns into awareness,
awareness of yourself and of the world
and what we might call consciousness,
right?
Or how does a word starts to have a
meaning?
What really is a meaning and how does a
child grasp it or how to children
actually learn what to babies brains
actually start with are they blank
slates or do they start with some kind
of cognitive structure?
And then what is real learning look
like?
These are just some of the questions
that we're interested in working on or
when we talk about culture remain,
how do you learn all the things you
didn't directly experience,
right?
But that somehow you got from the
accumulation of knowledge in society
over many generations or how do you ever
think of new ideas or answers to new
questions?
How do you think of the new questions
themselves?
How do you decide what to think about?
These are all key activities of human
intelligence.
When we talk about how we model the
world,
where our models come from,
what we do with our models.
This is what we're talking about and if
we could get machines that could do
these things well again on the bottom
row,
think of all the actual real engineering
payoffs now in our center and in both my
own activities and a lot of what my
group does these days and what a number
of other colleagues in the center for
brains minds and machines do as well as
an abrupt,
very broadly.
People in pcs and see sale.
One place where we work on the
beginnings of these problems in the near
term,
this is the longterm,
like think 50 years,
maybe,
maybe shorter,
maybe longer,
I don't know,
but think well beyond,
well beyond 10 years,
but in the short term,
five to 10 years,
a lot of our focus is around visual
intelligence and there's many reasons
for that.
Again,
we can build on the successes of deep
networks and a lot of pattern
recognition and machine vision.
It's a good way to put these ideas into
practice.
When we,
when we look at the actual brain,
the visual system in the brain,
in the human and other mammalian brains,
for example,
is really very clearly the best
understood part of the brain and at a
circuit level,
it's the part of the brain that's most
inspired current,
deep learning and neural network
systems.
But even there,
there's things which we still don't
really understand like engineers.
So here's an example of a basic problem
in visual intelligence that we and
others in the center are trying to
solve.
Look around you and you feel like
there's a whole world around you and
there is a whole world around you,
you know,
feel like your brain captures it,
but what the actual sensor data that's
coming in through your eyes,
it looks more like this photograph here
where you can see there's a crowd scene,
but it's mostly blurry except for a
small region of high resolution in the
center,
so that corresponds biologically to what
part of the images in your phobia.
That's the central region of cells in
the retina where you have really high
resolution visual data.
The size of your phobia is roughly like
if you hold out your thumb at arm's
length,
it's a little bit bigger than that,
but not much bigger.
Right?
Most of the image it in terms of the
actual information coming in and a
bottom up sense to your brain is really
quite blurry,
but somehow by looking at just one part
and then by being around or making a few
eye movements,
you get a few glimpses each.
Not much bigger than the size of your
thumb at arm's length.
Somehow you stitch that information
together into what feels like and really
is a rich representation of the whole
world around you.
And when I say around you,
I mean literally around you.
So here's another kind of demonstration.
Without turning around,
nobody's allowed to turn around.
Ask yourself what's behind you.
Now the answer is going to be different
for different people.
Depending on where you're sitting,
right?
For most of you,
you might think,
well,
there's,
I think there's a person pretty close
behind me,
right?
You know you're in a crowded auditorium,
although you haven't seen that person,
you know that they're there,
right?
For people in the very back row,
you know there isn't a person behind you
and you're conscious of being in the
back row,
right?
You might be conscious if there's a wall
right behind you,
but now for the people who are in the
room,
not in the very back,
think about how far behind you is the
back.
Like,
where's the nearest wall behind you so
we can look.
Maybe we can call out a try a little
demonstration.
So I didn't know.
I'm pointing to someone there.
Can you see phrase,
say something if you think I'm pointing
at you?
Uh,
well I could have been pointing at you
but I'm pointing someone behind you.
Okay.
I'll point to you.
Yeah,
I'm pointing to you.
Alright.
So how far is the nearest wall?
But no,
you can't turn around.
You've blown your chance without turning
around.
Okay.
So you,
you were loud.
Okay.
Do you see,
I'm pointing to you there with the tie.
Okay.
So without turning around,
how far is the nearest wall behind you?
That's how far.
Five meters.
Okay.
Well let me,
that might be about right.
No other people can turn around a how
now,
how about you?
How far is the nearest wall behind you?
Ten meters.
Okay.
Um,
that might be right?
Yeah.
How about here?
How,
how,
what do you think?
20.
Okay.
Um,
so yeah,
since I didn't grow up in the metric
system,
I barely know,
but yeah,
I mean,
I mean the point is that like your,
your,
each of you is surely not exactly right,
but you're certainly within an order of
magnitude.
And I guess if we actually tried to
measure,
you know,
you're probably,
my guess is you're probably right
within,
you know,
50 percent or less often,
maybe just 20 percent error.
Okay.
So how do you know this?
I mean,
even if it's not,
what did you say?
Twenty meters.
Even if it's not 20 meters,
it's probably closer to 20 meters than
it is to five or 10 meters.
And then it is to 50 meters.
So how did you know this?
You haven't turned around in a while,
right?
But some part of your brain is tracking
the whole world around you,
right?
Um,
and how many people are behind you?
Yeah,
like a few hundred,
right?
I mean,
I don't know if it's 200 or $300,
but it's not a thousand.
I don't think so.
Um,
and it's certainly not 10 or 20 or 50.
Right?
So you track these things and you use
them to plan your actions.
Okay.
So again,
think about how instantly,
effortlessly and very reliably,
okay,
your brain computes all these things.
So the people and objects around you.
And it's not just,
you know,
approximations certainly when we're
talking about what's,
what's behind you in space,
there's a lot of imprecision,
but when it comes to reaching for things
right in front of you,
very precise shape and physical property
estimates needed to pick up and
manipulate objects.
And then when it comes to people,
it's not just the existence of the
people but something about what's in
their head,
right?
You track whether someone's paying
attention to you and you're talking to
them,
what they might want from you,
what they might be thinking about you,
what they might be thinking about other
people.
Okay?
So when we talk about visual
intelligence,
this is the whole stuff we're talking
about and you can start to see how it
turns into basic questions I think of,
of,
of what we might call the beginnings of
consciousness or at least our awareness
of ourself in the world and of ourselves
as a self in the world,
but also other aspects of higher level
intelligence and cognition that are not
just about perception like symbols,
right?
To describe even to ourselves,
what's around us and where we are.
And what we can do with it,
you have to go beyond just what we would
normally call the stuff that perception
to to say the thoughts in somebody's
head in your own thoughts about that.
Okay.
So what we've been doing in CBMM is
trying to develop an architecture for
visual intelligence and I'm not going to
go into any of the details of how this
works and this is just notional.
This is just a picture.
It's like a just a,
a sketch from a grant proposal of what
we say we want to do,
but it's based on a lot of scientific
understanding of how the brain works.
There are different parts of the brain
that correspond to these different
modules in our architecture as well as
some kind of emerging engineering way to
try to capture at the software and maybe
even hardware levels,
how these modules might work.
So we talk about a sort of an early
module of a visual or perceptual stream,
which is like bottom up visual or other
perceptual input.
That's the kind of thing that is pretty
close to what we currently have and say
deep convolutional neural networks.
But then we talk about some kind of the
output of that isn't just pattern class
labels,
but what we call the cognitive core core
cognition.
So we get an understanding of space and
objects,
their physics,
other people,
their minds.
That's the real stuff of cognition.
That has to be the output of perception.
But somehow we have to,
we have,
we have to have,
this is what we call the brain ostp in
this picture.
We have to get there by stitching
together the bottom up inputs from a
glimpse here,
a glimpse here,
a little bit here and there,
and accessing prior knowledge that comes
from our memory systems to tell us how
to stitch these things together into the
really core cognitive representations of
what's out there in the world.
And then if we're going to start to talk
about it in language or to build plans
on top of what we have seen and
understood,
that's where we talk about symbols
coming into the picture.
Okay.
The building blocks of language and
plans and so on.
Okay.
Um,
so now we might say,
well,
okay,
this is an architecture that is brain
inspired and cognitively inspired and,
and we're planning to turn into real
engineering and you can say,
well,
do we need that?
Maybe,
you know,
again,
I know this is a question you consider
it in the first lecture,
maybe the engineering tool kit that's
currently been making a lot of progress
in let's say industry.
Maybe that's good enough.
Maybe you know,
let's take deep learning,
but to stand for a broader set of modern
pattern recognition based on
reinforcement learning based tools and
say,
okay,
well maybe,
uh,
that can scale up to this and you might,
you know,
maybe that's possible.
I'm happy in the question period of
people want to debate this.
My sense is no.
Um,
I think that,
um,
it's not a.
When I say no,
I don't mean like it,
it can't happen or it won't happen.
What I mean is the highest value,
the highest expected route right now is
to take this more science based reverse
engineering approach.
And that if at least if you follow the
current trajectory that industry
incentives especially optimize for,
it's not even really trying to take us
to these things.
So think about,
for example,
a case study of visual intelligence that
is in some ways as pattern recognition,
very much of a success.
It's again been mostly driven by
industry.
It's something that if you read in the
news or even play around with in certain
publicly available data sets,
feels like we've made great progress.
And this is an aspect of visual
intelligence,
which is sometimes called image
captioning.
It's bay or mapping images to text.
Um,
you know,
basically there's been a bunch of
systems.
Here's a couple of press releases.
I guess this one's about Google.
Google's Ai can now capture images
almost as well as humans.
Um,
here's ones about Microsoft.
a couple of years ago I think there were
something like eight papers all released
on to archive around the same time from
basically all the major industry
computer vision groups as well as a
couple of academic partners.
Okay.
Which all driven by basically the same
dataset produced by some Microsoft
researchers.
And other collaborators,
I'm trained a combination of deep
convolutional neural networks,
you know,
state of the art,
visual pattern recognition with
recurrent neural networks,
which had recently been developed for,
you know,
basically kinds of neural statistical
language modeling,
glued them together and produce the
system which,
which,
which made very impressive results in a
big training set and a held out test set
where the goal was to take an image and
write a sentence like short sentence
caption that that would seem like the
kind of way a human would describe that
image.
And these systems have surpassed human
level accuracy on the held out test set
from a big training center.
But what you can see when you really dig
into these things is there's often a lot
of what I would call Dataset
overfitting.
It's not overfitting to the trainings,
but it's overfitting to whatever are the
particular characteristics of this data
set.
You know,
wherever or wherever it came from.
Certain set of photographs in certain
ways of captioning them.
Okay.
Which even a big Dataset,
um,
it's not about quantity.
It's more about the quality of the
nature of what people are doing.
All right.
Um,
so one way to test this system is to
apply it to what seems like basically
the same problem but not within the,
a certain curated or built dataset.
And there's a convenient a twitter bot
that lets you do this.
So there's something called the pick
desk bought,
which takes one of the state of the art
industry.
Ai captioning systems.
A very good one.
Again,
this is not meant to.
I'm not trying to critique these systems
for what they're trying to do.
I'm just trying to point out what they
don't really even try to do.
So this takes the Microsoft caption
bought and just every couple of hours
takes a random image from the web,
captions it and uploads the results to
twitter.
And a couple of months ago when I
prepared a first version of this talk,
I just took a few days in the life of
this twitter Bot.
I didn't take every single image,
but I took,
you know,
most of the images in a way that was
meant to be representative of the
successes.
And the kinds of failures that such a
system will make so we can go through
this and it's a little bit entertaining
and I think quite informative.
So here's just a somewhat random sample
of a few days in the life of one of
these caption bots.
So here we have a picture of a person
holding.
Fortunately my screen is very small here
and I can't read up there,
so maybe you'll have to tell me what
sets,
but a person holding a cell phone.
I guess I'll just read along with you.
So you have a person holding a cell
phone.
Well,
it's not a person holding a cell phone,
but it's kind of close.
It's a person holding some kind of
machine to.
I don't even know what that is,
but it's some kind of musical
instrument,
right?
Um,
so that's a mixed success or failure.
Here's a pretty good one.
A group of people on a,
on a field playing football.
That's,
I would call that a,
you know,
a result,
maybe even a plus.
Um,
here's a group of people standing on top
of a mountain.
So less good there was a mountain,
but as far as I can tell there's no
people,
but these systems like to see people
because of both the combination because
in the data set they were trained on,
there's a lot of people and people often
talk about people.
Okay.
And the fact that you can appreciate
both what I said and why it's funny.
That's there.
You did some of my cognitive activities
that the system is not even trying to
do.
Okay.
Here we've got a building with a cake.
I'll go through these fast building with
a cake,
a large stone building with the clock
tower.
I think that's pretty good.
I'd give that like a b plus.
There's no clock,
but it's plausibly right.
There might be a clock in there.
There's definitely something like that.
Here's a truck parked on the side of a
building.
I don't know,
maybe a b minus.
There is a car on the side of a
building,
but it's not a truck and it's.
And it's not.
Doesn't seem like the main thing and the
image.
Okay.
Here's a necklace made of bananas.
Here's a large ship in the water.
This is pretty good.
I give this like an a minus or b plus
because there is a ship in the water,
but it's not very large.
It's really more of like a tug boat or
something.
Here's a sign sitting on the grass,
you know,
in some sense that's great.
No,
but,
but in another sense,
it's really missing what's actually
interesting and important and meaningful
to humans.
Um,
here's a,
uh,
here's a garden is in the dirt,
a pizza sitting on top of a building,
a small house with a red brick building.
That's pretty good.
Although it kind of weird way of saying
it.
A vintage photo of a pond.
That's good.
They liked vintage photos.
A group of people that are standing in
the grass near bridge.
Again,
there's two people and there's some
grass and there was a bridge,
but it's really not what's going on.
A person in the yard.
Okay.
Kind of,
um,
a group of people standing on top of the
boat.
There's a boat,
there's a group of people there
standing.
But again,
it's the sentence that you see is,
is more based on a bias of what people
have said in the past about images that
are only vaguely like this.
A clock tower lit up at night.
That's really,
I think,
pretty impressive.
A large clock mounted to the side of a
building a little bit less.
So a snow covered feel very good.
A building with snow on the ground.
A little bit less good.
There's no snow white.
Some people who I don't know them,
but I bet that's probably right because
face identifying faces and recognizing
people who are famous because they won
medals in the Olympics.
Probably I would trust current pattern
recognition systems to get that.
A painting of a vase in front of a
mirror.
I'm less good.
Also a famous person there,
but we didn't get him a person walking
in the rain.
Again,
there is sort of a person and there's
some puddles but not,
you know,
a group of stuffed animals.
A car parked in a parking lot that's
good.
A car parked in front of a building.
Less good.
A plate with a fork and knife.
A clear blue sky.
Okay,
so you get the idea again,
like if you actually go and play with
the system,
partly because I think Mike,
but my friends at Microsoft told me
they've improved it.
Some,
you know,
uh,
this is partly for entertainment value
is,
you know,
I chose what also would be the fun here
example.
So I'm clear,
I want to be quite honest about this and
these are.
I'm not trying to take away what are
impressive ai technologies,
but I think it's clear that there's a
sense of understanding any one of these
images that it's important to see that
even when it seems to be correct,
right?
If it can make the kind of errors that
it makes,
that even when it seems to be correct,
it's probably not doing what you're
doing and it's probably not even trying
to seel towards the dimensions of
intelligence that we think about when
we're talking about human intelligence.
Okay.
Another way to put this,
I'm going to show you a really
insightful blog post from one of your
other speakers.
So,
uh,
in a couple of days,
I'm not sure you're going to have Andre
carpathy who's one of the leading people
in deep learning.
This is a really great blog post.
He wrote a couple of years ago when he
was,
I think still at Stanford.
He got his phd from Stanford.
He did.
He worked at Google a little bit on some
early big neural net ai projects there.
Uh,
he was at open Ai.
He was one of the founders of open ai
and recently he joined Tesla as their
director of Ai Research.
But about five years ago he was looking
at the state of computer vision from a
human intelligence point of view and,
and lamenting how far away we were.
Okay.
So this is the title of his blog posts,
the state of computer vision and ai and
ai.
We are really,
really far away.
And he took this image which was a sort
of a famous image in its own right.
It was a popular image of Obama back
when he was president,
kind of playing around us.
He liked to do when he was on tour.
So if you take a look at this,
you can see you probably all can
recognize the previous president of the
United States,
but you can also get the sense of where
he is and what's going on and you might
see people smiling and you might get the
sense that he's playing a joke on
someone.
Can you see that?
Right?
So how do you know that he's playing a
joke and what that joke is?
Well,
as Andre goes on to talk about and his
blog posts to,
if you think about all the things that,
that you have to really deploy in your
mind to understand that it's a huge
list.
Of course it starts with seeing people
and objects and maybe doing some face
recognition,
but you have to do things like,
for example,
notice his foot on the scale and
understand enough about how scales work
that when a foot presses down,
it exerts forest at the scale of
sensitive,
doesn't just magically measure people's
weight.
But it does that somehow through force.
You have to see who can see that he's
doing that and who can't,
who cannot see that he's doing that
right.
And particularly the person on the scale
and why some people can see that he's
doing that and can see that some other
people can't see it,
why that makes it funny to them.
Okay.
And someday we shouldn't have machines
that can understand this,
but hopefully you can see why,
what I,
what,
what the kind of architecture that I'm
talking about would be the building
blocks of the ingredients to be able to
get them to do that.
Now I,
when I,
again,
I,
I prepared a version of this talk a few
months ago and I wrote to Andre and I
said I was going to use this and I was
curious if he,
what if he had any reflections on this
and where he thought we were relative to
five years ago because certainly a lot
of progress has been made,
but he said,
here's this email.
Um,
I hope he doesn't mind me sharing it,
but I mean,
again,
he's a very honest person and that's one
of the many reasons why he's such an
important person right now in ai.
Okay.
He's both very technically strong and
honest about what we can do,
but we can't do.
And as he says,
but what does he say?
It's nice to hear from you.
Uh,
it's funny you should bring this up.
I was also thinking about writing a,
a return to this and in short,
basically I don't believe we've made
very much progress,
right?
He points out that in his long list of
things that you need to understand the
image we have made progress on some the
ability to again,
the tech people and do face recognition
for well known individuals.
Okay.
Um,
but that's kind of about it all right.
and he wasn't particularly optimistic
that the current route that's being
pursued and industry is,
is anywhere close to solving or even
really trying to solve these larger
questions.
Um,
if we give this image to that a
captioned bought,
you know,
what we see is again,
represents the same point.
So here's the caption,
but it says,
I think it's a group of people standing
next to a man in a suit and tie,
right?
So that's right,
right.
As far as it goes,
it's just doesn't go far enough.
And the current,
the current ideas of build a Dataset,
train a deep learning algorithm on it
and then repeat,
um,
aren't really even,
I would venture trying to get to what
we're talking about or here's another.
I'll just give you one other example of
a couple of photographs from my recent
vacation.
I'm in a nice warm,
tropical local,
um,
which I think illustrate ways in which,
again,
the gap where we have machines that can
say beat the world's best at go but
can't even beat a child.
A tic TAC toe.
Now what do I mean by that?
Well,
you know,
of course we can build,
we don't even need reinforcement
learning or deep learning to build a
machine that can win or tie do as do
optimally in tic TAC toe.
But think about this.
This is a real tic TAC toe game,
which I saw on the grass outside my
hotel,
right?
Um,
what do you have to do to look at this
and recognize that it's a tic Tac toe
game.
You have to see the objects that you
have to see what's,
you know,
in some sense there's a three by three
grid,
but it's,
but it's only abstract,
right?
It's only limited by this.
These ropes are strings.
Okay?
It's not actually a grid in any simple
geometric sense.
Alright?
But yet a child can look at that and
indeed here's an actual child who was
looking at it and recognize,
oh,
it's a game of tic Tac toe and even know
what they need to do to win,
namely put the x and completed and now
they've got three in a row,
right?
That's literally childsplay.
Okay.
Um,
you show this sort of thing though to
one of these,
you know,
image understanding captioned bots,
and I think it's a closeup of a sign.
Okay?
Um,
again,
it's not saying that this is a closeup
of a sign,
is,
is not the same thing.
I would venture as a,
as a cognitive or computational activity
that's going to give us what we need to
say.
Recognize the objects to recognize it as
a game to understand the goal and how to
plan to achieve those goals.
Whereas this kind of architecture is
designed to try to do all of these
things ultimately.
Right?
And I bring in these examples of games
or jokes to really show where perception
goes to cognition,
you know,
that,
uh,
at all the way up to symbols,
right?
So to get objects and forces and mental
states,
that's the cognitive core,
but to be able to get goals and plans
and what do I do or how do I talk about
it?
That's symbols.
Okay,
here's another way into this.
And it's one that also motivates,
I think a lot of really good work on the
engineering side and a lot of our
interest in the science side is think
about robotics and think about what do
you have to do to,
you know,
what,
what does the brain have to be light to
control the body?
So again,
you're gonna hear from certainly,
I think maybe it's next week from Mark
Robert,
who's a one of the founders of Boston
dynamics,
which is one of my favorite companies
anywhere there,
uh,
without doubt the leading maker of
humanoid robots,
legged locomoting robots and industry.
They have also all sorts of other really
cool robots,
robots like dogs,
robots that have,
you know,
you'll,
I think you'll even get to see live
demonstration of one of his robots.
This really awesome,
impressive stuff.
But what about the minds and brains of
these robots will,
again,
if you ask mark,
ask them how much of of human light
cognition do they have in their robots?
And I think he would say very little.
In fact,
we have asked him that and he would say
very little,
very little.
He's,
he's actually one of the advisors of our
center.
And I think in many ways we're very much
on the same page.
We both want to know how do you build
the kind of intelligence that can
control these bodies.
I'm like the way a human does.
All right.
Um,
here's another example of an industry
robotics effort.
This is Google's arm farm where you
know,
they've,
they've got lots of robot arms and
they're trying to train them to pick up
objects using various kinds of deep
learning and reinforcement learning
techniques.
And I think it's one approach.
I just think it's very,
very different from the way humans learn
to say,
control their body and manipulate
objects and you can see that in terms of
things that go back to what you were
saying when you were introducing me,
right?
Think about how quickly we learn the
things right here.
You have these arm farm is trying to
generate,
you know,
effectively maybe if not infinite,
but hundreds of thousands,
millions of examples of reaches and
pickups of objects even with just a
single gripper and yet a child who in
some ways can't control their body
nearly as well as robots can be
controlled at the low level,
is able to do so much more.
So I'll show you two of my favorite
videos from youtube here,
which motivates some of the research
that we're doing.
The one on the left is a one and a half
year old and the other one's a one year
old.
So just watch this one and a half year
old here doing a popular activity for
many kids as a playing a video up there.
Okay,
there we go.
Okay.
So He's,
he's on doing this stacking cup
activity.
Alright.
He's stacking up cups to make a tall
tower.
He's got a stack of three.
And what you can see for the first part
of this video is it looks like he's
trying to make a second stack at that
he's trying to pick up at once.
Basically he's trying to make a stack of
two that'll go on the stack of three and
you know,
he's,
he's trying to debug his plan because
it's,
it got a little bit stuck here.
Um,
but,
and,
and think about,
I mean,
again,
if you know anything about robots,
manipulating objects,
even just what he did,
no robot can,
can decide to do that and actually do it
right at some point he's almost got it.
It's a little bit tricky,
but some point he's going to get that
stack of two.
He realizes he has to move that opted
out of the way,
look at what he did,
move out of the way,
use two hands to pick it up.
And now he's got a stack of two on a
stack of three and suddenly,
you know,
sub goal completed.
He's now got a stack of five and he,
he gives himself a hand because he know,
he knows he accomplished a key way point
along the way to his final goal.
That's a kind of early symbolic
cognition,
right?
To understand that I'm trying to build a
tall tower,
but the tower is made up of little
towers.
It's,
you know,
and,
and you can take a tower and put it on
top of another tower or a stack,
a stack on a stack and you have a bigger
stack,
right?
So think about how he goes from bottom
up perception to the objects of the
physical needed to manipulate the
objects.
So the ability to make those early kinds
of symbolic plans.
At some point he keeps doing this.
He puts another stack on there.
I'll just jump to the end.
Oops,
sorry.
You missed it.
Sorry.
Keep.
He gets really excited and he gives
himself another big hand,
but falls over again.
Um,
Boston dynamics now has robots that
could pick themselves up after that.
That's really impressive again.
Um,
but all the other stuff to get to that
point,
we don't really know how to do in a
robotic setting or thinking about this
baby here.
This is a younger baby.
This is one of the Internet's most
popular videos because it features a
baby and a cap and,
but the baby's doing something
interesting.
He's got the same cups,
but he's decided he's again,
decided to try a new thing.
So this is thinking about creativity.
He's decided that his goal is to stack
up cups on the back of a cat.
I guess he's asking how many cups going
to fit on the back of a cat?
Well,
three.
Let's see.
Can I fit more?
Let's try another one.
Okay.
Um,
while he can't fit more than three,
it turns out.
And then he then does.
It's not working,
so he changes his goal.
Now his goal appears to be to get the
cuffs on the other side of the cat.
Now watch that part when he reaches back
behind him there.
That's.
I'll just pause it there for a moment.
Um,
so many just reached back there.
That's a particularly striking moment in
the video.
It shows a very strong form of what we
call in cognitive science.
Object permanence.
Okay.
That's the idea that you represent
objects as these permanent enduring
entities in the world.
Even when you can't see them in this
case.
He hadn't seen or touched that optic
behind him for like at least a minute,
right?
Maybe much longer.
I don't know.
And yet he still knew it was there and
he was able to incorporate it in this
plan.
Right.
There's a moment before that when he's
about to reach for it,
but then he sees this other one.
Right.
And it's only when he's now exhausted
all the other objects here that he can
see.
He's like,
okay,
now time to get this audit and bring it
into play.
Right?
So think about what has to be going on
in his brain for him to be able to do
that.
Right?
That's like the analog of you
understanding what's behind you.
Okay.
It's not that these things are
impossible to capture machines far from
it.
It's just that like training a deep
neural network or any kind of pattern
recognition system we don't think is
going to do it,
but we think by reverse engineering how
it works in the brain,
we might be able to do it because we can
do it.
Okay.
It's not just humans that do this kind
of activity.
Here's a couple of,
again,
fit rather famous videos.
You can watch all of these on youtube.
Crows are famous objects,
manipulators and tool users,
but also orangutans,
other primates,
rodents.
We can watch if we just had.
Let me pause this one for a second.
If we watched this orangutan here,
he's got a bunch of big legos and over
the course of this video he's building
up a stack.
Legos.
It's really quite impressive.
Just jumping to the end.
There's actually some controversy out
there of what this video is a fake.
Um,
but the controversy isn't about,
it's not like whether it was,
I dunno,
done with computer animation,
some people think the video was actually
filmed backwards,
that a human built up the stack and the
orangutan just slowly disassembled it
piece by piece and it turns out it's
remarkably hard to tell whether it's
played forward or backwards in time and
people have argued over a little details
because you know,
it will be quite impressive if an
orangutan actually was able to build up
this really impressive stack of Legos.
But I would submit that it would be
almost as impressive if he disassembled
it.
Think about the activity.
I mean,
if I want it to disassemble that,
the easiest thing to do would just be to
knock it over.
That's really all most robots could do.
But to piece by piece,
disassemble it even if it's played
backwards like this.
That's still a really impressive act of
symbolic planning on physical objects.
Or here you've got this,
this famous mouse,
this you can find on the internet under
the mouse versus cracker video.
And what you'll see here over the course
of this video is a mouse valiantly and
mostly hopelessly struggling with a
cracker that they're hoping to bring
back to their nest.
I guess it's a very appealing big meal.
Um,
and at some point after just trying to
get it over the,
over the wall,
at some point the mouse just gives up
because it's just never going to happen
and he just goes away except that
because even mouses can dream or my
dream some point he decides,
okay,
I'm just going to come back for one
more.
Try and he tries one more time and this
time validly gets it over.
Yeah.
Isn't that very impressive?
Congratulations about.
Okay.
You don't have to clap.
You can clap for me at the end or clap
for whoever it later.
Okay.
But I will,
I want to applaud the mouse there every
time I see that.
Okay.
But again,
think what had to be going on in his
brain to be able to do that.
All right.
Um,
it's a crazy thing and yet he formulated
the goal and was able to achieve it.
I'll just show one more video that is
really more about science.
These other ones or you know,
some of them actually were from
scientific experiments,
but this is one that motivates a lot of
the science that I do and it's to me it
sets up kind of a grand cognitive
science challenge for ai and robotics.
It's from an experiment with humans,
again,
18 month old or one and a half year old,
so the kids in this experiment,
we're the same age as the first baby I
showed you.
The one who did the stacking and 18
months is really a very,
very good age to study.
If you're interested in intelligence for
reasons we can talk about later if
you're interested.
This is from a very famous experiment
done by two psychologists,
Felix Worn Akin and Michael Thomas
Cielo,
and it was studying the spontaneous
helping behavior of young children.
It also contrasted humans and chimps and
the punchline is that chimps sometimes
do things that are kind of like with
this human did,
but not nearly as reliably or as
flexibly.
Okay,
so not nearly as an.
I'll show you a particular kind of
unusual situation where human kids had
relatively little trouble figuring out
what to do or even whether they should
do it,
whereas basically no chimp did what
you're going to see humans sometimes
doing here.
So the experimenter in this movie.
I'll turn on the sound here if you can
hear it.
The experimenter is the tall guy and the
participant is the little kid in the
corner.
The sound but no words,
right?
And at some point he stops and then the
kid just does whatever they want to do.
So watch what he does.
He goes over,
he opens the cabinet,
looks inside,
then he steps back and he looks up at
Felix and then looks down,
okay,
and then the action is completed.
Now what I want you to watch it one more
time and think about what's going to be
going inside the kid's head to
understand this,
to understand like.
So it seems like what it looks like to
us is the kid figured out that this guy
needed help and helped him.
And the paper is full of many other
situations like this.
This is just one.
Okay.
But the key idea is that the situation
is somewhat novel.
People have seen people holding books
and opening cabinets,
but probably it's been,
it's very rare to see this kind of
situation.
Exactly right.
It's,
it's different in some important details
from what you might have seen before.
And there's other ones in there that are
really truly novel because they just
made up a machine right there.
Okay.
Um,
but somehow he has to understand
causally from the way the guys banging
the books against the thing that it's,
it's,
it's sort of both a symbol,
but it's also somehow he's got to
understand what he can do and what he
can't do and then what the kid can do to
help.
And I'll,
I'll show this again,
but really just watch.
The main part I want you to see is,
um,
I'll just sort of skip ahead.
So watch this part here.
Let's say I'll just jump right when he
watched.
Right now he's about to look up.
He looks up and makes eye contact and
then his eyes look down.
So again,
he looks up,
and then a Sakata sudden rapid eye
movement down down to his hands up,
down.
Okay?
So that's again,
that's this brain,
ostp and action,
right?
He's making one glance,
small glance at the big guys,
eyes to to make eye contact,
to see,
to get a signal.
Did I understand what you wanted and did
you.
Did you register that joint attention
and then he makes a prediction about
what the guy's going to do.
So he looks right down.
He doesn't just like look around
randomly.
He looks right down to the guys hands to
track the action that he expects to see
happening.
If I did the right thing to help you,
then I expect you're going to put the
books there.
Okay?
So you can see these things happening
and we want to know what's going on
inside the mind that guides all of that.
All right?
So that's the sort of big scientific
agenda that we're working on over the
next few years where we think some kind
of human understanding of human
intelligence and scientific terms could
lead to all sorts of ai payoffs in
particular.
I suppose we could build a robot that
could do what this kid and many other
kids in these experiments do just say,
help you out around the house without
having to be programmed or even really
instructed just to kind of get a sense,
oh yeah,
yeah,
you need to have with that shirt.
Let me help you out.
Okay.
Even 18 month olds will do that.
Sometimes not very reliably or
effectively.
Sometimes they'll try to help and really
do the opposite.
Right?
But imagine if you could take the
flexible understanding of humans,
actions,
goals and so on,
and make those reliable engineering
technology that would be very useful.
And it would also be related to say
machines that you could actually start
to talk to and trust in some ways.
Right?
That shared understanding.
So how are we going to do this?
Well,
let me spend the rest of the time
talking about how we tried to do this,
right,
some of the,
some of the technology that we're
building both in our group and more
broadly to try to make these kinds of
architectures real.
And I'll talk about two or three
technical ideas,
again,
not in any detail.
Alright.
Um,
one is the idea of a probabilistic
program.
So this is a kind of,
um,
think of it as a computational
abstraction that we can use to capture
the common sense knowledge of this core
cognition.
So when I say we have an intuitive
understanding of physical objects and
people's goals,
how do I build a model of that model you
have in the head probabilistic programs
a little bit more technically are one
way to understand them is as a
generalization of Bayesian networks or
other kinds of directed graphical
models.
If you know those.
Okay.
But we're,
instead of defining a probability model
on a graph,
you defined it on a program and thereby
have access to a much more expressive
toolkit of knowledge representation.
So data structures,
other kinds of algorithmic tools for
representing knowledge.
Okay.
But you still have access to the ability
to do probabilistic inference,
like in a graphical model,
but also causal inference in a directed
graphical model.
So for those of you who know about
graphical models,
that might make some sense to you,
but just more broadly what this is,
think of this as,
as a toolkit that allows us to combine
several of the best ideas,
not just of the recent deep learning
era,
but over if you look back over the whole
scope of ai and as well as cognitive
science.
I think there's three or four ideas and
more but definitely like three ideas we
could really put up there that have
proven their worth and have had that
have risen and fallen in terms of each
of these had ideas when the mainstream
of the field thought this was totally
the way to go and every other idea was
was obviously a waste of time and also
had its time when many people thought it
was a waste of time.
Okay.
And these three big ideas,
I would say our.
First of all,
the idea of symbolic representation or
symbolic languages for knowledge
representation,
probabilistic inference in generative
models to capture uncertainty,
ambiguity,
learning from sparse data and in their
hierarchical setting,
learning to learn,
right?
And then of course the recent
developments with neuro inspired
architectures for pattern recognition.
Okay?
Each of these things,
each of these ideas,
symbolic languages,
probabilistic inference and neural
networks have some distinctive strengths
that are real weak points of the other
approaches,
right?
So to take one example that I haven't
really talked about here,
um,
people in the butt but you,
but you mentioned as an outstanding
challenge for neural networks,
transfer learning or learning to take
knowledge across a number of previous
tasks to transfer to others.
This is a real challenge and has always
been a challenge in a neural net.
Okay.
But if something that's addressed very
naturally and very scalably in,
for example,
a hierarchical basie and model,
and if you look at some of the recent
attempts,
really interesting attempts within the
deep learning world to try to get kinds
of transfer learning and learning to
learn,
they're really cool.
Okay.
But many of them are in some ways kind
of reinventing within a neural network
paradigm ideas that people,
you know,
maybe just 10 or 15 years ago,
developed in very sophisticated ways in
let's say hierarchical Bayesian models.
Okay.
And a lot of attempts to get sort of
symbolic an algorithm like behavior in
neural networks are really,
they're very small steps towards
something which is a very mature
technology in computer systems and
programming languages,
probabilistic programs,
I'll just sort of advertise mostly are a
way to combine the strengths of all of
these approaches to have knowledge
representations which are as expressive
as anything that anybody ever did in the
symbolic paradigm that are as flexible
at dealing with uncertainty and sparse
data as anything in the probabilistic
paradigm.
But that also can support pattern
recognition tools to be able to,
for example,
do very fast,
efficient inference in very complex
scenarios.
And there's a number of,
probably that's the,
that's the kind of conceptual framework.
There's a number of actually implemented
tools.
Um,
I point to here on the slide a number of
public programming languages which you
can go explore.
Um,
for example,
there's one that was developed in our
group a few years ago,
almost 10 years ago now called church,
which was the antecedent of some of
these other languages built on a
functional programming course.
A church is a problematic programming
language built on the lambda calculous
or really enlist basically,
um,
but there are many other more modern
tools,
especially if you are interested in
neural networks.
There are tools like,
for example,
pyro or prob torch or base flow that try
to combine all these ideas in a or,
or for example,
jen here,
which is a project of the Kauffman
singles problems,
the computing group.
Um,
these are all things which are just in
the very beginning stages,
very,
very alpha.
You can find out more about them online
or by writing to their creators.
And I think this is a,
this is a very exciting place where the
convergence of a number of different ai
tools are happening and when,
and this will be absolutely necessary
for making the kind of architecture that
I'm talking about work.
Another key idea which we've been
building on in our lab.
Um,
and I think again,
many people are using some version of
this idea,
but maybe a little bit different from
the way we're doing it is what will the
version of this idea that I like to talk
about is what I call the game engine in
the head.
So this is the idea that it's really
what the programs are about.
When I talk about problems with
programs,
I haven't said anything about what kind
of programs we're using.
We're just basically these programming
languages at their best and church.
The language that was developed by Noah
Goodman and mccosh and others and Dan
Roy in our group some 10 years ago was
intended to be a turing complete
probabilistic programming language.
So any probability model that was
computable or for who's inferences
conditional inferences are computable.
You could represent in these languages,
but that leaves completely open.
What,
what I'm actually going to,
what kind of protocol I'm going to write
to model the world.
And I've been very inspired in the last
few years by thinking about the kinds of
programs that are in modern video game
engines.
So again,
I'm probably,
most of you are familiar with these,
but if you're an increasingly they are
playing a role in all sorts of ways in
ai,
but these are tools that were developed
by the video game industry to allow a
game designer to make a new game with,
without having to do most of,
in some sense many it must have the hard
technical work by from scratch,
but rather to focus on the characters,
the world,
the story,
okay.
The things that are more interesting
for,
for designing a novel game in
particular,
we,
if we want the player to explore some
new three dimensional world,
but to have them be able to interact
with the world in real time and to
render nice looking graphics in,
in real time,
in an interactive way as the player
moves around and explores the world or
if you want to populate the world with
non player characters that will behave
in a even vaguely intelligent way.
Okay.
Game engines give you tools for doing
all of this without having to write all
of graphics from scratch or all of
physics.
The rules of physics from scratch.
Um,
so what are called game physics engines
and in some sense are a set of
principles but also hacks from newtonian
mechanics and other areas of physics
that allow you to simulate plausible
looking physical interactions in very
complex world,
very approximately,
but very fast.
There's also what's called [inaudible],
which are basically very simple planning
models.
So let's say I want to have an ai in the
game that is like a guard that gardens
have base and a player is going to
attack the space.
So back in the old Atari days,
like when I was a kid,
you know,
the guards would just be like random
things that would fire missiles kind of
randomly in random directions at random
times,
right?
But let's say you want a garden to be a
little intelligent,
so to actually look around and Oh,
and I see the player and then to
actually start shooting at you and to
even maybe pursue you.
So that requires putting a little ai in
the game.
And you do that by having basically
simple agent models in the game.
So what we think,
and some of you might think this is
crazy and some of you might think this
is very natural idea,
I get both kinds of reactions.
What we think is that these tools have,
you know,
fast,
approximate renderers physics engines
and sort of very simple kinds of ai
planning are an interesting first
approximation to the kinds of common
sense knowledge representations that
evolution has built into our brains.
So when we talk about the cognitive core
or how do babies start,
what's,
you know,
ways in which a baby's brain isn't a
blank slate.
One interesting idea is that it starts
with something like these tools and then
wrapped inside a framework for
probabilistic inference.
That's what we mean by promising
programs that can support many
activities of common sense perception
and thinking.
So I'll just give you one example,
what we call this intuitive physics
engine.
Okay.
So this is work that we did in our
groups that Pete,
Natalia,
and Jess Hamrick did started this work
about five years ago now where we showed
people in some sense this is also an
illustration of a kind of experiment
that you might do.
I keep talking about science,
like I'll show you now a couple of
experiments,
right?
So we would show people simple physical
scenes like these blocks worlds scenes,
and asked them to make a number of
judgments.
And the model we built does it basically
a little bit of probabilistic inference
in a game style physics engine.
It perceives the physical state and
imagines a few different possible ways
the world could go over the next one or
two seconds to answer questions like
will the stack of blocks fall?
Or if they fall,
how far will they fall?
Or which way will they fall?
Or what would happen if say one of the
colored one color of blocks or one
material like the green stuff is 10
times heavier than the gray stuff or
vice versa.
How will that change the direction of
fall or look at those red and yellow
stack blocks,
some of which look like they should be
falling but aren't.
So why can you infer from the fact that
they are not fall in that one color
block is much heavier than the other.
Or let me show you a sort of a slightly
weird task.
It's an like other behavioral
experiments.
Sometimes we do weird things so that we
can test ways in which you use your
knowledge that you didn't just,
you know,
learn from pattern recognition,
but use it to do new kinds of tasks that
you'd never seen before.
So here's a task which many of you have
maybe seen me talk about these things.
So you might have seen this task,
but probably only if you saw me give a
talk around here before we call this the
red,
yellow task.
And again we'll make this one
interactive.
So imagine that the blocks on the table
or knocked hard enough to bump the
tables,
bumped hard enough to knock some of the
blocks onto the floor.
So you tell me,
is it more likely to be red blocks or
yellow blocks?
What do you say?
Red.
Okay,
good.
How about here?
Yeah,
yellow.
Good.
How about here?
Uh Huh.
Here,
here.
Okay.
Here.
So,
so you just experienced for yourself
what it's like to be a subject and one
of these expenses.
We just did the experiment here.
The data's is all captured on video,
sort of.
Okay.
You could see that sometimes people were
very quick.
Other times people were slower,
sometimes there was a lot of consensus,
sometimes there was a little bit less
consensus.
Right?
That reflects uncertainty.
So again,
there's a long history of studying this
scientifically,
um,
that,
you know,
you could,
but you can see some,
you can see the probabilistic inference
at work.
Probabilistic inference over what?
Well,
I would say one way to describe it is
over a one or a few short,
low precision simulations of the physics
of these scenes.
So here is what I mean by this.
I'm going to show you a video of a game
engine reconstruction of one of these
scenes that simulates a small.
So here's a small bump,
here's that same scene with a big bump.
Okay,
now notice that at the micro level,
different things happen,
but at the cognitive or macro level that
matters for common sense reasoning,
the same thing happen,
namely all the yellow blocks went over
onto one side of the table and few or
none of the red blocks did so it didn't
matter which of those simulations you
run in your head,
you'd get the same answer in this case,
right?
This is one that's very easy and high
confidence.
And also you,
you didn't have to run the simulation
for very long.
You only have to run it for a few times.
Steps like that to see what's going to
happen.
Or similarly here,
you only have to run it for a few times.
Steps,
okay?
And it doesn't have to be even very
accurate.
Even a fair amount of imprecision will
give you basically the same answer at
the level that matters for common sense.
So that's the kind of thing our model
does.
It runs a few low precision simulations
for a few times steps.
But if you take the average of what
happens there and you compare that with
people's judgments,
you get results like what I show you
here,
the scatter plot shows on the y axis,
the average judgments of people on the x
axis,
the average of this model,
and it does a pretty good job.
It's not perfect,
but the model basically captures peoples
graded sense of what's going on in this
scene and many of these others,
okay.
And it doesn't do it with any learning,
but I'll come back to that in a second.
It just does it by probabilistic
reasoning over a game physics
simulation.
Now we can use and we have used the same
kind of technology to capture in very
simple form.
It's really just proofs of concept at
this point,
but kind of common sense physical scene
understanding in child and a child
playing with blocks or other objects or
in what might go on in a young child,
understanding of other people's actions,
what we call the intuitive psychology
engine.
We're now,
the programs are defined over these kind
of very simple planning and perception
programs and I won't go into any
details.
I'll just point to a couple of papers
that my group played a very small role
in,
but we provided some models which
together with some infant researchers,
people working on both of these are
experiments that were done with 10 or 12
month infant,
so younger than even some of the babies
I showed you before,
but basically like that youngest baby,
the one with the cat.
Here's an example of showing simple
physical scenes.
These are moving objects to 12 month
olds where they saw a few objects
bouncing around inside a gumball machine
and after some point in time the scene
gets occluded.
You'll see the scene as occluded and
then after another period of time,
but one of the objects will appear at
the bottom and the question is,
is that the audit you expected to see or
not is it's expected or surprising?
The standard way you study what infants
know is by is by what's called looking
time methods.
Just like an adult.
If I show you something that's
surprising,
you might look longer.
Okay.
If you're bored,
you'll look away.
All right?
Um,
so you can do that same kind of thing
with infants and by measuring how long
they look at a scene,
you can measure whether you've shown
them something surprising or not.
All right?
People.
There are literally hundreds of studies,
if not more,
using looking time measures to study
what infants know,
but only with this paper that we
published a few years ago did we have a
quantitative model,
but we're able to show a relation
between inverse probability in this case
and surprise,
so things which were objectively lower
probability under one of these
probabilistic physics simulations across
a number of different manipulations of
how fast the objects were,
where they were when the scene was
occluded,
how long the delay was,
various physically relevant variables,
how many objects that were of one type
or another infant's expectations
connected with this model or another
paper that we published that one was,
was done.
The experiments that were done by
Aaronow tagless and Luca Menotti's lab.
Here is a study that was done just
recently by Sheri Lou enlists,
spelled [inaudible] lab at there at
Harvard,
but they're part,
they're partners with us in CBMM,
which was about infants understanding of
goals,
so this is more like again,
understanding of agents and intuitive
psychology.
We're in,
again,
in very simple cartoon scenes,
you show an infant and agent that seems
to be doing something like an animated
cartoon character,
but it jumps over a wall or it rolls up
a hill or it jumps over a gap and the
question is basically how much does the
agent want the goal that it seems to be
trying to achieve and what this study
showed.
Okay,
and the models here we're done by Tomer
omen was that infants appeared to be
sensitive to the physical work done by
the agent.
The more work the agent did in the sense
of the integral of force applied over a
path,
the more the the infant's thought the
agent wanted the goal.
We think of this as representing what
we've sometimes called the naive utility
calculus.
So the idea that there's a basic
calculus of,
of costs and benefits,
as you know,
we take actions which are a little bit
costly to achieve goal states,
which gives us some reward that's the
most basic way,
the oldest way to think about rational,
intentional action and it seems that
even 10 month olds understand some
version of that where the cost can be
measured in physical terms.
Okay.
Um,
I see I'm running a little bit behind on
time and,
and,
uh,
I wanted to leave some time for
discussion so I'll,
I'll just go very quickly through a
couple of other things and I'm happy to
stay around at the end for discussion.
Okay.
Um,
the,
what I showed you here was the science.
Where does the engineering go?
So one way,
one thing you can do with this is say
build a machine system that can look not
a little animated cartoon like these
baby experiments,
but a real person doing something and
again,
combined physical cough and constraints
of actions with some understanding of,
of the agents,
utilities,
that's the math of planning.
Trying to figure out what they wanted.
So look in the scene here and see if you
can judge which object the woman is
reaching for.
So you can see there's,
there's,
um,
a grid of four by four objects.
There's 16 objects here and she's going
to be reaching for one of them raised.
It's going to play in slow motion,
but raise your hand when you know which
ones he's reaching for.
Okay?
So just watch and raise your hand when
you know which one she wants.
Okay,
so most of the hands are up by now.
All right.
And notice I was looking at your hands.
Not here,
but when.
But what happened is most of the hands
were up at about the time when that
great or the one that dash line shot up.
Okay.
That's not human data.
You provided the data.
This is our model.
So our model is predicting more or less
when you're able to say what her goal
was.
Okay.
It's well before she actually touched
the object.
How does the model work?
Again,
I'll skip the details,
but it does the same kind of thing that,
that are models of those infants did
namely get it.
But in this case,
it does it with a full body model from
robotics,
so we use what's called the physics
engine,
which is a standard tool in robotics for
planning,
physically efficient reaches of say,
a humanoid robot,
and we say we can give this planner
program a goal object as input.
We can give each of the possible goal.
Optics is input and say,
plan the most physically efficient
action,
so the one that uses like the least
energy to get to that object,
and then we can do a Bayesian inference.
This is the probabilistic inference
part.
The program is the planner.
Okay,
but then we can say,
I want to do basie and inference to work
backwards from what I observed,
which was the action to the input to
that program.
What goal was provided as input to the
planner,
and here you can see the full array of
four by four possible inputs and those
bars that are moving up and down.
That's the basie and posterior
probability of how likely each of those
was to be the goal and what you can see
as it converges on the right answer at
least.
Well,
it turns out to be the ground truth
right answer,
but it's also the right answer according
to what people think with about the same
kind of data that people took.
Now you might say,
well,
okay,
I'm sure if I just wanted to build a
system that could detect what somebody
was reaching for,
I could generate a training data set of
this sort of scene and train something
up to analyze patterns of motion,
but again,
because the engine in your head actually
does something,
we think more like this,
it does what we call inverse planning
over a physics model.
It can apply to much more interesting
scenes that you haven't really seen much
of before.
So take the seat on the left,
right where again,
you see somebody reaching for one of a
four by four array of objects,
but what you see as a strange kind of
reach,
can you see why he's doing this?
Strange reach up there?
It's a little small,
but what is he?
You can see that he's reaching over
something,
right?
It's actually a pane of glass,
You see that and then there's this other
guy who's helping him,
who sees what he wants and hands him the
thing he wants.
So how does the,
for the guy in the foreground see the
other guy's goal,
how does he in for his goal and know how
to help him and then how do we look at
the two of them and figure out who's
trying to help who or that in a scene
like this one here that it's not
somebody trying to help somebody but
rather the opposite.
Okay,
so here's a model on the left of how
that might work.
Right?
And we think this is the kind of model
needed to tackle this sort of challenge
here,
right?
Basically it's a model.
We take this model of,
of planning,
sort of maximal expected utility
planning,
which you can run backwards,
but then we recursively nest these
models inside each other.
So we say an agent is helping another
agent if this agent is acting apparently
to us,
seems to be maximizing unexpected
utility.
That's a positive function of that
agent's expectation about another
agent's expecting to tilly and that's
what it means to be a helper.
Hindering is sort of the opposite if one
seems to be trying to lower somebody's
else's utility.
Okay,
and we've used these same kind of models
to also describe infants understanding
of helping and hindering and a range of
scenes.
I'll just say one last word about
learning because everybody wants to know
about learning and and the the key thing
here,
and it's.
It's definitely part of any picture of
Agi,
but the thought I want to leave you on
is really about what learning is about.
Okay.
It will be just a few more slides and
then I'll stop.
I promise none of the models I showed
you so far really did any learning.
They certainly didn't do any task
specific learning.
Okay.
We set up a provost at program and then
we let it do inference.
Now that's not to say that we don't
think people learn to do these things.
We do,
but the real learning goes on when
you're much younger,
right?
Everything I showed you in basic form,
even a one year old baby can do.
Okay.
The basic learning goes on to support
these kinds of abilities.
Not that there isn't learning beyond one
year,
but the basic way you learn to say solve
these physics problems is what goes on
in your bay,
in the brain of a child between zero and
12 months.
So this is just an example of some
phenomena that come from the literature
on infant cognitive development.
These are very rough timelines.
You can take pictures of this if you
like.
This is always a popular slide because
it's.
It's.
It really is quite inspiring I think,
and I can give you lots of literature,
but I'm summarizing in very broad
strokes with big error bars,
what we've learned in the field of
infant cognitive development about when
and how kids seemed to at least come to
a certain understanding of basic aspects
of physics.
So if you really want to study how
people learn to be intelligent,
a lot of what you have to study our kids
at this age,
you have to study what's already in
their brain at zero months and what they
learn and how they learn between four,
six,
eight,
10,
12,
and so on and on and on up beyond that.
Okay.
Now,
well,
effectively what that amounts to we
think is if what you're learning is
something like,
let's say an intuitive game,
physics engine to capture these basic
abilities than what we need.
If we're going to try to reverse
engineer,
that is what we might think of as a
program learning program.
If your knowledge is in the form of a
program,
then you have to have programs that
build other programs.
Right?
This is what I was talking about the
beginning about learning as building
models of the world are ultimately.
If you think what we start off with is
something like a game engine that can
play any game than what you have to
learn is the program of the game that
you're actually playing or the many
different games that you might be
playing over your life.
So think of learning as like programming
the game engine in your head to fit with
your experience and to fit with the
possible actions that you seem like you
can take.
Now,
this is what you could call the hard
problem of learning if you come to
learning from,
say,
neural networks or other tools in
machine learning.
Right?
So what makes machine makes most of
machine learning go right now and
certainly what makes neural networks so
appealing is that you can set up a
basically a big function approximator
that can approximate many of the
functions you might want to do in a
certain application or task,
but in a way that's end to end
differentiable and with a meaningful
cost function.
So you can have one of these nice
optimization landscapes.
You can compute the gradients on
basically just rolled down hill until
you get to an optimal solution,
but if you're talking about learning as
something like search in the space of
programs,
we don't know how to do anything like
that yet.
We don't know how to set this up as any
kind of a nice optimization problem with
any notion of smoothness or gradients.
Okay.
Rather,
what we need is a,
instead of learning as like rolling down
hill,
effectively write a process which just,
if you're willing to wait long enough,
you know,
some,
uh,
you know,
simple algorithm will take care of,
think of what we call the idea of
learning as programming.
There's a popular metaphor in cognitive
development called the child as
scientists,
which emphasizes children as active
theory builders and children's play as a
kind of casual experimentation.
But this is the algorithmic compliment
to that.
What we could call the child is coder or
around Mit will say the child is hacker,
but the rest of the world,
if you say child is hacker,
they think of something that someone who
breaks into your email and steals your
credit card numbers.
We all know that hacking is,
you know,
making your code more awesome,
right?
If,
if,
if your knowledge is some kind of code
or Lena Library of programs,
then learning is all the ways that a
child acts on their code to make it more
awesome,
more awesome can mean more accurate,
but it can also mean faster,
more elegant,
more transportable to other applications
or their tasks more explainable to
others.
Maybe just more entertaining.
Okay.
Children do.
All of them have all of those goals and
learning and the activities by which
they make their code more awesome.
Also correspond to many of the
activities of coding,
right?
So think about all the ways on a day to
day basis.
You might make your code more awesome.
Alright?
Um,
you might tune,
you might have a big library of existing
functions with some parameters that you
can tune on a data set that's basically
what you do with backdrop or stochastic
gradient descent and training a deep
learning system,
but think about all the ways in which
you might actually modify the underlying
function.
So write new code or take old code from
some other thing.
And Map it over here or make a whole new
library of code or refactor your code to
some other,
some other basis for that that will work
more robustly and be more extensible or
transpiling or compiling.
Right.
Or even just commenting your code or
asking someone else for their code.
Okay.
Again,
these are all ways that we make our code
more awesome and children's learning has
analogs to all of these that we would
want to understand as an engineer from
an algorithmic point of view.
So in our group we've been working on on
various early steps towards this.
And again,
we don't have anything like,
um,
program writing programs at the level of
children's learning algorithms.
But one example of something that we did
in our group,
which you might not have thought of
being about this,
but it's definitely the ai work we did
that got the most attention.
And the last couple of years from our
group,
we had this paper that was in science.
It was actually on the cover of science,
sort of just hit the market at the right
time if you like.
And it got about 100 times more
publicity than anything else I've ever
done,
which is partly a testament to the
really great work that Brendan Lake,
who was the first author did for his phd
here,
but much more so it just about the
hunger for ai systems at the time when
we published this in 2015 and we built a
machine system that the way we described
it was doing human level concept
learning for simple concept,
very simple visual concepts.
These handwritten characters in many of
the world's alphabets.
For those of you who know the famous m,
this Dataset,
the Dataset of handwritten digits zero
through 10 or 33 nine,
sorry.
Uh,
that drove so much good research in deep
learning and pattern recognition.
It did that not because Yann Macun who
put that together or Jeff Hinton,
who did a lot of work on deep learning
with Ms.
They weren't interested fundamentally in
character recognition that they saw that
as a very simple test bed for developing
more general ideas.
And similarly,
we did this work on getting machines to
do what we are kind of one shot learning
of generative models also to to develop
more general ideas.
We saw this as learning very simple
little mini probabilistic programs in
this case.
What are those programs that the
programs you used to draw a character.
So ask yourself how can you look at any
one of these characters and see in a
sense how somebody might draw it.
The way we tested this in our system was
this little visual turing test where we
showed people one character in a novel
alphabet and we said draw another one
and then we compared nine people like
say on the left and nine samples from
our machine say on the right.
And we said,
we asked other people,
could you tell which was the human
drawing another example or imagining
another example in which was the machine
and people couldn't tell when I said
ones on the left,
ones on the right.
I don't actually remember.
And and different ones you could see if
you can tell.
It's very hard to tell.
Can you tell which is for each one of
these characters,
which new set of examples were drawn by
a human versus the machine?
Here's the right answer and probably you
couldn't tell.
The way we did this was by assembling a
simple kind of program learning program,
right?
So we basically said when you draw a
character,
you're assembling strokes and sub
strokes with goals and sub goals that
produce ink on the page,
and when you see a character,
you're working backwards to figure out
what was the program,
the most efficient program that did
that.
So you're basically inverting a
probabilistic program,
doing basie and inference to the program
most likely to have generated what you
saw.
This is one small step we think towards
being able to learn programs to being
able to learn something ultimately like
a whole game engine program.
The last thing I'll leave you with is
just a pointer to sort of work in
action,
right?
So this is some work being done by a
current phd student who works partly
with me,
but also with Armando solar,
Lezama and Cecil sale.
This is Kevin Ellis is an example of
what's now.
I think again,
an emerging exciting area in Ai,
well beyond anything that we're doing is
combining techniques from where Amando
comes from,
which is the world of programming
languages,
not machine learning or ai,
but tools from programming languages
which can be used to automatically
synthesize code.
Okay.
With the machine learning tool kit,
in this case,
a kind of basie and minimum minimum
description link idea to be able to make
again,
what is really one small step towards
machines that can learn programs by
basically trying to efficiently find the
shortest,
simplest program which can capture some
data set.
So we think by combining these kinds of
tools,
in this case,
let's say from basie and infants over
programs with a number of tools that
have been developed in other areas of
computer science that don't look
anything or haven't been considered to
be machine learning or ai like
programming languages.
It's one of the many ways that going
forward we're going to be able to build
smarter,
more human like machines.
So just to end then,
what I've tried to tell you here is
taught first of all,
identify the ways in which human
intelligence goes beyond pattern
recognition to really all these
activities of modeling the world.
Okay.
To give you a sense of some of the
domains where you can start to study
this in common sense,
seen understanding for example,
um,
or you know,
something like a one shot learning for
example,
like what we were just doing.
Their learning is programming the engine
in your head.
Okay.
And to give you a sense of some of the
technical tools,
probabilistic programs,
program synthesis,
game engines for example,
as well as a little bit of deep learning
that bringing together,
we're starting to be able to make these
things real.
Okay.
Now that's the science agenda and the
reverse engineering agenda.
But think about for those of you who are
interested in technology,
what are the many big ai frontiers that
this opens up?
So the one I'm most excited about is
this idea which is,
which I've highlighted here in our big
research agenda.
This is the one I'm most excited about
to work on for the,
you know,
it could be the rest of my career
honestly,
but it's really what is,
what is the oldest and maybe the best
dream of AI researchers of how to build
a human like intelligence system,
a real agi system.
It's the idea that terrain proposed when
he proposed the turing test or Marvin
Minsky proposed this at different times
in his life or many people have proposed
this,
right?
Which is to build a system that grows
into intelligence the way a human does
that starts like a baby and learns like
a child,
and I've tried to show you how we're
starting to be able to understand those
things.
What a baby's mind starts with how
children actually learn and looking
forward,
we might.
We might imagine that someday we'll be
able to build machines that can do this.
I think we can actually start working on
this right now and we're.
And that's something that we're doing in
our group.
So if that kind of thing excites you,
then I encourage you to work on it and
maybe even with us or if any one of
these other activities of human
intelligence excite you,
I think taking the kind of science based
reverse engineering approach that we're
doing and then trying to put that into
engineering practice,
it's,
this is,
uh,
this is not just a possible route,
but I think it's,
it's quite possibly the most valuable
route that you could work on right now
to try to actually achieve at least some
kind of artificial general intelligence,
especially the kind of intelligence ai
system that's going to live in a human
world and interact with humans.
There's many kinds of ai systems that
could live in worlds of data that none
of us can understand or whatever live in
ourselves.
But if you want to build machines that
can live in our world and interact with
us the way we are used to interacting
with other people,
then I think this is a route that you
should consider.
Okay.
Thank you.
So earlier in the talk you expressed
some skepticism about whether or not
industry would get us to understanding
human level intelligence.
It seems that there's a couple of trends
that favorite industry.
One is the industry is better than
academia accumulating resources and
plowing back into the topic and it seems
at the moment we've got a bit of brain
drain going on from academia into
industry and that seems like an ongoing
trend.
If you look at something like learning
to fly,
learning to fly into space,
then it looks like the story is one of
industry kind of taking over the field
and going off on its own a little bit.
Academic academics still have a role.
The industry kind of dominate industry
and I would take the field.
Do you think?
Well that's a really good question and
it's got several good questions packed
into one there.
Right?
I didn't mean to say this wasn't meant
to say go academia,
bad industry.
What I was taught,
what I tried to say was the approaches
that are currently getting the most
attention in industry and they're really
because they are really the most
valuable ones right now for the short
term,
you know,
any industry is really focused on what
it can do.
What are the value propositions on
basically a two year timescale at most.
I mean if you ask,
say Google researchers to take the most
prominent example,
that's pretty much what they'll all tell
you.
Okay.
Maybe maybe things that might pay off
initially in two years,
but maybe take five years or more to
really develop,
but if,
if you can't show that it's going to do
something practical for us in two years
in a way that matters for our bottom
line,
then it's not really worth doing.
Okay,
so what,
when we see what I'm talking about is
technologies,
which right now industry sees as meeting
that specification.
And what I'm saying is right now,
I think those.
That's not where the route is to
something like human,
like the not the most valuable promising
route to humanlike kinds of AI systems.
All right,
but I hope that like in the case,
as you said,
you know,
the basic research that we're doing now
will be successful enough that it will
get the attention of industry when the
time is right,
but I think so,
so I hope at some point it won't.
It will at least the engineering side
will have to be done in industry,
not just in academia,
but you're also pointing to issues of
like brain drain and other things like
that.
That I think these are real issues
confronting our community.
I think everybody knows this and I'm
sure this will come up multiple times
here,
which is,
you know,
I think we have to find ways to even now
to combine the best of the ideas,
the energy and the resources of academia
and industry.
If we want to keep doing basically
something interesting,
right?
If we,
if,
if we just want to redefine ai to be,
well,
whatever people currently call ai but
scaled up well then then then fine,
forget about it and or if we just want
to say,
let me and people like me do what we're
doing.
At what industry would consider a
snail's pace on toy problems.
Okay fine,
but if but if we want to,
if you know,
if I want to take what I'm doing to the
level that that will really be paying
off that level the industry can
appreciate or just that really has
technological impact on a broad scale.
Right?
Or I think if industry wants to take
what it's doing and really build
machines that are actually intelligent,
right?
Or machine learning that actually learns
like a person,
then I think we need each other now and
not just in some point in the future.
So this is a general challenge for mit
and for,
for everywhere.
And for Google.
I mean we just spent a few days talking
to Google about exactly this issue of,
in fact this was a talk I prepared
partly for that purpose.
So we wanted to raise those issues and
and it's just.
I mean really there,
I don't know what I mean.
What rather I can think of some
solutions to that problem of what you
could call brain drain from the academic
point of view or what you could call
just narrowing in into certain local
minima and the industry point of view,
but they will require the leadership of
both academic institutions like mit and
companies like Google being creative
about how they might work together in
ways that are a little bit outside of
their comfort zone.
I hope that will start to happen,
um,
including at mit and at many other
universities and companies like Google
and many others.
And I think we need it to happen for the
health of all parties concerned.
Okay.
Thank you very much.
Thanks.
Uh,
I'm curious about sort of the premise
that you gave that a.
One of the big gaps missing at
determining intelligence is the fact
that we need to teach machines how to
recognize models.
And I'm curious as to what you think
sort of non goal oriented cognitive
activity comes into play there.
Things like feelings and emotions and,
and why you don't think that might not
necessarily be like the most
important question.
The only reason emotions didn't appear
on my slide is because there's a few
reasons,
but the slide is only so big.
I wanted the font to be readable for
such an important slide.
I had versions of my slide in which I do
talk about that.
Okay.
Um,
I,
it's not that I think feelings or
emotions aren't important.
I think they are important and I,
and I used to not have many insights on
it about what to do about them,
but actually partly based on some of my
colleagues here at Mit,
bcs,
Laura Schultz and Rebecca Saxe to,
of my cognitive colleagues who I work
closely with,
um,
they've been starting to,
to,
to do research on how people understand
emotions,
both their own and others and we've been
starting to work with them on
computational models.
So that's actually something I'm
actively interested in and even working
on.
But I would say,
and again,
for those of you who study emotion or
know about this,
actually you're going to have lisa
coming in,
right?
Oh.
So she's going to basically say a
version of the same thing.
I think the deepest way to understand
she's one of the world's experts on
this.
The deepest way to understand emotion is
very much based on our mental models of
ourselves,
of the situation we're in and of other
people,
right?
Think about,
for example,
all of the different.
I mean if,
if,
if you think about them,
I mean,
again,
Lisa will talk all about this,
but if you think about emotion,
it's just a very small set of what are
sometimes called basic emotions,
like being happy or angry or sad or you
know,
those are small number of them,
right?
There's usually only a few,
You might not say,
you might see that as somehow like very
basic things that are opposed to some
kind of cognitive activity.
But think about all the different words
we have for emotion,
right?
Um,
for example,
think about an,
a,
a famous cognitive emotion like regret.
What does it mean to feel regret or
frustration?
Right?
To just to,
to know both for yourself when you're
not just feeling kind of down or
negative,
but you're feeling regret that that
means something like,
I have to feel like there's a situation
that came out differently from how I
hoped and I realized I could have done
something differently.
Right?
So that means you have to be able to
understand,
you have to have a model,
you have to be able to do a kind of
counterfactual reasoning and to think,
oh,
if only I had acted a different way than
I can predict that the world would have
come out differently and that's the
situation I wanted,
but instead it came up this other way,
right?
Um,
or think about frustration again,
that requires something like
understanding,
okay,
I've tried a bunch of times,
I thought this would work,
but it doesn't seem to be working.
Maybe I'm ready to give up though.
Those are all.
Those are.
Those are very important human emotions.
We have to understand to understand
ourselves.
We need that to understand other people
to understand communication,
but those are all filtered through the
kinds of models of action that I was.
Just the ones I was talking about here
with these say cost benefit analysis of
action.
So what I'm.
So I'm just trying to say I think this
is very basic stuff that will be the
basis for building,
I think better engineering style models
of the full spectrum of human emotion
beyond just like,
well,
I'm feeling good or bad or scared.
Okay.
And if I think when you see Lisa,
she will in her own way,
say something very similar.
Interesting.
Thanks.
Yeah,
thanks Josh for your stock.
So all these are both human cognition
and try to build a model to mimic those
cognition.
What you don't.
How much could help you to understand
how the circuit implement those things.
I mean like the circuits in the brain.
What's the.
Is that what you work on by Newcastle?
Sorry,
what?
Is that?
What you work on by any chance?
Yeah,
yeah.
Yeah.
So,
so in the center for brains,
minds and machines as well as in brain
and cognitive science.
Yet we have a number of colleagues who
study the actual hardware basis of this
stuff in the brain and that includes
like the large scale architecture of the
brain,
say like what Nancy Campbell shirt,
Rebecca Saxe study with functional brain
imaging or the more detailed circuitry,
which usually requires recording from
say non brands right at the level of
individual neurons and connections
between neurons.
Alright.
So I'm very interested in those things,
although it's not mostly what I work on.
Right.
But I would say,
you know,
again like in many other areas of
science,
certainly in neuroscience,
the kind of work I'm talking about here
in a sort of classic reductionist
program sets the target for what we
might look for.
Like if I,
if I just want to go,
I would,
I would assert right.
Or my working conjecture is that if,
if you do the kind of work that I'm
talking about here,
it gives you the right targets or gives
you a candidates that have targets to
look for what are the neural circuits
computing.
Right?
Whereas if you just go in and just say,
start poking around in the brain or have
some idea that what you're going to try
to do is find the neural circuits which
underlie behavior without a sense of the
computations needed to produce those
behaviors.
I don't,
I think it's going to be very difficult
to,
to know what to look for and to know
when you found even Bible answers.
So I think that's,
you know,
that's the standard kind of reductionist
program,
but it's not,
it's,
it's not.
Um,
I also think it's,
it's not one that is divorced from the
study of neurocircuits.
It's also one,
if you look at the broad picture of
reverse engineering,
it's one where you were neurocircuits
and understanding the circuits in the
brain play an absolutely critical role.
Okay.
I would say the main as an.
When you look at the brain at the
hardware level,
as an engineer,
I'm mostly looking at the software
level,
right?
But when you look at the hardware level,
there are some remarkable properties.
One remarkable property,
again,
is how much parallelism there is and in
many ways how fast the computations are.
Okay,
neurons are slow,
but the computation of the tubs are very
fast.
So how do we get elements that are in
some sense quite slow in their time
constant to produce such intelligent
behavior so quickly?
That's a great mystery.
And I think if we understood that it
would have payoff for building all sorts
of,
uh,
you know,
apple basically application embedded
circuits.
Okay.
But also maybe most important is the
power consumption.
And again,
many people have,
have,
have noted this,
right?
If you look at the power consumption,
the power that the brain consumes,
like what did I eat today?
Okay?
Almost nothing.
My daughter,
who's again,
she's doing an internship here,
she literally yesterday,
all she ate was a burrito and yet she
wrote 300 lines of code for her
internship project on really cool
computational linguistics project.
So somehow she turned a Burrito into a
model of child language acquisition.
Okay,
but how did she do that?
Or how do any of us do this?
Right?
Um,
where if you look at the power that we
consume when we simulate even a very,
very small chunk of cortex on our
conventional hardware,
or we do any kind of machine learning
thing,
we have systems which are very,
very,
very far from the power of the human
brain computationally,
but in terms of physical energy consumed
way,
way past what any individual brain is
doing.
So how do we get circuitry of any sort,
biological,
or just any physical circuits to be as
smart as we are with,
with as little energy as we are.
This is,
this is a huge problem for basically
every area of engineering,
right?
If you want to,
if you want to have any kind of robot,
the power consumption is a key
bottleneck.
Same for self driving cars.
If we want to build ai without
contributing to global warming and
climate change,
let alone use ai to solve climate
change,
we really need to address these issues
and the brain is a,
is a huge a guide there,
right?
I think there are some people who are
really starting to think about this.
How can we say,
for example,
build somehow brain inspired computers,
which are very,
very low power but maybe only
approximate.
So I'm thinking here of Joe Bates,
I don't know if I don't have,
you know,
Joe,
he's,
uh,
been around mit and other places for
quite awhile.
Can I tell them about your company?
So,
so joe has a low,
a startup in Kendall Square called
singular computing and they have some
very interesting ideas,
including some actual implemented
technology for low power,
approximate computing in a sort of a
brain like way that might lead to
possibly even like the ability to build
something.
This is Joe's dream to build on this,
about the size of this table,
but that has a billion course,
a billion cores and runs on a reasonable
kind of power consumption.
I would love to have such a machine if
anybody wants to help joe build that.
I think he'd love to talk to you,
but it's one of a number of,
of,
of ideas.
I mean google x,
people are working on similar things.
Probably most of the major chip
companies are also inspired by this
idea.
And I think even if you didn't think you
were interested in the brain,
if you want to build the kind of ai
we're talking about and run it on
physical hardware of any sort and
understanding how the brain circuits
compute what they do,
what I'm talking about with as little
power as they do,
I don't know any better place to look.
It seems like a lot of the improvements
in ai have been driven by increasing
computational power.
How far are you,
would you say me like Gpu or CPU?
How far would you say we are from
hardware that could run a general
artificial intelligence
of the kind that I'm talking about?
Yeah,
I dunno.
I'll start with a billion cores and then
we'll see.
I mean,
I think we're,
I think,
I think there's no way to answer that
question in a way that software
independent.
I don't know how to do that right.
But I think that um,
it's and,
and you know,
I don't know,
like when you say how far we you mean?
Uh,
how far am I with the resources I have
right now?
How far my,
if,
if Google decides to put all of its
resources at my disposal,
like they might if I were working at
deepmind.
I don't know the answer to that
question,
but I think the,
I think what we can say is this
individual neurons.
I mean,
again,
this goes back to another reason to
study neurocircuits.
Um,
if you look at what we currently call
neural networks in the Ai side,
the model of a neuron is,
is very,
very simple thing.
Individual neurons are not only much
more complex,
but I have a lot more computational
power.
It's not clear how they use it or
whether they use it,
but I think it's just as likely that a
neuron is something like a revenue,
right?
Is that a neuron is something like a
computer,
like under one neuron in your brain is
more like a CPU note.
Okay.
Maybe,
um,
and thus the 10 billion or trillion,
you know,
the large number of neurons in your
brain,
um,
I think it's like 10 billion cortical
pyramidal neurons or something might be
like 10 billion corps.
Okay.
For example,
that's at least as plausible I think to
me as any other estimate.
So.
And I think so.
I think we're definitely on the
underside with very big error bars,
so I completely agree that um,
or if this is what you might be
suggesting and May,
you know,
going back to my answer to your
question,
I don't think we're going to get to what
I'm talking about.
Anything like a real brain scale without
major innovations on the hardware side.
And you know,
it's,
it's interesting that what drove those
innovations in the support current ai
was mostly not ai.
It was the video game industry.
I'm a way when I point to the video game
engine in your head,
that's a similar thing that was driven
by the video game industry on the
software side.
I think we should all play as many video
games as we can and contribute to the
growth of the video game industry
because.
No,
because I mean,
I mean you can see this [inaudible] like
there are companies out there.
For example,
there's a company called improbable
which is a London company.
I'm London based startup,
a pretty sizable startup at this point,
which is building something that they
call spatial Oscp,
which is a.
it's a,
it's not a,
it's not a hardware idea,
but it's a kind of software idea for
very,
very big distributed computing
environments to run much,
much more complex,
realistic simulations of the world for a
much more interesting immersive
permanent video games.
I think that's one thing that might
hopefully that will lead to more fun new
kinds of games,
but that's one example of where we might
look to that industry to drive some of
the computer systems,
really hardware and software systems
that will take.
We'll take our game to the next level.
Just understanding algorithmic level or
cognitive level is just to understanding
the learning.
The meaning of learning will be hard to
predict,
but on the circuit level these
different,
but at the what level under could live
with.
Well of course it's different.
Right,
but already I think you made a mistake
there.
Honestly,
like you said,
the cognitive goal is learning how to
predict,
but I'm not sure what you mean by that.
There's many things you could mean and
are what our cognitive science is about
is learning which of those versions,
like I don't think it's learning how to
predict.
I think it's learning what need to know
to plan actions and to uh,
you know,
all those things.
Like it's not just about predicting,
it's because there are things we can
imagine that you would never predict
because they would never happen unless
we somehow make the world different
generalizations.
Sorry,
not when you were methodical journalize,
but especially in this transfer learning
that you are interested in a few hundred
neurons in prefrontal cortex.
The generalize a lot.
Yes,
but not kind of a Bayesian model could
do that.
You said,
but lazy and model won't do that or they
don't do it the way a Bayesian model
does for sure.
Because that's in the abstract level.
Well,
I mean,
how do you really know like,
and what does it mean to say that some
neurons do it like.
So maybe another way to put this is to
say,
look,
we have a certain math that we use to
capture these.
You could call it abstract or I call it
software level abstractions,
right?
I mean all engineering is based in some
kind of abstraction,
but you might have a circuit level
abstraction,
a certain kind of hardware level that
you're interested in describing the
brain at and I'm mostly working out or
starting from a more software level of
abstraction.
Right?
They're all abstractions.
We're not talking about molecules here.
Right.
We're talking about some abstract notion
of maybe a circuit or have a program.
Okay.
Right now it's a really interesting
question.
If I look at some circuits,
how do I know what program they're
implementing?
Right.
If I look at the circuits and this
machine,
could I tell what program they
implementing?
Well,
maybe,
but certainly it will be a lot easier if
I knew something about what programs
they might be implementing before I
start to look at the circuitry.
If I just looked at the circuitry
without knowing what the program was or
what programs the thing might be doing
or what kind of programming components
would be mappable two circuits in
different ways.
Right.
I don't even know how to begin to answer
that question,
so I think we've made some progress at
understanding what neurons are doing in
certain low level parts of sensory
system and certain parts of the motor
system,
like primary motor cortex,
like basically the parts of the neurons
that are closest to the inputs and
outputs of the brain,
right where we don't eat when you can
say we don't need the kind of software
abstractions that I'm talking about or
where we sort of agree on what those
things already are so we can make enough
progress on knowing what to look for and
how to.
How to know when we found it.
But if you want to talk about flexible
planning,
things that are more like cognition that
go on and prefrontal Cortex,
right?
I,
at this point,
I don't.
I don't think that just by recording
from those neurons,
we're going to be able to answer those
questions in a meaningful engineering
way.
A way that that any engineer,
software,
hardware,
whatever,
could really say,
yeah,
okay,
I get it.
I get those insights in a way that I can
engineer with and that's what my goal
is,
right?
So my goal,
that's my goal to do at the software
level,
the hardware level or the entire systems
connecting them and I think that,
you know,
we can do that by taking what we're
doing and bringing into contact with
people studying neural circuits,
but I don't think you can,
you can leave this level out and just go
straight to the neural circuits and I
think the more you have,
the more progress we make,
the more we can help people who are
studying at the neuro circuit level and
they can help us address these other
engineering questions that we don't
really have access to like the power
issue or the speed issue.
Okay.
Thanks.
That was great.
Maybe give Janssen again
man.
Thanks.