Welcome back to six,
says zero,
nine,
nine artificial general intelligence.
Today we have Eylea says Giver,
Cofounder and Research Director of Open
Ai.
He started in the aml group in Toronto.
Geoffrey Hinton,
then at Stanford with Andrew Wang.
Co founded DNN research for three years
as a research scientist at Google brain
and finally cofounded open ai citations
aren't everything,
but they do indicate impact.
And his work,
recent work in the past five years has
been cited over 46,000
times.
He has been the key creative intellect
and driver behind some of the biggest
breakthrough ideas and deep learning and
artificial intelligence ever.
So please welcome Eylea.
Thanks.
Alright,
thanks for the introduction next.
thanks for coming to my talk.
I will tell you about some work we've
done over the past year on on Melania
and self at open Ai and before I dive
into some of the more technical details
of the work,
I wanted to spend a little bit of time
talking about deep learning and why it
works at all in the first place,
which I think it's actually not as self
evident,
seeing that they should work.
One fact it's actually a fact,
it's a mathematical theory that you can
prove is that if you could find the this
program does very,
very well in your data,
then you will achieve the best
generalization possible with a little
bit of modification.
You can turn it into a precise theory
and on a very intuitive level,
it's easy to see why it shouldn't be the
case.
If you have some data and you're able to
find a short term program which
generates this data,
then you've essentially extracted all
the old conceivable regularity from this
data into your program and then you can
use this objects to make the best
predictions possible.
If if you have data which is so complex
and there is no way to express it as a
shorter program and it means that your
data is totally random,
there is no way to extract any
irregularity from it whatsoever.
Now,
there is little known mathematical
theory behind this and the proofs of
these statements.
Actually,
not even that hard,
but the one minor,
slight disappointment is that it's
actually not possible,
at least given today's tools and
understanding to find the best short
program that explains or generates or
solves your problem.
Given your data.
This problem is computationally
intractable.
The space of old programs is a very
nasty space.
Small changes to a program result in
massive changes in the behavior of the
program as it should be.
It makes sense.
We have a loop.
We changed the inside of the loop.
Of course you get something totally
different,
so the space of programs is so hard,
at least given what we know today,
search,
there seems to be completely off the
table.
Well,
if we give up on the short side on short
programs,
what about small circuits?
Well,
it turns out that we are lucky.
It turns out that when it comes to small
circuits,
you can just find the best small
circuits circuit that solves a problem
using backpropagation,
and this is the miraculous fact on which
the rest of ai stands.
It is the fact that then you have a
circuit and you impose constraints on
your circuits.
On your circuit using data,
you can find a way to satisfy these
constraints,
these constraints using backdrop by
iteratively making small changes to the
weights of your neural network until its
predictions satisfy the data.
Well,
this means is that the computational
problem that sober backpropagation is
extremely profound.
It is circuit search.
Now we know that you can solve with
solid all this,
but you can solve it sometimes and you
can solve it that those times where we
have a practical data set,
it is easy to design artificial data
sets for which you not find the best
neural network,
but in practice it seems to be not a
problem.
Are you going to think of training
neural network as solving an equation?
In many cases where you have a large
number of equation terms like this,
Fox,
Scifi equals way,
so you've got your parameters and they
are present all your degrees of freedom
and you use gradient descent to push the
information from these equations into
the parameters of satisfy them all.
And you can see that the neural network,
let's say one with 50 layers is
basically a parallel computer that is
given 50 times steps to run and you can
look quite a lot to be the 50 slash 50
times step,
sort of very,
very powerful.
I'm massively parallel computer.
So for example,
I think it is not widely known that you
can learn to sort sort an n beat numbers
using a modestly sized neural network
with just two hidden layers,
which is not bad.
It's not self evident.
Especially since we've been taught that
sorting requires logan parallel steps
with a neural network,
you can sort successful using only two
parallel steps.
So there's some things like an obvious
going on now these a part of those steps
of thresholds for threshold neurons,
so they're doing a little bit more work.
That's an answer to the mystery,
but if you've got 50 such layers,
you can do quite a bit of logic,
quite a bit of reasoning all inside the
neural network.
And that's why it works.
Given the data,
we are able to find the best neural
network and because the neural network
is deep because it can run computation
inside of inside of its layers,
the best neural network is worth finding
because that's really what you need.
You need something you need to model
class which is worth optimizing,
but it also needs to be optimized.
Mobile and deep neural networks
satisfied both of these constraints,
and this is why everything works,
so this is the basis on which everything
else resides.
Now,
I wanted to talk a little bit about
reinforcement learning.
Reinforcement learning is a framework.
It's a framework of evaluating agents in
their ability to achieve goals and
complicated stochastic environments.
You've got an agent which is plugged
into an environment as shown in the
figure right here and for any given
agent,
you can simply run it many times and
computers average award.
Now,
the thing that's interesting about the
reinforcement learning framework is that
there exist interesting,
useful reinforcement learning
algorithms.
The framework existed for a long time.
It became interesting once we realized
that good algorithms exist.
Now,
these are perfect algorithms,
but they're good enough to do
interesting things and all you want.
The mathematical problem is one where
you need to maximize the expected
reward.
Now,
one important way in which the
reinforcement learning framework is not
quite complete is that it assumes that
the reward is given by the environment.
You see this picture,
the agent sends an action while the
reward sends it the observation,
and they're both of the observation and
the reward backwards.
That's what the environment communicates
back.
One way in which this is not the case in
the real world is that we figure out
what the reward is from the observation
we reward ourselves.
We are not told.
Environment doesn't say,
Hey,
here's some negative reward.
It's our interpretation over census that
lets us determine what the reward is and
there is only one real reward in life
and this is existence or nonexistence
and everything else is a corollary of
that.
So well,
what should the region be?
You already know the answers should be a
your own network because whenever you
want to do something,
then it's going to be a neural network
and you want the agents to map
observations to actions so you let it be
parameterized within your own net.
Then you apply learning algorithm,
so I want to explain to you how
reinforcement learning works.
This is model free reinforcement
learning.
Reinforcement learning has actually been
using practice everywhere,
but he's also deeply in it.
It's very robust.
It's very simple.
It's also not very efficient,
so the way it works is the following.
This is literally the one sentence
description of what happens.
In short,
try something new.
I'd randomness directions and compare
the results to your expectation.
If the result surprises you.
If you find that the results exceeded
your expectation,
then change your parameters,
but they could those actions in the
future.
That's it.
This is the full idea of reinforcement
learning.
Try it out,
see if you like it,
and if you do more of that in the
future,
and that's it,
that's literally,
this is the core idea.
Now it turns out it's not difficult to
formalize mathematically,
but this is really what's going on in a
neural network,
in irregular neural network,
I guess you might say,
okay,
what's the goal?
Iran,
the neural network.
You get an answer,
you compare it to the desired answer and
whatever difference you have between
those,
do you send it back?
The changing the neural network that's
supervised learning and reinforcement
learning.
You're running your own network,
you had a bit of randomness,
direction,
and then you feel like the result,
you're randomness turns into the desired
target in effect,
so that's it.
Trivial.
Now math exists without explaining what
these equations mean.
The point is not for you to derive them,
but just to show that they exist.
There are two classes of reinforcement
learning algorithms.
One of them is the policy gradients
where basically what you do is that you
take this expression right there,
the will expect expected,
some of rewards and it just crunched
through the derivatives.
You expand the terms,
Iran do some Algebra and you get the
derivative and miraculously the
derivative has exactly the form that I
told you which is try some actions and
if you like them increasing the low
probability of the actions.
That's literally follows from the math.
It's very nice when the intuitive
explanation as a one to one
correspondence to what you get in the
equation.
Even though you'll have to take my word
for it if you're not familiar with it.
That's the question.
At the top there was a different class
of reinforcement learning algorithms
which is a little bit more difficult to
explain.
It's called a cue learning based
algorithms.
They are a bit less stable and beat,
more simple efficient and it has the
property is that it can learn not only
from the data generated by the actor but
from any other data as well.
So it has,
it has some it,
it has a different robustness profile.
It should be a little bit important,
but it's only going to be the legality.
So yeah,
this is the policy of policy
distinction,
but it's a little bit technical.
So if you find this hard to understand,
don't worry about it.
If you already know,
then you already know it.
So now what's the potential of
reinforcement learning?
Wasn't the promise.
What is it actually why?
Why should we be excited about it?
Now,
there are two reasons the reinforcement
learning algorithms have today already
useful and interesting,
and especially if you have a really good
simulation of your world,
you could train agents to lots of
interesting things,
but what's really exciting is if you can
build a super amazing sample efficient
algorithms,
reinforcement learning algorithm,
which is give it a tiny amount of data
and the algorithm just crunches through
it and extract every bit of entropy out
of it in order to learn in the fastest
way possible.
Now,
today or algorithms are not particularly
efficient.
They are data inefficient,
but as our field keeps making progress,
this will change.
Next,
I want to dive into the topic of metal
learning.
The goal of metal learning.
So Methadone is a beautiful idea that
doesn't really work,
but it kind of works and it's really
promising too.
It's another promising idea.
So what's the dream?
We have some learning algorithms,
perhaps you could use those learning
algorithm is in order to learn to learn.
I'd be nice if we could learn to learn,
so how can you do that?
It will take a system which you train it
not on one task but on many tasks and
you ask it if it learns to solve these
tasks quickly and that may actually be
enough.
So here's how it looks like.
Here's how most traditional method
learning look works like a looks like
you have a model which is a big neural
network,
but what you do is that you treat every
instead of training cases,
you have training tasks and instead of
test cases,
you have test tasks,
so your input maybe instead of just your
current test case,
it will be all the information about the
news,
about the test tasks plus the test case,
and you'll try to output the prediction
reaction for that test case.
So basically you say,
yeah,
I'm going to give you your 10 examples
as part of your input to your model,
figured out how to make the best use of
them.
It's a really straightforward idea.
You turn the neural network into the
learning algorithm by turning a training
task into a training case,
so training,
task it constraining case.
This is learning this one sentence and
so there've been several success stories
which I think are very interesting.
One of the success stories of learning
is learning to recognize characters
quickly.
So they've been a dataset produced by
MIT,
by Lake at all,
and this is a data set.
We have a large number of different
handwritten characters and people have
been able to train extremely strong
metal learning system for this task and
now the successful and other very
successful example of metal learning is
neural architecture.
Search by is openly from Google where
they found a neural architecture that
sold one problem,
well small problem and then you could
generalize it and then it will
successfully solve large problems as
well.
So this is the kind of the,
the small number of bits matter
learning.
It's like when you learn the
architecture or maybe even learn a
program,
a small program or learning algorithm,
and she applied to new tasks.
So this is the other way of doing metal
learning.
So anyway,
but the point is what's happening,
what's really happening in matter
learning in most cases is that you turn
a training task into a training case and
pretend that this is totally normal,
normal,
deep learning.
That's it.
This is the entirety of metal learning.
Everything else that just minor details.
Next I want to dive in.
So now that I finished the introduction
section,
I want to start discussing different
work by different people from open ai
and I want to start by talking about
mindset experience,
replay.
There's been a large effort by
unrecalled.
Richard,
I'll develop a learning algorithm for
reinforcement learning that doesn't
solve just one task,
but it solves many tasks and it learns
to make use of it's experience in a much
more efficient way.
And I want to discuss one problem in
reinforcement learning.
It's actually,
I guess a set of problems which are
related to each other,
like one really important thing you need
to learn to do is to explore your in
that you start out in an environment you
don't know what to do,
what do you do?
So one very important thing that has to
happen is that you must get rewards from
time to time.
If you try something and you don't get
rewards,
then how can you learn?
So said that's the kind of the crux of
the problem.
How do you learn?
And relatedly,
is there any way to meaningfully benefit
from your,
from the experience,
from your attempts to,
from,
from your failures.
If you try to achieve a goal and you
fail,
can you still learn from it?
You tell you instead of asking your
algorithm to achieve a single goal,
you want to learn a policy that they can
achieve a very large family of goals.
For example,
instead of reaching one state,
you want to learn a policy that reaches
every state on your system.
Now,
what's the implication?
Anytime you do something,
you achieved some state.
So let's suppose you say I want to
achieve state A.
I try my best and I ended up achieving
state B.
I can either conclude while that was
disappointing,
I haven't flown almost anything.
I still have no idea how to,
how to achieve state aid.
But alternatively I can say,
well,
wait a second,
I've just reached the perfectly good
state,
which is b,
can I learn how to achieve state,
be for my attempt to achieve state a and
answer is yes,
you can,
and it just works and I just want to
point out this is the one case,
there's a small subtlety here which may
be interesting to those of you who are
very familiar with the distinction
between non policy and off policy.
When you try to achieve a,
you are on your own policy learning for
reaching the state a,
but you're doing off policy learning
fruition to state b because you will
take different actions if you actually
try to reach them beat.
So that's why it's very important that
the algorithm you use here can support
of policy learning.
But that's a minor technicality at the
crux.
The crux of the idea is you make the
problem easier by ostensibly making it
harder by training assistant which can,
which aspires to reach,
to learn to reach every state,
to learn to achieve every goal,
to learn to master it's environment.
In general,
you build a system which always learned
something,
it learns from success as well as from
failure because if it tries to do one
thing,
one thing and it does something else,
it now Australian data for how to
achieve.
That's something else we want to show
you a video of how this thing works in
practice.
So one challenge in reinforcement
learning systems is the need to shape
the reward.
So what does it mean?
It means that at the beginning of the at
the,
at the start of learning,
then the system doesn't know much,
it will probably not achieve your goal,
and so it's important that you design
your reward function to give it gradual
increments to make it smooth and
continuous so that even when the system
is not very good,
it achieves the goal.
Now,
if you give your state,
your system a very sparse report where
the reward is achieved only when you
reach a final state,
very hard for normal reinforcement
learning algorithms to solve the problem
because naturally you'll never get the
reward so you never learn.
No reward means no learning.
But here,
because you learn from failure as well
as some success,
there's this problem simply doesn't
occur.
And so this,
this,
this is nice.
I think,
you know,
let's,
let's look at the videos a little bit
more.
Like it's nice how say it confidently
and energetically moves the little green
buck.
Please target.
And here's another one.
Okay.
So we can skip the physical.
It works on the physical robot as well,
but he can skip it.
So I think the point is the hindsight
central experience,
replay algorithm is directionally
correct because you want to make use of
all your data and not only a small
fraction of it.
Now one huge question is where do you
get the high level states?
Where do the high level states come
from?
Because in the work that I've shown you
so far,
the system is asking your goal in the
states.
So I think one thing too will become
very important for these kinds of
approaches.
Is it a presentation,
learning and unsupervised learning.
Figure out what are the rates,
what are the right states?
What's the state space of goals that's
worth achieving?
Now I want to go through some real
method learning results and I'll show
you a very simple way of doing to real
from simulation to the physical.
Robert,
with Metta learning,
and this is where went panadol was in a
an entrance and an a really nice intern
project and vain 17,
so I think we can agree that in the
domain of robotics,
it would be nice if you could train your
policy in simulation and then somehow
this knowledge would carry over to the
physical robbed.
Now we can build,
we can build simulators that are okay,
but they can never perfectly match the
real world unless you want to have an
insanely slow simulator.
And the reason for that is that it turns
out that stimulating freakers simulating
contacts is super hard.
And I heard somewhere,
correct me if I'm wrong,
that simulating friction is NP complete.
I'm not sure,
but it's like stuff like that.
So your simulation is just not going to
match reality.
There'll be some resemblance,
but that's it.
How can we address this problem?
And I wanted to show you one simple
idea.
So let's say one thing.
What's one thing that would be nice is
that if you could learn a policy,
learn a policy that will quickly adapt
itself to the real world.
Well,
if you want to learn a policy that can
quickly adapt,
we need to make sure that it has
opportunities to adapt you in training
time.
So what do we do?
Instead of solving a problem in just one
simulator,
we add a huge amount of variability to
the simulator.
We say we will randomize the friction so
we will randomize the masses,
the length of the different objects and
their I guess and dimensions.
So you tried to randomize physics,
the simulator and lots of different
ways,
and then importantly you don't tell the
policy how we randomized it,
so what is it going to do?
Then you'll take your policy and you put
it in an environment.
Then says,
well,
this is really,
really tough.
I don't know what the masses are and I
don't know what the frictions are.
I need to try things out and figure out
where the friction is.
As I get responses from the environment.
So you build it,
you learn a certain degree of
adaptability into the policy and it
actually works.
I just want to show you,
this is what happens when you just
straight up policy in simulation and
deployed on the physical robots and here
the goal is to bring the hockey puck
towards the red dots and you will see
that it will struggle
and there isn't it struggles is because
of the systematic differences between
the simulator and the real physical
Robert.
So I could even the basic movement is
difficult for the policy because the
assumptions of allocated so much.
So if you do the training,
as I discussed,
we train the recurrent neural network
policy which learns to quickly infor
properties of the simulator in order to
accomplish the task.
You can give it to the real thing,
the real physics and it will do much
better.
Now this is not a perfect technique,
but it's definitely very promising.
It's promising whenever you are able to
sufficiently randomized simulator.
So he's definitely very nice to see the
closed loop nature of the policy.
You consider that it would push the
hockey puck and he would correct it
very,
very gently to bring into the goal so
that,
that was cool.
So that was very,
uh,
that,
that was a cool application of metal
learning.
I want to discuss one more application
of Methadone,
which is learning the hierarchy of
actions.
And this was working with and by France
at all.
Actually I'm Kevin France or the
intranasal did.
It wasn't high school.
I mean he wrote this paper.
So
one thing that would be nice is if
reinforcement learning was hierarchical,
if instead of simply taking my
corrections,
you had some kind of util sub routines
that you could deploy.
Maybe the term sub routine is a little
bit too crude,
but if you had some idea of which action
primitives are,
we're starting to now no one has been
able to get actually like real value add
from curriculum reinforcement learning.
Yet so far all the really cool results
or that really convincing is also
reinforcement learning does not use it.
That's because we haven't quite figured
out what's the right way for
reinforcement learning.
Reinforcement learning.
I just want to show you one very simple
approach where you use metal learning to
learn to the hierarchy of actions.
So here's what you do.
You have in this specific work,
you have a certain yellow,
let's say you have a certain number of
low level primitive,
so let's say you have to of them and you
have a distribution of tasks and your
goal is to learn low level primitives
such that when they are used inside a
very brief run of some reinforcement
learning algorithm,
it will make as much progress as
possible.
So the idea is you want to get the
greatest amount of progress.
You want to learn policies that result
in the great.
Sorry.
You want to learn primitives the result
in the greatest amount of progress
possible when used inside learning.
So this is a mental learning center
because any distribution of tasks,
and here we've had before,
we've had a little maze,
he have a distribution of amazes and in
this case and the little bug learned
three policies which morbid in speaks to
direction.
And as a result of having this
hierarchy,
you are able to solve problems really
fast,
but only when the hierarchies correct.
So correct.
Called reinforcement learning is still a
work in progress.
And this was in this work is an
interesting proof point of how
curricular reinforcement would be like.
Hi,
how correct.
Called reinforcement learning could be
like if it worked now I wanted to just
spend one slide addressing the
limitations of high capacity method
learning.
The specific limitation is that
the training task distribution has to be
equal to the test task distribution and
I think this is a real limitation
because in reality you the new task that
you want to learn to in some ways being
fundamentally different from anything
you've seen so far.
So for example,
if you go to school,
you learn lots of useful things,
but then when you go to work,
only a fraction of this,
of the things that you've learned
carries over.
Can you need to learn if he wouldn't
have quite a few more things from
scratch.
So madeloni would struggle with that
because it really assumes that the
training,
the training data is the distribution
over the training task has to be equals
with distribution over the test asks.
That's the limitation,
the thing that as we develop better
algorithms for being robust when the
test tasks outside of the distribution
of the training desk than metal and got
much better.
Now I want to talk about self play
thing.
Self plays a very cool topic that's
starting to get attention only now and I
want to start by reviewing very old work
cold td Gammon.
It's back from the older way from 1992.
So 26 years old now.
It was done by Jerry to Sarah.
So this work is really incredible
because it has so much relevance today.
What they did basically they said,
okay,
let's take two neural networks and lets
them let them play against each other,
let them play backgammon against each
other and let them try.
Let them be trained with culinary.
So it's a super modern approach and you
would think this was a paper from 2017
except with you look at the splots.
It shows that you only have 10 hidden
units,
20 hidden units,
40 and 84.
The difference in colors where you
noticed that the largest neural network
works best,
so in some ways not much has changed and
this is the evidence and in fact they
were able to beat the world champion and
backgammon and they were able to
discover new strategies that the best
human,
a backgammon players weren't a have not
noticed and they've determined that the
strategy is covered,
but ed gamut actually better.
So that's pure stuff.
Play with cue learning which is which
remained dormant until the Deq and work
with Atari Buddy of mine.
So now other examples of self blame
include Alphago Zero,
which was able to learn to beat the
world champion in go without using any
external data whatsoever.
And other results of this vein is by
open ai,
which is our daughter to bought,
which was able to build the world
champion on the one,
the one version of the game.
And so I want to spend a little bit of
time talking about the allure of self
play and why I think it's exciting.
So one important problem,
that's it,
that's the must face as we try to build
truly intelligent systems is what is the
task,
what are we actually teaching the
systems to do,
and one very attractive attribute of
self is that the agents create the
environment by virtue of the agent
acting in the environment.
The environment becomes difficult for
the other agents and you can see here an
example of an iguana interacting with
snakes,
the try to eat it on successfully this
time so we can see what will happen in a
moment.
The Guan Australian's best and so the
fact that you have this arms race
between the snakes and the iguanas
motivates their development potentially
without bound and this is what happened
in effective but in biological
evolution.
Now,
interesting work in this direction was
done in 1994,
but Carl,
since there is a really cool video on
youtube by Carl scenes,
you should check it out,
which really kind of shows all the work
that he's done.
And here you have a little competition
between agents where you evolve both the
behavior and their morphology.
When you Walkman,
the agents is trying to gain possession
of a green cube and so you can see that
the agents create the challenge for each
other and that's why they need to
develop.
So one thing that we deed and this is
work by and sell it up from open ai is
we said,
okay,
well can be demonstrates some unusual
results in self play that would really
convince us that there is something
there.
So what we did here is that we created a
small,
a small ring and you have these two
humanoid figures and their goal is just
to push each other outside the ring and
they don't know anything about
wrestling.
They don't know anything about standing
or balancing each other.
They don't know anything about centrals
gravity.
All they know is that if you don't do a
good job,
then your competition is going to do a
better job.
Now,
one of the really attractive things
about self play is that you always have
an opponent that's roughly as good as
you are.
In order to learn,
you need to sometimes in and sometimes
lose,
like you can't always win.
Sometimes you must fail,
sometimes you must succeed,
so let's see what will happen here.
Yeah,
so it was able to be so the green human
was able to block the ball in a so in a
well balanced environment.
The competition is always level.
No matter how good you are or how bad
you are,
you have a competition that makes it
exactly,
exactly have exactly the right challenge
for you in one thing here.
So this with your shows,
transfer learning,
you take the little wrestling humanoid
and you take its friend away and you
start applying a big,
large random forces on it and you see if
it can maintain its balance and the
answer turns out to be that yes it can
because it's been trained against an
opponent,
it pushes it and so that's why even if
it's doesn't understand where the
pressure forces being applied on it,
it's still able to balance itself.
So this is one potentially attractive
feature of software environments.
The QTC would learn a certain broad set
of skills,
although it's a little hard to control
those with the skills will be.
And so the biggest open question with
this research is how do you learn agents
in a software environment such that they
do whatever they do,
but then they are able to solve a
battery of tasks that is useful for us
that is explicitly specified externally.
Yeah.
I also want to want to highlight one
attribute of self play environments that
people observed in our daughter bought
and that is that you've seen a very
rapid increase in the competence of the
Bot.
So over the period over the course of
maybe five months,
we've seen the bottom go from playing
totally randomly all the way to the
world champion.
And the reason for that is that once you
have a self clean environment,
if you put computing into it,
you turn it into data.
Self play allows you to turn compute
into data and I think we will see a lot
more of that as being an extremely
important thing to be able to turn
compute into essentially data
generalization simply because the speed
of neural net processors will increased
very dramatically over the next few
years.
So neural net cycles will be cheap and
it will be important to make use of this
new,
of newly found over abundance of cycles.
I also wanted to talk a little bit about
the end game of the self blame approach.
So one thing that we know about the
human brain is that it has increased in
size fairly rapidly over the past 2
million years.
My theory,
the reason I think it happened is
because our ancestors got to a point
where the thing that's most important
for your survival is your standing in
the tribe and less the tiger and the
lion.
Once the most important thing is how you
deal with those other things which have
a large brain.
Then it really helps to have a slightly
larger brain.
And I think that's what happened and
that exists at least one paper from
science which supports this point of
view.
So apparently there has been convergent
evolution between social apps and social
birds even though in terms of various
behaviors,
even though the divergence in
evolutionary timescale between humans
and birds as occurred a very long time
ago,
and humans and humans,
apes and humans,
apes and birds have very different brain
structure.
So I think what should happen if we
succeed,
if we successfully follow the path of
this approach,
is that we should create a society of
agents which will have language and
theory of mind negotiation,
social skills,
trade economy,
politics and justice system.
All these things should happen inside
the multiagent environment and it will
also be some alignment issue of how do
you make sure that the agents we learn
behave innovative,
want.
Now,
I want to make speculative digression
here,
which is I want to make the following
observations.
If you believe that this kind of society
of agents is a plausible place where
truly where the full fully general
intelligence will emerge and if you
accept that our experience with Dota
both where we've seen a very rapid
increase in competence,
will carry over once all the details are
right.
If you assume both of these conditions,
then it should follow that we should see
a very rapid increase in the competence
of our agents as they live in the
society of agents.
So now that we've talked about
potentially interesting way of
increasing the competence and teaching
teaching social skills and language and
a lot of things that actually exist in
humans as well.
We want to talk a little bit about how
you convey goals to Asians and the
question of conveying goal to eight
calls to agents.
It's just a technical problem,
but it will be important because it is
more likely than not that the agents
that people train will eventually be
dramatically smarter than us.
And this is work by,
um,
are they opening a safety team by Paul
Cristiana at all and others.
So I'm just going to show you this video
which basically explains how the whole
thing works.
You there is some behavior looking for
and you the human gets to see pairs of
behaviors and you simply click on the
one that looks better and after a very
modest number of clicks,
you can get this little simulated leg to
do backflips.
There you go.
He can now do backflips and in this to
get this specific behavior,
it took about 500 clicks by human
annotators.
The way it works is that you take all
the,
so this is a very data efficient
reinforcement learning algorithm,
but it is efficient in terms of rewards
and not in terms of the environment
interactions.
So what you do here is that you take all
the clicks,
so you've got your here is one here,
which is better than the other.
You fit a reward function and numerical
reward function to those.
So you want to fit a reward function
which satisfies those cleats clicks,
and then you optimize this reward
function with reinforcement learning and
it actually works.
So this requires 500 bits of
information.
We've also been able to train him lots
of Atari Games using several thousand
bits of information.
So in all these cases you had human,
a human annotators or human judges just
like in the previous slide,
looking at the pairs of trajectories and
clicking on the one that they thought
was better and here's an example of an
unusual goal where this is a car racing
game,
but the goal was to ask the agent to
train the white car drive right behind
the orange car.
So it's a different goal and it was very
straightforward to communicate this goal
using this approach.
So then to finish off alignment is a
technical problem.
It has to be solved,
but of course the determination of the
correct goals we want our systems to
have.
You'll be a very challenging political
problem.
And on this note,
I want to thank you so much for your
attention and I just want to say that it
will be a happy hour at Cambridge
brewing company.
40th five.
If you want to chat more about Ai and
other topics,
please come by.
I think that deserves an applause.
Thank you.
So my population is a neural networks at
buyer inspired,
but backpropagation doesn't look as
though it's what's going on in the brain
because signals in the brain go one
direction down the excellence where as
back propagation requires the areas to
be publicated backup the wires.
So can you just talk a little bit about
that whole situation where it looks like
the greatest doing something a bit
different than our highest successful
algorithms algorithm is going to be
improved once we figure out what the
brain is doing or what is the brain
sending signals back even though it's
got no obvious way of doing that.
What's what's happening in that area?
So that's a great question.
So first of all,
I'll say that the true answer is that
the honest answer is that I don't know,
but I have opinions.
And so I'll say two things.
First of all,
given that like if you agree,
if me agreed.
So rather it is a true fact.
Backpropagation solves the problem of
circuit search.
This problem feels like an extremely
fundamental problem.
And for this reason I think that it's
unlikely to go away.
Now you also right that the brain
doesn't obviously do backpropagation,
although they've been in multiple
proposals of how it could be,
how it could be doing them,
for example,
there's been a work by and others where
they've shown that if you use that,
it's possible to learn a different set
of connections that can be used for the
backward pass and that can result in
successful learning.
Now the reason this hasn't been really
pushed to the limit by practitioners is
because they say,
well,
I got tf the gradients.
I'm just not going to worry about it,
but you're right that this is an
important issue and you know,
one of two things is going to happen.
So my personal opinion is that
backpropagation is just going to stay
with us til the very end and we'll
actually build fully human level and
beyond systems before we understand how
the brain does what it does.
So that's what I believe,
but of course it is a difference that
has to be acknowledged.
Do you think it was a fair match up for
the Dota bought and that person given
the constraints of the system?
So I'd say that the biggest advantage
computers having games like this,
like one of the big advantages is that
they obviously have a better reaction
time.
Although in Dota in particular the
number of clicks per second over the top
players is fairly small,
which is different from starcraft.
Starcraft,
starcraft is a very mechanically heavy
game because if a large number of units
and so the top players,
they just click all the time.
In Dota,
every player controls just one hero and
so that greatly reduces the total number
of actions they need to make.
Now still precision matters.
I think that we'll discover that later,
but I think will really happen is if you
will discover that computers have the
advantage in any domain or rather every
domain.
Not yet.
Do you think that the emergent behaviors
from the agent we're actually kind of
directed because the constraints are
already kind of in place.
Like so it was kinda forced discover
those or do you think that like that was
actually something quite novel that like
wow,
it actually discovered these on its own.
Like you didn't actually have bias
towards constraining it.
So it's definitely need discover new
strategies and I can share an anecdote
where our tester,
we have a prohibition,
would test the Bot and he played against
it for a long time and the bottom will
do all kinds of things against the
player,
the human player which were effective.
Then at some point that pro decided to
play against the better flow pro and he
decided to imitate one of the things
that they both was doing and this image.
But by imitating it,
he was able to defeat a better pro.
So I think,
I think the strategies to discoveries
are real and so like it means that
there's very little transport,
but you know,
I would say I think what that means is
that because the strategy's discovered
by the bulk of the humans,
it means that the fundamental game plays
the deeply related for,
for
a long time now I've heard that the
objective of reinforcement learning is
to determine policy
that chooses an action to maximize the
expected reward,
which is what you said earlier.
Would you ever want to look at the
standard deviation of possible rewards?
Does that even make sense?
Yeah,
I mean I think for sure,
I think it's really application
dependent,
one of the reasons to maximize the
expected reward just because it's easier
to design algorithms for it.
So you write down this equation of the
formula,
you do a little bit of derivation,
you get something which amounts to a
nice looking algorithm.
Now I think there exists like really
their existing applications where you'd
never want to make mistakes and you
wanna work on the standard deviation as
well.
But in practice it seems that the,
just looking at the expected reward
covers a large fraction of the situation
is you'd like to apply this to.
Okay,
thanks.
Cam.
Um,
we talked last week about motivations,
um,
and that has a lot to do with the
reinforcement and some of the ideas is
that the,
uh,
our motivations are actually connection
with others and cooperation and I'm
wondering if there through enough,
and I understand it's very popular to
have the computers play these
competitive games.
Um,
but is there any use in like having an
agent self play collaboratively
collaborative games?
Yeah,
I think that's an extremely good
question.
I think one place from which we can get
some inspiration is from the evolution
of cooperation.
I think cooperation be cooperate
ultimately because it's much better for
you,
the person to be cooperative or not.
And so I think what should happen if you
have a sufficiently open-ended game
incorporation of it will be the winning
strategy.
And so I think we will get cooperation
whether it be like it or not.
Hi.
Um,
you mentioned the complexity of the
simulation of friction.
I was wondering if you feel that there
exist open complexity theoretic problems
relevant to relevant to ai or whether
it's just a matter of finding good
approximations that humans have,
the types of problems that humans tend
to solve?
Yeah.
So complexity theory.
Well,
like at the very basic level,
we know that whatever algorithm we're
going to run,
he's going to run fairly efficiently on
some hardware.
So that puts a pretty strict upper bound
and the true complexity of the problems
you're solving,
like by definition,
via solving problems which aren't too
hard in complexity theoretic sense.
Now it is also the case that many of the
problems.
So while the overall thing that we do is
not hard from a complexity theoretic
sense and indeed humans cannot solve and
be complete problems in general,
it is true that many of the like
optimization problems that we pose to
our algorithms are in intractable in the
general case,
starting from neural net optimization
itself,
it is easy to create a family of
datasets for a neural network with a
very small number of neurons such that
find the global optimum is not complete.
And so how do we avoid it?
Well,
we just try grading dissent anyway and
somehow it works,
but without question like we cannot,
we do not solve problems which are truly
intractable.
So I mean I have the sense of the
question.
Hello.
It seems like an important sub problem
on the path towards Agi will be
understanding language.
And the state of generative language
modeling right now is pretty abysmal.
What do you think are the most
productive research trajectories towards
generative language models?
So I'll first say that you are
completely correct that the situation
with language is still far from great.
Although progress has been made,
even without any particular innovations
beyond models that exist today,
simply scaling up models that exist
today on larger data sets is going to go
surprisingly far,
not even larger datasets,
but larger and deeper models.
For example,
if you train a language model with a
thousand layers and it's the same layer,
I think it's going to be a pretty
amazing language model like we don't
have the cycles for week yet,
but to think it will change very soon.
Now.
I also agree with you that there are
some fundamental things missing in our
current understanding of deep learning
which prevent us from really solving the
problem that we want.
So I think one of these problems,
one of the things that's missing is
that,
or that seems like blatantly wrong,
is the fact that we train a model and
then you stop training the model and you
freeze it.
Even though it's the training process
for the magic really happens of the
magic is if you think about it,
like the training process is the true
general part of the whole,
of the whole of the whole story.
Because you're tends to flow code
doesn't care what your data set to
optimize.
He just says whatever,
just give me the data set,
I don't care which one solve also the
mall.
So like the ability to do that feels
really special and I think we are not
using it at test time.
It gets hard to speculate about like
things you don't know the answer,
but all I'll say is that simply train
bigger,
deeper language models.
They'll go surprisingly far scaling out,
but also doing things like training or
test stamina in,
for instance,
time.
I think it will be another important
boosts the performance.
Hi.
Thank you for the talk.
Um,
so it seems like right now another
interesting approach to solving
reinforcement learning problems could be
to go for the evolutionary evolutionary
strategies and although they have their
caveats,
I wanted to know if I'd open ai
particularly you're working on something
related and what are,
what is your general opinion on them?
So like at present,
I believe that something like
evolutionary strategies is another great
for reinforcement learning.
I think that normal reinforcement
learning algorithms,
especially if it's big policies a
better,
but I think if you want to evolve a
small compact object like like a piece
of code for example,
I think that would be a place where it's
gonna be a seriously worth considering,
but this,
you know,
you've all been a useful piece of code
is a cool idea.
Hasn't been done yet,
so still a lot of work to be done.
Before we get there.
Hi.
Thank you so much for coming.
My question is,
you mentioned what is the right goal is
a political problem,
so I'm wondering if you can elaborate a
bit on that and it also,
what do you think would be the approach
for us to maybe get.
Well?
Again,
I can't really comment too much because
all the thoughts that we have.
You now have a few people who are
thinking about this full time at open
Ai.
I don't have enough of this super strong
opinion to say anything too definitive.
All I can say at the very high level
isn't given the size.
Like if you go into the future,
whenever soon or whenever it's going to
happen,
when you build a computer,
which can do anything better than a
human,
it's will happen because the brain is
physical,
being picked on society is going to be
completely massive and overwhelming.
It's very difficult to imagine even if
you try really hard.
And I think what it means is that people
do care a lot and that's what I was
alluding to,
the fact that this will be something
that many people who care about strongly
and like as the impact increases
gradually be self driving cars,
more automation,
I think we will see a lot more people
care.
Do we need to have a very accurate model
of the physical world and then simulate
that in order to have,
uh,
these agents that can eventually come
out into the real world and do something
approaching,
you know,
human level intelligence tasks.
That's a very good question.
So I think if that were the case,
we'd be in trouble and I am very certain
that it could be avoided.
So specifically,
the real answer has to be that look,
you learn to problem solve,
we learned to negotiate,
you learn to persist,
you know,
lots of different useful life lessons in
the simulation and yes,
you learn some physics too,
but I ain't go outside to the real world
and you have to start over to some
extent because many of your deeply held
assumptions will be false and amount of
the goals,
so that's one of the reasons I care so
much about never stopped in training.
You've accumulated your knowledge.
Now we go into an environment for some
of your assumptions of let you continued
training.
We tried to connect the new data to your
old data and this is an important
requirement from our algorithms,
which is already met to some extent,
but it will have to be met a lot more so
that you can take the partial knowledge
is required and go to a new situation,
learn some more.
Literally the example of you go to
school alone,
learn useful things,
then you go to work.
It's not perfect.
It's not.
You know,
you pull your four years of cs in
Undergrad is not going to fully prepare
you for whatever it is you need to know
how to work.
It will help somewhat.
You'll be able to get off the ground,
but there will be lots of new things you
need to learn.
So that's,
that's the spirit of it.
I think of those,
of the school,
one of the things you mentioned pretty
early on in your talk is that one of the
limitations of this sort of style of
reinforcement learning is there is no
self organization so you have to tell it
went into the good thing or is it a bad
thing and that's actually a problem in
neuroscience as well and you're trying
to teach a rat to,
you know,
navigate a maze.
You have to artificially tell it what to
do.
So where do you see moving forward when
we already have this problem with
teaching,
you know,
not necessarily learning but also
teaching.
So where do you see the research moving
forward in that respect?
How do you sort of introduce this notion
of self organization?
So I think without question one really
important thing you need to do is to be
able to infer the goals and strategies
of other agents by observing them.
That's a fundamental skill we need to be
able to learn to,
to embed into the agents.
So if,
for example,
we have two agents,
one of them is doing something and the
other agents says,
well that's really cool.
I want to be able to do that too,
and then you go on and do that.
And so I'd say that this is a very
important component in terms of setting
the reward of you see what they do,
you further reward and now we have a
knob which says you see what they're
doing now go and try to do the same
thing.
So let's say this,
this is as far as I,
as far as I know,
this was one of the important ways in
which humans are quite different from
other animals in the way which in the
scale and scope in which we copy the
behavior of other humans
mind.
If I ask a quick followup or go for it.
So that's kind of obvious how that works
in this scope of competition,
but what about just sort of arbitrary
tasks like I'm in a math class with
someone and I see someone doing a
problem in a particular way and I'm
like,
oh that's a good strategy.
Maybe I should try that out.
How does that work in a sort of non
competitive environment?
So I think that this movie,
I think that that's going to be a little
bit separate from the competitive
environment,
but it will have to be somehow either
bake,
probably baked in,
maybe evolved into the system where if
you have other agents doing things,
they're generating data which you and
the only way to truly make sense of the
data that you see used to infer the goal
of the agent to strategy their beliefs
state.
That's important also for communicating
with them.
If you want to successfully communicate
with someone,
you have to keep track both of their
goal and their beliefs state instead of
knowledge.
So I think people find that there are
many,
I guess connections between
understanding what other agents are
doing,
inferring their goals,
imitating them and community
successfully communicating them.
Alright,
let's give Eylea and the happy hour
hand.
Thank you.