Welcome to mit course six zero nine,
nine artificial general intelligence.
Today we have ray Kurzweil.
He is one of the world's leading
inventors,
thinkers and futurists with a 30 year
track record of accurate predictions
called the restless genius by the Wall
Street Journal and the ultimate thinking
machine by Forbes magazine.
He was selected as one of the top
entrepreneurs by ink magazine,
which described him as the rightful heir
to Thomas Edison.
PBS selected him as one of the 16
revolutionaries who made America.
Ray was the principal investigator of
the first CCD flatbed scanner,
the first Omni font optical character
recognition,
the first point to speech reading
machine for the blind,
the first text to speech synthesizer,
the first music synthesizer capable of
recreating the grand piano and other
orchestra instruments,
and the first commercially marketed
large vocabulary speech recognition.
Among his many honors,
he received a Grammy Award for
outstanding achievements in music
technology.
He's the recipient of the National Medal
of Technology,
was inducted into the national inventors
hall of fame,
holds 21 honorary doctorates,
and honors from three US presidents.
Ray has written five national
bestselling books including the New York
Times bestsellers.
The singularity is near from 2005 and
how to create a mind from 2012.
He's Co founder and Chancellor of
Singularity University and a director of
engineering at Google.
Heading up a team developing machine
intelligence and natural language
understanding.
Please give a warm welcome.
It's good to be back.
I've been in this lecture hall many
times and walked the infinite Carter.
I came here as an undergraduate in 1965.
Within a year of my being here,
they started a new major called computer
science.
It did not get its own course number.
It's six one.
Even biotechnology recently got its own
course number,
but how many of you are cs majors?
Okay.
How many of you do work in deep
learning?
How many of you have heard of deep
I came here first in 1962 when I was 14.
I became excited about artificial
intelligence.
It it had only gotten its name six years
earlier,
the 1956 dartmouth conference by Marvin
Minsky and John Mccarthy,
so I wrote a Minsky,
a letter.
There was no email back then and he
invited me up.
He spent all day with me,
is if he had nothing else to do,
he was the consummate educator.
I then,
and uh,
the AI field had already bifurcated into
two warring camps,
the symbolic school which Minsky was
associated with a.
and the connectionist school,
uh,
was not widely known.
In fact,
I think it's still not widely known that
minsky actually invented the neural net
in 1953,
but he had become negative about.
It's largely because there's a lot of
hype that these giant brains could solve
any problem.
So the first popular neural nets,
the perceptron was being promulgated by
Frank Rosenblatt at Cornell.
So minsky says,
where are you going now?
And saying,
I said to c Rosenblatt at Cornell is
that,
don't bother doing that.
And I went there and Rosenblatt was
touting the perceptron that had
ultimately would be able to solve any
problem.
So I brought some printed letters that
had the camera and it did a perfect job
of recognizing them as long as they were
carrier 10 different type style.
Didn't work at all.
And he said,
but don't worry,
we can take the output of the perceptron
undefeated as the input to another
perceptron and take the output of that
and feed it to a third layer,
and as we add more layers,
it'll get smarter and smarter and
generalize.
And so that's interesting.
Have you tried that?
Well,
no,
but it's high in our research agenda.
Things did not move quite as quickly
back then as they do now.
He died nine years later.
Never having tried that idea turns out
to be remarkably prescient.
I mean he never tried multilayer neural
nets and all the excitement that we've
seen now about deep learning comes from
a combination of two things,
both many layer neural nets and the law
of accelerating returns,
which I'll get to a little bit later,
which is basically the exponential
growth of computing so that we can run
these massive nets and handle massive
amounts of data.
It would be decades before that idea was
tried several decades later,
the three level neural nets were tried.
There were a little bit better.
They could deal with multiple types.
Styles still weren't very flexible.
That's not hard to add other layers.
It's a very straightforward concept.
Uh,
there was a math problem,
a,
the disappearing gradient or the
exploding gradient,
which I'm sure many of you are familiar
with.
Basically,
you need to take maximum advantage of
the range of values,
uh,
in the gradients,
not let them disappear.
And a loser resolution,
a,
that's a fairly straightforward
mathematical transformation.
With that insight,
we could now go to 100 layer neural nets
and s that's behind sort of all the
fantastic gains that we've seen
recently.
A alpha go,
a trained on every online game and then
became a fair go player and then trained
itself by playing itself and soared past
the best human alphago.
Zero started with no human input at all,
within hours of iteration,
soared past Alphago.
Uh,
also sort past the best chest programs
that had another innovation.
Uh,
basically you need to evaluate the
quality of the board at each point.
And they used a,
another 100 layer neural nets to do that
evaluation.
Um,
so there's still a problem in the field,
uh,
which is there's a motto that life
begins at a billion examples.
One of the reasons I'm at Google is we
have a billion examples,
for example,
does have pictures of dogs and cats that
are labeled.
So you've got a picture of a cat and it
says cat and then you can learn from it
and you need a lot of them,
a Alphago trained on a million online
moves.
That's how many we had of master games
and that only created a,
a sort of fair go player.
A good amateur could defeat it.
So they worked around that in the case
of goal by basically generating an
infinite amount of data by having the
system play itself,
uh,
had a chat with Dennis Hassabis.
What kind of situations can you do that
with?
You have to have some way of simulating
the world.
So go or chess or even though go is
considered a difficult game,
it's a,
you know,
the definition of it is exists on one
page,
uh,
so you can simulate it.
A,
that applies to math.
I mean,
mass axioms are going to be contained on
a page or two.
It's not very complicated.
Uh,
it gets more difficult when you have
real life situations like biology,
so we have biological simulators,
but the simulators on perfect,
so learning from the simulators will
only be as good as the simulators.
That's actually the key to being able to
do deep learning on biology.
Autonomous Vehicles.
You need real life data.
Uh,
so the waymo systems have gone three and
a half million miles.
Uh,
that's good.
That's enough data to then create a very
good simulator.
The simulator is really quite realistic
because they had a lot of real world
experience and the,
they've got a billion miles in the
simulator,
but we don't always have that
opportunity to either create the data or
have the data around humans can learn
from a small number of examples.
Uh,
your significant other,
your professor,
your boss,
your investor a can tell you something
once or twice and you might actually
learn from that.
Some humans have been reported to do
that.
And,
uh,
that's,
that's kind of the remaining advantage
of humans.
Now.
There's actually no backpropagation and
the human brain,
it doesn't use deep learning.
It uses a different architecture that
same year in 1962 or older paper,
how I thought the human brain worked.
Uh,
there was actually very little
neuroscience to go on.
There was one neuro science test,
Vernon mountcastle.
It had something relevant to say,
which he did.
I mean,
there was a,
the common wisdom at the time,
and there's still a lot of neuroscience
instead say this.
So we have all these different regions
of the brain.
They do different things.
They must be different than v one in the
back of the head where the optic nerve
skills into that can tell that that's a
curved line.
That's a straight line.
Does a simple feature extractions on
visual images.
It's actually a large part of the
neocortex does a cruciform gyrus up
here,
which can recognize faces.
Uh,
we know that because if it gets knocked
out through injury or stroke,
people can't recognize faces.
They will learn it again with a
different region of the neocortex is the
famous frontal Cortex,
which does language and poetry and
music.
Uh,
so these must work on different
principles.
He did autopsies on the neocortex and
all these different regions and found
they all look the same.
They had the same repeating pattern,
same interconnections.
Uh,
he said Neocortex is neocortex.
So I had that hint.
Otherwise I could actually observe human
brains and action,
which I did from time to time.
And there's a lot of hints that you can
get that way.
For example,
if I ask you to recite the alphabet,
you actually don't do it from a to z,
you do it as a sequence of sequences a,
two.
We learn things as forward sequences of
sequences forward because if I ask you
to recite the alphabet backwards,
you can't do it unless you learn that as
a new sequence.
So these are all interesting.
Hence I wrote a paper that I,
that the Neocortex is organized as a
hierarchy of modules and each module can
learn to simple pattern and that's how I
got to meet President Johnson.
And that initiated a half century of
thinking about issue.
I came to mit to study with Marvin
Minsky.
Actually,
I came for two reasons.
Once Minsky became my mentor,
which was the mentorship that lasted for
over 50 years,
the fact that mit was so advanced and
actually had a computer,
which the other colleges I considered
didn't have a.
It was an IBM 70,
94,
32 K of 36 fit words.
So it's 150 k of core storage to
microsecond cycle time to cycles for
instruction.
So a quarter of a map and that thousands
of students and professors share that
one machine in 2012.
I wrote a book about this thesis is now
actually an explosion of neuroscience
evidence to support it.
The European brain reverse engineering
project has identified or repeating
module of about 100 neurons,
repeated it $300 million times.
So it's about $30 billion neurons in the
NEOCORTEX.
The neocortex is the outer layer of the
brain.
That's part where we do our thinking,
uh,
and they can see in each module,
axons coming in from another,
a module,
and then the output acts,
the single output accident of that
module goes as the input to another
module.
So we can see it organized as a
hierarchy.
It's not a physical hierarchy.
The hierarchy comes from these
connections.
The neocortex is a very thin structure.
It's actually one module thick,
the six layers of neurons,
but it constitutes one module.
And we can see that it learns and simple
pattern and various reasons I cite in
the book the pattern recognition model
that's using is basically a hidden
Markov model.
How many of you have worked with mark
off models?
And that's usually no hands go up when I
asked that question.
Um,
but a Markov model is not.
It is learned a,
but it's not backpropagation.
It can learn local features.
So it's very good for speech recognition
and speech recognition.
I work,
I did in the eighties,
used these mark models that became the
standard approach because it can deal
with local variations.
So the fact that a vow will is
stretched.
It can learn that in a Markov model,
it doesn't learn long distance
relationships that's handled by the
hierarchy and something we don't fully
understand yet is exactly how the
neocortex creates that hierarchy.
But we have figured out how I can
connect this module two,
this module,
does it then grow?
I mean,
there's no virtual communication or
wireless communication.
It's actually a connection.
So does it grow and Axon in are from one
place to another which could be inches
apart.
Uh,
actually they all,
all these connections are there from
birth,
uh,
like the streets and avenues of
Manhattan,
this vertical and horizontal connection.
So if the decides and how it makes that
decision is still not fully understood
that it wants to connect this module
two,
this module,
there's already a vertical,
horizontal and a vertical connection.
It just activates them.
We can actually see that now and could
see that happening in real time on
noninvasive brain scans.
Uh,
so this utterance amount of evidence
that in fact the neocortex is a
hierarchy of modules that can learn.
Each module learns so simple sequential
pattern.
And even though the patterns we perceive
don't seem like sequences,
they may seem three dimensional or even
more complicated.
They are in fact represented,
uh,
as sequences.
But the complexity comes in with the
hierarchy.
So the NEOCORTEX emerged 200 million
years ago,
uh,
with mammals.
All mammals have a neocortex.
It's one of the distinguishing features
of mammals.
These first mammals were small.
They were rodents where they were
capable of a new type of thinking.
Uh,
other nonmelanoma animals had fixed
behaviors,
but those fixed behaviors were very well
adapted for their ecological niche.
But these new mammals could invent a new
behavior.
So creativity and innovation was one
feature of the NEOCORTEX.
So analysis,
escaping a predator,
it's usual.
Escape Path is blocked.
It will invent a new behavior to deal
with.
It probably wouldn't work,
but if it did work,
it would remember it.
And we'd have a new behavior and that
behavior could spread virally through
the community.
Another mouse watching this say to
itself,
that was really clever going around that
rock,
I'm going to remember to do that.
Uh,
and it would have a new behavior.
Didn't help these early mammals that
much because as I say,
the Mammalian and animals who were very
well adapted to their niches and nothing
much happened for $135 million years,
but then 65 million years ago something
did happened,
there was a sudden violent change to the
environment.
We now call it the cretaceous extinction
event.
There's been debate as to whether it was
a immediate or an asteroid.
I mean a media or a volcanic eruption.
A the asteroid or media or hypothesis is
in the ascendancy.
But if you dig down to an area of rock
reflecting 65 million years ago,
the geologist will explain that it shows
a very violent sudden change to the
environment.
And we see it all around the globe.
So it was a worldwide phenomenon.
The reason we call it an extinction
event is that's when the dinosaurs went
extinct.
Uh,
that's when 75 percent of all the animal
and plant species went extinct.
And that's when mammals overtook their
ecological niche.
So to anthropomorphize,
biological evolution said to itself,
hmm,
this neocortex is pretty good stuff.
And it began to grow it.
So now mammals got bigger,
their brains got bigger at an even
faster pace,
taking up a larger fraction of their
body.
The neocortex got bigger even faster
than that.
And developed these curvatures that are
distinctive,
have a primate brain basically to
increase its surface area.
But if you stretched it out,
uh,
the human neocortex is still a flat
structure.
It's about the size of a table,
Napkin justice thin,
uh,
and uh,
it's basically,
uh,
created a primates which became dominant
in their ecological niche.
A then something else happened 2 million
years ago.
And biological evolution decided to
increase the neocortex further and
increase the size of the enclosure and
basically filled up the frontal cortex,
uh,
with our big skulls,
with more neocortex.
And up until recently,
it was felt that,
as I said,
that this was,
the frontal cortex was different because
it does these qualitatively different
things.
But we now realized that it's really
just additional neocortex.
So remember what we did with it.
We were already doing a very good job of
being primates.
So we put it at the top of the
neocortical hierarchy.
And we increased the size of the
hierarchy,
it was maybe 20 percent more neocortex,
but it doubled and tripled the number of
levels because as you go up the
hierarchy,
it's kind of like a pyramid.
There's fewer and fewer modules and that
was the enabling factor for us to invent
language and art.
Music.
Every human culture we've ever
discovered has music.
No primate culture has music.
There's debate about that,
but it's really true.
Invention technology,
a technology required another
evolutionary adaptation,
which is this humble appendage here.
Uh,
no other animal has add.
If you look at a chimpanzee,
it looks like they have a similar hand,
but the thumb is actually down here.
It doesn't work very well if you watch
them trying to grab a stick a so we
could imagine creative solutions.
Yeah.
I could take that branch and strip off
the leaves and put a point on it and we
could actually carry out these ideas and
create tools and then use tools to
create new tools and started a whole
nother evolutionary process of tool
making.
And that all came with the,
with the NEOCORTEX.
So Larry Page read my book a 2012 and
liked it,
so I met with him in essence for an
investment in a company I'd started
actually a couple of weeks earlier to
develop those ideas commercially because
that's how I went about things as a
serial entrepreneur and he said,
well,
we'll invest,
but let me give you a better idea.
Why don't you do it here at Google,
we have a billion pictures of dogs and
cats and we got a lot of other data and
lots of computers and lots of talents,
all of which is true.
And says,
well,
I don't know.
I just started this company,
uh,
to develop this as well by your company
and said,
Hey,
are you going to value a company that
hasn't done anything?
And just started a couple of weeks ago
and he said we can value anything.
Uh,
so I took my first job five years ago
and had been basically applying this
model,
this hierarchical model,
um,
to understanding language,
which I think really is the holy grail
of Ai.
I think touring was correct in
designating basically text communication
as well.
We now call a turing complete problem
that it requires.
There's no simple NLP tricks that you
can apply to pass a valid turing test
with an emphasis on the word valid Mitch
Kapor.
And I had a six month debate on what the
rules should be because if you read
turing's 1950 paper,
uh,
he describes this in a few paragraphs
and doesn't really describe how to go
about it,
but if it's a valid turing test,
meaning it's really convincing you
through into interrogation and dialogue,
uh,
that it's a human that requires a full
range of human intelligence.
And I think that a test says to the test
of time,
we're making very good progress on that.
I mean,
just last week you may have read that
two systems,
uh,
past the paragraph comprehension test.
It's really very impressive.
When I came to Google,
we were trying to pass these paragraph
comprehension tests.
We aced the first,
the first grade test,
second grade tests were Kinda got
average performance.
And the third grade test had too much
inference.
I already,
you had to know some common sense
knowledge is it's called a and make
implications of things that were in
different parts of the paragraph and
there's too much in France and really
didn't,
didn't work.
So this is now an adult level,
just slightly surpassed average human
performance.
Uh,
but we've seen that one something,
an ai does something at average human
levels.
It doesn't take long for it to soar past
a average human levels.
I think it'll take longer in language
and it didn't sort of simple games like
go,
uh,
it's actually very impressive that it
surpasses now average human performance
to use an Lstm long short temporal
memory.
But if you look at the adult test in
order to answer these questions,
it has to put together inferences and
implications of several different things
in the paragraph with some common sense.
Knowledge is not explicitly stated.
So that's,
I think a pretty impressive milestone.
So I've been developing,
I've got a team of about 45 people,
um,
and we've been developing this
hierarchical model.
We don't use Markov models because we
can use deep learning for each module.
And so we create an embedding for each
word and recreate an embedding for each
sentence,
uh,
this week.
Have a can talk about it because we have
a published paper on it.
It can take into consideration context.
If you use smart reply on Ge Fuse,
g mail on your phone,
you'll see it gives you three
suggestions for responses.
That's called smart reply there that are
simple suggestions.
But it has to actually understand
perhaps a complicated email,
uh,
and the,
the quality of the suggestions and
squarely quite good.
Quite on point.
Uh,
that's where my team using this kind of
hierarchical model,
uh,
so instead of mark off models,
it uses embeddings,
uh,
cause we can use backpropagation,
we might as well use it.
Uh,
but I think what's missing from deep
learning is this hierarchical aspect of
understanding because the world is
hierarchical.
That's why a evolution developed a
hierarchical brain structure to
understand the natural hierarchy in the
world.
And there are several problems with big,
deep neural nets.
One is the fact that you really do need
a billion examples and we don't.
Sometimes we can generate them as in the
case of go,
uh,
or if we have a really good simulator as
in the case of autonomous vehicles,
not quite the case yet in biology,
a very often you don't have ability to
example,
if you suddenly have billions of
examples of language but they're not
annotated.
And how would you annotate it anyway
with more language that we can
understand in the first place.
So it's kind of a chicken and an egg
problem.
Uh,
so I believe this hierarchical
structures needed another criticism of
deep neural nets.
They don't explain themselves very well.
It's a big,
a black box that gives you pretty
remarkable answers.
I mean,
in the case of these Games Dennis
described it's playing in both go and
chess is almost an alien intelligence
because it will do things that were
shocking to you and experts like
sacrificing a queen and a bishop at the
same time,
uh,
or in close succession which shocked
everybody,
but then went on win or early in a go
game,
putting a piece at the corner of the
board,
which is kinda crazy to most experts
because you really want to start
controlling territory.
And yet on reflection,
that was the brilliant move that enabled
us to win that game.
But it doesn't really explain how it
does these things.
So if,
yeah,
if you have a hierarchy,
it's much better at explaining it
because you could look at the content of
the,
of the modules in the hierarchy and
they'll explain what they're doing.
And,
uh,
just to end on the first application of
applying this to health and medicine,
this will get into high gear and we're
going to really see a breakout of the
linear extension to longevity that we've
experienced.
A,
I believe we're only about a decade away
from longevity,
escape velocity.
We're adding more time than is going by,
not just to infant life expectancy,
but to your remaining life expectancy.
I think if someone is diligent,
they can be there already.
I think I've at longevity,
escape velocity now a word on what life
expectancy means.
It used to be assumed that not much
would happen.
So whatever your life expectancy is a
with or without scientific progress,
it really didn't matter.
Now it matters a lot.
So life expectancy really means,
you know,
how long would you live,
what's the statistical likelihood if
there were not continued tying antic
progress,
but that's a very inaccurate assumption
that scientific progress is extremely
rapid.
I mean,
just as an ai and biotech,
there are advances now.
Every week is quite stunning.
Now you could have a computed life
expectancy,
let's say 30 years,
50 years,
70 years from now,
you could still be hit by the proverbial
bus tomorrow.
We're working on that with self driving
vehicles.
Um,
but we'll get,
we'll get to a point.
I think if you're diligent,
you can be there now in terms of
basically advancing your own statistical
life expectancy,
at least to keep pace with the passage
of time.
I think it will be there for most of the
population at least if they're diligent
within about a decade.
So if he can hang in there,
we may get to see the remarkable century
ahead.
Thank you very much.
You,
I have a
question.
Please raise your hand and we'll get you
on mic.
Uh,
high.
so you mentioned,
uh,
both your neural network models and
symbolic models.
Uh,
and I was wondering how far have
you had been thinking about combining
these two approaches?
Creating a symbiosis between neural
models.
Send symbolic ones.
I don't think we want to use symbolic
models as they've been used.
How many are familiar with the psych
project?
That was a very diligent effort in Texas
to define all of common sense reasoning
and it kind of collapsed on itself and
became impossible to debug because you
fix one thing and it would break three
other things.
That complexity ceiling has become
typical of,
of trying to define things through
logical rules.
Uh,
now it does seem that humans can
understand logical rules.
We have logical rules written down for
things like law and game playing and so
on.
Uh,
but you can actually define a connection
as system to have such a high
reliability on a certain type of action
that it looks like it's a symbolic role,
even though it's represented in a
connectionist way.
And connection systems can both capture
the soft edges because many things in
life are not a sharply defined.
They can also generate exceptions.
So you,
you don't want to sacrifice your queen
and chest except certain situations that
might be a good idea.
So you can capture that kind of
complexity.
Uh,
so we do want to be able to learn from
accumulated human wisdom that looks like
it's symbolic.
But,
uh,
I think we'll do it with a connection of
system.
But again,
I'm,
I think the connection systems should
develop a sense of hierarchy and not
just be one big massive neural net.
So I understand how we won,
you know,
using your cortex to extract useful
stuff and commercialize that,
but I'm wondering how,
you know,
our middle brain and the organs that are
below the neocortex will be useful for,
um,
you know,
turning that into what you want to do.
So.
Well,
the cerebellum is an interesting case in
point.
It actually has more neurons in the
neocortex and it's used to govern most
of our behavior.
Uh,
some things,
if you write a signature that's actually
controlled by the cerebellum,
so a simple sequence is stored in the
cerebellum,
but there's not any reasoning to it.
It's basically a script.
Uh,
and most of our movement now has
actually been migrated from the
cerebellum to the NEOCORTEX.
Cerebellum is still there.
Uh,
some people,
a tire cerebellum is destroyed through
disease.
Uh,
they still function fairly.
Normally they're moving,
might be a little erratic as our
movement is largely controlled by the
Neocortex,
but some of the subtlety is a kind of
preprogrammed script and so they'll look
a little clumsy,
but they're actually functioning okay.
Um,
a lot of other areas of the brain
control,
autonomic functions like breathing and
uh,
but our thinking really is,
is controlled by the neocortex in terms
of a mastering intelligence.
I think the NEOCORTEX is the brain
region we want to study.
I'm curious what you think might happen
after the singularity is reached in
terms of this exponential growth of
information.
Yeah.
Do you think it will continue or will
there be a whole paradigm shift?
What do you predict?
Well,
in the singularity is near talk about
the atomic limits based on molecular
computing as we understand it,
uh,
and it can actually go well past 20
slash 45 and actually go to trillions of
trillions of times a greater
computational capacity than we have
today.
So I don't see that stopping anytime
soon and we'll go way beyond what we can
imagine.
Um,
and it becomes an interesting
discussion.
What the impact on a human civilization
will be.
So take it maybe slightly more mundane
issue that comes up as us going to
eliminate most jobs are all jobs.
A point I make is it's not the first
time in human history.
We've done that.
How many jobs circa 1900 exists today.
Uh,
and that was the feeling of the
Luddites,
which was some actual society and that
formed in 1800 after the automation of
the textile industry in England.
They looked at all these jobs going away
and felt old employment's going to be
just limited to an elite.
Uh,
indeed,
those jobs did go away,
but new jobs were created.
So if I were oppression futurist in
1900,
I would say,
well,
38 percent of your work on farms and 25
percent work in factories.
That's two thirds of the working for us,
but I predict by 20 1,515
years from now,
it's going to be two percent on farms
and nine percent in factories.
And everybody would go,
oh my God,
we're going to be out of work.
And I said,
well,
don't worry for all these jobs we
eliminate through automation.
We're going to invent new jobs.
People say,
Oh,
really?
What new jobs?
And I'd say,
well,
I don't know.
We haven't invented them yet.
That's the political problem.
We can see jobs very clearly going away
fairly soon.
Like driving a car or truck,
uh,
and the new jobs haven't been invented.
I mean,
it's just look at the last five or six
years as many of the increase in
employment has been through mobile app
related types of ways of making money
that just weren't contemplated even six
years ago.
If I really pressured,
I would say,
well,
you're going to get jobs creating mobile
apps and websites and doing data
analytics and a self driving cars,
cars.
What's a car?
And nobody would have any idea what I'm
talking about a now the new job.
Some people say,
yeah,
we created new jobs for.
It's not as many actually.
We've gone from 24 million jobs in 1900,
242 million jobs today for 30 percent of
the population to 45 percent of the
population.
The new jobs pay 11 times as much in
constant dollars and they're more
interesting.
I mean,
as I talk to people starting out their
career now,
they really want a career that gives him
some life definition and purpose and
gratification.
We're moving up maslow's hierarchy a 100
years ago.
You are happy if you had a backbreaking
job to put food on your family's table.
So,
and we couldn't do these new jobs
without enhancing our intelligence.
So we've been doing that a well for most
of the last 100 years through education.
We've expanded k through 12 and constant
dollars tenfold.
We've gone from 38,000
college students in 1870 to $50 million
today.
Uh,
more recently we have brain extenders
and not yet connected directly in our
brain,
but they're great close at hand when I
was here at mit to take my bicycle
across campus to get to the computer and
show an ID to get in the building.
Now we carry them in our,
in our pockets and under our belts.
A,
they're going to go inside our bodies
and brains.
I think that's a really important
distinction,
but so we're basically going to be
continuing to enhance our capability
through merging with Ai.
And that's the,
I think ultimate answer to the kind of
Dystopian view we see in futures movies
where it's the ai versus a brave band of
humans for control of humanity.
We don't have one or two ais in the
world today.
We have several billion,
3 billion smartphones at last count and
it'll be 6 billion in just a couple of
years according to the projections.
Uh,
so we're,
we're already deeply integrated with
this,
uh,
and I think that's going to continue and
it's going to continue to do things that
we can't even imagine today just as we
are doing today.
Things we couldn't imagine know even 20
years ago
you showed many grasp that go through
exponential growth,
but I haven't seen one that isn't.
So I would be very interested in hearing
you haven't seen what that,
what that is not exponential.
So tell me about regions that you've
investigated that have not seen
exponential growth.
And why do you think that's the case?
Well,
price,
performance and capacity of information
technology invariably follows a
exponential where it impacts human
society.
It can be linear.
So for example,
the growth of democracy,
uh,
has been linear but still pretty steady.
I could count the number of democracies
on the fingers of one hand to century,
go a two centuries ago.
You could count the number of
democracies in the world on the fingers
of one finger.
Now there are dozens of them that this
has become kind of a consensus that
that's how we should be governed.
So the,
and I attribute all this to the growth
in information technology,
communication in particular for a
progression of social cultural
institutions,
um,
but information technology because it
ultimately depends on a vanishingly
small energy and material requirement
grows exponentially and will for a long
time.
Uh,
there was recently a criticism that,
well,
chest scars have.
It's actually a remarkably a straight
linear progression,
so humans think it's like 2,800
and it just soared past that in 1997
with deep blue and it's kept going,
uh,
and a remarkably straight and St.
well,
this is linear,
not exponential,
but the chest score is a logarithmic,
uh,
measurement,
so,
uh,
it,
it really is exponential progression.
So philosophers like to think about the
meaning of things,
especially in the 20th century.
So for instance,
Martin Heidegger gave a couple of
speeches and lectures on the
relationship of human society to
technology,
and he particularly distinguished
between the mode of thinking,
which is calculating,
thinking and a mode of thinking,
which is reflective thinking or
meditative thinking.
Um,
and,
uh,
he posed this question,
what is the meaning and purpose of
technological development?
And he couldn't find an answer.
He,
he recommended it to remain open to what
you called.
He called this an openness to the
mystery.
Uh,
I wonder whether you have any thoughts
on this.
Is there a meaning,
a purpose of technological element?
And,
and is there a way for us human success,
excess that meaning.
Well,
we started using technology to shore up
weaknesses and our own capabilities.
So physically,
I mean,
who here could build this building?
So we've leveraged the power of our
muscles with machines,
uh,
and were in fact very bad at doing
things that,
you know,
the simplest computers can do a pike
factor numbers or even just multiply two
digit numbers.
Computers can do that trivially.
We can't do it.
So we originally started using computers
to make up for that weakness.
Uh,
I think the essence of what I've been
writing about is to master the unique
strengths of,
of humanity,
creating loving expressions and poetry
and music and,
uh,
the kinds of things we associate with
the better qualities of humanity with
machines.
That's the true promise of Ai,
uh,
that we're not there yet,
but we're making pretty stunning
progress just in the last year,
this so many milestones that are really
significant,
including in language.
Um,
and,
but I think of technology as an
expression of humanity.
It's part of who we are and the human
species is already a,
a biological technological civilization
and it's part of who we are and ai is as
part of humans.
Uh,
so ai is human and it's just,
it's part of the technological
expression of humanity.
And we use technology to extend our
reach.
You know,
I couldn't reach that fruit at that
higher branch a thousand years ago.
So we invented a tool to extend our
physical reach.
Now extend our mental reach.
We can access all of human knowledge
with a few keystrokes.
Um,
and we're going to make ourselves
literally smarter by merging with Ai.
Hi,
first of all,
honor to hear you speak here.
Uh,
so I first read the singularity is near
nine years ago or so,
and it changed the way I thought
entirely,
but something I think it caused me to
oversee deeply discount was tail risk in
geopolitics in systems that span the
entire globe.
Um,
and my concern is that there are,
there's obviously the possibility of
tail risk,
existential level events,
swamping all of these trends that are
otherwise waterproof climate proof,
you name it.
So my question for you is,
what steps do you think we can take in
designing engineered systems in
designing social and economic
institutions to kind of minimize our
exposure to these tail risks and,
and survive to make it,
to,
um,
you know,
a beautiful mind filled future?
Yeah.
Well,
the world was first introduced to a
human made existential risk.
Uh,
when I was in elementary school,
we would have these civil defense drills
get under our desks and put our hands
behind our head to protect this former
thermonuclear war.
Uh,
and it worked.
We made it through,
but that was really the first
introduction to an existential risk,
uh,
and those weapons are still there by the
way,
and they're still on a hair trigger and
they don't get that much attention.
Uh,
there's been a lot of discussion,
a much of which I've been in the
forefront of initiating the existential
risks of what's sometimes referred to as
gnr g for genetics,
which is biotechnology and financial
technology and grey goo robotics,
which is ai.
Uh,
and I've been accused of being an
optimist.
I think you have to be an optimist to be
an entrepreneur.
If you knew all the problems you were
going to encounter,
you'd never start any project.
But,
uh,
I've written a lot about the downsides.
I remain optimistic.
Uh,
there are specific paradigms and not
foolproof that we can follow to keep
these technologies safe.
So,
for example,
uh,
over 40 years ago,
some visionaries recognize the
revolutionary potential.
Both were promise and peril of
biotechnology,
neither of the promise and the peril of
what's feasible 40 years ago.
But they had a conference at the Sylmar
Conference Center in California,
uh,
to develop both a professional ethics
and strategies to keep biotechnology
safe and they've been known to see in
Sylmar guidelines.
They've been refined through successive
sylmar conferences.
Much of that is baked into law and an,
in my opinion,
it's worked quite well.
We're now,
as I mentioned,
getting profound benefit.
It's a trickle today.
It'll be a flood over the next decade.
And the number of people who have been
harmed either through intentional or
accidental abuse of biotechnology so
far,
zero.
Actually,
I take that back.
There was one boy who died in gene
therapy trials,
but 12 years ago and there's
congressional hearings and the,
uh,
canceled all research for a gene therapy
for a number of years.
You could do an interesting message
thesis and demonstrate that,
you know,
300,000
people died as a result of that delay,
but you can't name them.
They can't go on.
So we don't know who they are.
But,
um,
so it has to do with the balancing of
risk.
But in large measure,
virtually no one has been hurt by
biotechnology.
Now,
that doesn't mean you can cross it off
our list.
Okay?
We took care of that one because the
technology keeps getting more
sophisticated.
Crispers great opportunity.
This hundreds of trials of crispr
technologies overcome disease,
but it could be abused.
You can easily describe scenarios,
so we have to keep reinventing it.
Uh,
January,
we had our first Sylmar conference on ai
ethics.
And so I think this is a good paradigm.
It's not foolproof.
Uh,
I think the best way we can assure a
democratic,
a future that includes ideas of liberty
is to practice that in the world today
because the future world of the
singularity,
which is a merger of biological
biological intelligence,
uh,
is not going to come from Mars.
I mean,
it's going to emerge from our society
today.
Uh,
so if we practice these ideals today,
it's gonna have a higher chance of us
practicing them as we get more enhanced
with technology.
Uh,
that doesn't sound like a foolproof
solution or it isn't.
But I think that's the best approach in
terms of technological solutions.
I mean,
ai is the most daunting.
You can imagine.
A,
there are technical solutions to
biotechnology and nanotechnology.
Uh,
there's really no set routine.
You can put it in your ai software that
will assure that have remained safe
intelligence.
It's inherently not controllable.
There's some ai that's smarter than you
that's out for your destruction.
The best way to deal with that is not to
get in that situation in the first
place.
If you are in that situation,
find some ai that will be on your side.
Um,
but basically,
uh,
it's going to it,
I believe we have been headed through
technology,
uh,
to a,
to a better reality,
a look around the world and people
really think things are getting worse.
Uh,
and I think that's because our
information about what's wrong with the
world is getting exponentially better.
I say,
Oh,
this is the most peaceful time in human
history in previously.
What are you crazy?
Didn't you hear about the event
yesterday and last week and a while,
a hundred years ago,
that could be a battle and wiped out the
next village.
And you wouldn't even hear about it for
months.
Uh,
have all these graphs on education and
literacy has gone from 10 percent to 90
percent over a century and a health
wealth,
uh,
poverty's declined 95 percent in Asia
over the last 25 years was documentary
about the World Bank.
All these trends are very smoothly
getting better and everybody thinks
things are getting,
but,
but you're right,
like on violence,
that curve could be quite disruptive.
There's an existential event,
uh,
as I say,
I'm optimistic,
but I think that is something we need to
deal with and a lot of it is not
technological,
it's dealing with our social cultural
institutions.
So you mentioned also exponential growth
of software and Ivs,
I guess related to software.
So one of the reasons for which you said
that all that information technology is
exponential is because of fundamental
properties of matter and energy.
But in the case of ideas,
why would it have to be exponential?
Well,
a lot of ideas produce exponential
gains.
They don't increase performance
linearly.
There's a case study during the Obama
Administration by the scientific
advisory board on assessing this
question,
how much gains on 23 classical
engineering problems were gained through
hardware improvements over the last
decade and software improvement.
So there's about a thousand to one
improvement.
It's about doubling every year from
hardware that was an average of
something like 26,000
to one through software improvements,
algorithmic improvements.
So we do see both ends.
Apparently if you come up with an
advance,
it doubles the performance so it
multiplies it by 10.
We see basically exponential growth from
each innovation.
Um,
so,
and we certainly see that in deep
learning.
Uh,
the architectures are getting better
while we also have more data and more
computation and more memory to throw at
these at these algorithms.
Thank you very much.
Thank you.