The following is a conversation
with Thomas San home.
He's a professor of same you
and Co creator of [inaudible],
which is the first AI system to beat top
human players in the game of heads up.
No limit.
Texas hold'em.
He has published over 450 papers on
game theory and machine learning,
including a best paper in 2017 at nips.
Now renamed to new reps,
which is where I caught up
with him for this conversation,
has research and companies have had
wide reaching impact in the real world,
especially because he and his group not
only propose new ideas but also build
systems to prove that these
ideas work in the real world.
This conversation is part of the MIT
course on artificial general intelligence
and the artificial intelligence podcasts.
If you enjoy, subscribe on Youtube,
iTunes or simply connect with
me on Twitter at Lex Friedman,
spelled f. R I. D.
And now here's my conversation
with Thomas sent home.
Can you describe at the high level
the game of Poker Texas? Hold 'em,
heads up Texas hold'em for
people who might not be familiar.
This card game. Yeah, happy to. So heads
up, no, let me fix this. Hold them.
It has really emerged in the Ai community
as main benchmark for testing these
application independent algorithms for
imperfect information games holding.
And this is a game, uh, that's
actually played by humans.
You don't see that much on
TV or casinos because uh,
well for that reverse reasons,
but uh,
are you do see it in some expert level
casinos and you see it in the best poker
movies of all time. It's actually an
event in the world series of poker,
but mostly it's played
online and typically for
pretty bad big sums of money.
And this is a game that
usually only experts play.
So if you go to your home
game on a Friday night,
it probably is not going to be heads up.
No limit. Texas hold that mic might be,
uh,
not limit Texas hold'em in some cases,
but typically for a big group and it's
not as competitive while heads up means
it's two player.
So it's really like me against you and
my better or are you a better much like
chess or, or, or go in that sense,
but in an imperfect information game,
which makes it much harder cause
I have to deal with issues of uh,
you knowing things that they don't know
and I know things that you don't know
instead of pieces being nicely laid
on the board for both of us to see.
So in Texas hold'em, uh, there's uh,
two cars that you only see
the lawn to you and there is,
they gradually layouts some cars that
add up overall to five cards that
everybody can see.
The imperfect nature of the information
is the two cards that you're holding in
front year. So as you said, you know,
you first get two cards in private each
and then you, uh, there's a betting rod,
then you get three clubs in public on
the table, then there's a betting round,
then you get the fourth card in public
on the table dissipating around.
Then you'll get the five fifth
card on the table is a big raw.
So there's a total of four betting rounds.
And for tranches of inflammation,
revelation,
if you will.
The only the first tranche is private
and then it's public from there.
And this is probably probably by far
the most popular game in AI and just the
general public in terms
of imperfect information.
So that's probably the most
popular spectator game to watch.
Right? So the, which is why it's a
super exciting given tackle. So it's a,
it's on the order of chess,
I would say in terms of popularity,
in terms of the AI, setting it as
the bar of what is intelligence.
So in 2017 liberators,
how do you pronounce it,
really brought us the broadest, the
broadest beats. It'll let him there.
A little bit of Latin. A
Lebron has beads, a few, uh,
for expert human players.
Can you describe that event? What you
learned from it? What was it like?
What was the process in general for people
who have not read the papers and the
study? Yeah. So the event was that, uh,
we invited four or the top 10 players
with these are specialists players in
heads up,
no limit Texas hold'em,
which is very important because this
game is actually quite different than the
multiplayer version.
We brought them in to Pittsburgh
to play at the Rivers Casino, uh,
for 20 days. We wanted to get the
hundred and 20,000 hands in because, uh,
we wanted to get statistical significance.
So it's a lot of hands for humans to
play even for these top pros who play
fairly quickly normally.
So we couldn't just have one of
them play so many hands, 20 days.
They were playing basically
morning to evening and um, uh,
you've raised 200,000 as a little
incentive for them to play.
And the setting was so that
they didn't all get 50,000. Um,
we actually paid them out based on
how they did against the AI each.
So they had an incentive to
play as hard as they could,
whether they're way ahead or way behind
or right at the mark of beating their Ai.
And you don't make any money.
Unfortunately, right now we
can't make any money. So,
so originally a couple of
years earlier, I was, uh,
actually explored whether
we could actually play for
money because that would be
of course a interesting as well, uh, to
play against the top people for money.
But the Pennsylvania gaming board
said no, so, so we couldn't,
so this is much like an exhibit Le uh,
like for a musician or a boxer or
something like that. Nevertheless,
you are keeping track of the
money and brought us, uh,
one close to $2 million I think so.
So if that,
if it was for real money, uh,
if you were able to earn money,
that was a quite impressive
and inspiring achievement.
Just a few details of what,
what were the players looking at?
I mean they were they behind a computer?
What, what was the interface like? Yes.
That they were playing much like they
normally do these top players when they
play this game, they play mostly online.
So they used to playing through a Ui.
Yes. And they did the same thing
here. So there was this layout.
You could imagine there's a
table on the screen, this, the,
the human sitting there. And then
there's the AI sitting there. And the ta,
this Korean source,
everything that's happening in the Chi
is coming out and source the bets being
made. And we also had the best in history
for the human. So if the human, for God,
what had happened in the hand so far, they
could actually reference back and, and,
and, and so forth. Is there a reason
we're given access to
the bedding history for,
well, we, we just, uh, uh, it's,
it didn't really matter that they
wouldn't have focused on any way.
These are top quality people,
but we just wanted to put out there.
So it's not a question of
what human forgetting and
the AI somehow trying to get
that advantage of better memory.
So what was that like? I mean,
that was an incredible accomplishment.
So what did it feel like before
the event?
Did you have doubt,
hope, or what, where was your
confidence at? Yeah, that's great. So,
great question. So, uh, 18 months earlier,
I had organized a similar brains versus
AI competition without previous AI
called Claudico and we couldn't
beat the teams. Uh, so, uh,
at this time around, it was only 18
months later and I knew that this new,
a liberal autos was way stronger,
but it's hard to say how you'll do
against the top humans before you try it.
So I thought we had about a 50 50 shot
and the international betting sites,
both us, us, us as a four to
one or five to one underdog.
So it's kind of interesting that people
really believe in people and I get over
Ai, uh, not just people, people don't
just believe over believe in themselves,
but they have overconfidence in other
people as well compared to the performance
of Ai. And uh, yeah,
so we were a four to one or five to 100
dog and even after three days of beating
the humans in a row, we were still 50,
50. On the international betting sites.
Do you think there's something
special and magical Bob Poker
in the way people think about
it? In a sense you have. I mean,
even in chess,
there's no Hollywood movies.
Poker is the star of many movies.
And there's this feeling that a certain
human facial expressions and body
language, eye movement, all these
towels are critical to poker.
Like you can look into somebody's soul.
I understand they're betting strategy
and so on there. So that's probably
probably why the possibly do you think
that is why people have a confidence that
humans will output?
Because AI systems
cannot in this construct,
perceive these kinds of tells.
They're only looking at
bedding patterns and uh,
and nothing
else. The betting patterns
and, and Statistics.
So what's more important to you if
you step back and human players,
human versus human?
What's the role of these towels of these,
uh, ideas that we romanticize? Yeah. So I,
I'll split it into two parts.
So one is wider.
Humans trust humans more than AI and
all have overconfidence in humans.
Yes. I think that's, that's not really
related. Those are the teller question.
It's just that,
that they've seen these top layers,
how good they are and
they're really fantastic.
So it's just hard to believe the bad or
that the knee, I could beat them. Yeah.
So I think that's where that comes from.
And,
and that's actually maybe a more general
lesson about AI until you've seen it
over perform a human. It's hard to believe
that it could. But, um, then the tailors,
um,
a lot of these top players,
they're so good at hiding tales
that among the top players,
it's actually not really worth it for
them to invest a lot of effort trying to
find tellers in each other because
they're so good at hiding them.
So a yes at the kind
of Friday evening game,
tell us up going to be a huge thing.
You can read other people and
if you're a good reader, you'll,
you'll read them like an open book.
But at the top levels of poker now
the tells become a lesson of much,
much smaller and smaller aspect of
the game. As you go to the top levels,
the amount of strategies, the
minds of possible actions is, um,
is very large, uh, 10 to
the power of hundred plus.
Uh,
so there has to be some,
I've read a few papers related to has
it has to form some abstractions of
various hands and actions.
So what kind of abstractions are
effective for the game of poker?
Yeah, so you're exactly right. So, uh,
when you go from a game
theory that's 10 to the 161,
especially in an imperfect
information game,
it's weight or life to solve directly
even that with our fastest equilibrium
finding algorithms. So, uh,
you want to abstract it first and
abstraction in games is much trickier than
abstraction in MDPs are other single
agent settings because you have these
abstraction pathologies that if I
have a finer grained abstraction,
the strategy that I can get from that
for the real game might actually be worse
than the strategy I can get from
the coarse grained obstruction.
Do you have to be very careful?
Now the,
the kinds of obstruction
is just to zoom out.
We're talking about there's the hands
obstructions and then there's betting
strategies. What wedding actions?
Yeah, beating action. So,
so there's inflammation obstruction.
Talk about general gangs,
inflammation obstruction, which is
the abstraction of what chance does.
And this would be the
cogs indication of poker.
And then there's action abstraction,
which is abstracting the
actions of the actual players,
which would be fits in the case of
poker yourself and the other players and
other players.
And uh,
for inflammation obstruction,
we were completely automated. So
this was, these are algorithms,
uh,
with they do what we call potential aware
abstraction where we don't just look
at the value of the hand,
but also how it might materialize
in the good or bad hands over time.
And it's a certain kind
of bottom up process, uh,
with integer programming
there and clustering and
various aspects how you build,
build this abstraction.
And then in the action abstraction there,
it's largely based on how um,
humans,
other and other ais have played this
game in the past. But in the beginning,
we actually use an automated
action obstruction technology,
which is provably convergent that it finds
the optimal combination or bed sizes,
but it's not very scalable.
So we couldn't use it for the whole game,
but we used it for the first couple of
pitting actions. So what's more important?
Uh,
the strength of the hand.
So the information extraction or the,
uh,
how you play them. Uh, the
actions does it, you know,
the romanticized notion again is
that it doesn't matter what happens,
you have that the actions, the
bedding, uh, maybe the way you win,
no matter what hands here.
So that's why you have to play a lot
of hands so that the role of luck gets
smaller.
So you could otherwise get lucky and get
some good hands and then you're going
to win the match. Even with thousands
of hands, you can get lucky, uh,
because there's so much variance
in no limit Texas hold'em,
because if we both go all
in, it's a huge stack, uh,
or variants or there are these massive
swings in no limit Texas hold'em.
So that's why you have to play
not just thousands, but, uh,
over a hundred thousand hands, they'll
get statistical significance. This is,
let me ask another way. This question,
if you didn't even look at your hands,
but they didn't know that the
opponents didn't know that,
how well would you be able to do? Oh,
that's a good question. There's actually,
I heard the story that there's this
Norwegian female poker player call and it
Oberstar who's actually won a
tournament by doing exactly that,
but that would be extremely rare.
So I cannot really play well. No. Okay.
So, so that the hands do
have some role to play? Yes.
So lowbrow does, does not, uh,
use as far as I understand,
a use learning methods and deep learning
is there room for learning in the,
you know, the, there's no reason
why the US doesn't, you know,
combine with an Alphago type approach for
estimating the quality a four function
estimator.
W what are your thoughts on this?
Maybe as compared to another algorithm,
which I'm not that familiar
with deep stack, the,
the engine that does use deep learning,
that is unclear how well it does,
but nevertheless uses deep learning.
So what are your thoughts about learning
methods to aid in the way that Tele
Broaddus plays the game of
poker? Yeah. So as you said,
Libratone did not use learning methods
and played very well without them.
Since then,
we have actually actually here we have
a couple of papers on things that do use
learning techniques.
Excellent. Uh, so, um, and,
and deep learning in particular and uh,
sort of the way you're talking about
where it's learning and evaluation
function. But um, in
imperfect information games,
unlike let's say in go or now,
now also in chess and Shogee,
it's not sufficient to learn and
evaluation for a state because the
value of an inflammation set
depends not only on the exact state,
but it also depends on
both players beliefs.
Like if I have a bad hand, I'm much
better off if the appointed thinks I'm,
I have a good hand and vice versa.
If I have a good hand,
I'm much better off if the opponent
believes I have a bad hand. Uh,
so the value of our state is not
just a function of the cards,
it depends on a, if you
will, the path of play.
But only do they extent that is captured
in the belief distributions. So,
so that's why it's not a simple as,
uh,
as it is imperfect information games.
And I don't want to say it simple,
they're either, it's of course very
complicated computationally there too.
But at least conceptually it's very
straightforward. There's a state,
there's an evaluation function.
You can try to learn it here.
You have to do something more. Uh, and uh,
what we do is in one of these papers
were looking at allowing where we allow
with the opponent to actually take
different strategies at the leaf of the
search tree yet if you
will. And, and that, uh,
is a different way of doing it.
And it doesn't assume therefore a
particular way that the opponent place,
but it allows our opponent to choose
from a set of different continuation
strategies and that forces us to not be
too optimistic in our look ahead search.
And that's what, that's one way
you can do sound. Look ahead,
search in imperfect information games,
which is very different, difficult.
And in, in, in your ass you were
asking about deep stack, what they did.
If we're very different than what we
do either in [inaudible] or in this new
work,
they were just randomly generating
various situations in the game.
Then they were doing it the look ahead
from there to the end of the game as if
that was a start of a different game.
And then they were using deep learning
to learn those values of those states.
But the states were not
the physical states.
They include the belief distributions.
When you talk about look ahead of war
deep stack or when Luvata's does it mean
considering every possibility
that the game can evolve?
Are we talking about extremely sort of at
this exponential growth of a tree? Yes,
so we're, we're, we're
talking about exactly that
much like you do in Alpha Beta
search or monitor tree research,
but with different techniques.
So there's different search algorithm
and then we have to deal with the leaves
differently.
So if you think about what Librato stayed,
we didn't have to worry about this because
we only did it at the end of the game.
So we would always terminate into a real
situation and we would know what the
payout is. It didn't do this
depth limited local hits.
But now in this new paper,
which is called depth limited,
I think it's called depth limited
search for imperfect information games,
we can actually do sound depth,
the limited local heads.
So we can actually start to do the local
head from the beginning of the game on
because that's too complicated
to do for this whole long game.
So in liberal arts we were just doing it
for the end. So and then the other side,
this belief distribution.
So is it explicitly modeled what kind
of beliefs that the opponent might have?
Yeah, it is explicitly
modeled, but it's not assumed.
The beliefs are actually output,
not input of course,
the starting beliefs,
our input,
but they just fall from the rules of
the game because we know that the dealer
deals uniformly from the deck.
So I know that every pair of cards that
you might have is equally unlikely.
I know that for a fact that just
follows from the rules of the game.
Of course except the two
cards that I have. I know you
don't have those. Yes. Uh,
you have to take that into account.
That's called cod removal.
And that's very important
is as the dealing,
I was coming from a single deck in
heads up. So all can assume single deck,
the as you know, if, if
I have the ace of spades,
I know you don't have an ace of space.
Great.
So in the beginning your
belief is basically the fact
that it's a fair dealing
of hands. But how do you adjust,
start to adjust that belief? Well,
that's where this beauty of game
theory comes. So natural equilibrium,
which John Nash introduce
in 1950 introduces what
rational play is when you have
more than one player.
And these appears or strategies where
strategies are contingency plans,
one for each player.
Uh,
so neither player wants to deviate or
different strategy given that the other
doesn't deviate.
But as a side effect,
you get the beliefs from base role.
So Nash equilibrium really isn't just
deriving in this imperfect information
games, Nash Equilibrium. It
doesn't just define strategies.
It also defines beliefs for both of us
and it refines beliefs for each state.
So at the each state,
each,
if they do call inflammation sits at
each inflammation sets in the game.
There's a set of different
states that we might be in,
but I don't know which one we're in.
It now basically ruined.
Tells me exactly what is a probability
distribution over those real states.
In my mind, how does national, they
give you that distribution. So why?
I'll do a simple example. So you know
the game rock, paper, scissors. So we,
we can draw it. This player one moves
first and then player two moles.
But of course it's important that player
tool doesn't know what player one moved.
Otherwise player tool
would win every time.
So we can draw that as an information
set where player one makes one or three
moves first and then there's an
inflammation set for player too.
So player to doesn't know which
of those nodes, the world.
A world is it.
Once we know the strategy for player one
Nash Equilibrium will say that the play
one third rock, one third
paper, one third seizures.
From that I can derive my beliefs on the
information set that they're one third
one third one third. There's a bays
gives you that there's an issue.
But is that specific to a
particular player or is it uh,
is it something you quickly update with
the Muslim with game theory isn't really
player specific. So that's what
also why we don't need any data. Uh,
we don't need any history
how these particular humans
played in the past or how
any AI or human had played before.
It's all about rationality.
So we just take the AI just thinks about
what would our rational upon it do and
what would I do if I were, I am
rushing island. What's that? That's,
that's idea of game theory.
So it's really a data free
opponent free approach.
So comes from the design of the game
as opposed to the design of the player.
Exactly. There's no opponent
modeling per se. I mean,
we've done some work on combining
opponent modeling with Game Theory.
So they're going to exploit
weak players even more.
But that's another
strand and in Libra does.
We didn't turn that on because I decided
that these players are too good and
when you start to exploit an opponent,
you typically open yourselves up,
self up to exploitation and these guys
have so few holes to exploit and their
world's leading experts
in counter exploitation.
So I decided that and that we're not
the kind of tenant that stuff on.
Actually I saw a few papers
in a exploiting opponents
and sound very interesting
to uh, explore. Uh, do you think
there's room for exploitation, Jay?
Generally outside of Libre
is, is there a subject, uh,
or people differences that could be
exploited maybe not just in poker but in
general interactions and negotiations,
all of these other domains that you're
considering? Yeah, I definitely,
we've done some work on that and I eat
a really like their work at hybridizes
that too. So you figure out what were
the rational upon it. And by the way,
that's safe in these sum games to players.
There were some games because if the
opponent does something irrational,
yes it might show a throw off my beliefs,
but the amount that the player can gain
by throwing off my belief is always less
than they lose by playing
poorly. So, so it's safe. But uh,
still if somebody's weak as a player,
you might want to play differently to
exploit them more so that you can think
about it this way,
a game theoretic strategies on a beatable,
but it doesn't maximally
beat other opponents.
So the winnings per hand might be
better with a different strategy.
And the hybrid is that you start from a
game theoretic approach and then as you
gain data from the, about the opponent
in certain parts of the game tree,
that in those parts of the game three,
you start to tweak your strategy more
and more towards exploitation while still
staying fairly close to the
game theoretic strategy.
So as to not open yourself
up to exploitation too much.
How, how do you do that? Do you, um,
try to vary up strategies, make
it unpredictable? It's like, uh,
uh, what is it a tit for tat strategies
in, um, prisoner's dilemma or
well, Italian that that's a repeated
game kind of compete against,
that's right in this dilemma
repeated games. But, but even there,
there's no proof that says
that that's the best thing.
But experimentally it actually,
yeah.
Does, does, does well, so what kind
of games are there? First of all,
I don't know if this is something that
you could just summarize that there's
perfect information games where all
the information is on the table.
There is imperfect information games,
there's repeated games that
you play over and over.
There's a zero sum games.
Uh,
there's non zero sum games.
Yeah.
And then there's a really
important distinction.
You're making a two player
versus more players. So what are,
what other games are there and
what's the difference? For example,
with this two player
game versus more players,
what are the key differences in review?
So let me start from the,
the basic.
So a repeated game is a game where the
same exact game is played it over and
over in these extensive form games.
Uh,
where I think about three form maybe
with these inflammation says to represent
incomplete information.
You can have kind of
repetitive interactions.
Even repeated games are a special
case of that by the way. But uh,
the game doesn't have to be exactly the
same. It's like in sourcing origins. Yes,
we're going to see you the
same supply base year to year.
But what I'm buying is a
little different every time.
And the supply base is a little
different every time and so on.
So it's not really repeated.
So to find a purely repeated game
is actually very rare in the world.
So they're really a very, uh,
course model of what's going on.
Then if you move up from
repair, just repeated, simple,
repeated matrix games. Uh, not all
the way to extensive form of games,
but in between there stochastic
games where you know,
there's these,
uh,
you think about it like these little
matrix games and when you take an action
and your text in action,
they determine not which next date
I'm going to next game I'm going to,
but the distribution of our next games
where I might be going through there.
So that's the stochastic game,
but it's like major schemes,
repeated stochastic games,
extensive form games that is
from less to more general and,
and poker is an example of the last one.
So it's really in the most general sitting
extensive form games and that's kind
of what the Ai community has been working
on and been benched marked on with
this heads up. No limit. Texas hold'em,
can you describe an extensive form games?
What's the, what's the motto here? So
if you're a present with the tree form,
so it's really the tree form.
Like in chess there's a search tree
versus a major third. It's a matrix here.
And uh,
that the new matrix is called the matrix
form or by matrix form or normal form
game and here you have the tree forms
so you can actually do certain types of
reasoning there that you
lose the information when
you go the normal phone as
say there's a certain form of equivalence.
Like if you go from three form and you
said every possible contingency plan is a
strategy,
then I can actually go back to the normal
form but they lose some information
from the lack of sequence reality.
Then the multiplayer versus two player
distinction is an important one.
So two player games in zero sum are
conceptually easier and computational
easier. The steel huge like
this one, this one, eh,
but they're conceptually
easier and computational,
easier in that conceptually you don't
have to worry about which equilibrium is
the other guy going into play when there
are multiple because any equilibrium
strategy is a best response to
any other equilibrium strategy.
So I can play a different equilibrium
from you and we'll still get the right
values of the game that falls
apart even with two players.
When you heard general some games,
even with our cooperation,
just even without cooperation.
So there's a big gap from two players
here are to top layer general some or even
two, three players there. Awesome. That's
a, that's a big gap at least in theory.
Can you maybe none mathematically provide
intuition while falls apart with three
or more players? Uh, it's,
it seems like you should still be able
to have a national equilibrium that
yeah. That that's
instructive. That holds, okay.
So it is true that all finite
games have a nash equilibrium,
right? So this is what John Nash
actually proved. So they do have a nash
equilibrium.
That's not the problem.
The problem is that there can be many
and then there's a question of which
equilibrium to select.
So,
and if you select your strategy from a
different equilibrium and I select mine,
they then did what does
that mean? Uh, and,
and in these non zero sum games,
we may lose some joints benefit where
her by being just simply stupid.
We could actually both be better
off if we did something else. Yes.
And in three player you get other
problems. Also like collusion,
like maybe you and I can get up on a third
player and we can do radically better
by color coding. So that are, there
are lots of issues that come up there.
So no brown student you work
with on this has mentioned, uh,
I looked through the Ama on reddit.
He mentioned that the ability of poker
players to collaborate, we make the game.
He was asked the question of how would
you make the game of poker or both of you
were asked the question, how would
you make the game of poker, uh,
beyond being solvable
by current AI methods?
And he said that there's not many
ways of making poker more difficult,
uh,
but uh,
collaboration or cooperation
between players, uh,
would make it extremely difficult.
So can you provide the intuition
behind why that is? Uh,
if you agree with that idea?
Yeah, so, uh, we, uh,
I've done a lot of work,
a coalitional games and we actually
have a paper here with my other student,
couple of [inaudible] and
some other collaborators on a,
an on that actually just came back from
the poster session where we presented.
But, uh, so, uh, when you
have a collusion, it's a,
it's a different problem and it
typically gets even harder then
even the game representations,
some of the game representations don't
really allow yeah. Would a computation,
so we actually introduced a
new game representation for,
for that. Is that kind of
[inaudible] part of the model
is, are you, do you have,
do you have information about the fact
that other players are cooperating or is
it just this chaos? There were,
nothing is known so, so there's some,
something's unknown.
Can you give an example of a collusion
type game or is it used breach?
Right. So think about bridge. It's
like when you and I are on a team,
I'll pay offs are the same. The
problem is that we can't talk. So,
so when I get my car, because I can't
whisper to you what my cards are,
that would not be allowed. So, uh,
we have to somehow coordinate our
strategies ahead of time and only ahead of
time. And then there are certain
signals that we can talk about,
but they have to be such that the other
team also understands that. So, uh,
so that,
that's,
that's an example where the coordination
is already built into the rules of the
game.
But in many other situations like
auctions or negotiations or diplomatic
relationships, poker,
it's not really built in,
but it still can be very
helpful for the colluders.
I've read you write somewhere
the negotiations you come
to the table with prior,
uh,
like a strategy that like,
that you're willing to do and not
willing to do those kinds of things.
So how do you start to now moving away
from poker movie beyond poker into other
applications like negotiations?
How do you start applying this to other,
to other domains? Yeah. Even real
world domains that you've worked on.
Yeah, I actually have two startup
companies doing exactly that.
One is called strategic machine and
that's for kind of beans in applications,
gaming, sports, all sorts
of things like that.
Any applications of these two
business and two sports at doe,
uh, gaming too about various
types of things for in finance,
electricity markets and so on.
And the other is called strategy robot,
where we are taking this
to a military security,
cybersecurity and
intelligence applications.
I think you've worked a
little bit in, um, how,
how do you put it to advertisement,
sort of suggesting, um,
ads kind of thing.
Yeah. Auction, that's another
company optimized markets optimize,
but that's much more about a combinatorial
market and optimization based
technology that's not using these a
game theoretic reasoning technologies.
I see.
Okay.
So what sort of high level do you think
about our ability to use game theoretic
concepts to model human behavior?
Do you think,
do you think human behavior is
amenable to this kind of modeling?
So outside of the poker games and where
have you seen it done successfully in
your work? I'm not
sure. The goal really is
modeling humans. Uh, like for example,
if I'm playing a zero sum game,
yes,
I don't really care that the opponent
is actually following in my model of
rational behavior because if they're not,
that's even better for
me. Right. So, so the sea,
the opponents and games,
there's a,
the prerequisite is that you formalize
the interaction in some way that can be
amenable to analysis.
And you've done this amazing
work with mechanism design,
designing games that have
certain outcomes. Uh,
but so I'll tell you an example from my,
from my world of autonomous vehicles,
right? We're studying
pedestrians, pedestrians and cars,
negotiating this nonverbal communication.
There's this weird game dance of tension
where pedestrians are basically saying,
I trust that you won't kill me. And so
as a Jaywalker will step onto the road,
even though I'm breaking the law and
there's this tension and the question is,
would really don't know how to model
well in trying to model intent.
And so people sometimes bring up
ideas and game theory and so on.
Do you think that aspect of human
behavior can use these kinds of imperfect
information approaches modeling?
How do we,
how do you start to attack
a problem like that? Uh,
when you don't even know how the game
design and game to describe the situation
in order to solve it?
Okay, so I haven't really thought about
Jay walking by. One thing that, uh,
I think would be a good application in
an autonomous vehicles is the following.
So let's say that you have fleets of
autonomous car as operating by different
companies. So maybe here's the way more
fleet. And here's the Uber Fleet. Uh,
if you think about the rules of the road,
they define certain legal rules,
but that still leaves a huge strategy
space open. Like as a simple example,
when cars merge, you know
how he must merge, you know,
there's low down and look at each
other and tried to tried to merge.
Wouldn't they do better
if these situations would
all repeat pre negotiated.
So we can actually merge at full speed
and we know that this is the situation,
this is how we do it and
it's all going to be faster.
But there are way too many
situations to negotiate manually.
So you could use automated negotiation.
This is the idea,
at least you could use automated
negotiation to negotiate all of these
situations or many of them in advance.
And of course it might be that, hey,
maybe you're not going to always let
me go first. Maybe you said, okay,
well in these situations
I'll let you go first.
But in exchange you're
going to give me two arms.
You're gonna let me go first
in this situation. Yes.
So it's this huge
combinatorial negotiation.
And do you think there's room in
that example of merging two model,
this whole situation is an imperfect
information game or do you really want to
consider it to be a perfect
no, that's a good question.
Yeah, that's a good question.
Pay The price of a assuming
that you don't know everything.
Yeah, I don't know. It's certainly much
easier games with perfect inflammation,
a much easier. So if you
can get away with it, uh,
you should. But if the real situation
is of imperfect information,
then you're going to have to deal
with and for imperfect information.
Great. So what lessons have you learned
the annual computer poker competition?
An incredible accomplishment of Ai.
You know,
you look at the history
of the Blue Alphago,
these kind of moments when AI stepped
up in an engineering effort and a
scientific effort combined to, to
beat the best human player. So what,
what do you take away from
this whole experience?
What have you learned about designing?
It has systems that play
these kinds of games.
And what does that mean for sort of,
uh,
AI in general for the
future of Iai Development?
Yeah. So that's a good question. Uh,
so there's so much to say about it.
I do like these type of
performance oriented research,
although in my group we go all
the way from idea to theory,
the experiments to big system
fielding the commercialization.
So we spend that spectrum by, but I
think that in a lot of situations in AI,
you really have to build the big systems
and evaluate them at scale before you
know what works and doesn't.
And we've seen that in the computational
game theory community if there are a
lot of techniques that
look good in this mall,
but then this is to
look good in the large.
And we've also seen that there are a
lot of techniques that look superior in
theory.
And I really mean in evenings
or convergence rates better
like first autometrix
better convergence rates, like the CFR
based bits, algorithms you have the CFR,
Bay based Algorithms are
the fastest in practice.
So it really tells me that you
have to test this. In reality,
the theory isn't tight enough,
if you will,
to tell you which algorithms are
better than the others. And, uh,
you have to look at these
things that in the large,
because any sorts of projections you'd
all from the small can at least in this
domain be very misleading.
So that, that's kind of from,
from our kind of a science
and engineering perspective.
From a personal perspective, it's been
just a wild experience in that, uh,
with the first poker
competition, the first, uh,
brains versus AI and machine barker
competition that we organized,
there had been, by the
way, for other poker games,
there had been previous competitions,
but this was no heads up, no limit.
This was the first.
And uh,
I probably became the most hated person
in the world of poker and I didn't mean
to cry. I size that, the crack
in the game for, so yeah,
it was a lot of people felt that it
was a real threat to the whole game,
the whole existence of the game. If,
if, if AI becomes better than humans,
people would be scared to play poker
because there are these superhuman AI is
running around taking their money and
you know, all of that sort of, so I just,
it's just really aggressive. Uh,
the comments were super aggressive.
I got everything.
Just short of death threats.
Do you think the same was true for chess?
Cause right now they just completed the
world championships and chess and humans
just started ignoring the fact that
there is AI systems now that I'll perform
humans and they still enjoy the game
is still a beautiful game. He's,
that's what I think. And I think the
same thing happens in poker as a,
so I didn't think of myself as somebody
who was going to kill the game and I
don't think I did. Yeah, I've
really learned to love of this game.
I wasn't the poker player before,
but learn so many nuances about it from
these ais and they've really changed how
the game's played by the way.
So they have these very Martian ways of
playing poker and the dop humorous are
now incorporating those types
of strategies into their
own play. So if anything,
to me,
our work has made poker a richer,
more interesting game for humans to play.
Not something that is going to
steer humans away from it entirely.
Just a quick comment
and something you said,
which is if I may say so an academia
is a little bit rare sometimes it is,
it's a pretty brave to put
your ideas to the test.
And the way you described saying that
it's sometimes good ideas don't work when
you actually tried to apply them at scale.
And so where does that come from?
I mean, what if you could do,
um, advice for people? What,
what drives you in that sense?
Will you always this way? I mean,
it takes a brave person,
I guess is what I'm saying.
To test their ideas and to see if this
thing actually works against human top
human players and
so on. Yeah. I don't know about
brave, but it takes a lot of work.
It takes a lot of work and a lot
of time, uh, to organize, do,
make something big and to organize
an event and stuff like that.
And what drives you in that effort?
Because you could still, I would argue,
get a best paper award at nips as
you did in 17 without doing this.
That's right. Yes. And
so, uh, so in, in general,
I believe it's very important
to do things in eh, in,
in the real world and at scale.
And that's really where the,
the, the pudding, if you're will proof
is in the pudding. That's where it is.
In this particular case,
it was kind of a competition between
different groups and for many years as to
who can be the first one to beat the
top humans at heads up, no limit.
Texas hold'em. So the game,
eh, it became kind of, uh, uh,
or, uh, like a competition
who can get there. Yeah.
So a little friendly competition can
be a can do wonders for progress. Yes.
So
the topic of mechanism design,
which is really interesting,
also kind of new to me except
as an observer of, I dunno,
politics and Amy, I'm an
observer of mechanisms, but you,
you write in your paper and the automated
mechanism design that I quickly read
some mechanisms design is designing the
rules of the game so you get a certain
desirable outcome and you have this work
on doing so in an automatic fashion as
opposed to fine tuning it. So what
have you learned from those efforts?
Uh, if we look, say I dunno
at a complex like, um,
our political system,
can we design our political system
to have in an automated fashion,
uh, to have outcomes that we want?
Can we design something like, um,
traffic lights to be smart?
It where it gets outcomes that we want.
So what,
what are the lessons that you
draw from that work? Yeah,
so I still very much believe in the
automated mechanism design direction. Yes.
But it's not a panacea.
There are impossibility results in
mechanism design saying that there is no
mechanism that accomplices
objective x in Class C so,
so it,
it's not going up.
There's no way you using any mechanism
design tools manual or automated to do
certain things in mechanism
design. He came. Describe
that again. So meaning there,
it's impossible to achieve.
That
would likely impossible.
So saw these are,
these are not statements about human
ingenuity date who might come up with
something smart.
These approves that if you want to
accomplish properties x in Class C,
that is not doable with any mechanism.
The good thing about automated mechanism
design is that we're not really
designing for a class. We're designing
for specific settings at a title.
So even if there's any possibility
that result for the whole class,
it just doesn't mean that all of the
cases in the class are impossible.
It just means that some of
the cases are impossible.
So we can actually carve these islands
of possibility within these noni possible
classes.
And we've actually done that.
So what one of the famous results in
mechanism design is some Irish and
Satterthwaite theorem for by Roger
Myerson and Mark Satterthwaite from 1983.
It's an impossibility of efficient
trade under imperfect information.
We show that you can in many settings
avoid that and get the efficient trade
anyway, depending on how
the design the game. Okay.
So depending on how you design the
game, man, of course it's not a,
it doesn't in any way, any way. Uh,
contradicting possibility was Arthur
in possibility results is still there,
but it just a finance sports within this
impossible class where in those sports
you don't have the possibility, sorry
if I'm going a bit philosophical, but a,
what lessons do you draw towards,
like I mentioned politics or human
interaction and designing mechanisms for
outside of just these kinds
of trading or auctioning or
purely formal games are human interaction
like a political system? What,
how can you think it's applicable to yeah.
Politics or to business,
uh, to negotiations,
these kinds of things.
Designing rules that have certain
outcomes. Yeah. Yeah. I do think so.
Have you seen success that
successfully done the didn't really,
oh you mean mechanism design or
automated automated mechanisms zone. So,
so mechanism design itself has
had fairly limited success so far.
There are certain cases but most of the
real world situations are actually not
sound from a mechanism design perspective.
Even in those cases where they've been
designed by very knowledgeable mechanism
designed people,
the people are typically just taking some
insights from the theory and applying
those insights into the real world rather
than applying the mechanisms directly.
So one famous example is the
FCC spectrum auctions. So,
um, uh, I've also had a
small role in that and uh,
very good economists have been word
excellent economists have been working on
that we'll know game theory yet the rules
that are designed in practice there,
they were such at beating
truthful is not the best strategy.
Usually mechanism design.
We tried to make things easy for the
participants saw telling the truth is the
best strategy.
But uh,
but even in those very high
stakes auctions where you
have tens of billions of
dollars worth of spectrum auction,
truth telling is not the best strategy.
And,
and by the way,
nobody knows even a single optimal
bidding strategy for those auctions.
What's the challenge of
coming up with an optimum?
Because there's a lot of
players and there's impersonal,
it's almost a lot of players,
but many items for sale and the these
mechanisms are such that even with just
two items or one item breeding
truthfully wouldn't be the best strategy.
If you look at the history of Ai,
it's marked by seminal events,
Alpha go beating the world
champion human goal player.
I would put [inaudible]
winning the heads up.
No limit hold'em is one of
those such event. Thank you.
What do you think
is the next such event,
whether it's in your life or
in the broadly AI community
that you think might be
out there that would surprise the world?
So that's a great question and under
really know the answer in terms of game
solving a heads up,
no limit.
Texas hold'em really was the one
remaining widely agreed upon benchmark.
So that was the big milestone.
Now are there other things? Yes,
certainly there are,
but there is not one that the
community has kind of focused on.
So what could it be? Other things,
there are groups working on starcraft,
there are groups working on Dota
two. These are video games. Yes.
Or You could have like
diplomacy or Hanabi, you know,
things like that. These are
like recreational games,
but none of them are uh,
really acknowledged as kind of the main
next challenge problem like chess or go
or heads up. No limit. Texas hold'em was,
so I don't really know in the
game solving space what is a,
what will be the next benchmark.
I hope kind of hope that they will be
an expense mark because the really the
different groups working on the same
problem really drove these application
independent techniques for board
very quickly, over 10 years.
Do you think there's an open
problem that excites you,
that you start moving away from
games into real world games?
Like say the stock market trading? Yeah.
So that's, that's kind of how I am.
So I am probably not going to work as
hard on these recreational benchmarks.
Uh, I'm doing two startups
on game solving technology,
strategic machine and strategy robot.
Then we're really interested in
pushing this stuff into practice.
What do you think would
be a really, you know, uh,
a powerful result that'd be
surprising. That would, would be, um,
if you can say, I mean the, you
know, five years, 10 years from now,
something that statistically
you would say is not
very likely, but if there's a
breakthrough, what achieve? Yeah.
So I think at the overall we're in a
very different situation in game theory
then we are in, let's say, machine
learning. Yes. So in machine learning,
it's a fairly mature technology and it's
very broadly applied and proven success
in the real world in game solving.
There are almost no applications yet.
We have just become superhuman,
which machine learning you could argue
happened in the 90s, if not earlier,
and uh,
at least unsupervised supervised learning,
certain complex supervised
learning applications.
Now I think the next challenge problem,
I know you're not asking about this way,
you're, you're asking, but the technology
breakthrough, but I think that big,
big breakthrough is to be able to show at,
hey,
maybe most of let's say military
planning or most of business strategy,
we'll actually be done strategically using
computational game theory that that's
what I would like to see as
the next five or 10 year goals.
Maybe you can explain to me again, forgive
me if this is an obvious question, but,
uh,
you know,
machine learning methods and all networks
are suffer from not being transparent
and they'd be explainable I game theoretic
methods, you know, Nash Equilibria.
Do they generally, when you see
the different solutions, are they,
uh, when you, when you talk about
military operations, are they,
once you see the strategies,
do they make sense of they explainable
or do they suffer from the same problems
as you know? And that works too.
So that's, that's a good question.
I would say a little bit yes and no.
And while what I mean by that is
that these games are the strategies,
let's say Nash Equilibrium,
it has provable properties.
So it's unlike let's say, deep learning
where you're kind of cross your fingers,
hopefully it'll work. And then after
the fact when you have the weights,
you're still crossing your fingers
and I hope it will work. Uh, here.
You know that the solution qualities
there, this provable solution,
quality guarantees.
Now that doesn't necessarily mean that
the strategies are human. Understandable.
That's a whole other problem.
So as I,
so I think it deep learning
and computational game
theory are in the same boat
in that sense that both are
difficult to understand,
but at least the game
theoretic techniques,
they have these guarantees
of sort of quality.
So did you see business operations,
strategic operations,
even military in the future,
at least the,
the strong candidates being
proposed by automated systems?
Do you see that?
Yeah, I do. I do. But
that's more of a belief,
belief then a and a substantiated
fact depending on where you land,
optimism or pessimism. And that's a
really, to me, that's an exciting future.
Especially if there's a provable
things in terms of optimality.
So looking into the future,
there's a few folks worried about the,
especially you look at the game of poker,
which is probably one of the last
benchmarks in terms of games being solved.
They, they worry about the future and
the existential threats of artificial
intelligence. So the negative
impact in whatever form on society.
Is that something that concerns you as
much or are you more optimistic about the
positive impacts of AI?
Oh, I am much more optimistic about the
positive impacts. So just in my own work,
what we've done so far, but we run
the nation where kidneys change.
Hundreds of people are walking
around alive today, who would it be?
And it's increased employment.
You have,
you have a lot of people now running
kidney changes and at the transplant
centers interacting with
the kidney exchange,
you have extra surgeons, nurses,
anesthesiologists, hospitals,
all of that.
And so,
so employment is increasing from that
and the world is becoming a better place.
Another example is a common
authorial sourcing auctions. We uh,
did 800 large scale combinatorial
sourcing options from 2001 to 2010,
uh, in a previous startup of
mine called combine it. And, um,
we increased the supply chain efficiency
on that $60 billion of spend by 12.6%.
So that's over $6 billion of
efficiency improvement in the world.
And this is not like shifting value
from somebody to somebody else.
Just efficiency improvement
like in trucking,
less empty driving so there's less waste,
less carbon footprint and so on.
It's a huge positive
impact in the near term,
but sort of tea to stay in it for,
for a little longer because I
think game theory has a role
in play here. Well let, let me actually
come back and do that. That is one thing.
I think AI is also going to make
the world much safer. So, uh,
so, so that's another aspect
that often gets overlooked. What,
let me ask this question,
maybe I can speak
to the safer. So I talked to Max
Tegmark and Stuart Russell, uh,
who are very concerned about
existential threats of Ai.
And often the concern is
about value misalignment.
So Ai Systems basically a working,
operating towards goals that are
not the same as human civilization,
human beings. So it seems like game
theory has a role to play there. Uh,
two to make sure the values
are aligned with human beings.
I don't know if that's how
you think about it. If not,
how do you think AI might help
with this problem? Uh, how,
how do you think AI might
make the world safer? Yeah,
I think this value is alignment is a
fairly theoretical worry and I haven't
really seen it in it cause I
do a lot of real applications.
I don't see it anywhere.
Uh,
the closest I've seen it was the following
type of mental exercise really where
I had this argument in the late
eighties when we were building these
transportation optimization systems and
somebody had to hear it and it's a good
idea to have high utilization of assets.
So they told me I take,
why don't you put that as the objective?
And we didn't even pull it as an
objective because I just showed him at,
you know,
if you had that as your objective,
the solution would be the load
your trucks fallen driving circles,
nothing would ever get delivered.
You'd have a hundred percent utilization.
So yeah, I know this phenomenon, I've
known this for over 30 years in about,
but I've never seen it actually be a
problem. Reality in reality. And yes,
if you have the wrong objective,
the AI will optimize that to the hilt
and it's going to hurt more than some
human who's kind of trying to
solve within a half baked way with
some human insight too. But I,
I just haven't seen that
materialize in practice.
There's this gap that you've actually
put your finger on very clearly just now
between theory and reality.
That's very difficult to put into words.
I think it's what you can
theoretically imagine. Uh,
the worst possible case
or even, yeah, I mean,
bad cases and what usually happens
in reality. So for example,
to me, maybe it's something you can
comment on. Uh, having grown up in,
I grew up in the Soviet Union,
you know,
there's currently 10,000 nuclear weapons
in the world and for many decades.
It's a theoretically a surprising to me
that the nuclear war is not broken out.
Do you think about this aspect is from
a game theoretic perspective in general,
why is that true?
A why in theory you could see how
things will go terribly wrong and
somehow yet they have not. Yeah.
So I do think that that about that a lot.
I think the biggest two threats
that we're facing as mankind,
one is climate change and
others nuclear war. So as, as,
so those are my main two worries
that that worry about. And I,
I've tried to do something about climate,
had thought about trying to do something
for climate change twice actually
before two of my startups.
I've actually commissioned studies of
what we could do on those things and we
didn't really find a sweet spot,
but I'm still keeping an eye out on that.
If there's something where we could
actually provide a market's a lotion or
optimizations law or some other
technology solution to problems right now.
Um, like for example, pollution critic
markets was what we were looking at them.
And it was much more,
the lack of political will by those
markets were not so successful rather than
bad market design. So I could go
in and make a Beta market design,
but that wouldn't really move the needle
on the world very much if there's no
political will. And in the u
s you know, the market, uh,
at least the Chicago market was just
shut down, uh, uh, and, and so on.
So it doesn't really help how
great your market design was.
And then the nuclear side,
it's more so global warming
is a more encroaching
problem, you know, nuclear
weapons. I've been here,
it's an obvious problem, has just been
sitting there. So how do you think about,
what is the mechanism design there that
just made everything seem stable and are
you
still extremely worried? I am
still extremely worried. So yeah,
you probably know the simple game
theory of mad. So, so, so, uh, at least,
uh, mutually assured
destruction and it's lazy.
It doesn't require any computation
with small matrix eats.
You can actually convince yourself that
the game is such that nobody wants to
initiate. Hmm. Yeah,
that's a very coarse grained analysis
and it really works in a situation where
you have two superpowers or
small number of super powers.
Now things are very different.
You have a smaller nukes or the threshold
of initiating a smaller and you have
smaller countries and non non nation
actors who make it an org sense.
I won. So it's, I think it's riskier
now than it was maybe ever before.
And what idea application of Ai,
you've talked about a little bit, but what
is the most exciting to you right now?
I mean you,
you're here at nips new Europe's now
you have few excellent pieces of work.
But what are you thinking into the future
with several companies you're doing?
What's the most exciting thing
or one of the exciting things?
The number one thing for me right now
is coming up with these a scalable
techniques for game solving and applying
them into the real world that I was
still very interested in market design
as well and we're doing that in optimize
markets,
but I'm most interested if number one
right now is strategic machine strategy
robot.
Getting that technology out there and
seeing as you were in the trenches doing
applications,
what needs to be actually filled,
what technology gaps
still need to be filled.
So it's so hard to just put your feet on
the table and imagine what needs to be
done. But when you're actually
doing real applications,
the applications tell you
what needs to be done.
And I really enjoy that interaction.
Is it a challenging process to apply
some of the state of the art techniques
you're working on and having the various
players in industry or the military or
people who could really benefit from it,
actually use it?
What's that process like of,
you know,
in autonomous vehicles will work with
automotive companies and they're, uh,
in in many ways are a little bit
old fashioned. It's difficult.
They really want to use this technology.
There's clearly will have
a significant benefit,
but the systems aren't quite in place to
easily have them integrated in terms of
data, in terms of compute, in terms of
all of these kinds of things. So do you,
is that one of the bigger challenges that
you're facing and how you tackle that
challenge?
Yeah,
I think that's always the challenge
that that's kind of slowness and inertia
really of let's do things
the way we've always done it.
You just have to find the
internal champions at the
customer who understand that
hey, things can't be the
same way in the future,
otherwise bad things are going to happen.
And it's in autonomous vehicles.
It's actually very interesting that the
car makers are doing that and they're
very traditional.
But at the same time you have tech
companies who have nothing to do with the
cars or transportation like Google and
Baidu really pushing on autonomous cars.
I find that fascinating.
Clearly you're super excited
about actually these ideas
having an impact in the
world. Uh, in terms of the technology,
in terms of ideas and research.
Are there directions they you're also
excited about whether that's on the,
some of the approaches you talked about
for the imperfect information games,
whether it's applying deep learning,
just some of these problems.
Is there something that you're excited
and in the research side of things? Yeah.
Yeah. Lots of different things
in the game solving. Uh,
so solving even bigger games,
uh, games where you have, um,
more he didn't action of the
play your actions as well. Uh,
poker is a game where really the chance
actions are hidden or some of them are
hidden,
but to play your actions are public.
It multiplayer games of various sorts,
collusion,
a opponent exploitation,
all,
all and an even longer games.
Some games that basically go forever,
but they're not repeated. So seek
extensive on games that go forever.
What would that even look like? How do
you represent that? How do you solve that?
What's an example of a game like
that? Oh, this is the sum of this.
The classic games that you mentioned,
that's a business strategy.
So it's not just modeling
like a particular interaction,
but thinking about the business from
here to eternity or r I c or like let's
say, um, military strategy. So it's
not like war is going to go away.
How do you the think about military
strategy that's going to go forever.
How do you even model that?
How do you know whether a move was
good that you use somebody made and,
and, and, and so on. Uh, so that,
that's kind of one direction.
I'm also very interested in learning
much more scalable techniques for integer
programming.
So we had a nice EML paper this summer
on that for the Automated Algorithm
configuration paper that has
theoretical generalization guarantees.
So if I see these many training examples
and I told my algorithm and this way
it's going to have good performance
on the real distribution,
which have not seen. So we just
kind of interesting that, you know,
algorithm configuration has been
going on now for at least 17 years.
Seriously. And there has not been
any generalization her theory before.
Well this is really exciting and has been,
it's a huge honor to talk to you.
Thank you. Summarize to us.
Thank you for bringing the,
brought us to the world and all
the great work you're doing. Well,
thank you very much. It's
been fun. Good questions.