The following is a conversation
with Peter at bill.
He's a professor at UC Berkeley and
the director of the Berkeley robotics
learning lab.
He's one of the top researchers in the
world working on how we make robots
understand and interact
with the world around them,
especially using imitation and
deeper enforcement learning.
This conversation is part of the MIT
course and artificial general intelligence
and the artificial intelligence podcast.
If you enjoy it,
please subscribe on Youtube,
Itunes,
or your podcast provider of choice or
simply connect with me on Twitter at Lex
Friedman, spelled f, r I. D.
And now here's my conversation
with Peter a bill.
You've mentioned that if there was
one person you could meet you be Roger
Federer.
So let me ask,
when do you think will have a
robot that fully autonomous,
he can beat Roger Federer at tennis,
Roger Federer level player a tennis?
Well first,
if you could make it happen for me
to meet Roger, let me know terms,
getting a robot to be him in tennis.
It's kind of an interesting question
because for a lot of the challenges we
think about in Ai, the software,
it's really the missing piece.
But for something like this,
the hardware is nowhere near either to
really have a robot that can physically
run around the Boston dynamics robots,
they're starting to get there,
but still not really
human level ability to do,
run around and then swing a racket.
So you think that's a hardware problem?
I don't think it's a harder problem only.
I think it's a hardware and a
software problem. I think it's both.
I think they'll, they'll have
independent progress. So I'd say the,
the hardware maybe in 10
15 years and this way,
not grass grass plague. I,
I'm not sure what's Carter? Cras
or clay. The clay involves sliding,
which might be harder to
master actually. Yeah, but you,
you're not limited to a bipedal.
I mean I'm sure there's only
going to build a machine.
It's a whole different question. Of
course if it can, if you can say, okay,
this robot can be on wheels,
it can move around on wheels
and can be designed differently,
then I think that that can be done sooner
probably down a full human humanoid
type of setup.
What do you think his swing a rack,
so you've worked at a basic manipulation,
how hard it do you think is the
task of swinging Arachat would uh,
be able to hit a nice
backhand or a forehand,
let's say, let's say we just
set up stationary, uh, an a
nice robot arm, let's say,
you know,
standard industrial arm and it can wash
the ball calm and then swing the racket.
It's a good question.
I'm not sure it would be
super hard to do.
I mean I'm sure it would require a lot
if we do it with reinforcement learning
would require a lot of trial and error.
It's not going to swing it right the
first time around. But yeah, I don't,
I don't see why I couldn't see anything.
I think it's learnable.
I think if you set up a ball machine,
let's say on one side and then a robot
with a tennis racket on the other side,
I think it's learnable and maybe a little
bit of pre training and simulation.
Yeah, I think that's, I think that's
feasible. I think, I think the swing,
the racket is feasible.
It'd be very interesting to see how
much precision it can get. Okay.
Cause I mean that's,
that's where,
I mean some of the human
players can hit it on the lines,
which is very high precision with spin.
This one is, it is, it is an interesting,
uh, well the RL can learn
to put a spin on the ball.
All you got me interested maybe
some day we'll set this off
your hands
sir. Is basically okay for this
problem. It sounds fascinating,
but for the general
problem of a tennis player,
we might be a little bit farther away.
What's the most impressive thing you've
seen a robot doing? The physical world?
So physically for me it's
the Boston dynamics videos always just
ring home and just super impressed.
Recently, the robot running up the stairs
during the park who are type thing.
I mean, yes, we don't
know what's underneath.
They don't really ride a lot of detail.
But even if it's hard code than than the
neath, which you might or might not be.
Just the physical abilities
of doing that park who are at,
that's a very impressive.
So a lot right there.
Have you met spot many or any of those
robots in person? It's spot mini.
Last year in April at demarce
event that Jeff pieces organizes,
they brought it out there and it
was nicely falling around Jeff,
when Jeff left the room,
they had it follow him along,
which is pretty impressive.
So I think
good. There's some confidence to know
that there's no learning going on on those
robots, the psychology of it. So while
knowing that, while knowing there's not,
if there's any learning going on,
it's very limited.
I met spot mini earlier this year and
knowing everything that's going on,
having one on one interaction.
So I've got to spend some time alone
and there's a immediately a deep
connection on the psychological level.
Even though you know the fundamentals,
how it works, there's something magical.
So do you think about the psychology
of interacting with robots and this
physical world?
Even you just showed me the PR to the
robot and there was a little bit something
like a face head, a little
bit, something like a face.
There's something that
immediately you draws you to it.
Do you think about that aspect of,
of the robotics problem?
Well, it's very hard with Brett
here. We're giving them a name.
Berkeley robot for the elimination of
tedious task is very hard to not think of
the robot as a person and
it like everybody calls him
a he for whatever reason,
but that also makes it more
a person than if it was a it
and it's, it seems pretty natural
to think of it. That would,
this past weekend really struck me of
FCM pepper many times on on videos.
But then I was at an event organized by,
this was by fidelity and they had scripted
pepper to help moderate some sessions
and at scripted pepper to have the
personality of a child a little bit.
And it was very hard to not think of it
as it's own person in some sense because
it was just going to jump in.
It would just jump into conversation and
in very interactive with moderate we'd
be saving, the pepper would just
jump in, hold on, how about me?
Can I participate in this? Doing? And just
like, okay, this is like like a person.
And that was 100% scripted.
And even then it was hard not to have
that sense of somehow there is something
there. So as we have robots
interact in this physical world,
is that a signal that can be used
in reinforcement learning? You've,
you've worked a little
bit in this direction,
but do you think that psychology
can be somehow pulled in?
So that's a question I would say a lot.
A lot of people ask.
And I think part of why they ask it is
there thinking about how unique are we
really still ask people.
Like after they see some results,
they see a computer play go to say
computer do this, that they're like, okay,
but can it really have emotion? Can it
really interact with us in that way?
And then once you're around robots,
you already start feeling it.
And I think that kind of
maybe mythologically the
way that I think of it as if
you run something like
reinforcement learning,
it's about optimizing some objective and
there was no reason that the objective
couldn't be tied into how much does a
person like interacting with
this system and why it could not.
The reinforcement learning
system optimized for the
robot being fun to be around
and why wouldn't it then naturally become
more and more attractive and more and
more maybe like a person or like a pet.
I don't know what it would exactly be,
but more and more have those features
and acquire them automatically.
As long as you can formalize an objective
of what it means to like something.
What, how you exhibit, uh, what's
the ground truth? How do you,
how do you get the reward from human?
Cause you have to somehow collect
that information with the new human,
but you're, you're saying if you
can formulate it as an objective,
it can be learned. There is no reason
it couldn't emerge through learning.
And maybe one way to formulate as an
objective you wouldn't have to necessarily
score and explicitly.
So standard rewards had numbers
and numbers are hard to come by.
I see. It's a 1.5 or 1.7 on some skill.
It's very hard to do for a person,
but much easier is for a person to say,
okay,
what you did the last five minutes was
much nicer than when we did the previous
five minutes.
And that now gives a comparison comparing,
in fact there has been some results that,
for example,
Paul Christian and collaborators
had opening. I had the hopper,
we Joko hopper one legged robot that
flew back flips purely from feedback.
I like this better than that.
That's kind of equally good.
And after a bunch of interactions,
it figured out what it was the person
was asking for it, namely a backflip.
And so I think the same thing, oh,
it wasn't trying to do a backflip,
it was just getting a score from
the comparison score from the person
based on,
uh,
person having a mind in their own
mind what I wanted to do a back flip.
But the robot didn't know what it was
supposed to be doing. It just knew them.
Sometimes the person said this is better,
this is force.
And then the robot figure it out what
the person was actually after it was a
back flip.
And I imagine the same would be true for
things like a more interactive robots
that the robot would figure out over time.
Oh,
this kind of thing apparently
as appreciate it more than
his other kind of thing.
So
when I first picked up a sudden's,
uh,
which is sons reinforcement learning book
before sort of this deep learning,
um,
before the reemergence of neural networks
is a powerful mechanism for machine
learning.
Rl seemed to me like magic.
It was a as beautiful.
So it that seemed like what intelligence
is a RL reinforcement learning.
So,
uh,
how do you think we can possibly learn
anything about the world when they're
award for the actions is delayed,
is so sparse.
Like where is,
why do you think are works?
Why do you think he can learn
anything under such sparser awards?
Whether it's regular reinforcement
learning, deep reinforcement learning,
it's your intuition.
The counterpart of that is why is RL,
why does it need so many samples?
So many experiences to learn from.
Um, because really what's happening
is when you have a sparse reward,
you do something maybe for like,
I dunno,
you'd take a hundred actions and then
you get a reward and maybe get like a
score of three. And I'm like, okay,
three, not sure what that means.
You go again and now I get to,
and now you know that that sequence of a
hundred actions that you did the second
time around,
somehow it was worse than the sequence
of hundred actions he did the first time
around. But that's tough to know which
one of those were better or worse.
Some might have been good
and bad and either one,
and so that's why I need
so many experiences.
But once you have enough experiences,
effectively RLS teasing that apart,
it's turned to say, okay, well
what is consistently there?
When you get a high reward
and what's consistently there,
we can get a lower award.
And then kind of the magic of it as
the policy grant update is to say,
now let's update the neural network
to make the actions that were kind of
precedent when things are good,
more likely and make the actions that
are present when things are not as good,
less likely.
So that's the,
that is the counterpoint,
but it seems like you would need
to run it a lot more than you do.
Even though right now people could
say that is very inefficient,
but it seems to be way more efficient
than one would imagine on paper that the,
the simple updates to the policy,
the policy gradient,
that that somehow you can
learn is executives just said,
what are the common actions that seem
to produce some good results that that
somehow can learn anything.
It seems counterintuitive,
at least did they, is there some
intuition behind that? So yeah,
I think there's a few
ways to think about this.
The way I tend to think about
it mostly originally when,
so when we started working on deep
reinforcement learning here at Berkeley,
which was maybe 2011, 12, 13,
around that time challenge Schulman
was a phd student initially.
Kind of driving it forward here.
And kind of the way we thought about
it at the time was if you think about
rectified linear units or kind of
rectifier type neural networks, um,
what do you get? You get something
that's piecewise linear feedback control.
And if you look at the literature,
uh,
linear feedback control is extremely
successful, can solve many,
many problems surprisingly well.
I remember for example,
when we did the helicopter flight,
if you're in a stationary flight regime,
not a non station but the station,
their flight regime like hover,
you can use linear feedback control
to stabilize and helicopter,
very complex dynamical system.
But the controller is relatively simple.
And so I think that's a big part of
is that if you do feedback control,
even though the system you
control can be very, very complex,
often relatively simple control
architectures can already do a lot.
But then also just linear
is not good enough.
And so one way you can think
of this neural networks is
that the incidences they
tiled a space which people were already
trying to do more by hand or with finite
state machines. Say this linear controller
here, this linear controller here,
neural network learns the towel dispenser,
Linear Controller here at
another leaner controller here.
But it's more subtle than that.
And so it's benefiting from this linear
control aspect is benefiting from the
tiling, but it's somehow telling
it one dimension at a time.
Because if, let's say you have a two
layer network, even the hidden layer,
you make a transition from active to
inactive or the other way around that is
essentially one axes but not access
align but one direction that you change.
And so you have this kind of
very gradual tiling of the space.
We have a lot of sharing between the
linear controllers that towel the space.
And that was always my intuition as to
why to expect that this might work pretty
well.
It's essentially leveraging the fact
that linear feedback control is so good,
but of course not enough.
And this is a gradual tiling of the
space with leaner feedback controls that
share a lot of
expertise across them. So that, that's
a, that's really nice intuition.
What do you think that scales to the more
and more general problems of when you
start going up the number
of control dimensions, uh,
when you start going
down in terms of how often
you get a clean reward signal,
does that intuition carry forward to
those crazy or weird or worlds that we
think of as the real world?
So
I think where things get really tricky
in the real world compared to the things
we've looked at so far with great
success in reinforcement learning is
the timescales,
which takes us to an extreme.
So when you think about the
real world, I mean, I dunno,
maybe some student decided to do
a phd here. Right, okay. That's,
that's a decision that's a
very high level decision.
But if you think about their lives,
I mean any person's life,
it's a sequence of muscle
fiber contractions and
relaxations and that's how you
interact with the world and that's
a very high frequency control thing,
but it's ultimately what you do and how
you affect the world until I guess we
have brain readings and you
can maybe do it differently,
but typically that's how you affect the
world and the decision of doing a phd,
it's like so abstract relative to what
you're actually doing in the world.
And I think that's where credit assignment
becomes just completely beyond what
any current RL algorithm can do.
And we need hierarchical reasoning at a
level that is just not available at all
yet. Where do you think we can pick up
hierarchal reasoning? By which mechanisms?
Yeah,
so maybe let me highlight for that.
I think the limitations are of what
already was done 2030 years ago.
In fact, you'll find reasoning systems
that reason over relatively long horizons,
but the problem is that that we're
not grounded in the real world.
So people would have to hand design,
uh,
some kind of logical
dynamical descriptions of the
world and that didn't tie
into perception and so then tie into
real objects and so forth. And so that,
that was, that was a big
gap. Now with deep learning,
we start having the ability to really
see with sensors process that and
understand what's in the world.
And so it's a good time to try to
bring these things together. One,
I see a few ways of getting there.
One way to get there would be to say deep
learning can get bolted on somehow to
some of these more traditional approaches.
Now bolted on would probably mean you
need to do some kind of end to end
training where you say,
my deep learning processing somehow leads
to a representation that in term uses
some kind of traditional
underlying dynamical, uh,
systems that can be used for
planning. And that's, for example,
the direction of Eve.
Tamara and the North Korea attach here
have been pushing with causal Infigen and
of course other people too that that's
one way can we somehow force it into the
form factor that is amenable to reasoning.
Another direction we've been thinking
about for a long time and didn't any
progress on was more information
theoretic approaches.
So the idea there was that what it means
to take high level action is to taken
choose a latent variable.
Now that tells you a lot about what's
going to be the case in the future because
that's what it means to, to take
a high level auction. I say, okay,
what do I decide I'm going to
navigate to the gas station?
Cause you need to get gas for my car.
Well that will not take five minutes to
get there. But the fact that I get there,
I could already tell that from the high
level action at took much earlier, um,
that we had a very hard
time getting success with.
I'm not saying it's a dead end,
the silly,
but we had a lot of trouble
getting that to work.
And then we start revisiting the notion
of what are we really trying to achieve.
Um, what we're trying to achieve is
not necessarily how he perceived.
We could think about what
this hierarchy give us. Um,
what it's we hope it would give us
this better credit assignment. Um,
Kinda what is better criticized is given,
is giving us,
it gives us faster learning,
right?
And so fast to learning is
ultimate maybe what we're after.
And so that's what we ended up with
the RL squared paper on learning to
reinforcement learning, which
had a time rocky Dwan led. Um,
and that's exactly the metal
learning approach where we say, okay,
we don't know how to design hierarchy.
We know what we want to get from it.
Let's just end to an optimize for one to
get from it and see if it might emerge.
And we saw things emerged,
the amaze navigation had
consistent motion down hallways,
which is what you want a
hierarchical control should say,
I want to go down this hallway. And then
when there is an option to take a turn,
I can decide whether to
take a turn in naught.
And repeat even had the notion of
where have you been before or not,
do not revisit places you've been before.
Um,
it still didn't scale yet to the real
world kind of scenarios I think you had in
mind,
but it was some sign of life that maybe
you can metal learn these hierarchal
concepts.
I mean, it seems like, uh, through
these metal learning concepts,
get at the,
what I think is one of the hardest
and most important problems of AI,
which is transfer learning.
So this generalization,
how far along this journey
towards building general
systems are we being able to
do transfer learning?
Well,
so there's some signs that you
can generalize a little bit,
but do you think we're on the right path
or s totally different breakthroughs
and needed to be able to
transfer knowledge between
different learned models?
Yeah,
I'm pretty tired on this and that.
I think there are some very
of the day they're there.
There's just some very impressive
results already, right? I mean, yes.
I would say when even with the initial,
kind of a big breakthrough in 2000
with Alex snap, right. Did initial,
the initial thing is, okay great,
this does better on image net,
the hands image recognition,
but then immediately thereafter there
was of course the notion that wow,
what was learned on image net and
you and I want to solve a new task,
you can fine tune Alex net for new tasks
and that was often found to be the even
bigger deal that you learned
something that was reusable,
which was not often the case before.
Usually machine learning you learned
something for one scenario and that was it
and that's really exciting.
I mean that's a huge application.
That's probably the biggest success of
transfer learning to date in terms of
scope and impact.
That was a huge breakthrough.
And then recently I feel like similar
kind of by scaling things up,
it seems like this has been
expanded upon like people training,
given bigger networks they might transfer
even better if you looked out for
example,
some of the opening I results on language
models and some of the recent Google
results on language models they are learn
for just prediction and then they get
reused for other tasks.
And so I think there is something there
where somehow if you train a big enough
model and enough things it seems to
transfer some deep mine results that I
thought were very impressive
to unreal results where um,
it was learning to navigate mazes
in ways where it wasn't just doing
reinforcement learning but it had
other objectives it was optimizing for.
So I think there's a lot of
interesting results already.
I think maybe where it's hard to wrap
my head around this to which extent l or
when they would call something
generalization, right?
Or the levels of generalization
involved in this different tasks.
All right,
so you draw this by the way,
just to frame things I've heard you
say somewhere is the difference between
learning to master versus learning.
To generalize that it's a nice
line to think about and it gets,
you're saying there's a gray area of
what learning to master and learning to
generalize where one starts.
And the might have heard this,
I might never heard it somewhere else.
And I think it might've been one of one
of your interviews and maybe the one
with Yosha Benjamin,
I'm not a hundred percent sure,
but I liked the example and I'm to
not sure who it was.
But the example was essentially if you
use current deep learning techniques,
what we're doing to predict, um,
let's say they're out of motion of,
of um, of our planets, it
would do pretty well. Um,
but then now if a massive new
mass enters our solar system,
it would proud not predict
what will happen. Right.
And that's a different kind
of channelization that's
a generalization that
relies on the ultimate,
simplest,
simplest explanation that we have
available today to explain the motion of
planets where I was just pattern
recognition could predict our current soil
system motion. Well, no problem.
And so I think that's an example of a
kind of generalization that is a little
different from what we've achieved so far.
And it's not clear if just,
you know,
regularizing more enforcing it to come
up with a simpler, simpler, simpler,
simpler. But that's what physics
researchers do, right? They say,
can I make this even simpler?
How simple can I get this?
What's the simplest equation that
can explain everything? All right.
The master equation for the
entire dynamics of the universe.
We haven't really pushed that direction
as hard. And in the planning I would say,
I'm not sure if it should be pushed,
but it seems a kind of general
history you'd get from that,
that you don't get in our
current methods so far.
So I just talked to Vladimir
vap. Nick, for example,
who was a statistician,
a statistical learning and he kind of
dreams of creating these are the a equals
e equals mc squared for a learning.
Right? The general theory of learning.
Do you think that's a fruitless pursuit
in a near term in within
the next several decades?
I think that's a really
interesting pursuit. And uh,
and in the following sense in that
there is a lot of evidence that
the brain is pretty modular. And so I
wouldn't maybe think of it as the theory,
maybe the underlying theory,
but more kind of the principal
were there have been findings where
people who are blind we'll use the part
of the brand usually used for vision for
other functions. And even after, uh,
some kind of, if people get
rewired in some way they might,
I'm able to reuse parts of
their brand for other functions.
And so what that suggests is some kind
of modularity and I think it is a pretty
natural thing to strive for to
see can we find that modularity?
Can we find this thing?
Of course it's not every,
every part of the brain
is not exactly the same.
Not Everything can be rewired arbitrarily.
But if you think of
things like the Neocortex,
which a pretty big part of the brain
that seems fairly modular from what the
findings so far,
can you design something equally modular
and if you can just grow it becomes
more capable probably.
I think that would be the
kind of interesting underlying
principle to shoot for
that is not unrealistic.
Do you think
you prefer math or empirical trial and
error for the discovery of the essence of
what it means to do something intelligent.
So reinforcement learning and bodies,
both groups, right? The prove
that something converges,
prove the bounds. And then at the same
time a lot of those successes that are,
well let's try this and see if it works.
So which do you gravitate towards?
How do you think of those
two parts of your brain?
So
maybe I would prefer we can
make progress with mathematics.
And the reason maybe I would prefer that
is because often if you have something
you can mathematically formalize,
you can leap frog a lot of experimentation
and experimentation takes a long time
to get through and a lot of trial
and error kind of reinforcement,
letting your research process.
Um,
but you need to do a lot of trial and
error before you get to a success.
So if we can leap out at, to my
mind, that's what the math is about.
And hopefully once you do a bunch of
experiments, you start seeing a pattern.
You can do some derivations that leapfrog
some experiments. But I agree with you.
I mean in practice a lot of the progress
has been such that we have not been
able to find the math that allows us to
leapfrog ahead and we are kind of making
gradual progress,
wants to out at time a new experiment
here in new experiment there that gives us
new insights and gradually building up
but not getting to something yet where
we're just, okay, here is some equation
and now explains how, you know,
that would be have been two years
of experimentation to get there.
But this tells us what
the result's going to be.
I'm unfortunately not so much as not
so much yet, but your hope is there
in trying to teach uh,
robots or systems to do every
day task or even in simulation,
what, what do you think you're
more excited about imitation,
learning or self play.
So letting robots learn from humans or
letting robots plan their own to try to
figure out and then their
own way and eventually play,
eventually interact with humans
or solve whatever problem is.
What's the more exciting to you?
What's more promising you think
as a research direction. So
when, when we look at self play,
what's so beautiful about it is because
back to kind of the challenges and
reinforcement learning. So the
challenge for me and forced planting,
it's getting signal.
And if you don't never succeed,
you don't get any signal in self play.
You're on both sides.
So one of you succeeds and the
beauty is also one of you fails.
And so you see the contrast,
you see the one version of me that
it better than the other version.
And so every time you play
yourself you get signal.
And so whenever you can turn
something into self play,
you're in a beautiful situation where
you can naturally learn much more quickly
than in most other reinforced
wanting environments. So I think,
I think if somehow we can turn more
reinforcement learning problems into self
play formulations, that would
go really, really far. So far.
South play has been largely around games
where the risk Nashville opponents,
but if we could do self play
for other things and let's say,
and I know a robot
learns to build a house,
I mean that's a pretty advanced
thing to try to do for our robot,
but maybe tries to build
a hut or something.
If that can be done through self play,
it would learn a lot more quickly
if somebody can figure it out.
And I think that would be something
where it goes closer to kind of the
mathematical leapfrogging where somebody
figures out a formalism to say, okay,
any RL problem by playing
this and this idea,
you can turn it into self play problem
where you get signal a lot more easily.
Reality is many problems who don't
know how to turn to self play.
And so either we need to provide detailed
reward that doesn't just reward for
achieving a goal,
but rewards for making progress.
And that becomes time consuming.
And once you're starting to do that,
let's say you want a
robot to do something,
you need to give all this detailed reward.
Well,
why not just give a demonstration,
right?
Because why not just show the robot and
now the question is how do you show the
robot?
One way to show is to teleoperate to robot
and then the robot really experienced
this things and that's nice cause that's
really high signal to noise ratio there.
Then we've done a lot of that and you
teach her about skills in just 10 minutes.
You can teach a robot a
new basic skill like okay,
pick up the bottle and
place it somewhere else.
That's a skill no matter
where the bottle starts,
maybe it always goes up to a target or
something that's fairly used to teach her
about with telly off.
Now what's even more interesting if you
can now teach her about through third
person learning where the robot watches
you do something and doesn't experience
it but just watches it and says,
okay,
well if you're showing me that that
means I should be doing this and I'm not
going to be using your hand because I
don't get to control your hand but I'm
going to use my hand.
I'd do that mapping.
And so that's where I think one of the
big breakthroughs has happened this year.
This was led by a Chelsea Finn here.
Um,
it's almost like learning and machine
translation for demonstrations where you
have a human demonstration and the robot
learns to translate it into what it
means for the robot to do it.
And that was a metal learning from English
and learn from one to get the other.
Um, and that I think opens up a lot of
opportunities to learn a lot more quickly.
So my focus is in autonomous vehicles.
Do you think this approach of
third person watching is a Ma the,
the autonomous driving is
amenable to this kind of approach?
So for autonomous driving,
I would say it's their
person is slightly easier.
And the reason I'm going to say slightly
easier to do with third person is
because the hard dynamics
are very well understood.
So the easier than a first
person you mean or easier.
So I think that distinction between third
person and first person is not a very
important distinction for
autonomous driving. Yeah,
they're very similar because the
distinction is really about who turns the
steering wheel or maybe I'll,
let me put it differently.
How it gets from a point
where you are now to a point,
let's say a couple of meters in front
of you and that's a problem that's very
well understood and that's the only
distinction between third and first person
there.
Whereas with robot,
many places and interaction forces
are very complex and it's still a very
different thing. Um,
for autonomous driving,
I think there is still the
question imitation versus RL.
So imitation gives you a lot more signal.
I think we're,
imitation is lacking and
needs some extra machinery.
Is it
okay?
Doesn't and it's normal format. It
doesn't think about goals or objectives.
And of course there are
versions of imitation,
learning, inverse reinforcement,
any type imitational in which
I'm also thinks about goals.
I think then we're getting much closer.
But I think it's very hard to think
of a fully reactive har generalizing.
Well if it really doesn't have a notion
of objectives to generalize well to the
kind of general that you would want,
you'd want more than just that reactivity
that you get from just behavioral
cloning.
Slash supervise learning.
Okay.
So a lot of the work,
whether it's self play or even imitation
learning would benefit significantly
from simulation,
from effect as simulation.
And you're doing a lot of stuff in
the physical world and in simulation.
Do you have hope for greater
and greater power of simulation,
Lou being boundless eventually to where
most of what we need to operate in the
physical world,
what could be simulated to degree that's
directly transferable to the physical
world or are we still
very far away from that?
So,
okay.
I think we could even rephrase
that question in some sense please.
So the power of simulation,
right,
as similar as get better and better of
course becomes stronger and we can learn
more assimilation.
But there's also another version
which is where you said assimilate,
it doesn't even have to be that precise
as long as it's somewhat representative.
And instead of trying to get one simulator
that is sufficiently precise to learn
in and transfer really
well to the real world.
I'm going to build many simulators,
ensemble of simulators,
ensemble of simulators.
Not any single one of them is sufficiently
representative of the real world such
that it would work if you train in there.
But if you trained in all of them,
then there was something that's good in
all of them. The real world will just be,
you know, another one I've done, but
that's not identical to any one of them,
but just another one of them.
Now, the sample from the
distribution of simulators,
we do live in a simulation. So, uh,
this is just one, one other one.
I'm not sure about that.
But yeah,
it's definitely a very advanced
simulator of it is. Yeah.
Pretty good one.
I've talked to us to rustle something.
You think about it a little bit too,
of course you're like really
trying to build these systems,
but do you think about the future of AI?
A lot of people have concern about safety.
How do you think about AI safety as you
build robots that are operating in the
physical world? What, what is, um, yeah,
how do you approach this problem
in an engineering kind of way?
In a systematic way.
Okay.
So,
okay,
what a robot is doing things to kind of
have a few notions of safety to worry
about.
One is that through about as physically
strong and of course could do a lot of
damage. Um, same for cars, which we
can think of as robots to in some way.
And this could be
completely unintentional,
so it could be not the kind of
longterm AI safety concerns that, okay,
AI is smarter than us and now what do we
do? But it could be just very practical.
Okay. This robot, if it makes a mistake,
whether the results going to be,
of course simulation comes in a lot
there too. Test testing, simulation.
It's a difficult question and I'm always
wondering like, oh, there's one there.
Let's say you look at it,
let's go back to driving because a lot
of people know driving well of course.
Well what do we do to test
somebody for driving right to,
to get a driver's license?
What do they really do?
I mean you fill out some tests and
then you'd drive and I mean we're a few
minutes of Bourbon California.
That driving test is just,
you drive around the block,
pull over you to do a stop sign
successfully and then you know,
you've pulled over again and you
pretty much done and you're like, okay,
if a self driving car did die,
would you trust it that it can
drive? And I'd be like, no,
that's not enough for me to trust it.
But somehow for humans we've figured
out that somebody being able to do that,
it's representative of them being
able to do a lot of other things.
And so I think somehow
for humans we figured out
representative tests of what it
means. If you can do this where you can
really do of course testing, you must,
you must don't want to
be tested at all times.
Self driving cars or robots
can be tested more often.
Probably you can have replicates that
get tested are known to be identical
because they use the same
neural net and so forth.
But still I feel like we don't have this
kind of unit tests or proper tests for
for robots.
And I think there's something very
interesting to be thought about there.
Especially as you update things,
your software improves,
you have a better self driving cars,
you update it.
How do you know it's indeed more capable
on everything than what you had before
that you didn't have any
bad things creep into it.
So I think that's a very
interesting direction of
research that there is no real
solution yet except that somehow
for us we do, cause we say,
okay you have a driving test you passed,
you can go on the road now and you must
have accents that every like million or
10 million miles,
some pretty phenomenal compared to
that short test that is being done.
So let me ask a,
you've mentioned,
you've mentioned that Andrew
Ang by example showed you
the value of kindness and
Tim,
do you think the space of a
policies,
good policies for humans and for AI is
populated by policies that with kindness
or ones that are the opposite,
exploitation,
even evil.
So if you just look at the Sea of policies
we operate under as human beings or
if AI system had to
operate in this real world,
do you think it's really easy to find
policies that are full of kindness like
when naturally fall into them or is it
like a very hard optimization problem?
I mean there is kind of to optimizations
happening for humans, right? So for you,
most just kind of the very
long term optimization,
which ever evolution has done for us,
and we're kind of predisposed
to like certain things.
And that's something that's what makes
our learning easier. Because I mean,
we know things like pain and,
uh,
hunger and thirst and the fact that we
know about those as not something that we
were taught that's kind of
innate when we're hungry,
we're unhappy when we're thirsty, we're
unhappy, won't have Penn, were unhappy.
And ultimately evolution built that
into us to think about this thing.
So I think there is a notion that it
seems somehow humans evolved in general to
prefer to get along and in some ways,
but at the same time also
to be very territorial and
can of centric to their own
tribe.
Is it like,
it seems like that's the kind of
space we conversed onto it. I mean,
I'm not an expert in anthropology,
but it seems like we're very kind
of good within our own tribe,
but need to be taught to
be nice to other tribes.
Well, if you look at Steven Pinker, he
highlights is pretty nicely. And, uh, uh,
better,
better angels of our nature where he
talks about violence decreasing over time
consistently. So whatever
tension, whatever teams we pick,
it seems that the long arc of history
goes towards us getting along more and
more. So. I hope so. Uh,
so do you think that,
do you think is possible to
cheat, teach, Rl base robots, the,
this kind of kindness, this kind
of ability to interact with humans,
this kind of policy even to, let
me ask, let me ask a fun one.
Do you think it's possible teach RL
base robot to love a human being and to
inspire that human to love
the robot back so to like, uh,
RL based a algorithm that
leads to a happy marriage?
Okay,
that's an interesting question. Maybe
I'll, I'll, I'll, I'll answer it with,
with another question,
right? Because I mean it's,
but I'll come back to it. So another
question I can have is, okay. I mean, how,
how close to some people's happiness
get from interacting with just a really
nice,
okay
dog. I mean, dogs, you come home,
that's what dogs do. They greet you,
they're excited, makes you happy when
you come home to your door. It just like,
okay,
this is exciting.
They're always happy when I'm here and
if they don't greet you because maybe
whatever your partner took them
on a trip or something, you,
you might not be nearly as happy when
you get home. Right. And so the kind of,
it seems like the level of reasoning
a dog has is, is pretty sophisticated,
but then it's still not yet at
the level of, of human reasoning.
And so it seems like we don't even need
to achieve human level reasoning to get
like very strong affection with humans.
And so my thinking is why not?
Right? Why? Why couldn't with an AI,
couldn't we achieve the kind of level
of affection that humans feel among each
other or with friendly
animals and so forth?
It's a question, is it a good thing for
us or not that, that's another thing,
right? Because I mean,
but I don't see why not.
Why not? Um, so Eli Musk
says love is the answer.
Maybe he should say love
is the objective function.
And then RL is the answer.
Maybe.
Peter, thank you so much. I don't
want to take up more of your time.
Thank you so much for talking today.
Well, likewise. Thanks for coming. Bye.
Great to have you visit.