Today we will talk about deep
reinforcement learning.
The question we would like to explore is
to which degree we can teach systems to
act,
to perceive and act in this world from
data.
So let's take a step back and think of
what is the full range of tasks than
artificial intelligence system needs to
accomplish.
Here's the stack from top to bottom,
top the input bottom output,
the environment at the top,
the world that the agent is operating in
sensed by sensors taking in the world
outside and converting it to raw data
and interpretable by machines,
sensor data,
and from that raw sensor data,
you extract features.
You extract structure from that data
such that you can input it,
makes sense of it,
discriminate,
separate,
understand the data,
and as we discussed,
you form higher and higher order
representations,
a hierarchy of representations based on
which the machine learning techniques
can then be applied.
Once the machine learning techniques,
the understanding,
as I mentioned,
converts the data into features,
into higher order representations and
into simple actionable,
useful information.
We aggregate that information into
knowledge,
would take the pieces of knowledge
extracted from the data through the
machine learning techniques and to build
a taxonomy,
a library of knowledge,
and would that knowledge we reason an
agent is tasked to reason,
to aggregate,
to connect pieces of data seen in the
recent past or the distant past to make
sense of the world that's operating in
and finally to make a plan of how to act
in that world based on its objectives
based on what he wants to accomplish.
As I mentioned,
a simple but commonly accepted
definition of intelligence is a system
that's able to accomplish complex goals,
so system that's operating in an
environment and this world must have a
goal,
must have an objective function or
reward function and based on that it
forms of plan and takes action and
because they're operates in many cases
in the physical world,
it must have tools,
effectors with which it applies to
actions to change.
Something about the world.
That's the full stack of an artificial
intelligence system that acts in the
world.
And the question is,
what kind of task can such a take on
what kind of tasks can an artificial
intelligence system learn?
As we understand ai today,
we will talk about the advancement of
deeper enforcement learning approaches
and some of the fascinating ways it's
able to take much of the stack and treat
it as an end to end learning problem.
But we look at games,
we'll look at simple formalized worlds.
While it's still impressive,
beautiful and unprecedented
accomplishments.
It's nevertheless formal tasks.
Can we then move beyond games into
expert tasks of medical diagnosis,
of design and into natural language,
and finally the human level tasks of
emotion,
imagination,
consciousness.
That's once again,
review the stack and practicality in the
tools.
We have the input for robots operating
in the world from cars to humanoid to
drones as Lidar,
camera radar,
gps,
stereo cameras,
audio microphone,
networking for communication,
and the various ways to measure
kinematics with Imu.
The raw sensory data is then processed
features.
The forum to representations are formed
and multiple higher and higher order
representations.
That's what deep learning gets us before
neural networks.
Before the advent of,
before the recent successes of neural
networks to go deeper and therefore be
able to form high order representations
of the data that was done by experts by
human experts today,
networks are able to do that.
That's the representation piece and on
top of the representation piece,
the final layers.
These networks are able to accomplish
the supervised learning task,
the generative tasks,
and the unsupervised clustering tasks
through machine learning.
That's what we talked about a little in
lecture one and we'll continue tomorrow
and Wednesday.
That's supervised learning and you could
think about the output of those networks
as simple,
clean,
useful,
valuable information.
That's the knowledge and that knowledge
can be in the form of single numbers.
It can be regression,
continuous variables.
It can be a sequence of numbers,
it can be images,
audio sentences,
text,
speech.
Once that knowledge is extracted and
aggregated,
how do we connect it in multi
resolution?
Always form hierarchies of ideas,
connect ideas.
The trivial silly example is connecting
images,
activity recognition and audio.
For example,
if it looks like a duck,
quacks like a duck and swims like a
duck,
we do not currently have approaches that
effectively integrate this information
to produce a higher confidence estimate
that is in fact the duck and the
planning piece.
The task of taking the sensory
information,
fusing the sensory information,
and making action control and longer
term plans based on that information,
as we will discuss today are more and
more amenable to the learning approach
to the deep learning approach,
but to date have been the most
successful as non learning optimization
based approaches like with the several
of the guest speakers would have,
including the creator of this robot
atlas in Boston Dynamics.
So the question how much of the stack
can be learned and to end from the input
to the output.
We know we can learn the representation
and the knowledge from the
representation and to knowledge even
with the kernel methods of Svm and
certainly with with neural networks.
Mapping from representation to
information has been where the primary
success and machine learning over the
past three decades has been mapping from
raw sensory data to knowledge.
That's where the success,
the automated representation,
learning of deep learning has been a
success,
going straight from raw data to
knowledge.
The open question for us today and
beyond is if we can expand the red box
there of what can be learned end to end
from sensory data to reasoning,
so aggregating for me higher
representations of the extract of
knowledge and forming plans and acting
in this world from the raw sensory data,
we will show the incredible fact that
we're able to do learn exactly what's
shown here and to end with deeper
enforcement learning on trivial tasks in
a generalizable way.
The question is whether that can then
move on to real world tasks of
autonomous vehicles,
of humanoid,
robotics and so on.
That's the open question.
So today let's talk about reinforcement
learning.
There's three types of machine learning.
Supervised unsupervised are the
categories that the extremes in relative
to the amount of human and human input
that's required for supervised learning.
Every piece of data that's used for
teaching these systems is first labeled
by human beings and unsupervised
learning on the right is no data is
labeled by beings in between is some
sparse input from humans.
Semi supervised learning is when only
part of the data is provided by humans.
Ground Truth and the rest was being
first gen analyzed by the system,
and that's what reinforcement learning
falls reinforcement learning as shown
there with the cats.
As I said,
every successful presentation must
include cats.
They're supposed to be Pavlov's cats and
a ringing a bell,
and every time they ring a bell,
they're given food and they learn this
process.
The goal of reinforcement learning is to
learn from sparse reward data from learn
from spar,
supervised data,
and take advantage of the fact that in
simulation or in the real world,
there is a temporal consistency to the
world.
There is a temporal dynamics that
follows from state to state to state
through time and so you can propagate
information even if the information that
you received about the supervision.
The ground truth is sparse.
You can follow that information back
through time to infer something about
the reality of what happened before then
even if your reward signals were weak,
so it's using the fact that the physical
world evolves through time in some,
some sort of predictable way to take
sparse information and generalize it
over the entirety of the experience as
being learned.
So we apply this to two problems today.
We'll talk about deep traffic as a
methodology,
as a,
as a way to introduce deeper
enforcement.
Learning.
The deep traffic is a competition that
we ran last year and expanded
significantly this year and I'll talk
about some of the details and how the
folks in this room can on your
smartphone today or if you have a laptop
training agent while I'm talking
training a neural network in the
browser.
Some of the things you've added our.
We've added the capability.
We've now turned it into a multiagent
deep reinforcement learning problem
where he can control up to 10 cars
within your own network.
Perhaps less significant but pretty cool
is the ability to customize the way the
agent looks so you can upload and people
have to an absurd degree have already
begun doing so,
uploading different images instead of
the car that's shown there as long as it
maintains the dimensions.
Shown here is a space x rocket.
The competition is hosted on the website
self driving cars that mit.edu/deep
traffic.
We'll return to this later.
The code is on get hub with some more
information,
a starter code and the paper describing
some of the fundamental insights that
will help you win at this competition is
an archive,
so from supervised learning and lecture
one to today.
Supervised learning we can think of is
memorization of ground true data in
order to form representations that
generalizes from that Ground Truth.
Reinforcement learning is we can think
of as a way to brute force propagate
that information,
the sparse information through time to
to assign quality reward to state that
does not directly have a reward to make
sense of this world.
When the rewards a sparse but are
connected through time.
You can think of that as reasoning,
so the connection through time is
modeled in most reinforcement learning
approach is very simply that there's an
agent taken an action in the state and
receiving a reward,
and the agent operating in an
environment executes an action,
receives an observed state and use state
and receives the award.
This process continues over and over and
some examples we can think of any of the
video games,
some of which we'll talk about today,
like Atari breakout as the environment.
The agent is the paddle.
Each action that the agent takes has an
influence on the evolution of the
environment and the success is measured
by some reward mechanism.
In this case,
points are given by the game and every
game has a different point scheme that
must be converted normalized until a way
that's interpretable by the system and
the goal is to maximize those points,
maximize the reward.
The continuous problem of card poll by
balancing the goal is to balance the
pole on top of a moving cart.
The state is the angle that angular
speed,
the position,
the horizontal velocity,
the actions are the horizontal force
applied to the cart,
and the award is one at each time step.
If the pole is still upright,
all the first person shooters,
the video games,
and now star craft the,
uh,
strategy games in case of first person
shooter and doom.
What is the goal?
The environment is the game that goes to
eliminate all opponents.
The state is the raw game.
Pixels coming in.
The actions is moving up,
down,
left,
right,
and so on.
And the reward is positive when
eliminating and opponent and negative.
When the agent has eliminated industrial
robotics,
been packing with a robotic arm,
the goal is to pick up a device from a
box and put it into a container.
The state is the raw pixels of the real
world that the robot observes the
actions or the possible actions with the
robot that different degrees of freedom
and moving through those degrees,
moving the different actuators to
realize the position of the arm,
and then award is positive on placing a
device successfully and negative.
Otherwise,
everything can be modeled in this way.
Mark off decision process as a state,
as zero action,
a zero and reward received and you state
is achieved.
Again,
Action Reward State Action Award,
state until a terminal state is,
is reached,
and the major components of
reinforcement learning is a policy,
some kind of plan of what to do in every
single state.
What kind of action to perform a value
function,
uh,
some kind of sense of what is a good
state to be in,
of what is a good action to take in a
state and sometimes a model
that the agent represents the
environment with some kind of sense of
the environment.
It's operating in the dynamics of that
environment that's useful for making
decisions about actions.
Let's take a trivial example,
a grid world,
a three by four,
12 squares where you start at the bottom
left and their task with walking about
this world to maximize reward.
The award that the top right is a plus
one and a one square below that is a
negative one.
And every step you take is a punishment
or as a negative reward of zero point
zero four.
So what is the optimal policy in this
world?
Now,
when everything is deterministic,
perhaps this is the policy.
When you start at the bottom left,
well,
because every step hurts,
every step has a negative reward.
Then you want to take the shortest path
to the maximum square with a maximum
reward.
When the state space is non
deterministic,
as presented before,
with the probability of point eight,
when you choose to go up,
you go up.
But with probability point one,
you go left and point one,
you go right,
unfair.
Again,
much like life,
that would be the optimal policy.
What is the key observation here that
every single in the space must have a
plan
because you can't because then a non
deterministic aspect of the control,
you can't control where are going to end
up.
So you must have a plan for every place
that's the policy.
Having an action,
an optimal action to take in every
single state.
Now,
suppose we change their reward structure
and for every step we take as a negative
or award is a negative two,
so it really hurts.
There's a high punishment for every
single step we take.
So no matter what,
we always take the shortest path,
the optimal policies to take the
shortest path to the to the only spot on
the board that doesn't result in
punishment.
If we decrease the reward of each step
two negative point one,
the policy changes were there a some
extra degree of wandering encouraged,
and as we go further and further in,
lowering the punishment does before to
negative zero point zero,
four more.
Wandering and wandering is allowed.
And when we finally turned the reward
into positive,
so every step it,
every step is increases the award.
Then there's a significant incentive to
to stay on the board without ever
reaching the destination.
Kind of like college for a lot of
people.
So the value function,
the way we think about the value of the
estate or the value of anything in the
environment is the reward we're likely
to receive in the future and the way we
see the reward we're likely to receive
as we discount the future award because
we can't always count on it,
hair or gamma further and further out
into the future.
More and more discounts decreases the
era,
the the importance of that reward
received and a good strategy is taking
the summer of these rewards and
maximizing it,
maximizing discounted future award.
That's what reinforcement learning hopes
to achieve.
And with cue learning,
we use any policy to estimate the value
of taking an action in the state.
So off policy,
forget policy,
we move about the world and use the
bellman equation here on the bottom to
continuously update our estimate of how
good a certain action is in a certain
state.
So we don't need this.
This allows us to operate in a much
larger space in a much larger action
space.
We move about this world or simulation
or in the real world,
taking actions and updating our estimate
of how good certain actions are over
time.
The new state that the left is the is
the update of value.
The old state is the starting value for
the equation and we update that old
state estimation with,
uh,
some of the reward received by taking
action as a tax action,
a in status,
and the maximum reward that's possible
to be received in the following states.
Discounted that update is decreased with
the learning rate.
The higher the learning rate,
the more value we,
the,
the faster we learn,
the more value we assigned to new
information.
That's simple.
That's it.
That's cute.
Learning as simple update rule allows us
to,
to explore the world and as we explore,
get more and more information about
what's good to do in this world,
and there's always a balance in the
various problem spaces we'll discuss.
There's always a balance between
exploration and exploitation.
As you form a better and better estimate
of the function of what actions are good
to take,
you start to get a sense of what is the
best action to take,
but it's not a perfect sense.
It's still an approximation and so
there's value of exploration,
but the better and better your estimate
becomes less and less.
Exploration has a benefit,
so usually want to explore a lot in the
beginning and less and less so towards
the end and when we finally released the
system out into the world and wish it to
operate as best,
then we have it operate as a greedy
system,
always taking the optimal action
according to the q,
a q value function and everything I'm
talking about now is parametrized and
our parameters that are very important
for winning the deep traffic
competition,
which is using this very algorithm
within your own network as a score.
So for simple table representation of a
function where the y axis to state four
states s one,
two,
three,
four,
and the x axis is actions a,
one,
two,
three,
four.
We can think of this table as randomly
initiated or initiated initialized in
any kind of way that's not
representative of actual reality.
And as we move about the world and we
take actions,
we update this table with a bellman
equation shown up top and here slides
now are online.
You can see a simple pseudo code
algorithm of how to update it.
I to run this bellman equation and over
the approximation becomes the optimal q
table.
The problem is when that cute table,
it becomes exponential in size.
When we take in raw sensor information
as we do with cameras with deep crash or
deep traffic sticking the full grid
space and taking that information,
the Ra,
the Ra grid pixels of deep traffic.
When you take the arcade games here,
they're taking the raw pixels of the
game or when we take go the game of go
when it's taking the units,
um,
the,
the board,
the raw state of the board as the input,
the potential state space,
the number of possible combinatorial
variations of what states as possible is
extremely large,
larger than we can certainly hold the
memory and larger than we can ever be
able to accurately approximate through
the bellman equation over time to
simulation
through the simple update of the
equation.
So this is where deep reinforcement
learning comes in.
Neural networks are really good
approximators.
They're really good at exactly this task
of learning this kind of queue table.
So as we started with supervised
learning,
when all networks help us memorize
patterns,
using supervised ground truth data,
and we'll move to reinforcement learning
that hopes to propagate outcomes to
knowledge.
Deep learning allows us to do so.
A much larger state spaces are much
larger action spaces,
which means it's generalizable,
it's much more capable to deal with the
raw stuff of sensory data,
which means it's much more capable to
deal with a broad variation of real
world applications,
and it does so because it's able to
learn the representations as we've
discussed on Monday.
They're understanding comes from
converting the raw sensor information
into into simple,
useful information based on which the
action in this particular state can be
taken in the same exact way,
so instead of the queue table,
instead of this queue function with
plugging in your network where they
input is the state space.
No matter how complex and the output is
a value for each of the actions that you
could take.
Input is the state.
Opera is the value of the function.
It's simple.
This is deep q network dqn at the core
of the success at deep mind.
A lot of the cool stuff you see about
video games,
dqn or variants of dqs or play.
This is what a first with a nature
paper,
deep mind,
the success came of playing the
different games including Atari Games.
So how are these things trained?
Very similar to supervise learning.
The bellman equation,
laptop takes the reward and the
discounted expected reward from future
states.
The loss function here for neural
network.
Then you'll network learns with the loss
function.
It takes the reward received at the
current state.
Does the forward pass through in your
network to estimate the value of the
future state of the best action to take
in the future state and then subtracts
that from the forward pass through the
network for the current state of action.
So you take the difference between what
your Acu estimator,
than your own network believes the value
of the current state is,
and what it more likely as to be based
on the value of the future states that
are reachable based on the actions you
can take.
Here's the algorithm.
Input is the state output as the q value
for each action or in this diagram and
as a state of inaction,
and the output is the q value.
It's very similar architectures,
so given the transition of s a r s prime
as current state taken an action,
we're seeing your reward and achieving
as prime state.
The update is do a feed forward past to
the network for the current state,
do a feed forward,
pass for each of the possible actions
taken in the next state,
and that's how we compute the two parts
of the loss function and the update the
weights using backpropagation.
Again,
last function backpropagation is how the
network is trained.
This has actually been around for much
longer than deep mind.
A few tricks made made it really work.
Experience replays the biggest one,
so as the games are played through
simulation or if it's a physical system
as it acts in the world,
it's actually collecting the
observations into a library of
experiences and that training is
performed by randomly sampling the
library in the past by randomly sampling
that previous experiences in batches.
So you're not always training on the
natural continuous evolution to the
system you're training on randomly
picked batches of those experiences.
That's a huge.
It's a.
it's a,
seems like a subtle trick,
but it's a really important one.
So the system doesn't overfit a
particular evolution of,
of,
uh,
of the game of the simulation.
Uh,
another important,
again,
subtle trick as in a lot of deep
learning approaches,
the subtle tricks make all the
difference is fixing the target network
for the last function.
If you notice,
you have to use the neural network,
the neural network,
the Gq,
I network to estimate the value of the
current state and action pair and the
next.
So using it multiple times.
And as you perform that operation,
you're updating the network,
which means that target function inside
that lost function is always changing.
So you're,
the very nature of your loss function is
changing all the time is you're
learning.
And that's a big problem for stability
that can create big problems for the
learning process.
So this little trick is to fix the
network and only update it every say
thousand steps.
So as you train the network,
the network that's used to compute the
target function inside the last function
is fixed.
It produces a more stable computation on
the loss function.
So the ground doesn't shift under you as
you're trying to find a minimal for the
loss function.
The last function doesn't change and
unpredictable,
difficult to understand ways and reward
clipping,
which is always true with general.
Those systems that are operating a
seeking to operate in a generalized way
is for very for these various games,
the points are different,
some,
some points are low,
some points are high,
some go positive,
negative,
and they're all normalized to a point
where the good points are,
the positive points are a one and
negative points are a negative one.
That's reward clipping,
simplify the reward structure and
because a lot of the games have 30 fps
or 60 fps and the actions are not,
it's not valuable to take actions as
such a high rate inside of these
particularly Atari Games.
Then you only take an action every four
steps while still taking into the frames
as part of the temporal window to make
decisions,
tricks.
But hopefully it gives you a sense of
the kinds of things necessary for both
seminal papers like this one and for the
more important accomplishment of winning
deep traffic is the.
Is the tricks make all the difference
here?
On the bottom is the circle is when the
technique is used and the excellent.
It's not looking at replay and target,
fixed target,
network and experience replay when both
are used for the game of breakout river,
raid,
sciquest and space invaders.
The higher the number,
the better it is,
the more points achieved so when it
gives you a sense that one replay and
target both give significant
improvements in the performance of the
system,
order of magnitude improvements to
orders of magnitude for breakup.
And here is pseudocode of implementing
dqn.
The learning.
The key thing to notice and you can look
through the slides,
is the,
the,
the loop,
the wild loop of playing through the
games and selecting the actions to play
is not part of the training.
It's part of the saving,
uh,
the observations,
the state action reward next state
observations is saving them and to
replay memory into that library.
And then you sample randomly from that
replay memory to then train the network
based on the last function
and with probability up up top of the
probability epsilon select a random
action that epsilon is the probability
of exploration that decreases at
something you'll see in traffic as well,
is the rate of which that exploration
decreases over time through the training
process.
You want to explore a lot first and less
and less over time.
So this algorithm has been able to
accomplish in 2015 and since a lot of
incredible things,
things that made the ai world think that
we were onto something that general ai
is within reach for the first time that
raw sensor information was used to
create a system that acts it,
make sense of the world,
make sense of the physics of the world
enough to be able to succeed in it for
very little information.
But these games are trivial even though
there is a lot of them.
This dq and approach has been able to
outperform a lot of the Atari Games.
That's what been reported on,
outperform the human level performance.
But again,
these games are trivial.
What I think,
and perhaps biased,
I'm biased,
but one of the greatest accomplishments
of artificial intelligence in the last
decade,
at least from the philosophical or the
research perspective,
is Alphago Zero First Alphago,
Alphago zero is deepmind system that
beat the best in the world in the game
of go.
So what's the game of go simple.
I won't get into the rules,
but basically it's a 19 by 19 board
showing on the bottom of the slide for
the bottom row of the table for board of
19 by 19.
The number of legal game positions is
two times 10 to the power of one 70.
It's a very large number of possible
positions to consider at any one time,
especially the game evolves.
The number of possible moves is huge,
much larger than in chess.
So that's why Ai Community thought that
this game is not solvable until 2016
when Alphago used to use human expert
position play to seed in a supervised
way.
Reinforcement learning approach,
and I'll describe it in a little bit of
detail in this couple of slides here to
beat the best in the world
and then Alphago zero.
That is the accomplishment of the decade
for me in Ai is being able to play with
no training data on human expert Games
and beat the best in the world and an
extremely complex game.
This is not a tare.
This is an this is a a much higher order
difficulty game and the and the quality
of player that is competing in as much
higher and it's able to extremely
quickly here to achieve a rating that's
better than Alphago and better than the
different variants of Alphago and
certainly better than the best of the
human players in 20 days of self play.
So how does it work?
All of these approaches,
much,
much like the previous ones.
The traditional ones that are not based
on deep learning are using Monte Carlo
tree search MCTs,
which is when you have such a large
state space,
you start at a board and you play and
you choose moves with some exploitation
exploration.
Balancing choosing to explore a totally
new positions or to go deep on the
positions you know are good until the
bottom of the game is reached until the
final state is reached and then you back
propagate the quality of the choices
you've made leading to that position and
in that way you learn the value of of
board positions and play that's been
used by the most successful.
Go playing engines before and Alphago
sense,
but you might be able to guess what's
the difference with Alphago versus the
previous approaches.
They use the neural network as the
intuition quote on quote to what are the
good states,
what are the good next board positions
to explore,
and the key things,
again,
the tricks make all the difference that
made Alphago zero work and work much
better than Alphago is first because
there was no expert play instead of
human games.
Alphago used that very same Monte Carlo
tree search algorithm,
MCTs to do an intelligent look ahead
based on in neural network prediction of
what are the good states to take.
It checked that instead of human expert
play it checked.
How good indeed are those states?
It's a simple look ahead action that
does the ground truth that does the
target,
a correction that produces the last
function.
The second part is the multitask
learning or what's now called multitask
learning is the network is is a quote
unquote two headed in the sense that
first it outputs the probability of
which moved to take the obvious thing
and it's also producing a probability of
winning and there's a few ways to
combine that information and
continuously train both parts of the
network depending on the choice taken.
So you want to take the best choice in
the short term and achieved the
positions that are highly likelihood of
winning for the player.
That's whose turn it is,
and another big step is that they
updated from 2015 the update of the
state of the art architecture,
which are now the architecture.
That one image that is residual networks
resume yet for image net.
Those that's it.
And those little changes made all the
difference.
So that takes us to do deep traffic and
8 billion hours stuck in traffic
America's pastime.
So we tried to simulate driving that
behavior layer of driving,
so not the immediate control,
not the motion planning,
but beyond that on top,
on top of those control decisions,
the human interpretable decisions of
changing lane speeding up,
slowing down,
modeling that in a microtrauma traffic
simulation framework that's popular and
traffic engineering,
the kindness shown here,
we applied deeper enforcement learning
to that,
we call it deep traffic.
The goal is to achieve the highest
average speed over a long period of time
weaving in and out of traffic for
students here,
their requirement is to follow the
tutorial and that Shiva speed of 65
miles an hour,
and if you really want to achieve a
speed over 70 miles an hour,
which is what's required to win and
perhaps upload your own image to make
sure you look good doing it.
What you should do,
clear instructions to compete.
Read the tutorial.
You can change parameters in the cold
box on that website.
Cars that mit.edu
site traffic.
Click the button that says apply code,
which applies the code that you write.
These are the parameters that you
specify for.
Then you'll network it,
applies those parameters,
creates the architecture that you
specify,
and now you have a network written in
javascript living in the browser ready
to be trained.
Then you click the blue button that says
run training and that trains the network
much faster than what's actually being
visualized in the browser a thousand
times faster by evolving the game,
making decisions,
taking in the grid space,
as I'll talk about here in a second,
the speed limit is 80 miles an hour
based on the various adjustments were
made to the game.
Reaching 80 miles an hour,
certainly impossible on average and
reaching some of the speeds that we
achieved last year is much,
much,
much more difficult.
Finally,
when you are happy and the training is
done,
submit the model to competition for
those super eager,
dedicated students.
You can do so every five minutes and to
visualize your submission,
you can click the request visualization,
specifying the custom image and the
color.
Okay,
so here's the simulation.
Speed limit,
80 miles an hour,
cars 20 on the screen,
one of them is a red one in this case,
that's that one is controlled by neural
network.
It's speed.
It's allowed the actions of speed up,
slow down,
change lanes,
left,
right or stay exactly the same.
The other cars are pretty dumb.
They speed up,
slow down,
turn left,
right,
but they don't have a purpose in their
existence.
They do so randomly or at least purpose
has not been discovered.
The road,
the car,
the speed,
the road is a grid space and occupancy
grid that specifies when it's empty.
It's set to
Ab,
meaning that the grid value is whatever
speed is achievable.
If you were inside that grid and when
there's other cars that are going slow,
the value in that grid is the speed of
that car.
That's the state space.
That's the state representation and you
can choose how much,
what slice that state space you've
taken.
That's the input to the neural network.
For visualization purposes,
you can choose normal speed or fast
speed for watching the network operate
and there's display options to help you
build intuition about the network takes
in and what space the cars operating in.
The default is there's no extra
information is added.
Then there's the learning input which
visualizes exactly which part of the
road the serves as the input to the
network.
Then there is the safety system,
which I'll describe in a little bit,
which is all the parts of the road the
car is not allowed to go into because it
would result in a collision and that
with javascript will be very difficult
to animate and the full map.
Here's the safety system.
You can think of this system as ACC
basic radar ultrasonic sensors,
helping you avoid the obvious collisions
to obviously detectable objects around
you.
And the task for this red car,
for this neural network is to move about
this space,
uh,
is to move about the space under the
constraints of the safety system.
The red shows all the parts of the
greatest,
not able to move into.
So the goal for the car is to not get
stuck in traffic,
is make big sweeping motions to avoid
crowds of cars.
The input like dqn is the state space.
The output is the value of the different
actions and based on the absalon
parameter to training and through
inference evaluation process,
you choose how much exploration you want
to do.
These are all parameters.
The learning is done in the browser on
your own computer,
utilizing only the CPU,
the action space.
There's five,
giving you some of the variables here.
Perhaps you'd go back to the slides to
look at it.
The brain,
quote unquote,
is the thing that takes in the state and
the reward takes a forward pass to the
state and producer.
The next action,
the brain is where the neural can.
It's contained both of the training and
the evaluation.
The learning input can be controlled in
width,
forward length and backward length.
Lane side number of lanes to the side
that you see patches ahead as the
patches ahead that you see patches
behind his patches behind these.
See new this year can control the number
of agents that are controlled by the
neural network anywhere from one to 10,
and the evaluation is performed exactly
the same way.
You have to achieve the highest average
speed for the agents.
The very critical thing here is the
agents are not aware of each other so
they're not jointly jointly planning.
The network is trained under the joint
objective of achieving the average speed
for all of them,
but the actions of taking in a greedy
way for each.
It's very interesting what can be
learned in this way because this kinds
of approaches are scalable to an
arbitrary number of cars and you could
imagine us plopping down the best cars
from this class together and having them
compete in this way,
the best neural networks because there
are full in their greedy operation.
The number of networks that can
concurrently operate is fully scalable.
There's a lot of parameters.
The temporal window,
the layers,
the many layers types that can be added
here is a fully connected layer with 10
year olds.
The activation functions.
All of these things can be customized as
specified in the tutorial,
the final layer,
a fully connected layer with I'll put a
five regression given the value of each
of the five actions and there's a lot of
more specific parameters,
some of which I've discussed from gamma
to epsilon
to experience replay size to learning
rate and temporal window,
the optimizer,
the learning rate momentum,
batch size l two l,
one,
two,
k for regularization and so on.
There's a big white button that says
apply code that you press that kills all
the work you've done up to this point,
so be careful doing it.
It should be doing it only at the very
beginning.
If you happen to leave your computer
running and training for several days is
as folks have done the blue training
button,
you press and it trains based on the
parameters you specify and the network
state gets shipped to the main
simulation from time to time.
So the thing you see in the browser,
as you open up the website is running
the same network that's being trained
and regularly updates that network so
it's getting better and better.
Even if the training takes weeks for
you,
it's constantly updated the network you
see on the left,
so if the car for the network that your
training is just standing in place and
not moving,
it's probably time to restart and change
the parameters.
Maybe add a few layers to your network,
number of iterations,
a certainly an important parameter to
control and the evaluation is something
we've done a lot of work done since last
year to remove the degree of randomness,
to remove the the incentive to submit
the same code over and over again to
hope to produce a higher award,
a higher evaluation score.
The method for evaluation is we collect
the average speed over 10 runs,
about 45 seconds of game each,
not minutes,
45 seconds,
and there is five hundreds of those and
we take the median speed of the 500 runs
has done server side.
It's extremely difficult to cheat.
I urge you to try.
You can try it locally.
There's a start evaluation run,
but that one doesn't count.
That's just for you to feel better about
your network.
That's.
That should produce a result that's very
similar to the one we were produced on.
The server is to build your own
intuition and as I said,
was significantly reduce the influence
of randomness,
so the the score of the speed you get
for the network you designed should be
very similar with every evaluation.
Loading is saving.
If the network is huge and you want to
switch computers,
you can save the network.
It saves both the architecture of the
network and the weights and the on the
network and you can load it back in.
Obviously when you load it in,
it's not a saving any of the data you've
already done.
You can't do transfer learning with
javascript in the browser yet submitting
your network,
submit model to competition and make
sure you run training first.
Otherwise it will be initiated or
initiated randomly and will not do so
well.
You can resubmit as often as you like,
and the highest score is what counts.
The coolest part is you can load your
custom image,
specify colors,
and request the visualization.
We have not yet shown the visualization,
but I promise you it's going to be
awesome.
Again,
read the tutorial,
change the parameters and the code box.
Click apply code run training.
Everybody in this room on the way home
on the train,
hopefully not in your car,
should be able to do this in the browser
and they can visualize request
visualization because it's an expensive
process.
You have to want it for us to do it well
because we have to run in server side.
Competition link is their get hub
started.
Code is there and the details for those
that truly want to win is in the archive
paper.
So the question that will come up
throughout is whether these
reinforcement learning approaches are at
all or rather if action planning control
is amenable to learning.
Certainly in the case of driving,
we can't do it.
Alpha go zero did.
We can't learn from scratch from self
play because that will result in
millions of crashes in order to learn to
avoid the crashes.
Unless we're working like we are deep
crashed on the RC car or we're working
on a simulation so we can look at expert
data,
we can look at driver data,
which we have a lot of and learn from.
It's an open question.
This is applicable to date that I'll
bring up two companies because they're
both guest speakers
deep irl is not involved in the most
successful robots operating in the real
world.
In the case of Boston dynamics,
most of the perception control and
planning I can.
This robot does not involve learning
approaches except with minimal addition
on the perception side.
Best of our knowledge and certainly the
same is true with Waymo.
As the speaker on Friday,
we'll talk about deep learning is used a
little bit in perception on top,
but most of the work is done from the
sensors and the optimization based,
the model based approaches,
trajectory generation and optimizing
which trajectory trajectory is best to
avoid collisions.
Deep Arrows not involved and coming
back and back again.
The unexpected local is a higher award
which arise in all of these situations
and applied in the real world.
So for the cat video,
that's pretty short where the cats are
ringing the bell and they're learning
that the ringing of the bell is,
is mapping to food.
I urge you to think about how that can
evolve over time in unexpected ways that
may not have a desirable effect where
the final reward is in the form of food
and the intended effect is to ring the
bell.
That's where ai safety comes in for the
artificial general intelligence course
in two weeks.
That's something we'll explore
extensively.
It's how these reinforcement learning
planning algorithms will evolve in ways
that not expected and how we can
constrain them,
how we can design reward functions that
result in safe operation.
So I encourage you to come to the talk
on Friday at 1:00
PM as a reminder.
So 1:00
PM that 7:00
PM instead of 32,
one,
two,
three,
and two,
the awesome talks in two weeks from
Boston dynamics to Ray Kurzweil and so
on for Agi.
Now tomorrow we'll talk about computer
vision and psych fuse.
Thank you everybody.