Welcome back to success zero,
nine,
nine artificial general intelligence.
Today we have Stephen Wolfe from.
Thank you.
That's the first.
I didn't even get started.
You already clapping,
uh,
in his book and you kind of.
Sciencey has explored and reveal the
power,
beauty and complexity of cellular
Automata as simple computational
systems,
which incredible complexity it can
emerge.
It's actually one of the books that
really inspired me to get into
artificial intelligence.
He's created the Wolfram Alpha
competition knowledge engine created
Mathematica that has now expanded to
become wolfram language.
Both he and his son were involved in
helping analyze,
create the alien language from the movie
arrival of which they used the Wolfram
language.
Please again,
give Steven a warm welcome.
Thanks so much.
The
brief here is to talk about how
artificial general intelligence is going
to be achieved.
Is that the set,
the basic picture?
So I,
I,
maybe I'm reminded of kind of a storage.
I don't think I've ever told them
public,
but um,
that something that happened just a few
buildings over from here.
So this was 2009 and Wolfram Alpha was,
was about to arrive on the scene.
I assume most of you have used wolf now
for a cmo of Alpha.
Yes.
The pump.
How many of you have used Wolf Malfa?
Okay,
that's good.
Um,
so I had long been a friend of Marvin
Minsky and Marvin was a sort of pioneer
of the ai world and I kind of seen for
years,
you know,
question answering systems that tried
to,
uh,
to sort of general intelligence question
answering.
And so Marvin,
and so I was going to show Marvin,
you know,
Wolf Malfa,
he looks at it,
he's like,
oh,
okay,
that's fine.
Whatever said no,
Marvin,
this time it actually works.
You can try real questions.
This is actually something useful.
This is not just a toy.
And it was kind of interesting to see.
It took.
It took about five minutes from Marvin
to realize that this was finally a
question answering system that could
actually answer questions that were
useful to people.
Um,
and so one question is,
how do we,
how do we achieve that?
So,
you know,
you go to wealth Malfa and you can ask
it.
I mean,
it's,
I don't know what we can ask it.
I don't know.
What's the,
um,
uh,
some random question.
What does the population of Cambridge
actually,
here's a question divided by.
Let's try that.
What's the population of Cambridge?
It's probably gonna figure out that we
mean Cambridge,
Massachusetts is going to give us some
number.
It's going to give us some plot.
Actually,
what I want to know is number of
students at mit divided by population of
Cambridge specific configure that out.
Um,
and uh,
okay.
It's kind of interesting.
I know that's divided by.
Oh,
that's interesting it guests that we
were talking about Cambridge University
as the,
as the denominator there.
So it says the number of students at mit
divided by the number of students at
Cambridge University.
It's interesting.
I'm actually surprised.
Let's see what happens.
If I say con Cambridge a,
the,
I'm not as will probably fail horribly.
No,
that's,
that's good.
Okay.
So,
um,
no,
that's interesting.
That's a plot as a function of time of
the fraction of the,
uh,
of um,
okay.
So anyway,
so I'm glad it works.
Um,
the uh,
so one,
one question is how did we manage to get
so many things have to work in order to
get stuff like this to work,
you have to be able to understand the
natural language,
you have to have data sources,
you have to be able to compute things
from the data and so on.
One of the things that was a surprise to
me was in terms of natural language
understanding was the critical thing
turned out to be just knowing a lot of
stuff.
The actual pausing of the national
language is kind of a,
I think it's kind of clever and we use a
bunch of ideas that came from my new
kind of science project and so on.
But I think the most important thing is
just knowing a lot of stuff about the
world is,
is really important to actually being
able to,
to understand natural language in it and
a useful situation.
I think the other thing is having a,
uh,
actually having access to lots of data.
Let me show you a typical example here
of what is needed.
So I asked about the ISS and hopefully
it'll wake up and tell us something
here.
Come on.
What's going on here?
There we go.
Okay.
So it figured out that we probably are
talking about a spacecraft,
another file format,
and now it's going to give us a plot
that shows us where the ISS is right
now.
So to make this work we obviously have
to have some feed of a radar tracking
data about satellites and so on,
which we have for every satellite
that's,
that's out there.
Um,
but then that's not good enough to just
have that feed.
Then you also have to be able to do
celestial mechanics to work out well.
Whereas the ISS actually right now based
on the orbital elements that have been
deduced from radar and then if we want
to know things like,
okay,
when is it going to.
It's not currently visible from Boston,
Massachusetts.
It will next rise at 7:36
PM,
uh,
on Monday and today.
Um,
so,
you know,
this requires a mixture of data about
what's going on in the world together
with models about how the world is
supposed to work.
Being able to predict things and so on.
And I think another thing that kind of
realized about,
about Ai and so on from the Wolf Malfa
effort has been that,
you know,
one of the earlier ideas for how long
would achieve ai was let's make it work.
Kind of like brainstorm and let's make
it figure stuff out and stuff.
It has to do physics,
let's have it do physics by pure
reasoning.
Uh,
like,
you know,
people at least used to do physics,
but in the last 300 years we've had a
different way to do physics that wasn't
sort of based on natural philosophy.
It was instead based on things like
mathematics.
And so one of the things that we were
doing and worth Malfa was to kind of
cheat relative to what had been done in
previous ai systems,
which was instead of using kind of
reasoning type methods,
were just saying,
okay,
we want to compute where the ISS is
going to be,
but we've got a bunch of equations of
motion that correspond to differential
equations.
We're just going to solve the equations
of motion and get an answer.
That's kind of leveraging the last 300
years or so of,
of,
of exact science that have been done,
rather than trying to make use of kind
of human reasoning ideas.
And I might might say that in terms of
the history of the wharf Malford
project,
when I was a kid a disgustingly long
time ago,
I was interested in ai kinds of things
and I,
in fact,
I was kind of upset recently to find a
bunch of stuff I did when I was 12 years
old,
kind of trying to assemble a pre version
of orphan malfa way back before it was
technologically possible.
But it's also a reminder that one just
does the same thing.
One's whole life,
so to speak at some level.
Um,
but,
uh,
what happened was when,
when I,
um,
I started off working mainly in physics
and then I got involved in building
computer systems to do things like
mathematical computation and so on.
And,
uh,
I then sort of got interested in,
okay,
so can we generalize this stuff and come
we can we really make a systems that can
answer sort of arbitrary questions about
the world and for example,
uh,
sort of the,
the,
the promise would be if there's
something that is systematically no one
in our civilization make it automatic to
answer questions on the base of that
systematic knowledge.
And back in the,
in around late 19 seventies,
early 19 eighties,
my conclusion was that you wanted to do
something like that.
The only realistic path to being able to
do it was to build something much like a
brain.
And so I got interested in neural nets
and I tried to do things with neural
nets back in 1980 and nothing very
interesting happened where I couldn't
get them to do anything very
interesting.
And uh,
that term.
So I kind of had the idea that,
that the only way to get the kind of
thing that now exists in Wolf Malfa for
example,
was to build a brain like thing.
And then many years later,
for reasons I can explain,
I kind of came back to this and
realized,
actually it wasn't true that you had to
build a brain,
like things sort of mere computation was
sufficient and that was kind of what got
me started actually trying to build both
Malfa when we started building wealth
Malfa,
one of the things I did was go to a sort
of a field trip to a big reference
library and you know,
you see all these shelves of books and
so on.
And the question is,
can we take all of this knowledge that
exists in all of these books and
actually automate being able to answer
questions on the basis of it.
And I think we've pretty much done that
for that,
at least the books you find than a
typical reference library.
Um,
so that was a,
it looked kind of daunting at the
beginning because it's this,
there's a lot of knowledge and
information out there.
But actually it turns out there are a
few thousand domains and we've steadily
gone through and worked on these
different domains.
Another feature of the wharf project was
that we didn't really,
uh,
you know,
I've been involved a lot in doing basic
science and trying to have sort of grand
theories of the world.
One of my principals in building Wolfram
Alpha was not to start from a grand
theory of the world that is not to kind
of start from some global ontology of
the world and then try and build down
into all these different domains,
but instead to work up from having,
you know,
hundreds then thousands of domains that
actually work,
whether they're,
you know,
information about cars or information
about sports or information about movies
or whatever else,
how each of these domains.
I'm sort of building up from the bottom
in each of these domains.
And then finding that there were common
themes in these domains that we could
then build into frameworks and then sort
of construct the whole system on the
basis of that.
And that's kind of,
that's kind of how it's worked.
And I can talk about some of the actual
frameworks that we ended up using and so
on.
Um,
but,
uh,
maybe I should explain a little bit
more.
So,
so one question is,
how does,
how does wealth map are actually sort of
work inside?
And the answer is it's a big program,
it's about,
it's the core system has about 15
million lines of Wolfram language code,
um,
and it's some number of terabytes of raw
data.
Um,
and uh,
so the,
the way,
the thing that sort of made building
wealth now for possible was this
language Wolfram from language which
started with Mathematica,
which came out in 1988 and has been sort
of progressively growing since then.
So maybe I should show you some things
about wealth language and,
and,
uh,
you know,
it's easy.
You can go use this.
Mit has a site license for it,
you can use it all over the place,
you can find it on the web,
et Cetera,
et cetera.
Um,
but,
uh,
okay,
the basics work.
Um,
the uh,
let,
let's,
let's start off with something like,
let's make a random graph and um,
let's say we have a random graph with
200 nodes,
400 vertices.
Okay.
So those isn't random graph.
The first important thing about Wilson
languages,
it's a symbolic language.
So I can just pick up this graph and I
could say,
you know,
I want to do some analysis of this
graph.
That graph is just a symbolic thing that
I can just do computations on.
Or I could say let's,
let's get a um,
a,
another good thing to do is get a
current image.
See,
there we go.
Um,
and now I could go and say something
like,
um,
uh,
let's,
let's do some basic thing.
Let's say let's edge detect that image
again,
this,
this image is just a thing that we can
manipulate.
We could take the image,
we could make it.
Um,
uh,
I don't know.
We could take the image and petitioners,
little pieces.
Do computations on that.
I don't know.
Simple.
Let's do,
let's just say sought each row of the
image.
Assemble the image again.
Whoops.
Assemble,
let image again.
We'll get some,
some mixed up picture there.
If I wanted to,
I could,
for example,
let's say let's make that the current
image and let's say make that dynamic.
I can be just running that code
hopefully,
and it'll loop and we can,
uh,
make that work.
So the one,
one general point here is,
there's no,
this is just an image for us is just a
piece of data.
Like anything else,
if we just have a variable a thing
called x,
it just says,
okay,
that's X.
I don't need to know particular value.
It's just a symbolic thing that
corresponds to a,
that's a thing called x.
Now you know,
what gets interesting when you have a
symbolic language and so on is we're
interested in having it represent stuff
about the world as well as just abstract
kinds of things.
I mean,
I,
you know,
I can abstractly say,
find some funky integral,
um,
I don't know what,
you know,
that's then representing a using
symbolic variables to represent
algebraic kinds of things.
But I could also just say I dunno,
something like Boston and Boston is
another kind of symbolic thing that,
uh,
has.
If I say what,
what does it really inside that's,
it's the entity,
a city,
Boston,
Massachusetts,
United States actually noticed when I
type that in,
I was using natural language to type it
in and it gave me a bunch of
disambiguation here.
It said,
assuming Boston as a city,
uh,
assuming Boston,
Massachusetts,
use Boston,
New York or.
Okay,
there's,
let's use,
let's use Boston in the Philippines,
which I've never heard of,
but um,
uh,
let's try using that instead.
And now if I look at that,
it'll say it's Boston in some province
of the Philippines,
etc.
Etc.
Now I might ask it of that.
I could say somEthing like,
what's the population of that?
Um,
and it,
um,
uh,
okay.
It's a fairly small place.
Or I could say,
for example,
let me,
let me do this.
Let me say jill list plot from that
bostoN a take from that boston too.
And now let's type In boston again and
now let's have it used the default
meaning of the word of boston.
and then let's join those up.
And now this should plot,
um,
this should show me a plot.
There we go.
Okay,
so there's the,
um,
a path from the boston that we picked in
the Philippines to the boston here.
Oh,
we could ask it.
I don't know.
I could just say,
um,
I could ask it the distance from one to
another or something like that.
So the,
the,
one of the thIngs here,
one things we found really,
really useful actually in both
languages.
The first of all,
there's a way of representing stuff
about the world,
like cities for example.
Well,
let's say I want to say let's,
let's do this.
Let's say,
uh,
let's do something,
let's say capital cities in south
America.
Okay.
So notice this is a piece of natural
language.
This will get interpreted into something
which is precise symbolic language code
that we can then compute with and that
will give us the citizens of the capital
cities in south America.
I could,
for example,
let's say I say fine shortest tour.
So now I'm going to use some,
uh,
some ups.
No,
I don't want to do that,
but I want to do first is to say,
show me the job positions of all those
cities online,
21 there,
so now it will find the geo positions
and now we'll say compute the shortest
tour.
So that's saying there's a 10,000
mile traveling salesman tour around
those cities.
So I could take those cities were online
21 and I could say order the cities
according to this and then I could make
another geo lists a lot of that,
join it up.
Um,
and this should now show us a,
a traveling salesman tour of the,
um,
of the capital cities in south America.
Um,
so,
you know,
it's,
it's sort of interesting to see what's
involved in making stuff like this work.
Um,
the uh,
uh,
one of my,
my goal has been to sort of automate as
much as possible about things that have
to be computed and that means knowing as
many algorithms as possible and also
knowing as much data about the world as
possible.
And I kind of view this as sort of a
knowledge based programming approach
where you have a typical kind of idea
and programming languages as you know,
we have some small programming
languages,
has a few primitives that are pretty
much tied into what a machine can
intrinsically do and then maybe you'll
have libraries that add onto that.
And so on.
My kind of a crazy idea of many,
many years ago has been to build an
integrated system where all of the stuff
about different domains of knowledge and
so on are all just built into the system
and uh,
and designed in a coherent way.
I mean this has been kind of the story
of my life for the last 30 years,
is trying to keep the design of the
system coherent even as one adds all
sorts of different areas of,
of,
uh,
of capability.
So as,
um,
I mean we can go and dive into all sorts
of different kinds of things here.
But,
um,
maybe as an example.
Well,
let's do,
what could we do here we could take.
Um,
let's try.
How about this?
Is that a bone?
I think so that's a bone.
So let's try a that as a mesh region,
see if that works.
So this will now Use a completely
different domain of,
um,
of human endeavor.
Okay.
Whoops.
There's two of those buttons.
Let's try,
let's just try a,
let's try left humerus and let's try
the,
that,
the mesh region for that.
And now we should have a bone here.
Okay.
There's a representational of bone.
Let's take that bone.
We could,
for example,
say um,
let's take the surface area of that as
in some some units or I could let,
let's do some much more outrageous
thing.
Let's say we take,
um,
region distance.
So we're going to take the distance from
some,
from that bone to a point,
let's say zero,
zero,
z,
and let's make a plot of that distance
with z going from,
let's say I have no idea where the,
where the bone is,
but let's try something like this.
So that was really borIng.
Let's try.
Um,
so what this is doing,
again,
a whole bunch of stuff has to work in
order for this to,
to operate this test,
to be.
This is a,
this is some region in three d space
that's represented by some mesh.
You have to compute,
you know,
do the computational geometry to figure
out where it is.
If I wanted to let,
let's try anatomy,
anatomy,
plot three d,
and let's say something like lefthand
for example,
and now it's going to show us probably
the complete data that it has about the
geometry of,
of,
um,
uh,
of a lefthand.
There we gO.
Um,
okay.
So there's,
there's the results.
And we could take that apart and start
computIng things from it.
And so on.
So what I'm a.
So this is,
um,
so there's,
uh,
there's a lot of kind of computational
knowledge that's built in here.
Um,
one,
uh,
let's,
let's talk a little bit about kind of
the modern machine learning story.
So for instance,
if I say,
let's get a picture here.
Let's say,
um,
let's,
let's just say picture of assembly.
Got a favorite kind of animal.
What?
Panda.
Okay,
so let's try.
Okay.
Giant panda.
Okay,
there's a panda.
Let's see what,
um,
now let's try saying,
let's try for this panda.
Let's try saying image identify,
and now here will be embarrassed
probably,
but let's just see.
Let's see what happens.
If I say image,
identify that and now it'll hopefully
wake up,
wake up.
This only takes a few hundred
milliseconds.
Okay,
very good.
John panto.
Let's,
let's see what it will see.
What the runners up were to the giant
panda.
Um,
uh,
let's say we want to say the ten one is
up in all categories for that thing.
Okay.
So giant panda,
a kitchenaid,
which I've never heard of.
Our pandas.
Commerce eat bamboo shoots.
Okay.
So that was so lucky.
It didn't get that one.
It's really sure it's a mammal and it's
absolutely certain it's a vertebrate.
Okay.
So you might ask how did it figure this
out?
And so then you can kind of look under
the hood and say,
so we have a whole framework for
representing neuron that symbolically.
And so this is the actual model that
it's using to do this.
So this is a um,
so there's a neural net and it's got.
We can drill down and we can see there's
a piece of the neural net.
We can drill down even further to one of
these and we can probably see what
that's our batch normalization layer
somewhere deep,
deep inside the trails of the not
pander,
but to have this thing.
Okay,
so now let's take that object which has
just a symbolic object and let's feed it
the picture of the panda and we can see
'em and the ups.
I was not giving up the right thing.
What did I do wrong here?
Let's.
Let's take.
Oh,
I see what I did.
Okay,
let's take this thing and feed it the
picture of the panda and it says a giant
panda.
Okay.
How about we do something more
outrageous?
Let's take that neuron that.
And let's only use the first,
let's say 10 layers of the neuron that.
So let's just take out 10 layers of the
neuron that and feed it the panda.
And now what we'll get is something from
the insides of the neuron that.
And I could say for example,
let's just make those into images.
Okay?
So that's what.
That's what the neural net had figured
out about the panda after 10 layers of
going through the neuron that and maybe
actually be interesting to see,
let's do a feature space plots and now
we're going to have those intermediate
things in the brain of the neural net so
to speak.
Um,
this is now taking.
So what this is doing is to do dimension
reduction on this space of images.
And so not very exciting.
It's probabLy mostly distinguishing
these by,
by total gray level,
but that's kind of showing us the space
of,
um,
of different term,
a different sort of features of the
insides of the chanel on that.
So it's also what's interesting to see
here is things like the symbolic
representation of the neuron nets.
And if you,
if you're wondering how does that
actually work inside,
it's underneath it susan mx net,
which we happen to have contributed to a
lot and there's sort of a bunch of
symbolic layers on top of that that feed
into that.
And maybe I can show you here,
let,
let me show you how you would train one
of these neural nets.
That's also kind of fun.
So we have a data repository that has
all sorts of useful data.
One piece of data it has is a bunch of
neuron that training set.
So this is the standard training set of
handwritten digits.
Okay.
So there's amnesty and you notice that
these things here,
that's Just an image which I could copy
out and I could do,
let's say I could do color and a gate on
that image because it's just an image.
Um,
and there's,
there's the results and so on.
And now I could say,
let's take,
let's take a neuron that like,
let's take a simple neural net like
lynette for example.
Um,
okay.
So let's take lanette and then let's
take the untrained initial evaluation
network.
So this is now a version of love,
that simple standard neuron that,
that didn't get trained.
So for example,
if I,
if I take that,
that symBolic representation of that,
and I could say net initialize than it
will take that and it'll just put random
weights until the net.
Okay?
So if I take those random weights and I
feed it a zero here,
I feed it,
that image of a zero,
it will presumaBly produced something
completely random and this particular
case too,
right?
So now,
now what I would like to do is to take
this.
So thAt was just randomly initializing
the weights.
So now what I'd like to do is to take,
uh,
the training set and I'd like to
actually train a learn at using eminence
training set.
So let's take,
let's take this and let's take a random
sample of a.
Let's say I don't know,
a thousand pieces of lanette.
Come on.
Why is it having to load it again?
There we go.
Okay.
So there's a,
there's a random sample a was on line
21.
And now let me go down here and say,
uh,
what was it?
Well we can just take this,
this thing here.
So this is the uninitialized version of
lanette and we can say take that.
And then let's say net train of that
with the thing on line 21,
which was that thousand instances.
So now what it's doing is it's running
training on,
um,
and that's,
you see the loss going down and so on.
It's running the training for,
uh,
for those thousand instances of,
of uh,
uh,
lynette and it will,
we can stop it if we want to.
Actually,
this is a new display.
This is very nice.
This is,
this is a new version of language which
is coming out next week,
which I'm showing you,
But it's quite similar to what exists
today,
but because that's one of the features
of running a software company is that
you always run the very latest version
of things for better or worse.
And that's,
and this is also a good way to debug it
was supposed to come out next week.
If I find some horrifying bug,
maybe we'll get to later,
but let's try and let's,
um,
let's try this.
Okay,
now it says it's zero.
Okay?
And so,
so this is now a trained version of
lynette trained with that,
uh,
with that training data.
I'm one of the things so we can talk
about all kinds of details of,
of neural nets and so on.
But maybe I should zoom out to talk a
little bit about bigger picture as it,
as I see it.
So one question is a sort of a question
of what is in principle possible to do
with computation?
So,
you know,
we have as we're,
we're building all kinds of things.
We're making image identifiers were
figuring out all kinds of things about
where the international space station
is.
And so on question is what is,
what is in principle possible to
compute?
and so the,
uh,
you know,
one of the places one can ask that
question is when one looks at,
for example,
models of the natural world can say,
you know,
how do we make models of the natural
world?
Kind of a,
a traditional approach has been,
let's use mathematical equations to make
models of the natural world.
A question is if we want to kind of
generalize that and say,
well,
what are all possible ways to make
models of things?
What can we say about that question?
So I spent many years in my lifetime to
address that question.
And basically what I've thought about a
lot is that if you want to make a model
of a thing,
you have to have definite rules by which
the thing operates.
What's the most general way to represent
possible rules while in today's world we
think of that as a program.
So the next question is,
well,
what does the space of all possiBle
programs look like?
And most of the time,
you know,
we're writing programs like wolfram
language is 50 million lines of code and
it's a big complicated program that was
for built for fairly specific purpose.
But the question is if we just look At
sort of the space of possible programs
more or less at random,
what's out there in the space of
possible program.
So I got an interest in many years ago
in cellular automata,
which are really good example of a very
simple kind of program.
So let me show you an example of one of
these.
So this is,
these are the rules for a typical
cellular automaton.
And this just says you have a row of
black and white squares.
And this just says,
you look at a black look at a square,
say what color is that square?
What color left left.
And right neighbors decide what color
the square will be on the next step
based on that rule.
Okay?
So really simple rule.
So now let's,
let's take a look at what,
what actually happens if we use that
rule a bunch of times so we can take
that rule.
The 2:54
is just the binary digits that
correspond to those positions and this
rule.
So now I can say this,
I could say let's do 50 steps,
let me do this.
And now if I run according to the rule I
just defined,
it turns out to be pretty trivial.
It's just sAying,
uh,
if any,
if any square is we start off with a
black square.
If any square is,
um,
if any neighbouring squares,
black makeup,
black square.
So we've,
we've used a very simple program,
we've got a very simple result out,
okay,
let's try a different program.
we can try changing this will get them.
That's a program with one bit different.
Now we get that kind of pattern.
So the question is,
well,
what happens,
you might say,
okay,
if you've got such a trivial program,
it's not surprising,
you're just going to get trevor results
out.
So.
But you can do an experiment to test
that hypothesis and you just say,
let's take all possible programs that
are 256 possible programs that are based
on these eight bits here.
Let's just take bullets.
Just,
whoops,
let's just take come.
Let's say the first 64 of those programs
and let's just make a.
I'm a go.
Let's just make a table of the results
that we get by running those first 64
programs here.
So here we get the result and what you
see is,
well most of them are pretty trivial.
The likely they started with black cell
in the middle and it just tools off to
one side.
Occasionally we get something more
exciting happening.
Like here's a nice nested pattern that
we get.
We were to continue it longer.
It would,
it would make a more detailed nesting.
But then my all time favorite science
discovery.
If you go on and just look at these
after a while,
you find this one here,
which is rule 30 and this in this
numbering scheme,
and that's doing something a bit more
complicated.
You say,
well,
what's going on here?
You know,
we just started off with this very
simple rule.
LeT's see what happens.
Maybe after a while,
you know,
if we run rule 30 long enough,
it will resolve into something simpler.
SO let's try running it.
Let's say 500 steps.
Um,
and that's,
whoops,
that's the result we get.
Let's say a,
just make it full screen.
Okay?
So aliasing a bit on the project to the
but,
but um,
you've got the basic idea.
This is a.
So this just started off from one black
sell at the top and this is what it
made.
And that's pretty weird because all of
this is,
you know,
this is a sort of not the way it's
supposed things are supposed to work
because what we have here is just that
little program down there and it makes
this big complicated pattern here.
And we can see there's a certain amount
of regularity on one side,
but for example,
the center column of this pattern is for
all practical purposes completely
around.
In fact,
it was,
we used as the random number generator
and mathematic or wolfram language for
many years.
It was recently retired after,
after excellent service because we found
it somewhat more efficient one,
um,
But,
uh,
the,
um,
so,
you know,
what do we learn from this?
What we learned from this is out in the
computational universe of possible
programs.
It's possible to get even with very
simple programs,
very rich,
complicated behavior.
While that's important,
if you're interested in modeling the
natural world because you might think
that there are programs that represent
systems in nature that might work this
way and so on.
it's also important for technology
because it says,
okay,
let's say you're trying to find a,
um,
let's say you're trying to find a
Program that's a good random number
generator.
How are you going to do that?
While you could start thinking very hard
and you could try and make up,
you know,
you can try and write down all kinds of
flow charts about how this random number
generator is going to work or you can
say,
forget that I'm just going to search the
computational universe of possible
programs and just look for one that
serves as a good random numBer generator
and this particular case,
after you've searched 30 programs,
you'll find one that makes a good random
number generator.
Why dOes it work?
That's a complicated story.
It's not a story that I think
necessarily we can really tell very
well,
but what's important is that this is
this idea that out in the computational
universe,
there's a lot of rich,
sophisticated stuff that can be
essentially mined for our technological
purposes.
That's the important thing.
Whether we understand how this works is
a different matter.
I mean it's like when we look at the
natural world,
the physical world,
we're used to kind of mining things.
You know,
we started using magnets to do magnetic
stuff long before we understand,
understood the theory of pharaoh
mannerism and so on.
And so similarly here we can sort of go
out into the computational universe and
find stuff that's useful for our
purposes now.
In fact,
the,
the world of sort of deep learning and
neural nets and so on as a little bit
like this,
it uses the trick that there's a certain
degree of differentiability there so you
can kind of home in on let's try and
find something that's incrementally
better and for certain kinds of problems
that works pretty well.
I think the thing that we've done a lot,
I've done a lot is just sort of
exhaustive search and the computational
universe of possible programs,
just such a trillion programs and try
and find one that does something
interesting and useful for you.
Um,
there's a lot of things to say about
what,
um,
what actually in,
in the such a chilean programs and find
one that's useful.
Let me show you another example of that.
Um,
let's see.
So I was interested in awhile ago in um,
uh,
the,
I have to look something up here.
Sorry,
I'm in.
I'm a see,
I'm in,
I'm a boolean algebra and in,
um,
uh,
it was interested in,
in the space of all possible mathematics
says,
um,
and ah,
let me just see here.
Uh,
I'm not finding what I wanted to find.
Sorry,
uh,
was a good example.
I should have memorized this but I
haven't.
So I'm.
Here we go.
There it is.
Um,
so I was interested in,
if you just look at.
So we talked about sort of looking at
the space of all possible,
um,
uh,
the space of all possible programs.
Another thing you can do is say if
you're going to invent mathematics from
nothing,
what possible axiom systems could be
used in mathematics.
So I was curious where do that again
might seem like a completely crazy thing
to do.
So just say,
let's just start enumerating axiom
systems at random and see if we find one
that's interesting and useful,
but it turns out once you have this idea
that out in the computational universe
of possible programs,
that's actually a lot of low hanging
fruit to be found.
It turns out you can apply that in lots
of places.
I mean,
the thing to understand is why?
Why do we not see a lot of engineering
structures that look like this?
The reason is because our traditional
model of engineering has been we
engineer things in a way where we were,
we can foresee what the outcome of our
engineering steps that are going to be
and when it comes to something like
this,
we can find it out in the computational
universe what we can't readily foresee,
what's going to happen.
We can't do Sort of a step by step
design of this particular thing.
And so in engineering and human
engineering as it's been practiced so
far,
most of it has consisted of building
things where we can foresee step by step
what the outcome of our engineering it's
going to be.
And we see that in programs,
we see that in in other kinds of
engineering structures and so there's
sort of a different kind of engineering
which is about mining the computational
universe of possible programs and it's
worth realizing there's a lot more that
can be done a lot more efficiently by
mining the computational universe of
possible programs than by just
constructing things step by step as a
human.
So for example,
if you look for optimal algorithms for
things like,
I don't know,
even something like sorting networks,
the optimal sorting networks look very
complicated.
They're not things that you would
construct by sort of step by step
thinking about things with a in a kind
of a in a kind of typical human way.
And so this,
this idea,
you know,
if you're really going to have
computation work efficiently,
you are going to end up with these
programs that are sort of just mined
from the computational universe and one
of the issues with mining thing so that
there this makes use of computation much
more efficiently than a typical thing
that we might construct.
Now,
one feature of this is it's hard to
understand what's going on and there's
actually a fundamental reason for that,
which is in our efforts to sort of
understand what's going on,
we get to use our brains are computers
are mathematics or whatever and our goal
is this,
this particular little program that a
certain amount of computation to work
out this pattern.
The question is can we kind of outrun
that computation and say,
oh,
I can tell that actually this particular
bit down here is going to be a black
black bit a.
You don't have to go and do all that
computation.
But it turns out that,
and again,
this will maybe as a digression,
which,
um,
there's this phenomenon I called
computational irresponsibility,
which I think is really common and it's
a consequence of this thing I call
principle of computational equivalence.
And that the principle of computational
equivalents basically says as soon as
you have a system whose behavior isn't
fairly easy to analyze,
the chances are that the computation
it's doing is essentially as
sophisticated as it could be.
And That has consequences.
Like it implies that the typical thing
like this will correspond to a universal
computer that you can use to program and
a thing.
It also has the consequence of this
computational reducibility phenomenon
that says you can't expect our brains to
be able to outrun the computations that
are going on inside the system.
If there was computational reduce
ability,
then we can expect that this thing went
to a lot of trouble and did a million
steps of evolution.
But actually just by using our brains,
we can jump ahead and see what the
answer will be.
Computational irreducible suggest that
isn't the case.
If we're going to make the most
efficient use of computational
resources,
we will inevitably run into
computational irritability all over the
place.
It has the consequence that we get the
situation where we can't readily sort of
foresee and understand what's going to
happen.
So back to mathematics for a second.
so this is just an axiom system,
um,
that,
uh,
so I looked for all possible look
through sort of all possible axiom
systems starting off with the really
tiny ones.
And I asked the question,
what's the first axiom system that
corresponds to boolean algebra?
so it turns out this,
this thing here,
this tiny little thing here,
a generates all theorems of boolean
algebra does it.
It is the simplest axiom for boolean
algebra.
Now,
something I have to show you this
because it's a new feature.
You see the,
if I say find equational proof,
let's say I want to prove commuter
activity of the nand operation.
I'm going to show you something here.
This is going to try to generate,
let's see if this works.
And this is going to try to generate an
automated proof based on that axiom
system of that result.
So it had 102 steps and the proof.
And um,
let's try and say,
let's look at,
for example,
the proof network here.
Actually,
let's look at the proof dataset.
Um,
no,
that's not what I wanted.
Oh,
I should learn how to use the,
the,
um,
let's see what I want is the,
you know,
proof dataset.
There we go.
Very good.
Okay,
so this is actually,
let's,
let's say,
uh,
first of all,
let's say the proof graph.
Okay?
So this is going to show me the,
how that proof was done.
So there are a bunch of lemons that got
approved and from those lemars,
those cameras were combined that
eventually approved the result.
So let's,
let's take a look at the.
Let's take a look at what some of those
lenders where,
okay,
so here's,
here's the result.
So after,
so it goes through and these are various
lemars it's using,
and eventually after many pages of
nonsense it will get to the result.
Okay?
Each one of these,
some of these llamas are kind of
complicated.
The,
that's uh,
that's that lama.
It's a pretty complicated lemme etc.
Etc.
So you might ask what on earth is going
on here?
And the answer is,
so I first generated version of this
proof 20 years ago and I tried to
understand what was going on and I
completely failed and it's sort of
embarrassing because this is supposed to
be approved for.
It's supposed to be,
you know,
demonstrating some results.
And what we realize is that,
you know,
what does it mean to have a proof of
something?
What does it mean to explain how a thing
is done?
You know,
what,
what is the purpose of a proof sort of
proof is basically to let humans
understand why something is true.
And so for example,
if you go to,
um,
let's say we go to wolf alpha and we do,
you know,
some random thing where we say let's do
an integral of something or another,
it will be able to very quickly.
In fact,
it Will take it one milliseconds
internally to work out the answer to
that integral,
okay?
But then somebody who's wants to hand in
a piece of homework or something like
that,
needs to explain why is this true?
Okay,
well,
we have this handy step by step solution
thing here,
which explains why it's true.
Now,
the thing I should admit about the step
by step solutIon is it's completely
fake.
That is the steps that are described in
the step by step solution.
I have absolutely nothing to do with the
way that internally,
that integral was computed.
These are steps created purely for the
purpose of telling a story to humans
about why the center came out the way it
did and now what we're seeing and so
that's a.
So that's one thing is knowing the
answer.
The other thing is being able to tell a
story about why the answer work that
way.
Well,
what we see here is this is a proof,
but it was an automatically generated
proof and it's a really lousy story for
us humans.
I mean if it turned out that one of
these theorems here was one that had
been proved by gauss or something and
appeared in all the textbooks,
we wouldn't be much happier because then
we would start to have a kind of human
representable story about what was going
on.
Instead we just get a bunch of machine
generated Lammas that we can't
understand that we can't kind of wrap
our brains around and it's sorta the
same thing that's going on in.
When we look at when is neuron that's
we're seeing,
you know,
when we were looking,
wherever it was at the innards of that
neuron that.
And we say,
well,
how is it figuring out that that's a
picture of a panda?
Well,
the answer is it decided that,
you know,
if we humans were saying,
how would you figure out if it's a
picture of a panda,
we might say,
well look and see if it has eyes.
That's a clue for whether it's an animal
look and see if it's looks like it's
kind of round and furry and things
that's a version of whether it's a
pander and et cetera,
et cetera,
et cetera.
But what it's doing is it learned to a
bunch of criteria for,
you know,
is it a pandora?
Is it one of 10,000
other possible things that it could have
recognized?
And it learns those criteria in a way
that was somehow optimal based on the
training that it got and so on.
But it learned things which were
distinctions which are different from
the distinctions that we humans make in
the language that we as humans use.
And so in some sense,
you know,
when,
when we start talking about,
well,
describe a picture,
we have a certain human language for
describing that picture.
We have in our human,
in typical human languages,
we have maybe 30 to 50,000
words that we use to describe things.
Those words are words that have sort of
evolved as being useful for describing
the world that we live in when it comes
to this neural net.
It could be using,
it could say,
well,
uh,
the,
the words that it is effectively learnt,
which allow it to make distinctions
about what's going on in the,
in the analysis that it's doing it as
effectively invented words that describe
distinctions,
but those words have nothing to do with
our historically invented words that
exist in our languages.
So it's kind of an interesting situation
that,
that it is,
its way of thinking,
so to speak.
if you say,
well,
what's it thinking about?
How do we describe what it's thinking?
That's a tough thing to answer because
just like with the,
with the automated theorem,
we're,
we're sort of stuck having to say,
well,
we can't really tell a human story
because the things that had invented a
things for which we don't even have
wordS in our languages and so on.
Okay.
So one thing to reAlize is in this kind
of space of sort of all possible
computations,
that a lot of stuff out there that can
be done,
there's this coat kind of ocean of
sophisticated computation and then the
question that we have to ask for us
humans is,
okay,
how do we make use of all of that stuff?
So what we've got kind of on the one
hand is we've got the things we know how
to think about human languages,
our way of describing things,
our way of talking about stuff.
That's the One,
one side of things.
The other side of things we have is this
very powerful kind of ocean of
computation on the other side where lots
of things can happen.
So the question is how do we make use of
this sort of ocean of computation in the
best possible way for our human purposes
and building technology and so on.
And So the way I see,
you know,
my kind of a part of what I've spent a
very long time doing this kind of
building a language that allows us to
take human thinking.
On the one hand and describe and sort of
provide a sort of computational
communication language that allows us to
get the benefit of what's possible over
in the sort of ocean of computation in a
way that's rooted in what we humans
actually want to do.
And so I kind of view or from language
as being sort of an attempt to make a
bridge between.
So,
you know,
on the one hand there's all possible
computations.
On the other hand,
there's things we think we want to do
and I view often language languages
being my best attempt right now to make
a way to take our sort of human
computational thinking and be able to
actually implement it.
So in a sense,
iT's a language which works in two on
two sides.
It's both a language where you as a,
uh,
as uh,
the machine can understand,
okay,
it's looking at this and that's what
it's going to compute.
But on the other hand,
it's also a language for us humans to
think about things and computational
terms.
So,
you know,
if I go and I,
I don't know,
one of these,
one of these things that I'm doing here,
whatever it is that this wasn't that
exciting but,
but,
um,
you know,
find shortest tour of the geo position
of a capital cities in south America.
That is a language that's a
representation or a precise language of
something.
And the idea is that that's a language
which we humans can find useful in
thinking about things in computational
terms.
It also happens to be a language that
the machine can immediately understand
and execute.
And so I think this is sort of a
general,
you know,
when I think about ai in general,
the,
you know,
what is the sort of,
what's the overall problem?
Well,
part of the overall problem is so how do
we tell the ais what to do,
so to speak.
There's this very powerful,
you know,
this sort of ocean of computation is
what we get to mine for purposes of
building ai kinds of things.
But then the question is how do we tell
ais what to do and what I see,
what I've tried to do with wolfram
language is to provide a,
a way of kind of accessing that
computation and sort of making use of
the knowledge that our civilization has
accumulated and because that's the,
you know,
there's the general computation on,
on this side and there's the specific
things that we humans have thought about
and the question is to make use of the
things that we've thought about to do,
do things that we care about doing.
Actually,
if you're interested in these kinds of
things.
I happen to just write a blog post last
couple of days ago.
It's kind of a funny blog posts.
It's about,
um,
well you can see the title there.
It came because a friend of mine has,
has this crazy project to put little,
little sort of a desks or something
that,
um,
should represent kind of the best
achievements of human civilization,
so to speak,
to send out.
It's,
it's hitchhiking on various spacecraft
that are going out into the solar system
in the next little while.
And the question is what to put on this
little desk that kind of represents,
you know,
the achievements of civilization.
It's kind of,
it's kind of depressing when you go back
and you look at what,
um,
what people have tried to do on this
before.
And I'm realizing how hard it is to tell
even whether something is an artifact or
not.
um,
but this is a,
this was sort of a,
um,
uh,
that's a good one.
That's from 11,000
years ago.
Can you.
The question is,
can you figure out what on earth it is
and what it means?
And this is,
uh,
but,
so what,
what's relevant about this is the,
this,
this whole question of there are things
that are out there and the computational
universe.
And you know,
when we think about extraterrestrial
intelligence,
I find it kind of interesting that
artificial intelligence is our first
example of an alien intelligence.
We don't happen to have found what we
view as extraterrestrial intelligence
right now,
but we are in the process of building
pretty decent version of an alien
intelligence here.
And the question is,
if you ask questions like,
well,
you know,
what is it thinking?
Is it,
does it have a purpose and what it's
doing and so on,
and you're confronted with things like
this.
It's very,
we can kind of do a test run of,
you know,
what's,
what's its purpose?
What is it trying to do in a way that is
very similar to the kinds of questions
you would ask about,
about extraterrestrial intelligence.
But in any case,
the,
um,
uh,
the,
the main point is that I see there's
sort of ocean of computation,
there's the,
let's describe what we actually want to
do with that ocean of computation.
And that's where,
you know,
that's one of the primary problems we
have now.
People talk about,
you know,
ai and what is ai going to allow us to
automate.
And my basic answer to that would be
we'll be able to automate everything
that we can describe.
The problem is it's not clear what we
can describe or put another way,
you know,
you imagine various jobs and people are
doing things that are repeated judgment,
jobs,
things like this there where we can
readily automate those things.
But the thing that we can't really
automate is saying,
well,
what are we trying to do that is,
what are our goals?
Because in a sense,
when,
when we see one of these systems,
you know,
let's say,
let's say it's a,
it's a cellular automaton here.
Okay?
The question is,
what is the cellular automaton trying to
do?
Maybe I can.
Maybe I'll give you another cellular
automaton that there's a little bit more
exciting here.
Let's do this one.
So the,
the um,
the question is what is the cellular
automaton trying to do?
You know,
it's got this whole big structure here
and things are happening with it.
We can go,
we can run it for a couple of thousand
steps.
We can ask.
So nice example of kind of
undecidability and action.
What's going to happen here?
This is kind of the whole thing.
Problem is this kind of holt,
what's it going to do?
A,
there's computational or disability that
we actually can't tell.
There's the case where we know this is a
universal computer.
In fact eventually,
well,
I wouldn't even spell it for you if I
went on long enough.
It would,
it would go into some kind of cycle.
But,
um,
we can ask what is this thing trying to
do?
What is it,
you know,
is it,
what's it thinking about?
What's it,
what's its goal,
what's its purpose?
And you know,
we get very quickly and in a big mess
thinking about those kinds of things.
I've,
um,
one of the things that comes out of this
principle of computational equivalence
is thinking about what kinds of things
have a,
are capable of,
of sophisticated computation.
So,
so I mentioned a while back here,
sort of my personal history with wealth
malware of having thought about doing
something like wealth now for when I was
a kid and then believing that you sort
of had to build a brain to make that
possible and so on.
And one of the things that I then
thought was that there was some kind of
bright line between what is intelligent
and what is merely computational,
so to speak.
In other words that there was something
which is like,
oh,
we've got this great thing that we
humans have that is intelligence and all
these things in nature and so on.
And all the stuff that's going on there.
It's just computation or it's just,
you know,
things operating according to rules
that's different.
There's some bright line distinction
between these things.
Well,
I think the thing that came about after
I looked at all these cellular automata
and all kinds of other things like that
is I sort of came up with this principle
of computational equivalence,
a idea which we've now got quite a lot
of evidence for,
which I talked about people are
interested in.
But that basically there isn't a,
that once you reach a certain level of
computational sophistication,
everything is equivalent.
And that means that that implies that
there really isn't a bright line
distinction between,
for example,
the computation is going on in our
brains and the computations going on in
this simple cellular automata and so on.
And that essentially philosophical point
is what actually got me to start trying
to build both from alpha because I
realized that,
gosh,
you know,
I've been looking for this sort of the
magic bullets of intelligence and I just
decided probably there isn't one and
actually it's all just computation.
And so that means we can actually in
practice build something that doeS this
kind of intelligent like thing.
And so that's what I think is the case,
is that there really isn't sort of a
bright line distinction and that has,
that has more extreme consequences.
Like people will say things like,
you know,
the weAther has a mind of its own.
Okay.
Sounds kind of silly.
Sounds kind of animistic primitive and
so on.
But in fact,
the fluid dynamics of the weather is as
computationally sophisticated as the
stuff that goes on in our brains.
But we can start askIng,
but then you say,
but the weather doesn't have a purpose.
You know,
what's the purpose of the weather?
Well,
you know,
maybe the weather is trying to equalize
the temperature between the,
you know,
the,
the north pole and the tropics or
something.
And then we have to say,
well,
but that's not a purpose.
And the way that we think about
purposes,
that's just,
you know,
and we get very confused.
And in the end what we realized is when
we're talking about things like
purposes,
we have to have this kind of chain of
provenance that goes back to humans and
human history and all that kind of
thing.
And I think it's the same type of thing
when we talk about computation and ai
and so on.
The thing that we.
This question of sort of purpose goals,
things like this,
that's the thing which is intrinsically
human and not something that we can ever
sort of automatically generate.
It makes no sense to talk about
automatically generating it.
Because these computational systems,
they do all kinds of stuff.
You know,
we can say they've got a purpose.
We can attribute purposes to them,
et cetera,
et cetera.
But you know,
ultimately it's sort of the human thread
of purpose that we have to have to deal
with.
So that means,
for example,
when we talk about ais and we were
interested in things like,
so how do we tell,
you know,
like,
like we'd like to be able to tell.
We talk about ai ethics for example.
We'd like to be able to make a statement
to the ais like,
you know,
please be nIce to,
to us humans and that's a,
you know,
that's something.
So one of the issues there is so,
so talking about that kind of thing,
I'm one of the issues is how are we
going to make a statement like be nice
to us humans.
What's the,
how are we going to explain that to an
ai?
And this is where again,
you know my,
my efforts to build a language,
a computational communication language
that bridges the world of what we humans
think about and the world of what is
possible and computation is important.
And So one of the things I've been
interested in is actually building what
I call a symbolic discourse language
that can be a general representation for
a sort of the kinds of things that we
might want to,
uh,
put in,
that we might want to say and things
like be nice to humans.
So sort of a little bit of background to
that.
So you know,
in,
in the modern world,
people are keen on smart contracts.
They often think of them has been deeply
tied into blockchain,
which I don't think it's really quite
right.
The important thing about smart
contracts is it's a way of having sort
of an agreement between parties which
can be executed automatically.
And that agreement may be,
you know,
you may choose to sort of anchor that
agreement on blockchain.
You may not,
but the whole point is you have to
watch,
you know,
when people like legal contracts,
they write them in an approximation to
english.
They write them in legal ease typically
because they're trying to write them in
something a little bit more precise than
regular english.
But the limitiNg case of that is to make
a symbolic discourse language in which
you can write the contract and code
basically.
And the.
I've been very interested in using
wolfram language to do that because in
wolfram language we have a language
which can describe things about the
world and we can talk about the kinds of
things that people actually talk about
in contracts and so on.
We're most of the way there to being
able to do that.
And then when you start thinking about
that,
you start thInking about,
okay,
so we've got this language to describe
things that we,
that we care about in the world.
And so when it comes to things like tell
the ais to be nice to humans,
we can imagine using both language to
sort of build an ai constitution that
says this is how the ai is supposed to
work.
But when we talk about sort of just the,
the untethered,
untethered,
ai doesn't have any particular,
it's just going to do what it does.
And if we want it to,
you know,
if we want to somehow align it with
human purposes,
we have to have some way to sort of talk
to the ai and that's,
that's uh,
you know,
I view my efforts to bilbo from language
as,
as way to do that.
I mean,
I,
you know,
as I was showing at the beginning,
you can use,
you can take natural language and wIth
natural language you can build up a
certain amount of,
you can say a certain number of things
and natural language.
You can then say,
well,
how do we make this more precise in a
precise symbolic language if you want to
build up more complicated things,
it gets hard to do that and natural
language.
And so you have to kind of build up more
serious programs in,
in,
in symbolic language.
And I've probably been numb,
been yacking while here and I'm happy
to.
I can talk about all kinds of different
things here.
But,
but maybe I'm,
uh,
I've not seen as many reactions as I
might've expected to think.
So I'm not sure which things people are
interested in,
which they're not.
But,
so maybe I should,
maybe I should stop here and we can have
discussion questions,
comments?
Yes.
Two microphones.
If you have questions,
please come up.
So,
uh,
I have a quick question.
It's close to the earlier part of your
talk where you say you don't build a top
down ontology,
you actually build from the bottom up
with disparate domains.
What do you feel are the core
technologies of the knowledge
representation which you used within
wolfram alpha that allows you a
different domains to reason about each
other to come up with solutions and is
there any feeling of differentiability
for examples if you were to come up with
a plan to do something new within
wolfram alpha language,
how would you go about doing that?
Okay,
so we've done maybe a couple of thousand
domains.
Okay.
They,
what is actually involved in doing one
of these domains.
It's,
it's a gnarly business.
Every domain has some crazy different
thing about it.
I tried to make up actually a while ago,
we,
um,
let me show you something that kind of a
hierarchy of what it means to make.
See if I can find this here,
kind of a hierarchy of what it means to
make a domain computable.
Uh,
where is it?
Here we go.
Okay,
here we go.
So this is sort of a hierarchy of levels
of what it means to make a domain
computable from just,
you know,
you've got some,
you've got some array of data that's
quite structured.
Forget the separate issue about
extracting things from unstructured
data,
but let's imagine that you were given,
you know,
a,
a bunch of data about landing sites of
meteorites or something.
Okay.
So you go through various levels,
so you know,
things like,
okay,
the landing sites of the meteorites are
the other positions,
just strings or there's some kind of
canonical representation of geo
possession.
Is the,
is the type of meteorite,
you know,
some of them are iron meteorites,
some of them are stone meteorites.
Have you made a canonical
representation?
have you made some kind of a way to uh,
to identify what.
I'm sorry,
go ahead.
No,
no,
I mean to do that.
So,
so my question is,
if you did have positions as a string as
well as a canonical representation,
do you have redundant pieces of the same
redundant representations of the same
information in different?
You always,
everything can that you have.
You have a minimal representation of
everything.
So our goal is to make everything
canonical.
Now that's,
you know,
there is a lot of complexity in doing
that.
I mean if you,
you know,
in each.
Okay.
So another feature of these domains.
So here's another,
another thing to say,
you know,
it will be lovely if I could just
automate everything and cut the humans
out of the loop.
Turns out this doesn't work.
And in fact,
whenever we do these domains,
it's fairly critical to have expert
humans who really understand the domain
or you simply get it wrong.
And it's also having said that once
you've done enough domains,
you can do a lot of crosschecking
between domains and we are the number
one reporters of error and have errors
and in pretty much all standardized data
sources because we can do that kind of
cross checkinG.
But I think if you ask the question,
what's involved in,
um,
in bringing online a new domain,
it's those sort of hierarchy of things.
Some of those take a few hours.
You can get to the point of having,
you know,
we've got good enough tools for
ingesting data,
figuring out,
oh,
those are names of cities in that
column.
Let's canonic allies.
Those,
some may be questions,
but many of them will be able to nail
down and to get to the full level of,
you've got some complicated domain and
it's fully computable is probably a year
of work.
Um,
and,
uh,
and you might say,
well,
gosh,
why?
Why are you wasting your time?
You've got to be able to automate that.
So you can probably tell we're fairly
sophisticated about machine learning
kinds of things and so on.
And we have tried to automate as much as
we can and we have got a pretty
efficient pipeline.
But if you actually want to get it right
and you see it,
here's an example of what happens,
that there's a level even going between
wolf malfa more from language.
there's a level of.
So for example,
let's say you're looking at,
you know,
lakes in Wisconsin.
Okay.
So people are querying about lakes in
Wisconsin and wolfram alpha,
they'll name a particular lake and they
want to know,
you know,
how big is the lake?
okay,
fine.
In wolfram language they'll be doing a
systematic computation about lakes in
Wisconsin.
So if there's a lake missing,
you're going to get the wrong answer.
And So that's a kind of higher level of,
of uh,
of,
of difficulty.
Okay.
But the,
there's,
I think you're asking some more
technical questions about ontologies and
I can try and answer those.
Actually.
One quick question.
Can you know there's,
there's a lot of other questions.
Okay.
All right.
I'll give it a recycles as I've got a
simple question.
Who or what are your key influences?
Whoa.
Gosh.
In terms of of language design for
orphan language in the context of
machine intelligence,
if you liked,
if you want to make it tailored to this
audience.
I don't know.
I've been absorbing stuff forever.
I think my main in terms of language
design,
probably lisp in apl with my sort of
early influences,
but in terms of,
of um,
thinking about ai,
you know,
in,
I mean I'm kind of
quite knowledgeable.
I like history of science.
I'm pretty knowledgeable about the early
history of kind of mathematical logic,
symbolic kinds of things.
I would say.
Okay,
maybe I can answer that in the negative.
Okay.
I have,
for example,
in building wolfram alpha,
I thought,
gosh,
let me do my homework.
Let me learn all about computational
linguistics.
Let me hire some computational
linguistics phds.
That will be a good way to get the
start.
It turns out we used almost nothing from
the,
from the previous sort of history of
computational linguistics,
partly because what we were trying to
do,
namely short question,
natural language understanding is
different from a lot of the natural
language processing,
which has been done in the past.
I also have made to my disappointment,
very little use of,
you know,
people like marvin minsky for example.
I really don't think.
I mean,
I knew marvin for years and in fact some
of his early work on simple turing
machines and things,
those are probably more influential to
me than his work on,
on ai and you know,
probably my,
my mistake of not understanding that
better,
but really I would say that I've been
been rather uninfluenced by,
by sort of the traditional ai kinds of
things.
I mean,
it probably hasn't helped that I've kind
of lived through a time when one sort of
ai went from,
you know,
when I was a kid,
ai was going to solve everything in the
world and then,
you know,
it kind of decade for awhile and then
sort of come back.
So I,
I,
so I would say I can describe my
negative,
my non influences better than my give is
that you made it your own head and it
sounds as though that's pretty much
right?
Yeah,
I mean,
yes,
I mean in so far as there's things to
me,
I mean look things like the um,
uh,
you know.
Okay.
So for example,
studying simple programs as a.
I'm trying to understand the universal
simple programs.
Actually,
the personal history of that sort of
interesting.
I mean,
I,
you know,
I used to do particle physics when I was
a kid basically.
And um,
uh,
then I actually got interested.
Okay.
So I'll tell you the history of that
just as an example of how sort of
interesting as a sort of history of
ideas type thing.
So I was interested in,
in how order arises in the universe.
So you know,
you start off from the hot big bang and
then pretty soon you end up with a bunch
of humans and galaxies and things like
this.
How does this happen?
So I got an interest in that question.
I was also interested in things like
neural networks for sort of ai purposes
and I thought let me make a minimal
model that encompasses sort of how
complex things arise from,
from other stuff.
And I ended up sort of making simpler
and simpler and simpler models and
eventually wound up with cellular
automata and whIch I didn't know were
called cellular automata when I started
looking at them and then found they did
an interesting things and the two areas
where cellular automata had been
singularly unuseful in analyzing things
are large scale structure in the
universe and your own networks.
So it turned out.
But,
but that,
by the way,
the fact that I couldn't have even
imagined that one could just start.
Yeah,
I should say,
you know,
I've been doing physics and in physics,
the kind of intellectual concept is you
take the world as it is and you're
trying to drill down and find out what,
you know,
what makes the world out of primitives
and so on.
It's kind of a reduced to find things.
Then I built my first computer language,
I think of the snp which went the other
way round where I was just like,
I'm just going to make up this computer
language and you know,
just make up what I want the primitives
to be.
And then I'm going to build stuff up
from it.
I think that the fact that I kind of had
the idea of doing things like making up
a little automatons as possible models
for the world was a consequence of the
fact that I've worked on this computer
language,
which was a thing which worked the
opposite way round from the way that one
is used to doing natural,
which is sort of this reductionist
approach.
And that's.
I mean,
so that's just an example of I've found.
I happened to have spent a bunch of time
studying,
as I say,
history of science and one of my,
one of my hobbies is sort of history of
ideas.
I even wrote this little book called
idea makers,
which is about biographies of a bunch of
people who for one reason or another
I've written about.
And so I'm,
I'm always curious about this thing
about how do people actually wind up
figuring out the things they figure out.
and you know,
one of the,
one of the conclusions that my,
you know,
investigations with many people is there
a very rarely moments of inspiration.
Usually it's long multi-decade kinds of
things which only later get compressed
into something short.
And also the path is often much,
uh,
you know,
it's,
it's quite,
uh,
can I say that the steps are quite small
and you know,
but the path is often kind of
complicated and that's what,
that's what it's been for me.
So I.
Simple question,
complex answer,
sorry about that.
Oh,
so,
um,
when I basically see it from the wall
from languages,
it's a way to describe all of objective
reality.
It's kind of formalizing your swabbed,
the entire domain of discourse,
user philosophical term.
And you kind of hinted at this in your,
a lecture where the,
where it sort of leaves offices that
when we start to talk about more
esoteric,
philosophical concepts,
purpose,
I guess this would lead to things like
epistemology because essentially you
only have signed there as amazing as
sciences.
There are other things that are talked
aboUt not,
you know,
like idealism versus materialism,
etc.
Do you have an idea of how well from
might or might not be able to branch
into those discourses?
Because I'm hearing echoes in my head at
that time,
baal shem said that an ai needs a,
you know,
when you give an ai a purpose,
there's like,
I think he said,
philosophers are divided completely
evenly between the top four ways to
measure how good something should be.
It's like utilitarianism and sugar are
the foremost japanese.
Yeah.
Right.
So the first thing is,
I mean,
this problem of making what about 300
years ago,
people like live nets were interested in
the same problem that I'm interested in,
which is how do you formalize sort of
everyday discourse and live minutes had
the original idea,
you know,
he was originally trained as a lawyer
and he had this idea if he could only
reduce all law,
all legal questions to matters of logic,
he could have a machine that would
basically describe the answer every
legal case.
He was unfortunately a few hundred years
too early.
Um,
even though he did have,
you know,
he tried to,
he tried to do all kinds of things,
very similar things I've tried to do,
like he tried to get various dukes to
assemble big libraries of data.
And stuff like this,
but,
but the point.
So what he tried to do was to make a
formalized representation of everyday
discourse for whatever reason for the
last 300 years.
Basically people haven't tried to do
that.
There's,
it's almost completely barren landscape.
There was this period of time in the 16
hundredS when people talked about
philosophicAl languages.
Lightness was one.
A guy called John Wilkins was another
and they tried to break down human
thought into something.
Symbolic.
People haven't done that for a long
time.
Um,
in terms of what can we do that with,
um,
you know,
I've been trying to figure out what the
best way to do it is.
I think it's actUally not as hard as one
might think these areas.
One thing you have to understand these
areas like philosophy and so on are
there on the harder end.
I mean things like,
good example,
typical example,
you know,
I want to have a piece of chocolate.
Okay.
They in wolfram language right now,
we have a pretty good description of
pieces of chocolate.
We know all sorts of,
you know,
we probably know 100 different kinds of
chocolate.
We know how big the pieces are,
all that kind of thing that I want part
of that sentence.
We can't do that right now.
Um,
but I don't think that's that hard and
I'm,
you know,
that's now if you ask,
let's say we had,
I think the different thing you're
saying is let's say we had the
omnipotent ai so to speak,
that was able to,
you know,
where we turn over the control of the
central bank to the ai return over all
these other things to the ai.
Then the question is we say to the ai
now do the right thing.
And then the problem with that is,
and this is why I talk about,
you know,
creating ai constitutions and so on,
we have absolutely no idea what to do.
The right thing is supposed to mean.
And philosophers have been arguing about
that.
You know,
utilitarianism is an example of that,
of one of the answers to that.
Although it's not a complete answer by
any means,
it's not really an answer.
It's just a way of posing the question.
Um,
and so I think that the,
you know,
one of,
one of the features of um,
so I think it's a really hard problem
to,
you know,
you think to yourself,
what should the ai constitution actually
say?
So first thing you might think is,
oh,
there's going to be something like
asimov's laws of robotics that's going
to be one,
you know,
golden rule for ais.
And if we just follow that golden rule
or we.
Well,
okay,
I think that that is absolutely
impossible.
And in fact I think you can even sort of
mathematically prove that that's
impossible because I think as soon as
you have a system that,
you know,
essentially what you're trying to do is
you're trying to put in constraints
that,
okay,
basically as soon as you have a system
that shows computational
irreplaceability,
I think it is inevitable that you have a
case of have unintended consequences of
things,
which means that you never get,
just say,
put everything in this one very nice
box.
You always have to say,
let's put on a patch here.
Let's put on a patch there.
And so on a version of this much more
abstract version of this girdle's
theorem.
So girdle's theorem is,
you know,
it starts out by taking the,
uh,
you know,
it's girls' therapist trying to talk
about integers and says,
start off with pianos,
axioms,
pianos,
you might say in piano thought described
integers and nothing but the integers.
Okay?
So another thing that's provable from
pianos,
accidents will be true about integers
and vice versa.
Okay.
What girdle's theorem shows is that yoU
can,
that will never work,
that there are an infinite hierarchy of
patches that you have to put on two
pianos,
axioms if you want to describe the
integers and nothing but the integers.
And I think the same is true if you want
to have a legal system effectively that
has no bizarre,
unintended consequences.
I don't think it's possible to just say,
you know,
if you,
when you're describing something in the
world that's complicated like that,
I don't think it's possible to just have
a small set of rules that will always do
what we want.
So to speak.
I think it's inevitable that you have to
have a long essentially code of laws and
that's what,
you know.
So my guess is that what we'll actually
have to happen is,
you know,
as we try and describe what you,
we want the eyes to do,
you know,
I don't know the socio political aspects
of how we'll figure out whether it's one
ai constitution or one per,
you know,
city or whatever.
We can talk about that.
That's a separate issue.
But,
but,
um,
you know,
I think what will happen is it'll be
much like human laws.
There'll be a complicated thing that
gets progressively patched.
And so I think it's some and these ideas
like,
um,
you know,
oh,
we'll just make the eyes,
you know,
run the world according to,
mills,
you know,
John Stuart mill's idea.
It's not going to work the best,
which is not surprising.
This philosophy has,
has,
has made the point that it's not as
easy,
not an easy problem for the last 2000
years.
And they're right.
It's not an easy problem.
Thank you.
I,
I'm,
you're talking about computational
reducibility and computational
equivalent and also that earlier on in
your intellectual adventures you're
interested in particle physics and
things like that.
I've heard you make the comment before
and in other contexts that things like
molecules compute and I was curious to
ask you exactly what you mean by that.
In what sense does,
I mean,
what would you like to compute so to
speak?
I mean in other words,
you what,
what is the case is that no one
definition of your computing is given a
particular computation like,
I don't know,
finding square roots or something you
can program.
A surprising thing is that an awful lot
of stuff can be programmed to do any
computation you want that some,
you know,
when it comes to.
I mean I think for example,
when you look at nanotechnology and so
on,
the,
the current,
you know,
one of the current belief says to make
very small computers,
you should take what we know about
making big computers and just,
you know,
make them smaller so to speak.
I don't think that's the approach you
have to use.
I think you can take the components that
exist at a lot of molecules and say,
how do we assemble those components to
be able to do complicated computations?
I mean,
it's likely cellular automata that the,
you know,
the underlying rule for the seller
automaton is very simple.
Yet when that rule is applied,
many times it can do a sophisticated
computation.
So I think that that's the,
that's the sense in which,
what can I say,
the raw material that you need for
computation can be,
you know,
there's a great diversity and the raw
material that you can use for
computation.
Our particular human development,
you know,
stack of,
of,
uh,
of technologies that we use for
computation right now is just one
particular path.
And we can,
you know,
so a very practical example of this is
algorithmic drugs.
So the question is right now drugs
pretty much work by most drugs work by,
you know,
there is a binding site on a molecule,
drug fits into binding site,
does something.
The question is,
can you imagine having something where
the molecule is something which has
computations going on in it,
where it goes around and it looks at
that,
you know,
that thing it's supposed to be binding
to and it figures out,
oh,
there's this knob here and that knob
there,
it reconfigures itself.
It's computing something.
It's trying to figure out,
you know,
is this likely to be a tumor cell or
whatever based on some more complicated
thing.
That's the type of thing that I mean by,
by computations happening at a scale.
Okay.
I guess I meant to ask if it follows
from that,
if in your view like the molecules in
the track board and in my face and in
the table are in any sense currently
during doing computer.
I mean the question of what computation.
Look,
one of the things to realize if you look
at kind of the sort of past and future
of things,
the,
the um.
Okay.
So here's an observation.
Actually I was about leipnetz actually.
Enlightenment says time.
Leipnetz made a,
a calculator type computer out of bras.
Took them 30 years.
Okay.
So in his day there was,
you know,
at most one computer in the world as far
as he was concerned,
right?
Today's world,
there may be 10 billion computers,
maybe 20 billion computers.
I don't know.
The question is what's that gonna look
like in the future?
And I think the answer is that in time
probably everything we have will be made
of computers and the following sense
that basically it won't be,
you know,
in today's world things are made of,
metal,
plastic,
whatever else.
But actually that won't make it.
There won't be any point in doing that
once we know how to do,
you know,
I'm not a killer scale manufacturing and
so on.
We might as well just make everything
out of programmable stuff.
And I think that's a,
that's a sense in which,
you know,
the,
um,
you know,
the one example we have molecular
computing right now is us bio and
biology.
Biology does a reasonable job of
specific kinds of molecular computing.
Um,
it's kind of embarrassing.
I think that the only,
you know,
molecule we know that sort of a memory
molecule is dna and it's kind of,
you know,
which is kind of the,
the particular biological solution in
time.
We'll know lots of others and um,
you know,
I think the,
the,
um,
sort of the end point is so if you're
asking is,
is computation going on in this water
bottle?
The answer is absolutely.
It's probably even many aspects of that
computation,
a pretty sophisticated.
If we wanted to know what would happen
to particular molecules here,
it's going to be hard to tell there's
going to be computational
reproducibility and so on.
Can we make use of that for our human
purposes?
Can we piggyback on that to achieve
something technological that's different
issue and that's the for that we have to
build up this whole sort of chain of,
of technology to be able to connect it,
which is what I've kind of been been
keep on talking about is how do we
connect sort of what is possible
computationally in the universe to what
we humans can kind of conceptualize that
we want to do in computation and that's,
you know,
that's the bridge that we have to make
and that's the hard part.
but getting the intrinsic,
getting the computation done is,
is um,
you know,
those computation going on all over the
place.
But maybe a couple more questions.
I was hoping you could elaborate on what
you were talking about earlier of like
searching the entire space of possible
programs.
So that's very broad.
So maybe like what kind of searching of
that space we're good at and what we're
not.
And I guess what I mean,
I would say that we're at an early stage
and not knowing how to do that.
Okay.
So I've done lots of these things and
they are the thing that I've noticed is
if you do an exhaustive search,
then you don't miss even things that you
weren't looking for.
If you do a non exhaustive search,
there is a tremendous tendency to miss
things that you weren't looking for.
Um,
and so,
you know,
we've done such as a bunch of function
evaluation and wolfram language is done
by,
was done by searching for optimal
approximations in some big space,
a bunch of stuff with hashing has done
that way.
A bunch of image processing is done that
way where we're just sort of searching
this,
doing exhaustive searches and maybe
trillions of programs to find things.
Now,
you know,
there is,
on the other side of that story is the
incremental improvements story with,
with deep learning and neural networks
and so on,
where because there is differentiability
um,
you're able to sort of incrementally get
to a better solution.
Now in fact,
people are making less and less
differentiability and deep learning
neural nets.
And so I think eventually there's going
to be sort of a,
a grand unification of these kinds of
approaches.
Right now we're still,
you know,
I don't really know what the,
the exhaustive search side of things,
which you can use for all sorts of
purposes.
I mean,
there's the reason,
the surprising thing that makes
exhaustive search not crazy is that
there is rich sophisticated stuff near
at hand and the computational universe,
if you had to go quadrillions,
you know,
through a quadrillion cases before you
ever found a thing.
Exhaustive search will be hopeless,
but you don't in many cases.
Um,
and uh,
you know,
I would say that we are in a fairly
primitive stage of the,
of the science of how to do those such
as.
Well.
My guess is that there'll be some sort
of unification,
which needless to say,
I've thought a bunch about between kind
of the norm.
That tradeoff typically in neural net
says you can have a neural net that is
very good at that is uses it's
computational resources.
Well,
but it's really hard to train.
Or you can have a neural net that
doesn't use this computational resources
so well,
but it's very easy to train because it's
very smoothly and you know,
my guess is that somewhere in the harder
to train but makes use of things that
are to the complete computational
universe is where one's going to see
progress,
but it's,
it's a,
it's a really interesting area and I
consider us own it at the beginning of
figuring that out.
The one last question.
Keep going.
Thank you for your talk.
I just to give a bit of context for my
question,
I researched how we could teach ai
toolkits and evolving platforms for
that.
How we could teach artificial
intelligence and machine learning to
children and I know you develop
resources for that as well.
So I was wondering like where do you
think it's problematic that we have
computation that is very efficient and
can promote utd darien and problem
solving perspective?
It achieves all the goals but we don't
understand that how we have it worked.
So we have to create this fake steps and
if he could think of scenarios where
that could become very problematic over
time and why do we approach it such and
such a deterministic way.
And when you mentioned that
computational intelligence are
differentiated by this,
like very thin line,
how does that affect the way you learn
and how do you think that will affect
the way we learn?
We learn.
So I mean look,
my general principle about,
you know,
future generations and what they should
learn.
I mean,
first point is very obvious point that
for every field that people study
archaeology to zoology,
there either is now a computational x or
there will be soon.
So you know,
every field,
the paradigm of computation is becoming
important,
perhaps the dominant paradigm in that
field.
Okay.
So how do you teach kids to be useful in
a world where everything is
computational?
I think the number one thing is to teach
them how to think in computational
terms.
What does that mean?
It doesn't mean writing code
necessarily.
I mean,
in other words,
one of the things that's happening right
now as a practical matter,
as you know,
there've been these waves of enthusiasm
for teaching coding of various kinds.
You know,
we're in a.
We're not actually,
we're in the end of an uptick wave.
I think it's going down again,
you know,
it's been up and down for 40 years or
so.
Okay.
Why doesn't that work?
What doesn't work?
Because while there are people like
people who are students at mit for
example,
for whom they really to learn
engineering style coding and it really
makes sense to them to learn that the
vast majority of people,
it's just not going to be irrelevant
because they're not going to write a low
level c program or something.
And it's the same thing that's happened
in math education,
which has been sort of a disaster there.
Which is the number one takeaway for
most people from the math they learn in
school is I don't like math.
And you know,
that's not for all of them obviously,
but that's the,
you know,
if you asked a general scale,
what people and why is that?
Well,
part of the reason is because what's
been taught is rather low level and
mechanical.
It's not about mathematical thinking
particularly.
It's mostly about what teachers can
teach and what assessment processes can
assess and so on.
Okay.
So how should one teach computational
thinking?
I mean,
I'm,
I'm kind of excited about what we can do
with wolfram language because I think we
have a high enough level language that
people can actually write,
you know,
that for example,
I reckon by age 11 or 12,
and I've done many experiments on this,
so I have some,
the only problem with my experiments as
most of my experiments end up being with
kids who are high achieving kids,
despite many efforts to reach lower
achieving kids,
that always ends up that the kids who
actually do the things that I set up for
the high achieving kids.
but,
but setting that aside,
you know,
you take the typical um,
uh,
you know,
11,
12,
13 year olds and so on,
and they can learn how to write stuff in
this language.
And what's interesting is they learn to
start thinking here,
I'll show you.
Let's be very practical.
I can show you.
I was doing every sunday I do a little
little thing with some middle school
kids and I might even be able to find my
stuff from yesterday.
This is,
this is,
um,
okay.
Let's see.
Programming adventures sharing 20 days.
Okay,
let's see what I did.
Oh,
look at that.
That was,
that was why I thought of the south
America thing here because I had just
done that with these kids.
Um,
the,
um,
and so,
uh,
what are we doing?
We were trying to figure out this,
this.
I'm trying to figure out the shortest
tour thing that I just showed you,
which is this is how I got where I got
what to show you is,
is what I was doing with these kids.
But this,
this wAs my version of this.
But the kids all had various different
versions of this and we had,
um,
somebody suggested,
let's just enumerate,
let's just look at all possible
permutations of these cities and figure
out what their distances are.
There's the histograM of those.
That's what we get from those.
Okay.
How do you get the largest distance from
those,
et cetera.
Terror,
terror.
And this is okay.
This was my version of that.
The kids had similar stuff and this is,
you know,
this is,
I think,
and it probably went off into,
oh,
there we go.
There's the one for the whole whole
earth.
And then they wanted to know how do you
do that in three d?
So I was showing them how to convert to
x,
y,
z coordinates in three d and make the
corresponding thing in three d.
So what's.
This maybe isn't the.
This is a random example from yesterday.
So it's not,
not a highly considered example,
but,
um,
uh,
what I think is interesting is that we
seem to have finally reached the point
where we've automated enough of the
actual doing of the computation that the
kids can be exposed mostly to thinking
about what you might want to compute.
And you know,
part of our role in language design as
far as I'm concerned,
is to get it as much as possible to the
point where,
for example,
you can do a bunch of natural language
input,
you can do things which make it as easy
as possible for kids to not get mixed up
in the kind of what the,
you know,
how the computation gets done,
but rather to just think about how you
formulate the computation.
So for example,
a typical example I've used a bunch of
times in,
you know,
what does it mean to write code versus
do other things.
Like a,
a typical sort of test example would be,
I dunno you,
you asked somebody a,
you're gonna,
there's practical problem.
We had them alpha.
You give a lat long position on the
earth and you say you're going to make a
map that lat long position.
What,
what scale of map should you make?
The lat,
long as in the middle of the pacific,
making a 10 mile radius map isn't very
interesting.
Fits in the middle of manhattan.
A 10 mile radius map might be quite,
quite a sensible thing to do.
So the question has come up with an
algorithm and come up with even a way of
thinking about that question.
What do you do?
You know,
how should you figure that out while you
might say,
you know,
oh,
let's look at the visual complexity of
the image.
Let's look at how far it is to another
city that's far.
You know,
there are various different things,
but thinking about that as a kind of
computational thinking exercise that um,
uh,
is um,
you know,
that's the kind of thing.
So in terms of what one automates and
whether,
whether people need to understand how it
works inside.
Okay.
Main point is you'll,
in the end it will not be possible to
know how it works inside.
So you might as well stop having that be
a criterion.
I mean,
that is,
there are plenty of things that weren't
teachers,
people that are,
let's say,
in,
in lots of areas of biology,
medicine,
whatever else,
you know,
maybe we'll know how it works inside one
day,
but you can still,
there's an awful lot of useful stuff you
can teach without knowing how it works
inside.
And I think also as we get to
computation to be more efficient,
inevitably we will be dealing with
things where you don't know how it works
inside.
Now,
you know,
we've seen this in math education
because I've happened to make tools that
automate a bunch of things that people
do in math education.
And I think,
well,
to tell a silly story,
I mean,
my,
my older daughter,
who at some point in the past was doing
calculus,
you know,
and learning doing intervals and things.
And I was saying to her,
you know,
I didn't think humans still did that
stuff anymore.
Um,
which was a very unending comment.
But um,
but,
but in any case,
I mean the,
the,
you know,
a question of whether do humans need to
know how to do that stuff or not.
So I haven't done an integral by hand
and probably 35 years that's true.
More or less true that.
But when I was using computers to do
them,
the I was for awhile in Hawaii,
I used to do physics and so on.
I use computers to the stuff.
I was a really,
really good integrator except that it
wasn't really me.
It was me plus the computer.
So how did that come to be?
Well,
the answer was that because I was doing
things by computer,
I was able to try zillions of examples
and I got a much better intuition that
most people got for how these things
would work,
roughly how,
what you did to make the thing go and so
on.
Whereas people who are like,
I'm just working this one thing out by
hand.
You get a different,
you know,
you,
you don't get that intuition.
So I think,
you know,
two points.
First of all this,
how do you think about things
computationally?
How do you formulate the question
computationally that's really important
and something that we are now in a
position I think to actually teach and
it is not really something you teach by,
you know,
teaching,
traditional quotes,
coding,
because a lot of that is.
Okay,
we're going to make a loop.
We're going to define variables.
I just as I think I probably have a copy
here.
Yeah,
the,
I wrote this book for this book kind of
for kids about oral language except it
seems to be useful to adults as well,
but I wrote it for kids.
So it's,
um,
I'm,
one of the amusing things in this book
is it doesn't talk it.
Talk about assigning values to variables
until chapter 38.
So in other words,
that will be a thing that you would find
in chapter one of most,
you know,
low level programming,
coding type type things.
It turns out it's not that relevant to
know how to do that.
it's also kind of confusing and I'm uh,
not necessarily.
And so,
no,
in terms of the,
you asked where will we get in trouble
when people don't know how this stuff
works inside.
Um,
that's,
I mean,
you know,
I think one just has to get used to that
because it's like,
you know,
you might say,
well we live in the world and it's full
of natural processes where we don't know
how they work inside,
but somehow we managed to survive and we
go to a lot of effort to do natural
science to try and figure out how stuff
works inside.
But it turns out we can still use plenty
of things even when we don't know how
they work inside.
We don't need to know.
um,
and I think the,
I mean I think the main point is
computational error,
reducibility guarantees that we will be
using things where we don't know and
can't know how they work inside.
And you know,
I think the,
the,
perhaps the thing that is a little bit,
you know,
to me a little bit unfortunate as a,
as a typical human type thing.
The fact that I can readily see that,
you know,
the ai stuff we build is sort of
effectively creating languages and
things that are completely outside of
the domain to understand and where by by
that I mean,
you know,
our human language,
but that's 50,000
words or whatever has been developed
over the last however many tens of
thousands of years.
And as a society we've developed this
way of communicating and explaining
things.
You know,
the ais are reproducing that process
very quickly,
but they're coming up with a,
an,
a historical,
you know,
something,
that way of describing the world that
doesn't happen to relate at all to our
historical way of doing it.
And that's um,
you know,
it's a little bit disquieting to me as a
human that,
that,
you know,
are things going on inside where I know
it is.
You know,
in principle I could learn that
language,
but it's not the historical one that
we've all learned.
And it really wouldn't make a lot of
sense to do that because you learn it
for one ai and then another one gets
trained and it's going to use something
different.
So it's some.
But my main,
I guess my main point for,
for education.
So another point about education I just
make,
which is something I haven't figured out
but,
but um,
just is um,
you know,
when do we get to make a good model for
the human learner using machine
learning?
So in other words,
you know,
part of what we're trying to do,
like,
like I've got that automated proof,
I would really like to manage to figure
out a way what is the best way to
present that proof so human can
understand it.
And basically for that we have to have a
bunch of heuristics about how humans
understand things.
So as an example,
if we're doing,
let's say a lot of visualization stuff
and wolfram language,
okay,
we have tried to automate to automate it
aesthetics.
So what we're doing is we're laying out
a graph.
What way of laying out that graph is
most likely for humans to understand it.
And we've done that by building a bunch
of heuristics and so on,
but that's an example of,
you know,
if we could do that for learning and we
say what's the optimal path given that
the person is trying to understand this
proof,
for example,
what's the optimal path to lead them
through understanding that proof.
I suspect we will learn a lot more and
probably fairly small number of years
about that.
And it will be the case that,
you know,
for example,
if you've got,
oh I don't know,
you can do simple things like you know,
you go to wikipedia and you look at what
the path of,
you know,
how do you,
if you want to learn this concept,
what are the concepts you have to learn?
We have much more detailed symbolic
information about what is actually
necessary to know in order to understand
this.
And so on.
It is,
I think,
reasonably likely that we will be able
to.
I mean if I look at.
I was interested recently in the history
of math education.
so I wanted to look at the complete sort
of path of math textbooks.
You know,
for the past,
well basically the,
uh,
like 1200,
you know,
even actually produced this one of the
early math textbooks.
So there'd been these different ways of
teaching math and you know,
I think we've,
we've gradually evolved a fairly
optimized way for the typical person
though.
It's probably the variation of the
population is not well understood for
you know,
how to explain certain concepts.
And we've gone through some pretty weird
ways of doing it from the 16 hundreds
and so on were which have gone out of
style and possibly,
you know,
who knows what that's because of.
Well,
but anyway,
so,
you know,
we've kind of learned this path of
what's the optimal way to explain adding
fractions or something for humans for
the typical human.
But I think we'll learn a lot more about
how,
you know,
by,
by essentially making a model for the
human.
A machine model for the human will learn
more about how to,
um,
you know,
how to optimize,
how to explain stuff to humans,
a coming attraction.
But
by the way,
do you think we're close to that at all?
Because you,
you,
you said that there's a,
something in wolfram alpha that,
that presents the human a nice,
our.
Where are we,
how far?
He said coming attraction,
tenure.
All right.
So I mean in that explaining stuff to
humans thing is a lot of human work
right now being able to automate
explaining stuff to humans.
Okay.
So some of these things but see,
I mean,
so an interesting question actually just
today I was working on something that's
related to this.
Yeah,
it's,
it's being able to,
um,
the question is given a whole bunch of,
can we,
for example,
train a machine learning system from
explanations that it can see roughly can
we train it to give explanations that
are likely to be understandable?
Maybe.
I think the.
Okay.
So an example that I'd like to do.
I'd like to do a debugging assistant
where the typical thing is program runs
program gives wrong answer.
Human says,
why did you get the wrong way?
Did it give the wrong answer?
Well,
the first piece of information to the
computer is that was the human thought.
That was the wrong answer because the
computer just did what it was told and
it didn't know that was supposed to be
the wrong answer.
So then the question is,
can you,
in fact,
you know,
in that domain,
can you actually have a reasonable
conversation in which the human is
explaining the computer what they
thought it was supposed to do.
The computer is explaining what
happened,
why did it happen?
And so on.
Same thing for math tutoring.
Um,
you know,
we have a lot of,
we've got a lot of stuff,
you know,
we're,
we're sort of very widely used for
people who want to understand the steps
in math,
you know,
can we make a thing where people tell
us?
I think it's this.
okay,
I'll tell you one,
one little factoid which I did work out.
so if you do multi arithmetic,
multi digital edition.
Okay.
So the,
the basis of this is kind of silly,
silly thing,
but,
but you know,
if you get the right answer for an
audition some.
Okay.
You don't get very much information.
The student gives the wrong answer.
The question is can you tell them where
they went wrong?
So I'd say you have afforded in addition
some and the student gives the wrong
answer.
Can you back trace and figure out what
they likely did wrong?
And the answer is you can you,
you just make this graph of all the
different things that can happen,
you know,
when did they know there are certain
things that are more common,
transposing numbers and things or you
know,
having a one on a mixed up,
those kinds of things you can with very
high probability given afforded addition
some with the wrong answer.
You can Say this is the mistake you
made,
which is sort of interesting and that's
being done in a fairly symbolic way.
Whether one can do that in a,
you know,
more machine learning kind of way for
more complicated directions.
I'm not sure,
but that's a,
that's one that works.
The.
Yeah.
I just had a followup question.
So do you think,
uh,
you know,
like in the future it is,
is it wasn't moved to simulate virtual
environment which can actually
understand how the human mind works and
then build a,
you know,
like finite state machines inside of
this watch and environment,
uh,
to,
to provide a better learning experience
and a more personalized learning
experience.
Well,
I mean,
so the question is if,
if,
if you're going to,
you know,
can you optimize if you're playing a
video game or something and that video
game is supposed to be educational,
can you optimize the experience based on
a model of you so to speak?
Yeah,
I'm sure the answer is yes.
And I'm sure the,
you know,
the question of how complicated the
model of you will be as an interesting
question.
They don't know the answer to.
I mean I've,
I've kind of wondered a similar
question.
So I,
I'm a kind of personal analytics
enthusiastic.
I collect tons of data about myself.
I mean,
I do it mostly because it's been super
easy to do and I've done it for like 30
years and I have,
you know,
every key stroke I've typed on a
computer,
like every keystroke I've typed here and
the screen of my computer every,
every 30 seconds or so of maybe 15
seconds,
I'm not sure it does.
A screenshot is a super boring movie to
watch.
But anyway,
I've been collecting all this stuff and
so a question that I've asked is,
is there enough data that a bot of me
could be made?
Other words,
do I have enough data about,
you know,
I've got,
I've written a million emails,
I have all of those.
I've received 3 million emails.
I'm over that period of time.
I've got endless,
you know,
things I've typed,
et cetera,
et cetera.
You know,
is there enough data to reconstruct you
know me?
Basically,
I think the answer is probably yes.
Not sure,
But I think the answer's probably yes.
And so the question is in an environment
where you're interacting with some video
game,
trying to learn something,
whatever else,
you know,
how long is it going to be before it can
learn enough about you to change that
environment in a way that's useful for
explaining the next thing to you?
I would guess I would guess that have
done that.
This is comparatively easy.
I might be wrong,
but,
but um,
uh,
and that the,
um,
I mean,
I think,
you know,
it's an interesting thing because no
one's dealing with,
you know,
there's a space of human personalities.
There's a space of human learning
styles,
you know,
I'm sort of always interested in the
space of all possible x,
y,
z,
and there's,
you know,
there's that question of,
well,
how do you parameterize the space of all
possible human learning styles and is
there a way that we will learn,
you know,
like,
can we do that symbolically and say
these are 10 learning styles or is it
something.
I think that's the case Where it's
better to use,
you know,
sort of soft machine learning type
methods to kind of feel out that space.
Maybe very last question.
I was just intuitively thinking when you
spoke about an ocean,
I thought of isaac newton when he said,
uh,
you know,
the famous quote,
I might not,
and I thought instead of newton on the
beach,
what a friends list.
Where there a,
what question would he ask?
What would he say?
And I'm trying to understand your,
the alien ocean and humans through maybe
franz liszt and music.
well,
so I mean,
the,
the quote from newton is,
is,
um,
a sort of an interesting quote.
I think it goes something like this if,
you know,
uh,
people are talking about how wonderful
calculus and all that kind of thing are.
And newton says,
uh,
you know,
to others,
I may seem like I've done a lot of
stuff,
but to me I seem like a child who,
who picked up a particularly elegance,
you know,
seashell on the,
on the beach.
And I've been studying this seashell for
awhile.
Even though there's this ocean of truth
out there waiting to be discovered,
that's roughly the quote.
Okay.
I find that quote interesting for the
following reason.
The,
what newton did was,
you know,
calculus and things like it.
If yoU look at the computational
universe of all possible programs,
there is a small corner.
Newton was exactly right and what he
said that his,
he picked off calculus,
which is a corner of the possible things
that can happen in the computational
universe that happened to be an elegant
seashells,
so to speak.
They happened to be a case where you can
figure out what's going on and uh,
and so on,
while there is still the sort of ocean
of,
uh,
of other sort of computational
possibilities out there.
Uh,
but,
but when it comes to,
you know,
you're asking about music.
I,
oH,
I think my computer stopped being able
to get anywhere but,
but sort of interest in the,
uh,
see if we can get to the site.
So this is a,
this is a website that we made years ago
and now my computer isn't playing on a
thing,
but let's try that.
Okay.
So these things are created by basically
just searching computational universe of
possible programs.
It's sort of interesting because
everyone has kind of a story.
Some of them look more interesting than
others.
Let's try that one
anyway.
The,
the um,
what's,
what's interesting,
what was interesting to me about this
was this is a very trivial,
you know,
what this is doing is very trivial at
some level.
It's just,
it actually happens to use cellular
automata.
You can even have it show you,
I think someplace here.
Where is it?
Somewhere there's a way of showIng your
show the evolution.
This is,
this is showing the behind the scenes
what was actually happening,
what it chose to use to generate that
musical piece.
Um,
and uh,
what I thought was interesting about
this site,
I thought,
well,
you know,
howard computers be relevant to music,
etc.
Etc.
Well,
you know,
what would happen is a human would have
an idea and then the computer would kind
of dress up that idea and then,
you know,
a bunch of years go by and I talked to
people who are composers and things and
they say,
oh yeah,
I really liked that.
Well,
from town site,
okay,
that's nice.
They say it,
it's a very good place for me to get
ideas.
So that's sort of the opposite of what I
would've expected.
Namely what's happening is,
you know,
human comes here,
listens to some ten second fragment.
And they said,
oh,
that's an interesting idea.
And then they kind of embellish it using
kind of something that is humanly
meaningful,
but it's like,
you know,
you're taking a photograph and you see
some interest in configuration and then
kind of your,
you know,
you're filling that with kind of some
human,
a sort of context.
Um,
but,
uh,
so I'm not quite sure what,
um,
uh,
what you were asking about.
I mean,
back to the newton quote,
the thing that I think has some,
uh,
another way to think about that quote is
us humans,
you know,
with our sort of historical development
of,
you know,
our intellectual history have explored
this very small corner of what's
possible in the computational universe
and everything that we care about is
contained in the small corner.
And that means that,
you know,
you could say,
well,
gee,
you know,
I want to know what w,
w,
what we end up wanting to talk about
other things that we as a society have
decided we care about and what.
There's an interesting feedback loop I
just mentioned it should end,
but,
um,
so you might say,
so here's,
here's a funny thing.
So let's take language,
for example,
language evolves.
We say we,
we make up language to describe what we
see in the world.
Okay,
fine,
that's a fine idea.
Imagine the paleolithic times,
people will make up language.
They probably didn't have a word for
table because they didn't have any
tables.
They probably had a word for rock.
But then we ended up as a result of the
particular,
you know,
development that our civilization has
gone through.
We build tables and there was sort of a
synergy between coming up with a word
for table and deciding tables were a
thing and we should build a bunch of
them.
And so there's this sort of complicated
interplay between the things that we
learn,
how to describe and how to think about
the things that we build and put an our
environment and then the things that we
end up wanting to talk about because
there are things that we have
experienced in our environment.
And so that's the,
you know,
I think as we look at sort of the
progress of civilization,
there's,
you know,
there's various layers of.
First we,
you know,
we invented a thing that we can then
think about and talk about.
Then we build an environment based on
that.
Then that allows us to do more stuff and
we build on top of that.
And that's why,
for example,
when we talk about computational
thinking and teaching it to kids and so
on,
that's one reason that's kind of
important because we're building a layer
of things that people are then familiar
with that's different from what we've
had so far.
And they give people a way to talk about
things.
I'll give you one example that I'm
seated.
I have that still up the
uh,
okay.
One,
one.
One example here,
uh,
from this blog post of mine.
Actually.
So
the.
Alright,
is it?
Okay.
So that,
that thIng,
there is a nested pattern,
you know,
it's a,
it's a penske,
um,
that,
that
tile pattern was created in 12,
10,
80.
okay.
that's the first example I know of a
fractal pattern.
Okay.
Well,
the art historians wrote about these
patterns.
There are a bunch of his particular
style or pattern they wrote about these
for years.
They never diScussed that nest pattern.
These patterns also have,
you know,
pictures of lions and elephants and
things like that.
And then they wrote about those kinds of
things,
but they never mentioned the nested
pattern until basically about 25 years
ago when fractals and so on became a
thing.
And then it's,
oh,
I can now talk about that.
It's a nested patterns,
fractal.
And then,
you know,
before that time,
the art historians were blind to that
particular part of this pattern.
It was just like,
I don't know what that is,
that there's no,
you know,
I don't have a word to describe it.
I'M not going to,
I'm not going to talk about it.
So that's a,
you know,
it's part of this feedback loop of,
of things that we learn to describe.
Then we build in terms of those things.
Then we built another layer.
I think one of the things,
I mean you talk about,
you know,
just in the sort of thing,
one thing I'm really interested in is
the evolution of purposes.
So if you look back in human history,
there's a,
you know,
what was thought to be worth doing a
thousand years ago is different from
what's thought to be worth doing today.
And part of that is,
is,
um,
uh,
you know,
good examples of things like walking on
a treadmill or buying goods and virtual
worlds.
Both of theSe are hard to explain to
somebody from a thousand years ago
because each one ends up being a whole
sort of societal story about we're doing
this because we do that because we do
that.
And so the question is how will these
purposes evolve in the future?
And I think one of the things that I
view as a sort of sobering thought is
that that term,
actually one thing I found rather
disappointing and then I became less
pessimistic about it is if you think
about the future of the human condition
and you know,
we'd been successful in making ai
systems and we can read out brains and
we can upload consciousnesses and things
like that.
And we've actually got this box with
trillions of souls in it.
And the question is,
what are these souls doing?
And to us today,
it looks like they're playing video
games.
So the rest of eternity.
And that seems like a kind of a bad
outcome.
It's like we've gone through all of this
long history and what do we end up with?
We end up with a trillion souls in a box
playing video games and I thought this
is a very depressing outcome,
so to speak.
And then I realized that that actually,
if you look at the sort of arc of human
history people,
are there any given time in history,
people have been.
uh,
my main conclusion is that any time in
history,
the things people do seem meaningful and
purposeful to them at that time in
history and history moves on and you
know,
like a thousand years ago,
there were a lot of purposes that people
had that you know what to do with weird
superstitions and things like that that
we say,
why the heck were you doing that?
That just doesn't make any sense.
Right?
But to them at that time,
it made all the sense in the world.
And I think that,
you know,
the thing that makes me sort of less
depressed about the future,
so to speak,
is that at any given time in history,
you know,
you can still have meaningful purposes.
Even thOugh they may not look meaningful
from a different point in history and
that sort of a whole theory,
you can kind of build up based on kind
of the trajectories that you've followed
through the space of purposes and sort
of interesting.
If you can jump,
like you say,
let's get cryonically frozen for 300
years and then be back again.
The the interest in cases.
Then you knoW all the purposes that you
sort of,
you know,
that you find yourself in ones that have
any continuity with what we know today.
I should stop with that.
That's a beautiful way to end it.
Yeah.