Today we're going to try something
different.
We're going to try a conversation.
Uh,
have a Lisa Feldman Barrett with us.
She is a university distinguished
professor of psychology at Northeastern
University,
director of the Interdisciplinary
Affective Science Laboratory,
author of the new amazing book,
how emotions are made,
the secret life of the brain.
She studies emotion,
human emotion from social,
psychological,
cognitive science and neuroscience
perspectives.
And so I think our conversation may help
us gain intuition about how we instill
emotional life into future artificial
intelligence systems as Josh Tannenbaum
give you a shout out on Tuesday and said
that,
uh,
if you want to understand how to create
artificial general intelligence systems
from an engineering perspectives,
which is study the human brain.
So with that,
let's have some fun.
Let me start with a curve ball to a
conjure up an image of emotion.
Have you ever cried while watching a
movie that you remember?
And what movie was it?
I've cried during lots of.
Okay.
Um,
let me think.
The last time I cried.
Actually,
here's an interesting thing.
When I'm speaking about when I'm giving
an academic talk,
I sometimes we'll talk about a study
that we did where we had people watch
films and we have them watch the most
evocative clips of films and there's
several clips that are really powerful
and a couple of them,
every time I talk about them,
I'm going to try not to cry.
Now.
Every time I talk about them,
I just scribing for the audience what
subjects are seeing.
One of the clips is from a movie called
Sophie's choice.
Does anyone know this film?
Raise your hand if you know this film.
So we show this is a film about a woman
who is forced in a concentration camp to
choose which of her children will die in
the gas chambers.
And so I'm already,
you know,
like if you were,
if I had um,
heart rate monitor and respiration
monitor,
you would see,
um,
like it's a really powerful scene.
Um,
Meryl Streep is Sophie and it's very,
very evocative.
We have,
we also show there's a scene from a,
a film with Susan Surandon who is dying
of breast cancer and she has to tell her
12 year old daughter that she's dying.
So there's another scene also that,
um,
that I find very compelling and you use
these scenes to listen emotion as part
of experiments we do.
Yeah.
And in fact,
I was just giving a presentation to the
Judicial Court of Massachusetts on
implicit bias and to start the year,
they wanted to understand the
neuroscience of implicit bias and
whether or not they should be crafting
jury instructions for juries to be aware
of implicit bias.
And to open the discussion.
I showed them a clip from a film that
was filmed a,
you know,
almost 20 years ago,
actually called a time to kill the scene
where Matthew mcconaughey is this kind
of his,
his closing statements in a case where
he,
um,
is defending an African American man who
murdered two European American men who
raped his 12 year old daughter.
And so the scene is,
he's this completely pathetic lawyer
until the end when he masters this
fantastic defense.
Basically of this man on trial for,
you know,
basically avenging his daughter's death
and that one I hadn't seen that for 20
years that film and it brought me to
tears.
Actually.
It's just a really powerful,
powerful scene and it's just really
punches you in the stomach.
You just can't help but just experienced
that weight of racism in that,
in that room and the brilliance of the
closing argument to sort of puncture
through it basically.
Okay,
so experience.
So one of the things you talk a lot and
you're working in your book is the
difference in the experience of emotion
and the expression of emotion.
So what are,
what's our biggest misconception?
Bottom motion of folks that haven't
considered,
have,
have only considered a emotions that are
surface level.
I would say one common misconception is
that you can look at someone's face and
read their emotion the way you read
words on a page that everyone around the
world,
when they're feeling angry,
they scowl.
When they're feeling happy,
they smile when they're feeling sad,
that they frown.
The way that I'm saying it sounds
preposterous and it is preposterous,
but unfortunately that is actually what
people,
a lot of people believe,
and tech companies around the world
spend tremendous amounts of money,
uh,
and you know,
in the investment of some of the most
creative people on this planet trying to
build emotion detection systems,
uh,
when really what they're building are
excellent systems for reading facial
movements which have no intrinsic
emotional meeting.
I mean,
sometimes facial movements communicate
emotion,
but many times they don't.
So people scowl for many reasons.
They scowl when they're concentrating,
they scowl.
Sometimes when they're sad,
they even can scowl when they're happy.
People smile when they're angry,
they smile when they're sad.
They don't just smile when they're
happy,
they sometimes smile to indicate a,
to send,
you know,
a social message that has nothing to do
with emotion.
And so the idea that there's one
universal facial expression,
for example,
for each emotion is just,
okay,
there's no strong scientific evidence
for that claim.
So how is emotion created them?
Because we nevertheless feel like we're
observing emotional when we're
communicating with others.
So how does emotion,
the creation of emotion change in the
presence of others?
The,
does the audience change the display of
emotion?
Is that essentially in the message?
Well,
emotions are not displayed,
I would say.
Right.
So basically you and I are having a
conversation right now and part of what
you know my brain is doing is it's
guessing,
make making educated guesses about what
your facial movements mean.
So right now you have a slight smile on
your face.
Not exactly a smirk,
but um,
and so,
you know,
um,
uh,
so by the way,
so we're not allowed to show any
emotion.
You know,
I have a friend of mine who was Russian
who told me,
and she would,
when she moved to this country,
actually,
I've had several friends tell me this,
that their cheeks hurt for a year for
how much smiling they had to do.
I've also found from the Netherlands who
moved here who told me the same thing.
Her face ached for how much smiling she
did an in Bulgaria.
They haven't apparently like a a name
for,
you know,
the pervasive,
a American smile,
kind of like a,
not flattering name for how much
American smile,
but basically when you look at someone's
face,
you're making a guess about how they
feel and although you yourself are
focused on their face to you,
it feels as if that's where all the
information is.
Your brain is actually taking in the
entire sensory ray,
so it's taking in also,
you know,
the sound of the person's voice and the
person's body posture and the dynamic of
temporal changes in all of those signals
to make sense of things.
It's not,
you're not really.
The face is not a lighthouse.
It's not a beacon that just displays
somebody internal state in an obligatory
way.
Nevertheless,
there's some signal there of course.
And so what are,
what would you say as far as I
understand there's no good answer yet
from sciences.
What are the basic building blocks of
emotion?
I wouldn't say that there's no good
answer from science.
I would say scientists disagree.
I think it's very clear what the
building blocks are.
Um,
but,
you know,
in one way or another,
if you look back all the way to ancient
Greece,
you can,
that there are two kinds of views of
emotion that had been battling it out
for millennia.
One is the idea that you have,
um,
all,
I will give you the modern versions of
these views,
but they really do have a very long
history.
One is the idea that you are born with
circuits in your brain that are pre
prewired for emotion so that everybody
around the world is born with an anger
circuit,
a fear circuit,
sadness circuit,
a happiness circuit,
some other circuits to you have them.
We all have them.
All neurotypical brains have them and
actually other animals have them too.
And the idea is that when you know one
of these circuses triggered,
you have an emotional response,
which is obligatory.
So you have a very stereotypic change in
your body.
Your breathing changes in a stereotypic
way.
You're,
you know,
heart rate changes,
your,
the chemicals in your body change in a
particular way.
You make a particular facial expression
and you are,
I'm a have a propensity to make a
particular action like you,
you know,
attack and anger and you run in fear are
you freezing here.
Um,
and then there's another view which
says,
well,
there are some basic kind of ingredients
or building blocks that the human mind
or the human brain.
Now,
um,
people talk about the brain.
Now there are some basic ingredients
that your brain uses a and it uses them
to make every kind of mental event that
you experienced.
And every action that you take,
the recipes are what are unique.
The ingredients are common,
right?
Just like you can take flour and water
and salt and you can make a whole bunch
of different recipes with them,
some of which aren't even food like
glue.
I'm in a similar way.
The idea is that your brain has some
kind of all purpose capacities and it
can,
it puts these ingredients together and
it makes a motion as you need them on
the spot and you don't have one anger.
You have a whole repertoire of anger.
You don't have one sadness.
You have a whole repertoire of sadness
and if you grow up in a culture that has
no concept for sadness,
you don't experience sadness and you
don't perceive sadness because your
brain becomes wired to make whatever
mental events that are exist in your
particular culture.
So for artificial intelligence systems,
the idea of emotional intelligence is
really difficult and it seems like it's
an important thing to try to instill.
So for human beings,
where do you see the importance on the
priority list of what makes us human?
Where does emotion sit?
I think that's the wrong question to ask
because I'm.
No,
I mean I think.
I think people constantly ask that
question,
but I don't think it's the right
question to ask because you know,
some cultures in our,
on our planet don't have a concept for
emotion and people don't.
While they experience what I'm going to
refer to as a in scientific terms we
call an effect,
which is our simple feelings of feeling
pleasant or unpleasant or feeling worked
up or calm or comfortable or disc or you
know,
having discomfort.
These are feelings that come directly
from the internal state of the physical
systems in your body.
Not everybody makes emotions out of
those feelings,
and in fact,
we often don't make emotions out of
those foods.
So let's feelings.
The way to think about it is that your
brain comes wired to regulate your body.
Actually sort of take that back you.
Your brain becomes wired when you're
born,
your brain becomes wired with the
potential to regulate your body.
Infants actually don't regulate their
own nervous systems very well.
They can't put themselves to sleep.
They can't calm themselves down.
They can't regulate their own
temperature.
That's what they need caregivers for.
And as caregivers regulate the nervous
systems of their infants that wires the
infant's brain,
right?
So infant little infant brains aren't
born,
uh,
like little miniature adult brains.
They're born at waiting for a set of
wiring instructions from the world and
they wire themselves to the physical and
social realities that they grow in.
And as they learn to do this,
they,
um,
experience,
uh,
these simple feelings that you know,
of,
feeling pleasant or unpleasant,
feeling worked up or feeling calm.
These are kind of like barometer
readings in a way.
They're very simple and they lack a lot
of detail because of how we're wired,
um,
and we have to make sense of them.
And the way the culture makes sense of
them is not always about emotion.
So I would say,
you know,
in our culture,
when we lose something significant,
like a loved one,
we feel sad into he into Haitian people
feel sick.
They have an illness.
It's not sadness.
A hundred or 200 years ago there was an
emotion called nostalgia,
which killed people was thought to kill
people after,
you know,
for example,
after serving in world war one,
we would now call that depression.
It's not just a matter of changing the
label of something and it's actually the
formation of the experience is very
different.
So if you want to build an intelligent
agent,
I don't think emotion is what you need
to endow it with.
You need to endow it with these basic
ingredients that it can use to make
whatever experiences or guide whatever
actions,
make whatever states or guide whatever
actions are relevant to the situations
that it's in.
That will be different if it's an
American or a British or a western
urbanized environment than say if you
were to go to Tanzania and steady,
you know,
the Hadza who were hunting and gathering
since that culture,
since the pleistocene words or human
interpretable labels on these basic
ingredients that we can understand.
I think so.
I mean,
I think the first thing to understand is
that when we think about building an
intelligent agent,
we think about endowing the agent with
cognition or with emotion or the ability
to,
you know,
to perceive things in the world because
as humans that those are.
These are the things that are really
important to us,
especially in our culture,
thinking,
feeling,
seeing,
and other cultures.
You know,
they have different ways of parsing
things,
but the truth is that your brain did not
evolve so that you could think and feel
and see.
It evolved.
Brains evolved to control bodies.
Brains evolved so that they could
control the various systems of the body
as creatures move around in order to
gain resources like food and water and a
brain has to figure out how much
resources to expand on getting
additional resources.
Now that may sound really trivial,
but it turns out it's actually really
hard and scientists actually haven't
really figured out completely how brains
do this.
I mean,
what's really interesting to me is that
if you look,
for example,
at computer vision,
try to figure out,
you know,
how an,
how to make,
um,
an agent.
See that's a pretty much solved problem.
Not Completely.
It's a pretty much solved problem in the
basics are solved your perception
problem.
Yeah,
the pure perception problem.
However,
if you want to create an agent that just
reaches out smoothly,
grabs a glass,
and brings it into the body to drink
that problem is not solved something as
simple as movement,
which we think of as this really basic
thing like,
oh,
it's so trivial.
All animals can do it is actually the
harder one of the hardest problems to
solve.
And brains basically.
I mean,
there's a whole story here about
evolution,
which has nothing to do with having a
lizard brain which is wrapped in a,
you know,
a cognitive brain or anything like that.
Um,
uh,
that's a reference to the triune brain,
which a lot of people believe it's a way
of thinking about brain evolution
instead.
Um,
what we,
what seems to be the case is that as
bodies got larger,
um,
and there were more systems because the
niche of the animal,
the environment,
the animal got bigger and bigger and
bigger.
Brains also had to get bigger,
but they had to get bigger to a point
with some constraints.
Like they have to be.
You have to keep,
um,
metabolic cost down.
It's really important.
If you don't,
you know,
creatures get sick and die.
Um,
we can talk about what that means in
terms of depression or metabolic
illnesses or what have you.
But so what are the basic ingredients?
Well,
one of the basic ingredients is that
your brain is controlling your body all
the time.
Whether you feel it or not,
whether you're thinking about it or not,
whether you're asleep or awake,
certain parts of your brain are always
very active all the time,
even when you're sleeping or else you'd
be dead,
and those parts of the brain that are
controlling your heart and your lungs
and your immune system and all of those
regions that are controlling the systems
of your body are also helping your brain
to represent the sensory consequences of
those changes in your body,
which you don't feel directly.
You don't feel your heart beating most
of the time.
You don't feel your lungs expanding most
of the time and there's a really good
reason why we are all wired not to feel
those things,
and that is you'd never pay attention to
anything outside in the world ever
again.
If you could feel every little movement
that was going on inside your body,
so your brain represents those as a
summary.
These kinds of simple summary feelings.
You feel good,
you feel bad,
you feel great.
You feel like shit.
You feel really jittery.
You feel really calm,
and these feelings are not emotions.
They sometimes keep your brain,
can make them into emotions,
but they're with you every waking moment
of your life.
There are properties of consciousness in
the way that lightness and darkness is a
property of vision,
and sometimes we make them into emotions
when they're,
when we have a big change in our heart
rate or a big change in our,
um,
in our breathing rate or a big change in
our temperature or a big surge of
glucose,
um,
we,
my brain might make a emotion out of
those changes,
those very strong changes which you will
feel as really feeling unpleasant or
really feeling pleasant,
but your brain might also make hunger or
your brain might make an instance of,
um,
uh,
a physical sensation like nausea or your
brain might even make a perception of
the world.
Like,
that's a nice guy.
That guy's an asshole.
This is a really delicious drink.
That's a beautiful painting.
Those are also moments where these
simple feelings,
which we call an effect are very strong.
So aspect is a basic ingredient.
There are others that I could talk about
too.
It's not the only one,
but one of the things I think that,
um,
that sometimes people who are to build
ai systems don't realize is that the
brain,
its fundamental job is to keep your body
alive and well.
And if you don't have some kind of body
to regulate with effective feelings that
come from that regulation
or something like that,
it's you're kind of going to be out of
luck.
I think in rendering something that
looks more something that seems more
human,
right?
So maybe you can elaborate a like in the
book sapiens that we as human beings are
really good en masse as a,
with thousands,
millions of people together believing
something,
even if it's not true.
So,
so while scientifically sort of from a
neuroscience perspective is maybe very
true that emotions aren't real.
But I said they're not there.
There isn't.
So it interesting are you finished?
So what I'm trying to say is also from a
perspective is they become these trivial
ideas of mapping a smile to being happy
and these kinds of trivial ideas become
real to us through Hollywood,
through cultural spreading that
information.
And we start to believe this and
therefore it becomes real innocent in,
in,
in as much as anything is real about our
called our perception together.
So it's really important scientifically
the ideas that you're presenting.
But does that mean there's just because
our brain doesn't feel those explicit
emotions,
does that mean they're not real?
I didn't say we don't feel explicit
emotions.
So I want to be really clear about this
because it's an interesting this,
you know,
this,
um,
this
in France,
it's an interesting inference that
people often make.
And so,
but it's,
it's a mistake and it's a mistake that
betrays a certain kind of thinking that
we do in this culture.
And it's,
it's the mistake of the following sort.
So when I say there is no facial
expression that is diagnostic of a
single emotion,
that doesn't mean that people don't
express emotion.
They certainly do express emotion.
They just don't,
you know,
when,
when they're in a state of anger,
in a state of sadness or an estate of
all their faces don't do one thing.
When I say,
well,
your body can do many things when you're
angry or when you're sad or,
but let's take anger.
Your heart rate can go up,
it can go down,
it can stay the same.
Your breathing rate can go up,
it can go down,
it can stay the same.
The same pattern that you see in anger
you sometimes see in sadness and you
sometimes see in fear.
You sometimes even see it in enthusiasm
and in.
All right,
so does that mean that emotions aren't
real?
No.
Emotions are real,
but,
but sometimes things are real because
the physical meaning of the signal is
endowed in the signal.
Okay?
So when your retina communicates to your
brain that you have,
that you are faced with a wavelength of
that,
you know,
is 600,
600 nanometers.
The signal is endowed in your brain.
That's like in the signal.
It's not like interpreted on interpret
that it's 600 nanometers.
It is 600 nanometers.
The information's in the signal,
but when you see read,
that information is not in the signal.
Your brain has added information that
isn't in the signal itself.
In a sense,
your brain has imposed meaning on a
signal that the signal doesn't have on
its own.
The let me back up and give a different
example to make it a little easier and
then will reapproach this.
There's is a,
there are some things that we impose.
In fact,
this is true almost all civilization,
right?
That we,
there are some things that are real by
virtue of the fact that we agree that
they exist.
Little pieces of paper serve as money or
now,
you know,
bit coin or little pieces of plastic or
gold or diamonds,
or in the past barley,
salt shells,
rocks serve as currency,
have value only because a group of
people agree that they have value.
So we impose meaning on objects.
And once we all agree that that object
actually has value,
we can trade it for material goods.
The minute that some of us disagree,
that,
uh,
we,
we withdraw our consent,
right?
The things lose their value.
That's what happened in the mortgage
crisis.
That's what happened in the tulip.
Crisis in the,
in the Netherlands.
Uh,
in the 17th century or 16th century
Renner was money.
Currency exists because we impose
meaning on objects in the world,
physical objects in the world that
themselves don't have that meeting on
their own and they are very real money
is very real to people.
I can stick somebody's head in a brain
scanner and show you that they
experienced value in a very real way,
but that,
that reality is constructed by,
um,
the fact that they have learned the
value in a particular culture.
Well,
that's also what we do with emotion.
We impose meaning on certain physical
signals that they don't have by
on their own and,
but we have collective intentionality.
We all agree that scowling is sometimes
anger and so it becomes anger in a very
real way.
Just like little pieces of paper become
money.
So it sounds like you kind of think
about the expression of emotions,
that kind of language as an extension of
a language that we'll learn in the same
way that we've collectively agree on a
language and the lexicon and a how we
use that language.
Sure.
You could think of it that way.
I mean,
everything,
everything in our culture is almost
everything in our culture is a function
of social reality in this way,
right?
Um,
we are citizens of a country because we
all agree that the country exists more
or less.
And I'm.
Wow,
you guys barely even laughed at that.
Okay.
Um,
what's a revolution a revolution is when
some people in the country withdraw
their consent.
They no longer agree,
right?
A president has powers in a country
because we all agree that a president
has powers.
President only has powers by virtue the
fact that we all agree that he or she
has powers.
If we stop agreeing,
the president doesn't have those powers
anymore.
It's very real.
People's lives depend on outcomes of
real people depend on these social
realities that we build and nurture and
we wire these social realities into the
brains of our children as we socialize
them.
And when people move from one culture to
another,
they have to learn the new,
a social reality that they are faced
with.
And if they don't,
they get very sick physically.
Because our ability to agree on what
something means actually is important
for regulating our nervous systems.
So can you speak to that a little bit?
I mean,
for machine learning methods,
for systems that learn to behave based
on a certain reward,
it's important to Kinda have some ground
truth and learn.
So how do it sounds like the expression
of emotion is learned.
Can you talk about how we learn to fit
into our culture by expressing emotion
with our phase body,
given the context,
given the rich,
uh,
what's that process look like?
When does it happen?
How much?
Yeah,
I wrote a 400 page book,
so I'll try to do it in like a couple
sentences.
Yeah.
Um,
uh,
so,
so how does it,
how does an infant learn anything?
So an infant's born
and it can't really do anything for
itself.
It can't regulate its own nervous
system.
It can't keep its body systems balanced.
This is a term scientific term for this
is allo stasis.
Allostasis is your brain's ability to
predict what your body's going to need
before it needs it and tries to meet
those needs before they arise.
So an example would be if you're going
to stand up,
if your brain's gonna stand you up,
it has to raise your blood pressure
before it stands you up.
If it doesn't,
you'll fall.
That's costly.
From metabolic standpoint,
it's costly,
you'll hurt yourself.
So an infant's brain can't do this very
well.
An infant doesn't know when to go to
sleep and when to wake up and infant
doesn't,
can't feed itself,
can't regulate its own temperature,
someone else has to do it.
And when someone does it,
the infant is learning,
it's taking insights and sounds and
smells and the physical sensations from
the body which are comfortable and
pleasant.
When the infant allo stasis is
maintained.
So right from the Gecko,
an infant is learning statistical
learning.
Um,
you know,
the capturing events,
including their consequence for the
infant's body.
Some people think babies are born,
you know,
attached already to their caregivers,
but they're not actually.
Infants don't even know what a caregiver
is.
It's just that the caregiver is,
they're constantly meeting that infant's
needs.
That's how infant start to learn.
Now,
if there are statistical regularities,
like for example,
an infant is not born with the ability
to recognize a face as a face,
but it learns that in like the first
couple of days of life.
Why?
Because human faces have some
statistical regularities to them,
right?
Two eyes,
a nose and a mouth kind of in the same
place most of the time.
So it learns really quickly.
But here's the interesting thing,
around three months of age,
infants start to learn what we call
abstract categories.
They start to learn that some things
which don't look the same or sound the
same or smell the same,
actually have the same function.
And how do they learn this?
They learn it with words.
So if you do an experiment with a three
month old,
three months old,
okay?
And you say that baby very,
very intentionally.
Look Sweetie,
this is a bug and you put the dog down
and it makes a noise,
like a beep.
And then you say,
I'm like,
I don't have props.
And then you have my wallet.
Yeah.
Okay.
And then you say,
give me your wallet.
Yeah,
And then you say,
look sweetie,
this is a watch dog,
and you put the walk down and it makes a
beep.
If you say,
look sweetie,
this is a watchdog that infant expects
that object to beep.
Why is that important?
Because in the real experiments,
this might be yellow and squishy and I'm
tall and this might be red and pointy
and you know,
hard.
And this might be,
you know,
so lots of different perceptual
features.
But,
um,
but the infant knows a learns that the
word is inviting the infant to
understand that the function of those
very different physical signals are
actually the same.
Similarly,
you can take,
you know,
six objects that are exactly identical
in their physical features,
how they sound,
how they smell,
what they feel like,
um,
what they look like.
And you can name three of them with one
word and three of them with the other
word.
And the infant will understand that,
um,
these are actually different objects
that happens a little after,
you know,
not,
not as early as three months.
But the point is that when we talk all
the time,
we use words all the time.
What do we do with infants?
We're constantly pointing things out and
labeling them.
This is a dog,
this is a cat.
You're angry.
This person sad.
Oh,
Mommy's really happy today.
you know,
mommy loves you.
Oh,
daddy's really excited about this.
And so on and so forth.
And infants learn really,
really quickly.
Words are considered to be kind of
invitations to form abstract concepts.
That is the basis of almost all of the,
um,
uh,
you know,
mental categories that we,
uh,
that,
that we,
mental events that we experienced were
basically teaching children to form
these abstract categories,
not,
and that's the basis of money and it's
the basis of,
um,
roles that we have with each other and
what we expect from each other.
It's the basis of a lot of the sort of
functional categories that we use in
everyday life.
We impose meaning on sensory,
on sensory arrays that those sensory
raised in and of themselves don't
necessarily have.
They only have that meaning because you
and I both learned that that package of
sensory rate means something,
so when I make that you can anticipate
what will happen next just because we've
learned those are wired into our brains,
you know,
in our culture and when we go to a
different culture,
we have to learn sometimes different
packages,
different mappings.
So you're saying that there's a few
sources of sensory data
and a few building blocks inside us,
the feelings of some kind that we
learned to then from an early they were
combined with those,
or
part of what your brain is doing is it's
trying to make sense of the sensory
array around it.
So from your brain's person.
So from your brain's perspective,
just think about it from your brain's
perspective,
your brain's perspective.
It spends it's entire life trapped in a
dark,
silent box and it has to make sense of
what's going on around in the world.
So that knows what to do to keep itself
alive,
right and well,
but it has to.
It has to know what to do based on,
it has to know what,
what's happening on around it,
only from the effects that it receives
through the sensory systems of the body.
So a flash of light.
What's a flash of light?
It could be anything.
Um,
what,
what's a like a,
like a siren.
The siren could be,
you know,
a firetruck or it could be um,
somebody's car alarm went off or it
could be a doorbell or it could be
right.
Any particular sensory cue could have
multiple causes.
So your brain's trapped basically in
your skull.
And all it gets are the effects,
the sensory effects of stuff that
happens in the world,
but it has to figure out what those
things are so that it knows what to do.
So how does it do that?
Well,
it has something else that it can draw
on.
It has your past experiences.
Your brain basically is,
it doesn't store experiences from the
past.
It can reconstitute them in its wiring.
And that's what it uses to guess at what
those sensory cues mean of those sensory
changes meet.
So in one situation,
a siren means one thing,
in another situation,
it means another,
a flash of light means one thing in one
situation and a different thing and
another.
So your brain is using past experience
to make guesses about what these sensory
changes mean so that it knows what to do
and it,
it has the same relationship to the
sensory changes in your body.
What's an ache in your stomach?
Well,
it could be hunger,
it could be anger,
it could be discussed,
it could be longing,
it can be nausea.
It's not that there's one,
um,
ache in your stomach for nausea and
another ache in your stomach for hunger.
There are many aches and your stomach,
benny different feelings of achiness for
nausea and many different feelings of
achiness for hunger.
And sometimes they overlap.
So your brain has to make the same kinds
of guesses about what's going on in your
body as it does about what the sensory
events meet in the world.
And that's really what it's doing.
It's guessing and making sense of the
sensory ray so that it knows what to do
next.
And when it guesses wrong,
it takes in that the,
you know,
the,
the sort of,
um,
the information that it didn't predict
well,
um,
which,
you know,
in psychology we have a really fancy
name for that.
We call it learning your brain takes in
the information that it didn't predict,
um,
so that it can predict better than the
next time to make sense of things the
next time.
So you kind of answered this a little
bit.
I'd like to elaborate on it.
If you were to build a robot that
performs,
maybe passes the turing test or performs
at the low bar level of instead of
myself here today,
it will be a robot talking to you.
It would be convincing as a human,
how would you,
what kind of,
how would you build that system in a
sense?
I'm in paralleling the infants.
What essential aspect of the infant
experience do you think is important?
Well,
I mean,
you know,
I don't,
I'm not a computer scientist so,
uh,
but,
so the way that I would say it is it
needs to have a body.
These have something like physical
systems or an analogy to physical
systems.
It has to do something analogous to
Alice.
Dcis.
So
what side to elaborate.
So what would be the goal for the
system?
You kind of mentioned previously that
the goal will be to,
for the brain to just stabilize itself.
No,
it's not that the brain is stabilized
now you have.
So people talk about reward.
What does reward?
Machine learning is pretty easy.
It's something that it's mathematical.
So it's a,
there's no philosophy to it.
Oh yeah.
There's philosophy that everything,
right?
Whether you admit it or not as a
different story.
Yeah.
So,
uh,
you wanted to play a game of chess play
given go,
you want to pick up a water bottle is.
But what is reward existence?
I
don't mean it's actually not reward.
Don't meet as effort,
don't meet as necessary for effort.
It's not necessarily for word.
I mean it's commonly if you read the
most,
those uptodate literature,
that is what you'll see that it's
actually people can,
animals can find things rewarding,
um,
can be without,
without domain actually.
But they,
uh,
they,
they need to open me to move,
they need job mean to encode that to,
to learn information.
So it's really for an effort that is
required to,
um,
work towards getting a reward,
I would say.
And um,
uh,
when the,
when a brain and animal brand a human,
you know,
any kind of animal brain,
Ms Dot predicts what the reward will be.
That's where see a real surge of
dopamine because the animal has to
adjust its action.
But the reward is basically I'm bringing
the body back into Alice Asis.
It feels good when that happens and
people will,
an animals will work tremendously hard
to have that happen.
So,
you know,
what is motivation?
Motivation is,
is expanding resources to get a reward.
So basically if,
if you don't have something like
physical systems that have to be kept in
balance,
water mean for humans or for actually
any living creature on this planet,
even single cell organisms.
Actually there's an analogy to what
we're talking about here.
Two,
two brains.
But you know,
Salt,
water,
glucose,
all these systems have to be kept in
balance and they have to be kept in
balance in a very,
very efficient way.
And that's the motivating so-called
motivating force.
Really that's what,
that's what,
that's what really brains are for.
So.
And that is the basis,
the consequence of that regulation are
the basis of effective feelings which
are for many,
many creatures on this planet.
A property of consciousness.
Okay.
So maybe if it's okay,
we'll take some questions from the
audience.
But first,
let me ask the last question is.
So on building on the robot question,
how would you build the same kind of
robot that you would be able to as a
human being fallen in love with?
Well,
you know,
people fall in love with their cars.
They fall in love with.
They fall in love with their blankets.
They fall in love with their toys,
you know,
you don't need.
It.
Doesn't need much to fall in love with
something.
The question is,
will it love you back
I w I would elaborate.
I think so,
yeah.
I think you're answering that love in
the way we're defining it loosely in
poetry and culture is a,
is a social construct and it's relative.
What I mean is sort of the idea of
monogamous,
long term love that we have deep
connection with other human beings that
we have.
You're saying you could do the same with
a car like a nice 69 Mustang.
Are you telling me that you,
you,
you're telling me that you've never,
you don't know anyone who was so in love
with their car that you.
Okay.
Now here's the thing.
So one.
So here's the thing,
we,
um,
we are social animals.
Okay.
What does that mean?
What does it mean to be a social animal?
It means that we regulate each other's
nervous.
So our brain,
my brain isn't just regulating my
nervous system right now.
It's regulating yours and actually it's
regulating other,
other peoples in the audience too.
And vice versa.
And why is that?
You know,
I mean,
other animals do it too.
We're just really good at it.
But other animals,
like there are some insects that are
social species.
They regulate each other's nervous
systems,
they do it with chemicals,
they do it with smell primarily and a
little bit with touch like earwigs will,
you know,
like they could actually,
I have this great picture of this like
totally disgusting looking little bug,
but it's like,
you know,
cuddling.
It's little baby,
ugly little ugly baby bug too.
It's adorable picture.
Um,
but you know,
what about mammals like rats?
Well,
they also use chemicals like smell,
but they also use touch and to some
extent,
um,
they also use sound.
These hearing primates add vision.
And as primates we do all,
we use all of those senses to regulate
each other.
And we also use something else words,
right?
Exactly.
And words.
The systems in our brains that allow us
to speak and allow us to understand
words are directly connected to the
parts of the brain stem that controls
the body.
I don't mean like there are a bunch of,
I mean,
I mean Monta synaptic,
[inaudible] connected.
So exactly the same systems in your
brain that are important for you to be
able to understand language and to speak
are also directly directly affecting the
systems of your body.
And that is why I can say something to
somebody I can speak to you and I can
have an impact on the nervous systems of
people all the way at the back of this
auditorium without they,
you know,
maybe they can see me.
Maybe they can't.
Maybe they can.
Hopefully they can smell me.
Maybe they can hear me.
Maybe they know that they can,
if they hear me speak words,
I can affect their nervous systems.
That's why telephone works.
That's why telephone works where you can
feel connected to someone just merely by
hearing their voice,
um,
because the sound of their voice has an
effect on your nervous system.
It can,
it can make you breathe faster,
it can make you breathe slower.
And the words also have an effect.
Because when I say a word like,
mm,
I dunno.
Um,
when I say word like car,
that's a short form.
I have a bunch of mental features in my
mind when I say the word car,
and I say that word and that invokes
those similar mental features,
maybe not identical,
but similar enough that invokes it in
your mind and your mind is made by your
brain.
So it invokes,
if I just say the word car,
there are changes in your motor system
that would be exactly the same or very
close as if you were actually in a car,
right?
So this is something that we do and the
fact we're attachment comes from an
infant to a caregiver or um,
or two lovers or two really close
friends comes from the ability that we
have to regulate each other's nervous
systems.
And that is why,
um,
when you don't have that kind of
attachment,
uh,
you die sooner on average seven years
sooner.
Loneliness kills.
I always tell my daughter,
my daughter's 19 years old and I always
tell her,
you know,
breaking up,
when you break up with someone,
it feels like it will kill you,
but it won't.
Loneliness however will kill you.
It will kill you on average seven years
earlier than it would if you didn't have
a an attachment,
and that's because our nervous systems,
as our bodies got really complex through
evolution and our brains got bigger,
they could only get so big.
There are constraints on how big any
brain can get that have to do with
birthing the infant,
but it also has to do with the metabolic
cost of a brain.
Your brain is really expensive.
My brain really expensive.
Three pounds,
20 percent of your metabolic budget.
That's a lot.
Okay,
and so what did evolution do to solve
this problem?
Well,
it couldn't make our brains any bigger,
so it just in trained other brains to
help manage our nervous systems so you
bear the burden of other peoples' alice
basis and they bear the burden of yours.
Not always at the same time,
but that's what it means to give people
support.
When someone,
when you're feeling horrible and
somebody pats you on the back or says
nice words to you or gives you a hug,
they are physically having an effect on
your body that they are helping your
body to maintain aloe status at a time
when your brain probably couldn't manage
it on its own.
And so the basis of love or attachment
is,
is basically that it's the ability to
affect each other's nervous systems in a
positive way.
Like always say to people,
you know,
the best thing for nervous system,
a human nervous system is another human.
And the worst thing for a human nervous
system is another human.
Because we're social animals.
Beautifully put.
So maybe a few questions in the
audience.
Do you mind if there's,
there's microphones on both sides.
Go ahead.
Sure.
Thanks for talking
here.
You're saying cool stuff,
not a question.
I'll take it.
So thinking about what you were saying
about reward,
and I'm wondering first of all,
is he described it as a returned to
Alice.
Asis is reward in any way linked to the.
I just like the reinforcement of
pathways or behavior.
So that the next time you get that
stimulus,
you will,
you'll respond in the same way.
And I'm also wondering about,
uh,
the link between the desire for Elo
spaces
and the need for novelty and then need
to like explore our environment.
It's a really great question.
So the second question is so much more
interesting than the first actually.
So let me say this,
that,
um,
that uh,
there is a need for novelty.
The need differs,
fried for different people.
I will say novelty.
Um,
so first of all,
uh,
the,
we can think about the need for novelty
in a really proximal way where we can
think about it in a really distilled way
like,
but basically when I say that a brain is
organized or,
or engineered for metabolic efficiency,
that doesn't mean that the goal is to,
to only ever have your prediction.
You know,
your brain is predicting all the time to
always have its predictions completely
perfect.
So you'll never learn nothing because
you'll be bored out of your mind.
Right?
And also,
you know,
humans like to expand their niche,
they like to explore.
So it's a constant balance between what
I'm biologists would call exploitation
and exploration.
Novelty is,
is,
um,
it's exciting.
There's actually an increase in
norepinephrine and increase in arousal.
It feels really exciting.
Um,
but it's also super costly.
Novelty requires usually that you learn
something new that means that's actually
really metabolically expensive thing to
do.
Um,
and it also means usually that you're
moving your body around,
which is also metabolically expensive
thing to do.
So the need for novelty is balanced by
its cost.
And um,
different nervous systems can bear ca
different amounts of cost.
So for example,
if you take two rats that are somewhat
genetically,
you know,
model like they've been genetically
bred,
one is bread.
When you stick it in a,
a novel cage,
it just sits still.
And the other one,
when you put it in all the cage,
it roams all over the place and it's
just,
you know,
it's going crazy kind of exploring
everything.
Well,
the one that sits still,
scientists might say,
oh,
that's a nervous rat or that rats
afraid.
What does that read doing?
The Ra is not moving and it's not
encoding anything because encoding,
coding something is expensive,
it's expensive.
This rat on the other hand is roaming
all over the place,
moving a lot,
learning a lot,
so it's encoding a lot,
spend,
save,
spend their time.
There are differences between people and
there are also differences between times
in your life where moments where you
feel like you have a little bit to spend
and other moments where you feel like
you really have to conserve.
When I talked to the public,
I always talk about,
I don't use the word Alice status,
it's just too boring a word,
but I sort of do is sort of explain it
like a budget.
You know,
like your brain is sort of like the
financial office of accompany.
Accompany has lots of offices.
It has to balance the expenditures and
revenues and it's got to keep everything
in balance so it might take a little
money here and move it over to that
office.
You know,
it's got to keep everything in balance.
What is always trying to do is,
is spend a little bit to make a little
bit more,
um,
well,
what happens when it spends a little bit
and it doesn't get a revenue back,
there's no reward.
What happens will it goes into the red a
little bit.
So what do you do when something goes
into the red?
Well,
you might do something risky.
You might actually spend a lot to try to
really make,
you know,
not just make back your deficit,
but actually make a lot.
That would be novelty,
that would be move and spent moving in
code.
Or you might reduce your spending.
You might say,
well,
I'm going to save a little bit now.
That would be,
I'm not going to move too much.
I'm not gonna spend too much.
I'm not going to code anything.
So I certainly don't mean to suggest to
you that,
um,
that novelty is unimportant or that
learning is unimportant.
Um,
and it's a really important question
about,
um,
what is there any intrinsic value to a
novelty over and above,
uh,
the rewards that it would give you an
analysis static sense,
but it is really clear to me that the
extent to which you,
any nervous system will embrace novelty
and even seek it pretty much depends on
the alis static state of that,
of that system.
If you don't have a lot to spend and
you're already in the red,
if you at a certain point,
if you continue to spend,
when you're in the red,
you go bankrupt.
What that means in human terms is you
get depressed.
It means that your brain makes you
fatigued so you can't move and it makes
you,
locks you in.
So you stop paying attention to anything
going on around you in the world and
your experiences.
Just what's in your head that that's
actually what depression is.
It makes me think of Alice is more of as
a range than as a zero,
not homeostasis.
It's Alice thesis.
It's arrange for sure where we.
I'll answer some other questions and
maybe I'll get back to your first
question if there's time.
So if I understand your argument
correctly,
we're going to make anything like a
general intelligence,
something approaching.
No,
like,
uh,
like a,
a human.
Um,
it needs to be an embodied system.
Well,
I,
I want to be careful about saying that
because for two reasons.
One,
because in biology there is this concept
of degeneracy,
which is a sucky word,
but it's a great concept and it means
that there's more than one way to skin a
cat.
Basically,
you want to functional outcome.
There are many ways to get to that
functional outcome.
So genes for example,
you know,
there are a lot of characteristics that
are heritable,
but we don't know the genes for them.
And the reason why is that there isn't
one set of genes,
there are like multiple sets of genes
that can give you actually the same
outcome.
So what I want to say is that you need
something akin to a body.
It doesn't actually have to be a body.
I imagine there are lots of ways that
you could implement a system.
You can implement an agent that has
multiple systems of some sort that it
has to manage,
but my point is that one thing about
that is very important that we
continually miss.
When we think about building an agent
with mental states.
We continually miss the fact that it has
a body and as humans have bodies and
that's the brain's primary task and our
most fundamental feelings come from the
physical changes in our body.
Even though we don't normally experience
it that way.
That actually is how it is.
If you just look at the wiring of the
brain,
you can just see it.
So it seems to me that if you want to
build an agent that is human,
like it has to have something like a
body doesn't have to maybe be a body and
I'm sure there are many clever ways that
you could implement something like a
body without it actually being a body,
if you know,
if you understand what I mean.
So Amazon,
Alexa couldn't be there if we just gave
it some sort of representation of mental
states or some kind of alostatic target.
Sure.
Here's the.
Let me just say one other thing.
I think it's really important.
All the brain requires is that you at
some point had a body.
You don't.
Right?
So basically being this is what phantom
limb pain is,
this is what chronic pain is,
this is what happened.
You know,
if at some point you cease to get
information from your body anymore,
your brain still can simulate,
still can reinstate the sensory patterns
that once came from the.
And that's what's required,
right?
At some point the body isn't really
needed anymore.
Yeah,
I think we're here.
Yeah.
Emotions in humans are implemented by a
bunch of hacks,
so there's a bunch of chemicals that go
into your brain,
the oxytocin,
Serotonin,
a whole bunch of biochemical things that
diffused around in the fluids in your
brain that affects your emotional state,
and that seems like a hack that we've
inherited over millions of years from
premature ancestors.
I'm an.
If you look at the machine learning
world,
we can do a bunch of similar things with
neural net,
so you can increase the activation
threshold on a large scale.
Yeah,
change the map noise going into the
system.
You can do a bunch of similar things,
but you don't have to rely on fluids
being,
um,
kind of cleaned slowly by glial cells.
Um,
things don't diffuse around in and
fluids in the system necessarily.
It seems like there's a lot more
flexibility.
So when you come to an implementation,
there's not many,
so many constraints imposed by the
evolutionary history on the whole system
and it seems like that would make it
work better.
So when people are in negative emotional
states,
um,
they can't think straight,
not true.
People can think actually quite well and
negative emotional states.
I haven't tell you.
So emotion,
they can do very nefarious things very,
very effectively.
Right?
So the general point I think is true,
even if the example is not so,
um,
emotions kind of flood your nervous
system with emotions don't flood,
you're nervous.
Some of them do.
So here's the thing in your bloodstream
stream,
let's talk about this chemicals.
There was not a single camera
well in your brain or anywhere in your
nervous system that is for emotion.
Serotonin is not for emotion domain,
it's not promotion.
Oxy chosen is not for emotion,
even opioid,
you know,
even even even opioids are not for
emotion.
So they influenced your emotions,
very involved,
influenced
every mental event that you have,
not just emotion,
so your brain,
for example,
your brain is a physical.
It's a set of physical cells that are
bathed in neurochemical systems and the
neurochemical systems that you're
referring to basically change the ease
with which information is passed back
and forth between those neurons.
That's always true.
It's true.
Regardless of whether the event is
emotion or whether it's a perception or
whether it's a thought or whether it's a
belief,
it's always true.
So for example,
serotonin.
Serotonin is a neurotransmitter that
allows your brain to delay gratification
of a reward.
It allows you to expend energy now
because you anticipate a reward at some
point in the future,
and if you have a deficit in Serotonin,
then you can't do that very well.
And it turns out for humans,
one of our great superpowers is the
ability to do mental time travel,
to remember in the past,
and also to do things now because we
know they're gonna have an effect 10 or
20 or 50 or 100 years from now.
So the,
the,
you know,
in when I said you have to have
something like a body.
I'm not saying literally you have to
have a physical corporeal body.
I'm saying you have to have.
I mean,
it's just a fact.
It's not an argument.
It's a fact that your brain,
that brains evolved for the purposes of
regulating multiple systems.
Um,
and from a cybernetic standpoint,
you know,
the best way to regulate a system is to
build an internal model of it.
That's what your brain is.
Your brain is an internal model of your
body in the world.
It's running simulations,
it's running this model.
And if you want to have an agent that is
somewhat humanlike that has feelings
like humans,
then they have to do something that they
have to have to be able to do something
similar and whether it's a actual
physical corporeal body or not,
I think is,
you know,
that's an open question.
Premises before I've got to my question.
So I started off by saying I started off
by saying emotions are implemented as a
bunch of hacks.
So would you say broadly correct?
Or would you say that they're not hacks,
they're finely tuned and adaptive and.
Well,
I wouldn't say not maladaptive,
but would you say it's a bunch of hacks?
I don't know what you mean by hacks
is kind of historical accident.
You're talking about emotions like
they're talking the premise of your
question.
I can't answer your question because I
think it's not the correct question.
I mean,
it's.
Emotions aren't like blood pressure,
you know,
they don't exist in that sense.
They are,
um,
they are the way that they are.
First of all,
not all cultures have.
Not all people in all cultures have
emotions.
Everybody has an effect.
Assuming they have a neurotypical brain
of sorts,
but um,
but they don't all have emotion.
And so to answer your question that your
answer asking me is I can't answer it
because I don't think it's the right.
I don't think so.
The right question.
The pain systems seem like things that
influence your emotions fairly directly.
So this is not the same thing,
but it's a powerful link.
Opioids though.
So opioids are important for instances
of emotion,
but they are also important for every
other category of mental event that you
brand can make a lot of other things
too.
I agree.
Um,
so I,
I,
you know,
but you will see sometimes will assign,
I'm an emotional meaning to something
like dopamine is for first hedonic
pleasantness and then it's for reward.
People like to assign single functions
to biological entities like a chemical
or a brain region,
a cluster of neurons or it's just not.
That's really.
I'm not saying every chemical does
everything but whatever.
Okay.
Whatever opioids do they do in every
waking moment of your life,
not just in moments that are emotional
for you.
Um,
I should stop now.
I'm thinking.
Yeah,
I figure it was very interesting that
you brought up the last topic of love
because I think it actually brings up a
really important thing which is,
and what you were saying about
connection,
that's the primary purpose of life is to
procreate,
right?
I mean that,
that's what our deans do.
So first of all,
right,
I'm not going to be touching that.
I'm so that.
And of course in humans it's not just
genetic,
it's mimetic.
I mean we,
we procreate our ideas as well as
physically and so a primary purpose of
our winning our,
our reactions and interactions with
other people and other things is that
goal is that we get rewarded when we
interact with other things in a way that
creates something new,
whether it's art or you know,
a book or technology or something like
that.
And if we don't put that,
if there's no inherent reason for a
robot or a computer system to want to do
that,
I mean,
how do,
how could we can even imagine putting
that into a system inherently that it
wants to,
that it just desperately wants to make
something new.
I mean,
well,
here's what I would say,
you know,
when we're,
when,
first of all,
when we talk about,
we've been focusing a lot on bodies.
I'm certainly not saying that's a
sufficient condition,
right?
I'm just saying it's a necessary one or
something like a body.
But I certainly have the motivation to
create.
And I'm imagining that you do too.
I have to tell you,
not everybody has that.
Most adolescents don't have that many
adolescents don't have it.
Okay.
That was a joke.
I have a teenage daughter just telling
you.
But the point is that,
um,
that what people,
what people find rewarding is remarkably
diverse.
But the property I think is that there
has to be a feature of reward for,
for a lot of people,
that's,
you know,
that's having an impact in some way.
I'm having an impact on another person
having an impact,
um,
you know,
on a building,
something that wasn't there before,
whatever,
you know,
in,
in innovating or I'm discovering,
but it's not true for everybody.
It's just true for a lot of people in
this room probably.
And certainly the people that we
probably spend a lot of time with,
but not,
not for everybody.
There's also the genetic part.
Sure.
I mean,
look,
but if you want to,
you know,
if you want to,
um,
if you,
you know,
we can certainly make a,
a genetic argument here.
Absolutely.
They're there.
The,
there's nothing that I've said today
that is inconsistent with the idea that,
um,
that you have,
that you have to pass your genes onto
the next generation and actually make
sure that that generation survives to
reproductive age.
It's not just enough to have offspring.
You have to make sure that the offspring
survive to reproductive age.
And there's a whole argument about,
you know,
uh,
the,
the learning of,
um,
social reality,
concepts of social reality that we've
been talking about,
like money and emotions and so on.
That makes that argument,
right,
that it's very expensive to have to
encode everything in jeans or to have to
learn everything from scratch,
every generation.
So instead what we have is a system,
a genetic system that allows us to wire
the brains of the young,
uh,
with what we know and that's what we do
basically.
Alright.
So it's the.
I'm curious about your analogy about
intentionality that you talked about
when you use the analogy between money
and the perception of read to the facts
that we,
the fact that we have emotion because
the distinguishing feature,
it seems to me is the level of
intentionality.
And as you said before,
our brain assigns meaning to things but
we don't or maybe.
And my question is whether or not you
agree with this.
I guess we don't always deliberately
assigned.
No,
this is nothing I've said is about ever
delivered.
But sometimes we do sometimes quite
often actually.
Yeah.
So when you go back to like the question
of what makes something intelligent,
a lot of previous talks have been about,
you know,
we want to pick a goal and then we
create costs to achieve that goal,
but that goal is deliberately assigned.
So when you talk about like what makes
something intelligent,
what do you think the role of
intentionality is and the spectrum there
in?
So first of all,
we talk about
intentionality.
I think you have to really be careful
that you are.
Philosophers talk about intentionality
in two ways.
They talk about intentionality to mean a
deliberate action the way you mean it,
but intentionality can also mean that
something has a reference out in the
real world outside of you.
Really.
So that a word,
a word has a,
a reference that's the,
um,
you know,
the intention of the,
of the word basically.
So I think you have to be really
careful.
I also think that you have to make a
distinction between a conscious,
deliberate,
explicitly a goal that you can
explicitly describe.
And I'm a,
I mean,
you're,
you're sort of making your,
sort of,
making the kind of question you're
asking is getting very close to the
question of freewill.
Joe would love to not have to discuss,
but um,
but basically what I'm about to say is
gonna sound very Cartesian,
unfortunately,
because that's English.
I don't know.
There's no other way to do it actually.
But what I want to say is that your
brain is always,
there's always,
um,
volition,
but it's not always consciously
experienced by you as,
as agency or will.
So you're not a,
you're not a,
a sea urchin.
You know,
your sensory neurons are not hardwired
to your motor neurons.
You have interneurons.
That means you have choice.
Do you consciously experienced yourself
as making choices all the time?
No,
you don't,
but your brain is actually making
choices all the time.
That's why people who study decision
making,
you know,
think they're studying the whole brain
because they,
they are actually.
Um,
so I think you have to be really careful
about.
There are words that we use in English
and in science that have two meanings.
They can have a meaning that is about
decision making or choice that is just
obligatory automatic and a function of
how the system works and then there's
the kind of choice that feels deliberate
and effortful and where we feel like
we're the agents we experience ourselves
as the agents.
Um,
and intentionality.
I'm usually can be assigned to the
second one,
but actually in truth,
in philosophical terms,
it can also be assigned to the first
that when you,
even,
if you're completely unaware of having
made a choice,
you're acting on something with some
degree of volition because you,
you,
it's not a reflex.
It's not like somebody hit your patellar
tendon,
a new kit.
And so it's really interesting that.
So,
you know,
I think you just have to,
you have to make that distinction and I
probably should get to the next question
we can follow.
Yeah.
Yep.
Uh,
so you've been asked a lot of esoteric
questions about ai,
but I think we might gain some insights
by wondering about Dei.
That is a dog intelligence.
So I believe I,
I sort of understand what my dog is
feeling and I,
I usually believe that,
um,
my dog,
you know,
believes the same,
um,
but not the same with,
you know,
a cat and you're not a cat person.
Sure.
Um,
and,
you know,
I'm not,
I don't know that much about monkeys,
but I've never really seen a monkey be
able to make the expressions that are,
let's say a dog can.
Um,
and I was wondering if you had any
insights about why dogs are able to do
this and why we're able to read dogs.
Is it something just simple,
like they're,
they have the right facial muscles or is
it something,
some drive that allows them to learn
this?
So I think before I wrote my book,
I would have answered this question
differently.
Um,
but now here's what I would say.
I think,
um,
you know,
many creatures on this planet have an
effect,
right?
And we can debate about whether,
you know,
I just came across a paper the other day
about whether fly,
you know,
just her Sophala have an have an effect
and you know,
it's,
it's actually a really interesting
question.
They certainly,
they have something like opioids and
they,
you know,
so it's essentially a question but dogs
dogs are really interesting because they
do seem to have some capacities that
only that you only see in,
in great apes and they may have
capacities that great apes even other
than us don't have.
And I mean,
so they certainly have some capacities
we don't have either,
but.
But here's my point.
We actually bred them.
We bred these animals,
we selected them basically not natural
selection.
It's,
it's artificial selection.
And we selected them for a couple of
things,
right?
If you look at the experiments on
breeding,
taking a Fox,
you know,
taking foxes and breeding them into what
looked like a little dog like animals.
It's interesting what they can do and
one of the things they can do is they
can move their facial muscles and in,
in,
in a lot of ways that they have a lot
more control over their facial muscles
then chimpanzees and uh,
do um,
and,
and other apes,
um,
and they also do,
they do joint attention really well with
gays.
So this is something that really no
other animal can do,
I think other than a dog,
other end humans.
And that is,
they can,
they,
they meet your gaze and they use gaze
for reference so you know,
they'll look at something and they'll
look back at you and you know,
that's actually partly,
that's how we communicate with each
other.
Chimpanzees lose that ability after
about 10 or 11 months,
a year of age,
but,
but dogs continually do it.
And actually joint attention,
shared gaze is how we communicate with
our infants will also.
That's actually partly how we teach
infants about what's important in the
world is with gays.
So I think that dogs may actually have
some capacities probably because we bred
them to have those,
but we selected the animals that,
uh,
you know,
and bred them to,
to have those capacities.
That's very interesting.
Thank you.
Awesome.
What would that.
Let's get at least a big hand.
Thank you so much.