The following is a conversation with
Vladimir of apnic.
He's the inventor of the support vector
machines,
support vector clustering,
vc theory and many foundational ideas
and statistical learning is born in the
Soviet Union and worked at the Institute
of Control Sciences and Moscow.
Then in the United States.
He worked at a and t and e Silabs
facebook research and now as a professor
at Columbia University.
His work has been cited over 170,000
times.
He has some very interesting ideas about
artificial intelligence and the nature
of learning,
especially on limits of our current
approaches and the open problems in the
field.
This conversation is part of mit course
on artificial general intelligence and
artificial intelligence podcasts.
If you enjoy it,
please subscribe on Youtube or rated on
itunes or your podcast provider of
choice,
or simply connect with me on twitter or
other social networks at legs.
Friedman,
spelled F,
R I,
D,
and now.
Here's my conversation with Latimer vap.
Nick Einstein famously said that God
doesn't play dice.
You're.
You have studied the world through the
eyes of statistics,
so let me ask you,
in terms of the nature of reality,
fundamental nature of reality,
does God play dice?
You don't know some fuck,
that's your course.
You don't know some doctors which could
be important.
It looks like a good way,
nice,
but we don't discourage it.
If you must distinguish between two
positions,
positions of instrument,
where you're creating,
it will production in positional for
areas where you're trying to understand
what God did,
can you describe instrumental and
realism a little bit?
For example,
if you have some,
because Nicole laws work is that is it
low each through always and everywhere
or it is law which allow you to predict.
Position of moving element is what you
believe.
You believe that it is God's law.
God created the world which are the two,
this physical law or it is just low for
predictions and which one is
instrumental?
Asm for predictions,
this is law of God.
It isn't always true everywhere.
That means you're the artist so you're
trying to.
I'm distant,
understands.
Got Salt.
Say the way you see the world is as an
instrumentalist,
you know,
are working for someone else,
model of machine learning.
So in Zeus model you can see a second,
the soul is the second assault is a
problem and you can do in two different
way from the point of view of
instrumentalists and that's what
everybody does,
not because,
uh,
this is a goal of machine learning is a
find zero for clarification,
is that the bucket is instrument for
production,
but they can say Zygote of a machine
learning is to learn about conditional
probability.
So I have got played use in play.
What your probability for one,
what is a given situation.
But for production,
I don't need this.
I need zero,
but for understanding I need
conditioner.
So let me just step back a little bit.
First to talk about,
you mentioned,
which I read last night,
the parts of the 1960 paper by a eugene,
a wagner,
a unreasonable effectiveness of
mathematics and natural sciences because
you're such a beautiful paper by the
way.
You made me feel it to be honest,
to confess my own work in the past few
years on deep learning,
heavily applied,
made me feel that I was missing out on
some of the beauty of nature in the way
that math can uncover.
So let me just step away from the
poacher that for a second.
How do you see the role of math in your
life as it?
Is it a tool as a poetry where where
does it sit and does math for you?
Have limits of what it can describe
some people singing each user growth,
so I believe
and that to God or use God used God.
Yeah,
so I believe the zoo's article about
effectiveness,
unreasonable effectiveness of mass is
that if you're looking for in which a
magical structures,
so ignore something Kubota and
scientists from natural science zero
looking on equation in trying to
understand sort of the same in machine
learning.
If you really cared,
if we look on all the equations,
did you define conditional probability?
You can understand something in both the
reality,
more zen from your fantasy.
So math can reveal the simple underlying
principles of reality.
Perhaps
you know what mean simple,
it is very hard to disclose,
but then when you discover them and look
at them,
you see a beautiful that are in it.
The surprising white people did not
choose that before you're looking
equation derived from equations.
For example,
I talked to yesterday about Netapp and
people had a lot of fantasy improve,
coordinate,
but if you look going step by step by
solving some equations,
you're suddenly,
you get some term which of the sinking
your stands in describe position of
observation point wrote a lot of
information.
You don't look in composition of points
of observations.
We're looking commonly on residuals,
but when your understood that,
that's a very simple idea but not too
simple to understand.
And you can derive this just for
mcorigins.
So some simple Algebra,
a few steps or take you to something
surprising that when you think about
so am that is proof that human intuition
not to reach in very primitive and it
does not see where it says simple
situations.
So,
oh,
let me take a step back in general.
Yes,
right.
Uh,
but what about human as opposed to
intuition,
ingenuity,
um,
moments of brilliance.
So I use.
So,
uh,
do you have to be so hard on human
intuition?
Are there moments of brilliance and
human intuition that can leap ahead of
math and then the math will catch up?
I don't think so.
I assume the best human intuition it is
putting in Oxford homes and technical
where see where they axioms take you,
but if they take actions but it ducks
your Polish during generation or
scientist,
and this is integral,
so that's beautifully put.
But if you maybe look at when you,
when you think of Einstein and special,
well,
what is the role of imagination coming
first there in the moment of discovery
of an idea.
So there's obviously a mix of math and
out of the box imagination there
that's a good goal or exclude you
because whatever is so emotional
learning conference nation like futures,
like the deeper nick looked at it,
what was a problem when you're looking
vertically from Maki,
magical liquidations,
you did arrive,
been converted.
Simple story usually goes fall by God.
It's good.
Then whatever people can imagine because
it is not good frontage,
it is just interpretation is just fun
things,
but it is not what you need.
You don't need any imagination to derive
a say.
My principal of machine learning.
When you think about learning and
intelligence,
maybe thinking about the human brain and
trying to describe mathematically the
process of learning,
uh,
that is something like what happens in
the human brain.
Do you think we have the tools
currently?
Do you think we'll ever have the tools
to try to describe that process of
learning?
You descriptions was growing up.
It was interpretation.
It is your interpretation.
Your vision can be wrong.
You know,
when God microscope living book for the
first time just instrument and nobody
will.
He kept secret about microscope,
but he wrote reports in London sites and
excuse the report.
When he looked and goes a blood heel.
Look,
every barrels of water owns or blood on
him,
but he described blood like fight
between you and king.
So he saw blood cells,
red cells and modules that is mute,
I think chose it.
And before his interpretation of
litigation,
and she sent it yesterday in no signs
and they are very creative for your look
because they believes that he's right.
He's right.
You saw something,
yes,
but keep going from interpretation and
they believe the same can happen.
His brain,
what is the most important.
But you know,
I believe in human language,
in some product is so much this.
For example,
people say that it is better than
thousand days of diligence studies one
day this great.
But if I ask you what did you does?
Nobody knows and that this intelligence
and but we know from Houston and now
from,
in machine learning is that teachers can
do a lot.
So what from a mathematical point of
view is the great teacher.
I don't know.
That's not,
not what have.
You can see what teachers can do.
You can introduce some,
uh,
some medicate for creating convergence.
Have you doing,
I dunno because teacher nor seriality
and can describe from this reality
predicate in variance.
But he knows that when you're using
convenient you can decrease the number
of observations hundred times.
That's
so,
but uh,
maybe try to pull that apart a little
bit.
I think you mentioned a,
like a piano teacher saying,
uh,
to the student play like a butterfly and
I played piano.
I play guitar for a long time and it,
yeah,
that's theirs.
Maybe it's romantic,
poetic,
but it feels like there's a lot of truth
in that statement.
Like there is a lot of instruction to
that statement and so can you pull that
apart?
What is,
what,
what is that?
The language itself may not contains
information.
Okay.
Blah,
Blah Blah because blah,
blah blah.
Yeah.
It's what if you,
if you blank.
Yes it does,
but what?
It's not the lane.
It's if it feels like a,
um,
what is the information being exchanged
and error?
What is the nature of information?
What is the representation of that
information?
I believe sort of educated,
but I don't know exactly what work
intelligence and machine learning should
be.
Yes.
Because this is just what you might call
a.
What was discovered recently is that
there is offloading one called stone
convergence mechanism and conversions.
Macanese before people use only one.
If you can go just because using you can
use educate,
that's what plainly bought the land and
if you immediately affect your plan,
you'll also see soon as English program.
Great.
It looks like the dark sleeves like the
dark and walk like a duck then it is
probably duck.
Yes.
But this is exact.
Put indicates.
Looks like a duck.
What it means.
So you,
so many dogs that you're training data.
So you're,
you have description or hub looks.
Integral looks ducks.
Yeah.
The visual characteristics of yard.
But you won't.
And you'll have modeled for,
you know,
so you would like show that theoretical
description for more.
The core site is empirical description
each year.
So on.
So about looks like the it general.
But what about,
seems like a doc.
You should know the dogs names.
You can say it.
Play chess like a duck.
Okay.
Doug doesn't relate.
Yes.
And it is completely legal.
Educate,
but it is useless.
So how teachers can recognize not
useless.
So up to now you don't use this in
existing machine a lot and you have data
but English forever use.
It looks like a duck.
Seems like a duck and quacks collecting
that
so you can't deny the fact that swims
like a duck and quacks like a duck,
has humor in it,
has an ambiguity.
Let's talk about sitting duck in.
It doesn't say jumps,
jumping duck.
Why?
Because
it's not relevant,
but music,
you know,
dogs,
different doors you know,
and your mouth and you derive from it is
really want to say,
say like in jail.
So underneath,
in order for us to understand swims like
a duck,
it feels like we need to know millions
of other little pieces of information we
pick up along the way.
You don't think so that doesn't need to
be.
This knowledge base in those statements
carries some rich information that helps
us understand the essence of duck.
Yeah.
How far are we from integrating a
product gets,
you know,
when,
when you consider complete sewer
machine.
So what does you have?
A lot of functions.
And then you're,
you're,
you're talking,
it looks like a duck.
You see your three new data from
training data.
You recognize his life.
Uh,
expected dark should look all functions
did,
you,
does not look like you think it should
look from staining it.
So you could use a multifunction from
vhp pickup,
what you a second predicate and they pay
this could decrease the second function
enough to that.
You a function,
you can find it.
Just stunned that machine learning.
So why are you need not too many
examples
is your products aren't very good,
Mrs.
Yeah,
because every political is invented to
decrease it leaseable set of function.
So you talk about admissible set of
functions.
Can you talk about good functions?
So what makes a good function?
So admissible set of function is circle
function.
You chose small capacity of small
diversity.
She did mention except did you continue
to good function,
etc.
So by the way,
for people who don't know,
vc,
you're the v in the vc.
Uh,
uh.
So,
uh,
how would you describe to a lay person?
What vc theories,
uh,
how would you describe these?
We're mushroom,
so machine capable to pick up one
function from zed miscible,
settler reflection.
But certified miserables function can be
contained.
All continuous functions in useless.
you don't have so many examples to pick
up watch,
but it can be small,
small,
uh,
because capacity,
but maybe better diversity,
so not very different function in the
function but not very diverse.
So if it's small,
you shouldn't mention when you mentioned
a small union,
you union smaller moment of training
data sources.
The goal is to create admissible set of
functions.
Ditch is small vishy dimension and
contained good zoom.
You should use it.
You'll be able to pick up the function
using a small amount of sort of
is that,
that is the task of learning is creating
a set of admissible functions as a small
vc dimension.
And then you've figured out a clever way
of picking up
the is that this goal of learning which
a fully formulated yesterday?
Yep.
Statistical learning surgery does not
involved in creating admissible set.
The function in classical learning
surgery everywhere.
Hundred percent in textbook is a set of
function.
Admissible central function is given,
but this is both nothing because the
most difficult problem to create
admissible setup functions given see a
lot of functions continuum set up,
auction create admissible central
functions.
That's been the key is finding it to be
small and contained good function.
So this was out of consideration.
So what's the process of doing that?
I mean,
it's fascinating.
What is the process of creating this,
um,
admissible set of functions that's in
various.
can you describe the variance
of appropriate use of data in a proper
just means is that you have some
function in your,
you're just cold.
What does your aVerage,
your function on your kind of model in
what is the expectation of this function
on some,
on set so that the problem was bold.
HaVe to piCk up functions.
It can be in yoU.
Fuck you,
fuck you for all functions.
But because when talking,
see doug does not jumping so you don't
ask questions,
jump like a duck because if this three
really doesn't the junk and from doesn't
help you mature nor something vg task
you're asking for you like figure it
like a duck but looks like a duck.
It haS general looks like see go.
Who covers his illness?
Is this disease?
It says legal.
Yeah.
So there is a general type of political
groups like in specific special nikki,
which he related to this specific and
his intelligence,
but also business and that were teachers
involved.
Incorporating the specialized predicates
a.
Okay.
What do you think about deep learning as
a neural networks,
these arbitrary architectures as helping
accomplish some of the tasks you're
thinking about their effectiveness or
lack thereof?
what are,
what are the weaknesses and what are the
possible strengths?
No,
this is fun.
Everybody seems huge.
Deep learning like futures.
Let me give you this example.
One of the greatest book is churchill
book about history of second world war
and he starting this book,
describing that in old time when the war
is over,
so the great kings together,
almost all of them were relatives and
they discuss what should be done,
have to create peace and they came to an
agreement in what happens for the
general public came in,
bought in.
They were so good that rope Germany and
it was clear for everybody that it is
not peace that peaceful last only 20
years because they was not professionals
in the same way.
She in machine learning zarama,
zara mathematicians,
we're looking for the problem from a
very deep point of your magical point
and zara computer scientists,
there's mostly does not know market is.
They just have interpretation of that
and they invented a lot of blablabla
interpretations like deep learning,
deep learning does not know.
Deploying which you might have,
does not know a neurons.
It is just function if you like to say
piecewise linear function,
say that and do it in class of piecewise
linear function,
but they went something and then they
try to to to proof advantage of that
through interpretations which mostly
wrong and again they appeal to brain
which they know nothing about that
nobody knows what god can break,
so I think that more reliable woke en
masse.
There's as much scope problem or do your
best to solve this problem.
Try to understand that there is no only
one way of convergence which is strong
wave of euphoria of conductors which
requires predicate.
If you will go through all this stuff,
you will see that you don't need even
more.
I was one of the tour him.
Each color presented theory.
It says that optimal solution of logical
problem,
which is,
would you describe lord ngukurr,
his own shuttle network,
not on deep learning and a shower.
Again,
problem is there.
Absolutely.
So in the end,
what you're saying is exactly right.
The question is,
you have no value for throwing something
on the table playing with it,
not math.
So like in your network or you said
throwing something in the bucket and
our,
um,
by the biological example in looking at
kings and queens with the cells,
with a microscope you don't see value in
imagining the cells are kings and
queens.
And using that as inspiration and
imagination for where the math will
eventually lead you.
You think that interpretation,
who was basically deceives you in a way
that's not productive
are soon.
If you're on the laws of nature,
of a spiritually discussion about
deploying it was discussion about
interpretation.
Not the boat sinks your boat.
What you can say about sings.
That's right.
But aren't you surprised by the beauty
of it?
So the,
the,
uh,
not mathematical beauty,
but the fact that it Works at all,
or are you criticizing that very beauty?
Our human desire to,
to interpret,
to find our silly,
silly interpretations and these
constructs like,
let me ask you this,
are you surprised in that?
Does it inspire you or how do you feel
about the success of a system like
alphago beating the game of go using
neural networks to estimate the quality
of a board of a board and the quality of
the interpretation coordinator support?
Yeah.
Yes.
So it's not our interpretation.
The fact is,
and you're on our system,
doesn't matter.
A learning system that we don't.
I think mathematically understand that
well beat the best human player does
something that was,
it's not very difficult.
That's so you empiric.
we've empirically have discovered that
this is not a very difficult problem.
It's true.
Uh,
so maybe can't argue.
so
you would more obviously the user uses
the polluting.
It is not the most effective way of
learning theory and usually when people
use the learning using zillions of
training data,
but you don't need this.
So I guess challenge generally do some
problems.
Did you do real deep learning method?
You are using contract terms lists even
more.
Some problems deploying cannot solve
because it's not necessarily z create
admissible set of function.
When creek
deep architecture muesli created
miscible set of functions,
you cannot say that you create in good,
admissible setup,
you're just a ceo fantasy.
It does not come from us,
but it is possible to create ugly
stubble set of functions and because you
have a training data that the actually
for magicians,
a run,
you're considering warrior,
you need to use law of large numbers
when you making training in existing
algorithm,
uniform law of large numbers,
which is much more difficult to acquire.
So we said imagine and all that stuff,
but never the less.
If you use morse code stroke way of
convergence,
you can decrease a lot of training data.
Yeah,
you could do the three.
This one was like a duck,
quacks like a duck,
but are.
So let's,
let's,
let's step back and think about intel.
Human intelligence in general.
Clearly that has evolved in a non
mathematical way.
It wasn't,
uh,
as far as we know,
god,
uh,
or,
or whoever didn't come up with a model
in place in our brain of admissible
functions.
It kind of evolved.
I don't know,
maybe you have a view on this,
but.
So alan turing in the fifties,
in his paper,
I'm asked and rejected the question,
can machines think it's not a very
useful question,
but can you briefly entertain this
useful,
useless question.
Can machines think?
So talk about intelligence and your vieW
of it.
I don't know.
Hearing,
describe imitation computer can imitate
human being.
Let's call it intelligent and he
understands that it is not sinking
computer.
Yes.
He completely understand what he does,
but he's set up problem of imitation so
long.
He understands that the problem,
not in limitation.
I'm not sure that intelligence just
inside of us.
It might be all soft side of us.
I have several observations.
So when they approved some sodium,
difficult,
sorry,
a couple of years in several places,
people pull off the same sorta loma
after ours was done in other guys in the
history of science.
It's happened all the time.
For example,
john certain similar foster did a little
and goals and [inaudible] and another
guy in the approximately in 10 times
video taped up the spirit of time.
If they saw a lot of examples like that
in which my tuition wednesday develop
something big sampson,
congenital ditch effect everybody.
So maybe you're our models.
It intelligence only inside the foss is
incorrect.
It's our interpretation.
Yeah.
It might be some connection.
You wold intelligence,
I don't know.
You're almost like plugging in into a.
Yeah,
exactly.
And contributing to this network to a
big maybe in your own network.
And the flip side of that,
maybe you can comment on a big old
complexity in how you see classifying
algorithms by worst case,
running time in relation to their input.
So that way of thinking about functions.
Do you think p equals np?
Do you think?
That's an interesting question.
It was interesting coalition,
but let me talk about complexity.
In the worst case scenario,
zoos in which you might circle setting
when they came to the United States in
1990,
so people did not know this show is I
get not no statistical lot.
So in Russia it was published two
motocross.
Oh,
one more grass,
but in America said that no zinzi lord,
and somebody told me the worst case
scenario,
create three.
Okay,
so what do it not,
because it is much in what's called
tool.
You can do only what you can do using
the markings and ditch [inaudible] a
clear understanding and clear
description and for some reason the
introduce complexity and didn't he just
because using.
Actually it is diverse like this one
more dimension.
You can pro sodiums,
but we also create order for case when
you low probability to measure is that
the best case which can happen at the
same therapy.
Stability.
So from which you might scope point of
view,
you know the best possible case is the
worst possible case.
You can have different model in medium
but not so interesting.
You think that the edges are interesting
and yeah,
just because
it is not so easy to get
good bob,
exact boat.
It's not my crisis or where you up,
but interesting principles.
Did you discover the moss?
Do you think it's interesting because
it's challenging and reveals interesting
principles that allow you to get those
bounds?
Or do you think it's interesting because
it's actually very useful for
understanding the essence of a function
of a,
of an algorithm.
So it's like me judging your life as a
human Being by the worst thing he did in
the best thing he did versus all the
stuff in the middle.
It seems a not productive
are those things.
So because you can not describe the
situation in the middle or not general.
So you can describe it just,
and it is clear because some model,
but you cannot describe model for every
new case.
So you're,
you'll be nervous when you're using
mortal.
But from a statistical point of view,
the way you've studied,
uh,
functions and,
and the nature of learning in the world,
don't you think that the real world has
a very long tail,
that the edge cases are very far away
from the mean the stuff in the middle
or.
No,
because as soon as you,
which from my point of view,
if you use formal statistic,
you uniform wolf lodge,
if you will use,
is this in avoidance business,
you've just flushed homeless.
You don't have this huge difference
between uniform law.
Is it useful to describe that a little
more or it will show we just take it to,
for example,
when,
when talking about doc I give city
pretty dedicated enough.
but if you try to distinguish,
you didn't need a lot of observing.
Uh,
and so does that means,
is that information?
It looks like a duck contained a lot of
information form of bits of information.
So if you don't know thAt,
how much bit of information
sinks from artificial intelligence is
that,
does this album,
you know,
old business are.
I don't like cuff people and she the
artificial intelligence is consider us
some quotes which imitate activity or
human being.
It is not science,
which is applications you would like to
imitate.
Go heretic is very useful.
It was problem,
but
junior to to to lord substance more have
people try to do cricket.
People came to see a pretty face,
so you just like a dock or play like
butterfly or something like that.
The teacher says you have it came in his
mind how he chooses.
So that process is problem of
intelligence.
That is the problem of intel and you see
that connected to the problem of
learning options are they requested you
immediately gives us predicate like a
specific predicate streams,
like a dark hole.
You just choose it somehow.
So what is the line of work would you
say?
If you were to formulate it as a set of
open problems that will take us there,
will play.
Look,
a butterfly will get a system to be able
to look at two stories,
one story,
the predicate.
You can do something.
Then those stories have to get
predicate.
It is intelligence problem and people
even did not start the understanding
because to understand intelligence,
the full try to understand what do
teachers of teacher teach via one
teacher butlers in another one.
Yup.
And so you,
you think we're really even haven't
started on the journey of regenerating
the protocols.
You don't understand.
You don't understand this problem exist
because did you,
do you know,
are you just normal name and I won't
understand a why one tissue,
but in a teacher student,
not because he repeating zipparo boom,
which isn't textbook.
Yes,
she makes somebody marks.
She makes some philosophy of,
you know,
that's a beautiful.
So it is a formulation of a question
that is the open problem.
Why is one teacher better than right?
What she does,
but yeah.
What,
what,
why?
In every level people,
how do they get better?
What does it mean to be better?
The whole?
Yeah.
From,
from whatever model I have,
one teacher can give a very good
predicate.
My pitcher can say a severe selected doc
and it does,
it can say jump like a duck and jump
like conducts cut a zero in front of me.
Yeah.
So what is the most exciting problem and
statistical learning you've ever worked
on or are working on now?
Oh,
I just feel years is either on story.
I believe zipped it is loading story.
At least they can shows is that it
doesn't nick nicole only what zay say
statistical bought from intelligent and
they know nothing about intelligent and
you know there's intelligent bot so it
you'll help us a lot in teaching in the
learning.
so we'll know it when we see it.
So for example,
in my talks,
the last slide was a challenge.
So you have say nist digitalization
problem and deploy new claims.
If they did it very well,
say 99 point five percent of it correct
answers,
but say you're 60,000
to observational.
Yeah.
Can you lose a sale user called
defenseless but incorporating things in
variance.
What it means,
you know,
digital want to see.
But yeah,
just looking concert explained the
vision.
The orientation would keep to use
examples or say 100 times less examples
to do the same job.
Yeah,
that last slide in a.
Unfortunately you're talking too
quickly,
but that last slide was a powerful open
challenge and a formulation of the
essence does exactly
problem often the diligence because
everybody,
when nick started it was working with
too much emotion.
Z immediately recognize that views use
much more a trading datas of human
needed.
but no,
again,
we came to the same study have to
decrease.
Is that this problem of loading?
It does,
like in deploying the z subterranean
date,
the cost,
my resilience of not enough.
If you have a good,
uh,
invariance might be,
you'll never collect some observations,
but now it is a question to,
to intelligence have to do that because
statistical part is in here.
As soon as your suppliers this
predicament,
you can do good job in a small amount of
observations as a very first challenges
will know digital coordination and you
know,
digits and police,
there'll be variance.
I think that they can say four digit
city.
I would introduce concept of horizontal
symmetry.
So it was a digital has horizontals,
symmetry say malls and say digital or
something like that.
but as soon as I get the deal is
announced symmetry,
I can watch a lot of measure your senior
year or the organon cemetery or
whatever,
if I could ever deal cbt,
but foretells looking on on on digital
use it.
It is mit,
the mit,
the predicate which is not shape the
subsidy lake cemetery,
like half dark.
His whole pictures,
something like that each can sell for as
a predicate.
You think such a predicate could rise of
something that's a
not general meaning
it feels like for me to be able to
understand the difference between the
two and three,
I would need to have had a a childhood
of 10 to 15 years playing with kids,
going to school,
being yelled at by parents,
all of that walking,
jumping,
looking at ducks and now then I will be
able to generate the right predicate for
tying the difference between two and a
three.
Or do you think there's a more
efficient.
Oh no,
for sure.
You must know some signals of digits yes
to.
And that's a powerful state,
but maybe there are serval languages of
description,
um,
elements of digits.
So you talking about symmetry
properties,
Jordan,
talking about some gaps there.
I don't know that,
but this is a problem of intelligence.
So in one article it is revealed to show
that every example can cut it not more
than one beautiful information in the
hill because,
uh,
with your show example,
and you say this is one you can remove a
function which does not tell your mom
the best strategy if you can do it,
the city move off of options.
But when you used one predicate which
looks like a duck,
you can remove much more functions in
the cuff.
And that to me,
that did contain a lot of information
from formal point of view.
But when you have a little picture what
you want to send general picture.
So what can you just put indicate?
And that predicates carter a lot of
noise,
beautifully put maybe just me,
but in all the math you show in your
work,
uh,
which is some of the most profound
mathematical work in,
in,
in the field of learning ai.
And just math in general,
I hear a lot of poetry and philosophy.
You really kind of,
um,
talk about philosophy of science.
there's a,
there's a poetry and music to a lot of
the work you're doing and the way you're
thinking about it.
So do you.
Where does that come from?
Do you to escape to poetry?
Do you escape to music?
Doesn't exist.
Ground truth,
ground truth is that get seen
everywhere.
Yeah.
The smart guy,
she lost them.
Sometimes I surprise of the deep sea.
Sometimes some of them are completely
out of subject,
but the sheet music,
music is the ground truth be important
to you when you point z,
z believes if they take dictation.
So what a piece of music as a piece of
empirical evidence gave you a sense that
they are,
um,
they're touching something in the
ground.
Truth it to Structure the structure.
Listening to bach structure.
Yeah,
very,
very classic.
Very simple.
It was the same with,
when you enjoying the,
you can just say the same.
Yeah.
Um,
and if you look back at your childhood,
you grew up in Russia,
you maybe were born as a researcher in
Russia,
you've developed as a researcher in
he came to United States in a few
places.
If you look back,
what were,
what was some of your happiest moments
as a researcher?
Some of the most profound moments,
not in terms of their impact on society,
but in terms of their impact on how damn
good you feel that day and you remember
that moment,
you know,
every time when you followed something.
It is great and everybody,
simple things,
just like your little feelings that they
mostly,
most of my time was broke.
You should go again and again and again
and try to be honest with yourself,
look more contemporary,
but try to understand that the new way
to grant,
not marty,
blah,
that.
But you're allowed to get excited at
the,
at the possibility of discovery here.
You'll have to double check it.
But uh,
no,
but covered related to throws.
Is it just for hair?
But you know,
you always have a feeling your phone,
something of that.
So 20 years ago with the discovery of
statistical loading,
so nobody believe except for one guy dr
jay and live in 20 years then became
fashion is the same,
the support vector machines,
machines.
So what was supportive and machines are
learning theory with when you were
working on it,
you had a sense that you had a sense of
the profundity of it,
the how that this,
this seems to be right.
It seems to be powerful,
right?
Absolutely.
Definitely lost waiver and know when
fallen zoos.
In what story you feel the same
feelings.
Look at this company because I have
perused.
No different mechanisms.
You can some say cosmetic improvement
you can do,
but in terms of your audience,
the more statistical learning they
should work together,
but also I'm credited as a fordable
lights.
What is intelligence that and to
separate from technical bottom.
Exactly.
it's completely different.
Absolutely.
well thank you so much for talking
today.
Thank you.
It's an honor.