Today's show is sponsored by audible.
Audible is offering our listeners a free
audio book with a 30 day trial
membership.
Just go to audible.com
forward slash Carlin and browse the
unmatched selection of audio programs.
Download a title free and start
listening.
It's that easy.
Go to audible.com/Carlin
or text Carlin to 500 dash 500 and get
started today.
It's hardcore history.
I've said before that one of the
wonderful side benefits of a gig like
this is the chance to speak to people
whose work you really admire and talked
to them about it,
and in this case I have a guest on the
program today who is a source,
somebody that we use in our work and
when we did blueprint for Armageddon,
he was sort of my go to guy in terms of
somebody that I knew could add a
different dimension to the storytelling
by having a letter or a document or a
quote or something that was just,
you know,
so visceral or perfect or emotional or
that in one short little paragraph
managed to capture such a poignant point
that just sort of made the whole section
of the piece.
I mean Peter Hearts work is finding
emotional nuggets that just knock you
over and then incorporating them into
the story in a way where they not only
have the most impact,
but they managed to add a part of the
story that often gets missed.
If you're telling,
for example,
a story on the first World War,
which is Peter Harte specialty.
It is so easy to get yourself locked
into the giant troop movements in the
big decisions made at headquarters and
all this.
Sometimes you can go the total opposite
extreme and it's easy to get caught up
in the diary of this one soldier or this
one nurse or something like that,
but to be able to blend the two in a way
that helps you understand,
for example,
how the decision's made at headquarters
with all those high muckety mucks
thinking about things abstractly,
how they influence and intersect with
the lives of some poor guy,
mortally wounded in a shell hole,
writing his last letter back to his wife
and family.
It's an art and I think Peter Hart does
it as well or better,
especially on the subject of the first
World War than anyone I've ever read.
So you get to see me enjoying my
byproduct.
The best aspect of this Gig,
the chance to talk to people whose work
you admire.
People like Peter Hart,
who is amongst other things,
an oral historian by the way at the
British imperial war museum,
which is every military history,
nuts,
dream gig.
Love to go to work by a couple of giant
15 inch naval guns.
Which one of those,
you know,
they have several of these war museums,
but the main one in London has the big
naval guns outside.
You just take a picture.
Here's where I work,
right?
Eat your heart out.
Anyway,
uh,
one little note.
Normally we have an in house phone
system we use when we do interviews,
but normally we only use that for North
American interviews when we're overseas
calls.
We've been using sort of an internet
system and uh,
this time it led us down with some
pretty serious glitches at times,
especially near the end of the
interview.
Not only my apologies to Peter Hart,
but to you also.
Uh,
it's frustrating and there was no way
for us to fix it.
So I am going to put a couple of,
shall we call them end notes after the
interview where I both a quote something
that we referenced in the show so that
we include that,
uh,
explained something.
Mr Hart said at the end that the digital
glitches did not make easy to understand
and also read a letter that we
referenced in the story to something
that Peter Hart,
a uncovered for one of his books that we
used in the blueprint for Armageddon
series and reread that to just show you
the man's ability to demonstrate the
ripples of pain that something like this
conflict,
you know,
created in that era,
in those societies,
and drop you right into the middle of it
for a minute.
So without further ado,
uh,
the wonderful author and oral war
historian,
maybe a good way to put it,
the Great Peter Hart.
So the first thing I want to know
because I'm just curious as a person who
is absolutely jealous of anyone who can
find such a specialty to devote their
lives to,
um,
how did it,
for you mostly become because you've
done other things but mostly become
something about the first world war.
What grabbed your interest about this
and what is it that keeps you so
interested in the subject?
Well,
I think it started when I was young and
there was a program called the Great
Wall,
uh,
which was all Italian,
the 19 sixties,
and it was gloomy and miserable and it
seems so awful.
People suffered so much and for me it's
always been that dichotomy.
It's a dichotomy between the people who
suffered and what the generals did and
why they did that because you may or may
not realize I,
I quite support the approach of the
generals and it,
it's the way that it's an entirely
logical way of behaving,
but it's terrible for those that are
involved and that has always informed or
I hope has informed all the work.
I do it.
It's,
it's,
it's what it's all about for me
now.
You've been doing it long enough so that
you've been around to watch sort of how
public perception over time on these
events has changed.
Because I remember I was born in 1965
and I remember in the United States
growing up as a kid,
there was a sense about the first world
war that it was like the Second World
War,
but a little less in terms of the good
and evil,
still the good and evil.
The Kaiser was evil man,
but not quite to Hitler standards.
And then since I've grown up that good
evil aspect to first world war has
seemed to be,
um,
to fade over time quite a bit,
at least here in the United States.
Have you noticed,
can you comment a little bit on the
differences in the way,
you know,
Barbara Tuchman writes a book years ago
that,
that Jack Kennedy reads,
that's really particularly hard on the
Germans.
The stuff I read today has a very
different tone.
What have you noticed in the change of
if we were doing news,
we would say the coverage over the last,
say,
four decades of the first world war.
Oh,
I've,
I've noticed a fair amount of coverage.
My perception has always been that in
the end,
if there were batteries,
then it was the Germans,
but that there were a lot of people
doing things that were difficult or
wrong,
um,
that there were four or five major m and
pause that was struggling together
trying to establish domination.
A lot of them had agendas that we
wouldn't particularly recognizes today
has been a pleasant or,
you know,
uh,
the,
the colonialism,
things like that,
uh,
that,
that treatment of the colonies,
the way they generally behaved and
everything.
And for me,
um,
we have now an acceptance that whilst
the Germans pushed the war,
they were partly did that because they
were being pushed,
bothered the Russians and the French and
the French who had their own agendas.
And it's just become much more
complicated.
Uh,
the thing is,
it's not easy,
is it?
You know,
that's the problem with history that
when you add new orleans,
things stopped being good and evil.
So becoming just much more complex
now.
One of the things you do so
fantastically,
we try to do it here too.
It's a great if you can pull it off,
it's a great way to do it.
You pull it off all the time where
you're able to take the reader from the
macro,
you know you'll have us in the in the
board room and you'll have quotes from
assistance to the great grand
strategists who are deciding how to use
troops on the battlefield and then all
of a sudden you'll telescope down to
some poor,
a combatant who's injured mortally in
some shell hole who's writing alas,
letter to his wife and kids that he's
going to strapped to his body to find
later.
First of all,
you know,
explain to the listener a little bit how
you go about finding these materials.
It would seem to me to be one of the
luxuries of working in a in a semi
modern era.
I mean the poor Roman historian has much
less in the way of letters from
combatants to go on,
but.
But you're able to mind emotionally mine
this material out there.
How do you find it?
And if it's as powerful as it is on the
sterile text page as I'm reading it,
how much more powerful is it for you
when you're holding the,
the actual stained letter in your hands?
Well,
I'd say more than my books that I found
a letter that was from a French soldier.
I used that,
but I am extremely lucky that I have
been for the last 30,
35 years,
the oral historian at the imperial war.
So I a did all the,
a lot.
Not all at all,
but I did a lot of the first row or
interviews with veterans and that
provided with a fantastic source which
the war museums allowed me to use.
And secondly,
I have worked closely with the
Department of documents there that uh,
and that just opening the dusty old
folders that they're all cataloged and
preserved by,
by the staff.
But you know,
you open these and you no idea what
you're going to find.
And sometimes it can be utterly tedious.
You know,
Joe's letter after letter or boring you.
No,
no,
no.
And then suddenly you get someone
swimming.
It's really fiscal that,
that tears you apart,
that you know it,
you just get letters at that,
you realize these are the last letters.
They,
you know,
you've been reading this bloke's life
and then suddenly they're suddenly,
it's not his letter,
it's a letter from his commanding
officer and you know,
it.
It's amazing.
And I just think I'm very lucky to work
at the war museum from that.
I then look through lots of other
sources.
I go to other museums,
I go to other places and of course I
look at personal experience,
um,
uh,
books,
mainly old ones,
but like I use quite a few modern one
serve,
you know,
or,
or regimental history is often have it
buried inside them.
Personal experience accounts,
you know,
the Americans.
I picked up a lot from the Internet
where the pdfs of the books are 19
twenties are online and you can consult
them.
It's fabulous.
And,
and that's where I get the material.
Uh,
and uh,
yes,
it,
it can be,
you know,
the,
the actual real letters that I see at
the museum can be really painful.
Obviously humans are humans at Ground
Zero,
but when you're reading and you focus
mostly on the British side of the
experience,
but you cover everything,
do you notice any broad,
broad differences in,
say you're reading something from ground
zero from a French soldier or some
German soldier on the line versus some
British or American soldier.
Are there any differences in terms of
the way that their national
characteristics sort of come through in
the material or at ground zero when
you're sitting in a trench with
artillery falling all around you are.
We are.
We are broadly the same.
I very much go for broadly the same.
I'm not a great believer in national
characteristics I need anyway.
It can help sometimes it's a shorthand
to explain certain things,
but if you take it too literally it goes
into dark alleys.
Uh,
what,
uh,
I really think though is that underneath
human beings when they placed under real
pressure tend to respond in a similar
sort of way.
And for me,
a French soldier that the accounts,
you know,
sometimes I have to translate which can
be difficult.
Um,
gray,
uh,
a friend of Mine,
translation to the German ones for me
because I don't speak or read German.
And fundamentally they're the same.
They have slightly different ways of
expressing themselves,
but that's just cultural.
But underneath,
when the shelves are falling,
when their friends are killed,
uh,
when they given oldest,
it could lead them to be killed.
There.
The same sort of people.
They are,
uh,
you know,
they are,
they're just ordinary people.
You know,
that's maybe one of the things that at
least I imagine touches many people once
they start in a reading about the war is
these,
these incidents where,
you know,
the,
the comradeship.
Maybe the German soldiers would say,
but we're,
the soldiers have multiple sides who,
you know,
more and more modern history's we'll
talk about how prisoners would be killed
sometimes and all the horrors of war.
And yet at the same time,
you know,
the notion is when these people end up
having truces where they,
you know,
share Christmas decorations or play
football,
as you guys would call it soccer,
we would call it or,
or any of the many,
many incidents like that getting stuck
in a shell hole with someone from the
other side in your latest book that was
a primary source quote where a British
soldier had his arm really badly injured
and goes marching to the back with a
bunch of German prisoners who start
doctoring his wounds.
Do you notice,
I mean I don't see as much of that and
it might be part of the historiography
or what have you,
part of the myth making.
But when I read stuff in the Second
World War,
I find a lot less of that than in the
first world war.
Anything in on the front of your mind
that might account for the difference
there?
Or Am I just imagining that there is
one?
If there is a there,
there was more hatred in the Second
World War.
I think we all,
it's only our opinions from the things
we've read and,
but I,
I into,
I've interviewed an awful lot of second
one more second world war soldiers in
the first world war,
so I'll just,
and there is more hatred there,
bit bit because of the nature of the
regime they're fighting.
Now.
The communist regime in Russia was
pretty rough as well,
but,
but there was a hatred of the Nazis,
but very rarely in any war,
there are not many soldiers that,
that,
that respond,
uh,
with murder and torture.
And the rest of it,
most of them in my experience,
uh,
a main maintain a lid on their emotions.
And,
and,
uh,
it's,
it's there,
but there are a few who do respond with,
with,
uh,
well,
just murder,
you know,
or,
or panic.
Often it's panic.
The trick,
the trick is the murder.
So the first World War that you've
mentioned it first up,
comradeship is the thing that binds the
army's together.
But most of all,
it binds.
It binds you to your fellow soldiers.
That's what helps you.
That's what it lets you go over the top.
It's,
it's not a king and country a or
precedent.
Uh,
it's not,
um,
it's not religion.
What in the end when it all comes down
to,
it's mostly the bugs.
You're with your mates,
the,
the men who went through training with
who faced death with you,
that that's what helps you get through
it.
You know,
you mentioned something going over the
top a minute ago,
such an iconic way of differentiating
the,
at least western front experience of
this war from all the others.
And you know,
it occurs to me that because of sort of
the nature of technology and the way
things have gone,
I don't think you're ever going to get
the same experience that those first
world war soldiers went through ever
again.
I mean,
I don't think you're ever gonna have
hundreds and hundreds or thousands of
guns peppering a small space of
territory anymore.
You don't need to because of the
accuracy.
You're never going to mix them with gas
the way you did.
I mean,
if you think as I do that that would
have been equal to the worst place a
soldier could have ever been right in
front of the line about to go over the
top western front.
I don't think you're ever going to get
that experience again.
You're never going to have human beings
watch.
Uh,
I think I forgot the.
I'm the author who had said one of the
soldiers described watching a forest
disappear in front of his eyes due to
artillery.
I mean,
that's a human experience that I don't
think any human being's going to ever
see again in the beginning of the second
world war Churchill's history of the
war.
He talked about what was in store in 19,
19 if the war hadn't ended in 1918.
The various,
you know,
horrible concoctions that the allies had
put together your latest book.
The last battle is from that era.
Can you talk a little bit about what 19,
19 on the front might have looked like?
Uh,
uh,
the British had a,
the,
the Germans had that blue cross gas.
It didn't work properly.
I mixture of a punishes gas and the sort
of particles,
the particles made you vomit,
so he had to take your gas mask off and
then they got,
you know,
the poisonous gas.
Got You.
Now the German version didn't work
properly,
but the British had worked out on their
allies by the way.
I'd worked out how to do it and I fully
intended to poison most of the German
army in 19,
19.
Uh,
it,
it is a vicious war.
Uh,
and,
and the practices in a way that was just
one step forward,
you know,
the,
the um,
because we've sort of moved on.
Then it was mass barrages.
Now there's no need for mass priorities
now.
And although we did revert to it after
El Alamein for instance as well,
and they have them on the,
in 1944 on the west,
only in Europe,
but it's replaced by mass bombing isn't
it?
And then of course it's a nuclear method
and then its accuracy and so technology
moves on and.
But like the killing can still be on a
mass scale.
For instance,
in the Iraq war,
there was mass killing the Gulf war,
mass killing of a,
an it needs to be remembered.
What happens is the masculine tends not
to be on our side anymore.
Um,
you know,
uh,
so that,
that pretty well how I feel about it.
Well,
it is interesting too,
because when we were talking about the
first world war in the series that we
did on it,
you know,
you,
you almost want to overwhelm the
listener with both the casualty
statistics and then the,
the amount of mean,
the sheer numbers of things like shells.
I mean the numbers overwhelm you.
I'm,
you know,
a lot of Americans,
for example,
they like to tell jokes about the French
and surrendering in the Second World
War.
And so you would like to point out,
Hey,
wait a minute,
you know,
when did our side ever take 27,000
dead in a single day?
You know,
those kind of numbers are so
overwhelming that in the United States,
you know,
there's not a lot of memorials to the
first world war and all this.
But you go to Europe and they are
everywhere.
Um,
can you talk a little bit about sort of
the lasting effect?
I mean,
the,
the feeling of connection to the first
world war never died down in Europe.
Did it
not really?
Well,
for the French and Germans,
it was monstrously painful business.
I mean,
they are much hotter than the British.
The French in particular,
you'll right.
That's all nate.
Uh,
I'd say August 19,
14,
the French lost 27,000
dead in a single day.
Now the British,
when John about suffering,
I think a 600 that uh,
uh,
it's a different scale and the French
sector and the French then fault almost
on their own for two or three years.
People say the Americans took a long
time to get into the wall,
you know,
from a April 19,
17 to a,
to well properly June,
July 19,
18,
17 years.
Not 17 to 19 eight,
so bit over a year.
But the British took from August 1914 to
the somme,
July on the somme before we were
properly involved.
Uh,
you know,
that people often forget when they're
throwing stones at other countries,
they forget,
like we sometimes do it,
the Americans or the Americans or the
French or British or the French.
When you look at your own decide we
often have the same sort of problems or
the same,
uh,
false.
Um,
and I find that it's one of those
interesting things.
Um,
the American losses were dreadful in the
first world war that they suffered a
very high rate of losses from when they
fully joined the battle of the battle.
Uh,
uh,
in the,
the are gone,
the [inaudible] gone region is
murderous.
It's as murderous as any of the battle
in the first world war and considering
that they only really for full pelt for
three months,
the American casualties are worth
remembering.
But,
but for one reason or another possibly
could say disengaged from Europe a bit
in,
in the,
in the interwar years,
the Americans have never really
remembered it in the same way as we do.
Yes.
I always try to imagine if the US had
fought for two years at those kinds of
casualty rates.
Um,
yeah,
we'd have a few more war memorials
around here.
Certainly would,
you know,
I think about,
um,
contexts,
you know,
if history teaches anything,
it helps us understand how things get to
where they are and in this country,
once again,
you know,
they'll try to use in political
discussions the lessons of history,
right?
We know from the 19,
38 appeasement stuff that you can't do
this or that or the other thing,
you know,
the classic misuse of the lessons of
history,
but I always try to,
and I'm going to ask you for your
opinion on this because you've read a
lot of stuff.
The generation that gets accused of
really doing anything they could to
avoid another world war are the ones
that lived through it as younger people.
How did that scar?
The leadership on both sides really in
the second world war as they sort of
maneuvered jockeyed a threatened try to
avoid via compromise a repetition of the
worst thing any of them had ever lived
through.
I think there's some truth in that I'm
not an expert,
but certainly that there was peace
movements in Britain and France for the
French pretty broken by their awful
experiences,
you know,
[inaudible] is the one that gets most of
the blame for what happened,
but he was responding to a popular
element within the country.
I see that they just were not willing to
suffer it all.
Again,
I'll have so much sympathy for them.
Uh,
the Germans of course also that you just
have less sympathy for them.
So,
um,
the,
the British,
you know,
it took a while for us to get properly
into the wall.
I mean,
even in the second we'll,
we'll,
uh,
the,
the phony war and then you know,
that people were trying to get that.
There was an appeasement movement in
Britain right until Churchill took over.
And Churchill,
for all his faults was the walnut
finally pinned the British into,
into a post in Nazi Germany in the long
term because they were elements in
British society that we're perfectly
happy to do a deal with it.
Um,
it,
you know,
it's a complex period,
which I am not an expert on at all.
Your latest
we'll call the last battle focuses on,
you know,
from a military history standpoint,
I think one of the most fascinating
periods in the first world war,
but it seems to get lost in the burdens
and the psalms and the passion Dales and
all that.
Talk a little bit about that era where
we go away from the iconic western front
of,
of a stalemate on the front to open
movement again and something that looks
like a prototype for 1939 warfare.
It,
it certainly is.
Um,
I mean,
everything changes with the,
the itch the allies come up with the
alarms battle,
which is basically finding all the
different weapons,
the artillery,
the gas,
the mass machine gun fire that tanks,
the aeroplanes,
that light machine guns,
mortars,
everything together,
working together with,
uh,
to,
to overwhelm anything that Germans do,
took a breakthrough.
But also it's the difference that not
just attacking on one place,
like at the summer pasture,
but to attack for attacks,
for battles for days.
He Americans go first,
that then,
then the British and the Canadians then
and then uh,
the French,
the Belgians and the British,
and then finally the British again,
and the French full battles for day is
pushing the Germans.
Now,
the reason it's missed out and normally
book's finished roundabout the eighth of
August.
My own book on 1918,
a very British victory,
which was a bit of a job title.
I have to admit,
I don't know why I did that.
I have got a sense of humor which does
come out at a parcel really normally.
And the point was that you sort of,
you publish it.
If they say right,
we've had enough of them go to the top.
Now we've had.
And that's what you tend to miss out.
Even that book by me,
you know,
Mrs the last six weeks of the war.
And I wanted to put that right with this
because there are so many enormous
battles.
Open warfare comes in.
Open warfare is worse.
The casualty figures get higher,
much higher because because you're in
the open,
if something goes wrong,
you know,
hey,
God is the British to go forward,
push through in a very modern fashion,
push through,
ignore isolated pockets of resistance
there'll be dealt with,
but if you're an infantry soldier and
you go past an isolated pocket of
resistance,
you'll get killed and the inmates will
as well because they'll fire into your
flanks.
Does she go by?
So it's efficient militarily,
but it leads to huge casualties.
It's a painful time for the British and
the Americans who are learning at the
same time and anyone,
anyone who has insults,
the American,
the courage of the American troops on a,
in the Argon,
those battles is mad because if you
insult them,
you're insulting the British on the
Somme and you're insulting the French in
1914,
you're insulting basically armies that
don't know what's going to happen to
them.
They haven't had a chance to learn and
that I think you don't learn this until
you get right into the end of the war
because the Americans don't really get
into the war until,
uh,
until September about September the
26th.
That's when their wall really starts
when they attack the Argonne forest
water place.
You know,
I've been there.
It's murder,
you know,
you mentioned earlier and you just sort
of opened the door to it again.
I'm one of the,
one of the aspects,
one of the opinions,
one of the points of views on this
subject that you're kind of known for,
you know,
I,
I'd put you and I guess you would put
yourself in the camp of those who look
at,
for example,
the performance of the generals,
which of course famously some compared
to butchery to.
If I could,
I could sum it up maybe A.
I'm doing pretty well considering what a
natural learning curve on,
on,
on a big technological revolution in
military affairs like this one might be
a.
is that fair to say that you think that
they've done a pretty good job?
All things considered spot on,
particularly some of the more advanced
French and British general and uh,
I,
I stand by,
Hey,
I,
I know it makes me a puppet or in some
places.
The thing about Haig was he was don't
think of him as a general thinking of
him as a chief executive of a massive
American Corporation.
Someone who,
who provides direction,
someone who brings things together.
So who enables or makes things happen.
If you think of him that way,
you get in a much better idea of what he
was.
He was a commander in chief of five
armies.
There is no such thing as in,
uh,
in the,
Second World War.
I mean,
you know each.
there people are supreme commanders,
but they had people to deal with.
Politicians have to deal with our
allies.
That doesn't happen in the first world
war.
It's just,
hey,
who has to deal with all of them and it,
that's how it works.
And they did come up and.
But when it's not,
Haig comes up with it,
but it enables the system which allows
the all arms battle to function.
And can I just want,
it's not a learning curve,
what it is is too big,
deepest side by side and once the allies
or the British,
if you were to look at it narrowly
British or Americans and then the other
side is the Germans and for every new
attacking method you bring in the
Germans bringing a defensive attitude.
It's not a curve.
You go up and you go down and something
that works on Tuesday,
it might not work next Thursday because
the Germans will have changed their
tactics.
That's an analogy.
Not An exact timeframe obviously,
but what I mean is it's constantly
changing.
So in 1951 trench line,
perhaps one and a half.
Then later in that year there's three
trench lines.
By the year afterwards,
there's three trench systems and then
readouts.
Soon after that you start to get the
pill is the underground block houses
where the troops can be kept safe.
You get different machine can tactics.
So the Germans are constantly changing.
Now we changed as well.
British bringing tanks,
are they great?
Not First,
but they're part of it that were
different tactics,
different infantry tactics.
So both sides are changing,
enhance.
If you think of two big diapers,
I think you call them something else in
America,
but you know a little right,
well,
lots going up and down hills at running
side by side and you find out who's
going to win a battle by where you are
in relation to the other side.
Henson,
the Psalm,
first,
Psalm,
first day of the somme,
19th,
six days were very low down there.
They've got great trench systems,
great weapons of defense.
And we,
we're,
we're an,
we don't know what we're doing,
but all told by the end of the war,
we really have learned to where the very
high end we're looking down on the
Germans.
But it is a complex system that,
that the,
uh,
I think,
Golden Corrigan,
a British historian once said,
it wasn't the generals killed up boys.
It was the Germans and it's the same for
your American lads.
It's the Germans that did it.
And when we try and blame just our
generals or just our senior offices or
blame our allies,
you're not understanding what's
happening.
We're fighting a very complex war
against the best army in the world,
one of the biggest army in the world.
The Germans
you wrote in your book that modern
warfare was just so damn complicated at
every level.
Um,
so let's talk about that for a minute
because it seems to me and I,
you know,
obviously there were,
there were earlier wars were,
these changes happened,
but so slowly that they may not have
been important.
It seems to me that the first world
wars,
the first one where we get that very
modern sort of sense where technology is
changing so quickly that it's not that
you're going to have to learn the
lessons of this war and adapt for the
next war.
You're going to have to learn the
lessons of today's air combat,
for example,
so that in six months you have the
newest discovery or the other side's
gonna shoot your people out of the air.
Now,
in the Second World War you saw this,
this,
this dynamic going on all the time.
What's the latest tank?
What's the latest version of the
airplane?
But in the first world war,
it seems like that's the first time
that,
that needing to learn on the fly and
adapt during the conflict becomes,
well a war winning or a war losing
potentially thing.
Absolutely.
And it's so quick.
I mean,
the aircraft that took place before the
battle of the somme,
the aircraft that took control of the
air over the song were British and that
there were things like the Idh to the
uh,
you know,
the,
um,
uh,
the fee to be that the sopwith strutter
by God,
there were names to conjure with them
camels 17.
That's later.
But they took control.
They will outclass totally by the
Albatross just three months later,
three months now.
People like me still think that the,
uh,
you know,
the whole carrier,
a decent aircraft,
that's 19 fifties technology that flew
in the sixties,
seventies and eighties and has been
outdated now.
Best part of 10 years.
Then it was months,
just months.
And you could be flying an aircraft that
was great.
And now he's useless.
In fact,
it's a death trap when you meet
something better.
And,
and I find,
and I think that there is a warfare as a
catalyst for change,
you get generals or people like generals
who defined the need and then you get to
a scientist who,
who do the thinking,
who work out the theory of how to meet
that need and then you have a,
you know,
you have the practical men that they're
engineers are practical soldiers and
they work at it to actually do it,
you know,
how to fix that camera to an airplane,
how to,
you know,
somebody else works at the focal lengths
and everything else,
but someone has to work it out.
You get the theory of a synchronization
machine so you can shoot through the
propeller or not through the propeller
if you see what I mean,
that the theories very well and good,
but you need practical mentor,
make it work.
And warfare drives along technological
change.
A bit like in the sixties,
um,
if I might,
although it's not my subject a bit like
the space race did the same,
you know,
driving along technological change
because someone's defined a very real
need.
Well,
and then to bow tie this with what we
just talked about and then somebody from
the military hierarchy has to figure out
how it all fits together operationally.
And if you're the CEO,
like you said,
in a guy like Douglas Haig,
you have to remember that it's a guy who
has to factor in all this,
what we would call today,
high tech stuff.
Who was a cavalry officer born in the
mid 19th century.
Yep.
He was a buddy.
He was known as he educated soldier.
He was saying,
I mean,
you read,
you can find a quote for everything if
you look through the thing,
so you'll find,
you know,
but he was an enthusiast for machine
guns eight to has a problem,
a problem.
He's often too keen on new weapons,
uh,
you know,
he,
um,
uh,
he,
he doesn't realize that.
Well,
not that he doesn't realize,
but sometimes he doesn't appreciate
that,
that you have to bed them in.
There's no point building 300 tanks and
sending them forward if you don't know
how to drive them.
Which we didn't in 1968.
It's only 1917.
We knew how they worked,
how the,
how to use them in action,
how to fit them in,
into the all arms battle,
the what's going on is very,
like,
I may be a British term or it may be an
American term that we used,
but hey,
you could not have recognized this term,
but best practice,
you know what I mean?
Uh,
all the time the British army is engaged
in something called best practice.
They wouldn't know what that meant,
but they,
they look at a battle,
what worked,
what didn't best practice.
They then disseminate in a series of
pamphlets called the SS unfortunately
with our perspective,
but ss pamphlets,
a those pamphlets,
how to do this,
how to use a tank in battle,
how to use a louis machine guns,
how to make an attack,
how to do this,
how to do that.
And this,
this is just,
you know,
this is just the stuff of modern warfare
and it takes staff officers.
It takes generals and it takes someone
like,
Hey,
get the top,
uh,
to,
to co ordinate.
He's not a genius.
He's not the Polian.
It's probably not even Wellington,
but what he is is a driven individual
who,
whose mind for one reason is it's a
perfect staff officer mind,
a combination of detail Dr and the,
the guts to set a direction,
a direction which is painful to many of
the men who served for it.
When you're reading the histories too,
I mean,
it's so funny because,
and you'll churchill is a perfect
example of someone who will push this,
but you mentioned it with Hashtag to
where you can see that the best way to
use this new technology is to sort of
surprise the other side with it and
benefit from the shock value.
But as you just pointed out,
the problem is,
is that you don't know how to use it
until you've used it a few times.
And then by then of course the Germans
have started responding with
countermeasures and whatnot.
I mean,
remember,
uh,
was it churchill talked about using the
tanks when they first appeared in pin
pricks as opposed to some giant battle
where a thousand of them overwhelmed the
front.
But as you pointed out,
if that was the first time you ever
really employed them,
would it have been effective at all?
That I'd like to take?
Yes.
That's a great exam because the 15th of
September is the first tank attack.
A three quarters of them broke.
I'm rubbish at statistics.
I'm not that kind of historic,
but let's just take the broad brush.
Three quarters or two thirds of them
broke down and never got to the front.
They'd left gaps in the barrage,
the creeping barrage which run forward
in front of the infantry for the tanks
when they weren't there,
the infantry didn't have any artillery
support.
And in front of them they got lost.
They had at the wheels because I thought
they needed wheels at the back to steer
them.
They had no idea how to communicate
between themselves and the infantry when
they go into action.
To be absolutely honest,
there are several,
several historians,
a cynical historically think the tanks
probably killed more British troops in
German troops that day.
Now that is more,
uh,
what we call an outlier.
You know,
it's more just a point,
robin,
the serious remark,
but the point,
what do you have the slightest how to
use the tanks inaction and we didn't
have until home bright now,
which is,
which is a 1978 in 1970 a year and a
couple of months later,
if we'd sent a thousand tanks as they
were on the 15th to September 1916 over
the top,
it would have been.
Sorry.
No,
that's,
that's okay.
And we're getting some glitches on this
end,
which is not wonderful.
Um,
so talk to me,
talk to me a little bit if you could,
about the,
the difference that for years has made
by the time this book that you put out
now.
The last battle is focusing on this.
The governments of all these countries
are fundamentally transformed.
I mean Russia,
imperial,
Russia has gone by this time,
Austria,
Hungary is shattered and looking for a
way out of the war behind the scenes.
You know,
France has endured some serious troop
morale problems in the not too distant
past.
And you know,
that's traditionally like the finest
army in the world and Britain has gone
from the greatest creditor nation to one
that is transferring their debt to New
York.
Now.
What's the difference between the armies
of 1914 in the governments that support
them versus these armies of early 1918
and the governments that support and
direct them?
Well,
the non toll tina armies would have been
recognizable by Napoleon.
The tactics,
the way that we used would have been
recognizable from Napoleon from 100
years before they've got modern weapons,
but they had no idea how to use the
governments were old fashioned
governments.
I mean I know Britain best but so I'll
use him as an example.
Lloyd George is Berry Berry.
Different prep from,
from asquith.
The who led the government asked with is
not particularly competencies.
Apply Towel gentlemen drinks far too
much.
Squiffy asquith.
Lloyd George has many,
many faults.
In fact,
I need a few more men to really
encompasses many faults,
but he is driven and you don't have to
hate Lloyd George just because you like,
hey,
they would chalk and cheese,
but they both did their bit.
Lloyd George was a classic wall leader.
He provided civilian direction.
His idea of what to do with soldiers was
madness and he.
He did not help the direction of the war
on a strategic level,
but on a sort of global level.
He provided the drive,
but Britain was running out of money.
It was running out of resources.
It was running out of troops and and,
and,
and it was running out of time.
The war had to be finished in 18 and
that's one thing that hey,
realized he was desperate to have
finished the war,
not to give the Germans and no other
chance to provide,
to dig another set of trench lines,
shortened perhaps say from
because that's what they really hate and
fear that they have to get them.
The war finished.
Frank,
you had a revolution.
We know that wasn't a revolution in
France.
We know there wasn't one in Britain,
but they could have been and people were
very aware of that.
Um,
those governments that would have made
it into 1919 if the war we're continuing
might've had problems on the allied side
too.
Not just the,
um,
the,
the central powers.
Oh,
absolutely.
Uh,
uh,
wall weariness.
I mean it's just,
you know,
it was an incredible,
uh,
there was no money that now men,
everything's depressed.
It,
it's,
it's just,
you know,
an awful thing to be involved in.
Um,
countries are struggling and we needed
Lloyd George to provide the leadership
at the center and,
and the determination to fight on,
to make sure that the would be beaten.
I mean,
it's so easy just to give up,
uh,
to just say,
well,
we'll come to some compromise,
but the leaders like Lloyd George would
not accept that.
I think that's everything.
I mean,
did I,
is there something about the new book
that I didn't ask you about that,
that is worth pointing out?
I mean,
I,
I'm with you.
I find it not just fascinating,
but it's a little like discovering that
a band and you thought you'd heard every
song from them had a whole bunch of
songs you didn't know about and they're
bigger and more interesting than you
ever knew other than not being able to
pronounce all of the battlefields and
the wonderful.
Isn't that wonderful?
Last push in France.
What about that last book have we not
talked about that you think is.
It is especially compelling.
I'll tell you what the thing for me is
it's an emotional response,
which I think you'll appreciate this.
Just A.
It's the essence of the book.
If you've been fighting for years,
say you're a soldier in those trenches
you've been fighting for for years and
just as start to think it's coming to an
end,
it's come into them and then you.
You have to go forward.
You have to go into the attack and not
everybody do.
You recognize her Second World War.
It's called shell hole.
Drop it.
You can't all drop out.
You know you can't all fall back.
Keep keep behind.
You just have to keep going with your
mates and the temptation to shirk in
those final attacks in the final days
must have been enormous,
but somehow most found from somewhere,
the inner resolve which,
which people are made just can't really
grasp or understand because it's beyond
our experience to finish the job.
Generally.
It was the worst of all for that.
And I'm not just saying this because
you're American.
First of all,
as pershing forced the final attack on
the,
the night of the 10th,
11th,
and even the morning of the 11th and,
and you know,
the Americans had nearly 3000
casualties.
I'm rubbish on that final 24 hours and
just imagine what was going through
their heads when they were told.
I mean the Marines who were told they
had to cross the mers in a lead foot
wide river,
which Germans with machine guns on the
other side and just,
I mean,
what went through their head and that's
the last thing I'd like to say about
just just put yourself there and think
about it.
That's why I liked your book so much
because you do such a great job of
giving me the chance to do that.
Listen,
we'll try to sell you a few books this
time.
I hope you'll come on the next time you
have one and I hope you'll write a bunch
more.
Thank you very much.
I'd love to.
I've really enjoyed it.
Thank you very.
Had a great time with,
like I said,
meeting heroes.
Take care.
And thank you so much.
Que Ca.
So again,
my apologies for the,
uh,
digital glitches there.
Uh,
I will try to figure out a better
method.
I do want to encourage you,
if you are a fan or interested in the
first world war to get Mr Hartz books.
The Great War is absolutely a classic.
Is One on the naval battle of Jutland in
1916.
Follows the same pattern with his,
um,
context punctuated by oral historian
quotes.
It works so well.
Uh,
he wrote one on passion Dale,
um,
which is,
you know,
as you know,
probably awful,
muddy,
horrible,
bloody symbolic of the whole war at that
stage.
And then the new book,
of course,
the last battle,
which focuses on the less well known but
murderous time period in the war and the
phase of the first world war where
everyone got into the trenches and
started moving again and began to take
the kinds of casualties that reminded
them why they first dug into the ground
in the first place.
Now,
as an addendum,
a couple of things worth noting.
First of all,
at the very end of the conversation with
Mr Hart,
he was talking about pershing and he was
saying things like,
you know,
on the 10th or even on the 11th,
he was launching these offensives,
uh,
just a little explanation.
The 10th and the 11th or the November
10th and November,
11th,
19,
18,
the day before and the day of the end of
the war,
the armistice taking effect.
Everybody knew that,
you know,
at this hour on this day,
we're going to stop shooting.
So everybody knew,
okay,
the war ends tomorrow,
or the war ends today.
So how much does it bother you as a
soldier in the trenches?
Well,
maybe not even in the trenches at that
point,
leaning up against a broken down old
French brick house in a ruined French
building behind a tank as you're
prepared to move forward to find out
that your general wants to launch an
offensive that's going to cost a lot of
your lives in the last 24 hours of the
war or something.
So that's what he was talking about.
You might think in your head of reasons
why a general might want to do something
like that and play with your own
motivations for a minute.
Now,
the other thing I wanted to quote was we
had mentioned that in the beginning of
his famous series on the Second World
War,
you can't even call it a history.
You should call it almost like a
personal account from a participant.
Uh,
but Churchill's history of the Second
World War has a wonderful start to at
where he kind of talks about.
He sort of picks up at the end of the
first world war,
which when you think about it,
it's not a bad way to write the
histories.
And he talks about,
you know,
the war ending,
when it did,
and what was going to happen if it
didn't,
right what,
what the plan was for 19,
19,
and of course the war ends in 1918,
right?
But,
but Churchill says,
if 19,
19 happened,
you know,
it was going to unleash terrorists,
unlike any of the world had ever seen
Churchill writes quote.
But all that happened in the four years
of the Great War was only a prelude to
what was preparing for the fifth year.
The campaign of the year in 1919 would
have witnessed an immense,
a session to the powers of destruction
of the Germans retain the morale to make
good their retreat to the Rhine.
They would have been assaulted in the
summer of 1919 with forces and by
methods in comparatively more prodigious
than any yet employed.
Thousands of airplanes would have
shattered their cities.
Scores of thousands of Canon would have
blasted their front arrangements were
being made to carry simultaneously a
quarter of a million men together with
all their requirements continuously
forward across country in mechanical
vehicles moving 10 or 15 miles each day.
Poison gasses of incredible malignity
against which only a secret mask which
the Germans could not obtain in time was
proof,
would have stifled all resistance and
paralyzed all life on the hostile front
subjected to attack,
no doubt the Germans to had their plans,
but the hour of wrath had passed.
The signal of relief was given and the
horrors of 1919 remain buried in the
archives of the great antagonists and
quote,
and it's worth pointing out that even
with the terrible and horrible
destruction of the Second World War,
there were some of the horrors of the
first that we're not revisited,
which seems counterintuitive to human
history,
doesn't it?
This idea that in total war,
human beings would use every single
weapon at their disposal to fend off
total destruction.
Yet those leaders in the Second World
War who themselves were younger people
who fought in the first and we
experienced that somehow managed to not
use poison gas again on a wide scale,
for example.
I don't know what conclusions you can
draw from that,
but it's an interesting variable to
consider,
isn't it?
Finally,
we had mentioned a,
a,
a note specifically that it's stuck in
my mind and it obviously stuck in I'm
Peter Hearts buying to from a soldier
that was writing his turns out to be
last note home to his family and it
exemplifies the way heart tends to work
where he will write a piece that sets up
this emotional,
an exclamation point and then deliver it
to you.
And it just stayed.
We used it blueprint for armageddon
because it is so emotionally powerful.
So here's what heart rights he's talking
about this battle at the song which he
referenced in the interview,
that terrible British day where they've
figured out,
oh my gosh,
you know,
this isn't working the way we thought,
and meanwhile we're trying to figure it
out in the open,
under machine gun fire,
behind a lot of barbed wire.
And he says that the soldiers about to
go on this attack would write these
letters home to their families
and here's what he says.
And then he quotes the powerful letter.
He says,
and this is from his book,
the Great War,
by the way,
quote,
the final reports from the front,
meaning of the Somme battle that
filtered back to the British high
command,
were generally positive in tone.
Overall,
the visual impression of the barrage
proved far more devastating than the
truth on the ground.
British progress had been more than
discounted by German improvements in
their defenses,
but that was not known at the time on
the British side of the wire.
In any case,
they had no choice.
The offensive had to go ahead is the
future of the alliance with France
dependent on it in the last few hours as
Hague's men prepared for the ordeal.
Many wrote their sad last letters.
Home one was so beautifully expressed
that it exemplifies the feelings of men
trapped and tormented by the conflicting
calls of country and family.
Now he's quoting an original letter
quote,
I must not allow myself to dwell on the
personal.
There's no room for it here.
Also,
it is demoralizing,
but I do not want to die.
Not that I mind for myself.
If it'd be that I am to go,
I'm ready,
but the thought that I may never see you
or are darling baby again turns my
bowels to water.
I cannot think of it with even the
semblance of equanimity.
My one constellation is the happiness
that has been ours.
Also,
my conscience is clear that I've always
tried to make life a joy to you.
I know at least that if I go he will not
want.
That is something,
but it is the thought that we may be cut
off from one another which is so
terrible and that our baby may grow up
without my knowing her and without her
knowing me.
It is difficult to face and I know your
life without me would be a dull blank.
You must never let it become holy.
So for two,
you will be left the greatest charge and
all the world,
the upbringing of our baby.
God blessed that child.
She's the hope of life to me.
My darling are for.
It may be that you will only have to
read these lines as one of passing
interest.
On the other hand,
they may well be my last message to you
if they are no throw all your life that
I've loved you and baby with all my
heart and soul that you to sweet things
were just all the world to me.
I pray,
God that I may do my duty for I know
whatever that may entail,
you would not have it otherwise,
and to quote Captain Charles,
May Twenty Second Manchester Regiment
and then Peter Harte writes quote
Charles May,
the loving husband of Bessie Mae and the
father to his baby,
pauline would indeed be killed.
The next day he's buried in the dancing
ally,
British cemetery,
small scale tragedies.
He writes,
litter,
the history of war,
sad reminders that the necessities of
war ruined the lives of millions and the
quote that ladies and gentlemen is an
art form.
My thanks to Peter Hart for talking with
us today and listened down the road.
If we're lucky,
we'll get to do it again.
We've been telling you about audible for
years.
Obviously audio books and a whole lot
more.
If you haven't discovered the joys of
audio books,
there's elements to it that I think are
going to develop that I already find
fascinating.
Take the element of whose voice it is
reading to you,
something you don't consider.
When you think about getting a book.
Is it,
I mean,
who's the narrator?
I imagine one day you're going to be
able to customize this with some sort of
button,
you know,
with your favorite movie star.
I went Michael Caine narrating today's
book and it'll all come out that way,
but I was looking for recommendations
for today's a particular little
discussion.
And uh,
Peter Hart,
who we just talked to has a couple of
books on audible,
but they're narrated by different
people.
And so I'm sampling them going,
okay,
do I want Peter Hart's spoke on the
Somme in this voice.
You're doing what Peter Hearts,
other book on the Somme in other voice.
And it's interesting because it's an
element.
You don't think about this,
a performance aspect to it.
It's one of the things to like about
audio books as you get to Kinda,
you know,
have different people read to you in
different voices,
decide what you like.
And like I said,
some day I imagine this will be quite
customizable.
Audio books of course been around a long
time.
So has auto.
We've been telling you about them for
years.
They've been supporting us.
Um,
and we've watched as they have,
you know,
sort of rolled out more and more
features to what they do.
I mean,
one of the things we've talked about
that's great about audible,
you know,
you sign up to audible,
you get points,
you get a book that's free every month.
I mean it's one of those membership type
services,
but there's things that they just do,
right?
I mean they roll over,
you know,
your points kind of.
So if you don't get a book this month
while those points accrue,
so the,
you know,
you have more next month.
He owned the books,
which I love.
It is so weird to me to purchase
something and then realize,
wait a minute,
if you read the fine print,
you don't.
Actually own this,
you own these books.
If I'm going to buy something like this,
I want to own it.
I need a big selection too,
and audibles got one that carry titles
in business,
the classics,
fiction history,
Romance,
mystery,
thriller,
Sci Fi,
fantasy,
self-development kids,
and yeah,
I mean,
you know like a bookstore,
right?
When I was younger,
if you liked audio books,
you got to go to the library and see
what they had available on cassette
tapes.
Now when a new book comes out and hits
the bookstores,
digital and brick and mortar,
I'm audible usually has the two.
That's a sign of the popularity of these
things and why not?
It allows you to read a good book,
to motivate yourself,
educate yourself,
entertain yourself,
make yourself more successful and
inspired while you're doing some other
chore that Does Not Require Your full
attention.
You got to mow the lawn.
Well,
maybe you can,
you know,
get one of those classic books,
read at the same time,
got an iron sheets.
Well,
why can't you be enjoying a romance
novel at the same time?
You get where I'm coming with this.
Busy people are consuming books at rates
that well when you consider how busy
they are,
they shouldn't be able to find the time
to do that.
Audio books fill a void and audibles the
best place to get them.
And if you sign up today,
you can get a free audiobook with a 30
day trial membership.
Go to audible.com,
forward slash Carlin,
and browse the unmatched selection of
audio programs.
You can download a title,
start listening.
It's that easy.
Go to audible.com,
forward slash Carlin or texts Carlin to
500 dash 500 and get started today.
If you don't know what to get,
I recommend Peter Hearts two books on
the somme.
The newer one probably has more updated
information.
The official title of that is the Psalm,
the darkest hour on the western front,
but he's got an earlier book on the
Somme also on audible,
narrated by an English gentleman.
I believe his name is pronounced.
Uh,
Tim Pickets Smith.
And to me it sounds like Peter Hearts
actually reading the,
the book.
So the newer book probably has the newer
information,
but if you really want to have somebody
reading to you that sounds more like the
author get the earlier book.
The good news is they're both available
on audible and if you can't decide,
feel free to buy them both.
Sure.
They older hardcore history shows can be
a bit traumatic with titles like death
throes of the republic judgment had been
a va and addicted to bondage.
We just consider that truth in
advertising.
No pain,
no gain is our motto.
Pick up the entire catalog from Dan
Carlin.com.
Be sure to follow us on twitter.
The address is at hardcore history.