Which military was superior?
The first world war,
military of the German imperial state
where the Second World War,
military of Nazi Germany.
I know that sounds like a random
question,
but it's actually something that I get
asked about all the time.
All the time.
It's not so random either because these
people are not just asking me that
question out of thin air.
They are asking me to elaborate on a
statement that I once made kind of a
throw away line,
if I'm remembering correctly,
where I had pointed out that I thought
that the first world war,
a German military,
and when we say that we mean the entire
defense apparatus,
right?
The entire structure.
Not the army per se,
not the navy per se,
but all of it put together with the
industry,
the grand strategy,
the.
I mean the states and and armies are
intertwined in ways that are key.
So let's understand that,
but when we compare or when I do compare
the two,
I was comparing the entire structure
against the entire structure.
First World War Germany is military
against Second World War Germany
military.
Now what I was not prepared for was the
fact that this would be so surprising to
so many people and interesting to them
to be honest.
I mean,
like I said,
I've,
I've been asked to elaborate on that
question many times and no one is
argumentative by the way or upset
they're interested.
They're curious and it took me a while
to realize why,
but I think I figured out that it's
because it's counterintuitive.
Most people out there who are not World
War II buffs just assume because my
goodness,
who hasn't heard seen hours of black and
white footage or what have you,
you know,
all the stuff that Nazi Germany was
working on from ballistic missiles to
Panzer divisions to jet aircraft.
I mean,
you know,
there's Nazi scientists are such great
fodder even today that that's why you
have them in all the comic books and the
Red Scout on the captain American.
I mean Odessa said the boys from Brazil.
I mean it goes on and on.
This Nazi science thing is fascinating
and so,
so mid.
You know,
it's not steam punk because it's too
late.
It's whatever.
The mid 20th century version of steam
punk is first World War Germany really
is steam punk.
I guess what I'm trying to say is I
think there's been a lot of hype for
Second World War Germany,
the first World War Germany doesn't get,
and that's what makes it compelling to
hear a different opinion to some people.
Now,
why the heck am I talking about this now
and what?
What are we even doing here towards a
little explanation since this is the
first new podcast we started in more
than a decade and really the first thing
we were going to do is just throw all
this on the history feed,
figuring that it's history,
but you people have taught me a valuable
lesson over time and that's that you
don't want anything that isn't what
you're expecting on that feed.
You may be okay with me interviewing
people,
but you don't want it on your hardcore
history feed when you think you're
getting a hardcore history episodes
downloaded and it turns out to be an
interview.
So we've learned you want something very
specific on the hardcore history,
proper feed.
The problem for us of course,
and maybe you too,
is that we're averaging about two point
five new shows a year on that feed,
which is a long time to be out of touch
with your audience.
So for a very long time we have been
looking for some sort of content,
I guess you could call short form
content.
I'm obviously a long form guy.
Takes me 20 minutes to clear my throat.
As you all know,
originally a long time ago,
the idea of blitz additions which was
supposed to mean short now it just means
a completely different kind of focus on
the show that was supposed to fill this
gap,
didn't work.
We are cutting back and that might be
um,
that might be an optimistic way of even
putting it on the common sense stuff
right now.
So how do you better use the time that,
that would free up?
Well,
how about touching base with the
hardcore history audience?
More than two point five times a year.
So that's what we're trying to do here.
And just so you know,
I couldn't decide on a format because I
liked all of them to a degree,
but I didn't want to get locked into
anything.
I mean,
I like interviews,
but I don't want to have to do them all
the time.
I don't want to do an interview show per
se.
I like doing short little history
things.
If I can manage to do anything short
that don't turn into hardcore history
show,
but I don't want to be responsible for
doing that every time.
Right.
The last thing we want to do is do a new
show that takes away from the old show
that already takes too long to do.
Right?
So we understand the parameters with
which we're working here.
Led Zepplin once said that their format
for their music was tight,
but loose.
That's the way I like to operate to.
Let's say let's have a format where,
you know,
it's our stuff,
right?
We are recognizably us.
But what's you're going to get?
That's anybody's guess.
Um,
this is,
for lack of a better word.
And I still don't know what we're going
to call this.
This is the hardcore history overflow
feed.
This is everything we're not putting in
the regular feed,
whether it's interviews with historians,
biographers,
or maybe historical participants from
time to time.
Love to do some primary source work
where we could record somebody's
memories in digital stone and then maybe
somewhere down the line historian can
mine that for useful info someday.
Be great to contribute to the storehouse
of personal experiences and knowledge.
I do have weird things I'd like to throw
out there.
Sometimes I may love to have a recurring
segment that I call the worst place to
be in the world.
I think it's self explanatory,
but I have a bunch of little things like
that.
Nothing that.
Nothing that I think you could base a
whole podcast series on forever but
enough so maybe we can throw some stuff
out there.
Not,
you know,
we couldn't figure out how to make it
anything but Matt to you when you're
expecting five hours or hardcore history
depth and you get 20 minutes of
scampering over thin ice.
I mean,
is there anything we could do in 20
minutes where you would go,
yeah,
that was great when you were expecting
five hours.
I don't know,
but we feel like if nothing else,
I would love to say hi to you more often
and that's what this is,
so the reason we're talking about the
two World War militaries of Germany and
comparing them is because after the
thousandth person asked me recently to
elaborate on that question,
I was walking away from the discussion
and a person who may or may not be real,
who was with me,
turned to me and said,
why don't you make that a podcast?
Just do a whole show on answering that
question.
Which military was better first or
Second World War Germany?
He goes,
you get asked about it enough.
There's obviously an interest out there.
Why can't that just be a show answered
that question?
Twenty minutes,
25 minutes,
whatever it is.
Boom.
Thrown out on the end,
done right,
said hi to the audience and everything.
I think if we could get one of those out
a month,
wouldn't that fill in the gap a little
bit between epic hardcore history shows,
but I don't know if it's going to
provide anything of venture,
so we're experimenting here a little
bit.
I'd like to answer that question if I
can and maybe this'll be one of the
recurring segments where I essentially
stand up amongst all of you and I make
my case.
I'm not saying I'm right.
I certainly am coming at this from an
angle of a,
this is my opinion,
but let me throw out my viewpoint and
then you can talk amongst yourselves and
decide whether you give it any validity
or not and of course me being me,
I had planned to come in here and just
do it off the off the cuff so it didn't
take any hardcore history recording
time,
but I can't add to pull out the books,
look up some stuff.
I figured who wants to just hear my
opinion?
You've got to have a few supports.
Carlin,
you can't walk in there and just you
know you to.
If you're gonna be a lawyer.
You've got to cite some things,
so I have a few things to site.
Obviously this whole question is a bit
silly and war Gamey,
if you will,
but I like my silly wargame he questions
to be as scientific,
hardheaded,
realistic and logical as possible,
don't you?
So let's lay out some parameters.
The first thing we have to point out is
we are not talking about these two
armies fighting each other,
right?
We all understand how silly that would
be.
It wasn't always silly and I've always
found that interesting up until a
certain point in history,
each not wild to imagine armies that
existed in very different time periods
successfully fighting one.
Another few said Alexander,
the great's army's going to take on
Julius Caesar's.
Romans,
which were about 250 years later.
You don't automatically say Alexander's
doomed.
You Bet your money on Caesar and the
Romans,
but if you said Alexander had a 25
percent chance of winning,
I don't think that's wrong,
but that's 250 years difference in time
by about what would you say,
the mid 19th century,
somewhere that all changes when the pace
of change speeds up and all of a sudden
if you're a great power and you find
your battlefield technology 30,
30,
five years out of date,
you're in big trouble
and by the 20th century you can see this
pace of change acceleration going so
fast that the innovations that occur
inside of a war can win or lose you.
The war.
I think you most clearly see this for
the first time in the air war in the
first world war where if you get a leap
in terms of a technological innovation
for airplanes ahead of the other side
and you get your planes in the air,
it could be six months of owning the sky
before the other side catches up and in
certain circumstances that could cost
you the war.
So this technological race is getting so
fast.
We end up,
certainly by the early 20th century with
the
dynamic that we see all the time now and
that we're very comfortable with the
idea of innovation happening all the
time during the war and the Second World
War all you second world war buffs.
I mean,
how often do you think of which
particular variant of this particular
plane is this an emi one?
Oh,
nine e or g because it makes a huge
difference.
Right?
Why?
Because the pace of change will
literally when you were lose you the war
by about the first or Second World War.
So we're not comparing these two armies
against each other because even the 1918
version of the German army,
which is really an Alpha or a Beta
version of the wehrmacht and yet it
ain't facing the Wehrmacht successfully
at all and it's only a 20 year
difference between the two.
So we're not pitting them against each
other.
We're petting them,
you know,
on a curve based on their historical
enemies.
And that point I made a second ago I
think is very relevant.
Only 20 years between each other.
When you're 20 years old,
that seems like a long time,
but when you get to 50,
like I am,
50 1:20
years looks short.
As one historian said,
20 years is not peace.
It's an intermission.
I had a air force colonel I grew up next
door to.
He always said it was the equivalent of
reloading.
It always boggles the mind a little bit
to realize how quickly the Germans were
moving to get around the treaty
restrictions.
I mean some historians have pushed it
all the way back to like 19,
19,
which if true would mean that the seeds
of rearmament we're already being sown
as the agreement to end.
The first World War was being concluded.
That's wild.
You all know that there were things
going on in the Soviet Union where they
had hidden deals to develop weapons
systems and tactics and factories and
all that stuff on Russian soil hidden
from the prying eyes of the people who
would enforce these treaties.
The German attitude would probably be
that the treaties were forced upon
Germany under false pretenses.
I mean,
there's a lot of criticism you can make
against those versailles,
treaty restrictions.
In fact,
the allies,
you know,
before Hitler came to power,
there were lots of negotiations about
cutting slack on some of this stuff
later.
Nonetheless,
the point is,
is that long before Hitler was in
anybody's rearview mirror,
even in the Weimar Republic,
early days,
you know,
you already an attempt to rearm Germany
or set the groundwork,
laid the groundwork for rearmament and
it provides an interesting what if
scenario to wonder if Hitler had never
come to power?
How much of his early agenda happens
under any German government?
I mean,
in my mind,
it's hard to imagine any German
government not eventually remilitarizing
the land,
you know,
even if you're a Weimar republic
democratic ones.
So it's interesting to wonder about the
early stuff that Hitler did and whether
a Weimar Republic might've done it too.
And it's also intriguing to note,
you know,
that long before Hitler,
the foundation was being laid for the
rebuilding of the German military.
For those who don't know,
the German military at the end of the
first world war was essentially I'm torn
apart.
An army that had numbered in the several
millions at one point in the field was
reduced to 100,000
men,
a one person at the time called them a
police force.
Paramilitary is the way there somehow
described now,
which basically means something between
a police force and a soldier,
100,000
men,
their neighbors all had many more.
All kinds of weapons systems are
prohibited.
The reason all this stuff matters is
because in this short period of time
between the two world wars,
the Germans have to recreate an army
from scratch and they can't even really
get going until the Middle Nineteen
thirties.
So how deep do the roots of this thing
go?
Even if you attach it to the earlier
military traditions when you compare it
to the first World War German state,
which has these deep old roots and they
can trace it to to before Germany was a
state with the histories of several
different individual German states like
Prussia in Bavaria and all these places.
The first World War German state is one,
you're like a bodybuilder who's been
eating right and building themselves up
slowly but surely the one in the second
world war as somebody who had to go
heavily into steroids because of a
terrible injury and they come into the
war looking pumped up and initially
doing good,
but when you know something that was
supposed to be an easy knockout,
turns into a slug fest.
If you had the legs to weather the storm
into the later rounds,
you know I can't help but use the boxing
analogies.
Can I?
And in that sense,
you'd have to say that both of these
armies,
the first and Second World War German
armies are big punchers knockout
artists.
But the Second World War One is like
Mike Tyson,
malevolent,
intimidating,
awesome throws.
These knockout blows,
knockout,
knockout people spectacularly.
Can't take your eyes off him,
but foundationally week maybe psyche
stamina,
all those things.
First World War Germany a little bit
more controlled,
although they're a big gambling army
too.
They remind me a lot more.
Have a boxer like Joe Lewis,
the heavyweight champion of the world in
the 19 thirties,
19 forties,
and end of the 19 fifties.
Louis was a fantastic puncher to a
killer,
but a little bit more defensive,
more careful plotting was the way
Muhammad Ali described him,
but that's a little unfair,
but they're not as wild as the second
world war.
Tyson ask one.
They too can knock out opponents and
they do with regularity in the first
world war,
but the difference is is that their
foundation is much more solid.
They're much more stable and they can
take you into the later rounds and knock
you out.
Remember the Second World War was
essentially over in terms of knowing the
outcome by about mid 1943.
That's two years before the war against
Germany ended,
but everyone knew the Germans weren't
winning anything two years earlier,
so Tyson is defeated.
It just is uncertain which round he will
actually be knocked out in.
Whereas in the first world war,
you know the Joe Lewis First World War,
German military is still throwing
potential knockout blows in the last
year of the war.
I don't know what value I put on this,
but let's note that the German army that
went to war in 1914 is an undefeated
force and going back almost to Napoleon
they trace and almost unbroken string of
victories.
Whereas the army in the second world war
is literally and figuratively the child
of defeat,
the rank and file soldiers likely to
have had a father who fought,
maybe died,
maybe grievously wounded in the first
world war,
the upper echelons of the officer corps,
uh,
almost to a man first world war
veterans.
And of course the totalitarian leader at
the apex of the leadership pyramid.
Hitler himself was a corporal in the
trenches.
How much did that defeat and seeing what
they saw in that war changed them?
I don't know that you could ever put a
number on it.
I will just say if you have to boxing
champions facing each other and one is
undefeated and the other,
isn't there something that helps the
undefeated fighter?
It may be different person to person and
I couldn't tell you how much and in what
way,
but everyone notices it and acknowledges
it.
I would say the same is true here,
but that's hard to make a case if I'm
standing up here as a lawyer
representing this point of view,
so let me represented in a way that
maybe I can pull some evidence together
and convince you.
Let's start with the army's themselves
as opposed to the navy's the air forces
in the rest.
Both these armies were very similar to
each other,
so you have to kind of compare the
things that are different about them.
Both of these armies have at core,
the magnificent German fighting soldier
at the squad level,
trying to figure out what makes them as
good as they are.
A very hard to measure.
I remember Neil Ferguson in his book,
a pity of war,
tries to break it down to some sort of
chart,
you know,
how much more deadly are the German
soldiers then,
you know,
soldiery of other countries.
But remember,
it's a lot of things working together.
Uh,
and a lot of things that the German
military had been good at for a long
time.
Discipline,
drill,
obedience,
tactical efficiency coordination between
various arms,
et Cetera,
et cetera.
The same adjectives that are used about
the German soldiers in both world wars
are adjectives that are used to describe
Frederick degrades mid 18th century,
Prussian troops and the and the German
military tradition of both world wars is
one that can be traced back easily to
Frederick,
the grades,
Prussia,
some people like to go a lot earlier
than that,
but it's easy to look at the military
traditions of of 18th century Prussia
and see those infused into 20th century
German armies and so they're comparable
at the soldier level.
There are also comparable in terms of
their tactical equipment.
I mean you look at like,
okay,
what were the rifles like?
What were the machine gun?
All this stuff is predictably very good
in the German army.
The artillery was good.
All these things are pretty much the
same.
So when you try to figure out what would
make one less strong than the other,
you look at the underpinnings and in
this case,
I try to imagine the German army in the
Second World War without Nazis.
If you take the Nazis out of the Second
World War,
German army,
it instantly gets better.
Then I think you could compare the two.
I still think I'd go first world war
better because of the underpinnings of
the state being much more old and strong
like a well constructed building.
You know,
whatever happens.
The Second World War,
German military is a rickety,
hastily thrown up structure.
If you're talking about the economy that
supports it,
every World War II buff knows that the
people who were trying to build up the
stockpile of weaponry and whatnot did
not want to go to war.
As early as 1939,
Adam two's points out the economic
realities that made Hitler decided not
to wait until the equipment and all that
was ready for that good reasoning of
both sides.
Believe it or not,
but I'm going to hang my hat on the idea
that the fact that the Second World War
German military is infested and run by
Nazis is what makes it inferior to the
first world war military.
So let's start with why this would
matter at all.
And the basic answer that covers most of
these bases is that the ideological
question now becomes at least as
important,
and I think you can easily make the
argument more important than the
question of merit
or technical expertise.
Once ideology becomes more important
than merit,
and once the Nazis begin to place people
in positions all up and down the
leadership tree from top to bottom,
just like Stalin did in his system,
then you begin to see the impact of
people that are less competent on the
system.
People that never would have gotten jobs
in first World War Germany because there
would have been much better than they to
occupy those positions are getting work
in Second World War Germany and it
degrades everything.
In fact,
let's look at the guy.
To me this.
This is the person who proves the rule.
He's just maybe the highest ranking
competent official,
unless of course you include Hitler
himself.
There are still,
by the way,
those people who consider Hitler some
sort of military genius.
I would make the case,
and maybe this is a question for another
show that if you had Hitler transported
back to the deliberations of the first
World War German general staff and
there's only 20 people that can fit in
the room.
They're having this discussion in and
they're only going to let the 20 best
strategist in the room.
I don't think Hitler gets anywhere near
the front of the line to even get in the
room.
But let's not talk about him.
Let's talk about his second in command.
A guy who is.
He's in charge of,
maybe you could say the most
disappointing underperforming wing of
the German military and the one that
probably was most responsible for a lot
of the problems because you know,
they put a lot of weight and a lot of
resources into the German air force and
then they handed those resources,
that responsibility and the weight of
the war in so many areas and put it on
the shoulders of Hermann goring.
A guy who was so incompetent at his job
at one point that if you were sending
out commandos from the allied side,
hit teams to take out German leadership,
you would specifically want to make sure
you did not shoot Hermann goring because
he's one of the best things that ever
happened to the allied war effort
because he was incompetent and he would
not have had that job in the first world
war system.
Now let's understand something.
The first world war system had it's own
problem with nepotism,
were not forgiving them.
They're part of that tradition of blue
blooded aristocracy.
Right?
And you'll look at the nominal
commanders have a lot of the first world
war armies on the German side and their
prints this and crown prince that and
some of those guys were decent generals
by the way,
but you'll notice that for the ones who
weren't,
the German military was extremely adept
at walling off their ability to
negatively impact things too much.
And the best example of that,
of course at all,
is how the military dictatorship of
Germany were able to sort of isolate and
quarantine the Kaiser himself,
the imperial war,
Lord of Germany,
or you know,
sit in the corner,
play with your maps and your ships.
We have a war to conduct and they did.
Who's going to do that in the Second
World War?
Who's going to coordinate off Hitler and
Quarantine Hitler from his bad decisions
being transmitted to the military?
Nobody.
Because it's an ideological state and
the ideology plays as larger role or a
larger role in everything.
And ideology by the way,
is absolutely key for understanding the
Second World War at all.
Adam two's,
the wonderful economic historian,
makes these wonderful points in his
book,
and I'll have to quote a little bit of
it,
but he points out essentially.
And it occurred to me when I read the
lines,
I'm like,
oh,
this is wild.
Basically my words put in his mouth,
you know,
it's the question is what would happen
if a major nation state got taken over
by a,
by a leader who was a fanatical
conspiracy theorist.
And saw the world strictly through their
conspiracy lens and then acted upon.
You know,
what they thought they saw.
For example,
let's imagine that the person running a
major nation state believes that aliens
from outer space had been controlling
nations and world leaders for 100 years.
And when they get into power and they
start acting as if that's what's really
going on,
right?
We don't base our decisions on what
these countries say.
They're puppets for the aliens.
It's Kooky,
isn't it?
But you know,
to reminded me something we all know,
but we tend to forget,
especially we war gamers will sit down
there and we're thinking about this tank
and that gun and you forget the ideology
that that's pushing these armies forward
to begin with.
Hitler is a fanatical conspiracy
theorist,
but he's not thinking of space aliens.
He's thinking of Jews running the world.
And there's a tendency to think yes
asked,
she asked,
but you know,
these other things matter until you
realize that,
and this is what was so good at in his
2006 work,
the wages of destruction.
I mean,
you have to understand that it explained
so much of the crazy stuff that they did
because when I was growing up,
this was still the end of the era.
We're in the United States.
The classic thing to say about Hitler
was that he was crazy and then you'd
read about what they would do and they
would go,
yeah,
that's crazy.
Only crazy man would do that.
Well,
two's points out that only if you
consider these fanatical conspiracy
theorists to be crazy,
would that work?
Because Hitler's got a logical plan and
is actually acting logically,
but only if you're able to see things
through that same fanatical conspiracy
theorist lens he's looking at,
for example,
the classic stupid maneuver of the
Hitlarian regime in the Second World
War.
Was there anything worse?
Everybody always likes to say attacking
Russia,
which was bad,
but remember when Hitler was already at
war with Britain and Russia,
he then declared war on the United
States.
The United States didn't declare war on
Germany first and there's a great.
What if scenario that some people play
with about what would have happened if
Hitler hadn't declared war on the United
States at all because there was still a
lot of isolationist in the US.
A lot of people that would not have
wanted to go to war with Germany would
have been able say,
hey,
they didn't do anything to us or at the
Japanese bombed us,
but the Germans didn't.
Interesting counterfactual to play with
their kettler takes it right out of
everyone's hands and declares war on the
United States,
and when I was younger,
you just thought crazy,
but his points out,
Adam points out that not if you see the
world controlled by a cabal of Jews who
use whole nation states is they're
puppets to do their bidding.
One of the great,
weird ironies of Nazi-ism is that Hitler
saw Stalin's Soviet Union as a Jewish
Bolshevik Communist.
In his mind,
communism is Judaism.
They're mixed up.
I mean,
it's all the same,
right?
So that's a main Jewish stronghold to
Hitler.
But Hitler also thinks that the United
States,
because it's democracy and freedom and
capitalism,
is also somehow a sign of Jewishness,
that that's also another one of these
Jewish puppets.
If you're fighting Jews and not nation
states will then declaring war on the
United States if you think they're this
Jewish puppet all of a sudden makes
sense.
And what two's kind of woke me up to is
that if you're operating with this
conspiracy theory as your guide,
yeah,
the United States is just another one of
these alien controlled countries that
the space aliens are using against us.
You might as well go after him.
Now,
here's the way Adam two's encourages us
to think about,
you know,
the way that these Nazis worldview
explains a lot
quote,
President Roosevelt was identified as
the chief agent of a worldwide Jewish
conspiracy bent on the destruction of
national socialist Germany.
It was no coincidence that Hitler's
famous threat of annihilation of 30th
January 1939 came as a direct response
to Roosevelt state of the Union address.
The United States,
as everyone understood,
was the key to deciding the balance of
the arms race.
It Britain and France could count firmly
on American aid.
Their position would be well nigh
unassailable,
but the position of the United States
was precariously balanced.
Whilst Roosevelt led the rhetorical
assault against Hitler and encouraged
Britain,
France,
and Poland in their resistance to Nazi
expansionism isolationist currents in
the United States.
We're still strong.
Hitler in the rest of the Nazi
leadership.
He writes,
could not help but interpret this
complex situation through the dark haze
of Manichaean antisemitism.
For them,
it was obvious that it was Jewish
elements in Washington,
London and Paris bent implacably on the
destruction of Nazi Germany,
that we're tightening the international
encirclement and it was this paranoid
sense of menace that precipitated
Hitler's decision to launch a strike
against Poland and then against the
Western coalition that continued to
stand obstinately in his way and quote,
if you wanted to say,
you know what?
The Germans in both world wars did
poorly because they were tactically.
Most of the time it was the grand
strategy stuff.
It was deciding for example,
which countries to go to war with and
which wars to fight or not to fight.
That they really screwed up in and in
the Second World War,
the reason for declaring wars and
accruing more and more enemies was
ideologically based.
Right?
So the doom of the German military,
no matter how good it might have been on
the battlefield,
was sealed by the politicians who put
them in wars that no one could hope to
win,
but that's getting a little off the
subject.
Let's talk about how the Nazis made the
German army weaker in the Second World
War and the difference that you would
have had in a system like the first
World War Germany,
that was more merit based.
You can't say it was merit based,
but more merit based.
Start with the idea that you have all
these Nazis in key positions that are
incompetent or untrained or non expert.
This is not,
by the way a bug.
This is a feature as Hitler sees it.
There are lots of critiques.
One could pull off the shelf.
How about,
and again,
all of these people have access to
grind,
so take everything that these ex Nazi
people,
right?
With a grain of salt,
but in his famous book,
inside the Third Reich,
which may be,
I'm not sure,
maybe the closest account you'll ever
get of the Nazi situation
originally his architect,
but then the minister of armaments,
Albert Speer wrote his memoirs after the
war and when you read them,
he'll say things.
It's like reading churchill stuff
because instead of saying they said,
and then they said it's,
I said,
and then he said,
and a lot of the he says is Hitler.
Um,
so in Albert speer,
his book,
he talks about Hitler's tendency to put
people in positions of authority and
great importance in the survival of the
state who had never done anything like
what their jobs were going to require in
the past,
including spear himself.
Right?
A guy who had become Hitler's friend
because he was an architect who was
going to design Hitler's new Berlin.
And Hitler takes a liking to him and all
of a sudden tells the architect,
yeah,
you're going to be the,
uh,
the armaments minister with no
experience at all.
Here's the way spirit described it.
Quote one can only wonder at the
recklessness and the frivolity with
which Hitler appointed me to one of
those three or four ministries on which
the existence of estate depended.
I was a complete outsider to the army,
to the party,
and to industry,
never in my life had anything to do with
military weapons,
for.
I'd never been a soldier.
And up to the time of my appointment had
never even used a rifle as a hunter to
be sure it was in keeping with Hitler's
dilettantism that he preferred to choose
nonspecialists as his associates.
After all,
he'd already appointed a wine salesmen,
as his foreign minister is party
philosopher as,
as minister for eastern affairs and an
erstwhile fighter pilot as overseer of
the entire economy.
Now,
he was picking an of all people to be
his minister of armaments.
Undoubtedly Hitler preferred to fill
positions of leadership with layman all
his life.
He'd respected but distrusted
professionals.
And to quote any names or professional
how marsh locked,
who was fantastic.
And,
um,
a perfect example of the kinds of
people,
um,
that were merit based.
Now,
the perfect example that should prove
the rule of what a spear was just saying
was the guy who was second in command in
the Nazi regime,
the famous Hermann goring,
head of the Luftwaffe,
a right,
arguably the most underperforming branch
of the German military
goring story of course,
is fascinating.
He was a dashing,
handsome fighter pilot in the first
World War,
shall we say,
gone to seed by the second between the
wars.
He was one of Hitler's comrades,
took a bullet in the groin area during
the early Nazi marches.
The pain of that was what was blamed on
him becoming a morphine opioid addict.
And,
um,
I love the way,
uh,
the great tank General Hind Scuderi in
describes a goring.
You have to understand another thing
that made that the Nazi state so much
weaker,
I think,
than the first World War state is the
Nazi state was full of,
of the most.
I mean,
it was like,
you know,
if Hitler is Taylor Swift,
sorry,
Taylor Swift,
uh,
his,
his little gang,
his entourage,
we were a bunch of backbiting.
I you can't even describe the drama,
but hind spewed Arion describes goring
and he's just the most one.
The Nazis are the most in the 20th
century.
Perverse,
wonderful,
colorful,
awful.
I mean you can't even the adjectives are
not even there.
Here's what hines good Erin writes
about,
goring who's in charge of the German air
force,
the arm that is receiving an inordinate
amount of the state's resources because
it's seen as this cutting edge thing
that can win you the war and then it's
going to underperform time and time
again.
Here's what one of the great tank
theorists of all time,
General Heinz good area and wrote in
this post war memoirs of Goring,
and you can just feel,
well,
I'm not even sure what the emotion is.
It's dripping off the page.
You tell me.
He writes,
quote,
once,
however goring had seen the young German
air force through its teething troubles,
he surrendered more and more to the
charms of newly one power.
He adopted a futile manner of life,
collecting decorations,
precious stones and antiques,
building his famous country seat Karen
Hall,
concentrating with visible results on
the joys of the table.
That just means he's getting fat.
He continues on one occasion while sunk
in contemplation of old pictures in an
east,
Prussia and castle,
he suddenly cried out.
This is goring magnificent.
I too am a man of the renaissance.
I adore splendor,
good area,
and continues quote.
His style of dress grew ever more
eccentric at Karen Hall or while
hunting,
he adopted the costume of the ancient
two tons and went on duty.
His uniform was always unorthodox.
He either wore red boots of Russian
leather with Golden Spurs,
an item of dress scarcely essential to
an aviator or else he would appear at
Hitler's conferences in long trousers
and black patent leather pumps.
He was strongly scented and he painted
his face.
His fingers were covered with heavy
rings in which were set the many large
gems that he loved to display and quote
Kadarian taking a shot at going there
for a perhaps a little cross dressing
goes a little beyond the metrosexual
probably,
but at the same time,
you know,
that's just one of the wonderful
hypocrisy of the Nazis is that they
always had a strain of people doing
things like that and there's nothing
wrong with that unless of course you
hypocritically make them one of the top
targets that you send to your
concentration camps.
The Nazis were extremely hard on sexual
minorities and the fact that they have
people in them that probably could have
passed for some just makes it extra,
as I said,
hypocritical.
Now once again,
you think,
well,
what does this have to do with the army?
Right?
This isn't a guy in the field with the
weapon,
but it is.
They're all interconnected in ways that
you can't separate.
So for example,
when Albert speer gives an account of
Hermann goring shouting down a German
general who was explaining to him really
important things that will affect what
happens to the German army,
which will affect what happens on the
battlefield.
Spear writes,
quote,
I took part in a session with goring in
the course of which General Thomas
expressed his anxieties about the vast
demands the leadership was making upon
the economy.
Goring answered the respected general by
roaring Adam quote,
what business is that of yours?
I'm handling that I am.
Do you hear or are you by any chance in
charge of the four year plan you have
nothing to say in this matter.
The fewer has entrusted all those
questions to me alone.
End Quote.
Spear says,
quote in such disputes,
General Thomas could expect no support
from his chief General Keitel,
who was only too glad to escape being
bullied by goring.
The well-conceived economic plan of the
Armaments Office of the High Command of
the armed forces was never carried out.
But as I had already realized by the
end,
goring did nothing about these problems.
Whenever he did do anything,
he usually created total confusion since
he never took the trouble to work
through the problems,
but made his decisions on the basis of
impulsive inspirations and quote
goring's one of these guys,
and you see this amongst a lot of the
Nazi officials were theoretically on
paper.
Goring is not a bad guy to run the air
force.
I mean with his qualifications.
The problem is,
is those qualifications were created at
a time when goring was a different guy.
He's a hardcore addict by this time,
and his decisions concerning the
Luftwaffe,
uh,
are catastrophic if you're German mixed
in with these Nazi officials put in
place,
even in the army for ideological reasons
are hardcore professional merit based
people in all these services who are
horrified when his generals helmet,
forester set of goring quote.
I've seen the Reich's Marshall not off
in mid conference.
For instance,
if the conferences went on too long and
the morphine wore off,
that was the commander in chief of our
air force exclamation point.
End Quote.
So imagine this goring question up and
down the chain of command and how much
that affects everything.
And if you took those Nazi officials out
and put people that were more merit
based,
let's not get utopian here from the
first world war sort of standards,
you'd have a better army in the Second
World War in my opinion.
So let's discuss some of the other
things besides the Merritt question that
play into this.
In my opinion,
as I'm making my case here,
the Nazi ideology of racial exclusion
and superiority makes the army weaker.
If you go to or some of the German
graveyards from the first World War in
France,
you will come across a every now and
then,
but with regularity,
a German grave that has a star of David
on it.
The reasons are obvious,
right?
That is a German Jew who fell in service
to his country,
a patriotic Germans.
You have the time period.
They were everywhere from the rank and
file soldiery to the,
uh,
scientist bankers,
industrialists,
business people.
Uh,
it's,
it's a long list of people who helped
the German war effort in the first world
war as loyal Germans,
you know,
to the Kaiser,
the Nazi ideology,
of course,
turns the state against those people.
And whereas you had good Germans helping
the state,
now you have an enemy within the first
thing that happens of course,
as you see a brain drain,
and Albert Einstein will be just one of
the people who leaves Germany as times
get tough.
He will famously come over to the United
States,
send that letter to President Roosevelt
saying it might be possible to harness
the power of the atom,
blah,
blah.
Right?
In the first world war,
Albert Einstein stays in Germany and
worked his physics calculations for the
Kaiser's regime.
Likely.
Anyway.
Not only that,
but now you have this people who
would've been helping the war effort
that now you have to figure out how to
at first get rid of.
And there was a balance of payment
problems that was complicating matters.
But by and large,
it just basically means at some point in
the war,
you look at a Germany that really,
really,
really needs to allocate its resources
carefully and wisely and yet because of
their ideology,
have to apportion a certain amount to
wiping out this ethnic group.
Well,
one of many,
but the Jews most prominently.
And you had your Gypsies and you had
your poles and you had your Russians and
you had your.
I mean,
the list goes on and on and you had your
homosexuals,
you had your priest and all of them have
to be warehoused and exploited and then
killed.
And I mean that takes resources from the
war effort and why are they doing that
again?
Oh yeah.
Ideology.
Let's switch to what the ideology means
in terms of your commanders.
Both World War saw the traditional high
standards of German general ship upheld
great generals in both wars,
but in the first world war,
once again,
if you did a good job commanding troops
and you were a winner,
you were commanding troops
in the Second World War.
How much the Nazis like you or feel that
you are loyal to them plays a part in
whether or not you get an important
role.
There were guys like Gudera and who we
just quoted that were sometimes
sidelined because they weren't
ideologically supportive or pure enough.
And of course,
I mean,
we all know that a decent number of
German generals were killed by the
regime,
the Desert Fox,
or when Rama,
one of their great ones,
right?
Patent thought he was one of the best
ever.
What did they do to him?
They forced him to commit suicide.
Why?
Ideological problems again?
So not only is it not merit based in
some ways,
but if the people who do deserve those
jobs don't conform to the ideology
enough,
they're gone too.
That's another thing that's going to
make the first World War German military
better than the second.
Let's talk economics for a second.
Without getting too deeply into it,
you wouldn't want me to.
Anyway,
that's where I'll start making some
mistakes.
But by and large,
the Nazis had their own theories on
economics.
And this is well understood.
In the first world war,
they were more,
shall we say,
Orthodox on their economics.
The Germans were very much in the second
world war and we described steroids
earlier.
That's not a bad way to put it.
Uh,
leveraging their economy for the short
term is another way to put it.
It's another reason why they were more
like Mike Tyson and they're front
loading their power and if the fight
goes into the later rounds,
they in trouble and it did,
and they were in the first world war
with a better understanding of
economics,
smarter people at the helm who were not
blinded by ideology.
They did better with what they had
longer.
Finally,
you look at how the ideology boxed the
German government in the Second World
War from any sort of outcome that wasn't
a total catastrophe.
Take a look at the performances of the
two armies and what they did right?
The German army from the first world war
from the Kaiser.
Those guys are fighting a two front war
from day one.
The worst nightmare of any central
continental state,
right?
You have Russians in the east,
French and British in the West.
How do you deal with that?
Year by year,
the Germans in the first world war went
around knocking out their enemies.
I mean,
they knocked Russia out of the war.
How'd they do that?
Well,
their plan was to hurt them and then go
and get a settlement with them and take
as much of a deal as they could get.
Right?
They got one of the great treaties of
all time.
Breslow task right?
Famously in Germany's favor.
Why in Germany of the Second World War
do that?
I mean they had a lot more going for
them.
They didn't have to fight a two front
war until 1943.
You're knock France out,
which they did with a Mike Tyson like
spectacular knockout.
You're not fighting in any front war for
a while.
Then you fight the Soviet Union without
having to worry about anyone on your
western flank there on the continent.
Perfect situation.
But by 1942 perhaps maybe 19,
43,
you've lost on the eastern front and the
second front is just opening up in
Europe,
in Italy.
So you say,
well,
why did the Germans cut their losses?
When you have all this territory in the
Soviet Union?
Well,
in the first world war,
that's when you make a deal,
right?
You'd go to the Russians and you go,
listen,
we all this territory of yours and we're
going to stay here,
but I'll tell you what,
you give us a good peace deal.
We'll pull back a little.
You know,
you can negotiate from that,
right?
But the Nazis were hemmed in by their
ideology.
They can't make a deal here.
This isn't a battle,
you know,
for the best deal we can get.
This is in Hitler's mind,
a life or death struggle.
The plans that the Nazi leaders have for
this area in the east requires them to
move millions of people eastward,
maybe have a starvation plan to start
calling the numbers and then inserting
German farmers into this whole.
I mean,
the entire thing.
There is no plan b here.
There is no place for compromise and
what's more,
the extreme brutality,
Nazi racial superiority and the
ideology,
um,
that pushed for a brutal campaign in the
east pretty much made the people on the
other side in no mood to be cutting any
deals with anyone.
Once again,
didn't have to be that way.
The German military is always tough on
people throughout history,
right?
Remember Belgium in 1914,
you know they're,
they're.
They're not a lightweight army when it
comes to justice ever,
but the crimes of the Nazis,
because of the ideological question were
so much greater that there was nobody
willing to compromise,
so my opinion,
you take the Nazis,
you pry the infestation out of the
German military and all the influence
that had had over the equipment,
tactics,
doctrine,
strategy and approach of the German
military,
and you instantly get stronger.
You put the World War leadership and
ideology.
You know what?
There was,
it was an aristocratic kind of an
ideology in 19th century ideology,
but you put that in charge of the Second
World War German army and I bet it's
better.
Let me end my attempt at making a case
here by once again,
turning to General Heinz Kadarian who
was not afraid to go up to Hitler and
ask the kinds of questions that might
get some people you know,
hanging from the end of a meat hook.
So it pretty gutsy.
But of course,
we don't know if this really happened or
not,
this is a man's memoirs,
but he says that after he watched Hitler
basically yell in the face of goring
that he was a disaster,
good area,
and walks up to him and says,
so why is he still here?
He writes,
quote,
as a result of this conversation,
meaning the dressing down of Hermann
goring,
I urged Hitler to act according to what
he now realized,
and to appoint some competent air force
general just exceed the Reich's
Marshall.
I told him that we dare not risk losing
the whole war on account of the
incompetence of one man like goring,
but Hitler replied,
and this is Hitler talking,
and he's showing why the ideology
trump's merit.
Hitler,
according to God's Marion said,
quote,
for political reasons I cannot do as you
suggest,
the party would never understand my
motives and quote.
So if you can't fire Hermann goring in
1944 near the end of the war for
political reasons,
well that might explain why your
military is less formidable than the
first world war military right there.
Remember,
we didn't even mention the goring isn't
just in charge of the German air force.
He's in charge of the German economy.
When the four year plans going on,
you could make an argument that at least
goring has a background in fighter
aircraft and all that stuff because he
did,
but why would you put that guy in charge
of the German economy and who is good
enough even among the uber competent to
be in charge of both,
and of course we only chose Hermann
goring because he's the most obvious
target,
the tip of the iceberg.
The Nazis had people like this up and
down as we said,
the leadership chain mixed with a lot of
uber competent people.
We should point that out.
Otherwise the Germans are not as
formidable as they were in the Second
World War.
Lots of traditional German competency.
That's why I compare these Nazis to
their war effort,
like like some sort of parasite
infestation,
sucking some of the blood of competency
out of them,
leaving them still very competent but
weaker than they otherwise would be
compared,
for example,
in my opinion,
to their first world war version.
Now in my account for brevity's sake,
not really my strong point,
as you know,
I left out a lot of stuff.
We didn't even deal with things like the
navy,
you know,
in comparison,
first world war,
German navy,
second most powerful navy in the world,
Second World War,
German navy,
nowhere near that.
I mean there's no comparison there.
And the air force,
I mean,
let's remember to get back to goring
again.
This is an air force that continually
delayed the influx of new equipment in
terms of new designs,
which as we pointed out earlier,
is critical,
right?
The technology changes during the war
itself because they're changing things
like,
well,
do we want this new jet to be a fighter
or a bomber or a fighter,
but I mean back and forth and every time
they changed their mind as they lose
months and months of production time
could have had jet aircraft years
earlier,
perhaps goring's the guy who told Hitler
to have his army stop and not annihilate
the British who,
who were trapped did dunkirk in 1940
because the luftwaffe a wood finish them
off.
They didn't goring's the guy that said
he could supply the encircled German
troops of Stalin Grad.
Don't worry,
we'll do it by air.
Couldn't.
And you said you can't fire him in 1944.
Well,
to me,
in my opinion,
as I said,
that is exhibit a right there,
that the German first world war military
would have been in more formidable
opponent to face in its day.
Then the Second World War German
military was in its day.