What you're about to hear is part three
of a multipart series on the first world
war.
If you're one of those individual that
likes to know the story before the
story,
you might want to catch up on those if
you missed either one of them,
although some of you probably don't mind
just being dropped into the middle of a
story like you arrived in the time
machine and you have to figure things
out.
If you're one of those kind of
individuals,
you know who cares about those earlier
two shows,
why don't you just jump on in and
joining the horror in progress with
blueprint for Armageddon,
part three,
some bus seven,
19,
41 date which will live in infamy.
Each one,
the events
that dude,
the figure is going to the lead on this
time and place.
I take pride in the words the Alina tear
down.
Wow.
Complete.
Hi,
welcome.
This kind of examination because people
have got to know whether or not their
question,
well,
I'm not a crop.
If we dig deep in our district and our
doctors and remember we are not
descended from fearful.
Man.
It's hardcore history.
The very same week that the first world
war breaks out,
August 19,
14,
a British expedition leaves British
waters and heads for the South Pole.
Antarctica led by a guy named Ernest
Shackleton.
Shackleton is one of the people that's
normally associated with the very tail
end of what's called the age of
discovery,
the age of exploration,
and you know what's the tail end?
Because you know,
unlike guys like Christopher Columbus,
Shackleton and his crew have cameras.
Nineteen 14,
you bring a camera with you and he's
able to document in photographs.
Real clear,
interesting photographs.
This ordeal that he's about to
experience as he's on his way to
Antarctica,
he's keeping tabs on this war that's
broken out right when he left.
I mean this is the first real period of
globalization and the world and he can
keep track via telegraph of the sort of
major events that are going on
and like everyone.
Shackleton is appalled by the scale.
You can't believe the amount of
casualties,
the number of people,
the challenges involved in logistics.
It feels like this flame that is burning
at an unbelievable intensity.
So everybody just assumed that couldn't
continue very long.
That had been the assumption even before
the war broke out.
The Kaiser famously says to his
departing troops,
you'll be home before the leaves fall.
When the French military leader Joseph
offer is told that his troops should be
issued metal helmets to replace those
cloth hats that they're starting the war
with.
He says,
don't bother.
They'll never reach the troops before
the war is over.
So there's this real feeling that
something that's operating at that level
of intensity can't continue for very
long before shackleton gets to find out
how the whole thing ends,
though he in his ship and his crew get
trapped in the ice in the Antarctic and
again,
photos exist.
It's wonderful.
You get to watch the ship as it's
crushed by the ice and shackleton and
the crew have to get out and basically
live on the ice flows while they wait to
be rescued,
which is not happening fast enough.
And he can see that his people are going
to die out there.
If somebody doesn't do the really brave
thing and take one of the little boats.
You know,
the 20,
25 footers off the big boat amounting to
almost an open rowboat,
not quite,
but almost,
and he and a few crew members get in it
and head out into the Arctic waters
looking for land.
It's insane when you think about it and
it's insane that he survived and in May
19,
16,
he and these couple of guys that he set
out,
you know,
into the Arctic with,
I mean with amazing stories of of
towering waves and all these things
stumbled into an isolated whaling
station on south Georgia island,
which normally most of us would think as
penguin territory.
It must've seemed positively Balmy to
shackleton and his crew,
who by this time looked like bigfoot or
something like a missing link.
Totally sunburned.
The beards on their faces,
frozen and icicles hanging off them.
They were originally wearing animal
skins,
but those skins did not like the salt
water very much and had melted and were
rotting and smelled and were falling off
of them.
I mean,
the first thing they do when they get to
this whaling stations scare the heck out
of two boys.
A couple of 12 year olds or something,
see them first and go off running and
who could blame him?
Eventually though the adults come
running,
shackleton identifies himself.
He's taken in to be sort of restored,
given water and I guess you could say
debriefed and we're told that one of the
first questions he asks,
his benefactor is for an update on
whatever happened with the war he was
following and he says,
tell me when was the war over and in one
of the more famous responses you'll ever
get about this,
because it says so much in a couple of
sentences and that's why it's gone down
in history.
The benefactor as opposed to have
answered is when was the war over
question with the war isn't over
millions or dead.
Europe is mad.
The world is mad.
If Shackleton reacts to this news with
horrified,
disbelief,
then he's just catching up to the rest
of the world because no one can believe
that the level of intensity that this
conflict displays from minute one can be
sustained.
Remember,
this war starts very differently than
the second world war does.
The Second World War kind of ramps up
slowly.
The first world war is like someone
pulling the pin on a grenade and
everything explodes at once.
Everyone attacks at once.
There are a lot more people killed in
the first month of the first world war.
Then the first month of the second,
in fact,
so many people are killed that the
people living through this period have
nothing to compare this to.
The numbers are off the charts.
I mean look at what they were looking at
as normal casualty numbers and by the
way,
this is considered to be horrible.
So I mean they.
They thought it could be bad.
It could be like the Russo,
Japanese war on steroids could knit.
That war happened the decade before.
The first world war lasted.
Eighteen months is seen as sort of the
testing ground for a lot of the weapons
and tactics and everything that would be
used in the next war.
And in 18 months a hundred and 65,000
people are killed.
It's horrible.
One hundred and 65,000
people are killed in a week or two when
the first world war breaks out.
Twenty 2000 Frenchmen die in a day in
August,
1914.
There are no metrics for that for you.
American history fans out there.
What's the worst war in American
history?
The US civil war,
right?
Because everyone who dies is an American
casualty.
Last four years,
you lose between 600,000
and 700,000
Americans killed.
That's how many people you lose killed
roughly in the first month of the first
world war.
Everyone is stunned and it's not just
gender roles and world leaders and
everything.
Let's say that this war can't last.
You have some of the top economic minds
in the world saying that for economic
reasons,
it can't continue.
John Maynard Keynes,
the guy who will later be the father of
Keynesian economics says in 1914 that
the war won't last a year.
As soon as the financial liquidity dries
up,
he says,
all the belligerents will be forced to
come to terms and make peace.
He couldn't have been more wrong.
Countries will ditch the gold standard
almost immediately.
They'll inflate their currency,
they'll open up lines of credit and
they'll start borrowing.
It was lord her ratio,
kitchener Britain's war minister,
and one of the few people who understood
how long this war was really going to.
Last said,
quote,
no financial pressure has ever stopped a
war in progress and kitchen or
understood what many of these people who
should have understood better didn't,
and that's that we had entered the era
where nation states could really take a
punch.
We talked about that in an earlier
episode.
It's a mixed blessing.
It means that you don't succumb to the
enemy's attacks right away,
but it means you also last longer and
when you last longer,
you see your human and your financial
capital ground into powder.
There are a lot of people who wonder
whether it was actually a benefit for
the French and the British to win the
battle of the Marne.
That's where we left off the last
program.
The Battle of the Marne at the time was
seen as know the savior of France.
The Germans would their prewar battle
plans with they're meticulous precision
planning that had had decades to come up
with perfecting this plan.
They'd failed at the battle of the Marne
when,
when by the time you know the,
the,
the crowning moment happens where
everything rests on what the Germans are
doing.
Both sides are like a couple of punch
drunk prize fighters.
We've been using that analogy for this
whole conflict because it worked so well
and up until you know the French and
British victory at the Marne.
The Germans had been the one really
dishing out the heavy blows,
but everyone is so tired and at the end
of their rope,
by the time the Maren happens only a
month into the conflict that you get the
feeling like it's the end of the first
round of that both fighters have given
everything they have and they're so
tired that if anybody could just land
one solid blow on either side,
it'll be over on the French and the
British land that blow and the Germans
are forced backward.
They're forced backward so that they can
reorganize their lines and close up this
dangerous hole in their lines that was
exploited by French and British troops,
as Churchill famously said,
as only he can.
Those troops were probing their way into
the German liver and it's a classic
maneuver to try to pull your troops back
and reorganize your lines,
but it's also a dangerous one and it
also means that the Germans have given
up on the so called Schlieffen plan.
Can I find it interesting?
Sometimes when you read some of the
histories of the first world war,
you will find yourself in a very similar
situation to the commanders on both
sides of the western.
What will become the western front and
that is you will be studying this as
though you're playing around with toy
soldiers.
I mean,
I'll read stuff where they'll say,
you know,
this division did this and pulled back
to here and you're totally losing track
of the human element.
And the problem with that is if you
don't understand the condition of the
people on the ground,
you're going to create all sorts of
plans that don't take into account what
they can actually carry out.
I mean,
for example,
the general staffs have all these armies
are tens of miles behind where the
fighting is.
I mean,
most of them,
the German general staff for example,
are sitting in wonderful French chateaus
with roaring fire places,
drinking wine out of crystal glasses and
playing with maps and protractors trying
to decide where to move people and what
to do with them.
And the British and the French
commanders are often doing the same
thing.
The problem is is that these little
protractors in these armies that they're
moving around on maps bear no
resemblance to what the human beings on
the ground or dealing with.
The human beings on the ground are
spent.
Both sides have warned themselves down
to the nub and can hardly function
anymore.
I mean,
this is the point in the war.
Once the Germans start retreating after
the battle of the Marne,
where the British and French commanders
think they've got them on the run,
Sir John French,
the British commander thinks that he's
going to be in Berlin in six weeks.
It's going to be over.
We'll unleash the cavalry will launch
this massive pursuit,
will destroy the enemy who's routing and
it'll be all over.
The problem is as Sir John French's
troops are in no condition to do that.
In fact,
every side is finding out another one of
the new realities of modern warfare and
that's that they use ammunition at a
pace that nobody was prepared for.
At this point in the conflict,
everybody is actually rationing the
artillery.
They can't even use the guns the way
they want to because they don't have
enough shells.
I mean,
take the Russians as a perfect example.
At this point in the war,
the Russians are producing 35,000
artillery shells a month.
Sounds great,
doesn't it?
Until you realize that once the fighting
actually starts,
they're using 45,000
shells a day,
making $35,000
a month,
shooting off 45,000
shells a day.
Now all these armies went into the
conflict with nice reserves of these
shells,
but by a month and a half into it,
they are down to almost nothing and even
the French and the British,
you know,
as they pursued the German armies,
as the German army's retreat from the
modern,
they can't function the way that they're
trained and ready to do so.
They have to ration everything and so
did the Germans and everybody's just at
the end of their rope and you lose the
human element.
When you study the history of things
from the very highest levels in the
moving of armies around on maps and you
see arrows and cavalry armies and all
these kinds of things.
When the people on the ground or in a
completely different situation.
Here's how writer Gj Meyer describes the
situation after them on quote the French
and British.
Though jubilant at and in many cases
astonished by the German withdrawal from
the Marne were badly battered,
worn out,
and running low on essential equipment.
Many were almost too exhausted to move.
He's quoting an English soldier now
quote,
after five days and nights of fighting,
one English soldier wrote,
decimated,
spent and hungry.
We are lying on the bare earth with only
one desire in our hearts to get
ourselves killed.
Meyer continues and they were short of
shells for their artillery.
It is one measure of the intensity of
this new kind of warfare that the French
faced critical shortages of ammunition
for their 75 millimeter canon.
They're most effective field artillery
piece because only 10,000
rounds were being produced per day.
That was barely 20 percent of the need.
He continues for any number of such
reasons.
The armies of the entente,
the allies failed to close with the
retreating Germans or exploit the huge
gap that had prompted their withdrawal.
They did not attack in force until the
German first,
second,
and third armies had settled into
fortified positions on high ground north
of the Ain,
the next east,
West River,
north of the Marne.
By then it was too late and to quote the
Germans themselves were in a horrible
condition.
German soldier,
Julius Koch,
and writes about the retreat from the
Marne quote.
The streets were badly worn,
abandoned vehicles.
We're aligned on the sides of the road.
We began to move at 3:00
in the morning and before we were fully
aware of what was happening,
we found ourselves with the rear guard.
Regiments of infantry shot to pieces
arrived in a pitiful condition.
They had cast away their knapsacks and
all unnecessary impediments and we're
trying to get along as fast as possible.
Soon after the first shrapnel of the
enemy began to burst above our heads,
which caused us to accelerate our march
continually.
The road which had also been used during
the advance,
was still marked by deep shell holes
that were filled with water to the very
edge for it rained without interruption.
It was pitch dark and every now and then
someone would fall into one of those
shell holes we were all wet through,
but continue to press on.
Some would stumble over something in the
dark,
but nobody paid any attention.
The great thing was to get along dead
horses and men lay in the middle of the
road,
but nobody took the trouble to remove
the obstacle into quote,
lest we forget about the human element.
Remember that these Germans are moving
through country that was formally
occupied by civilians.
Where the heck are they?
Well,
in a lot of cases they're still there
and in very great danger.
Here's what coach and writes about that
quote.
The road was covered with the equipment
the soldiers had thrown away.
We too had long ago cast aside all
unnecessary ballast.
Thus we were marching when we passed a
wood densely packed with refugees.
Those hunted people had stretched
blankets between the trees so as to
protect themselves from the rain.
They are.
They were lying in the greatest
conceivable misery all in the jumble men
and women,
children and gray beards.
They're camp reached as far as the road
and one could observe the terrible hours
that they'd lived through,
had left deep furrows in their faces.
They looked at us with we're retired
eyes.
The children begged us to give them some
bread,
but we had nothing whatsoever left and
we're ourselves tormented by hunger.
The enemy's shrapnel was still
accompanying us and we had scarcely left
the wood when shrapnel began to explode,
which caused the refugees now exposed to
the fire to crowd into the fields in an
attempt to reach safety.
Many of them joined us,
but before long they were forbidden to
use the road because they impeded the
retreat of the troops.
Thus all of them were driven without
pity into the fields soaked by the rain
end quote.
As German soldiers like Julius or Yulia
coaching are retreating back the way
they came there being closely pursued by
their French and British fab.
The series one of whom is the Irish
soldier fighting in the British
Expeditionary Force that we've talked
about earlier.
John Lucy,
who writes about this time quote,
our advanced continued steadily as the
Germans were driven back from the Marne.
Their rear guards showed some resistance
every day and occasionally we picked up
stragglers and wounded from the enemy
army.
Although we took our turn in our brigade
at advanced garden outpost duties.
Our battalion did not really cross
swords with the enemy again until the
14th of September.
On that day and on the few days
proceeding it,
rain fell and we were not very
comfortable either.
In bivouac are on the line of March.
The weather began to get cold on the
evening of 13th September,
a British airplane,
one of the few the British army
possessed approached us from the German
side and wheeling around a lighted in a
field to the right of our marching
columns.
The flying officer climb slowly out of
his machine and coming stumbling towards
us in his heavy kit.
Did Not wait to find an officer,
but shouted to us all there.
They are waiting for you up there.
Thousands of them and he waived his
right arm toward the wooded heights
across the river ane some three miles
away,
and to quote the river Ain was right by
the highest elevated point in this whole
area of the front.
Now it's not very high in terms of the
grand scheme of geography around the
planet,
but in the very flat Harry in near the
French and Belgian borders,
it was 500 feet tall in some places and
that gave a commanding view of all the
flat country around it.
This is the point that the German
soldiers had been told to turn back
around and face their pursuers and dig
in and stopped them.
This had been one of the last command is
made by the former German commander,
the one whose job it was to carry out
the Schlieffen plan.
Helmut von Moltke,
the younger before he totally collapsed
from his nervous breakdown.
After his plan failed,
he's replaced by one of his critics a
controversial choice that the kaiser
tabbed a guy named General Eric from
Falcon.
Hi.
Now,
one thing that becomes clear when you
look at the high commands have all these
armies is the generals have outrageous
most of the time and they often are
jealous and they snipe at their peers
and when Falcon hine is named,
it angers among other people.
Eric Luton door,
this young wonder kin who's been doing
great things for the Germans on the
eastern front and who,
who will say a Falcon Heinz appointment,
I am only capable of love and hate,
and I hate General Falcon Heine and
Falcon.
Haim was critical of von Moltke before
the battle of the Marne even starts
Falcon High and looks at what von Moltke
is doing and thinks he's lost his mind
and writes.
On September fifth,
19,
14 quote,
our general staff has completely lost
its head.
Sleeping's notes do not help any further
and so his wits come to an end and to
quote,
well,
the Kaiser must've read that and decided
that since von Moltke couldn't pull this
off,
maybe one of his critics can falcon hine
turns his troops around,
tells them to dig in and begins looking
for replacements for the people who've
died.
Because the German army is a fraction of
what it was just a couple of weeks
before and they aren't the only ones.
The British and the French armies have a
similar problem.
They're all decimated.
The differences is Britain and France
have colonies and dominions and
Commonwealth nations who the minute the
war starts are basically told to get
people over there and there are arriving
every day.
The British have Indian troops from
India arrive and Canadian show up very
quickly.
The Scots from Scotland are always a
part of the British forces and they
arrive in kilts and this is where they
will get their famous nickname,
which some people wonder if it even
happened this way,
but it's too good of a nickname to not
mention the German supposedly call them
the ladies from Hell because of the
kilts they were and they were all
showing up every day in greater numbers
and taking their place in the line to
replace the dead and the wounded.
The French are bringing troops from
North Africa,
from Morocco and Algeria and troops from
central Africa and places like Senegal.
So you have dark skinned black Africans.
In the French army,
something that the Germans one are not
accustomed to and to a little dismayed
about because they think about all of
the black Africans left in Africa that
may be could be brought to fight against
them too.
When the Germans tried to reinforce
their own,
you know,
torn open ranks,
they have to do it with Germans.
Now they have a bunch of them people who
the minute the war was declared,
signed up and joined the forces and
we're in training this whole time.
The problem is that the war is only
about six weeks old.
None of these people have had enough
training to make them anywhere near as
good as the soldiers they're trying to
replace but fall could and calls them
up.
Anyway.
The situation is desperate.
The war could be lost right here,
right now and every man is needed
and all these troops are going to be
thrown into the blood bath up near the
French and Belgian border.
It's at that spot where the Germans had
turned around,
halted the retreat that had been going
on ever since the battle of the Marne
taken the heights on the other side of
the river ane and begun to Deegan
fortify,
reequip reinforce and are waiting for
their pursuers to show up.
They're French and British pursuers
assume that they're going after a bunch
of Rowdy Germans.
They're not expecting to run into
heavily four to five positions in a
very,
very strong spot.
Remember John Lucy and the BDF or
marching toward that area.
When that airplane lands in the field
and the pilot goes running up to the
British march column saying they're
waiting for you.
Thousands of them on the other side of
the river on the night of September
13th,
1914,
the French and the British tried to
cross that river and dislodged the
Germans from the height and it's a
disaster.
The British do this crossing at night in
heavy fog on pontoon boats for the most
part.
They get to the other side aside that
has no natural cover and that's facing,
you know,
four to 500 foot hills in the distance,
heavily wooded and the sun comes up and
burns off the fog,
leaving the British troops totally
exposed and the Germans slaughter them.
Artillery machine guns even from the
flank,
the British stagger back across the
river and their commander Sir John
French orders them to dig in and face
the Germans who were dug in on the other
side of the river.
This is the main thing.
Your history books will tell you that
the first battle of the ane is known
for.
It's supposedly the time when trench
warfare is initiated.
This will be the most iconic and
memorable part of the first world war,
but it's a misnomer to suggest that
trench warfare just started here because
given the technology of the day,
trench warfare begins organically.
It's a natural human response to the
fact that the air above ground level is
filled with so much steel and lead that
it's suicide to be out in the open,
so across the entire front,
stretching all the way from the Swiss
border across the entire Franco German
border up through Luxembourg,
up into Belgium.
More than 400 miles and millions of men
on both sides.
Long human beings have done the most
natural thing possible.
They've gone to ground and they've tried
to get as low as possible to escape what
earns gender.
We'll call the storm of steel.
Later in the war,
in addition to digging down,
they throw up things called breast
works,
which is putting stuff in front of your
position to stop the bullets from
hitting you.
If you're lucky,
it's sandbags.
If you're not lucky,
it's anything you can get your hands on.
The combination of digging in the earth
and putting up barriers in front of you
begins to fortify the entire line on
both sides and in some spots.
The Germans and the French are only a
couple hundred yards from each other.
The fortification of the entire line
changes this war in ways that the
generals on either side are unprepared
for.
They don't know what to do,
so they go back to the training manuals
which say find a flank,
turn the flank attack in the rear.
The problem is is that there's only one
tiny little area of this more than 400
mile line where it hasn't calcified into
a normal siege situation and that's the
area between,
you know,
this battle at the river and that has
just happened and the ocean to the north
of it.
It's not a very big zone and both the
British and the French on one side and
the Germans on the other begin a crab
like dance of death as one historian
described it,
trying to probe their way towards open
country for a very long time.
This was known as the race to the sea,
but historians have come to hate that
term because it gives the false idea
that somehow reaching the c is the goal
of both these sides would.
In fact,
if both sides reached the sea,
it means that there are no flanks
anymore and there will be several big
battles between the army's as they
collide in their attempt to find an open
flank to turn.
Now,
it's worth pointing out here that what
we're about to experience is the most
complicated war I've ever studied and
it's a very unusual conflict because in
many cases,
the battlefield is not going to change.
This area up near the Franco Belgian
border,
for example,
is going to become one of the worst
killing grounds,
extended killing grounds in all human
history,
and later in the war,
troops marching up to this battle ground
will be able to smell it before they
actually get there.
In addition,
when one side attacks,
the other side will often counter
attack,
so if you look at the battle on a map,
it makes no sense at all.
I've got 400 page books that deal with
just single encounters between the two
sides and it's impossible to make heads
or tails of it even with maps,
even if you're an expert.
And part of the reason why is because
the nature of battle has changed.
Armies are staying in contact with each
other now,
and that's very different than through
most of human history.
Through most of human history.
Armies come together,
there's a short,
sharp clash,
and then they break contact and move in
opposite directions.
Again,
battles that last more than one day are
extremely rare.
Up until this time period,
all of a sudden,
these armies aren't going to break
contact.
They're going to stay on opposite sides
of a short little no man's land and hold
each other by the throat even on so
called quiet parts of the front.
Hundreds or thousands of men can be
killed every day.
Now,
this is not unheard of near the end
stages of the US civil war,
ulysses s grant,
the northern general,
will have a similar strategy where he
maintains contact with the enemy,
grabs them by the throat,
doesn't let them go and grind them down.
A strategy of attrition,
but that's new to the European
experience and neither side's giving up
yet they're going to try to find that
flank until there is no flank anymore.
That race to the sea will involve
several more big battles including one
that involves you know what's left of
the poor Belgian army.
Remember the Belgian army was what the
Germans thought.
We're going to be a bunch of chocolate
soldiers and instead they put up this
heroic doomed resistance to them.
You know,
fighting and being pushed backwards
every step of the way.
Once the Germans reform their lines at
the river and their entire flank is
threatened by the parts of Belgium that
haven't fallen to them yet,
including the giant and vital port city
of Antwerp.
So this is when the Germans go take all
that they pound and top with those same
enormous guns that they destroyed the
Belgian forts with at the beginning of
the war and they pushed the Belgian
army.
All the ways too that the Belgians are
sitting there with their backs to the
ocean.
There is no place left to run and the
Belgian king is with them.
And at one point he orders his officers
to stand behind the trenches and shoot
any Belgian soldiers that dare run away
and they stay there being pounded by the
artillery until they can't stop the
Germans.
They realized that if they don't hold
that area,
the Germans are going to be the one who
find that open flank and the turn,
the British and the French.
And this is,
you know,
the part of the war where it looks like
the Germans might actually reverse the
entire battle of the Mons results and
when any way.
So the Belgians do something that is,
you know,
their nuclear option and it's a,
it's a sacrifice that might have saved
the war for the allies.
Remember,
Belgium is one of those areas of Europe
that is actually,
for the most part,
this part of flanders that we're talking
about in Belgium below sea level.
And the reason that it even exists is
because you know,
forever the Belgians have been pumping
out water and building dikes and things
like that to keep the ocean out the king
of Belgium.
When things become desperate to the
point of doomsday blows up the dykes,
the Belgian king makes the decision to
let the seawater in on October 22nd,
and it's a true sacrifice because he's
not just flooding one of the more
fertile parts of his country.
He's flooding it with sea water and the
salt water will do terrible damage to
the fertility of the region.
Remember,
the Romans supposedly would so salt into
the ground of the territory of their
very worst enemies so that nothing would
ever grow.
There again,
the Belgians had done this to themselves
voluntarily to protect the very end of
the allied line and keep the Germans
from breaking through and perhaps taking
the channel ports,
which would have been a disaster.
The Germans have no idea what's going on
as the water level rises,
but within a couple of days there's a
five mile wide shoulder deep lake
separating them and the Belgian forces
and the Belgians will stay behind that
lake for years.
That essentially shuts off that part of
the front.
The bad news for the other allied forces
is that now that the Germans didn't need
those troops to try to deal with the
Belgians,
they turn them around and threw them
into the developing battle at a place
called [inaudible],
which on October,
22nd breaks out big time and eat crap
becomes this point where the true
futility of the wasting of lives is so
aptly demonstrated because of course,
war is all about spending lives to
achieve a goal.
The tragedy happens when you spend lives
for no good reason and an eat pray.
You begin to see the kinds of tragic
levels that this will reach a large
number of the troops that the Germans
had called up.
You know,
with very little training or young
people,
students whose teachers had
indoctrinated them into the idea that
this is what you do when you fight for
Germany and what a great honor it's
going to be.
You know,
when they would all join up together as
students with fraternity badges and all
these things.
And after very little training,
they were thrown into this combat that
was developing around the city of Ipa
and the surrounding area
in one of the really tragic parts of the
conflict,
the students would run up against what
was left of some of the greatest
military units in the world,
what was left of the old British
professional army,
which had been ground down.
You know,
ever since the war started,
but still had some of its best units
intact.
These badly trained 16,
17 and 18 year old kids
would be massacred for no good reason.
As author Winston Groom writes,
quote on a front of nearly 20 miles,
tens of thousands of men came to grips
and did their best to murder each other
in the cold,
Dank,
misty hill surrounding April.
In many places,
the fighting was hand to hand that
morning,
divisions of the German Fourth Army
consisting in large part of students
attack the British line,
such as it was in a fit of Wagnerian
frenzy.
The German students came on arm in arm
or waving their rifles in the air,
singing and with their spiked pickle.
How the helmets festooned with flowers
by the thousands they were shot down
even though they outnumbered the British
at times six to one that morning.
They faced the most professional and
elite regiments of the British Army,
if not the world,
the Black Watch,
coldstream guards',
Scots Guards,
Cameron's Grenadier Guards,
Irish Guards,
Stafford's,
Gordon,
highlanders,
green,
howards,
royal,
Scots,
fusiliers,
Welsh,
and others almost too numerous to
mention,
including the [inaudible] and dragons of
the Cavalry Corps when it was all over.
The British official history estimated
that at least half of these youthful
teutonic warriors,
100,000
of them had been shot down.
The Germans named the battle,
the massacre of the innocence and quote
in German it was the kinder Morgan and
after the war,
the parents of some of these children
would put a poignant monument over
there,
mass grave showing a weeping father and
mother looking out over the mass graves
festooned with the fraternity pins of
these young kids who thought war was
going to be a romantic,
heroic adventure.
I'm not going to focus on battle after
battle after battle of pointless
conflict in this story.
It's a complicated and detailed enough
conflict.
Did you kind of have to pick your
battles,
if you'll pardon the pun,
and it's the human side of this affair
that I want to focus on what the people
who were living through it,
we're forced to experience.
For example,
20 year old Herbert Solves Bach,
a gunner who had joined up as the war
starts and it was getting his first
taste of battle as the battle of eep or
begins and he writes,
quote,
change of position.
We pull forward,
get our first glimpse of this
battlefield and have to get used to the
terrible scenes and impressions,
corpses,
and more corpses rubble and the remains
of a captured village trenches hastily,
Doug,
by the British,
are full of bodies.
We get driven out of this position by
infantry and artillery fire.
We stand beside the guns with the horses
and a dreadful night comes down on us.
We've seen too many horrible things all
at once.
They make a very strong impression on
us.
Barely 20 years old as we are,
but these things also hardened us up for
what's going to come and to quote,
he's not the only one.
The German writes to his sweetheart with
care for her sensibilities and an
understanding of what military
censorship might do to his letter about
what the reality of what he's
experiencing is like,
and he writes during these battles in
Flanders,
quote my dear Maria,
I feel so terrible.
I'd really rather not write to you.
That doesn't mean I've forgotten you
though.
Every day spent here makes it clearer to
me how beautiful home is and what a
crowd of feelings that word home brings
out in me.
I've lived through such horror recently.
No words can describe it.
The tragedy all around me,
every day the fighting gets fiercer and
there is no end in sight.
Our blood is flowing in torrance.
When I think of our 247th regiment,
my ice swim with tears.
The first and second battalions have
only 250 to 300 men left.
So more than half are gone today.
Only a few of my comrades will be still
standing.
My company commander,
Lieutenant Moss Power,
had been at the front for one hour when
he was shot through the head Pale and
close to death.
He was carried past me today.
Sunday,
I stood at this modest grave and joined
in prayer.
That's how it is all around me.
The most gruesome devastation.
Dead and wounded soldiers,
dead and dying animals,
horse cadavers,
burned out,
houses,
dug up fields,
cars,
clothes,
weaponry.
All of this is scattered around me.
A real mess.
I didn't think war would be like this.
We can't sleep for all the noise.
At least 30 shells exploded once the
whole time.
We called for backup yesterday and
today.
I hope they make it.
There are only a few of us left to
tackle the English.
I managed to wash myself properly
yesterday for a change.
My beard is getting ever longer.
Otherwise I'm feeling fine.
As you can see,
all this noise is not going to ruffle my
Wurtenburg calm and cool.
That's from a German soldier named Paul
Hub.
This war brings out the extremes of
humanity and even the most monstrous
human beings that you can pick out
throughout history,
exhibit some of that humanity through
their writing.
If you go read one of the most monstrous
human beings who's ever lived,
chronicles of this combat,
even he seemed somewhat human by the
whole thing out off hit,
but it was there in flanders in 1914 at
these battles.
It was his first encounter with combat
and he wrote about it in his book,
mine comp and said quote
at last.
The day came when we left Munich to
begin the fulfillment of our duty.
For the first time I saw the Rhine as we
rode westward along.
That's quiet waters to defend it.
The German stream of streams from the
greed of the old enemy.
When through the tender veil of the
early morning mist,
the neater vault monument gleamed down
upon us in the gentle rays of the sun.
The old watch on the Rhine roared out of
the endless transport train into the
morning sky,
and I felt as though my heart would
burst and then came a damp cold night in
flanders through which we marched in
silence and when the day began to emerge
from the mist,
suddenly an iron greeting came whizzing
at us,
over our heads and with the sharp report
sent the little pellets flying between
our ranks,
ripping up the wet ground,
but even before the little clouded
passed from 200 throats,
the first hurrah rose to meet the first
messengers of death.
Then a crackling and a roaring and a
singing.
In a howling began and with feverish
eyes.
Each one of us was drawn forward faster
and faster until suddenly passed turnip
fields and hedges.
The fight began the fight of man against
man and from the distance,
the strains of a song reached our ears
coming closer and closer,
leaping from company to company just as
death plunged a busy hand into our
ranks.
The song reached us too,
and we passed it along.
Deutschland,
Uber,
lesson develop.
Four days later,
we came back,
even our staff had changed.
Seventeen year old boys now looked like
men.
The volunteers of the list regiment may
not have learned to fight properly,
but they knew how to die like soldiers.
This was the beginning.
He said,
thus it went on year after year,
but the romance of battle had been
replaced by horror.
The enthusiasm gradually cooled and the
exuberant joy was stifled by mortal
fear.
The time came when every man had to
struggle between the instinct of self
preservation and the admonitions of
duty.
I too was not spared by the struggle
always.
When death was on the hunt of vague,
something tried to revolt,
strove to represent itself to the weak
body is reason.
Yet it was only cowardice,
which in such disguises tries to ensnare
the individual,
a grave tugging and warning set in,
and often it was only the last remnant
of conscience which decided the issue.
Yet the more this voice admonished one
to caution,
the louder and more insistent it's
lures.
The sharper resistance grew until at
last.
After a long inner struggle,
consciousness of duty emerged
victorious.
By the winter of Nineteen 15,
1916,
he writes,
this struggle had been for me,
decided at last.
My will was undisputed master,
if in the first day is I wonder over the
top with rejoicing and laughter,
I was now column and determined and this
was enduring.
Now,
fate could bring on the ultimate tests
without my nerves shattering or my
reason failing.
The young volunteer had become an old
soldier and this transformation had
occurred in the whole army.
It had issued hard and old from the
eternal battles and for those who could
not stand up under the storm while they
were broken and quote,
Hitler would actually leap out into no
man's land under a hail of bullets and
try to rescue a commanding officer by
putting them on his back and carrying
him back to the German lines.
It will be decorated by the Kaiser for
this,
even though the man he rescued died,
what Hitler is talking about in this
struggle,
but he has to go through to try to make
himself do something that the entire
urges of humanity inside a human being,
you know,
argue against is something that every
soldier in the war who's going to face
this kind of carnage needs to,
you know,
deal with at one point or another,
sometimes they don't even have control
over what happens.
People will be affected by the storm of
steel is Ernst Junger.
We'll call it later in the war in
different ways,
sometimes consciously,
but sometimes in a way that defies even
what they want to do.
Now.
One of the things that the human side of
the first World War requires us to look
at is how and why are these people doing
these things.
Intelligent human beings from the modern
era.
Look at what our grandfathers and great
grandfathers did in this conflict and
can understand how and why they did it.
Part of it is the romance and the
heroism and the idea of duty and what's
expected of them,
and some of that is what motivates
soldiers to continue to press forward in
unbelievable situations in combat even
today,
but there were other elements in play,
less savory elements.
We were dealing with modern nation
states who had ways of compelling a
certain level of behavior.
There were a lot of people who were not
brave in this combat on all sides or
whose bodies simply would not do with
their mind and told them to do.
Those people often had to be sacrificed.
As an example to others.
In 1914,
a British brigadier general name e l
spears wrote about one of those methods
that the modern state and really states
had for some time before this use to
compel their troops to be brave and to
do their duty,
and he wrote quote generally my day had
just been roused from sleep on the straw
or the shed and was standing in the
street when a little group of
unmistakable proport came around the
corner.
12 soldiers and an NCO,
a firing party.
A couple of gendarmes in between them
and unarmed soldier.
My heart sank and a feeling of horror
overcame me and execution was about to
take place generally my day took a look
and then held up his hand so that the
party halted and with a characteristic
quickstep went up to the doomed man.
He asked what he had been condemned for.
It was for abandoning his post.
The general then began to talk to the
man.
Quite simply,
he explained,
disciplined to him,
abandoning your post was letting down
your pals more.
It was letting down your country that
look to you to defend her.
He spoke of the necessity of example,
how some could do their duty without
prompting,
but others less strong had to know and
understand the supreme cost of failure.
He told the condemned man that his crime
was not Venal,
not low,
and then he must die as an so that
others should not fail.
Surprisingly,
the rich agreed nodding his head.
The burden of infamy was lifted from his
shoulders.
He saw a glimmer of something redemption
in his own eyes,
a real hope,
though he knew he was going to die,
the general went on carrying the man
with him to comprehension that any
sacrifice was worthwhile if it helped
France ever so little.
What did anything mad or if he knew
this?
Finally,
the general held out his hand,
meaning to shake the condemned person's
hand.
Yours is also a way of dying for France.
She said the procession started again,
but now the victim was a willing one.
The sound of a volley in the distance
announced that all was over general demo
day wiped the beads of perspiration from
his brow and for the first time,
perhaps his hands trembled as he lit his
pipe,
and that's something that all sides will
do in this war.
It's a way of saying that yes,
you may face certain death if you walk
into the storm that is modern combat,
but you'll also face certain death if
you don't.
It's very important though to bear in
mind that the fact that these soldiers
who failed in their duty somehow are
exposed to capital punishment,
does not mean that that's why soldiers
fought.
That's something that has been present
in most armies throughout history since
ancient times.
Heck,
the Romans,
if your unit fought badly,
would make the men draw lots and one out
of every 10 soldiers in the unit would
be killed.
That was called decimation,
and to add insult to injury,
the Romans would make their comrades
killed them.
So that's a standard part of warfare.
Throughout most of history.
Most of these soldiers were fighting for
much higher values.
Things that to the more cynical 21st
century mind sometimes almost sounded
like you know,
military recruiting,
marketing slogans,
but they meant something to these people
and they mean something to soldiers
today,
duty,
honor,
country,
sovereign God,
and what's more,
once the soldiers get into combat a
responsibility to your comrades.
Nonetheless,
the first world war is able to take one
of the most extreme activities humans
ever take part in warfare and make it
worse and start,
for example,
with what trench warfare means for the
soldiers on the ground in terms of day
to day living.
Go out in your backyard,
dig yourself a hole,
sit down in it in the rain and just live
in a day after day without any bombs,
guns,
bullets,
or murderous combat and it's horrible.
That's what these face,
most of them in Flanders,
one of the rainiest parts of Europe,
they live in the mud
and they can't quite get their mind
around how that changes this whole
romantic idea of adventurous combat that
so many of them signed up for.
Take for example,
some of the most elite units in Francis
military men who were in the French
Foreign Legion and he will find
themselves in holes in the ground.
Alan Seeger,
who will die on the western front in
1916.
Rights as this trench warfare is getting
started.
Quote,
this style of trench warfare is
extremely modern and for the artillery
men is doubtless very interesting,
but for the poor common soldier,
it is anything but romantic.
His role is to simply dig himself a hole
in the ground and keep hidden in it as
tightly as possible,
continually under the fire of the
opposing batteries.
He is yet never allowed to get a glimpse
of the enemy exposed to all the dangers
of war,
but none of it's enthusiasms or splendid
Elon.
He is condemned to sit like an animal
limits burrow and hear the shells
whistle over his head and take their
little daily toll from his comrades.
His feet are numb,
his canteen frozen,
but he's not allowed to make a fire.
He's not even permitted to light a
candle.
He must fold himself up in his blanket
and lie down,
cramped in the dirty straw to sleep as
best as he may.
How different from the popular notion of
the evening campfire,
the songs,
and the good cheer and quote.
It's after the battles up in flanders on
the ane and an IPA or this trench
warfare sets in the German soldier.
Rudolph binder tries to explain what's
happening in 1914 when he writes,
quote,
the war has got stuck into a gigantic
siege on both sides.
The whole front is one endless fortified
trench.
Neither side has the forced to make a
decisive push.
Everyone seems settled on a winter
campaign,
but as far as I can judge,
there is no possibility of an early
finish.
We are still stuck here for perfectly
good reasons.
One might as well say for perfectly bad
reasons.
This business may last for a long time.
End Quote.
Now,
it's important to remember that most of
the people who are finding themselves
stuck in this business in 1914 aren't
really soldiers.
Soldiers might be expected to deal with
this kind of incredible experience,
but most of the troops in these uniforms
and carrying weapons,
which you know for all intents and
purposes,
appeared to be soldiers six or eight
weeks ago were civilians.
They were shopkeepers and delivery boys
and students and insurance salesmen and
teachers who all of a sudden find
themselves in circumstances that they
just can't make sense of horrible
situations.
Many of these people had never seen a
dead body in their lives and then all of
a sudden find themselves in situations
like this German soldier in 1914
describing this new phenomenon of trench
life day to day,
living in a hole in the ground with
combat going on all around you,
and he writes,
quote,
the dangers of trench life may be
realized when I say that often neither
the dead nor wounded can be removed.
If you put up as much as a little finger
above the edge of the trench,
the bullets come whizzing around
immediately.
The dead bodies must therefore be
allowed to remain in the trench.
That is to say the dead man has got rid
of by digging a grave for him in the
floor of the trench.
A few days ago a soldier was so badly
hit by a shell that he was cut into his
shattered body,
could not be removed without risk to the
survivors and was therefore allowed to
remain,
but presently he gave rise to a horrible
stench and whatever they did,
the men could not get away from the
mutilated blackened features.
Sometimes arms and legs torn away from
the body are allowed to lie about the
bottom of the trench until someone can
bury them.
One gets hardened in time and to quote,
getting hardened in time is what's
happening during this period.
In 1914,
once the fighting of these major first
battles died down because this is when
the reinforcements arrived and the
reinforcements are not part of the
regular army.
These are the civilians from a short
time ago,
thrown into uniform and sent into this
hell of combat.
It's a little bit different for the
veterans,
especially the professionals,
the British professional army,
you know that existed before the war
started.
The so called old contemptible.
Our being,
as we said,
widdled down to practically nothing,
but there's a few of them left and
they're trying to integrate these former
civilians into their ranks without
getting killed in the process because
those people don't know the ropes yet
and they're doing things that scare the
regulars.
John Lucy,
one of the old contemptible in the Irish
Guards in the BDF writes,
quote,
we stood to in the wet shell holes and
crumbling trenches under the thunder and
blasting flashes of German high
explosives.
There is no need to describe this
bombardment except to say that it was
the worst of my experience.
A few of our fellows broke under it and
one poor chap entirely lost his head and
ran back out of his trench.
He had not a chance in the open.
The earth was vomiting all around us and
he tumbled over in a few yards better to
have kept to the trench.
No trained soldier would leave that.
A corporal,
a burly fellow fell near me where the
shrapnel bullet in his head,
he lay unconscious all the day nodding
his hold head as if suffering only from
some slight irritation.
And did not become still until evening.
Earlier in the day one youngster said,
what about putting him out of his
misery?
A more experienced man explained that
there was no pain.
The smallest stirrings and little mons
came from a man who was then already as
good as dead.
Another soldier,
Lucy says,
had his belly ripped open and sat
supporting his back against a trench.
While he gazed with fascinated eyes at
large coils of his own guts,
which he held in both hands.
This was almost the gasoline aside.
I saw it's sequel was better.
The man's entrails had not been
penetrated.
He got safe out of the trench,
was washed,
tucked in,
and mended well in hospital maimed men
past crouching and crawling behind me,
leaving trails of blood on the ground on
their way to a ditch witch lead back
into the woods behind.
Some of them were moaning to loud.
Unlike our old men,
he means the veterans.
One young militia man in particular came
by roaring and seeking sympathy for a
broken arm from everyone.
He met.
A lance corporal told him that for God's
sake to put a sock in it,
and then if he were really badly
wounded,
he would have no breath left to howl
that stopped his hysterics.
I should say that the non coms of the
old army had the worst time of all
trying in circumstances like these to
keep inexperienced men in hand.
Some of these men could not even fire a
rifle properly and at times our hearts
quailed for our safety and theirs and
quote
this experience was so unlike with the
soldiers of the day.
We're accustomed to that minister of war
and war hero himself,
Lord her ratio,
kitchener and Britain famously said,
when seeing what this whole deal was
like,
this is not war.
Well,
maybe it hadn't been,
but this was sort of a way of telling
everyone in this generation,
welcome to the 20th century.
This is how it's going to be for awhile.
These battles in flanders,
like dre shatter many of the leaders
confidence in what's going on.
Remember when the war starts,
they have a plan for winning the war.
That's been worked out over years,
but once that fails,
all these generals have to improvise.
They have to create new offensive and
new ways to win the war from where
things stand and after these battles in
flanders die down and you have this
trench warfare setting in general,
Vulcan Vulcan Hine in Germany runs the
numbers and they're horrible.
I mean the battle at Ipa,
all sides combined.
You're talking about another 250,000
casualties in a few weeks.
That brings the German totals on the
western front.
Since the war started,
which is August to more than 750,000.
The French are topping a million.
The British had,
for all intents and purposes,
lost their army,
the greatest
in the world,
small but the greatest in the world.
It's down to dozens of many new units
that had hundreds of men,
you know,
a very short time ago and in Britain
they're trying to scrape up replacements
and you can see how,
how bad it is by how quickly they're
changing the requirements.
Because when the war starts,
you have to be five foot eight inches
tall to be in the British army in
October.
They lower that to five foot five inches
tall,
a single month later in November,
they lower that to five foot three
inches tall.
The Germans are having a similar
problem.
They learned a very hard lesson in these
battles in flanders.
You must let the troops finished their
training because they threw away a ton
of lives with people who weren't ready
to fight,
but fall.
Heinz got a more difficult situation
because the British and the French,
as we said,
have dominions and Commonwealth nations.
I mean the Canadians alone in a fit of
patriotism are sending more than 30,000
fresh troops across the Atlantic in the
largest transportation of troops,
you know,
in the history of the world across the
large oceans on Falcon high and has to
account for this and he can't.
He goes and he tells the civilian
leadership that the war in the west
can't be worn anymore.
He tells them that they have to come to
some sort of an arrangement and he
suggests making peace with somebody,
maybe the Russians,
because if you make peace with the
Russians,
maybe the French will lose heart.
He says all of these other nations are
simply weapons in the hands of the arch
enemy,
which is England,
and that they have to be that the
British have to be the ones that the
Germans focused on and we have to get
these other countries which are merely
swords in the hand of perfidious albion
and he says,
we have to get them out of the war.
Now.
This is going to be very hard to do
because way back in September,
all the allies sign these agreements
saying nobody will make a separate peace
nonetheless high and hopes that he can
make his war aims.
You know,
no longer victory but shattering some of
these powers.
So they leave the war.
The civilian leadership in Germany,
the politicians like Beckman whole veg
are appalled by what Falcon High and
tells them they can't figure out a way
to do this because the German,
just like all these other countries are
so appalled by the casualties and the
blood that's been spilled that nobody is
willing to give up anything.
You've already lost too many people.
It's one thing if you lose all those
people in a victory to another thing.
If you lose all those people in a loss
besides Beth holding just a couple of
months ago was writing up plans for what
the victory conditions in the war are
going to be and he's got these grandiose
schemes where we're going to push the
Russians back.
We're going to keep the French down
forever.
We're going to have all these vassal
states and now his chief military leader
is saying,
listen,
we can't win the war
now.
Fun Fall.
Get Heinz rivals guys like Luton,
door from the east who already hate him
this early say that his attitude,
you know this early in the war,
is tantamount to treason and basically
insinuating in no uncertain terms that I
change in military leadership might
change all these sorts of things.
When on Falcon Highness told that
there's no way that we're ending the
war.
He tells his troops on the western front
to hold onto what you have.
Never surrender a square foot of what
you've won.
If you do counterattack immediately and
retake it because they've taken valuable
territory,
valuable farmland,
valuable resources,
valuable industrial land from the
French,
and if he can't get the war stopped from
the political leadership,
he's going to hold onto what he has.
He tells the troops on the west to
deepen their fortifications instead of
just one line of trenches.
He wants multiple lines of trenches.
He and all the other leaders on both
sides begin to use this wonderful weapon
which doesn't seem like a weapon at all
of barbed wire.
Something that was first invented a
generation before to keep cattle pending
in the American west.
And in the last couple of wars since
then,
had been used sparingly and sort of
experimentally now all sides take this
wire with all these sharp edges and
begin to use it as a fortification.
This will be another one of these iconic
things on the western front and you
don't even think that something like
wire with little teeny barbs on it will
make that much of a difference,
but it proves to be one of the most
important elements of the of the war on
the western front.
You can even make a case that they will
invent weapon systems which still
dominate militaries today,
simply to overcome the barrier created
by things like barbed wire.
Now it's not all bad news for the
central powers in Germany is 1914 wines
down.
Sure General [inaudible] high and has
decided that he can't see a way to
victory on the western front,
but there's fighting going on on other
fronts to his main ad.
This areas in Germany,
Germany's high command,
the ever more powerful team of
Hindenburg and Ludendorff are believers
that you can win the war by beating the
Russians.
They will become part of the group of
German generals that will be known as
easterners,
people that think you can win the war by
being victorious in the East Falcon
Hines,
one of these guys who you know as part
of the cabal known as the Westerners,
believers that any real victory in the
war will come on the western front,
but there are new fronts opening up his
19,
14 winds down strange fronts to first of
all,
we haven't even mentioned that there's
fighting going on in the Pacific because
it really is a sidebar to this story.
Japan,
for example,
once the war breaks out quickly,
throws in their lot with Britain and
France and Russia and the allies,
they do so for purely opportunistic
reasons.
The Germans have some territories in the
Pacific that Japan can easily snap up.
It won't be much fighting.
It won't be much trouble,
and if the allies somehow lose the war,
there's not much.
Germany and Austria,
Hungary and stuff can do to Japan way
over in the Pacific anyway.
There's no downside to the Japanese snap
up.
Some of these German island possessions
in the Pacific that takes some German
territories on the Asian mainland and
the most important part of all of those
actions will be the fact that some of
those places will be battle grounds in
the Second World War and also that
Japan's taking of German possessions on
the Asian mainland help precipitate
later war between Japan and China,
which will help create the conditions
where the Japanese are part of the
Pacific War and the Second World War.
I mean it's more of a long term
situation.
I mean it's more of a longterm cancerous
situation,
but Japan's been in the war since the
beginning.
It's part of what makes this a world
war.
But in November 19,
14,
Turkey enters the war and this is a very
different situation.
First of all,
the Turks are not united on the idea at
all.
Some of the more aggressive,
you know,
members of the government who are now
called the young Turks sort of
precipitated in a way that leaves the
rest of the government out of the
decision.
They in some Germans working together
decide to shell some Russian port
facilities and the Black Sea without
getting the rest of the government's
position,
and then of course Russia declares war
on Turkey and boom,
they're in,
but the Germans had been trying to set
this up for a long time.
They wanted Turkey on their side,
which is strange because Turkey is one
of those powers that's really having a
hard time right now and the Germans
already have one of those.
They're allied to Austria,
Hungary,
which you know in four or five months of
war already looks done.
The Germans will take to saying about
they're Austrian allies that they are
fettered to a corpse.
Well now they're adding another corpse.
I mean,
you really have to admire how well
Germany does in this war,
considering that they have to have the
weakest powers in Europe,
not just on their side but requiring a
lot of their help,
but the Turks provide an interesting use
to the Germans.
It's not that they have an army and navy
that's going to be real helpful,
but the Turks control a nice chunk of
what today we would call the Middle East
and by simply deciding to get into the
war,
they forced the British and the French
who have a lot of possessions in that
area to defend them.
They've expanded the battlefield to
include a whole bunch of areas that
nobody was fighting over before.
Turkey got into the war.
What's more turkeys?
Historic enemy is Russia a Russia that
is putting all their manpower to dealing
with the Germans and the ostrow
Hungarians and all of a sudden south of
all that fighting,
they now have their historic enemy
Turkey in the war.
Again,
it's not that they're so afraid of the
Turks,
it's they're afraid of taking any troops
away from the main battle front to
defend that area at all.
Same thing with the British and the
French.
Now they have to take troops away from
places where they're using them against
the Germans and use them elsewhere so
the Germans aren't really getting.
The Turkish armies help as much as
they're getting.
You know,
the fact that the people they're
fighting have to fight somewhere else
too.
Now,
for our purposes,
there's a wonderful little moment right
at the beginning of Turkey's involvement
where the highest ranking figure in the
Muslim world,
religious wise,
proclaims a jihad against the allies
against Britain,
France,
Russia,
Serbia,
and this is an era where the Muslim
world was,
was more united in a religious sense.
I mean,
nowadays it's more like the Protestant
version of Christianity where there's a
lot of different religious leaders who
kind of all have equal standing at this
time period.
The guy who was running the religion
from Turkey had not total control over
the religion,
but he carried a lot of weight and when
the war breaks out on November 14th,
19,
14,
he proclaims a holy war against Britain,
France,
Serbia,
Russia,
and this is big because Britain,
France,
and Russia all have huge Muslim
populations and Germany's ambassador to
Turkey.
He says that now you know the British
are going to burn up in Jihad.
Whether or not that's what really
happens.
If you're Britain and France and you're
Russia,
you need to be concerned about that and
now you need to divert forces from other
crucial fronts to deal with this new
dilemma.
Now,
Turkey is and has been for more than 100
years known as the sick man of Europe.
They've just fought two wars before the
first world war,
breaks out the first and second Balkan
war and lost most of those European
possessions there.
Penniless.
It's a disaster.
They just bought two battleships,
which they had to ask their citizens to
essentially donate the money for.
They purchased them from Britain,
and then when the war broke out,
Britain kept them,
which was another reason the church were
not too happy with the allies.
Nonetheless,
the fact that Turkey is going to be in
the war means that the British who have
controlled Egypt for some time now have
to worry about Egypt.
I have to worry about the Suez Canal.
Also.
This is the era where oil is finally
becoming important in uh,
right before the first world war breaks
out,
Britain lays down it's first ships that
are going to burn oil instead of coal
and everybody is starting to see that
not only is oil important,
but the Middle East is a place that has
a lot of it and now the Middle East is
going up in flames.
Some of those flames probably would have
been very welcome on the eastern front
at this point where the Russians and the
Germans and the ostrow Hungarians are
locked in mortal combat because it
begins
to freeze at the end of the year as one
might expect they may be dealing with in
a rain and historic cold,
one of the coldest winters on memory on
the western front,
but the coldest winters in memory on the
western front are pretty darn average on
the eastern front and the weather
conditions slow.
Everyone down,
the eastern commanders,
Hindenburg and Ludendorff also don't
have enough troops to do anything truly
momentous.
They keep begging Falcon hine in the
Kaiser for them and they keep getting
rebuffed.
The Russians are inapt when they're
attacking,
but they're very tough when they're
defending,
so things tend to slow down and the
Russians tend to go on the defensive.
The Austral Hungarians are already
almost done,
you know,
five months into the war and they're
fighting the last offensive that they
will launch independently in the whole
war.
They already have a giant fortress with
150,000
Austro-hungarian troops in it,
surrounded by the Russians.
It's a bad situation.
The weather slows everything down and if
you actually try to follow the various
battles going on,
you'll notice that there's a rhythm to
them that makes it difficult for
anything to ever be solved.
I mean,
one side moves forward,
the other side moves back and then you
know,
they reversed course.
I'm historian Peter Hart does a pretty
good rundown of the rhythm of the
eastern front at this time and sums up
the way the first six months of war
ends.
You know,
in Philadelphia and Poland and places
like that.
When he writes,
quote the seesaw nature of the fighting
in the east two steps forward,
three steps back.
One step forward was becoming
increasingly apparent to all along the
line in the north for all their efforts,
the Russians only managed to hold onto a
token sliver of east Prussia.
In contrast,
they lost much of Russian Poland to the
German advance,
but the strategic drawback of occupying
this territory was such that it was not
a particular disadvantage in the broader
scheme of things.
It was in the south against the
Austrians that the Russians had made
their biggest gains as they had overrun
nearly all of Austrian Galitzianers.
Just as on the western front.
The scale of the forces involved had
been incredible.
By the end of the year,
143 Russian divisions faced 53 Austrian
and 38 German divisions.
Losses on all sides had been simply
breathtaking.
By the end of 1914,
up to 750,000
Russian soldiers,
500,000
Austro-hungarian and 140,000
Germans had become casualties.
All this in just five frantic months of
mayhem and the quote,
it will await a change in weather
conditions before that front heats up.
Again.
Throughout this most inhumane of
conflicts,
there are tons of stories of prisoners
being killed and horrible things being
done all over.
I mean when you have millions and
millions of men involved in warfare,
there are going to be stories that run
the gamut.
The ones though that sort of reinforce,
you know,
your connection to humanity are there
too and they deserve to be pointed out.
Sometimes they were on an individual
level.
There's a story from the western front
that I like right around the time of
pray about a British soldier named
Willie Frazier who was wounded in the
shoulder and who gets stuck,
you know,
in place as the Germans overrun his
position and the stories were counted by
author Winston groom.
Here's groom talking about frazier
injured on the battlefield.
Quote,
his shoulder had been shattered by
shrapnel.
There was fighting and killing all
around and the Germans captured him.
Having studied German in Frankfurt in
1909,
he was astonished to hear a German
sergeant yell out in order to shoot him.
Will.
He yelled to a German officer and when
the officer spoke,
really recognized his accent and he
asked if he was from Frankfurt when the
officer replied that he was Willie,
asked him in German,
don't you wish you were there?
Now the two men exchanged forced grins
and the officer ordered his men not to
harm frazier and quote.
You can find stories like that all
throughout the war.
People whose humanity shines through on
an individual basis,
on all sides.
By the way,
no one had a monopoly on that,
but there were times when the humanity
sort of just burst forth and mass
spontaneously.
None more famous may be overrated.
Some people say,
but I don't see how it can be overrated
than what happened on Christmas Eve.
Nineteen,
14.
Especially on the western front.
The conditions are horrible.
It's freezing.
You know your feet are stuck in gruelle
mud water,
but you can't get any worse,
and then it all freezes in.
You're stuck out there in the cold and
then all of a sudden the people on the
western front see something relatively
unbelievable in a conflict where you
have shells going on every second,
snipers picking off anyone who raises
his head above the trench and then all
of a sudden soldiers reported hearing,
singing,
and seeing weird colored lights.
The colored lights were often coming
from the German trenches.
Soldier Yulia is collection was in one
of those trenches opposite the French
saying the conditions were horrible,
but on Christmas Eve,
this is what happened.
Quote
Christmas in the trenches.
It was bitterly cold.
We had procured a pine tree for there
were no for trees to be had.
We had decorated the tree with candles
and cookies.
We had imitated the snow with wadding.
Christmas trees were burning everywhere
in the trenches and at midnight all the
were lifted onto the pair of it with
their burning candles.
And along the whole line,
German soldiers began to sing Christmas
songs in chorus,
old Thou blissful old thou joyous mercy,
bringing Christmas time.
Hundreds of men he writes,
were singing the song in that fearful
would not.
A shot was fired.
The French had ceased firing along the
whole line.
That night I was with a company that was
only five paces away from the enemy.
The Christmas candles were burning
brightly and were renewed again and
again for the first time.
We heard no shots from everywhere
throughout the forest.
He writes one good hear,
powerful Carol's come floating over
peace on earth and such.
The French,
he says,
left their trenches and stood on the
parapet without any fear there.
They stood quite overpowered by emotion
and all of them with cap in hand.
We too had issued from our trenches.
We exchange gifts with the French
chocolate,
cigarettes,
etc.
They were all laughing and so where we
why?
We did not know,
then everybody went back to his trench
and incessantly the carol resounded
evermore,
solidly,
evermore longingly.
Oh Thou blissful and quote
private william quinten in the trenches
on christmas eve,
on the british side wrote about a
similar situation farther down the line,
quote all around us lay about three
inches of snow.
A typical picture postcard christmas,
things were very quiet,
that peace and goodwill to all men
feeling seemed to be in the air.
We could hear the germans still strafing
up separate way,
but the next night,
christmas eve even up there,
it was much quieter.
Something in the direction of the german
lines caused us to rub our eyes and look
again here and they're showing just
above the parapet we could see very
faintly would look like very small
colored lights.
What was this?
Was it some prearranged signal and the
fore runner of an attack or was it to
make us curious and thus expose
ourselves to a sudden raking of machine
gun fire?
We were very suspicious and we were
discussing the strange move of the enemy
when something even stranger happened.
The germans were actually singing not
very loud,
but there was no mistaking it.
We began to get interested.
The enemy,
at least we're going to enjoy themselves
as much as the circumstances would
permit.
Suddenly across the snow clad,
no man's land.
A strong clear voice rang out singing
the opening lines of annie lori.
It was sung in perfect english and we
were spellbound.
No other sound,
but this unknown singer's voice to us.
It seemed like the war had suddenly
stopped,
stopped to listen to this song from one
of the enemy,
not a sound from friend or foe,
and as the last notes died away,
a spontaneous outburst of clapping arose
from our trenches encore,
good old fritz.
End quote.
All along the line,
the two sides would have this
interesting moment where they kind of
began to emerge from the trenches little
by little,
you know,
a place where they couldn't stick a
finger up without having a shot off just
hours before and everybody must have
been so incredibly brave to try,
but one side would raise themselves up a
little bit and the other side would
raise themselves up a little bit more
until both sides.
In this hellish environment where nobody
could go anywhere near,
you know the open air.
We're standing apart from each other,
gazing right at the enemy in no man's
land on christmas,
private.
William quintin again wrote quote,
as daylight crept in,
we were surprised to see the germans
waist high out of their trenches,
gazing across at us with impunity.
Imagine the position,
whereas yesterday,
the mere sight of a bit of field gray
uniform would have caused a dozen
british rifles to crack.
Here was the enemy in full view of us
gazing serenely across no man's land at
us,
and we had him to us in the front line.
The whole world had changed.
We could take stock of our surroundings
that are leisure.
At 9:00
precisely,
the german burying party climbed from
the trenches,
shovels and picks on their shoulders.
They advanced about 10 yards in our
direction and waited.
Expectedly a word from our company
officer and our party were soon out.
The officers looked on,
apparently conversing the digging party
soon lost interest in their task and
before long we're busy,
fraternizing cigarettes were being
exchanged and they seem to be enjoying
themselves immensely.
Needless to say,
before very long,
we in the trenches were soon out on top
sauntering about the snow,
but keeping this side of wire
entanglements.
Likewise,
the germans for the whole of that day
and for many days to come friend and foe
mixed freely out on no man's land,
except for the fact that a few of the
enemy could speak a little english.
We found the language difficulty,
a bar to conversation,
but we may do with signs and gestures.
I remember distinctly a german holding
out an open box of chocolates for me to
take one.
The germans wanted to play a football
match on no man's land,
but our officers would not allow it and
the quote,
there are reports though of british and
german troops engaging in soccer matches
up and down the line.
It was an amazing spontaneous outburst
of humanity and it's so appalled the
higher leadership that they made sure in
future christmases,
nothing like this would ever be allowed.
Again,
if you thought the war was bad before
it's about to get worse and I'll let
winston churchill.
He in a leadership position during this
part of the war setup 1915 a time when
he says men lost control of the conflict
and forces took over.
He wrote,
quote,
the year 19,
15 was faded to be disastrous to the
cause of the allies and the whole world.
By the mistakes of this year,
the opportunity was lost of confining
the conflagration within limits,
which though enormous we're not
uncontrolled.
Thereafter,
the fire roared on until it burned
itself out.
Thereafter,
events past very largely outside the
scope of conscious choice governments
and individuals conformed to the rhythm
of the tragedy and suede and staggered
forward in helpless violence,
slaughtering and squandering on ever
increasing scales till injuries were
brought to the structure of human
society,
which a century will not have face and
which may conceivably proved fatal to
the presence civilization.
But in january 19,
15,
the terrific affair was still not
unmanageable.
It could have been grasped and human
hands and brought to rest in righteous
and fruitful victory.
Before the world was exhausted,
before the nations were broken,
before the empires were shattered to
pieces before europe was ruined,
it was not to be he writes,
mankind was not to escape so easily from
the catastrophe in which it had involved
itself.
Pride was everywhere to be humbled and
nowhere to receive it.
Satisfaction,
no splendid harmony was to crown the
wonderful achievements,
no prize to reward the sacrifices of the
combatants.
Victory was to be bought,
so deer has to be almost
indistinguishable from defeat.
It was not to give even security to the
victors.
There never was to be the silence
following the great words of peace to
the convulsions of the struggle must
succeed.
The impotent turmoil of the aftermath,
noble hopes high comradeship and
glorious daring.
We're in every nation to lead only to
disappointment,
disillusion,
and frustration.
The sufferings and impoverishment of
peoples might arrest their warfare.
The collapse of the defeated might still
the cannonade,
but their hatreds continue on appeased
and their quarrels are still unsettled.
The most complete victory ever gained in
arms has failed to solve the european
problem or to remove the dangers which
produced the war.
End quote,
the war was entering a new phase.
The phase of stalemate.
What do you do to break the stalemate?
That Was the main challenge facing
commanders on all sides.
As 1915 rolls around and you know later
in the war,
the allied generals especially will get
labeled,
you know,
as butchers and and and blockheads and
people who can't think their way out of
a paper bag and and some of it's
justified later in the conflict,
but we have to cut them quite a lot of
slack early on because as the western
front in the trench warfare and
everything begins to,
all of these generals on all sides are
confronted with circumstances that there
are no metrics for.
There is no data on how you deal with
this.
They have to learn,
they have to experiment and then they
have to look at the data afterwards.
The problem is is in this conflict,
in the experimentation in this military
laboratory,
human beings have the lab rats and you
learn that the cost of human carnage.
Now the allies are more willing to do
this.
They have more lab rats to play with and
this becomes a huge feature in the early
part of 1915 because if you are sir John
French,
the british commander,
or if you are joseph shaft for the
french commander,
you know that if this thing has devolved
from a wild swinging boxing encounter in
the first round,
just something that's more like a
wrestling match where both combatants
are holding each other in a death grip,
that that works in your favor.
You're the stronger combatant.
You have more men,
you have more industrial power.
you control the seas.
If it's going to go that way,
you're going to win.
Now,
you may not want to have to be as hurt
as you may have to be to make that work,
but worst case scenario,
long term,
you're going to win that encounter.
It's the german commanders that are
forced to think outside the box because
they're not going to win that encounter.
The problem is,
is the box that they have to think
outside of is the one that was worked on
for decades before the first world war
came out to create laws of war,
humanitarian restrictions on what you
could do,
ways to protect civilians,
noncombatants,
and even combatants from,
you know,
things that were considered to be
unsportsmanlike or extra horrific,
more horrific than it needed to be.
Remember in the first episode we talked
about things like the hague conference,
ways to make war conform to
international law.
The problem was the germans in the
central powers,
we're now in that position that everyone
kind of knew was going to happen.
You know when you wrote those laws of
war,
which is they have to decide whether or
not adhering to international law is
worth losing a war over and you begin to
see both sides try to use asymmetrical
warfare and new technology to break the
stalemate and a lot of what used are the
very things that were prohibited in
these prewar agreements.
A perfect example starts in late 1914
when german warships open fire on
british coastal towns kill more than 100
british citizens,
uh,
becomes a wonderful propaganda tool for
the allies to cite the baby killers of
Germany.
But that's nothing compared to what's
coming in 1915.
The first thing that happens is a
absolute benchmark in warfare.
When in january the germans start really
trying to get involved in what we call
today strategic bombing.
Now,
aircraft had been in use since the very
moment the war started.
One of the excuses that the germans used
for attacking France was they said that
some plane had come from France and
bombed nurenberg at the very moment that
the war started,
which is probably nonsense,
but it shows that there were airplanes
involved in the conflict from the very
beginning,
but in ways that really didn't involve
the laws of war very much.
I mean all Of the air force's puT
together in the world when the war
started,
had less than 500 planes.
but what planes they did have turned out
to be wonderfully valuable tools for
reconnaissance,
which was what air power had been used
for earlier than this time.
Even in the american civil war,
there were hot air balloons that they
would use to see what the enemy was
doing in the distance.
Planes were wonderful for that.
They also turned out to be fantastic in
the more technologically sophisticated
armies at what was known as artillery
spotting and that allowed your guns to
shoot at targets that the gunners
couldn't see.
You know,
you could shoot,
for example,
you know,
far away over a hill and if there was an
airplane there that could tell you what
was happening.
And that was interesting enough to try
to explain without radios and everything
what was happening.
But they could tell you that your shot
fell short or went long or was too far
to the left or too far to the right.
And this gave a huge advantage to the
armies that could make that work for
them.
The less sophisticated armies like the
russians couldn't.
And hence we're relegated to shooting at
things.
They could only see it,
but this early on in the fighting,
you can see how primitive things are
because early on when aircraft would
encounter enemy aircraft,
they didn't have any way to do anything
about it.
I mean they were taking hand guns,
these pilots up in the plane with them
and trying to take pot shots with their
pistols at the enemy air pilots.
I mean,
that's how you know,
sophisticated things are at this stage
in the war.
It's only when the germans run up
against the trench warfare and the
western front and they're forced to
start looking for things that might help
them break the stalemate that they
noticed.
They had the greatest zeplin fleet in
the world.
[inaudible] of course are lighter than
air aircraft,
like blimps,
dirigibles,
those kinds of things.
And before the war,
the germans had built 10 or 12 of them
and had them sort of sitting aside when
the war started,
which scared their enemies probably more
than they should have.
They sort of had a fleet in being role
where people like churchill in britain
had to be,
you know,
worried about what are the journals,
zipline is doing,
what might the german zepplins do.
That was probably out of all proportion
to what the german zepplins could do.
The germans tried to use them at the
beginning of the war,
for example,
when they invaded Belgium and had to try
to deal with those forts.
A couple of zepplins flew over and tried
to drop some bombs,
but when the stalemate on the western
front reaches its real,
you know,
calcification moment,
the germans start looking for ways to
use these tools that they have and there
is no metrics just like there aren't any
metrics on the western front to try to
figure out how to break that stalemate.
There's no metrics that will tell you
what the zepplins will do if they bomb
targets in another country.
There was a british theorist who
suggested that the very powerlessness
that people,
you know in another country in their
home country feel when the enemy is able
to with impunity,
fly over your territory and bomb you.
He suggested that if they bombed the
civilians with confetti,
it wouldn't make any difference.
It would still damage their morale
terribly because it's a feeling like you
can't be defended even at home,
a place that most people tend to feel
safe at this stage in military history.
There were people arguing,
you know,
in the german high command saying,
for all we know these ziplines could win
the war and before the war,
at these big conferences that were part
of trying to come up with international
laws of war.
You know,
there were rules discussed about how
bombing should work.
I mean,
should you have to give the city that
you're going to bomb a chance to
surrender before you bombed them and
lest you think only the germans were
doing this.
Both the british and the french were
sending small bombing raids over into
Germany and Germany was sending small
bombing raids with aircraft that were
holding little hand bombs out of the
open cockpits and dropping them.
Nothing significant.
Nothing like sending large numbers of
zeppelins all together in bombing raids.
But in january,
in 1915,
the germans launched their first one of
those,
they go after some port facilities in
britain.
The problem with this is the same
problem they're going to have in the
early second world war,
which is,
you may say you're trying to hit
military targets,
but the accuracy is so terrible.
You're lucky to fly over a city the size
of london and be able to hit it.
So these poor facilities end up being an
example,
an early example of when civilians get
hit with these weapons,
they'll start bombing london in may 19,
15.
And of course this becomes a propaganda
victory right away for the allies who
again labeled the germans baby killers,
which make the germans defensive.
As you might imagine,
there's a wonderful letter from a german
zeplin leader,
uh,
to his mother trying to explain to her
what apparently he's already tried to
explain to her before that this isn't,
you know,
evil stuff,
that this is modern warfaring.
Yes.
It's not like,
you know,
nights fighting a duel,
but at the same time the situation is
different than when nights fought duals.
People in the home front are no longer
innocent in modern warfare.
They are the ones who make the weapons
that the soldiers require to fight.
If the soldiers can't breakthrough on
the western front,
what if you could prevent one side from
building the shells necessary to keep
the war going?
This is where the idea of the home front
first really takes hold and it becomes
the justification for attacking
civilians in other countries.
Here's the letter that the german zeplin
leader Writes to his mother
trying to make his actions that he
apparently feels guilty over himself.
Sound morally okay.
We who strike the enemy where his heart
beats have been slandered as baby
killers and murderers of women.
What we do is repugnant even to us,
but necessary very necessary.
Nowadays.
There's no such animal as a
noncombatant.
Modern warfare is total warfare.
A soldier cannot function at the front
without the factory worker,
the farmer,
and all the other providers behind him.
You will die.
Mother have discussed this subject and I
know you understand what I say.
My man are brave and honorable there
causes holy.
How can they sin while doing their duty?
If what we do is frightful,
then may frightful be Germany,
salvation end Quote.
This same attitude will be applied to
the other parts of warfare that rear
their ugly head in 1915 because of the
needs of the situation.
I mean flame throwers are one of the
technological weapons that will first
appeared in 1915.
Again,
using science in ways to try to create
openings,
whether it taCtically on the battlefield
or strategically in the war itself.
Another perfect example of this,
when the first world war has to do with
anothEr one of these new weapons systems
that challenged age old theories and
orthodoxies,
one of them had to do with rules
concerning naval blockades.
You see,
when the first world war breaks out,
the british and the french navy
literally sweep the cs clean of german
shipping,
Both military and merchant shipping.
this sort of naval blockade was one of
the main things that britain could offer
early in the war.
They certainly weren't going to offer
millions and millions of troops.
They didn't have millions and millions
of troops.
They had the greatest navy in the world
and just like in napoleon's time when a
strong continental power takes hold,
you shut down their merchant shipping,
you close their porch.
You don't allow them to get any
materials,
resources,
anything from anyone else.
If you can help.
Now,
there were international laws concerning
what you were allowed to keep from
combatants.
You weren't supposed to keep food stops
or the needs of everyday life.
You could keep weapons in those kinds of
things,
but the british and the french push
those rules way past the boundaries of
common sense and we're classifying
things like cotton fabrics is war
necessary materials.
They weren't really going to allow
anything through.
Now,
for all of human history,
there had been sort of a of a calculus
you could count on and that's the.
The weaker naval power cannot blockade
the stronger naval power by see,
how could you write your ships?
Tried to blockade a country like great
britain.
They'll just send their navy out and
sweep your ships off the sea.
But what if your ships aren't on the c?
What if the ships that are trying to
blockade an island nation like britain
or instead under the sea,
the germans had some marines,
this was not a brand new invention,
but one that had finally reached a stage
of effectiveness where the british were
to find out that the old naval
orthodoxies about what a weaker naval
power could and couldn't do had changed.
There was no answer at this point in
history to the submarine surface.
Vessels could not detect them,
and unless the submarine surfaced,
they couldn't destroy them.
Now,
Germany had a lot less submarines than
britain and France,
but here's the thing.
Britain and France couldn't do anything
with their submarines.
They couldn't use their submarines
against german merchant shipping because
there wasn't any german merchant
shipping.
About five minutes after the war breaks
out,
the surface fleets of France and britain
saw to that,
but germany's surface fleet,
which was one of the things that had
precipitated the war,
one of the many causes that's always
cited as the naval arms race between
britain and Germany stayed in port.
For the most part.
Neither british nor the germans were
willing to risk these enormously
expensive and hard to replace surface
ships that were the what are called
capital ships,
battleships,
the really unbelievably expensive
lenses.
For example,
the british had just commissioned to
class ships known as the queen elizabeth
class of battleships,
which were so good in the first world
war.
They'd still be very effective units in
the second world war,
but if a cheap little submarine could
sink one of those ships with a torpedo,
that's nothing that any naval commanders
were willing to risk,
and so all of a sudden,
everybody's being so careful with their
big ships that it leaves openings for
the little ships to make a difference.
Everyone thought at the beginning of the
war that these submarines would be used
in the military sense against other
warships by february 19 slash 15.
The germans are now using them against
merchant shipping and all of a sudden
the greatest navy in the world finds
that they can't defend their merchant
shipping because of a new technological
creation.
We're weAker.
Naval power has the potential to turn
the tables on the best weapon that the
great naval powers have blockading
weaker naval powers and the british who
are doing a very good job of keeping
goods and weapons from flowing into
Germany by sea are finding out that the
germans had the capability to do the
same thing back to them.
Now the big issue will surface,
if you'll pardon the pun,
around whether or not the warfare should
follow the old famous rules of the ce or
not.
The old famous rules of the c word that
you didn't destroy,
you know,
merchant shipping nonmilitary vessels
without letting them know that's piracy.
You basically are supposed to give them
a message and say,
we're seizing your ship.
Let them take their people off the ship
on lifeboats and stuff,
and then you can either sink the vessel
that you were after or you can take it
as a prize and Capture it.
The problem is,
when the submarines tried to do this,
it opened them up to being destroyed and
the british played this up.
They started putting guns on all these
merchant ships.
So if the germans came up and did what
they were supposed to do,
tell the merchant ship were captured
your prize of war.
Now get your life boats out,
get your people off the ship and we'll
sync it.
They'd often pull the canvas off a gun
and starts shooting at the now
vulnerable submarine because it had,
had to surface in order to comply with
the international laws of war,
right to the germans were having these
debates in 1915 about whether or not
they should do that at all.
Maybe they should just sink these
vessels without surfacing or warning
them or anything.
But this again would look like the
germans were,
you know,
the ones outside international law were
the ones who were the bad guys.
And worse than that,
they risked alienating neutral powers.
The most important of which was the
United States,
which was a very,
um,
know maritime power,
huge into trade.
And by the way,
at this point in the war,
if you wanted to say who's gaining from
the first world war,
it's the United States because one of
the things that all these powers do when
they find out they can't produce enough
shells and weapons and war materials to
keep the war going,
is borrow money from the United States
and then turn around and spend that
borrowed money on stuff and production
from the United States often called the
great neutral.
The United States just wants to be able
to keep delivering their stuff where it
has to go.
They're already getting tense with the
british,
you know,
searching their ships and saying that
this shipper,
that ship can dock at this porter,
that port.
But when the germans start sinking
merchant vessels,
sometimes those merchant vessels have
americans on them.
In early 1915,
one of those vessels was called the
lusitania.
The lusitania,
if you want to think of it,
you know,
to conceptualize what we're talking
about here is very much like the titanic
and extremely large ocean liner,
a passenger ship.
This is how people got from the old
world,
the new world,
and back again across the atlantic in
the days before transatlantic air
flight.
Now,
controversy has raged ever since the
german submarine,
which opened fire on the lusitania,
sank that ship on whether or not he was
a legitimate target of war.
They did have munitions.
If it did,
supposedly they could sync it.
There's a lot of evidence that suggested
did and some conspiracy theories out
there that suggests that people like
winston churchill assured that it did so
that it would be another nail in the
coffin he was starting to construct that
would eventually get the United States
into the war.
More than 100 americans were on the
lusitania and died when it went down at
various times in the war,
the germans would start up what was
called unrestricted submarine warfare,
where they shot at anything that looked
like enemy ship of any kind and other
times where they would stop because
there was a huge debate within the halls
of german leadership over whether or not
they gained more or last more when they
did this.
If the United States comes into the war,
it's a huge loss,
but it's one of the few ways that in
1915 they can see that they can bring
britain to its knees.
They can starve that island in ways that
the british never could have imagined
before the war because before the war
they thought you had to have a bigger
navy to do that.
Technology had turned the tables on the
greatest naval power in history.
The perhaps the most iconic asymmetrical
warfare of this period has to do with
something that was a big worry at the
hague.
Conferences in the late 18 hundreds and
early 19 hundreds.
Something that shows the desperation of
the germans at this stage in the war
that they would resort to this.
It involves the use of what the hague
conference called asphyxiating gases.
Everyone had realized by the late 18
hundreds that the modern chemical
industry is.
We would recognize it today,
had come of age mean there were all
sorts of explosive gunpowders and
everything that we're so much more
explosive than had been the case in
napoleon's time,
less than a century beforehand.
So everyone was aware of the
possibilities,
but gunpowder and explosives were just
more powerful versions of weapons that
had been used for a very long time.
The chemical industry made possible the
use of weapons that had never been used
and that no one knew.
You know,
what the effects if they were used,
would be.
And so with the hague conference in
1899,
the issue was addressed.
The conference outlawed the use of
poison or poisoned weapons,
arms projectiles or material calculated
to cause unnecessary suffering and
projectiles designed for the diffusion
of is fixating or deleterious gases and
to quote.
But in 1915,
Germany is looking at all these laws of
war through a completely different lens
as we said,
the tradeoff between follow
international law or lose the war.
What's more,
they're dealing with this front.
As we sat on the western front that had
solidified in interesting ways.
As we said,
you have a continuous trench system from
the swiss border all the way you know,
up to the ocean.
And the interesting part is a lot of
that territory is not really good
fighting ground.
A lot of it's to marshy.
A lot of it's to forest did a lot of it.
The germans are in such an amazingly
strong position.
You'd be an idiot to challenge them,
which leaves the same few spots as good
areas to launch offensive,
you know,
campaigns,
which means that those areas become the
most horrific battlefields in human
history because they basically don't
move very much for the entire war and
the same ground is plowed up by
artillery shells over and over again.
The people that die in,
some of these places are never buried
and so you have a charnel house of
horrors of people who have just been
killed the other day.
People that were killed a month ago,
people that were killed a year ago,
all in the same spot and you as the
soldier have to live in this environment
and that of course ignores the more
mundane aspects,
which is if you are trapped in a trench
and you can't move without being shot,
where do you go to the bathroom?
I mean early on in the combat,
british soldiers were talking about
taking the german helmets with the
spikes on them as souvenirs for the war,
but quickly realized that the best thing
you could do with those things is used
them as a receptacle for the call of
nature and then toss it as far away from
the trenches possible so that the smell
of thousands of men doing this in a
confined space over years doesn't
overwhelm you.
As We said,
certain battlegrounds like ipa will
become famous for their smell and you
will be able to smell them before you
get anywhere near them.
The canadians are arrivinG in early 1915
in numbers and they take over some of
these battlefields.
You know where nothing has changed.
I mean no one's gone out and buried
anybody.
That was one of the things,
by the way,
during the christmas truce is that we
talked about that was the number one
thing both sides tried to do,
which tells you how crazy the smell and
the situation and now horrifying it must
have been,
but they jump out of these trenches and
start to try to bury these bodies that
have been out there for months.
Canadian soldier on the western front
arriving at the trenches of eat in early
1915 trenches that had been occupied by
the grca forces from around India and a
canadian sergeant name sv britain
describes his,
you know,
welcome to the western front in suitably
horrific terms.
He says,
quote,
left at 6:30
PM for reserve trenches and reached our
reserved dugouts via st julian just rat
holes.
One hell of an accommodation.
Got to the trenches as a fatigue party
with steak and sandbags,
and though there were reserved trenches,
they were so rotten.
No trenches at all in parts,
just isolated mounds,
found germans feet sticking up through
the ground.
The gurkhas had actually used human
bodies instead of sandbags right beside
the stream where we were working,
where the bodies of two dead since
november last one,
face downward in full marching order
with this kit on his back.
He died game stench,
something awful and dead all around
water rats had made a home of their
decomposed bodies visiting the barb wire
with ray,
ordinary wire strung across,
quit about 1:00
AM,
came back to our dugouts and found them
on fire.
Had to march out to st julien and put up
in a roofless house,
not a roof left on anything in the whole
place.
Found our sack of food had been stolen,
and we were famished.
Certainly a most unlucky day for I lost
my cherished pipe bed at 4:00
AM and quote,
well,
if the canadians thought the battlefield
and the traditional aspects of what war
had already come to be by that time were
as bad as it was going to get.
They were frightfully mistaken for at
this battle.
That will be called.
The second battle of ipa is the first
time that a major gas attack happens and
the canadians will be the reason that it
doesn't turn out to be a huge tragedy
for the allied cause.
The other reason will be that the
germans had no idea that their attack
was going to be this successful and this
becomes a pattern with all this new
technology.
Very often the commanders are trying to
figure out whether this new technology
is going to be something that's
effective and useful,
so they try it out on a small scale,
not really expecting to make good use of
it and because of the sheer shock of the
new stuff,
it proves wonderfully effective,
but it can't be exploited because the
generals who authorized it's use hadn't
planned to explore it.
If they were hoping to test it out a
little bit and then if it was good,
they'll use it later,
but by the time later Comes around,
the other side has figured out
countermeasurEs.
Gas worked exactly like that.
Then before it was used,
the german high command,
just as they did with submarine warfare,
debated whether or not this was a good
thing intensely.
As we said,
there were all these laws that the hague
conference had sat down saying you
couldn't use this stuff,
and some of the german leaders had said,
we sign these papers,
and others had found little loopholes
like legal loopholes that said,
well,
it said we couldn't use shovels,
but nothing said anything about just
taking the lids off of,
you know,
containers that had chlorine gas in
them.
Historian eric dorm burroughs writes,
quote the same kind of murderously cold
war time mentality that would terminate
1200 civilians aboard the lusitania two
weeks later did not allow.
However,
for respect of international law,
german legal experts advised general
falcon hein,
that the attack could be justified
because the gas was released from
containers.
In fact,
just to save artillery shells and not
from projectiles.
On the other side of the debate,
duke albert avert and commander of the
sixth army argued that unleashing this
new weapon would not only be a moral but
also with dubious military value.
For the allies with the wind,
normally at their backs would probably
send 10 times as much gas onto german
positions.
Karl von item of the third army agreed
and then additional worries over the
quote,
tremendous scandal and quote that would
compromise in disgrace Germany in the
eyes of the world.
War haS nothing to do with chivalry
anymore.
He wrote,
the higher civilization rises,
the more vile man becomes and quote,
if anybody still had any of those old
19th century,
truly going back to ancient times,
versions of the romantic glorious,
heroic dual that they had been raised to
believe that war was operation.
Disinfectant will cure them of such
ills.
That will be the german name for the
program and the code word to start the
operation will be god punish england.
The operation involves almost 6,000
cylinders containing chlorine gas,
a byproduct of the German dye
manufacturing industry that the germans
had planted in the soil carefully over
time,
around the battlefield that ether in
August,
1915,
they took the tops off the containers
when the wind was right and let the
chlorine gas blow across the battlefield
toward the allied trenches.
Which were occupied by french algerian
forces which involve both french troops
and Algeria and troops,
and also the newly arrived canadian
forces.
They didn't know what to make of this,
but they figured out pretty quickly it
was hell on earth as one indian soldier
would write his father afterwards.
This isn't war.
This is the end of the world.
The end of the world to some of these
people at the second battle of ipa
looked like a cloud of greenish yellow
gas that was floating across the
battlefield so slowly you could actually
walk ahead of it,
but because these soldiers didn't know
what they were looking at,
most of them didn't move until it hit
them.
Again.
Historian eric dorn bros quote,
stretching 6,000
meters along opposing lines and
bellowing high up into the air.
A thick,
ghastly looking green.
Yellow cloud of gas moved eerily and
threateningly with the breeze across no
man's land.
The gassiest monstrosity took on a
pinkish hue from certain angles.
As the descending western sun shone
through it.
To compound the shock and terror,
german heavy artillery began to lay down
a pounding barrage to french colonial
divisions.
And a canadian division were caught
completely unaware.
Quote,
take a look at this.
Sir said one canadian artillery observer
to his superior as he stared through
binoculars,
it was coming towards them.
There's something funny going on when he
dove for cover from the incoming shells,
but just then the wind shifted
compressing the gas cloud over the
algerian who's forward units were the
soldiers grabbed their throats,
choking and riding in excruciating pain
from the searing chlorine gas in
minutes.
Many hundreds laid drowning in fluids
given off by the lungs.
Seeing this others panicked,
drop their rifles and ran,
leaving a six kilometer gap in the line
and quote private william quintin,
a british soldier experience his first
gas attack only about a week after the
first time it had been used.
That affair had caused
the high command to tell the troops to
soak flannel in water and just put it
over their noses is a cheap,
easy attempt to try to forestall the
gas.
But none of these soldiers knew what
they were facing until they actually,
you know,
had a gas attack hit them.
Which quintin had hit him on May 1st 19,
15 quote.
Suddenly over the top of our front line,
we saw what looked like clouds of thin
gray smoke rolling slowly along with a
slight wind.
It hung,
did the ground reaching to the height of
eight or nine feet and approached so
slowly that a man walking could have
kept ahead of it.
Gas the word quickly passed round even
now,
it had no terror for us,
for we had not yet tasted it from our
hammer stacks.
We hastily drew the flannel belts,
soak them in water,
and tied them around our mouths and
noses.
Suddenly through the communication
trench came rushing.
A few khaki clad figures,
their eyes glaring out of their heads,
their hands tearing at their throats as
they came on,
some stumbled and fell and lay writhing
at the bottom of the trench.
Choking and gasping will those following
trampled over them.
If ever men were raving mad with terror,
these men were what was left of our
section.
Still crouched at the support end of the
communication trench are frontline.
Judging from the number of men who just
come from,
it had been abandoned and we now waited
for the first rush of germans,
but they did not come.
Our biggest enemy was now within a few
yards of us and in the form of a cloud
of gas.
We caught our first whiff of it.
No words of mine can ever describe my
feelings as we inhaled the first
mouthful.
We choked,
spit and coughed.
My lungs felt as though they were being
burnt out,
that they were going to burst.
Red hot needles were being thrust into
my eyes.
The first impulse Was to run.
We had just seen men running to certain
death and knew it rather than stay and
be choked into a slow and agonizing
death.
It was one of those occasions when you
do not know what you were doing.
The men who stayed was no braver than
the man who ran away.
We crouched.
They're terrified.
Stupefied a large shell burst on the
pair of pitt.
Just where we were sheltered.
We were almost buried beneath the
falling earth.
Young addington,
a chap about my own age was screaming at
the top of his voice and trying to free
his buried legs.
He got free and before we could stop
him,
he rushed off.
God knows where we then saw the reason
for his screams.
His left was blown off above the elbow.
He left a trail of blood over my tunic
as he climbed over me in a mad rush to
get away and to quote
quintin and his unit of canadians will
block heroically in the hole that
develops in the line keeping the germans
from breaking through.
Of course,
the germans hadn't expected to break
through.
The entire reason for this gas attack
was to experiment with the gas and to
cover the fact that the germans were
removing troops for use on the eastern
front.
The german high command had no idea it
was going to be this successful and no
one had any idea how horrifying it was
going to be.
Private.
William quintin and his unit will move
up to the front line and will experience
the aftermath of what the gas attack did
to the people who first encountered it.
He wrote,
quote black in the face,
their tunics and shirt fronts torn open
at the next,
in their last desperate fight for
breath.
Many of them quite still while others
were still wriggling and kicking in the
agonies of the most awful death I've
ever seen.
Some were wounded in the bargain and
they're gaping wounds.
Lay open.
Blood's still oozing from them.
One poor devil was tearing at his throat
with his hands.
I doubt if he knew or felt that he had
only one hand and that the other was
just a stump where the hand should have
been this stump.
He worked around his throat as if his
hand was still there and the blood from
it was streaming over his bluish black
face and neck.
A few minutes later,
he was still except for occasional
shutters as he breathed his last and
quote,
as I've said before in this program,
and I think I will say many times more.
This is the most horrifying sustained
situation of terribleness I've ever seen
soldiers forced to endure and millions
and millions of people will get to
experience this before the end of the
conflict.
My own grandfather would be gassed on
the western front and he was never the
same afterwards.
The use of poison gas is a defining
moment in this conflict,
one that puts the final end stamp on the
19th century victorian romantic ideals
of warfare.
You can't pretend anymore when human
beings are being treated.
You know the way you would treat ants
with a can of raid or some other
insecticide even before gases used the
times of london,
the great paper in britain.
In November,
1914,
we'll run an article which seems amazing
by modern standards,
but of course we're in a post first and
second world war era now.
Those people were coming into this
conflict with certain ideals and
understandings of what war was going to
be like and the trenches and the
continual death for no apparent gain had
shaken their whole view of what war was
all about.
November 19,
14,
the times ran this piece quote,
all the spectacular side of the war has
gone never to reappear trenches and
always trenches and within range of the
concealed guns in visibility.
The supreme law,
day after day,
the butchery of the unknown by the
unseen war has become stupid.
The strain on the infantry is tremendous
and it is endless at the cost of
thousands of lives,
a few hundred yards maybe gained,
but rarely indeed does.
Even the most brilliant attack produce
anything fresh troops brought up under
cover of a tremendous artillery fire,
which opens up by surprise,
may affect a breach,
but only with heavy loss.
Can such an attack be carried through
and to quote that little rundown about
how war has become stupid,
now accurately describes what the entire
year of 1915 on the western front will
be like.
Nobody's going to move at all and
amazing numbers of people are going to
die in efforts that gain nothing.
Now in the defense of the general sue,
order these efforts to gain nothing.
They have to figure out how to do things
including experimentation to our minds.
You would think you would stop after a
while,
but these people had to figure out how
to win the war.
I mean,
they didn't even know,
for example,
how to get through the ever expanding
fields of barbed wire that crop up
between the two enemy trench lines.
You have to have battles to simply see
what kind of artillery blows up enough
of the wire to create a path for your
troops to attack through.
This is lessons being learned at an
incredible cost,
but there's really no other way to do
it.
It's fascinating to look at pictures
already in 1915,
six to eight months after the war has
started and see how this period has
become sort of an estuary between the
19th and the 20th century where you see
the combination of the two centuries
blending.
I mean when the war starts,
you have cavalry that is
indistinguishable from napoleon's queer
sears going off to war with gleaming
breastplates and horse herrick helmets
and sabers and spurs and white gloves,
and now you have gas and soon you're
going to have,
you know,
german cavalry lancers.
For example.
As soon as 1916 rolls around,
they start having the same helmet that
the germans would use in the second
world war,
the stall helm,
and you have know cavalry with lances
and install helm and a gas mask,
and it's the perfect example of the two
arrows blending in sort of like I said,
a historical estuary.
You go from that napoleonic feeling of
war with french soldiers going off into
the conflict with bright red pants.
You know,
in six to eight months later,
we have gas,
we have flame throwers,
we have hundreds of guns,
a time firing on battlefields.
We have trenches,
barbed wire,
snipers everywhere.
This is not what anybody thought was
going to happen and it begins to unhinge
a lot of people,
which is something that is new to the
human experience,
at least as far as the modern european
armies are concerned.
People begin to go insane
to lose their mind,
to have their nerves shattered,
and this is something,
as I said,
no,
this war does something that seems
unbelievable.
The ability to take one of the most
stressful situations human beings ever
find themselves in and make it worse
because all war is psychologically
challenging,
isn't it?
What made the first world war more
difficult than almost any other major
conflict you can think of is not just
the changes in warfare,
although that's significant,
but how long the soldiers were forced to
deal with it.
I mean take one of the worst battles in
human history to be a soldier in the
famous second punic war battle of kony,
right where hannibal and his
carthaginians famously surround maybe
80,000
romans and then spend the entire
afternoon.
No slaughtering them by hand,
cutting their way into the center of
this crowd of doomed men who have to
wait all day in the most unbelievably
just orienting environment you can think
of.
They can't hear anything.
They can't see anything.
There's dust everywhere,
but they know what's coming and were
told by the ancient writers.
That's so terrible that when the
carthaginians cut their way into the
center of this massive doomed men,
they will find that some roman soldiers
packed so tightly that they couldn't
even raise their hands in this crowd of
people just sunk to their knees,
dug a little hole with their hands,
put their head in the hole and covered
it up,
committing suicide because either they
had lost their minds or they'd come to
the conclusion,
why wait for the inevitable that's
supposed to show you how terrible the
situation is in the first world war.
You begin to see very quickly people who
are unhinged,
these soldiers trapped at the battle of
[inaudible].
we're having a historic bad day,
but it was one day a week or two before
that battle.
They were in relatively little danger if
they survived a week or two after that
battle,
same thing.
The soldiers in the great war had no
such luxury.
They had to deal with these
circumstances day after day after day
and after this war.
Military psychologist looking into the
phenomenon of what will later be known
as shell shock will determine that under
the conditions these soldiers were
fighting in.
It doesn't matter how brave you were.
Eventually,
you know,
we each had a different threshold we
could stand,
but eventually anyone would lose their
mind.
Think about what's involved and you
begin to understand why.
First take the shelling itself,
which is something that is really
impossible for any of us to understand.
There are very few people living that
have ever been through the kinds of
shelling that these world war one
soldiers routinely had to deal with and
it's very hard to describe one of the
traditional kinds of shelling in that
war was something that came to be known
as drum fire.
Drum fire is so named because it sounds
like a drum roll.
And instead of,
you know,
just hearing the drum being tapped at
that speed,
each one of those things represent a
shell going off.
That's how quickly the shells are
landing.
Ernst,
younger who we've quoted,
uh,
the author of the storm of steel,
one of the most unusual soldiers by the
way in the first world war because he
kind of liked the war and he kind of saw
positive benefits to it,
you know,
so sort of the uplifting side of war.
And he was about as brave as any soldier
you will ever find lost his composure
under artillery fire.
He explains a situation where he comes
under fire and just loses his mind
temporarily.
You know this again,
one of the strongest people mentally in
the first world war that we know about
and younger says,
quote,
we fell out and extended order and lay
down expectantly and a series of
flattish depressions that some
predecessors of ours had scooped out of
the ground are rebelde.
Conversations were suddenly cut off by a
marrow freezing cry 20 yards behind us,
clumps of earth,
world up out of a white cloud and
smacked into the bows.
The crash echoed through the woods
stricken eyes,
looked at each other.
Bodies pressed themselves into the
ground with a humbling sensation of
powerlessness to do anything else.
Explosion followed explosion choking
gases drifted over,
the undergrowth,
smoke obscured the tree tops,
trees and branches came crashing to the
ground,
screams.
We leapt up and ran blindly,
chased by lightnings and crushing air
pressure from tree to tree,
looking for cover,
skirting around giant tree trunks like
frightened game,
a dugout where many men had taken
shelter and which I too was running
towards,
took a direct hit that ripped up the
planking and sent heavy timber spinning
through the air like a couple of
squirrels having stones thrown at them.
The nco and I dodged panting around a
huge beach tree quite mechanically and
spurred on by further explosions.
I ran after my superior who sometimes
turn round and stared at me wild.
I yelling,
what in god's name are those things?
What are they?
Suddenly there was a flash among the
route work and a below on the left thigh
flung me to the ground.
I thought I had been struck by a clump
of earth,
but the warm trickle of blood indicated
that I had been wounded.
Later I saw that a needle sharp piece of
had given me a flesh wound.
Don't my wallet had taken the brunt of
it,
the fine cut,
which before slicing into the muscle had
split.
No fewer than nine thicknesses of stout
leather looked as though it might've
been administered by a scalpel.
He continues.
I threw down my haversack and ran toward
the trench we had come from,
from all sides,
wounded men were making tracks towards
it from the shelled woods.
The trench was appalling,
choked with seriously wounded and dying.
Men of figure stripped to the waist with
a ripped open back,
leaned against the parapet another with
a triangular flap hanging off the back
of his skull emitted short high pitched
screams.
This was the home of the great god pain,
and for the first time I looked through
a devilish chink into the depths of his
realm and fresh shells came down all the
time.
I lost my head completely.
Ruthlessly.
I barged past every one on my path
before finally having fallen back a few
times in my haste,
climbing out of the hellish crush of the
trench to move more freely above like a
bolting horse.
I rushed through the dense undergrowth
across paths and clearings.
To I collapse in the cops by the grand
trine,
she and quote this one of the most
suicidal,
he brave soldiers of the great war.
If it can happen to him,
it could happen to anyone and I am
constantly amazed at the immense bravery
and an almost carelessness of death that
our grandparents and great grandparents
showed consistently in this conflict and
I always wonder about how I do or my
generation would do in the same
situation.
Younger tries later on to explain what
the feeling of being in an artillery
barrage is like.
And it's difficult because we have
nothing to compare it to.
have you ever been on an airplane,
for example,
with when it's in heavy turbulence and
it takes one of those horrible drops in
your stomach?
Just sort of.
I mean there's.
I can't even describe that feeling and
that's nothing younger.
Writes this in one of the greatest
descriptions I've ever heard of what it
feels like and he was trying to explain
it to people who've never experienced
it.
He wrote this quote.
It's an easier manner to describe these
sounds than to endure them because one
cannot put associate every single sound
of flying steel with the idea of death,
and so I huddled in my hole in the
ground with my hand in front of my face,
imagining all the possible variants of
being hit.
I think I found a comparison that
captures the situation in which I and
all the other soldiers who took part in
this war so often found ourselves.
You musT imagine that you were securely
tied to a post beinG menaced by a man
swinging a heavy hammer.
Now the hammer has been taken back over
his head,
ready to be swung.
Now it's cleaving the air towards you on
the point of touching your skull.
Then it struck the post and the
splinters flying.
That's what it's like to experience
heavy shelling in an exposed position
and quote.
Now when you can take cover in the
trench and press yourself up against the
earth and dig your head into the soil
and try to just weather the storm,
that's hard enough,
but there are a lot of times in this
conflict.
A lot of times when your job is to run
through the drum,
fire in the hail of shells,
to do everything your body tells you not
to do.
If orange younger can get carried away
by the shell fire,
you know what hope do regular role joe's
like yours truly have right yulia scotch
and is in one of those situations that
soldiers all through the war will be in.
When you know some officer blows a
whistle and says,
time to jump out of the trench and run
past the gunfire,
and he writes the feeling you have when
it's your turn.
We had approached the firing line a
little more than two miles when we got
within reach of the enemy's curtain of
fire.
A terrific hail of shells was plowing up
every foot of ground.
Thousands of corpses of german soldiers
were witnesses to the immense loss as
the germans had suffered in bringing up
all available reserves.
the french tried their utmost to prevent
the germans from bringing in their
reserves and increased their artillery
fire to an unheard of violence.
It seemed impossible for us to break
through that barricade of fire.
Hundreds of shells were bursting every
minute.
We were ordered to pass that hell singly
and that a running pace.
We were lying on the ground and observed
how the first of our men tried to get
through.
some ran forward like mad,
not heating.
The shells that were bursting around
them and got through.
Others were entirely buried by the dirt,
dug up by the shells or were torn to
pieces by shell splinters.
Two men had scarcely reached the line
when they were struck by a bullseye.
I eat the heavy shell,
exploded at their feet,
leaving nothing of them who can imagine
what we were feeling during these
harrowing minutes as we lay crouching on
the ground,
not quite a hundred feet away,
seeing everything and only waiting for
our turn to come.
One had entangled oneself and amaze of
thoughts.
Suddenly one of the officers Would cry.
The next one that was I just as if
roused out of a bad dream,
I jumped up and race away like mad,
holding the rifle in my right hand and
the bayonet in my left eye.
Jump aside a few steps in front of to
bursting shells and running into two
others which are bursting at the same
time.
I leapt back several times,
run forward again,
race about wildly to find a gap through
which to escape,
but fire an iron everywhere like a
hunted beast.
One,
seek some opening To save oneself.
hell is in front of me and behind me.
The officers revolver kept ready to
shoot the lumps of steel,
fall down like a heavy shower from high
above hell and damnation.
I blindly run and run and run until
someone gets me by my coat.
Where there someone roars into my ear,
stopped.
Are you wounded?
Have a look.
Perhaps you are and you don't know it.
Here I am trembling all over.
Sit down.
The other person says,
you will feel better.
We trembled too.
End quote.
How many of us could do that and think
about the mentality and how these people
were raised,
you know,
and what was involved that allowed them
to do this.
I mean,
I have a feeling that my generation
would just turn around at the office or
holding a gun to wash to get us to do
that and figure that guy can't take us
all out.
We're not going into that.
We did a history show once about the
question of whether the older generation
raised in a different time.
We're tougher than we were,
and of course there's no way to really
come to any conclusions about that,
but when you read this and you see what
our grandparents and great grandparents
did,
it boggles the mind and if those shells
will drive you insane,
the carnage that they create that you
have to live around every day just may.
As I said,
one of the terrible things about this
battle that's different from most of the
second world war is in the second world
war.
you have what's called the moving front.
When dire in his famous piece war talked
about the continuous front,
as he calls it,
the first world war initiated in the
second world war.
The continuous front moves,
right?
You have blitzkrieg and the people are
continually changing locations.
What makes the battlefields of the first
world war,
as we said earlier,
so particularly horrifying,
is that it doesn't change location.
You get to live around the carnage from
years past,
even in the second world war eugene
sledge riding,
you know from the us marines talking
about fighting in the pacific.
We'll talk about his particularly
horrified feeling as he watched flies
that were feeding on dead bodies right
near him,
fly right to the edge of his coffee cup
and land in his coffee.
these are the little horrifying things
that you would think after a while will
just drive you out of your mind.
Phillip gibbs and his absolutely
groundbreaking work now it can be told
was a journalist on the scene,
as we said earlier,
and unable to write about the reality of
the war until afterwards.
He describes one of these situations and
just how incredible it was to have to
live in this.
It's worse than the charnel house.
He describes an area called a huge that
was so terrible near the battlefield and
he says,
quote,
the worst school of war for the sons of
gentleman was in those days and for long
afterwards huge.
This was the devil's playground and his
chamber of horrors wherein he devised
mary tortures for young christian men.
It waS not far out of [inaudible] to the
left of the men and road and to the of
is wildwood and sanctuary would for a
time.
There was a chateau.
They're called the white shadow with
excellent stables and good accommodation
for one of our brigades staffs until one
of our generals was killed and others
wounded by a shell which broke up their
conference.
Afterwards.
There was no shadow but only a rubble of
bricks banked up with sandbags and deep
mind craters filled with stinking water
slopping over from the belvoir data lake
and low lying pools.
Bodies and bits of bodies and clots of
blood and green.
Metallic looking.
Slime made by explosive gases were
floating on the surface of that water
below the crater banks when I first
passed that way,
and so it was always our men live there
and died there within a few yards of the
enemy crouched below the sand bags and
pasted into the mud banks.
If they dug to get deeper,
cover their shovels went into the
softness of dead bodies who had been
their comrades.
Scraps of flesh,
booted legs,
blackened hands,
eilis heads came falling over them.
When the enemy trench more in their
position or blew up a new mineshaft end
quote,
how would that not drive anybody crazy?
That is war made worse.
That's you living in zombie land and
being shelled at the same time.
It's.
It is,
As I said many times and will continue
to say,
this is the worst experience for
soldiers in warfare I've ever seen on a
mass scale,
even in stalin grodd and the second
world war,
widely considered one of the worst
places to be in the world.
That just equals the experience that
many men on the western front got to
experience routinely.
How did they deal with it in ways that
are some sort of a wonderful testament
to human nature?
They often joked about it.
They adopted a sort of gallows humor at
times that reminds you of police
officers or firemen or let's be honest,
journalists and soldiers and people who
see this horrible stuff and their way of
coping with it.
His humor,
the journalist Philip Gibbs experienced
this and took part in it,
and this was his theory on the whole
thing.
It was astonishing how loudly one laugh
to tales of gruesome things of wars
brutality I with the rest of them.
I think at the bottom of it was a sense
of the ironical contrast between the
normal ways of civilian life and this
hark back to the cave man code.
it made all of our old philosophy of
life monstrously ridiculous.
It played the hat trick with the
gentility of modern manners.
Men who had been brought up to christian
virtues who would prattle dear little
prayers at their mother's knees who had
grown up to love poetry,
painting music,
the gentle arts over sensitized to the
subtleties of halftones delicate scales
of emotion.
Fastidious in their choice of words,
in their sense of beauty found
themselves compelled to live and act
like eight men and it was a bottom
bubbly funny.
They laughed at the most frightful
episodes which revealed this contrast
between civilized ethics and the old
beast law.
The more revolting it was,
the more sometimes they shouted with
laughter,
especially in reminiscence,
when the tail was told of the gilded
sAlon of the french chateau or at the
table,
it was I think he writes the Laughter of
mortals at the trick which had been
played on them by an ironical fate.
They had been taught to belIeve that the
whole object of life was to reach out to
beauty and love and that mankind in its
progress to perfection had killed the
beast instinct,
cruelty,
blood,
lust,
the primitive savage laws of survival by
tooth and claw and club and acts,
all poetry,
all art.
All religion had preached this gospel in
this promise.
Now that ideal had broken like a China
vase dash to hard ground.
The contrast between that,
and this was devastating,
and to quote the stories that they told
were both funny and revealing in a
horrified way,
like the gallows humor you see from
police officers and soldiers and
whatnot.
OnE of the ones is this one quote in one
section of trenches,
the men made a habit of bedding upon
those who would be wounded.
First.
It had all the uncertainty of the
roulette table.
One day when the german gunners were
putting over a special dose of hate,
a sergeant kept coming to one dugout to
inquire about a quote end quote,
new chum who had come up with the drafts
is private smith.
All right,
he asked,
yes,
sergeant,
he's all right,
answered the men crouching in the dark
hole.
Private.
Smith isn't wounded yet.
Asked the sergeant again.
Five minutes later,
no sergeant
private smith was touched by this
interest in his wellbeing and said,
that sergeant seems a very kind man,
said,
the boy seems to love me like a father.
A yell of laughter answered him.
You pour bleediNg.
Fools said one of his comrades,
he's drawn you in a lottery.
Stood dwayne,
if you'd been hit,
and another example of this amazing
ability of human beings to adapt in
these kinds of situations with the tools
given to us,
including humor,
which again you,
you,
you look at survivors of auschwitz and
treblinka and the death camps of the
nazis.
The jews were using humor even there to
cope.
Gibbs tells this story quote
in digging new trenches in new dugouts.
Bodies and bits of bodies were on earth
and put into sand bags with the soil
that was sent back down the line of men
concealing their work from german eyes
waiting for any new activity in our
ditches.
Bit of bill said,
the leading man putting in the leg.
Another bit of bill,
he said,
unearthing a hand bills,
ugly mug.
He said at a later stage in the
operation when a head was found,
gibbs says,
quote,
as told afterwards,
that little episode in the trenches
seemed immensely.
Comic generals chuckled over it.
Chaplains treasured it and quote all the
coping mechanisms in the world.
Though we're not enough to help.
You know when things got to a really
critical stage,
every human being has a breaking point
as we said,
and what in the first world war was
called shell shock.
We mentioned it earlier,
would later be updated to battle fatigue
as soon as the experts realized it was
an imprecise term because you didn't
have to be exposed to artillery shells
at all to get it.
Now we would call It post traumatic
stress disorder.
You see it in soldiers today.
It's pretty common now.
I'm not just not a historian.
I'm not a psychologist either,
so take this with a grain of salt,
but this is something that appears to be
what they call a spectrum disorder,
meaning you can have a severity scale
like one to 10,
and not to minimize anything our current
veterans go through,
but they'll often come back from these
wars,
you know,
with nightmares or an inability to sleep
or eat properly or to reintegrate into
society and they've obviously suffered
some trauma and damage.
In the first world war though,
those people would often be shot if you
couldn't see visible evidence.
And oftentimes,
even if you could,
the people in that era,
especially early in the war,
didn't look at this as some sort of a
legitimate problem.
To them,
this was just another manifestation of
cowardice,
punishable by death.
Take for example,
Philip Gibbs,
his account,
and he has a bunch of them because this
was one of the things that upset him the
most.
He would go to the front report on what
the soldiers had to endure and then once
they were damaged by what they had to
endure,
report on how the completely clueless
militaries of the day,
you know,
then punish them again for something
they were already victimized once for he
tells one story,
for example,
of an officer that he's meeting with who
comes back to the meeting with him from
a court marshal hearing.
He'd just been to where they had
sentenced one of these people who had
had his mind blown by his experience to
death.
He says,
quote,
going up to kemo one day I had to wait
in battalion headquarters for the
officer.
I'd gone to see he was attending a court
marshal.
Presently.
He came into the wooden hut with a
flushed face.
Sorry,
I had to keep you.
He said,
tomorrow there will be one swine less in
the world,
a death sentence.
Gabe said.
He nodded a damned coward,
said he didn't mind rifle,
fire,
but couldn't stand shells.
Admitted he left his post.
He doesn't mind rifle.
Fire.
Well,
tomorrow morning,
the officer laughed,
grimley and then listened for a second.
There were some heavy crumps fallen over
campbell hill rather close.
It seemed to our wooden hut.
He's talking about artillery shells
falling nearby,
by the way.
Damn those german gunners said,
the officer,
why can't they give us a little piece?
he turned to his papers,
but several times while I talked with
him,
he jerked his head up and listen to a
heavy crash.
On the way back,
I saw a man on foot walking in front of
a mountain man past the old hill,
loved the shepherd berg.
Toward the village of luck.
There was something in the way he walked
in,
his attitude,
the head hunched forward a little and
his arms behind his back,
which made me turn to look at him.
He was manacled and tied by a rope to
the mountain man.
I caught one glimpse of his face and
then turned away cold and sick.
There was doom written on his face and
in his eyes,
a captured look.
He was walking to his wall and quote,
meaning the wall where he was going to
be put up against and shocked by his
compatriots.
Gibbs later quotes another general
saying that anyone who comes down with
these symptoms as a damn coward and he'd
have them all shot now early in the war.
This is how they thought because they
didn't deal with this routinely.
There had been a little talk of this
during the so japanese war,
a decade before this,
where the russians were encountering
this kind of a problem,
but this was a new experience.
This idea of combat fatigue,
battle fatigue,
shell shocked.
This would be stuff by the way,
that all the major militaries of the
world would study after the first world
war and they would incorporate what they
learned into training procedures and how
you dealt with combat in the next war to
try to minimize these problems.
Even later in the first world war,
the generals would learn that you need
to rotate your troops away from the
front lines,
you know,
at regular intervals,
you can't leave them up there
indefinitely or they're all going to go
crazy,
so you'll see these times where for a
week or two,
the troops will have to live in the mud
in three feet of standing water under
shell fire,
you know,
all the time,
but then they'll take them to the back,
to the rear areas that are safer and
then let them recover and then slowly
move them back toward the front.
This rotation was intended to keep them
fresh and keep them from becoming
psychological casualties and you know,
these are people who are foaming at the
mouth sometimes when they are brought
back from the lines.
These aren't people who are saying,
I just can't handle it any more general.
Although sometimes that's what you
encounter.
These are people whose limbs have turned
to rigor mortis or who are so palsy.
They can't walk For the epileptic
seizures or seizure like things you're
seeing.
You can actually go sEe this by the way,
because after the war,
many of these people didn't heal.
They never healed.
Forty years later,
they're still taking up hospital
space in some of these countries and
there are films that the doctors made
showing you these people's symptoms and
they're online.
You can view them.
Some of these symptoms are so physical
in nature that this is kind of how the
term shell shock first became
fashionable because there were theories
that maybe the concussion and the change
in air pressure that the shells nearby,
you know,
exploding actually did brain damage or
nerve damage to these people because
when you actually see some of these
cases and how they're affected,
that looks like physical damage.
It doesn't look like mental damage,
but again,
that did not prevent the militaries from
treating this as cowardice,
especially early on and dishing out the
capital punishment penalty for it.
That having been said,
it's still fascinating to me how few
actually had to be executed for this
stuff.
Sometimes you can read books where the
british hurt themselves in the 19
seventies.
I have a book from the 19 seventies and,
and it's just this outbreak,
you know,
and you look in and 330 people or
executed or something for uh,
you know,
running away in combat,
abandoning your post desertion,
those kinds of things.
And I think to myself,
I think my generation,
if we were forced to go through what
those people had to go through,
that's how many people they'd shoot in a
month
because what's happening in 1915 and you
can sum up the entire western front in
1915,
you don't have to deal with any of the
battles is that the situation is,
is degenerating into what we understand.
The first reward would be like on the
western front trenches and defenses that
are becoming evermore sophisticated.
We are now getting beyond the era where
we are talking about,
you know,
one long trench on one side and one long
trench on the other and maybe a little
bit of sophistication here and there,
but you know,
it's a little barbed wire between and
we're entering into a phase now we're on
the western front.
You begin to have to fortifications and
you're not talking now about successful
attacks going after people.
You're trying to batter down defenses
that go sometimes miles backwards.
Historian eric dorm bros describes these
deepening 1915 fortifications like this
Quote.
When the Allies attacked in may 19,
15,
the trenches were shielded by two belts
of barbed wire each five feet high and
30 meters deep behind the wire lay a
trench network consisting of three
lines,
100 meters apart at regular intervals.
Each tranche had a zigzag or dog leg
traverse to shield defenders from shells
landing nearby and prevent attackers
from firing machine guns down the entire
length of the trench.
This network of trenches were supported
1000 meters back by concrete machine gun
pill boxes to mow down enemies.
Soldiers who pierced the forward
positions,
those
already formidable sounding defenses
were increased during the summer.
Burrows continues quote during the
summer,
a second double belt of barbed wire went
into place 1000 meters.
Behind the rear.
Pillbox is of the first trench system.
Then came a second triple line of
trenches,
also backed by machine gun emplacements.
The defenders also burrowed ever more
deeply into the ground to make the
system work optimally.
Monthly outputs of machine guns had
increased nearly 12 fold.
Both the first and second trench systems
were linked by communication trenches
for moving up.
Reinforcements are retreating
underground.
Telephone cables connected the first
line with the second as well as with the
artillery far to the rear general falcon
hinds,
well-designed kilometers deep double
killing zones amounted to a massive
engineering and construction project,
but it was carried out before the allies
attacked again in september and to quote
that's attacking a fortress now,
the allies were also deepening and
making their trenches more
sophisticated,
but not to the same degree the germans
were because the allies attitude is why
would we waste that much effort when
we're hoping the next attack or the next
attack breaks us through.
We be out of these trenches,
will be in their trenches.
The germans have a much more defensive
attitude on the western front at this
time.
They plan on staying a while.
They dig deeper into the earth and build
these bunk houses with timber overhead.
You know,
big trees laid down.
Log cabin style with earth on top of
that.
Sometimes they have carpeting on the
floor,
wallpaper on the walls,
shelving.
I mean it's in some ways a giant,
you know,
roman empire,
kind of hadrian's wall up and down the
line,
many belts deep.
These are insane fortifications.
Who in their right mind would think you
want to slam human beings up against
that over and over again.
Well,
french and british military leadership
on the continent.
That's who francis military leaders
also.
Jennifer has an attitude of just get
them out there on the sacred soil to
France.
It's also important resource and
industrial territory.
You know,
jennifer will waste if necessary and
entire generation of young frenchman to
eject the honey from francis soil,
the hun being one of those propaganda
stake names for the germans and the
british commander of british forces in
France.
Confusingly,
unironically named as we said before,
sir John French agrees with jennifer.
Just give us more troops.
Were the bigger boxer in this prize
fight and who cares if we hit their
elbows and their wrists and their bones?
They're going down eventually,
just give us more troops who will pound
these fortifications down,
and the way they did this,
by the way,
was with more guns.
Nineteen 15 is not just the beginning of
the heavy duty trench warfare,
it's the beginning of the attempts to
deal with the heavy duty trench warfare
and you'd do this with ever increasing
amounts of guns,
have bigger caliber and using them for
longer periods of time in just one of
these sort of double headed battles that
will be fought in the middle of the 1915
sir John French figures out a way to
break through these kinds of
fortifications is with many,
many hours of many,
many guns shooting in a confined area.
He stockpiles piles.
Five point 2 million shells for use in
this one.
Double-headed defensive,
so you're going to pound these
fortifications and then you're going to
send men into the gap to occupy them.
That's what a french general battan said
that artillery conquers the ground and
you send the men in afterwards to occupy
it.
That's the 1915 strategy.
It's also called by some commanders bite
and hold.
Some of these generals ideas was,
you know,
you're grabbing area,
you grab it with artillery,
you take it over with people when all
the other side's killed by the
artillery,
and then you start fortifying it.
You turn that into your little castle
and now you've just moved your sides,
fortifications more toward their side.
It's a giant moving war of trenches and
siege fortifications,
and when one side takes a new area,
the other side goes and attacks them
right away before they can fortify it
again.
It makes it impossible to follow these
battles,
but that's what 1915 looks like evermore
big guns ever more wasted opportunities,
evermore futility and the most forward
thinkers amongst the allied leaders and
decision makers are looking at this
already at the end of 1914 and they can
see it in the distance and they're
thinking to themselves,
must we go there?
A french thinker as supposed to have
floated the idea first,
but it was picked up most famously by
winston churchill and idea of finding a
flank in another fighting theater.
Why do we have to throw more troops into
the meat grinder?
The british empire is just starting to
produce a decent number of people.
They've got some building up of troops
happening.
These volunteers that first joined up at
the very beginning of the war are now
gone through their training period.
They're not going to be thrown in early
like general falcon hind did with those
poor students,
soldiers they're going to be husband did
for just the right time.
They're green,
but they're trained.
Must we throw these precious,
you know,
troops into the meat grinder.
More empire troops by the way,
are also showing up.
The canadians,
as we said,
and indians are already there,
but other troops really from dominions,
I think we said commonwealth earlier and
although the term was used,
it's not officially the right term until
between the two wars,
when commonwealth status is granted to
some of these places.
Um,
let's just call them dominions.
Troops from New Zealand and Australia
raised up again in,
in patriotic fervor for the cause and
large numbers of people relative to the
total population of these places.
They're on the way.
Are you really going to sacrifice all
these troops into attacking these deep
fortifications?
Well,
for the commanders on the western front,
french and british who were were of
the opinion that every person should be
thrown into the western front.
They would argue that it's only a meat
grinder on the western front because we
don't have enough men yet to overrun
that meat grinder and you give us enough
people will will end this war fast and a
lot less people will die.
There was,
as I mentioned earlier,
a kind of cabal of thinkers who had come
to the conclusion that that sort of
thinking was mistaken and that surely
there are better ideas out there than to
throw,
you know,
more and more human beings into the
teeth of the enemy's defenses.
That cabal had some famous members in
it.
Winston churchill,
for example,
maybe the most famous,
although lord horacio kitchener,
the war minister not far behind,
and these people were of the opinion,
I guess you could compare it to a sort
of a predatory idea.
They had been trying to take down the
nastiest animal in the herd for months
now and they'd gotten gord in the
process.
The germans had done damage to every
major member of the ally is by this time
and there were the great lions of France
and britain and Russia looking around
and thinking to themselves,
well,
why don't we just follow the traditional
predatory sort of approach and go after
the weak and the sick and the old
instead of going after the strong and
young and dangerous,
and there was a country in the war now
that met all three of those key
classifications as a guy like churchill
would have made them country that was
old and sick and weak.
There's more than a country was an
empire,
was a dying empire.
I've been calling a Turkey throughout
this whole show because that's the
proper name for it in the first world
war,
but there's another proper name to that
conjures up a whole different set of
images than the perhaps modern sounding
name of Turkey and that's the ottoman
empire
and that conjures up images of sultan
and janissaries and harem and being on
the gates of vienna,
almost overrunning into central europe.
At one point.
At the height of their history of
knocking down the walls.
of constantinople,
formerly known as byzantium to the
greeks,
constantinople to the romans,
and then after the salton,
you know,
got through that historic barrier and
conquered the city.
He renamed it is stem bowl as sort of a
momento and giant monument for what his
ottomans had achieved.
That was when the ottomans were young
and the ottomans were old now and they
were losing territory over the decades
like nobody's business.
They were seen as a carcass to be picked
at,
as we said,
the sick man of europe.
They were called and someone like
churchill looked at Turkey just sitting
there.
They come into the war in november,
several months after the war officially
starts and they're surrounded by water
and they're maybe not even a second rate
power.
They have the territory of a big second
rate power.
Lots of places trying to get out of
Turkey but still stuck in Turkey.
That's how an read might look at it or
occurred.
My look at it or an armenian might look
at it nonetheless without the means to
sort of protect all that territory.
And then one of their main reasons there
had been a war called the crimean war in
the middle of the 19th century is
because Turkey was so weak and yet so
filled with territory you could take
that the british and the french had to
get involved to keep the russians from
snapping up too much of it.
So this appeared to be the easy animal
in the herd to take down and a crucial
place that might have all sorts of
impact on the war.
If you did take him down,
take for example,
all the countries that hadn't decided
whose side they were going to fight on.
Yet when Turkey enters the war,
as we said,
it's a bit of a headache for the allies
because they opened up an entire new
theater of operations.
Really.
There might've been a little stuff on
the side going on,
but when Turkey gets into the warren,
november 19,
14,
the middle east is now in play.
India may be in place.
Southern russia's imply north africa and
Egypt in play.
The balkans is in play.
the balkans is territory that when the
ottoman turks were young and powerful,
they owned,
they had fought two wars in the past
couple of years with the former
territories that they used to own and
watch them,
you know,
shake off the ottoman empire,
Serbia,
Bulgaria,
Romania,
Greece,
all these places had been pulling
themselves away from autumn and
influence for some time now and none of
them had decided which side they were
gonna fight on in this war yet.
And It's fascinating.
I mean you talk about watching open
diplomacy in a way that's like watching
horse trading going on is watching the
allies on one side and the central
powers on the other side try to convince
a country to go their way.
I mean with Italy for example,
it's almost open auction time.
I mean one alliance will walk in the
front door and say,
well,
if we win the war and you're joining us,
you can have this province from the
enemy in that province,
in that province do.
And then you know,
they'll leave.
And then the other door comes.
The other alliance system saying,
is that all they promised you?
Well,
if we could have this,
that and the other thing,
and this was going on with all these
countries in the balkans,
Greece,
for example,
in the aegean,
the number two thing they were all
concerned with is what were they going
to get?
They got in the war.
What are you promising me and you know,
going to the highest bidder,
but the number one thing they were all
concerned with his who was gonna win.
These countries knew that they were
absolutely like roadkill if they pick
the wrong side,
but in early 1915,
no clearcut dominant side had emerged
and so churchill and his compatriots had
this idea
that they could strike a big blow in
that theater right in that part of the
world.
Even if they did knock anybody out with
it,
it might convince a lot of these powers.
While you can see britain's gonna,
when France is going to win,
let's join them.
Right?
Changed the course of the war that way.
So all these good arguments like this
are starting to accrue for this cabal of
people like winston churchill.
When all of a sudden something
intervenes to bring the whole thing to
ahead,
put it on the front burner and make the
government consider whether or not it's
a good idea.
It's one thing to have a good idea.
It's another thing to really be thinking
about,
okay,
is this What we do?
And a request from the russians changes
this from a theoretical question to one
that they're debating.
In early january of 1915,
the russians are asking for help.
they are facing the turks down near
there,
you know,
border the church and the russian
territory,
touch but far away from where russian
forces are fighting the germans and the
austra hungarians because of the
distance,
the russians had pretty much taken their
troops and they're fighting for their
lives against the germans and use them
up north and now the turks are attacking
and strength down south.
The situation will get critical.
In late december,
went on December 29th,
the turkish forces up against the
russians on their mutual border,
start the battle of sarah calmness and
try to attack the russian defenders from
multiple sides at once.
It's a very optimistic,
very napoleonic in concept plan led by a
civilian strategist actually who will
take $120,000
on a good turkish army and ruin it.
I'm in this battle because these
russians,
a smaller force than the turks attacking
them are ensconced in the natural
fortress that is the caucasus mountain
range.
In the middle of winter,
all this fighting is going to happen at
elevations between 5,000
feet and 6,500
feet.
Turkish soldiers are going to be
fighting as though they're dressed for
the low lands.
The logistics of this hundred and 20,000
man army are going to be carried up into
these mountains on tiny little windy
mountain roads and there's not even many
of them and it's snowing like you can't
believe.
We're told,
have you know,
multiple days of 14 our marches through,
you know,
waist deep snow.
By the time these poor turkish troops
get to the russians there darn near
defeated.
Then some of them surrender right away.
May several cores just surrender that
you and you just get this image of these
starving,
you know,
units that are just falling apart.
And at the end of their rope,
some fight bravely and almost
fanatically anyway.
And then the next part of the story
that's famous is the retreat of this
turkish army back to Turkey.
They lose about half their strength.
We're told that of the people that do
make it back to Turkey,
a third of them are so badly wounded
that they'll have some part of their
body amputated and the stories
themselves and it's amazing alike.
They are booked a book,
but they they.
They create this sort of mental image of
like napoleon retreating from moscow in
the winter.
Harry did the whole way back with these
soldiers that were freezing on the march
because it was so cold and the mountain
passes in the middle of winter and the
army is supposed to be followed by packs
of wolves through these,
you know,
almost bram stoker ish,
like terrain and taking the frozen
soldiers as they freeze or as they
become too wounded to defend themselves.
It's a horrifying story.
And the turks will be very bitter and
affected by this battle.
The russians will be though too,
because even though they technically
when it,
for all they know,
the turks could do this in another three
weeks or another month and they're not
ready for this.
Again,
the turkish attack down here prove that
this is not a quiet safe front and you
better be ready for more.
They're not ready for more.
This is why they asked for help
and they asked for some diversion to be
made that will draw some of these
turkish troops away from them and maybe
something that will open up the supply
lines again beCause the turks control
one of the most strategically important
spots,
not just in the world,
but in world history.
When you take constantinople in the 15th
century,
like the turks did,
the dardanelles come with it.
The dardanelles are the actual
separation and this is a geographic
feature that goes back to forever
between asia and europe.
If you look at it on satellite images,
it looks like a rather large,
um,
river,
but it really is only a mile apart in
some spots.
And this is the waterway that takes you
from,
you know,
the g and c,
which is connected to the mediterranean
sea,
which is connected to the rest of the
world and get you from there to the
black sea,
which is not connected to the rest of
the world unless you're using the
dardanelles.
It's a straight of extreme importance
and the turks control it.
They have fortresses on both sides of
this glorified river with canon.
they've got mines in the waterway to
prevent people from getting through that
they don't want to get through.
And once they get in the War in
november,
19,
14,
they don't want the russians to get
through and they don't want the british
to get through and the french to get
through.
And this is a huge problem for Russia
because they don't have a lot of places.
You know,
where people can trade with them via the
ocean.
Especially,
you know,
if it's anywhere near the winter months,
if it's near the winter months,
you need this port open,
the black sea port open and now the
turks have closed it.
The russians are in such bad straights.
They are sending soldiers into battle
with a rifle and then another soldier
whose job it is to shadow the first
soldier and when the first soldier dies,
pick up his rifle and use it because the
second person didn't get a rifle.
The russian industry keep up with the
military needs and so they're having
problems like that so you can see how
important it is for them to be able to
trade with britain and France and maybe
outside powers if just to get rifles to
arm their troops with and now the turks
have closed off that important area and
winston churchill thinks he can open it.
He gets an idea that will involve any
ground troops at all.
He continually points this out in his
book.
By the way,
we've used this book for this show,
but not as a history book because it's
not the kind of book you want to use to
find historical truth.
It's the kind of book you want to look
to find the truth.
As churchill saw it,
unjustified it afterwards,
which is a very different thing.
Churchill,
his fingerprints are all over this thing
and this thing is going to go south
fast,
and so in churchill's book he does with
almost any other person with any
responsibility for world war one does in
their post war memoirs,
he defends himself,
answers his critics,
justifies this,
explains that,
and um,
be no different than the german generals
and whatnot in that respect.
But his point is when he thought of this
idea it didn't involve any land troops,
and since land troops are going to be a
huge part of the tragedy that this
unfolds into,
he basically says he washed his hands of
the whole plan.
Once that situation changed,
churchill's plan was to take the
largest,
most powerful fleet ever assembled in
world history and forced the streets
simply sail through him,
wiping out any fort,
you know,
that's anywhere nearby with naval
gunfire and go from one side to the
other.
And then once you're on the other side,
you're right next to formerly
constantinople.
Now istanbul,
and you have a giant megalopolis
underneath the guns of the greatest
fleet ever assembled and sent to war.
It's an idea that looks great on paper
and then by the time events go from a
all the way through the alphabet to z,
though you see who rules the alphabet
between a to z when it comes to getting
something from the theoretical stage to
the reality stage and that's murphy's
law and murphy's law grabs hold of these
events and Quickly turns this whole
affair into something that no one had
ever thought was the right thing to do.
Shows you how people can get swamped by
events sometimes and churchill spends a
good part of his book on this subject
trying to point out that he was one of
the victims of what happened.
He's often been portrayed as the
architect
and if you ever want to see how
frustrating history can be some times
look at churchill's thinking on all this
because when you examine it,
it's so logical.
He's doing exactly what any of us would
hope somebody in a position of power
would do in terms of going down the
arguments and the risks and benefits
logically,
and it still turns out horribly.
What sort of lesson is that teaching to
the other commanders who were saying,
yes,
just keep smashing against the wall or
my goodness doesn't seem to matter
whether you think outside the box,
you do the same darn stupid pointless
thing again and again.
The first world war equalizes the
results of both of that.
In a.
You're darned if you thinking you're
darned if you don't think churchill.
Basic assumption was that the british
empire was sitting on an enormously
powerful fleet that was useless and the
part that was useless is so useless you
can't even use it.
If the enemy fleet comes out to fight,
there's a whole bunch of british ships
that were made obsolete only in 19.
Oh six.
Remember it's 19,
14,
1915.
What happened in 19?
Oh six.
A brand new type of battleship arrived
on the scene,
became the name,
you know,
the initial ship's name was dreadnought
and that becomes the name for that
entire type of vessel,
a dreadnought or super dreadnought.
That's a class name now,
and that's because that's how
revolutionary this ship was.
The problem is,
is the instantly it arrives on the
scene.
It makes obsolete fleets of hugely
expensive vessels,
dozens and dozens and dozens of them
that have been built up over a lifetime
makes them obsolete overnight,
and of course the british being the
greatest navy in the world.
They had the most of these battleships,
the older battleships,
the ones that in 19,
oh,
five or the greatest force of float and
in 19,
oh,
six are ready for the scrap heap,
and that's what churchill said.
All these ships were heading for.
What are we saving them for?
They're just going to be scrapped after
the war and he says that the admiral's
had these emotional attachments to these
ships because they had served on the
more they remembered the day when these
were the most powerful war ships afloat
and churchill's attitude is these are
assets to be used up for.
AGain,
we can use them in the dardanelles and
if we lose them,
we don't lose anything,
but he's got a lot of them.
winston churchill's plan of using the
fleet in a lightening attack that the
turks weren't ready for with massive
forest.
I could just force the straights before
anyone could respond to it turns into
something totally different over the
next several weeks,
and churchill has always claimed that
the events were completely out of his
control,
but he uses as an argument the line that
he was told that there were no troops
available,
so any plan he came up with pretty much
had to have a tiny little group of
marines to run on shore and knock out a
gun if necessary,
but nothing else.
So he says basically he can't be
responsible for this land disaster
that's about to happen.
He never assumed there'd be any troops
anyway,
and here's what he says.
Quote at the evening meeting of the war,
counsel on January 28th when the final
decision to adopt the plan was taken,
lord kitchener,
repeated quote,
we have at present,
no troops despair.
It was on that foundation alone that all
our decisions in favor of a purely naval
attack had been taken,
but hence forward a series of new facts
and pressures came into play which
gradually,
but unceasingly changed the and
enormously extended the scale of the
enterprise under these influences.
In less than two months,
the naval attack with its lack of
certainty,
but with its limited costs and risks
became subsidiary and in its place there
are rows and military development of
great magnitude over this new plan.
The admiralty had no responsible
control.
Our advice did not prevail,
are criticisms were not welcomed and
even inquiries became a matter of
delicacy intact.
Nonetheless,
by the results of this military
operation,
we had to stand or fall and quote,
I know you don't need translation for
me,
but isn't that the same as saying,
hey,
that wasn't my idea.
You changed it,
but I still have to be responsible for
it.
You see a lot of post world war one
memoirs that sound like that.
Nonetheless,
it adequately explains how out of
control the process.
Seeing once churchill and his cabal had
taken their little private idea and had
it adopted by not just one government,
but the allies as the plan and of course
in the final analysis,
the people with the most control over
your plan.
If you're winston churchill or the ones
on the scene who actually have to make
it work.
The military commanders in this case,
the admiral's on February 17th,
a couple of those admirals are leading
the most powerful fleet that's ever gone
to war.
Now I say that as sort of leaving a
little loophole because the most
powerful fleet in the world is the
british fleet sitting up in scapa,
flow up in scotland,
waiting for the german fleet to come out
and play,
but that leads never done anything.
They're waiting for their chance.
The largest most powerful fleet that's
ever gone to war and tried to do
something so far.
This one,
18 or so battleships,
most of them british,
some of them french.
Most of these,
the old battleships that were made
obsolete a decade before,
but also including,
you know,
the newest super dreadnought,
the queen elizabeth with 15 inch guns,
you know,
12 or so cruisers,
30 destroyers,
a couple hundred transports.
This fleet might not have lasted very
long against the crack in the german
fleet,
but in this part of the world,
it's the most powerful force afloat and
would have been the greatest athlete in
the world a decade before it arrives.
You know,
off the coast of Turkey and begins
shelling those straits on February 19th
and things start slowing down.
The plan is to batter your way through,
destroy all these fortresses as you
continue to move deeper and deeper into
this sort of river like piece of
geography,
but you know the weather gets bad,
so the fleet retreats,
you know,
to a safe distance and then it comes up
and they shell some force and then
something else goes wrong and churchill
is sitting back in britain going crazy.
PullIng his hair out.
Sending messages after message is
basically saying,
hurry,
hurry.
The whole plan requires you to hurry
because the longer they take,
the more you lose.
This whole idea that there's some
surprise to it that catches the turks
off guard and so the turks have already
figured out when you see the largest
fleet that had ever gone to war,
oh,
the british are doing something down
here.
The good news is that does take away
troops fighting the russians and take
some pressure off the tsar,
which was the reason he asked for help
in the first place.
The bad news is instead of the british
advancing against a totally unready foe,
you know,
and taking advantage of surprise,
they're sitting there giving the whole
basic idea way for months on the 18th of
March,
the fleet decides to try again in a big
way.
Churchill's back there,
prodding them,
get to work,
get out there,
do it,
big attack and the 18 battleships and
the whole fleet goes in and start
shelling the forts.
Some marines are detached and send on
land to go take some of these sports
that are particularly troublesome and
then shit hits a mine.
A french battleship rolls over really
quickly.
About 700 people die,
boom,
fast before anyone's had time to digest
that.
Another one hits a mine and then another
one,
and by the way on the scene,
they don't know that these are mines.
Mines are one of the things they thought
about torpedoes or another.
All they know is big,
expensive,
important ships,
at least in the old days,
are starting to sink and list and
explode and the commander is pull
everything back and by the time they get
away from the streets they've lost or
seeing crippled six battleships now what
winston churchill would say and what he
did say is,
who cares?
These are old battleship.
They're not of any use to us at all,
so use them to take the straits,
but at least take the streets.
He said the admiral's had a whole
different opinion.
They didn't see this as an asset to be
used.
They saw it as a charge to protect these
admirals.
He said,
had an emotional attachment to these
ships.
They walked their decks back when they
were young officers in these ships were
the queens of the seas and he says,
now they had this attachment.
They didn't want to lose them,
and the whole point was they were there
because they were losing a bowl.
Again,
what's so terrible about what follows is
churchill,
his attitude was that this fleet was
totally expendable,
but in order to protect this expendable
fleet,
the high command decides the ground
troops had to be sent in.
They pulled the fleet back.
They begin assembling these 80,000
men that they're going to attack.
This area within.
The plan is to overwhelm this peninsula
called the gallipoli peninsula.
That's right next to the dardanelles and
take over all those fortune,
all those gun positions with your ground
troops.
Then those guns won't fire on your
little teeny minesweepers who are
clearing the streets of the mines and
then your big battleships won't get
mind,
but it's the tail wagging the dog here
and churchill and others have said,
ever since the war was over that this
was a disaster waiting to happen because
the whole point of this plan is to use
strategic surprise to catch the enemy
off guard.
How's the going to be going to be caught
off guard when it takes five weeks after
the battleships pull
back to get the ground forces onto the
beaches?
The turks are commanded by a german
general.
In this case,
a very competent guiding liman von
sanders,
who supposedly says if the allies will
just give him eight days,
he can put together a defense.
He's desperate for time,
eight days,
just give me eight days.
They gave him five weeks and by the time
the landings take place in late april,
early may,
19,
15,
to say that the turks are ready,
maybe is a little bit presumptuous,
but they're waiting and you get a chance
to see what the worst nightmares of
allied planners who were planning for d
day in the second world war.
You know the attack across the beaches,
across the english channel,
landing allied troops on the occupied
french coastline.
You can see what their nightmares must
have been like because they were young
men.
When they got to see how something like
an amphibious assault could go wrong
because they saw it on the beaches of
gullapalli.
First of all,
it was a nightmare of improvisation.
These troops were trained for war,
not trained for amphibious assault.
They landed sometimes on the wrong
beaches.
They had completely somehow gotten the
terrain or wrong.
Even with aerial surveillance.
I mean the poor australians are landed
in a cove a mile from where they were
supposed to land.
It's like a reverse amphitheater and
historian john keegan who visited the
site said,
the one thing that overwhelms you when
you go there is how tiny it is.
It's this tiny little cove and you drop
a ton of australians there with the high
ground all around them like an
amphitheater and just leave them there
on some of these beaches.
The allies are able to land route
relatively easily and try to capture the
high ground on other beaches they land
and aren't sure what to do on a couple
of these beaches.
The turks are waiting for them and
massacres in shoe.
In one,
the allies had taken a like a transport
ship and cut out a hole in it so that
they could drive it right up on the
beach and the soldiers could just jump
out and be ready to fight.
The turks trained machine guns on the
door and when the door opened and all
these troops jumped out,
they were machine guns one by one by
one.
As they hit the beach,
less than 25 of them made it to the
beach out of several hundred.
Even when the allied forces at great
cost sometimes take these beaches,
they're not always sure what to do next.
They have no idea how things are going
on the beach next to them.
They don't know if the ship's know where
they are,
the ships don't know where they are.
There's no coordination going on and you
really get a wonderful object lesson in
which you're also getting on the western
front concerning what weapons system is
really missing from this war.
I mean it exists,
but not in a way where it's coordinated,
not in a way that you'll see it come of
age in the next world war.
It's one of those things that when you
consider in a vacuum,
it doesn't even sound like a weapon.
It's like barbed wire.
You don't think of barbed wire as a
weapon.
You don't think of radio communications
as a weapon either,
but it's been the missing ingredient in
so many of these missed opportunities in
this war.
If only the troops that broke through
knew they broke through,
if only they could change where the
artillery was shooting.
If only we could bring up
reinforcements.
This happens all the time on the western
front.
Now it's happening at [inaudible].
Sometimes these troops land and they
just sort of stand there.
They don't know what they're supposed to
do next.
Or they take the first position that the
plans ahead of time called for them to
take and they stopped there.
What would you expect them to do?
They don't know what's going on.
They have to be careful or their own
artillery is going to shell them.
The problem is is once again,
it allows the turks to respond and you
will see a lot of fighting going on for
the high ground of these areas that
overlook the beaches and you know,
this whole plan still might have work is
the turks had turned out to be a soft
enemy.
You know,
if they'd turned out to be as weak and
as decadent and as you know,
unmotivated as allied planner sort of
assumed that they would be.
Instead,
they fought like lions,
which the turks are capable of.
The turks are very dangerous soldiers.
The ethnic turks especially,
and there'll be an incident at one of
the tops of these heights were allied
forces are fighting with turkish forces,
led by a guy named mustafa kemal,
who after the war will become one of the
most important figures in postwar
Turkey.
It's about 35 years old and he sees the
allied forces in his area reaching the
heights.
Everybody knows that these heights are
going to be important and he orders his
troops that are out of ammunition to
hold them off and he says these famous
lines that have gone down in turkish
history.
He says,
quote,
I don't order you to attack.
I order you to die in the time which
passes until we die.
Other troops and commanders can take our
place.
End quote.
That's about the opposite reaction of
what the allies were expecting.
The turk resistance to be like.
The allied resistance is just as
spirited.
The australians and new zealanders and
gurkhas.
To Be honest,
we'll prove themselves some of the best,
if not the best fighters in the war on
these beaches,
but they're completely hamstrung by the
screw up of the situation and in almost
no time,
the gallipoli campaign turns into a
mediterranean version of the western
front and it's got all the same tragic
hallmarks that the western front has
barbed wire artillery,
no man's land trenches.
The whole thing and the military
historian would point out that of course
it does.
It's the same situation,
the same things and conditions that
created the need to have people dig into
the earth and they created the power of
the defensive over the offensive is just
present in the mediterranean
and the aegean as it is on the western
front.
The australians find out about this
firsthand and I grew up next to an air
force colonel when I was a kid who
fought in the second world war and I
used to ask him who the toughest
soldiers were.
You know,
wHen I'm eight.
That was an interesting question to me
and I always wanted to hear something
like the germans and I remember he
surprised me once by saying the british
in general and the australians and New
Zealand troops specifically,
and I said,
why?
And he said because you would find
yourself in these horrible situations
and they would be laughing and joking
and he said,
that's indicative of a,
of a level of bravery that you don't
normally see,
but it doesn't always help you.
There's a story,
um,
of an australian corporate who wrote
about being pinned down on one of these
beaches when they land and the turks
have the high ground and they're
shooting down at these poor australians
who are trying to get their act
together,
get organized,
figure out what we do next while they're
under fire and while their friends are
dying.
And yes,
for a little while,
some of them are laughing.
He writes,
quote,
a galling fire rained on us from the
left where there were high cliffs.
One man dropped down alongside me
laughing.
I broke the news to him gently.
You've got yourself into the hottest
corner you'll ever strike.
I'd shown him where the enemy were.
He fired a few shots and again,
I heard the sickening thought of a
bullet.
I looked at him in horror.
The bullet had fearfully mashed his face
and gone down his throat,
rendering him dumb,
but his eyes were dreadful.
To behold,
how he squirmed in agony.
There was nothing I could do for him,
but pray that he might die swiftly.
It took them about 20 minutes to
accomplish this and by that time he
tangled up his legs and pain and
stiffened.
I saw the waxy color creep over his
cheek and breathe easier and cool.
Amazing to think about this one person
who's got to consider his own life,
which is under attack,
how he deals with troops,
who need him,
and he gets to watch that going on for
20 minutes to.
If I tend to focus on the horror and the
story,
ladies and gentlemen,
it's because that's what gets to me.
Any history read on any subject is going
to by its very nature the person telling
the story,
usually a historian,
but then sometimes you get stuck with me
is going to focus on the things that
intrigue or interest them for me.
It's what these people had to go through
on all sides and it's the horror that I
constantly try to imagine myself
experiencing and it's mind blowing to me
and I think after as many shows as we've
done,
the ones who've stayed with me listening
like you,
there's got to be something that touches
you too.
AT the literally.
You have this same charnel house
situation where dead bodies are a part
of your life and living amongst them is
part of the horror.
It's bad enough that your life is always
at stake,
that you watch all this death and
destruction,
but you live with corpses.
Corpses of people you often know or
knew.
This is a remembrance by british soldier
leonard thompson who arrives at the
dardanelles right after the major
landing quote.
We arrived at the dardanelles and saw
the guns flashing and heard the rifle
fire.
They heaved our ship,
the river clyde,
right up to the shore.
They had cut a hole in it and made a
little pier,
so we were able to walk straight off and
onto the beach.
We all sat there on the hellespont
waiting for it to get light.
The first things we saw were big wreck
turkish guns.
The second a big marquee.
It didn't make me think of the military,
but if the village phets,
other people must have thought like this
too,
because I remember hoW we all rushed up
to it like boys getting into a circus
and then found it all laced up.
We unlaced it and rushed in.
It was full of corpses,
dead englishman,
lines and lines of them with their eyes
wide open.
We all stopped talking.
I'd never seen a dead man before and
here I was looking at two or 300 of
them.
It was our first fear.
Nobody had mentioned this.
I was very shocked and I thought of
suffolk and how it seemed to happy place
for the first time we set to work to
bury people.
We push them into the sides of the
trench,
but bits of them kept getting uncovered
and sticking out like people in a badly
made bed.
Hands were the worst.
They would escape from the sand,
pointing,
begging,
even waving.
There was one which we all shook when we
passed by saying good morning in a posh
voice,
everybody did it.
The bottom of the trench was springy
like a mattress because of all the
bodies underneath at night when the
stench was worse,
we tied crepe around our mouth and
noses.
This crepe had been given to us because
it was supposed to prevent us from being
gassed.
The flies entered the trenches at night
and lined them completely with a density
which was like moving cloth.
We killed millions of them by slapping
our spades along the trench wall,
but the next night it would be just as
bad.
We were All lousy and we couldn't stop
shitting because we caught dysentery.
We wept not because we were frightened.
We were so dirty and quote and like a
bad movie.
The gallipoli campaign,
which was supposed to do an end around
the suffering of the western front and
ended more quickly by striking,
you know,
the weak joint in the enemy's alliance
just extended that suffering to a new
front.
The entire affair will get continually
worse as generals and admirals,
who don't want to admit defeat,
keep pouring more and more
reinforcements into it.
The turks do the same thing.
It just becomes this ongoing hell and
this ongoing hell will eventually cost
winston churchill his job.
In fact,
the british government essentially has
to reorganize.
They have to create a coalition
government and churchill's the one left
out.
He will leave the admiralty were told
after being sacked with tears in his
eyes,
certain that his career is over.
Talk about one of the great mistakes all
time.
Obviously he has a great career ahead of
him,
but churchill,
a weird guy and then we'd have to watch
myself with him because I liked him.
I think a lot of us like him as a
historical figure.
He's quite likable,
teddy roosevelt's the same way,
but you have to remember that these guys
have qualities that make them somewhat
unusual and it's hard to factor those
qualities into the man.
Churchill told one of his best friends
in february 19,
15,
the time when he's planning this whole
[inaudible] thing,
something that's relatively shocking to
hear when the whole world is stunned by
the carnage of the worst war in human
history.
He told his friend this quote,
I think a curse should rest on me
because I love this war.
I know it's smashing and shattering the
lives of thousands every moment,
and yet I can't help it.
I enjoy every second of it and to quote,
imaGine if the people whose loved ones
were over there fighting and dying and
her churchill admitted that and you
know,
one of the things that happens when you
use churchill's account of these events
that he played an important role in is
you get all his excuses and you get his
point of view and you get,
you know,
very one sided account of these affairs
where churchill is the hero and he was
right all along and if only people had
listened to him and if only they hadn't
screwed up,
his plans at all would have been great.
But there are very good historians,
Peter Hart and britain I find to be very
fair and he had this to say,
and he's not on the churchill was right
bandwagon.
He wrote about the whole gullapalli
affair.
Quote apologists for the gallipoli
campaign have long tried to boast of
what could have been with a heavy
emphasis on if only this fails to
recognize that the allies bought the
campaign with levels of naval and
military support that were considered
acceptable until the turks defeated
them.
Time and time again,
hamilton promised success again and
again,
he failed.
Go liberally was one of a series of
military easterner adventures launched
without proper analysis of the global
strategic situation without
consideration of the local tactical
situation,
ignoring logistical realities,
underestimating the strength of the
opposition,
and predicted on a hugely optimistic
assessment of the military capabilities
of their own troops.
Not for nothing is hubris regarded as
the english disease,
but the gallipoli campaign was a serious
matter.
vital resources have been drawn away
from where it really mattered.
The turks were all but helpless if left
on their own.
They had tried to launch an ambitious
attack across the sinai desert on the
suez canal,
but had been easily thwarted.
Gullapalli achieved nothing but to
provide the turks with the opportunity
to slaughter british and french troops
and copious numbers in a situation in
which everything was in the defenders
favor.
Meanwhile,
back on the western front was the real
enemy,
the german pyre and quote,
and by saying that [inaudible] was a
side show
and blaming churchill in large part for
the disaster.
While this tragic side show was going
on,
another horrible disaster was as well.
This is a conflict after all full of
horrible disasters,
but this one was somewhat different from
soldiers fighting it out on
battlefields.
This one involved an entire people,
several entire peoples in fact,
and it is perhaps the most argued about
case of genocide in world history.
In order to understand the context of
what we're about to talk about,
we need to recall how much of a role the
idea of ethnic self-determination plays
in leading up to the conditions that
create the first world war and to the
first world war itself.
Remember,
there are a bunch of centuries old pre
20th century empires that sort of
stumbled into the 20th century carrying
all sorts of baggage from previous era's
with them.
Baggage that is in part tearing them
apart and a lot of this baggage is
ethnic.
Take.
The austrian hungarian empire is a
perfect example.
Here's a multiethnic empire with a ton
of different ethnicities in it that are
presided over by a german slash
hungarian elite on paper.
All these people are equal
austro-hungarian subjects,
but if you happen to not be german or
hungarian,
often you don't feel very equal and
during this time period,
many different ethnic groups are either
looking to create their own states for
themselves or they're looking to join
with ethnic brethren of theirs that have
already done this.
When the first world war is touched off,
let's recall it's touched off by a serb
nationalist,
someone the slavs would probably look at
as a patriot,
but the austro-hungarian is looked at
him as a terrorist and looked at any of
their own people that wanted to join
with Serbia.
A not that old country created by the
ethnic serves.
Anyone who wanted to do that,
who was an austro-hungarian subject was
now treasonous and an insurrectionist
and a rebel.
And if you'rE actually in a war with
that country,
you're a fifth columnist or a cancer on
your nation
and there's no question that there are a
bunch of empires that are dealing with
these problems.
And then there are a bunch that just
sorta put those problems off.
Even the winners in the first world war,
for example,
britain and France are only going to
push these questions farther down the
road and after the next world war,
the british will be dealing with similar
situations in India and the french will
be dealing with it in north africa and
indochina,
but the ostrow hungarians and the
russians and the ottoman empire deal
with it now and it creates huge problems
and it does so in a realm that is
historically extremely violent inducing
ethnic in these old empires where people
have very long memories and everybody
has,
you know,
atrocities that the other side is
committed over the centuries that they
can point to as a justification for what
they are going to do.
Now,
modern people can think,
for example,
of the situation in the middle east
right now and how to sit down with
anyone who's involved,
you know,
close at hand with those conflicts.
The first thing you find out is everyone
has a ton of bad things that they can
point to that the other side did,
and after a while your head just spins
because you don't even know where to
start.
Everyone's got such long memories and
there are so many bad things that have
happened that they pointed.
The other side is being responsible for
that.
you just don't even know how to solve
that problem and untie that gordian
knot,
but that's nothing compared to the
ethnic memories of people in europe and
anyone who remembers the breakup of the
former yugoslavia and the middle 19
nineties in a will remember.
That's a perfect example of how deep
these ethnic tensions go.
You know,
we were all under the impression that
that whole ethnic animosity between
groups in those areas had been tamed and
that those fires had been completely put
out.
Little did we know that the heat under
the ashes were smoldering the whole time
that all it took was a little gasoline
poured on the smoldering heat for it to
flare up and for horrible things to be
done.
And then when you went and questioned
anyone,
for example,
a serb or croat or a bosnian muslim
about it,
they would point to the other side and
talk about hundreds of years of awful
things that they had done to them.
You don'T even know where to begin with
ethnic hatred like that.
The worst situation of this kind that
happens in the first world war,
although it happens in a lot of places.
Let's not forget,
during the 1915 retreat,
the russians did a lot of terrible
things to poles and jews.
I mean,
these things get paled though in the
history books by comparison with what
happened to the christian minorities in
the ottoman empire.
For example,
the greeks who have been inhabiting the
anatolian plain of asia minor since the
bronze age,
or the assyrian people,
the christian,
the syrian minority.
I'm in what's now kind of northern Iraq
and who claim to be the descendants of
the ancient assyrians.
Which if that's true,
that's a weird,
horrible karmic wheel of genocide coming
around,
hit them.
Because after all,
the biblical assyrians are one of the
very early confirmable,
you know,
instigators of ethnic cleansing and
genocide.
You can find ben,
of course,
the most famous of all the armenians.
The armenians are an ancient people who
inhabit an area that during the first
world war is kind of around where the
borders of Russia and the ottoman empire
come together to historic arch enemies.
The armenians caught in the middle
and they always have been certain
periods in history.
They've been able to form their own
independent state.
For example,
when rome,
persia,
we're a little weak.
They could do that.
And then as soon as roman persian,
the ancient world got their act together
from.
They swallowed up Armenia.
Armenia was the first official christian
state,
which did not particularly make the
ottomans enthusiastic.
It's kind of part of the reasons that
the armenians in the ottoman empire had
always been treated as second class
citizens and they remind one of the jews
in Russia where periodically you would
have these pogroms or these,
these incidents of violence breakout
that are just appalling when men,
women,
and children would just be slaughtered.
I mean,
there were in 18,
95,
18,
96,
the sultan hammad,
um,
did awful things and from 50,000
to 300,000
armenians died and just that one.
And then there was another one a couple
years later in another one,
a couple years after that,
in 1,909,
there was another one and the armenians
are between a rock and a hard place
because part of them live in what's the
ottoman empire,
but part of their territory and ethnic
group extends up into southern Russia
and area by the way that Russia had been
taking over over the past century.
So it's,
it's sort of a battle ground area.
And you take this people that the
ottoman turks had never been that
enthusiastic about any way.
And then you start this war.
Remember the russians and the turks
start fighting in late 19,
14,
early 1915.
And the turks get defeated by the
russians.
They have that napoleonic retreat where
the wolves are eating all the frozen
people and a lot of that army that beat
the turks in that battle were composed
of armenians,
armenians from the russian side of the
border,
a bunch of the ottoman troops in the
defeated army or also armenians.
And to make matters even more
complicated,
there were some armenian rebels who were
trying to create some sort of a state of
their own
and who can blame them by the way,
for wanting their own state after so
much persecution for so long,
but the way the ottoman empire viewed
these people,
you know,
what the best of times was unreliable
once the russians,
when that important battle in late 19,
14,
early 1915 and the turks field their
back up against the wall.
Now they begin to worry that the
armenians on their side of the border
are positively dangerous to them.
You know,
the ones who are loyal are potentially
vulnerable to subversion or propaganda
or maybe even having the guerrilla
groups,
um,
you know,
coerce them into cooperation through age
old practices like killing collaborators
as it's called.
That's the best case scenario.
Worst case scenario,
you're armenian subjects are disloyal to
the core and are hoping,
waiting and actively working behind the
scenes to help the russians when to the
turkish government.
This is treason.
They are feeling like they they're
either about to be or are being stabbed
in the back and their government,
as we said,
never all that enthused about armenians
anyway decided that a solution has to be
found and their solution is to get rid
of the armenians.
If you believe the official turkish
line,
getting rid of the armenians meant
relocating them.
If you believe what the vast majority of
historians and obviously armenians
believe,
getting rid of the meant killing them.
The process when it began with
systematic one village after another,
it was done with a certain amount of
understanding that it would be bad
publicity.
The Christian Powers Russia mainly,
but also britain and France had
oftentimes used persecution against the
armenians and other christian groups as
an excuse to intervene in the internal
affairs of the ottoman empire.
That's the way the ottoman empire would
look at it.
So to them,
there was all the reason in the world
not to publicize that you were doing
this and not make a big deal out of it.
The official line of the turkish
government is that during these efforts
to move the armenian people away from
the trouble spot,
they won't be a problem if you move them
to say Syria.
A lot of them died through starvation,
through disease,
through hostile ethnic groups that never
liked them,
liked the courage,
deciding to take advantage and swoop in
and killed a man and raped the women and
all the horrible things.
But there's so much evidence that this
was done in the same sort of fashion
that any one of us would recognize
genocide being if it was the holocaust
or Rwanda or it really reminds one of
the former yugoslavia a lot.
And the turks are very sensitive about
this and the armenians are very angry
that they won't admit it.
You know,
this is where I get a little upset with
this whole thing.
The idea of genocide as an official
international crime only arose in the
middle 19 forties.
And since that time,
that word has become a legal hot potato
where it would,
if someone were actually convicted of
genocide trigger all sorts of real world
ramifications.
And so everybody does everything they
can for the most part,
unless it's a pariah state to find
anything except genocide.
Well,
it's hundreds of thousands of people
died.
Oh,
but it's merely a crime against humanity
because there was no intent.
I mean you have to.
It's become a legalistic word where all
the different things have to be met and
it's a big deal if they are countries
can find themselves,
you know,
dealing with sanctions or calls for
reparations or issues with alliances or
trade deals.
And,
and Turkey didn't want that.
Nobody wants that.
I mean,
even in countries that acknowledged
their genocidal practices at one time,
they were a group that have arisen in
them,
are trying to get that overturned in
Japan.
There are right wing nationalists now
who are trying to now cover up and
downplay japanese genocidal activities
against China during the second world
war.
It's the most normal thing in the world,
but we've all done it.
That's why it's hard for me to
understand the turkish attitude that
this is a bloated,
their pride,
if they hadn't committed the genocide,
they be what?
Like one of the only people on the
planet have any consequences that
hadn't.
It's part of the shared human
experience.
As sad as that sounds.
Go.
Look at the old testament of the bible,
a book the jews,
christians and muslims all hold sacred.
The god of the old testament orders
genocide after genocide,
after genocide,
kill everyone put the men,
women,
children,
and all the animals to the sword.
The reason it's in the old testament is
because that was such a common behavior
that those people at the time would have
understood it too.
I've often said about slavery,
that we all have slaved blood running
through our ancestral veins somewhere.
same is true for genocide.
We've all had ancestors who were the
victims of genocidal attacks and we've
all had ancestors somewhere down the
family tree who were the ones committing
the genocide in their book.
Why not killed them?
All professors,
daniel and clark mccauley,
right?
That one of the downsides of this whole
thing is that we act as though that bad
man or that bad people committed this
unusual act when in reality,
as they say,
quote,
given the right circumstances,
normal human beings are all too ready to
kill by category and quote,
you will often hear the turks in their
own defense when accused of the armenian
genocide say,
well,
look at what was happening to muslims
and turkish folks who were in the
balkans and who were being treated by
those countries that had thrown off the
turkish yoke to rape and murder and all
these horrible things and displacement
and all that is totally true,
but it doesn't alleviate turkish guilt
in the armenian situation.
It just adds more people to the court
docket.
What happeNed to the armenians and other
christians in the ottoman empire during
this time,
including greeks and syrians,
was a tragedy between 500,001
point 5 million armenians died.
Women,
children,
men,
old people,
lots of rapes,
horrible stories.
Sounds like the einsatzgruppen under the
nazis.
Sounds like Rwanda.
Sounds like Indonesia sounds most like
the former yugoslavia in the 19 nineties
on steroids,
but I don't blame the turks anymore than
I blame the rest of us for it.
That's human behavior and what's
interesting is the armenian genocide
actually overshadows something similar
to it involving the russians retreating
in 1915 from a german offensive in
Poland and at gunpoint,
taking hundreds of thousands of poles
and jews out,
and a lot of those people never
returned.
They were seeing in the same way that
the armenians were seen by the turks as
unreliable,
disloyal elements likely to side with
the germans and interestingly enough,
in a wonderful sort of karmic way,
a lot of the reports that are considered
to be the most reliable about what the
armenians were going through come from
the turks allies,
the germans,
chairman advisers and military officials
and ambassadors who are telling their
own government about the terrible things
that are happening to the armenians in
that country.
And then within a generation,
those stories will be coming out of
Germany.
That's how endemic.
This whole idea of killing your enemies
down to the last person are as terrible
as this is.
That's the way we are as human beings
and killing your enemies down to the
last person is not just beginning to
look like the equation in these horrible
criminal genocides and starting to look
like the equation.
You know in that algebraic problem.
If you're one of the military commanders
in this conflict of how you win the war
itself,
not killing every man,
woman and child,
just killing every soldier on the other
side.
You know,
after another horrible battle on the
western front in 1915 when the allies
lose a ton of people to gain literally
not an inch of territory.
The french general baton becomes one of
the first ally commanders to openly say
that this war is not going to be won by
some miraculous breakthrough or some
tactical or strategic bit of brilliance
that opens up into a flank or a
breakthrough.
It's going to be won by killing more of
the enemy than we lose ourselves.
The wars turning into a war of attrition
and while that might sound like an
ultimate allied victory,
because if everybody kills,
you know one person on the other side
until there no one left.
The allies have a lot more people than
the central powers.
The problem with that little bit of
mathematics is that the central powers
are killing more allied troops and
they're losing themselves and will do so
every single month until almost the end
of the war.
So that mathematical equation is as yet
unsolved and unpredictable.
But of course,
modern nations don't fight to the last
man.
At some point they cry uncle,
which in this conflict has been ruled
out by the allies signing those treaty
saying no one will make a separate
piece,
which means they'll fight until the
political system or the armies or the
will of the soldiers to resist
collapses.
And by the end of 1915,
there's a coupLe of countries that look
in real danger of having that happen.
And even the countries that look quite a
bit safer than Austria,
Hungary or Russia.
Look,
even they are showing,
you know,
cracks and vulnerabilities.
Can this war really go on for another
year?
It's going to go on longer than that,
but not everyone is going to make it to
the end.
Don't forGet,
you can now buy the classic hardcore
history shows directly from itunes.
Just type in dan carlin and the search
window and if you want,
you can still purchase those shows from
dan carlin.com.
Would you like to help us out?
Help the podcast buckets show.
It's all we ask.
Go to dan carlin.com
for information on how to donate to the
show
like alice susanna,
and that's what the child prodigy and
genius musical composer mozart is
supposed to have answered when someone
said,
how do you come up with your
compositions in a start with the piano
and then build off of that,
or do you start with the structure and
then fill in the middle or.
and he's supposed to have said that it
comes to him.
Gleick alice,
suzanne amman at the same time all
together.
And that phrase keeps popping into my
head because that's the biggest
challenge in telling this first world
war story.
The second biggest challenge is the
ungodly amount of material that is
produced from many different countries
and viewpoints about this story.
I've never been so overwhelmed with
material as I have been for this and
it's all controversial,
so you really need to read a bunch of
different authors and viewpoints to to
get a sort of a nice broad view of some
of these topics.
But the stories can't even be
compartmentalized because they affect
each other.
What's going on in the eastern front
affects outcomes on the western front,
which affect outcomes in the
mediterranean theatre.
And so you can't even tell the stories
and the separately.
They all have to kind of weave together
and it's really easy with this much
going on to lose track of the story.
So I thought we would have a rare little
recap as to where we are right now.
Sort of broad trends to get us up to
speed and a few thoughts from the last
show that I'd like to just throw in
little extra fluff here at the end,
no extra charge.
Just bring us up to speed and make sure
I've covered them.
I have a list of things I want to make
sure I get through.
I'd hate to get through this whole show
and say,
oh,
I left that out.
Nonetheless,
are quick recap can be done relatively
simply.
The war breaks out in august,
19,
14.
A bunch of these countries had been
ready for it,
predicting it.
They mobilized quickly.
It's all on a timescale and everybody
launches.
They're prewar battle plans,
which for the germans is most famously
called the schlieffen plan,
advanced through Belgium in a wide arc.
Smash the french armies on the head
while you're keeping them occupied to
the front as well.
That doesn't go too well.
It does for a while.
I mean the.
The armies clash and the first month of
the war is commonly referred to as the
battle of the frontiers.
When you get these 19th century tactics
running into 20th century,
mechanized warfare,
which leads to the worst single month in
terms of casualties that you're going to
get in the whole war because you're not
going to see a lot of cavalry charges
against machine guns and artillery
positions after the first month of the
war.
That's when the really mindblowingly
shocking things.
I mean guys with armor and swords and
white gloves and red pants and you know,
bayonet,
charging,
prepared positions.
I mean the whole thing is is cookie and
that lasts for about a month.
The next month is what happens after the
germans lose the battle of the marne and
there schlieffen plan is broken and so
the second month of the wars then
basically running away from their
earlier positions,
trying to find a place to regroup,
finding a really good place to regroup
on the other side of the river ane and
digging in and the allies following
them,
unable to take those wonderful positions
on the other side of the river ane and
digging in themselves.
Inaugurating officially trench warfare.
then you have the so called race to the
sea.
When the germans and the french and the
british who don't want to run into each
other's prepared defenses anymore,
start trying to find a flank in the only
open part of the battle line left from
the river ane up north towards the see
both sides reached the sea before they
find a flag.
They have a couple of terrible battles
including the first battle of april up
there,
and then we settled down to the 1915
warfare basically,
which is going to involve both sides
launching offensives that don't do
anything and that if you read the book,
sometimes they can make them exciting.
Oh,
they almost broke through and all if
they've only been modern communication,
but the bottom line is thE bottom line.
You have a bunch of battles during 1915
on the western front.
Nothing changes on the eastern front.
Nothing changes either,
but a lot of movement happens.
A lot of people die.
A lot of movement happens.
The overall strategic situation remains
the same because when the russians and
the germans clash right at the war
start,
the russians get crushed in the couple
of big battles.
Tannenberg mazarine lakes.
But then they beat the ostroW,
hungarians,
the serbians beat,
the austro-hungarian whole bunch of
stuff happens when you turn around and
subtract all the deaths and all the
movement and everything else.
The situation is the same.
The russians are there,
they're not defeated.
They can replace all their losses and if
you really want to chase them,
they'll run all the way back to moscow
like they did against napoleon and like
they'll do against hitler.
And do you really want to follow them
all the way back there so they don't
have trench warfare.
They have movement warfare,
but the movement's not ending anything.
And then of course,
because the russians and the turks start
getting into it down in the south,
the russians asked the allies for help,
which leads to winston churchill's
cabal,
having yet another good argument to
argue that maybe we should take the
dardanelles with all these pre
dreadnought battleships and then the
dardanelles happen.
Now here's where we can kind of add the
fluff.
I was just promising you because
remember one of the sidebar hopes with
this dardanelles campaign is that it
might influence some of those countries
down in that region that hadn't decided
which side to join yet,
but it was obvious that they were sort
of taking bids,
Italy most among them.
They liked the allied bead better.
They saw the dardanelles campaign
looking pretty strong back in may,
19,
15,
you know when there were landings and
troops assaulting the heights every day
and it looked like britain and France
were strong.
So the italians joined the war.
They instantly attack the ostrow
hungarians at really the only good spot
on their board or to do that because the
rest of their borders basically the alps
and basically the austro-hungarian
hungarians have the high ground.
Although they find and have found
recently,
it's,
it's almost like something out of the
old captain America comic books,
you know,
with captain America frozen in the snow.
except of course he was alive when they
defrosted them.
These poor austrian and italian soldiers
that they're finding with these glaciers
melting up in the alps,
in these caves.
And I mean they look perfect like they
were frozen yesterday,
their uniforms,
their weapons,
their facial characteristics,
everything.
I mean,
it's crazy.
It's like a time capsule of the most
grotesque kind.
Nevertheless,
the one area that's good for fighting at
least compared to the alps,
is on the river.
He songs though.
So the italians attack the
austro-hungarian right away at the river
is sancho and lose.
So then they attack agaIn on the
riversand.
So this will be called the second battle
of the riversand.
So when they lose again,
they do it again.
Third battle of the riversand.
So they do it again.
The fourth battle of the river.
So by the last year of the award there
on the twelfth battle of the reverse,
monzo and hundreds of thousands have
died.
And in fact,
in only six months of warfare,
the italians will have 200,000
casualties and are quickly playing catch
up with the rest of the powers.
I should point out something about
casualties to.
We keep using that term and it's worth
defining it.
casualties is a military term,
as many of you know,
and it's simply refers to the loss of
battles.
StrenGth.
So if you're a general and it's your
army,
we're talking about casualties,
simply means the number of people you
don't have available to fight those
who'd been killed,
those who have been wounded,
those who have been captured,
and those who are missing.
So when I say casualties,
that's what it means.
Although missing in this war usually
means dead.
If I say dead,
well,
that means killed in action.
So the italians,
200,000
casualties within six months,
the other power that gets into the war
does so in october,
and it's the bulgarians,
another one of these powers that
churchill and his friends at hope to
convince to join the allied side when
they saw how the dardanelles campaign
was going,
but by october the dardanelles campaigns
really going poorly and the bulgarians
had been promised good land and they
don't like the serbs anyway.
So they joined with the germans and the
austrian hungarians,
all three of them promptly attack
Serbia,
um,
and knock them out of the war.
And there'll be this story,
this harrowing story of the serbian
army,
you know,
going all the way through Albania and
the mountain passes like a bunch of
wraiths starving until they reached the
sea.
And there'll be evacuated by french and
british warships to fight another day.
The one thing I wasn't sure if I
mentioned in the story,
you know,
we talked about the second battle of eep
or where the germans used poison gas for
the first time in a successful way.
It was used on the eastern front in a
weird way once,
um,
but after the second battle of eep are
the allies start using gas to.
And by the end of 1915,
the standard mix of shells is you want
some high explosive in your mix and you
want some shrapnel shells and your mix,
which are like giant balls filled with
tiny little beebees.
And when they explode it's like a giant
hand grenade going off.
And then the last gels you want mixed
into your little triad of,
um,
you know,
horrific ness are your gas shell.
So gas high,
explosive in shrapnel.
You shoot it all at the same time,
it makes a nasty little cocktail for the
poor troops on the ground,
so everyone's got gas and everybody's
wearing gas masks now and you end up
with these images that are still,
to my mind,
the greatest images of the first world
war because they say the most when
you'll see,
for example,
I love the one that shows a german
cavalry,
lancer in 1969,
1917 who's wearing the stall helm,
which will come into vogue in 1916,
which is basically the same basic
design.
You'll see the german army having the
second world war,
so he's wearing like a german wehrmacht
helmet with a lance on a horse and
wearing a gas mask.
He's like half medieval knighT and half
storm trooper from star wars and that to
me encapsulates what this war is.
These meetinGs of the modern world with
the premodern world,
like a historical estuary,
like I said,
and in fact,
you know it's,
it's uber modern because really there
hasn't been a major war fought with gas
since this time period.
I mean,
there have been incidents of chemical
weapons and gas use,
but you've never had the major.
I mean the second world war,
there was none of this.
Also,
it should be obvious that there have
been several theaters that have not
gotten much or perhaps any attention
from yours truly,
and it's not because I don't find them
interesting.
I mean I think you could do a whole
podcast just on the african experience
in the first world war,
but it's not important to the outcome of
the first world war.
So when you have to chop in places for
time,
these are long enough already.
You naturally look at the pacific in the
first world war or africa because it
didn't affect the outcome.
What had more of an effect on the
outcome are the soldiers from those two
areas that were trucked into places like
the western front and who fought there.
Lots of north africans,
lots of subsaharan africans,
lots of people from the far east fought
on the western front and at places like
the dardanelles and eventually at slomka
and places like that.
So in a funny way,
the place where africans and asians had
the most impact on the war going one way
or the other was the same western front
that we normally think of as being a
british french canadian sort of preserve
and down the road and american one.
so by the end of 1915 you basically have
a static situation.
western front stays unchanged.
Eastern front keeps moving around,
but everybody's still standing there
facing each other down in Turkey.
The war has been extended to down there,
but it's just stable to one of the
reasons this is called the gear of
stalemate in the first world war,
if you want to talk about something new
that has happened,
helmets have started arriving.
We mentioned the german stall helm a
minute ago.
The first one is the french helmet.
Then the british metal helmet than the
german one appears and it's one of those
things that doesn't seem like a big
deal,
but all of those helmet designs will be
the basic design that the second world
war helmets come from.
So they'll all look very familiar and be
in vogue for quite a while.
At least in their basic look,
the german one changes,
for example,
they all change a little,
but also because it boggles the mind a
little bit,
doesn't it,
that you don't get your first metal
helmet really till late 1915,
which means all these people have been
fighting the most artillery intensive
war in human history by far with cloth
hats on their heads,
digging holes in the ground where the
only thing that's exposed to fire is the
top of your head and it's covered by a
hat and forget the obvious thing about
like shrapnel exploding in the air and
just hitting you in the head.
So many of these shells don't come all
that close to you.
They just Blow tons of rocks and stuff
up in the air that then come down and
land on your head.
How many casualties from the first year
of the war could you attribute to the
fact that none of these troops had metal
helmets?
It's crazy to think about and crazy to
think that it took them a year to come
up with that more than a year.
Finally,
and I think this firmly belonGs in the
casualty area when we're discussing
casualties,
modern medicine has changed the
situation at this conflict and if you're
studying military history,
you'll notice a very interesting change
in the way the casualty death too.
Wounded figures show up in this
conflict.
I'm normally the number of people
wounded and the number of people who die
are pretty close together.
I mean take the crimean war that
happened in the 18 fifties.
More people died from disease than from
combat related wounds.
That might've been a little extreme but
not that far off the norm by the first
world war.
That changes immensely and it's because
the medical situation has been
revolutionized.
modern military medicine really begins
in the first world war and a lot of
these doctors,
especially on the western front,
our doctors from private practice who
have been drafted or who joined and
volunteered for the war effort,
they're often doing surgeries right near
the front.
These are people who live in the modern
era.
When medIcine is starting to be pretty
darn good and it completely changes the
game.
I mean,
these people are not just able to save
lives and this is sort of a mixed
blessing,
I guess if you're a soldier,
but they will be able for the nation
states that they work for to send a lot
of these damaged soldiers back to fight
again another day and sometimes multiple
times.
That ends up increasing the ability of
many of these states to keep fighting
past where they otherwise would have
been able to.
I mean all you have to do for example,
is look at the burn rate on some of
these armies.
By the end of 1915.
By October,
1915,
the russians are losing 235,000
men every month.
By the end of 1915,
17 months into the war,
the total russian casualties are over 2
million men and even though they could
replace the human beings,
what they can't do is replace the morale
of the people in the capital.
The czar tells his french and british
counterparts at the end of 1915 that the
population has turned pacifistic an anti
allied.
Meanwhile,
the western allies are having their own
problem.
The soldiers in the trenches starting to
get a little uppity about their
willingness to continue suicidal attacks
endlessly.
That's not a good sign commander of the
german forces.
Creating strategy is deciding that if
they're really in a war of attrition,
why not design the battles to kill the
most people instead of having
breakthroughs and maneuvers and all
that,
and eric von falcon hine creates a
killing ground to invite the french
nation to bleed itself white in the big
fleets.
Finally come out to play and new
technologies debut whose job it is to
break this log jam of trenches,
machine guns,
barbed wire and gas.
The year in 1916 is sometimes called the
breaker of nations.
There's going to be some nations that
suffer some mortal wounds before that
year is over.
All that and more.
In part four of blueprint for
armageddon.