Because some bus,
it's history,
41,
a date which will live in infamy,
perfect to the lead from this time and
place,
I take pride in the words Ich Bin,
the Alina
The drama.
Hi,
welcome.
This kind of examination because people
have got to know whether or not their
president or crop,
if we dig deep in our history and our
doctor and remember that we are not
descended from fearful man.
It's hardcore history.
The dictionary defines the word laconic
as a form of speech that is blunt or
pithy that uses an economy of words to
make a point and sometimes the point is
particularly biting or on target or
maybe mysterious,
and I love the word because the word
refers to a way of speaking that was
popular amongst a particular group of
people in Ancient Greece.
People known as lack of Demoniac,
otherwise known as spartans laconic
speeches,
spartan speech.
That's the way they're supposed to have
talked.
Imagine you know the love child of Clint
Eastwood and Batman,
and that's the way they spoke.
You know man's gotTa know his
limitations.
Man's got to know his limitations.
Spartans are the kings of the one liners
in ancient Greek history and they are
cinematic and character.
I mean there's not a movie maker out
there that wouldn't want Clint Eastwood
during his various movie years playing
various forms of Spartans,
you know,
from a Spaghetti Western era in his
twenties.
He could play your average spartan
warrior and he gets into the dirty Harry
films,
you know,
72,
73,
19,
74 and he begins to age a little bit
more,
but he plays one of those older spartan
warriors and then you get him,
you know,
after the dirty Harry's or over.
And he's an older man and now he's the
king and he talks like he talks in all
his other movies combined with Batman.
And you have,
you know,
the way the spartans are supposed to
have spoken laconically how cool is it
the 25 centuries after those people were
at the height of their fame and power.
We still know the way they talked.
It's famous,
it's famous because people wrote about
it.
People whose works,
we still have
telling you the way a certain people
spoke that long ago.
Describing some of the things that they
said,
all these sorts of little details help
bring color to the story.
They,
they help us all relate to these people
a little bit more.
These are human touches that flesh out
these historical figures.
When you begin to get this sort of
stuff,
the sorts of details that you were
likely to hear in an oral tradition
anywhere in the world before this time
period,
but when you begin to get these stories
that have come down to us,
you begin to see truly cinematic type
creations stories that you could take
with very little changes and updating
and make movies out of them today and
have them be popular
and it's not just the character
development either.
The themes can be epic in these stories.
Take for example,
the most famous story involving Sparta
at all.
The famous incident in for ADBC.
He at the pass of Thermopylae,
the so called hot gates.
This may be because of the movies and
because of the books that have been
written forever.
This may be the earliest confirmable
historical event.
Most Americans know about the defensive
300 spartans against a million or so
Persians,
a battle that some have described over
the era's for the existence of Western
civilization.
By the way,
if those are the stakes,
whose side are you rooting for?
What was it?
The India leader Mohandas Gandhi
supposedly said,
when someone asked him what he thought
of Western civilization,
didn't he say something like,
I think it would be a good idea.
Nonetheless,
the way this story is framed from the
get go is designed to have you affiliate
with one side over.
The other.
One side is like the plucky little
republic with Luke Skywalker in star
wars and their beleaguered and you know
they're good and they're under pressure
and they're trying to survive against
darth vader and the empire.
That will sniff out all freedom and hope
and happiness and you know,
all those kinds of things.
That's the way the ancient story is
handled.
Have what are called the Greek and
Persian wars.
A moment that has sometimes been
portrayed in apocalyptic terms for what
is sometimes been called the West once
upon a time.
Christendom,
so already many in the West are going to
feel like it's a sporting event and
we're the home team,
right?
We're all homeowners when it comes to
the Greek and Persian wars,
unless of course you're more like the
people who were portrayed as the
Persians back then remember,
this is not just an ethnic thing.
This is a values
thing,
and in the narrative sometimes called
the grand narrative by some greases,
fighting for things like liberty and
freedom and democracy and artistic.
I mean everything that the evil empire
isn't evil.
Empire will sniff it all out and make
slaves of everyone.
So who are you going to side with?
Right?
The story of [inaudible] is one of those
that is absolutely dramatic beyond
anything you get in earlier history and
it's because you have a master
storyteller.
Imparting the story to you.
When I started in news reporting and
editor said to me,
your job is to relate the facts of the
story,
the true information,
and do so in the most compelling way you
can.
If you imagine the battle of Thermopylae
as written by,
say the scribes of Babylonia,
it might sound like this,
in the 14th year,
the king of lands by the will of Marduk
overcame the Spartan army at a place
called the hot gates.
Two hundred 97 of the enemy were
counted.
The Spartan King went to his destiny.
The Babylonians had been writing that
way forever.
They were great.
Record keepers.
Things were a little dry though.
Now north of them were the Assyrians,
a culture that existed sort of alongside
the Babylonians,
a lot more aggressive and big on the
propaganda front and didn't mind
shoveling people's nose in their defeats
and they like to maintain,
shall we call a muscular foreign policy.
There's what sounded a little bit more
like darth vader's pr from issuing a
press release.
They would have described the battle of
thermopylae like this,
like a storm.
I overthrew them all.
I slew their king.
I crucified their land.
I devastated that.
You may notice that there's not a lot of
character development there and less
making the king of Assyria.
Frightfully terrifying is the
development you're after.
Nonetheless,
as I said in this story,
darth vader's really the only character
on the other side that gets fleshed out
very much compare the sample Babylonian
and the Syrian approaches to this story,
to something like the description you
get from people like Heraclitus of
helicon Asas sometimes called the father
of histories,
occasionally called the father of lies,
writing his history,
a generation after the events at their
mop Ali.
He talks about,
you know the spartans blocking this
road,
and there's a tale that has developed
over the hundreds of years afterwards of
an event that people have been adding a
few screen writing touches to since the
very beginning.
As the story is often told,
there's a bunch of Greeks trying to
block the army of the Persians from
coming into southern Greece.
Xerxes,
the crack of doom named Persian king,
the only truly free person in his whole
society.
The story would have you believe rules
all of Asia and so many other lands that
he is entitled a King of Kings.
All his people or the equivalent of
slaves who can live or die on his whim
and when he orders them to fight the
spartans in this past,
they obey and our whipped by overseers
onto the spears of the spartans.
The last stand is it's called a
thermopylae.
The greatest last stand probably in all
human history was not supposed to be the
kind of last stand.
It turned out to be there with thousands
of Greek soldiers at their monopoly
initially,
but eventually it became apparent that
it was going to be a death trap.
And so the Spartan King,
a guy named Leon,
he does supposedly sent the other Greeks
away and kept a sort of rear guard.
If you want to stick with the narrative,
a rear guard for Greek and western
freedom behind to hold off the Persians.
There were other Greeks who were
involved in the so called last stand at
thermopylae,
but it's the spartans who get the most
attention,
about 300 of them.
And again,
you can understand why as characters
they were fascinating in their own time.
The spartans are a kind of a cultural
experiment.
A better way to put it is when you think
about all human history together,
there's enough law of averages stuff
working where you can see all kinds of
little human experiments going on in
various communities in Sparta.
It's whether or not the culture can
infuse a certain fighting quality too.
It's human beings.
If they grow up a certain way,
pressured by the culture in certain
facets that just make them more likely
to be extremely nasty.
In Combat Spartan Warrior Sparty,
it's do nothing but fighting.
There is no other job for them.
The entire culture seems to be designed
from much of what we know now to
reinforce this,
including a code of laws and behavior
that tended to make these spartans
enough alike so that laconic became a
term that described.
You know,
most of them,
they're not a lot of chatty spartans in
history.
The culture didn't encourage that.
Listened to the color though.
That's come down from this story.
The great kings,
xerxes with his army reported to be a
million men so large that it drinks.
The river is dry that it passes through,
comes to this road with this past that
has to be crossed,
and these small group of Greek hoplites
guarding it and xerxes,
according to Hurghada tests,
doesn't know what to do,
can't quite believe what he seeing.
Look at the color in the story.
According to Hurghada,
xerxes sends a spy to go up to the
spartan lines and try to figure out
what's going on and not get caught.
Not only does he not get caught,
but according to Herat at this,
he reports back to xerxes and says that
the Spartan warriors couldn't have cared
less,
that he was there.
They were fine with him looking around.
They didn't care.
He said they were doing exercises and
combing their hair.
Again,
you have to imagine clint eastwood with
long hair and a beard right there.
That'd
be worth the price of admission right
with his tall sinewy guy,
not a big muscle bound guy doing
bodyweight exercises.
You know,
calisthenics,
pushups,
sit ups,
gymnastics.
That's how they prepped and the combing
the long hair was a spartan thing.
XERXES could not get his mind around.
Hurghada is basically says the idea that
these people,
a couple hundred of them,
we're going to try to take on his
reportedly million man army,
so he calls in an advisor that he has.
He's got a spartan king with him,
a guy who fell out of favor and he
hooked up with the Persians,
thinking that if they conquer all the
grease,
it might be good for him.
He's been the advisor to the great king
of kings up till now.
He had told the king earlier about these
people and they'd made fun of him,
so now xerxes called him back to report
on what the spy had said.
The spartans were doing.
I'll let hirata tests.
This ancient screenwriter handled the
story from their writing.
Twenty 500 years ago,
quote xerxes listened,
but could not understand that the lack
of Simonian's we're really preparing to
kill or be killed to fight as much as
was in their power,
seemed to him to be the height of folly,
the action of fools.
So he sent for Dme,
Maritou,
son of aristotle who was in the camp and
when to meritus arrived.
Xerxes questioned him about everything
he had been told,
trying to understand the meaning behind
what the lack of Simonian's we're doing
to tomorrow answered.
You heard what I said about these men
before when we were just setting out
against the Greeks and you made me a
laughing stock when you heard my view of
how these matters would turn out,
but it is my greatest goal to tell the
truth in your presence,
so hear me now.
Once again,
these men have come to fight for control
of the road and that is really what they
are preparing to do for it.
Is there a tradition that they groom
their hair whenever they are about to
put their lives in danger?
Now know this,
if you subjugate these men and those who
have remained behind in Sparta,
there is no other race of human beings
that will be left to raise their hands
against you.
For you are now attacking the most noble
kingdom of all the Greeks and the best
of men.
What to Maritou said Hirata test rights
seemed quite incredible.
Dessert sees and he asked for a second
time how they could possibly intend to
fight his whole army since there were so
few of them to Mera toast,
replied,
sire.
If things do not turn out,
just as I claim,
they will treat me like a liar and to
quote to lie to the great king of kings,
of the acumen,
Persian empire was a capital crime.
He was basically saying,
if this doesn't turn out exactly like I
told you,
it will.
You can kill me.
That's pretty darn colorful right there,
but it gets even better.
The Great King of the Persians were
supposed to send a messenger to the
spartan lines to King Leona and say,
basically,
join us.
We'll make you the overlords.
Greece,
you'll have more than you ever had
before.
A lot of nations had done that.
Joining the Persian empire was not a bad
idea.
Sometimes he's basically saying,
we can make a deal here.
It'll be worth your while.
His father dairy,
this was a great deal maker in the
xerxes,
was coming from a position of
negotiation here and the spartans
basically dressed him down morally
saying something to the effect of,
you know,
you have all this land already,
but you need to bother us.
We'd rather die for Greece than own
anything.
It was one of those wonderful spartan,
moralistic,
putdowns.
Again,
spoken with as few words as possible and
then famously as recorded by plutarch's
600 years after the event,
surrogacy sends another messenger to the
Spartan lines,
supposedly another message for the king
of the spartans and says to all the men
who can hear them,
you can all go home,
all will be forgiven.
Just put down your arms and then you get
the wonderful phrase,
Milan of a translated in many different
ways,
but it just is good.
Pretty much any of them come and take
them.
Lay down your arms,
come and take them.
Come and get them having come take.
You can take them when we're all dead.
A lot of the different ways,
the difficult to translate.
Greek is used.
It's still,
by the way,
the motto of the Greek First Army Corps,
it's been used for many causes all
throughout history cause it's such a
great,
dramatic,
colorful spit in the face of death line,
isn't it?
It's a clint eastwood line.
Do you feel lucky?
Punk come and take them.
How do you not stand up in the theater
and cheer when that moment hits?
That's every screenwriter,
his dream to have a scenario like that
and if it can be true,
how wonderful is that?
The Greek chroniclers who wrote about
this stuff did not skimp on the drama
and it makes it colorful.
It makes it real,
it makes it compelling even 2,500
years later and you give your right arm
to have this kind of stuff right out of
the mouths of the oral historians from
all these places that didn't have them
and look black and white because of it.
The Persian story must be magical.
Also,
we don't have that story and
traditionally it's difficult for us to
imagine that.
We'd like to hear from a pro perspective
the story of Darth vader and the empire,
but throughout history they weren't
always darth vader and some of the
greatest chroniclers of all time have
gone to great lengths to show in fact
that they may have been on God's side,
if you will.
If that turns out to be the case,
who's side are you rooting for them?
Of course in this time period,
the Iron Age,
ancient world and in this area,
the Mediterranean and the Near East,
you'd have to be a heck of a lot more
specific when you start talking about
dvds to just say God.
The likely response during that era
might've been which God.
It was a wild and crazy time for
religion in that part of the world and
they had a lot of different ones and
they ran the gamut from things you might
understand today too wild and crazy and
everything in between.
Most of these religious beliefs had a
pantheon of gods,
a bunch of them.
Some of them had a sort of a dominant
leave God,
but,
but having,
you know,
multiple gods was normal.
There were groups,
especially one known for only having one
God and they were the ones that put
together with divine or without divine
help.
Take your pick a tome,
a combination of catalog of events and
stories and accounts and perspectives
and admonitions and hymns,
and it's hard to describe exactly what
the old Hebrew Bible is.
It's also hard to know when it was
written,
are the accounts from the period around
the time the Persians first appeared on
the scene legitimate from that period.
Most Biblical experts think they were
written later.
Nonetheless,
we use plutonic 500 years after the
fact,
and so does everyone else.
So when the old Hebrew Bible in multiple
places talks about the Persians,
we should probably at least note the
attitude and the attitude that the
writers,
whomever they may have been of those
works had toward the Persians,
especially early on,
wasn't just positive.
It was divine,
meany,
technical.
You farson number number,
weight divisions.
That's my favorite part of the Bible.
The Old Hebrew Bible,
which is so full of wonderful stuff.
You know,
the Greeks don't have the market totally
cornered on color.
There's just not a ton of stuff from the
parts of the world during the time
period represented by the Bible,
but remember there's a lot of discussion
over when various pieces of the Bible
were written.
A lot of this good stuff might've been
written in well into the pros periods.
So we've entered into the color era
because there's so much color on the
book of Daniel has this scary story,
spooky story.
It's not like a horror movie,
but it's a spooky movie.
And today you'd have to have a little
CGI helped to make it work.
But it's my favorite scene.
It's out of the book of Daniel and it
involves a ghostly hand writing words on
a wall,
meany,
meany tackle.
You farson.
And you have to back up a little bit in
the story to set the scene.
But the king of Babylon,
who the Bible Calls Belshazzar is having
a party,
he and his buddies and some concubines.
That's the way the Bible puts it.
Probably have to imagine some loud
music.
Um,
you know,
and there's,
there's booze.
I mean,
they're drinking and at a certain point
the king of Babylon wants to really nice
silver were brought in and the big cups
of gold and silver,
the ones they took from Jerusalem when
they sacked the capital of Judah not
that long ago,
because that's what the Babylonians had
done,
scattered a bunch of Jews everywhere,
forced a lot of the premier families and
craftsmen and artisans to deport all the
way back to Babylon and destroyed
Solomon's temple when it comes to pr.
This belshazzar guy and the Babylonians
are not getting a ton of it positive
from the Bible.
And while he's drinking out of his big,
you know,
alluded cup,
hanging out with the concubines,
all of a sudden the ghostly hand with a
finger appears right under the lamp and
it starts writing on a wall,
meany,
meany tackle.
You farson.
And everybody freaks out.
My King James version of the Bible makes
it sound like he essentially couldn't
control his bowels.
He was so scared.
My,
uh,
later,
more colloquial version just sticks to
the knees shaking version.
Nonetheless,
he couldn't figure out what it meant.
So the Bible says,
this Babylonian leader called in all his
sorcerers and necromancers and
astrologers.
All these people you know,
the wizards that advised you know the
high Babylonian King and part of what
makes Babylonian so fricking wonderful
is there a combination of like rational,
logical,
hard,
observational science and mathematics
and all these kinds of things with
divination.
You have to imagine a Stephen Hawking
type character,
but a [inaudible] board is an integral
part of how he goes about his business.
It's fascinating,
but none of these people,
the Bible says,
can explain to Belshazzar what the
writing means.
And then someone reminds him that his
father used this guy,
this depor tea from Judah after the
Babylonians had destroyed Jerusalem
there and he was here in Babylon and we
could bring them in and see if he knows
what the ghostly writing means.
And belshazzar grabbed the guy and
brought him in,
and it was Daniel who was indeed a
deportee.
And Belshazzar,
our gives him the same offer he gave to
his soothsayers.
Listen,
you tell me what this means and you
know,
gold chains and you'll rule a third of
the kingdom.
And all this kind of stuff,
and Daniel says,
you keep your gifts or give them to
somebody else.
I'll tell you what the writing means.
I have a lot of different versions of
the Bible,
the Torah.
All these things in front of me and all
the versions are good,
but the King James Bible with it's you
know,
wrath of God style,
no sums it up perfectly.
Daniel looks at the meany,
meany,
teco you Farson and describes the words
is meaning number number,
weight divisions,
and then defines that as meaning this
from the King James version quote,
this is the interpretation of the thing.
God has numbered thy Kingdom and
finished it.
Now art weighed in the balances and
found wanting thy kingdom is divided and
given to the medes and the Persians and
quote that pretty colorful stuff,
isn't it?
And in that version,
the king of the Persians,
a guy named Darrius conquers Babylon
that knife and kills Belshazzar.
Well,
none of that's true,
but that's how the Bible story goes.
Nonetheless,
it's clear from that perspective that
the Persians in this story are not going
to be the bad guys.
They're going to be the instrument of
God that rectifies things.
If God is on any one side in that story,
he's on the side of the medes and the
Persians.
Who the heck are these medes and
Persians,
and if they're so good in this story,
during the time of the Babylonians,
how do they go from that to the evil,
the Greek?
See,
you know,
two or three rulers later.
Well,
let's remember,
darth vader wasn't always evil,
and in fact,
the guy who will kick off the Persians
first real appearance on the world stage
will be a guy that is so beloved by at
least the Hebrew God.
He will be the only non Jew ever
proclaimed a messiah.
The person who will get this honor is
known in your history books by the name
of Cyrus,
the second or cyrus the great.
If you wanted to make it sound a little
bit more like it probably sounded in
Persian,
you would say,
cool rush.
He's probably the greatest conqueror in
world history.
Up until the time of Alexander,
he's got some of the best historical
press anybody's likely to get.
Nobody has a bad word to say about the
guy,
even the Greeks like him xenophon,
we'll write a whole book essentially
romanticizing Cyrus's,
the greatest perfect world leader in
wind.
You like to be like him and here's how
you could emulate what he did and that
Kinda thing.
Cyrus becomes part of a Greek motif that
western tradition will continue for a
long time that portrays the east as
decadent and soft and corrupt,
but then how do you explain how some of
these great empires got started?
Well,
the way the Greeks do it is Cyrus's
fantastic,
and he builds up this entire thing and
bequeathed it to the Persians who
proceeded to become soft and rich and
lazy and decadent and ruined what the
great cyrus gave them.
So even the Greeks portray,
Cyrus has this great figure,
and yet we know so little about the guy.
If you contrast what we know about him
and the guy who probably takes the crown
from him,
his greatest conqueror in the world up
to that point,
Alexander the Great.
It's night and day.
Alexander the great exists in a fully
colorized historical world.
A post hirata tests world,
a world where Alexander will bring his
own publicists with him from place to
place so they can record his latest
deeds and sayings and doings.
Cyrus the great founds,
the last great empire and maybe what
could call the black
and white era in the Near East,
an era where we know the majority of the
people back then because of things like
monoliths and statues and reliefs and
carvings and tune paintings and
architecture and ruins.
When you do have writing,
you get business records and
proclamations and transactions.
Some of the best stuff you get from this
era are the correspondence is the
letters between diplomats and governors
and rulers,
but what none of those people are doing
is writing to amuse or entertain
anybody.
All of the writing from the black and
white period of human history is colder.
They all have a purpose beyond being
entertaining.
It might be a religious purpose of
business purpose at governmental purpose
or even two important officials writing
each other about in a matters of state
and a few personal things creep in.
That's very different than writing
something to be performed in front of a
live audience for their entertainment
and enjoyment.
I read something historian Michael Grant
had written about Hurghada tests
suggesting that the reason hirata test
has the interesting structure that he
does to his histories is because it was
not meant to be read as much as it was
meant to be performed.
Live,
ran allowed by Hirata test himself and
that the digressions and the tangents in
the work represent things that would
have worked much better in a live
situation with somebody broadcasting,
if you will,
an oratory as opposed to you somebody
writing something to be read by somebody
else remotely.
If that's the case and you don't really
have the first written prose history
with Hurghada tissue of the script for
Hurghada does his live show,
if you will,
which would explain a lot considering
that if you want to get drama and color
and stories before the period of Herat
at is you're looking at things like the
Iliad by homer or the epic of Gilgamesh
from Mesopotamian history.
Both of which are believed by the way to
have been stories told for hundreds of
years that we're finally compiled and
written down.
Same thing with like a beowulf in
Scandinavian history may be Hurghada.
This is more like the ancient
storytellers than first meets the eye to
give him some credit.
Heraclitus was trying to be a chronicler
at the same time that he was trying to
do the same thing I was told to do in
news reporting to relate the facts as
best as he understood them in the most
compelling way he could.
So what you have here in this ancient
story is not so much myth that wouldn't
be fair,
not just to people like Hurghada.
Despite all of the great historians over
time who have found all these records
and put together like a jigsaw puzzle,
a,
a viewing of the past that is always
being redone and improved,
but wouldn't have even existed there if
a ton of different pieces of the puzzle
hadn't been brought together.
But at the same time,
while it's not myth,
not exactly true either.
There are historians who've spent their
whole lives trying to separate the truth
from the fiction in works like
Heraclitus actually laughed out loud
when I read [inaudible] book from Cyrus
to Alexander Brown is one of the great
historians of Ancient Persia.
And this book is like the encyclopedia.
I mean,
it's very detailed,
very specific.
It's 1200 pages.
It's a,
it's an enormous comprehensive book and
the very first lines in it are as part
of the opening page where he quotes an
artist,
um,
who says quote,
and even if it is not true,
you need to believe in ancient history
and quote,
does anything better set up the
dichotomy here and how wonderful that in
a 1200 page book that is exhaustive as
all get out,
the very first line from the historian
is yeah,
it might not be true,
but you have to believe it anyway.
It's,
it's,
it's wonderful.
And it sums up the problem with ancient
history and that is that you have the
feeling that most of what you're reading
here is the truth.
And these events did happen,
but there's a lot of fiction mixed in
and it's difficult to know what's what,
and it's difficult to separate one from
the other.
It's also difficult to know where to
begin the story.
This is a classic problem anybody has
trying to explain something,
right?
How do you begin a story of Cyrus the
second and the Persians?
When does that start?
All histories connected as we know,
right?
It's all a bunch of tumbling dominoes
and one event and series of events leads
up to other ones and sets it all up.
Where's the logical starting point?
I'm terrible at this by the way.
I did a whole series on the decline and
fall of the Roman republic hours and
hours and hours because I was trying to
find the logical place to start a story
about Cleopatra never even got
practically to Cleopatra was all
dominoes before.
Then Iran test starts with the earliest
thing.
He knows about it and it's a miracle.
He knows about it at all.
He begins by talking about the
Assyrians.
He also talks about having multiple
versions of this story,
so Hurghada is being harassed at this.
He says,
listen,
I've heard a lot of different things.
Here are my sources.
The story begins,
boom,
and here's what he writes.
Quote from here,
our story demands that we inquire
further about Cyrus and the Persians,
who was this man who destroyed the
empire of creases and how did the
Persians become the leaders of Asia?
I shall write this account using as my
sources certain Persians who do not
intend to magnify the deeds of Cyrus,
but rather to tell what really happened.
Although I know of three other ways in
which the story of Cyrus is told and
quote,
and then he begins the story using a
phrase that should probably be proceeded
by a line like once upon a time quote.
The Assyrians ruled inland Asia for 520
years and the needs were the first to
revolt from them.
It would seem that they proved
themselves to be truly courageous men by
fighting the Assyrians for the cause of
freedom and they succeeded in casting
off slavery and we're liberated
afterwards.
The other ethnic groups freed themselves
as the medes had done and quote,
well,
the medes need a little explaining,
just like at the biblical story of
Belshazzar is feast when he said that
the empire is going to be divided
between the medes and the Persians.
The medes and the Persians are a related
people.
The Greeks used the terms
interchangeably.
They were,
you know,
practically like brothers in the eyes of
the Greeks when I was growing up,
they were just starting to change from
the brothers sort of interpretation and
may be saying,
oh,
maybe they were more like first cousins.
Some of the more recent histories I've
been reading.
Maybe you could say we downgrade the
relationship even a step further to
something like second cousins who
fought.
Sometimes historians differ on when
these related people's arrived in the
area where they can now play a role in
the history of this,
you know,
enclosed sort of geopolitical world with
Egypt and Babylon in the Syria and all
these places.
There's even a few historians who think
they may have always been there and you
just didn't hear about them.
Nevertheless,
the world upon which they have intruded
is so old.
It's hard for modern people to get our
minds around because it's hard for us to
imagine something 2,500
years ago.
You know when thermopylae is happening.
Now,
imagine something from 2,500
years before that.
That's how old this world is.
I love the way in the 19 forties,
historian 80 olmsted tried to give the
reader a sense of how old this world was
and how the people who lived in it new
it was old.
He starts by talking about Cyrus.
The second are Cyrus,
the great person after he takes over
Babylon,
trying to describe how old the world is
that Babylon represents,
and he says,
quote,
when Cyrus entered Babylon in 5:39
bce,
the world was old,
more significant.
The world knew its antiquity.
It scholars had compiled long dynastic
lists and simple addition appeared to
prove that kings whose monuments were
still visible had ruled more than for
millenniums before,
yet earlier were other monarchs,
sons of Gods,
and sold themselves.
Demi gods who's rains covered several
generations of present day short lived
men.
Even these were proceeded,
the Egyptians believed by the gods
themselves who held sway through long,
eons before the universal flood.
The Babylonians placed 10 kings,
the least of whom ruled 18,000,
600 years,
the greatest 43,200
years.
Other peoples,
he writes new this flood and told of
monarchs,
Nanacast Odium for example,
who reigned in predelivery in times,
meaning you know the times before the
biblical flood.
He continues the sacred history of the
Jews extended through 4,000
years,
modest,
as were their fingers when compared with
those of Babylon or Egypt.
They recorded that one.
Predelivery and patriarch almost reached
the millennium mark before his death.
Greek poets chanted a legendary history
which was counted backwards to the time
when the genealogies of the heroes
ascended to the God.
Each people and nation,
each former city,
state boasted of its own creation story
with its own local God is creator and to
quote,
he then goes onto diagram that in the
600 and 700 bce,
there were quite a few rulers in quite a
few of these old countries that became
archeological buffs where they would go
back and pay for the excavation of
earlier rulers that ruled a thousand,
1500 years before them and in Egypt may
have dressed similarly.
That's the continuity of the Egyptian
fashion.
Look,
my favorite story that really gives you
an idea of the antiquity of things and
how the peoples of this region
understood it,
knew it in a way that you don't normally
think about,
has to do with an archeological
excavation that happened in the late 18
hundreds,
early 19 hundreds in modern day Iran in
a city through much of the historical
period that was called Sousa.
Sousa is a very old city,
ancient city.
It will be important in the Persian
period.
It will be important.
After that period for a very long time
of people called the elamites resided in
Sousa and he was in a strata were the
Eland Mike period,
was that these archeologists began to
uncover some of the greatest treasures
and antiquities in near eastern history
and they didn't belong there.
They found,
for example,
the famous steel or steely take your
pick of Hammurabi,
something that is huge.
I mean it's a giant seven foot tall or
something heavy,
big thing,
and they find it there.
What's it doing there?
That should be in Babylon.
Now,
if you think this deal of Hama Hammurabi
is old circus,
17 hundreds bc or something like that,
archaeologists then find something
that's a good deal older than that.
It's called the victory steel of sin.
He was an Acadian King from the 22
hundreds BC.
He,
so by the time they were making the
steel of Hammurabi,
the victory steel of Naropa sin was half
a millennia old.
There were other antiquities that they
found to all of them from elsewhere.
They were the spoils,
the loot,
the stuff that the Ila Mites took back
with them when they sacked Babylon,
and in fact you could tell because
somehow all this stuff was on display
and below the original inscriptions in
the original language explaining what
this was,
was an eland might inscription
explaining when it was taken from the
Babylonians as loot and spoils and as a
piece of memorabilia commemorating a
great victory.
I keep imagining a bunch of trophies in
like a college or university or school
trophy case,
you know,
commemorating the victories over the
arrows over your school rivals the oaken
bucket,
the Apple Cup,
the steel of Hama,
Robbie,
you know,
that Kinda thing.
And by the way,
it wasn't just,
you know,
cultural artifacts that were taken in
the famous elamite might invasion that
happened in the 11 hundreds.
They took the god of Babylon with them.
They took,
Martin,
took with them the statue that
represented the God.
And this is one of my favorite things
about ancient history is this idea
sometimes that these statues that
represented the gods were somehow
connected to the god,
him or herself.
And sometimes were,
I mean there were some beliefs that they
were the gods,
and so you'll see,
for example,
the Assyrians in a lot of their stone
reliefs,
when they're showing the conquest of
some civilization or city,
they've got the God that their soldiers
are carrying away along with all of the
loot.
And it's kind of symbolic when you think
about it.
It's a sign our God is stronger than
your God.
After all,
we've got your God.
And in a lot of these near eastern
civilizations,
the historians wrote that you can't
reestablish some of these cities until
the god is returned.
So in other words,
when Babylon gets sacked and the god is
taken away,
they can't do a big rebuilding thing
until the God has brought back.
We got your God.
I mean,
talk about rubbing your nose in a defeat
there.
I mean,
I was trying to think about what the
equivalent would be in the modern world.
Certainly if somebody took over the
United States,
if the elamites had done it,
they would have the statue of Liberty in
their little museum there with a little
notation underneath taken from New York
City after we crushed the Americans.
I love the elamites and would love to
know more about them.
They're there.
One of those peoples that just not a lot
is known.
What you can say for sure is that they
are the great long standing urban power
in what's now modern day or ron for
thousands of years.
The big contemporaries and the big power
from that region that rival the
Babylon's and the Assyrians in the
Egypt's.
There's usually a power in the north to
north of Assyria,
but that changes.
It could be Matatani,
it could be the hittites.
It could be.
You are to.
Nonetheless,
you have a relatively stable geo
political balance going on for a long
time,
even through the ups and downs,
and then that world begins to be
consciously destroyed and that opens up
the door to an instability where you
know anything can happen and shocking
things did.
It starts with the absolute skyrocketing
by historical standards of the military,
dominance of the Assyrians.
Now you may be thinking,
we were just talking about the needs a
minute ago and now we've shifted over to
the Assyrians and what does one have to
do with the other,
but it's their paths crossing that sort
of up the stage for the next period.
In western Asian history,
the medes will turn out to be one of a
couple of David's in this story,
who will take down Goliath in order to
understand what a big deal that is.
You need to understand how big of a deal
Goliath was in this story.
The Assyrians are Goliath and they were
transformed in the 700 bce from one of
the great power,
sometimes the greatest of the great
power,
sometimes not into the regional
superpower,
and as far as these people were
concerned,
the region was the entire world
and this quickly growing absolutely
devastating new empire in terms of its
military abilities,
would have been the ones fighting the
Greeks and the spartans at their mop.
Ali had the medes and their allies not
been able to take down this Goliath,
and I got news for you.
I don't think the neo was Syrian.
Armies at their height would have beaten
Alexander the great and his Macedonians.
I'm not sure,
but I don't think,
but I think they crush the ancient
Greeks of Athens and Sparta,
and so maybe if the past that they're
happily in the Greco.
Persian wars really was a war for
Western civilization.
We should be thankful that there were
people like the needs to take down the
people who I think would have been the
odds on favorite in any vegas betting
pool to take down the ancient Greeks and
for ADBC,
he.
They weren't around in for ADBC in part
because of these people.
The medes who in the seven hundreds when
the story really heats up and get
strange or a people on the periphery of
the known universe at the time to the
Assyrians.
The medes are sort of the eastern edge
of the known galaxy and beyond those
muddy and tribes with all their petty
little kinglets are groups of half
human,
half monsters called the Lumen Monda in
the Syrian animals,
the Human Monda by the way in old
acadian term that means the horde from
who knows where and it's believed that
this refers to the nomadic peoples of
the step,
the cultural forebears of the hands and
the Turks and the Hmong goals and all
those people.
In fact,
the medes and the Persians were supposed
to be able to speak to the Human Monda
without the use of translators.
How'd you like to be related enough to a
people known as the horde from who knows
where to be able to understand their
language without anybody helping.
Nonetheless,
it's in this period right around 7:50
bce where you get a sort of an unusual
happening in ancient history where a lot
seems to happen in a relatively short
period of time because in ancient
history you get these long stretches
where it seems like very little changes
in 7:45
BC.
He,
with the arrival of a new Assyrian King,
a guy named Tim [inaudible],
the third,
uh,
Syria,
begins to go on this sprint,
maybe you could call it a historical
sprint that will last until about six,
15,
six,
12 bcee,
and we'll be like,
maybe you could say the last burst of
rocket fuel of that historical era of
that ancient world about to give way to
the era of the Greeks and classical
antiquity and all that kind of stuff and
rockets it to the heights where the
Assyrian army,
for example,
in say 700 BC,
he or the equivalent of like the Roman
empire,
his armies at their height for their
era.
The Assyrians will systematically smash
the other great powers in that area and
it's difficult by the way.
They're powerful.
They're sophisticated,
they have a lot of money.
Some of these places,
the Assyrians often have to face not
single states,
but coalitions of states,
big allies that allied simply to deal
with the Assyrians and they lose most of
the time.
Anyway.
I'll try not to geek out on the army too
much,
but it's the gold standard for the era.
Richard Gabriel and Karen mets in their
book from sewer to Rome,
so to describe it in a nutshell in terms
of just giving you a mental picture of
the capabilities of an army from this
era,
you know the so called Biblical era when
I was growing up,
they right quote the Assyrian Army of
the eighth century BC.
He was comprised of at least 150,000
to 200,000
men and was the largest standing
military force that the Middle East had
witnessed to this time,
and a Syrian combat field army numbered
approximately 50,000
men with various mixes of infantry
chariots in cavalry in modern times the
size of an Assyrian field.
Army was equal to five modern heavy
American divisions are almost eight
Soviet field divisions.
When it rained for battle,
the army took up an area of 2,500
yards across and a hundred yards deep.
The Assyrian army was also the first
army to be entirely equipped with iron
weapons and quote,
boy,
he doesn't that Soviet reference date
me.
Nonetheless,
you get an idea that we're talking about
armies that were exponentially larger
than in the recent past in the bronze
age,
you know,
narrow sin was putting like 6,000
guys into the field and thinking he had
a lot of men.
The Assyrians have multiple divisions of
50,000
each.
They will smash the power of the
mountain state of you.
Rawr too.
At one point during this period,
that's where modern Armenia is.
They will several times have to deal
with Babylon.
Another one of their great kings,
Senaca rib takes care of that and then
they just have to do it again and again.
Babylon is the thorn in the side
perpetually of the Syria and the
elamites always get in trouble with the
Assyrians because they always support
the Babylonians because after all,
all of them would like to see the
Assyrians cut down to size.
Eventually the Assyrians will cut the
elamites down to size to one of the most
horrifying of all the Assyrian reliefs.
And you know there's a lot of them in
historians.
Don't always know how to classify them.
You can't tell if you want to say that.
These are real scenes that they're
showing.
When you see these carvings which were
probably painted at one time,
and we're often displayed in the waiting
room before you got to see the king,
what are you looking at while you're
cooling your heels,
waiting to see the Assyrian King,
the things he did to the people like you
who may be turned against him.
Sometimes historians think that they're
taking a sadistic sort of cruel love in
this.
Sometimes it's meant to be terrifying
and they enjoy that Saddam Hussein
style.
Sometimes they think of it as a
convention in the same way the Egyptians
always seem to show them,
you know,
wearing certain kinds of clothing,
whether or not they did anymore,
it was an artistic convention.
Showing people getting their heads
lopped off is just,
you know,
if you go to a Syria,
you expect to see the Assyrian things,
that kind of deal.
That's who we are and it's.
It's a staple.
Nonetheless.
One of my favorite Assyrian reliefs
shows the aftermath of the era where the
Assyrians finally decided to deal with
the ongoing Isla might problem.
It shows the Assyrian King Osher,
Bonnie Paul reclining on one of those
wonderful oriental near eastern,
you know,
kinds of things that they used to lay
down on like a couch where they would
have somebody feed you grapes or
something and he's sitting there
drinking wine or eating food in a
luxury,
really relaxing sort of pace in a garden
with palm trees,
if I recall correctly,
and there's a woman there with him and
you get the feeling like he and that
woman are together and then right over
near by,
up on the side of a wall or a post or a
pillar is a head.
The head of the Ila Mike King,
pickled or otherwise,
and that woman who you think maybe is
osher bonded,
Paul's wife or maybe a royal concubine.
Some historians think is the wife of
that elamite.
She having to be there with the person
who killed him and have him looking on
body list the whole time at the
Assyrians just had this wonderful
historical reputation for something that
once again is cinematic.
Now it's not color,
it's not like Hurghada tests and all
that.
We don't have it in color,
but it's a really scary black and white
horror film.
If you're on the receiving end of a
series and violence,
I should point out that,
you know,
focusing so much on geopolitics and the
Syrian foreign policy may,
you know,
sort of colored the picture in a very
negative way because to live in,
in the Syrian city during this time
period might've been awesome.
I might might've been the height of
civilization,
you know,
it was,
it was a society that was in some
respects,
one of the most literate at all time
periods.
It was wealthy.
It was cultured.
Might have been great to live in the
Siri.
You just didn't want to be on the wrong
end of a,
of foreign policy.
And from about 7:45
BC to about the,
you know,
early six hundreds.
A lot of people were and very few people
came away doing very well after that.
They systematically battered down the
structures of this region.
Now battering down the structures of the
region.
We're very important.
If you wanted to kind of make it a
mineable to being incorporated into a
single political entity like an empire.
Everybody's individualistic.
Nature had to be curtailed somewhat.
The problem will come when the unifying
force that did this disappears to get an
idea by the way of how many peoples
we're talking about here and as a
wonderful way to sort of contradict the
earlier way the story was told,
which was focusing on people's ethnicity
a lot and to say,
you know,
the Assyrians were submitted and the
Iranian people's,
the medes and the Persians were Indo
European,
and all that is to realize when you deal
with a place that is so filled with
different ethnic groups,
intermarrying living together,
that it doesn't take very long for
people's languages to change.
Which used to be the way we judged who
was whom.
It also means that the job of any
unifying force that wants to turn all
these different freedom loving groups
into a single political entity is huge.
Historian will durant tries to,
you know,
lay the foundation and and basically
says,
you know,
just so you know,
look at how many peoples there are in
this part of the world and they're all
interacting all the time and they're
intermarrying and to me it's an ethnic
melting pot.
He says,
quote,
do a distant and yet discerning eye.
The Near East in the days of
Nebuchadrezzar would have seemed like an
ocean in which vast swarms of human
beings moved about in turmoil,
forming and dissolve in groups in
slaving are being enslaved,
eating or being eaten,
killing or getting killed endlessly
behind and around the great empires,
Egypt,
Babylonia,
Assyria,
and Persia flowered this medley of half
nomad.
Half settled tribes can marion's
colleague Ian's Kapito oceans,
but Finian's Ash Caymanians Messinians
me own Ian's carions,
like Ian's pamphlet to presidions
Lakini,
Ian's Philistines,
Amorites Canaanites,
Eda,
Mites ammonites,
the Moabites,
and a hundred other peoples,
each of which felt itself the center of
geography and history.
And would have marveled at the ignorant
prejudice of a historian who would
reduce them to a paragraph and a quote.
I've got a bunch of historians who talk
about how difficult the task is to Meld
all these individualistic different
peoples into a single political entity.
Chester star writing in the middle of 19
sixties,
put it this way,
as he tries to sort of counterbalance
this ruthless image the Assyrians have
with the job they're trying to do,
and he writes,
quote,
this spirit perhaps proves not so much
that the Assyrians were in human
monsters.
As it shows the sternness required to
break and harness the Near East.
The Assyrian period was in reality,
one of the greatest turning points in
the civilized history of the area,
and in this fact must be sought the
justification for the booty and the
tribute of empire.
If Empire needs justification
politically,
such kings as tig left.
The third took decisive steps towards
uniting the Fertile Crescent.
The next grade empire,
the Persian reaped the benefit.
And so could afford to exercise its sway
in a more lenient style.
And quote,
this is actually key to one of the
things we've been talking about,
the fact that even though the Greeks
portrayed,
you know,
the Persians as sort of darth vader and
the empire history outside the Greeks
knew them as a comparatively tolerant
empire,
comparatively lenient,
who were they being compared to the
Assyrians,
but it may have taken what the Assyrians
did to make an empire that was docile
enough for the Persians to treat them
that way and have it all work out.
I should also point out that there are
quite a few historians that would
suggest that the Assyrians have another
legacy that we should potentially credit
them with a much more noble sounding
one.
By the way,
despite the horrific marketing and the
frightful branding of the Assyrians,
perhaps you might look at them during
this time period,
depending on your viewpoint.
In more of a captain America style role,
fending off the hordes of barbarism from
swamping the civilized world with their,
you know,
murder and robbery.
Because in the last years of the seven
hundreds bce,
the Uhlmann Monda breakthrough.
And when they do,
it will take the greatest military of
that age to be able to resist and go up
against what is a revolutionary military
challenge.
The first peoples in history probably
who had to try to figure out how you
defeat an army where everyone in the
army is mounted on horseback.
Now.
Our modern era is so different than how
the dynamics of warfare worked for most
of human history that at sometimes.
And sometimes we have to reintroduce the
more obvious things to sort of click a
light bulb on in your head and remind
you,
oh yeah,
we're talking about something this
basic.
For example,
I and I love these military revolution
periods.
Can you imagine what it must have been
like when the first cherry,
it's attacked the first,
you know,
settled civilizations out there in the
first time in army that was composed
entirely of people walking,
had to deal with something moving at the
speed of a horse.
And by the way,
the way that they usually function was
that the person inside the cherry and
had a very powerful blow and shot arrows
at people and never really tried to
contact them at all until they were
broken and running away so you couldn't
catch them and they moved faster than
you did.
And it changed warfare.
And sometimes it's funny by the way,
to read some of the,
the,
the records that have been kept that you
have from some of these very early
chariots societies and you realize how
little they know about horses because
people who knew anything about horses
are these really high paid,
important individuals and they have this
hidden knowledge about,
you know,
here's how you take care of the feet of
a horse and here's what you do.
If they get bloat,
I mean things that today,
bazillions of people know back then.
This was like privileged information,
how you care for these things,
right?
And the Horse in the subtle societies,
the Egypt,
the Babylon's in the series.
At first you can see that they,
that they don't know how to deal with
the animal.
I mean,
there are wonderful little figurines and
whatnot showing you know,
the Egyptian,
maybe it's like an Egyptian scout during
maybe the first 200 years or something
that the Egyptians were really trying to
use horses and he's sitting way back
over the tail of the horse,
like he hasn't even figured out that
that's not the right spot to sit in,
but we take it for granted that this is
an obvious thing,
might not have been about 1000 bce.
Cavalry first appears and it generally
appears in,
in,
in a way that once again makes you think
that these people are not very
comfortable writing.
And remember there are no saddles,
there are no spurs,
there are no stirrups.
I mean there's a lot of knack to knowing
what you're doing here.
And remember also that riding horses can
be injurous and fatal if you're not used
to it.
Right?
And none of these people are growing up
doing a whole lot of horse riding and
about 900 bce you can see carving
showing a Syrian cavalry,
which is probably,
if you think about it,
you know,
cutting edge for the time period for the
subtle civilizations and they send the
cavalry riders out in Pairs because one
guy has to hold the reigns for the other
guy's horse.
When the other guy decides he's gonna
shoot or anything.
In other words,
they don't even feel comfortable enough
to shoot and ride.
You know,
independently.
You've got to have someone there to hold
the horse.
When you do it.
Another words,
you can watch the evolution,
right?
It's different when the armies from the
Middle East,
the ancient near east first run into the
steppe troops.
That will make up one of the dominant
important tribal areas in world history
for almost ever.
I mean it's only the last couple hundred
years that the Eurasian Steppe part of
which you would refer to as Central Asia
today,
Kazakhstan,
Kyrgyzstan,
those kinds of places.
Certainly in the last couple hundred
years,
those places have not been massively
relevant to what's going on.
I was reading a book not that long ago
that it was going into all of the things
that China and Russia have.
The 17 hundreds see is only
a couple hundred years ago.
All the things that they had to do to
deal with the tribes on the step and
it's crazy because,
you know,
when you look at history,
you become very accustomed to watching
the so called civilized society is just
rolling over tribal peoples,
you know,
at a certain point in history once,
once the momentum gets going and you
have like Julius Caesar and Roman armies
just rolling over Celtic society,
you're already prepared to get to the
part where the colonial Europeans,
you know,
show up on these distant shores and run
into people with wooden clubs and bows
and arrows.
When you've got guns,
I mean,
it's a foregone conclusion,
right?
But you look at the step and you see the
one place in history,
we're for a number of different reasons.
The odds are much more equal between
settled and tribal peoples.
First of all,
it's likely that the odds in terms of
fighting power in terms of manpower was
probably pretty close.
The settler societies had a lot more
people,
but a lot of them weren't fighters.
The tribal societies usually had most of
their mail people as fighters
and some females.
By the way,
the weapons technology was probably
comparable.
The the bose used by this step.
People are famously some of the best
ever made,
but there would've been other things
that the settled so called settled
societies had in their favor,
so probably a wash there,
but imagine imagine the native Americans
with a rough parody and fighting men and
a rough parody in weapons technology.
What would the native Americans have
done to the settlers?
Then?
Who knows,
but at least it's a fair fight added
that the geographic conditions and the
distance,
right?
This is a harsh environment.
The steps sometimes if you're not
adapted to it and it's a long way from
point a to point b,
no matter where you're going and you had
a part of the world that was protected
by step peoples for Millennia,
where they maintained their way of life
and were,
shall we say,
relevant,
is a good non biased in any direction.
Word relevant to the societies and world
powers around them and we've known them
forever,
right?
We've seen wave after wave of these
people come forward from the Magyars to
the Turks,
to the hands to the Hmong goals.
This is the first period in recorded
history where these people break through
and someone's there to record it.
There's always been a historical school
of thought that chariot invasions from
Central Asia long before this period
represent earlier versions of these
kinds of invasions,
but this is the first one recorded where
you get to see,
you know,
the kinds of step armies you will expect
for the next 2000 years mounted on
horseback with people who are.
You know,
as we said about the Spartans,
that they were sort of a laboratory
experiment to see if a culture could
create a super soldier.
The step societies are are kind of a
laboratory experiment too.
If you put people on horseback from the
time when they're toddlers and put a bow
in their hand from not much later and
have them ride all the time and do
everything on horseback and use those
bose continually and develop tactics
where they never really come into
contact with peoples.
They don't want to come in.
I mean,
what do you end up with?
And the answer is you end up with a
weapons system that was so effective
that even after guns were developed.
Modern societies,
we're having a tough time,
pardon the pun,
corralling these people even up until
relatively modern times now when you
think about how long that is,
people trying to contend with the step
people.
Think about how much admiration we
should have with the first people who
had to try with no track record or
experience.
The Assyrians would develop a kind of a
broad policy of dealing with these
tribal step people that resembles what
very sophisticated people who dealt with
them for a very long time came up with
the Chinese and the Byzantines for
example.
Would you use a mix of diplomacy,
intermarriage,
warfare,
and you know,
keeping the tribes divided and fighting
amongst themselves and the Assyrians did
all this stuff too.
They use some of these people as allies.
Sometimes they'd have mercenaries who
were,
you know,
people from these tribes,
the tribes like the comedians in the
[inaudible] and the various psychotic
tribes and the massive ged.
They have all these wonderful tribal
confederations and one is scarier than
the next,
and if you're one of those settled
society people,
barbarians in air quotes always scared.
You mean there was just something scary
to settle people about.
You know,
people like the celts for example,
the Athenians are no different.
The various step peoples are no
different.
They're headhunters,
for example,
famously will drink from the skulls of
their dead enemies.
Make cups out of them and if you want to
see how the wonderful continuity of step
culture sometimes go.
They were doing this in in ancient times
and they were doing this up until
relatively,
you know,
goal type history,
the drinking cups.
Golfing was a perennial favorite,
but that's just a cultural thing,
right?
I mean the Assyrians are hanging
enemies,
heads on walls so that they can watch
their wife have relations with the
Assyrian king who killed them.
I mean,
everybody's got their thing right.
At the same time,
you know these people are scary,
they're effective,
they are entirely mounted,
which means they have amazing challenges
to the militaries of the day because
remember,
you move at the speed of your slowest
person.
If you have an entire army mounted,
the entire army moves at the speed of a
horse.
These are huge challenges and the
Assyrians managed to ward off the worst
of the attacks and in the sense,
you know,
you could make a case that they
protected this entire area of
civilization from marauding is scary
peoples who were not going to leave it
intact.
And you know this because there were
several invasions that did break
through.
There's a hoard of [inaudible] that will
rape and pillage all the way down to
Egypt before the Egyptians either buy
them off or militarily turned
them back and they they go bouncing
around the region like a sneaker ball.
The fact that in a lot of these step
armies,
every single person was mounted was also
revolutionary and huge in the armies of
the day.
If you were lucky,
had 15 or 20 percent of their force
mounted,
sometimes quite a bit less.
You still move at the speed of your
slowest troops though if you don't.
If you break the cavalry officer,
you can operate independently.
You'll have a nice small group of
cavalry that gets overwhelmed by an
entirely mounted forest,
so nonetheless,
and army with inventory moves at the
speed of infantry.
These armies that the settled societies
in this geopolitical realm and Cheyenna
are trying to deal with,
move at the speed of a horse
strategically on the map.
That's a devastating thing to try to
counter.
The fact that the Assyrians could is a
testimony to how great the greatest
military of the world had ever seen was
and how well lead.
Nonetheless,
you could see how big the challenge was
in seven.
Oh,
five bce Sargon the second,
arguably the greatest king of Syria ever
had will as an elderly man lead the
Assyrian Army in person up to modern
southeastern Turkey,
near the border of neo hittite area
called to ball and probably fighting in
conjunction with some of these,
uh,
neo hittite cities,
Eurasian Steppe troops,
comedians are skiff,
eons and Sargon.
The second will disappear with the army.
The body will never be recovered.
That is a very rare event.
When the body is not recovered,
the assumption is that nobody got out
because one of the last things you will
do is grab the king's body and spirited
away.
It's like saving the flag times 10,
there'll be an Egyptian king to famously
who was bones will stay on the
battlefield and they,
they,
they ended up getting it later.
And mummifying a body that's been
mutilated it on the battlefield for a
few weeks.
And you can still look at the mommy
today and see,
oh wow,
they didn't get to him for awhile.
So I on the second will never be found.
I've often thought it's not a
coincidence his son Senaca.
We've never actually led a force in
person when he was king.
He left that to the generals.
There's very important things in Nineveh
that need taken care of.
As we all understand.
Anyone who could do that too,
in the Syrian army at the height of a
serious power is formidable indeed.
Now,
even though a Siri could protect some of
this region,
they couldn't protect all of it,
and some of these tribes filtered down
into the area where the people were
ostensibly talking about,
here are the medes,
the Persians,
the Elamites,
the Zagros mountains,
Iran.
The peoples in this region are about to
go through a one,
two punch that will change them forever.
The second of these punches will be
delivered by
the Assyrians.
Surprise,
surprise.
They were throwing punches everywhere.
Why shouldn't this region get hit to the
first will be delivered by these step
people,
these tribes of [inaudible] and
[inaudible] who will at a certain point
I said filtered.
I thought that was a nice ambiguous way
when you don't really know what
happened,
but the traditional idea is that the
[inaudible] and the comedians attacked
and broke into an assaulted the needs in
a giant invasion.
There's even a year associated with its
6:53
bce,
which if you think about it's like 50
years after Sargon,
the second dies,
you know,
up into ball,
right?
About 55,
60 years since these horse people first
appeared and they're still managing to
totally disrupt in a huge areas of this
geopolitical ecosystem.
Only use that word from now on.
We all know what I mean,
right?
Filtered is a good word though,
because it also allows room for a theory
where warfare sort of doesn't dominate
the reasoning behind why all of a sudden
all these central Asian tribes moved
into this part of Iran.
One of the things that's really changed
since I first started studying the story
is the concept that historians have
about who these medallions were and what
kind of state they had when I was
growing up.
The history is all made.
It sound like the means were like the
Babylonians and the Assyrians by this
time,
a centralized state with cities and
governments and bureaucracies and all
that.
Historians today,
and you know,
I'm not one I just read the best,
um,
they make it sound much more like the
current state of theory is that these
needs are much more tribal than we had
previously assumed.
And if so might not be that much
different than these [inaudible] Syrians
coming into their area.
This could be much more like a tribal
relationship.
What did we say?
The medes and the Persians were second
cousins who fought.
Sometimes these step people's are like
third cousins who fight a lot.
Remember they could allegedly speak to
each other without the use of a
translator.
When you're that close to another
people.
What appears to be a conquest from
outside might be much more like dynastic
marriage or someone having to change
their alliance status or becoming a
vassal of someone else or having to pay
tribute Hurghada tissue might see all of
that stuff as a version of slavery,
but when he calls it slave,
where we might be picturing something
else entirely
erotic just says that the domination of
the needs last 28 years and an
interesting little in a tidbit that
might confirm what he says is during
that time period,
the Assyrians,
the Babylonians who keep records and who
knows and mentioned the medes from time
to time,
start calling everyone who lives in that
whole region,
the womb and Munda and recess are gummy
among others.
Suggest that this might mean that the
entire area has just been sort of
overwhelmed and that you can't tell one
tribe from another without a scorecard.
Hurghada test if you want to go with
this,
tells one of his really fun stories.
Um,
you know,
if you're like me,
about how the medes eventually threw off
the nomadic yoke that was oppressing
them.
And he tells a story about how they
invited the [inaudible] and leaders to a
banquet and then got them all drunk and
then when they were also a knee created,
they could hardly stand.
They went in and killed them all,
I guess you could call that,
you know,
decapitating the enemy leadership
literally.
Or maybe the tactic is drunk and mass
homicide,
whatever you want to call it.
It seems like a motif.
Another one of these recurring sorts of
things you see all throughout history
and the writing and one of those,
one of those aspects of the story that
oftentimes professional historians will
discount because after all we see this
all the time.
This sounds just like blah,
blah,
blah.
And they're almost always right.
Here's the weird part though.
This is something that you actually see
in history,
confirm bubbly.
The relationship between using alcohol
as some sort of a trap to ensnare other
people who then become vulnerable.
I mean,
we've seen this in recorded history like
not that long ago.
Native American tribes had this
treatment done to them sometimes
multiple times.
In other words,
what might it look in this case?
Like a recurring motif might actually be
a recurring historical occurrence.
How would you tell the difference?
In any case,
it'll happen again in this story,
which once again makes you say,
okay,
is this just a recurring motif or is
this a tactic that worked last time?
So we're trying it again.
Nonetheless,
somehow the medes regain in a freedom of
action from these people who were then
thrown out,
leaving behind another wonderful ethnic
strain of the central Asian bloodline
that will run through Iran over the ages
and that will be added to with new
blood,
sometimes,
tragically from time to time.
The guy who is supposedly the king of
the medes during this period of
domination by the [inaudible] is a mead
name.
See accessories,
carotids his credits him with totally
reorganizing the military of the medes.
He says that because the accessories
becomes the first Asian leader too,
you know,
separate and army into component parts,
archers and Spearman and cavalry.
He says before that they all fought
together in a chaotic mass,
which is not true at all,
but some historians think he's
preserving some sort of a memory of this
important medean ruler who reorganize
the military and made it much more
powerful and considering what he was
about to do with it.
There seems to be some historical
evidence for the medes all of a sudden
becoming very formidable indeed.
Right about the same time.
When the great traditionally great power
in that region gets mortally wounded by
Assyria,
and we alluded to this earlier,
part of a serious laying waste to all
these,
you know,
competitors for their superpower status,
right?
There's not going to be anybody that
even gets to put up a little resistance.
The elamites,
once again,
get on the hit list for doing the same
thing.
They always do.
Babylon revolt against the Syria.
Elom helps Babylon.
As soon as the Assyrians take care of
Babylon,
they come for the elamites and this
happens under the last of the Great
Assyrian rulers is Bonnie,
Paul Oscher,
Bonnie Paul,
who's who's a very long ruling guy,
and at the start of his reign,
the empire could not be at a higher
place by the end of his reign.
You know he's writing these.
Woe is me tales.
What did I do to have the gods turned
against me?
Everything sucks,
you know,
but all die soon,
at least kinds of.
I'm in a writings.
Syria will go from the height of its
fortunes to 1945,
Berlin follow the Third Reich
devastation,
never to rise again in a very short
period of time and some have argued that
part of the reason why is because of
what they did to the people around them.
They destroyed the other powers who
might have acted as barriers against new
rising ones.
Whether the new rising ones are
[inaudible] and [inaudible] from the
Eurasian Steppe,
or whether they're an obscure tribal
people known as the medes,
who all of a sudden they're really
getting powerful and well led who
otherwise would have been dealing with
the Ila Mites,
but the elamites gets smashed by Asher,
Bonnie Paul in 6:46
BC.
He and the devastation is arguably
mortal.
We already mentioned a scene from the
aftermath of this isla might final
solution when Asha,
Bonnie Paul's lying on his couch with
that woman there and then the severed
head,
you know,
up on the pillar of their wall.
That's,
you know,
part of the aftermath of dealing with
the elamites this way.
Asha,
Bonnie,
Paul Leeds,
the greatest Syrian army,
all the way.
It's a long way again to susa devastates
elom as his scribe,
writing for himself recounts,
quote for a distance of one month in 25
days.
March.
I devastated the districts of Ylem.
I spread salt and thorn Bush there to
injure the soil.
Sons of the king's sisters of the king's
members of royal family,
young and old prefix governors nights.
Artisans,
as many as there were inhabited and male
and female,
big and little horses,
mules,
asses,
flocks and herds more numerous than a
swarm of locusts.
I carried them off as boody to Assyria,
the dust of Sousa of Murdoch to of how
and of the other cities.
I carried it off to a Syria in a month
of days.
I subdued elam in its whole extent,
the voice of man,
the steps of flocks and herds.
The happy shouts of Mirth.
I put an end to them in its fields,
which I left for the asses,
the gazelles and all manner of wild
beasts to people and quote.
The Assyrians were thorough.
They even removed the bones of the old
going back to ancient times.
Isla might rulers from their tombs and
took them back to a Siri with dilute my
story in a tea.
Olmsted says they put them in
particularly awful spots so that they
would get no rest ever again,
laying in a foreign land and paying an
eternal price for their enmity to
Assyria.
That may have happened in the deep,
misty errors of the past.
I mean,
we said to you earlier that the elamites
conquered the United States.
They take the statue of Liberty back as
a prize of war to be displayed.
Will.
The Assyrians wouldn't stop at the
Statue of Liberty.
They'd steal our constitution.
They take the Washington monument,
they sniff out the flame of John f
Kennedy's grave and take the bones with
them.
The Assyrians were sort of setting the
bar for this region.
People like the Babylonians who come
afterwards will be just as brutal,
like they're trying to imitate whatever
the standard of the day is,
but the standard of the day is,
even today,
I mean,
try making a movie out of it.
It's gonna be.
It's gonna.
Be a cable one for sure.
I mean the story almost had tells of the
parade.
Is that a good word?
When Osher,
Bonnie,
Paul and his army arrived back home in
Nineveh,
displaying the loot and the prisoners
and meeting out punishment by the way to
all and sundry is frightful.
First of all,
the head of that elamite ruler that will
be sitting up on us.
You're bonded.
Paul's wall or what have you,
was transported from Susa on foot around
the neck of the Ila might general
imagine how freaky that would have been
to live through who did the walking.
Shane's supposedly,
and then the various generals are
brought out and punished,
and there's a psychological twists to a
Syrian punishment.
By the way,
that is part of kind of what the
Persians will sort of do away with.
Here's what 18 olmsted writes,
and I'm going to try my best at some of
the pronunciations of these Mesopotamian
names.
They are wonderful.
He writes,
quote Osher,
Bond I.
Paul was about to leave our Bella for
Nineveh and the severed head of the Ila
might ruler was entrusted to his general
dot,
New News,
neck for transport.
As the musicians lead the gasoline
procession into Nineveh,
the terrible site crazed how Mandara and
Nabu domonique the ambassadors who had
received their commissions from the dead
monarch.
One tour his beard,
the other thrust,
his girdle sword into his bosom.
Apulia son of Nabulu Shalam and grandson
of the famous Mera Doc Bala.
Don was extradited from elom.
Manu done nu new and Nabulu Shalam.
The Gumbo Ulu chief tins had spoken
blasphemy against the Assyrian Gods and
for this crime they had their tongues
pulled out by the roots and were skinned
alive.
The horrible scene is represented on one
of the reliefs,
although strangely enough,
olmsted writes,
the names have never been filled in.
The blanks left for the purpose.
The new new was placed on the rack and
slaughtered like a lamb.
His brother,
Sam Guna,
when Appalachia were slain and their
flesh distributed among the surrounding
lands.
Now Bu naive and Bella tear,
sons of Nablus,
Schumer were forced to crush the bones
of their father and the head of the Ila
Mike King found its final resting place
over the gate,
which led to assure and quote,
osher being a primary Assyrian city.
The forcing the sons to crush the bones
of the father is one of those really
psychologically horrible things.
And you'll see this in other occasions.
The Babylonian King,
for example,
who supposedly once he took Jerusalem,
took the ruler the king and forced him
to watch the slaughtering of his two
young sons in front of his eyes and then
had his eyes put out.
So that the last thing he saw was that,
I mean,
those are the extra little cruelties
that just seem,
well,
that just seemed calculated to subdue
somebody who's will to resist,
but you could easily see how it might
have the opposite effect.
You could see how,
uh,
people coming after this time might be
able to make all sorts of political hay
selling themselves as the alternative to
this kind of cruelty.
And you can also see why when a Syria
foul,
there were not a lot of tears cried for
what was gone.
In fact,
you know,
even the biblical prophets are
rejoicing.
As I was trying to come up with some
sort of analogy to try to define the
stakes here with what's about to happen.
All I could think of in my uncreative
mind was the idea of the United States
over the next five or so years.
Somehow,
you know,
with jaw dropping,
astonishing events fell apart or
imploded
and a broken to some kind of a civil war
ended up getting involved in maybe a
foreign war at the same time.
I mean,
he never know how these things are gonna
turn.
Remember how you felt if you were old
enough to remember what the 9:11
attacks look like
on live television while you watched
them?
There's almost nothing positive that
comes out of something like that,
but one of the few things that was in my
mind was as you watched it,
you were reminded that the most
astonishing things not only can happen
but will happen.
They're like earthquakes.
You know there's going to be a big one.
You just don't know when you know
there's going to be some massive jaw
dropping historical event in the future.
You just don't know the date ahead of
time,
like a nine slash 11,
but when you watch that happening,
that astonishment is how mankind has
failed over and over and over again.
As you look back on it,
there's about to be an astonishing
moment in this story.
It's not really a moment,
five to 15 years.
It just appears astonishing now,
but it's akin to the United States
imploding.
Really.
I think it's more than the Soviet Union
falling,
but a little less than the modern United
States going away.
Nonetheless,
if the United States did go away in the
next five years,
what does the international situation
look like then mean what world instantly
springs up to replace such an important
cog and how does that go?
This is actually the world that is going
to exist as soon as this story that must
be,
you know,
one of the great events in all human
history,
but we don't know because we don't have
a [inaudible] there to give it even with
a bunch of lies and exaggerations and
untruths that may have filtered in over
the hundreds of years.
We don't have his version or anyone like
him to explain it to us.
We liked the color.
I brought at this,
by the way,
promised he was going to tell this story
in one part of his histories and then
never did or didn't come down to us or
something.
Have a few tourists,
Babylonian sources and that's it.
In fact,
the stuff you thought you could count
on,
like those wonderful Assyrian,
you know,
pronouncements by the king of kings.
I went in there,
I planted thorn bushes.
I killed everybody.
That ends in like 6:30,
nine bce,
ominously,
and mysteriously all of a sudden,
what the heck's going on?
I love the different ways that
historians try to describe this to.
One one historian says it was unclear
what was happening.
Author Mark Healey explained the
importance though of this period silence
because he says quote,
and it is in the silence of those years
that is written the fate of the Assyrian
Empire,
and so the important stuff is happening.
We just don't know much of what it is.
Open to interpretation is how another
historian put it,
but here's what basically goes on.
Osher,
bond,
I Paul's rain.
At the end,
you start to see things fraying.
It begin to see places that were under a
serious control on the on the margins
break free.
A lot of historians think that it's
rather telling that all of a sudden you
can have these skiffy and tribes riding
rough now in areas where the Assyrians
used to keep them out.
It must mean that they can't.
While no
one is really paying a lot of attention.
The medes are beginning to fuse sort of
ends,
and it's unclear how they did this with
the elamites.
Civilization.
Could have been peaceful,
could been warlike,
could've been diplomatic marriage,
but it's making both civilization
stronger.
And Osher,
Bonnie Paul dies and his sons go to war
with each other.
Now,
this is not uncommon in Assyrian royal
succession,
but this is coming at a particularly bad
time because all of a sudden the
Babylonians are resurgent again.
They've got a new dynasty.
They've got an army that is modeled.
It's,
it's,
uh,
not as effective copy of the Assyrians,
the Assyrians copy,
the Babylonian civilization not quite as
well as the Babylonian original.
And the Babylonians copied the Assyrian
military.
Though it's not quite up to the
originals standards either,
but when you've been fighting one half
of your army against the other,
which is what the Assyrians were doing
in a civil war,
that's why they're so ruinous.
You know,
you have outside powers starting to loom
over you.
And what do you do with your army?
You divide it in half and fight it
against each other.
Worse possible thing that could happen.
And then the Babylonians starting in
about 6:16,
start sending out an army,
taking some of these border cities
between Assyria and Babylon,
and then the war heats up a little bit
in there fighting back and forth,
and the Assyrian Army seems to be a
shadow of its former self.
But you could see how strong it still is
because they're holding their own
against these Babylonians,
pushing them back,
sometimes chasing them back sometimes,
but it's all they can handle.
And then in like six slash 15 bce,
the medes jump in from the east and the
north,
they start taking cities in the east.
The next year,
the medes come forward under their king,
see accessories and advances on,
you know,
one of the capitals,
Nineveh,
they can't take it because Nineveh is
this massively fortified,
probably the most fortified city west of
China in this whole human history up to
this point.
I mean,
just an incredible feat.
Human Marvel and it pushes these means
sideways.
They just can't deal with it right now.
But unfortunately for the Assyrians,
if you can't go out there and defeat
that muddy and army,
they can do whatever they want so they
go sack in nearby city that's not as
well defended.
It just happens to be one of the great,
you know,
once upon a time,
a Syrian capitals vital,
connected to their religion and their
God and and morale and everything else.
It's a big deal.
At the last minute,
the Babylonians run up to be a part of
it.
This is a famous event.
They,
they,
they don't want to allow the media to
take this important city by themselves,
be left out of the spoils,
the reputation,
everything,
but they arrived too late with their
army.
The means of already the place,
maybe
rushing the attempt so that they'd beat
the Babylonians mayor.
They treated the way the Assyrians would
have treated it,
and it's a horrific event.
The Babylonian King and the Medean king
pledged their friendship to each other.
As osher burns in the background and the
killing continues in,
the slaves are being dragged off and all
of a sudden a week into Syria has
Babylon and the medes working together
and advancing on Nineveh in six,
12 bcee.
If this wasn't bad enough at the last
minutes,
allegedly not everybody says this,
but the standard belief is at the last
minute,
a horde of skiff,
Ian's in a rides in the wild northern
horsemen and joins both the medes and
the Babylonians in this last assault
upon this greatest of West Asian
military fortresses,
and together they take it down,
had to fight three battles on the
plains,
supposedly before they even got a chance
to get near the walls with this last old
aging damage,
lion of a serious swatting them away and
fighting well as long as they could
the Babylonian king in the terse style.
You know that those people wrote in,
described what he did to what he calls
the land of [inaudible],
which is their word for Syria.
And by the way,
notice how he's couching this in terms
of liberation from the,
you know,
a Syrian yoke.
The record,
say,
quote,
I slaughtered the land of [inaudible].
I turned the hostile land into heaps and
ruins the Assyrian who since distant
days had ruled over all the peoples and
with his heavy yoke brought injury to
the people of the land,
his feet from a cod.
I turned back his yoke.
I threw off and quote,
and you have a basic problem when,
when discussing events of the past like
this,
if we're discussing something from
recent history,
say the end of the third,
right,
hit the second world war,
all that emotion is still felt right.
You get a real feel for the kinds of
things historians don't want to touch.
Once you get back a certain distance,
some day they're not going to look at
the Nazis as the kind of evil that we
do.
They're going to somehow say,
well,
they were on the far end of the spectrum
of what people did then,
which is kind of what a lot of modern
ones would say about a Syria.
They're not doing anything anybody else
isn't doing.
They just may be at the far end of the
spectrum of,
you know,
conduct.
It's all kind of relative,
right,
but you could certainly see the anger
and vengeance in the people that goes
beyond mere,
you know,
the taking of and slaves
and the things that have motivated
soldiers sometimes in the heat of battle
at all times.
This involved some payback
story.
Mark Vandy,
Maru explains that you can still see at
vengeance today mean there's an eternal
bit of payback that was done.
He writes,
quote,
the conquerors set out to destroy the
cities of Assyria,
taking revenge for the humiliations they
had suffered a serious hands on wall
reliefs of kings,
Senaca Reeb and Asher,
Bonnie Paul in Nineveh,
for example.
They identified the representations of
the kings with the help of the
inscriptions accompany them and ritually
destroyed them by cutting out the ears
and eyes.
These were not random acts of mutilation
in the detailed depiction of Asha Bonnie
Paul's defeated the Elamites,
for example,
only the face of a soldier cutting off
the head of the king of Ilan was
similarly destroyed probably by the
medes who saw the elamites as their
ancestors.
Likewise,
the records of loyalty oaths that King
Esr had on had forced Medea and body
guards to swear and which had been
stored at cal who were smashed.
The palaces were burnt down only after
the lengthy task of defacing images and
destroying symbols of submission to a
Syria had been completed and quote.
If you go to the British Museum today
and look at the Assyrian reliefs,
you can see,
you know the defacing done by some angry
vengeful and probably rightfully so
soldier as they took down with Syria
piece by piece,
but stunningly quickly by historical
standards.
And while there may be no hurghada tests
to give color to this story,
there is one of the most,
I guess for military history fans,
one of the most colorful sections of the
Old Testament of the Bible that deals
with the fall of the Syria and I'm sure
a Syrian descendants and people who are
big Assyrian fans think this is very
unfair sort of propaganda.
Again,
it's just they're bad luck to get bad pr
sometimes in the Bible and the biblical
Prophet Niamh was prophesizing
supposedly that you're going to get it.
And then once they did get it,
he was sort of saying,
see,
this is what you get.
Now what's kind of interesting about
nay,
unlike some of these other prophets,
it's,
there's a decent chance he was a
contemporary.
A lot of this stuff was put together in
the hellenistic period later,
you know,
from earlier stories are all kinds of
things dealing with that era.
But some of this goes back and it's
tough to know and historians argue,
but it's possible that this prophet
named guy was maybe even a predecessor
to some of these events.
So who knows,
you know,
I won't get into something like that.
I just found it interesting because when
he recounts what happens,
first of all,
he gives you the color and tells you a
little bit about the story in a,
in a religious sort of framework.
Still doesn't sound like Hurghada just
there's a religious tone to it.
But at the same time it's very colorful.
So he describes,
for example,
you know what the battle is like after
prophesizing,
that you're going to get it for a long
time,
and he says,
quote,
he that shatters in pieces has come up
against the guard,
the wall guard the way good thy loins
make dice strength,
the utmost.
The Shield of his heroes is red.
His warriors are colliding scarlet.
They prepare the chariots today that
cherry had horses are eager.
The Cherry,
it's rage in the field.
They rushed to and fro in the plazas.
Their appearance is like that of
torches.
They dart about like lightning's.
He reads out the list of his nobles in
their eagerness.
They stumble,
they hastened to reach the walls.
The battering ram is made ready.
And then they,
um,
describes the unleashing of the rivers.
I guess the dams were broken or rerouted
or they reroute the course of the rivers
or what have you to help undermine the
walls.
That's not that unusual a tactic.
But with a big city like this,
not a small engineering feat.
And the prophet named says,
quote the reverse sluices or opened the
palace,
walls are crumbling.
The Queen is stripped of her clothing.
They are leading her away captive.
Her handmaidens Moan like doves,
upon their breasts,
they are beating Nineveh was a tank of
water from it.
They are now escaping stand,
stand.
They cry,
not one of them looks backward and then
he basically tells everybody to take
back the stuff that a Syria took from
them and that their housing in this
immensely wealthy city.
He says,
quote,
take either spoil of silver,
take either spoil of gold.
There is no end to the store and
abundance of all goodly objects.
She is empty and void and waste hearts
melt,
knees shake.
There is pain in all loins and Pale.
Have waxed all the faces and then he
does a little trash talk,
gloating,
you know,
where he says,
where are the,
you know,
great lions now and all the people who
took all this stuff.
And then like again,
so many of the people during this era,
this was seen to involve,
you know,
a little proof that their God was
superior.
Or in the case of some of these people,
by this point in history,
the only God a name says,
behold I am against thee,
says y'all way of hosts that I layer I
will burn with smoke.
They're young.
The sword shall devour.
I will cut off,
die,
pray from the earth.
No more be heard.
They messengers voices and he continues
to rub it in and basically blame this on
Karma if you will.
Woe to the bloody city full of lies and
robbery,
the crack of the whip and the thunder of
the rumbling.
We'll the prancing horse and the
bounding chariot,
the horseman mounting and the flash of
stored the gleam of spear and a massive
slain a heap of corpses.
There are no end to the dead bodies for
the many infidelities of the well
favorite,
the
mistress of incantations who sold states
for her wicked deeds and clans through
her incantations.
Behold say,
if the outweigh of host I am against
thee,
I will strip the UAE clothing and show
that I shamed the nation's filth.
I will cast upon thee and disgraced the.
I will set the up as a warning.
All who see the shall flee shall cry,
desolate Nineveh,
who shall be whale her end quote.
Well listen,
they may not have a ton of dramatic
stuff from the Near East during this
time period,
but that's awesome.
I mean all history aside,
that's awesome stuff and it does give
you a feel for the emotion of the time
period.
We may think you know that it's all been
drained,
but that's somebody who is clearly
thinking that is Syria is reaping what
she sewed.
Again,
I pity the poor Syrian people who have
to live with one piece of horrible pr,
making it down through the errors,
the most widely read book in history in
Europe.
People get some negative pr in it.
The last two Syrian king is rumored is a
good way to put it.
There's not enough information to know
on this is rumored to have as the enemy
was closing in pile all of his worldly
possessions that were in his palace
around him and the gold and the silver
and have family members killed and unix
and concubines thrown on.
You know,
the,
the pile of stuff with him.
And then have it all set a light with
him sitting in the middle of it.
There's a scene like that in the Lord of
the rings to apparently in this time
period.
It happened a few times,
probably it was a Motif they certainly
referred back to for a short time and a
Siri and successors state.
Maybe you could call it,
maybe you could call it the last gasp of
resistance.
Tried to make a stand,
but by six,
oh,
five.
That was destroyed to and the Assyrians
will turn into a people that never
disappeared,
but who's destruction was so massive and
so sustained and so total that they seem
like they did.
You will hear a Syrians trying to tell
the world,
still today we're still here and try to
fight that idea that every last one of
them was killed in the,
in their version of a holocaust.
You know,
at the end of that era.
Well,
it's not true,
but you could certainly say that within
a very short period of time,
those massive,
you know,
top of their era cities and fortresses.
We're almost unrecognizable in a famous
passage.
The Greek General xenophon with his
10,000
Greeks fleeing a Persian civil war will
get chased all the way through what's
now northern Iraq.
He will come upon these great massive
cities by their standards of the day,
simply,
you know,
rotting in the dust,
deserted,
but the walls are so high and the
workmanship on the streets and
everything so modern that he doesn't
understand where it came from.
The locals don't know anything about a
Syria.
They think the medes built it.
In other words,
within 200 years these cities are lying
in ruins,
are still larger than almost anything
new being built at that time and nobody
even remembers that they were a Syrian.
The account by xenophon of these ghost
cities.
By the way,
I've spoken about them before.
It's the ultimate statue of liberty in
the sand sort of historical moment.
You know what I mean when I say that
right?
The end of the planet,
of the apes where Charlton Heston
believes he's been on a distant planet
the whole time and the very last scene
in the movie,
he looks into the distance,
you know,
with the surf crashing against it,
he sees the statue of Liberty three
quarters buried in the sand.
If you could take an Assyrian individual
from three,
four,
500 years before xenophon lived and
bring him forward or her forward in a
time machine so that she could hang out
there,
you know,
by the ruins of Nineveh with xenophon
and what,
what,
what were run through her head,
what would run through your head if you
could go forward in a time machine and
see our ghost cities someday.
And I marveled at the size.
I mean 200 years later,
xenophon says,
and he can't really lie.
There's a lot of people who know,
you know,
what xenophon's talking about here and
have seen it and could call him a liar.
I mean he says the base of the
fortification,
he's camping bias.
Fifty feet broad and 50 feet high and
then has a brick wall 50 feet broad.
And another hundred feet high on top of
that and the circumference of the
fortifications is 18 miles.
He says there are some people sort of,
you know,
little like refugees and small villages
and semi-nomadic groups of people
camping by.
But that city used to have hundreds of
thousands,
maybe a million people living there.
That's a ghost city from a dead era by
the times and uh,
funds.
They're only a couple of hundred years
later.
And when a series of falls,
it's like that moment we spoke about
earlier,
what would happen if the United States
disappeared in five or 15 years?
What's the world then look like without
that,
you know,
senator spoke of the wagon wheel
anymore.
It's hard even to think for people born
in the last 20,
30 years maybe of any other sort of
reality.
Maybe that's the case for the people who
lived through it,
maybe they were blinking and just waking
up to a new day.
It really does have sort of an end of
the Second World War.
So to feel like everything's been
devastated in whole bunch of people
who had allied together for this common
interest of taking down the Assyrian
Empire.
We're now staring over the rubble
wondering who gets what and all of a
sudden,
like in 1946 in a Europe,
especially,
allies were turning into potential
adversaries very quickly.
There were four know.
If we look at this as a encapsulated
little micro world here,
geopolitically speaking,
which is how I look at these stories.
Sorry for all you folks who'd like a
little bit more culture or religion.
Nonetheless in this geopolitical setup,
we really have four great powers.
Now you go from one,
hey,
hegemonic power,
Syria to Babylon,
picking up a lot of,
uh,
Syrian territory in this whole deal.
By the way,
you'll also have the medes obviously
doing the same thing.
You know,
moving into territory in the north of
Syria,
owned.
You have Egypt always a great power if
they can be,
but not that long ago,
you know,
under Syrian domination like everyone
else,
they start moving towards the modern day
area around Israel and in there.
And they are a player.
And finally,
if at fourth power called Lydia,
Lydia is the power that's now in modern
day Turkey for the most part,
like everyone else,
they benefited from the Assyrians going
away.
They were able to move and expand into
other areas.
They are generally credited with the
one's inventing metal money at least in
the western world.
And you will begin to see at least in
the longterm view of things,
all sorts of conflicts breaking out now
as all these new powers sort of vie with
each other.
The Egyptians and the Babylonians for
example,
we'll go at it,
you know,
several times trying to figure out,
is anybody gonna Conquer anybody?
Where's the border going to be?
And all that kind of stuff.
And a lot of the littler states just get
totally screwed in this deal.
It's a little like the cold war where
some states in the middle try to decide,
do I side with the Soviets or do I side
with the Western?
And then if you screw up,
all kinds of bad things can happen.
That's exactly what happened to poor
Judah.
That was sacked by the Babylonian King.
During this era for continually swaying
sort of between the two powers that were
vying for them,
Babylon on one side and Egypt on the
other,
and finally exasperating the Babylonian
king to the breaking point.
There are Jews in Iraq today whose
ancestors were a part of the Babylonian
King,
you know,
taking them out of the city of Judah
that he was just destroying.
That's where by the way,
Solomon's temple was destroyed by the
Babylonians.
Again,
earning them bad pr in one of the most
important per books of all time.
The medes will scare the Babylonians to
the point where the Babylonians will
build something called the median wall
to hopefully slow them down.
And xenophile installed that to about
150 years later.
It was a wall that supposedly ran across
the narrow part of the division between
the Tigris and Euphrates river.
So you'd have the river on two sides and
then this wall in the middle and
xenophon says that 200 years later it
was made a burnt bricks laid in bitumen.
It was 20 feet thick,
a hundred feet high and said to be 60
miles long.
It is quite close to Babylon and quote
again,
if he's lying about that,
there's a lot of people who would know
that he was,
he'd have a reputation for that,
that would follow him unto our own time.
Now the medes will famously go to war
with the Lydians and this is when some
of her [inaudible] really Hurghada test
has a little bit of,
um,
a horror story and Alfred Hitchcock side
to him sometimes or maybe just the
people he talks to happen to because
during this little period which will
really only last like 40,
45 years between the fall of the
Assyrians and the rise of the Persians,
there's going to be incidents that are
eerily similar and you start to wonder
whether the guide telling you about them
or the people existing in this era have
a certain weakness for that sort of
incident.
In this case,
Heraclitus says,
this is how the war with the medes and
the Lydian started.
There were some skiff.
Ian's who were hunters for the Medean
king,
that guy see accessories,
right?
And normally they'd bring back food,
but one time they show up,
Heraclitus says empty handed in front of
the accessories,
who supposedly Hurghada test says,
has this awful temper freaks out and
starts abusing,
including so physical abuse.
One must imagined him kicking maybe
these skinny and archers.
Now the skiff,
Ian's were never known to have
particularly non excitable temperaments,
shall we put it that way?
Is that fair?
And Hurghada to says that they went and
in their anger,
killed one of the boys probably from the
royal court that the Medean king had
sent to learn archery from these same
skiff.
Ian's wow,
they're great archers.
Let's send some of the royal boys out
there and they can learn how to shoot
bows like an ancient Eurasian Steppe
Archer.
And they killed one of these boys Herata
to says and cut him up like the game
that they normally give to the Medina
king showed up,
gave him the food,
watched him eat it.
Hahaha.
It's like putting urine into someone's
beer before you give it to them.
The king finds out,
you know,
goes after them.
They run to Lydia and then the median
king says,
I want those skit.
The ones who cut up that boy and made me
eat him and Herat at this says that the
king of Lydia said,
no,
can't have him.
Boom war.
Now we'll run into Hurghada telling a
similar story with an even greater
psychological twist very soon after
this.
Nonetheless,
this war with the medes and the Lydians
have gone for like five years.
Hurghada to says,
and we'll end with an.
You know,
we have a fact here.
We can play with something that's real.
We don't have to say.
He says,
she says this historian claims we've
heard from Herat at this.
There is a solar eclipse that happens on
May 28th,
five,
85 BC.
He
and at the time that solar eclipse
happened,
which by the way Hurghada says a Greek
predicted claiming it was the first time
that had ever been done.
I'm sure the Babylonians probably pulled
off a few of those correctly.
Who knows?
Modern astronomers.
Of course I have no problem going back
and with precision.
Calculating the date of that past
astronomical event,
which is why we have a rare confirmable
fat at this point in the story,
but when that eclipse happened,
the medes and the Lydians happen to be
fighting a battle and Hurghada to says,
as it was warming up,
as the battle was getting hot,
there goes the sun.
Now,
if you are an ancient person with the
religious beliefs,
you must imagine many of these ancient
people had.
There are few atheists in the ancient
world and sometimes it can be very
superstitious indeed,
as you might imagine.
Now you're involved in a battle man
killing man.
You know,
both sides of almost certainly had
sacrifices and the omens examined and
they're looking at the liver and saying,
is this a good day to attack?
And all these kinds of things,
and then in the middle of the battle of
the sun goes out,
what are you going to think?
Well,
as you might imagine,
the medes and the Lydian stopped
fighting in the heat of the fighting.
They stopped fighting.
We're talking about tens of thousands of
people on each side and then everybody
just stops.
That's the way it's portrayed anyway,
but think about it this way.
If an eclipse is really going to stop a
battle,
it's going to happen fast because the
eclipse doesn't last that long.
The piece was brokered.
We are told by another of the great
powers,
Babylon and also the clique.
Ian's involved,
maybe you would call them a midsize
power in that region.
Regional power in that part of the world
and the deal sealed.
We are told in the traditional way,
although the Greeks did it a little
differently.
We're not told how both rulers slipped
their skin and suck blood from each
other.
Also gave daughters and whatnot in
marriage.
That's the part I left out.
Two of the deal when the Babylonians and
the medes sign,
that agreement probably the same way,
a little vampiric blood sucking to go
along with it outside of Asher.
They destroy that a
Syrian city.
They also married off daughters to each
other and I mean it was one of these
things where all of a sudden the
families are related as though that's
really going to stop anything given the
history.
Nonetheless,
they did the exact same deal here,
got a few daughters we can spread
around,
got some blood weaken,
suck,
and and,
and forever friends.
That bottle is known as the battle of
the Haley's river or the battle of the
eclipse sometimes.
Now one thing that it's worth pointing
out from this period because it's going
to matter in the north west and very
west parts of modern day Turkey,
Anatolia,
as it was called earlier,
our settlements and villages and cities
of Greeks,
they're called Ionian Greeks,
but Greeks of one kind or another being,
you know,
such a seafaring,
people around that region head in a
colonized that whole area a very long
time ago.
And they had relationships with the
Greeks,
you know,
on the mainland where places like Athens
are,
for example.
You've got to imagine trade routes back
and forth,
people going back and forth.
In fact,
the part of the Greek world that was
located in modern day Turkey at this
time was the more sophisticated,
the more cultured than more learned.
Uh,
the Greeks in Athens and Sparta might
say,
the more feminine,
the more corrupted,
the more lazy,
the more opulent,
you know,
connected to all that eastern opulence
as they were.
See how that motif works.
Nonetheless,
those Greeks in Anatolia will become a
big part of,
you know the problem because they are
the part that links Asia back to the
Greek mainland and the Greek mainland
has an interest in how their,
shall we call them cousins,
second cousins,
how they're doing
at the time.
The Battle of the eclipse figures out
what's going on between the Lydians and
the medes.
Those Greeks are for the most part,
subject to the Lydian king that's going
to change.
That's going to change for everybody.
What's about to happen in this region
that will affect the Greeks and everyone
else is every bit as shocking and
unexpected as the fall of Assyria was.
And it's interesting that they will
happen within a reasonably historically
speaking,
short period of time from each other.
You have to imagine that analogy.
We had the United States disappearing in
five to 15 years and what would the
world look like after that?
Well,
what if I told you that within,
you know,
another 20 or 30 years after that one
country that you'd never,
you know,
some out of the way place had taken over
the entire planet.
That's how this analogy works.
When we start trying to realize that
somehow this people call the Persians
will first get their control over the
means and how that even happens.
I mean,
recess are gone.
Me,
the author has a great line where he
points out that,
you know,
between the fall
of the last great Assyrian monarch and
the rise of Cyrus the great.
There's no mention of these Persian
people in any text,
in any politically significant way.
They are virtual.
Nobody's and within a generation they're
running the show for everyone in this
part of the world.
How did that happen?
Judging from the overwhelming number of
historians from ancient times all the
way to the,
you know,
the latest,
often contrarian writings,
the lion's share of the answer seems to
have something to do with this
incredible leader.
Cyrus the second also called,
as we said earlier,
Cyrus the great.
There are lots of stories by the way,
and some of them are fantastic.
One of her auditees is best is one of
the ones you know he tells about the
rise of Cyrus,
but you have to remember something.
This person,
cyrus the great is to Persian and
Iranian history,
sort of what George Washington is to
American history,
what King Arthur is to British legend.
I mean this is a legendary figure and
because there so little that talks about
him during his rise to power historians
are in a really thrust into the
detective role trying to figure out what
it is you know is going on.
I liked the way historian peer brand
kind of tries to explain what sort of
assumption she should maybe build into
this and I'm not a historian,
so he was writing as a historian trying
to explain to a lay person like yours
truly.
Let's hope the layperson understood.
But he kind of said,
listen,
if something that appears to happen out
of nowhere,
but it's unlikely that it could,
you should assume that there was stuff
bubbling up under the surface,
you know,
a foundation taking place.
But that's hidden from our eyes through
the historical veil,
right?
So when a cyrus the great all of a
sudden takes over the muddy and empire
and it looks like a lightning bolt
strikes,
it's probably safe to assume things had
been leading up to this somehow for
awhile,
for a long time.
One of the things historians like to
suggest was percolating beneath the
scene that you couldn't see with
something like rot,
I guess you could say maybe moral rot.
This is something that is,
you know,
part of earlier histories.
And because it's impossible to quantify,
I mean we could even ask these questions
a day,
is there any truth to the idea?
And we have by the way,
that the older generations in tougher
times are tougher than we are today.
If there is any truth to that because
that had been true in the past.
How would a historian even measure that?
So they don't anymore writing in 1935
and I love him,
but it was written in 1935 historian
will,
Duran tries to tie,
you know,
the downfall of the media to their moral
degeneration.
And the fact that they were sort of
nouveau riche,
he writes,
quote,
their degeneration was even more rapid
than their rise.
Osteology who succeeded his father.
See accessories proved again,
that monarchy is a gamble in who's royal
succession,
great wits and madness,
or nearly allied.
He inherited a kingdom with equanimity
and settled down to enjoy it.
Under his example,
the nation for God.
It's Stern,
morals and stoic ways wealth had come to
suddenly to be wisely used.
The upper classes became the slaves of
fashion and luxury.
The men wore embroidered trousers.
The women covered themselves with
cosmetics and jewelry.
The very horses were often comparison to
in gold.
These once simple and pastoral people
who had been glad to be carried in rude
wagons with wheels cut roughly out of
the trunks of trees now road and
expensive chariots from feast to Feast
and quote.
The truth is though,
that what Doran rights there in 1935
isn't a whole lot different from what
the ancient Greeks saw.
The ancient Greeks sorta saw themselves
as Marlboro men compared to these people
from the east that were at best sort of
Metro sexuals.
The Greeks likes to point out the use of
makeup as part of their idea that these
easterners were a feminist writing
hundreds of years later.
By the way,
xenophon talks about osteology is the
last king of the medes and his
guidelines,
I guess you would call it today,
his stencilled eyes,
the rouge on his face,
and xenophon who would have no way of
knowing,
says a wig have fake hair.
Now,
here's the thing though,
in the east,
these kinds of things were cultural
norms.
It wasn't a sign of a feminist.
The Pharaohs and the Egyptians had been
using the dark coal around the eyes
forever.
Just a different cultural thing,
but the Greeks saw it as just another
sign of these oriental.
If Feminine,
Opulent Week,
Clever,
sneaky,
you know,
fill in the blank.
Easterners,
I will leave it to the credible
historians to decide some day whether
there's any truth to this motif about
the medes sort of slouching towards
Gomorrah or what have you.
Most of the modern stuff I read today
looks at that as a as a terribly old
fashioned way to view the situation,
but as I said,
how do you quantify something like that
anyway,
but if you follow that narrative the way
a guy like Hurghada test is taking it or
a guy like will durant writing in 1935
is taking it.
There's an almost opportunity created by
the decadence of the medes and the
cruelty of their ruler.
Right,
and that can be exploited by somebody
who has the opposite values from the
people that are busy,
slouching towards Gomorrah.
In other words,
people that were less corrupted by
luxury,
who were not as decadent,
who were more,
shall we say,
possessors of the old time virtues,
if you will,
and this gets us back to a secondary
value that a guy like Herat at this has
for us.
Remember,
like I said,
he's like the color era,
the first real screenwriter,
writer show runner,
and and you learn two things from a guy
writing the way he writes in the way.
A lot of after him,
right?
One,
you learn about these events.
He's trying to relate to you,
which may or may not be true and are
probably a combination of the two.
Right?
We learned about,
you know,
the rise of Cyrus,
at least the story that this guy heard,
but at the same time you're having like
a Vulcan Mind Meld with a 2,500
year old basically alien mind,
a one way conversation with a 2,500
year old guy
and when you read Hurghada,
just this,
you know,
I,
I really wish I could speak the ancient
Greek and read it and understand the
little nuances so I could really hear
this guy in his own words as he meant
every specific word.
But you getting a chance to see,
you know,
what this guy from a completely
different time period likes and dislikes
his worldview.
What he thinks is good and what he
thinks is bad.
You know,
his view sort of on the supernatural and
the gods,
his biases and his prejudices.
You're learning about he and his world.
When you read his stuff,
part of what you have to filter it so
carefully because just like all of us,
his world pollutes his worldview so that
you know,
we don't get as nonbiased a view now as
we might want,
but what Hurghada tests does in this
story is kind of say that because
[inaudible] was the way he was a cyrus
arises on the scene.
Modern Day historians can't decide or
argue over whether or not there was some
war fought between the medes and the
Persians.
Remember,
these are for the most part,
semi tribal peoples probably at this
time.
They used to think they were more like
states.
Now,
no one's sure.
Maybe a combination of some cities with
some pastoral people that were lied to
it.
It's an interesting sort of hybrid and
there might've been a lot of these kinds
of societies around back then when
they're transitioning from,
you know,
an old tribal world to something more
along the lines of a centralized
bureaucratic state.
When you're in sort of a tweener zone,
if you will.
So either a war between these medes and
the Persians or the tribes that they
controlled,
or sort of like,
as one historian described it,
the Medean empire getting a change in
management
with maybe some Medea nobles helping to
rebel against this osteology person and
modern historians have some interesting,
understandable sort of common sense
reasons why they might want to.
The theory is that this osteology guy is
trying to convert the leads into more of
a typical centralized Mesopotamian
government.
Where the king is is more autocratic.
It has a lot more authority.
It sounds like maybe he has to share a
lot of authority with these different
tribal rulers and as you might imagine,
it's almost like a law of nature.
They're unlikely to like that.
This may have some modern historians
think to sort of an uprising and
internal coup,
if you will.
And this Cyrus,
the second guy might be the person who
gets to lead this now as the greatest
early screen writer,
Hirata tess has his own view of sorta
what turns the tables on this.
Now.
It's one of these stories that,
again,
maybe tells us more about Hurghada and
the audience he's trying to please,
but he must've heard this story
somewhere.
This is a typical tale by the way of
oriental cruelty,
but he setting up something that
actually seemed to happen in the story
and trying to give you a reason why it
happened without having any real way of
knowing other than these people he's
talking to.
He tells one of the most horrific
stories in his writings,
but he tells it like Alfred Hitchcock or
west craven or someone like that.
We alluded to it earlier when we said in
an earlier story,
you know,
those [inaudible],
killed a boy and served it to the and
king and he didn't like that.
Well,
in this story,
it's that same thing,
but with an extra twist.
I have several different versions of
Heraclitus.
Um,
but let me set this up.
What happens in the story is it concerns
this osteology guy,
the son of succe accessories and nowhere
near his father in terms of greatness
and kind of a jerk.
And that's the way he's portrayed.
And he has a dream and that these
dreams,
you got to love ancient history because
they're always so wild.
Hurghada tests related by the way the
dream has something to do with his
daughter urinating over the whole world
or something,
as I said,
got to love the ancient history.
And he asked the Magic to interpret it
and they say,
I'm not very good.
This daughter's gonna give birth to
something or she's the seed of something
that's maybe going to overthrow you.
And so to play it safe,
Hurghada says he marries her off to some
Persian,
um,
you know,
maybe a great Persian guy,
but this is the muddy and empire and,
and no son of a Persian is going to be
ruling the midian empire.
So that's been taken care of.
But then about a year later,
Herat at this says he has another dream
about his daughter who's about to give
birth to her first child.
And in this dream he sees,
I think it's,
it's like vines coming out of her womb
and then encompassing the whole earth or
something.
Again,
akin to that and the match.
I come in and interpret that,
and as you might imagine,
it's not good and it scares osteology
who thinks that she,
his daughter is going to give birth to a
person who takes his throne.
So in a story that you see in other
tales,
in other words,
it's a pretty common motif with
different twists.
Osteology calls in the general.
A guy named Harper Gus,
who seems to be a historical figure and
tells harper guests to get rid of the
baby.
Now Harper Guess Herata says,
doesn't want to get rid of the baby.
Just let me stop for a second.
In this story,
Heraclitus is lovingly telling this
story.
He knows what the colorful pieces are
and he says he doesn't want to get rid
of the baby,
doesn't want to kill a baby.
So he gives the job to a shepherd and
gives the shepherd the baby and says,
get rid of the baby,
expose it,
you know,
out into the open and let it die,
and the shepherd doesn't want to get rid
of the baby and it just so happens his
wife is pregnant and she gives birth.
Adjust this time to a stillborn child.
Doesn't this sound like a bunch of old
grimms fairy tales at this point?
So as you might imagine,
they take the stillborn child rapid in
the royal close,
keep the live when they were supposed to
kill and give the stillborn child back
to heart,
biggest to give to his boss,
to king and stacy.
It was done fast forward 13 years later
or something like that and a boy is
brought before.
This is the headwater two story
osteology because he's been whipping
boys higher on the social standing
scale.
Then he,
after a bunch of questioning it is
determined and again this is the
wonderfulness of the ancient mind meld
you're having with Hurghada.
This that basically osteology can tell
that this boy is a king.
It's like in your DNA.
You can tell the difference between blue
bloods and non blue bloods by the way
they handle situations and it's inbred.
Besides that osteology notices that the
kid looks like him and after all he is
his grandfather.
He calls in hospice.
Then he calls in the shepherd.
He does a little investigation,
figures the whole story out and pretends
he's not mad.
Tells heart biggest.
He's often felt,
I'm paraphrasing here from paralysis,
but,
but tells harper because he's often felt
bad about the whole thing afterwards.
So He's,
he's secretly relieved that the whole
thing went the way it did.
Why don't you go home,
tell your wife we're going to have a
banquet to celebrate all this and you
can come over and,
and,
and we'll,
we'll highlight you at the banquet.
Send your son over your 13 year old son
so he can keep the new boy,
you know,
my grandson company and uh,
we'll have a party tonight and
Heraclitus says that heartbeat has goes
back home and he's relieved because he
knows he could have gotten in big
trouble and the wife is happy and they
go to this banquet.
And this is where Alfred Hitchcock,
Hurghada test of helicopter takes the
story over.
And again,
I keep telling myself,
I don't think this is making this stuff
up.
Somebody told him this story.
This is what somebody somewhere
believed.
Now listen to this and try to imagine a
story like this from the Assyrians,
the Babylonians or the ancient
Mesopotamians.
They just didn't write this way.
Hurghada is a story.
Has the 13 year old son of heart biggest
going to the palace as requested and
then picks up the story and says,
this is from my discipline core
translation.
By the way,
quote,
when Harper gets his son,
arrived at the palace,
last Dr,
had him butchered,
cut up into joints and cooked,
roasting some boiling the rest and
having the whole properly prepared for
the table.
Dinner Time came and the guests
assembled with heart.
Biggest among them dishes of mutton were
placed in front of osteology is then if
everyone else except purpose to purpose
was served the flesh of his son.
All of it except for the head,
the hands and feet,
which had been put separately on a
platter,
covered with a lid.
When heartbreak is thought he had eaten
as much as he wanted.
I asked him if he enjoyed his dinner.
He answered that he had enjoyed it very
much indeed.
Where upon those whose business it was
to do so brought in the boy's head,
hands and feet in the covered dish,
stood by heart,
biggest his chair,
and told him to lift the lid and take
what he fancied.
Heart biggest,
remove the cover and saw the fragments
of his son's body as he kept control of
himself and did not lose his head.
If the dreadful cite us dog has asked
him if he knew what animal it was,
whose flesh he had just eaten.
I know my Lord was her biggest this
reply and from my part may the kings
will be done.
He said no other word,
but took up what remained of the flesh
and went home intending I suppose to
bury all of it together.
And that was how Harper Gus was punished
and quote.
If that had been in the Syrian record,
it would have said something like his
son.
I divided the pieces I fed to him.
I mean,
it would be a straightforward sort of
thing.
You wouldn't have anybody setting up the
suspense of,
you know,
having him eat and not know what it is.
And then having the platter brought in,
having the king asked the question,
do you know what you ate?
Did you like it?
And then the platters lifted up.
I mean those moments where you set up
the tension and the drama,
it's a movie.
You could do that movie and change
nothing.
It's living color.
What's more,
Heraclitus is clearly setting up these
moments for his audience to do the
equivalent of what we would do in a
movie theater when some great seen on
the screen happens that we're all really
glad to see and you clap or something.
He's got these moments because when you
make osteology out to be such a jerk,
when he gets what's coming to him in the
story,
it's a crowd pleaser.
And then this story,
of course he does.
And while it's tempting to think that
the entire thing is just a great tale,
somebody great tale,
maybe not initially,
there are definite facts mixed in and
you can see her test.
Trying to explain the reasons behind the
facts.
Today may be a screenwriter would call
it dramatic license because Babylonian
records indicate that there was a
general who corresponds to this heart
biggest guy and that that general was
involved in a battlefield.
Betrayal,
maybe you could say in a key battle,
osteology has had a large part of his
army,
desert him on the battlefield and go to
the other side.
It very well may have been this heart
biggest person who led them to do that
and Hurghada test wants you to think
that see,
he was a jerk and now this is what he
gets,
and and who would think that you could
trust a man whose son you had served to
him for dinner with the entire army in
the first place,
but nonetheless,
the moment when Harper guests and the
medes crossover to cyrus aside of the
battlefield,
must've been a crowd pleasing and
satisfying moment for the audience,
right?
That jerk got what he deserved.
In the Babylonian records,
it's much more stark,
as you might imagine,
one of the texts from Babylon as quoted
by peer Briana reads,
quote,
osteology is mobilized his army and he
marched against Cyrus King.
Avant Sean,
to conquer the army,
rebelled against osteology and he was
taken prisoner.
They handed him over to Cyrus Cyrus
march towards Batna,
the royal city and quote by 5:50
bce or thereabouts,
Cyrus and the Persians were basically in
control of the old Isla might
territories and now had inherited
control of the Medea and empire,
which was already one of the great
empires in this particular world stage.
It's kind of possible that the Lydian
King,
for example,
that in three years Cyrus will be at war
with,
doesn't even really have a key idea who
the Persians are.
I'm not sure,
but I mean judging from the sources,
this is quite the turnaround.
And as I said in 5:47,
cyrus and the new Persian empire is
fighting those same people.
The means were fighting when that
eclipse,
you know,
caused everyone to think that maybe they
shouldn't be fighting,
and it's a great story because the guy
who runs the lydian empire now at this
time is a guy named creases.
And there's a saying about him.
You may have heard rich as creases,
and that's the stereotype of the
Lydians.
At this time,
uh,
as I said,
they're known as people who invented
metal coinage,
don't know if that's really true or not,
but that's their reputation and it's
attached to them because they're thought
to be extremely wealthy and creases is
supposed to have gone to one of the
famous Oracle's maybe the most famous
oracle in the entire Greek world,
the Oracle at Delphi,
which he may have been giving money to
influence.
There was a whole big problem during
this period where some questioned the
reliability of these oracles.
Can you imagine a because of them taking
money to keep operating from people.
Increases was a bridge and he gave money
to everybody's a little Donald Trump
ish.
Maybe you might say.
And,
um,
asked the oracle,
you know,
now what would happen if I went to war
with the Persian empire?
Now,
little sidetrack here,
maybe only worthwhile for the bedding
people amongst you,
but if you went to an advisor in Las
Vegas who gave you advice and you said,
will the Green Bay packers win the
superbowl?
And the answer was,
if the Green Bay packers play in the
superbowl,
they will add to a great legacy.
Do you bet?
Creases was told by the Oracle at Delphi
that have creases attacks the Persians,
he will destroy a great empire.
You could take that a number of
different ways,
couldn't you?
You could say,
hey,
the greenbay packers are going to win.
Or You could say,
listen to the Dallas cowboys beat the
Green Bay packers.
They have added to a great championship
legacy too.
It's just the Dallas cowboys
championship legacy.
When creases and the lydians fight,
Cyrus and the Persians,
he loses.
He destroys a great empire.
The one that invented metal coinage.
I would love to get into the kind of
army that Cyrus had and what he used to
accomplish this victory over the
Lydians.
But no,
the acumen and military system is not
well understood anyway.
And it was only in the 19 eighties that
they started putting together realistic
reconstructions of the army in the days
that are much better known than this
period.
I mean during the Greek inversion wars
or after against Alexander in this
period.
It's all conjecture what the heck cyrus
was using.
I mean,
you can say,
well,
he probably use this and it's logical to
assume that,
but nobody knows.
When you read Herodotus,
he's always got some little stratagem in
play that keeps you from having to know
in a really what the army was doing in
one of these big battles against
creases.
You know,
the Persians were told we'll take their
baggage camels and take the baggage off
of them and put them in front of the
army so that when the Lydian horses
who've never seen camels right up to the
front,
they'll be scared off by the camels.
I mean,
you know,
you get a victory in the battle just
with that doesn't really help you know
much about an army that must've been
really,
really good to do all these things cyrus
was doing with it.
He does look like a very bold commander
from the sources.
I mean,
one of the things he brought it just
talks about is this,
shall we call it a misunderstanding
between creases and Cyrus after this big
battle that starts off the campaign and
it's bloody and inconclusive and
winter's coming,
so creases does with any ancient
commander would have done during that
period.
He went home,
went to the capital at stardust,
this giant fortified city and dismissed
mercenaries and let most of the army go
home and told his allies,
you know,
in four months,
show up here and we'll deal with this
emerging Persian threat.
His allies,
by the way,
included,
you know,
the great powers,
Babylonia and Egypt.
So maybe cyrus was starting to be seen
as the destabilizing force in that
little geopolitical ecosystem in that
part of the world.
Nonetheless,
Cyrus didn't disband the army.
He didn't go home for winter.
He were told,
pursued the Lydians right on their
heels.
This is bald strategy,
and he forced another battle and were
told it was after creases had already
basically sent most of the people,
the Persians,
but not paddling.
That's the camel battle.
And then they faced this monstrous
fortification at Sardis.
The capital of Libya that could easily
hold out until all those allies show up
in four months,
you would think we're told it holds out
for like 14 days,
and again,
we have another story about a a back
path to the citadel being found by a
Persian who spies one of the guards.
Hats falling off,
helmets falling off in the guard,
retrieving it down some path.
Again,
you wouldn't know about what amazing
siege engines maybe cyrus had because we
always have some little story that
accounts for how one of the great
fortified cities in this part of the
world gets taken in 14 days.
Nonetheless.
We also get some accounts now of of of
something we've spoken about,
about how the Persians may be like darth
vader to the Greeks,
but they have something and and you
know,
you don't know if you want to call this
propaganda or a sincere and clever and
common sense and realistic approach to
things.
If you could sort of take either way,
but shall we call it the tolerance bomb.
We're told Theodora stimulus,
especially mentions that cyrus gave a
deal to the lydians before this whole
thing started.
He said,
listen,
submit to me and I'll leave you in
charge of this whole area.
It's basically the same deal.
Xerxes offered the spartans.
If they're awfully,
come on,
let's make a deal.
Put down those weapons and not only will
you get to go home,
I'll put you in charge of all these
people.
You'll benefit,
submit and profit.
Maybe you could call this combination of
sort of machiavellian thinking with a
sort of Gandhi like ethic that's going
too far,
but I love the connection.
A realistic hardheaded knife in the
back,
sort of diplomacy with tolerance and
mercy and leniency as your weapon.
Get a knife,
you with leniency and you know,
you would have to suggest perhaps that
there were two ways this lenient idea
could go either not work at all and then
you see why the Assyrians had to be as
harsh as they were or because the
Assyrians were as harsh as they were in
the Babylonians who followed after them.
The area was ripe for somebody who would
offer.
I mean,
if everybody was going to be under
somebody control,
when did you want to go with the
tolerant guy and remember we are grading
on a curve here.
When we talk about tolerance,
the Persians could be every bit as
atrocious as any other ancient people on
occasion.
It just seemed like once they took over,
there were a lot fewer of those
occasions,
maybe the historians or some of them
that I grew up with would say something
like,
well,
that's because the Assyrians already
broke.
All the troubles in people to the yoke
of Empire seems a bit far fetched.
Certainly you can say though that the
whole sort of mood and attitude was
altered and you don't get any more of
those really intimidating reliefs
showing things like,
you know,
heads of your enemies staring up at you
or horrible violence or the flying of
live captives and you don't get the
writings where there's a boasting and a
propaganda value where you're saying,
this is what will happen to you if you
rebel against us.
Recess are gummy quotes.
The SOM cylinder,
it's called and it's Osher,
Bonnie Paul,
the last great king of Assyria,
boasting of what he did to Babylon after
his brother,
who he put on the throne of Babylon,
rebelled against him in 6:49
bce.
First,
he's besieged the people until they were
cannibalistic and then picks up the
narrative saying,
quote,
out of hunger,
the flesh have their sons and daughters
they ate.
Afterwards,
I ripped out the tongue of those
officers whose mouth said,
blast themed against Asher,
my master,
and then slaughtered them.
Any soldiers found still alive,
were flogged in front of the wing.
Good bowls built by Senaca.
Rip My grandfather.
I whipped the Naca ribs tomb and then
tossed.
They're quivering flesh for the jackals,
the birds,
and the fish to eat.
In this way,
I placated the wrath of the gods who
would become incensed by their ignominy,
his deeds,
and then start gummy picks up the
narrative saying,
quote,
this grizzly passage related to events
that transpired in Babylon proceeds a
brief description of the restorative
work that Osher,
Bonnie,
Paul undertook in that city that the
Assyrian king was unabashed about
intertwining the account of his
brutality with that of his clemency
indicates that Mesopotamian royalty did
not frowned upon the infliction of
vicious reprisals against conquered
populations.
This attitude enabled the Assyrian and
Babylonian kings to base their policies
largely on terror.
During the two centuries proceeding
Cyrus's rise to power,
the Assyrians and Babylonians had sacked
nearly every major near eastern capital
and their preferred practices of
population,
deportation and kidnapping.
Sacred Images had deeply traumatized the
people of the ancient near east end
quote.
In other words,
if you had ever wanted to find a winning
military strategy,
this might be the time where mercy
tolerance and being the cool conquerors
really worked in your favor.
Cyrus is the one who initiated this idea
that we're not going to impale everybody
and we're not going to fly them and
we're not going to force them to convert
to our religion.
You join us,
pay your taxes.
I may have some representatives in a
garrison in your city,
but life will be good.
This Persian deal was very seductive.
Now here's where the story begins to
dove tail with what we've already talked
about earlier.
The peoples that we spoke about,
these Greeks who were in Anatolia,
some of them spoke a language that was
called Ionian,
so they're often called Ionians,
but there were other types of Greeks
there to Asiatic Greeks is a term that's
sometimes used.
These people had been paying tribute to
creases and the Lydians and Cyrus had
gone to them before the war with creases
in the Lydians and said,
listen,
how about you revolt against creases?
And they said no,
and some of them fought on creases
aside.
So after Cyrus winds,
all the people in the region are coming
to him to kind of say,
Hey,
boss,
I always wanted you to win.
I'm glad.
I'm glad you're victorious.
And Dha in the case of these Greeks,
they went to him and said,
can we have the same deal we had with
the lydians and cyrus gets mad at them.
We're told.
He basically says,
you could've had that deal if you join
me and didn't fight against me.
Now you want a special deal over all the
other people in this region who didn't
fight against me
and got mad.
And those Greeks went back home,
had a big meeting amongst each other,
started rebuilding the walls of their
cities,
which they had knocked down and you
know,
as part of their deal with creases,
um,
and put the word out for help.
And they sent word to the spartans.
Now the spartans had also promised help
decrease this when he was in trouble.
Supposedly they were just getting in the
boats,
getting ready to go help.
When in 14 days the Lydian capital falls
didn't give him enough time to get
there.
Now they get,
you know,
in a very short period of time,
a second call for help.
And this time from Greeks,
it's about the Persians,
just like that last call,
these Persians must be a troublesome
people.
The spartans were a little busy when the
message came,
but they sent an emissary to talk to
this Persian.
Now every historian I'm reading is
assuming that these Persians and these
spartans do not know each other,
that this may be the first time they
ever encounter one another.
It seems illogical considering all the
trading and whatnot going on,
but let's understand best case scenario,
it's unusual and these people don't
really know each other,
and a spartan diplomat shows up in front
of Cyrus,
we're told,
and we have one of these wonderful
periods.
We can imagine our Clint Eastwood type
figures showing up in front of this king
on the rise.
Again,
I try to imagine in Alexander the great
light like figure on the rise must've
been a pretty good looking guy because
we're told that the Persians standards
of beauty were modeled on him ever
afterwards.
This is the way Hurghada tests from my
purpose translation,
describes the diplomat talking to the
king of the Persians,
who conquered lydia and who's just about
to put the hammer down on the Greeks of
Asia.
Herata says quote,
and when they arrived at Ikea,
they sent the most distinguished man
with them,
name latrines to Sardis to declare to
Cyrus in the name of the lack of
Simonian's that he must not inflict
reckless damage on any of the Greek
territory since the lack of Simonian's
would not tolerate it.
Remember,
liking ammonium is another name for
spartans.
Now,
this people that Cyrus has never heard
of is just told him not to mess with any
of these people.
He just conquered and he basically turns
to the Greek advisor next to him and
says,
who are these people and how many of
them are there?
Hirata to says quote.
They say that when the Herald had
delivered this message,
cyrus question,
the Greeks who were with him asking them
who were these lack of pneumonia,
who would send such a command to him and
how many of them were there when he
heard their response?
Hirata says,
he said to the Spartan Harold quote,
I have never yet feared any men who have
a place in the center of the city set
aside for meeting together,
swearing false oaths and cheating one
another,
and if I live long enough,
lack of Simonian's will have troubles of
their own about which to converse rather
than those of the Ionians.
Hurghada test then says,
quote Cyrus,
thus insulted the Greeks because of
their custom of setting up a Gorillaz,
which are marketplaces in their cities
for the purpose of buying and selling,
which is unknown among the Persians,
who do not use markets and indeed have
no such place as an a gore in any of
their cities.
And to quote this is worth a little
digression for a second.
Just from an interest standpoint.
First of all,
Hurghada tests would have probably known
what Persian cities were like.
He himself was an Ionian Greek or lived
in an Iranian Greek city.
He would have known this and that's
fascinating when you consider that you
think of the Middle East now and you
think of the bazaars and the
marketplaces and all that,
but the Persians had this really
interesting cultural carrot and stick
thing going themselves.
You know,
we've talked about the human laboratory
experiment a few times in this program,
like the spartans for example.
The Persians had a different one going
and it's fascinating to me.
Everything you read about them says
that,
you know,
of the top three things that,
that society places import on.
One of them is the truth.
And the funny thing is,
is in our world today,
we think,
oh yeah,
sure,
everybody should tell the truth,
but what if you made this like a
commandment that people took ultra
seriously?
We told you earlier that when the
Spartan told xerxes about the Persians,
he said,
if I'm lying,
you know,
treat me like a liar.
And I told you that that's a death
penalty.
The Persians took lying really
seriously.
We're told that the education of Persian
male youth was to learn to ride,
to learn,
to shoot the bow,
and to learn,
not to lie,
to tell the truth.
Isn't it fascinating to imagine a
society where this was both a state and
legal requirement perhaps,
and certainly
a heavily,
you know,
encouraged and incentivized cultural
norm.
Thou shalt not lie.
It almost becomes like the plot to one
of those movies,
you know,
where the main character drink some
potion and all of a sudden,
you know,
is forced to tell the truth all the
time.
What if you had a society like that?
What what Cyrus is saying to the
spartans is,
I can't respect any people who have
these places in their cities set up
where people can specifically go to lie
to one another,
and by the way,
without going too deeply into it,
there's a lot of connection to Persian
religious beliefs during this time
period.
And how that plays into the question of
lying.
The Persians were worshipers of who were
a Mazda was a God's name and the old
needs used to worship a god named
Mithra.
And there's connections between good and
evil that some religious experts tied to
Christianity and ancient Judaism.
And,
and who the heck knows?
All you know is that it's not just a
cultural and legal question,
it's a religious one.
Two,
it's interesting to speculate how much
people still lied in a society with that
many things favoring the truth.
It's interesting to think about now
they're human laboratory experiment,
if you will,
the truthful society.
And how realistic is that?
Nonetheless,
we have now set the stage for problems
between the Greeks and the Persians.
From this point on,
if you want to call it a clash of
civilizations,
you who have marketplaces in lie and we
who don't.
It's about to happen.
Lucky for the spartans.
They'll get to stay out of it for awhile
because Cyrus isn't done conquering yet.
Not by a long shot.
Historians still discuss whether or not
cyrus should be seen as an intentional,
you know,
a conscious conquer river.
Allah Alexander the great or Napoleon.
You know,
somebody who's sat down and said,
I'm going to recreate the old Assyrian
Empire or somebody that got involved in
a bunch of conflicts each for their own
reason and you know,
when you,
when you take over their territory in
and kind of tripped into empire.
I mean,
obviously that's a little simplistic,
but um,
I think it's indicative of how in,
in certain really key motivational
areas,
this guy is still a bit of a mystery.
He will disappear behind the veil of our
historical site,
I guess you could say for several years
after his.
I'm taking over of Lydia,
he will leave a general who may be this
historical heart biggest guy and an army
behind in western Turkey,
what's now modern day western Turkey to
reduce these Asiatic Greek cities.
And he will go.
It's assumed to the eastern part of his
realm and the northern part of his realm
and conquer further and also shore up
his defenses against the many powerful
tribes that sort of ring his territory.
Probably a combination of fighting.
Some of them showing the flag to some of
them are intermarrying and making
diplomatic agreements with some of them
accepting vassalage from others.
I mean it was years of work.
So this guy is doing the Yeoman's work,
the hard slogging of creating a stable
state and that requires years of
constant effort and he disappears from
the historical record while he's doing
this.
And then in 5:39
bce,
he reappears again at the head of an
army heading toward Babylon.
Now what Cyrus is going to do to Babylon
is probably his crowning achievement in
his career and I have to remind myself
that his career is already incredible.
This is a guy who by 5:39
bce has been a king for about 20 years
and in 20 years he's taken this people
from a virtual,
you know,
backwater Nowheresville to a point where
they've conquered half of the great
nation states in their little ecosystem
that exists,
you know,
after the fall of Assyria.
And he's outside the gates of number
three of four with an army.
That's pretty awesome right there for a
king of an Sean who will very soon be
referring to himself as part of his
official royal titles as the King of the
universe.
When you go from an Sean to King of the
universe,
that's quite a jump and he's kind of a
self made conqueror.
You compare him to someone like
Alexander the great who is of course
awesome,
but Alexander reminds you of sort of a
historical rich kid who inherits his
father's already thriving corporation
with tons of ready cash and does great
things with it.
No offense to Alexander,
it's awesome,
but Cyrus never had any of those
advantages and look where he is only 20
years into his reign.
Now let me just voice my own opinion
that that what Cyrus is about to do to
Babylon is strange.
You can't tell what the sources,
what's really going on and the different
histories have different approaches to
it and it's been argued about and and
the views have changed and updated over
time.
There's just not enough hard sources
though for anyone to really know for
anyone to conclusively when I'm
certainly not going to take a position
on it,
but I am going to explain sort of the
weirdness of it.
The first thing you have to ask is
whether or not cyrus arriving outside
Babylon when he did was a coincidence
because the timing is awesome if you're
hoping to take over Babylon.
Is that just because he gets lucky or is
that just because of the Babylonian
propaganda would say later the hand of
Marduk had seized him and brought him to
Babylon to get rid of the horrible king
of Babylon and restore things.
Just lucky or did Cyrus and the Persians
have advanced information that things
suck in Babylon right now?
You come now and half the population
will be ready to welcome me with open
arms.
Was that may be part of the reason he
showed up when he did or as some have
argued for years.
Could you make a case that the reason
that people were so disaffected
in Babylon was in part due to Persian
propaganda that undermined it?
No,
the entire wheel to resist and I have to
be honest,
I did not understand that part of the
story for years growing up,
but something has changed in the way
historian's view it,
so now makes more sense to me.
When I was growing up,
the attitude was that in 5:39
BC,
this was when Cyrus arrived.
So something happens and occurs in
Babylon falls and Cyrus takes it over
and there you go.
So this idea that he had this propaganda
undermining Babylon made you think about
when,
when was that going to happen?
I mean just everything happened so
quickly.
The modern way of viewing this amongst a
lot of historians is that may be the
Persians in the Babylonians had been
fighting battles for a couple of years
and that in 5:39
when Cyrus in his army show up outside
of Babylon,
that's like the end of the Second World
War when the Russians show up outside of
Berlin and you're having your last
climactic battle,
you know,
in a multi battle long war.
Again,
the sources are just not there to
confirm any of this,
you know,
categorically.
But it would make a heck of a lot more
sense if you were saying that Cyrus and
the Persians were undermining the
Babylonians with propaganda.
If you had years to do it right now,
understanding what Cyrus might've been
doing requires talking about Babylon
itself a little bit like the Assyrian
city of Nineveh.
This is a great urban center and it's
large enough and complex enough so that
you see a lot of the same sorts of
dynamics going on.
You know,
I'll be it through an ancient lens that
you would see in any modern large city
today.
There are fissures,
there are divisions,
there are tensions,
there are disagreements there.
There are all sorts of things that if
someone wanted to come in,
they could widen the disagreements and
it's slowly but surely increase the
level of anger and discontent.
There's a number of things to be
exploited.
To start with the fact that the king is
unpopular.
The king of Babylon during this time
period almost certainly suffers from
from bad,
bad historical publicity.
His name is nab Unitus,
and by the time all of this is going
down,
nab and I.
This is about 70,
70 years old in a world,
you know,
with the lifespan is so much shorter.
How many 70 year old people are there?
He's like a wizard,
you know,
to the population in terms of this is a
guy whose memory goes back to events.
Most people can't get anywhere near
memory wise.
He may have been the general who helped
seal the deal between those two sides at
the battle of the eclipse.
Remember when they suck each other's
blood as part of a,
you know,
sealing the deal.
This,
this,
this nab unitus guy when he was much
younger and more vigorous may have been
one of the generals on site.
Now he's old and it's really hard to get
your mind around what this guy was
really like.
He sort of portrayed as a,
as a kind of a doting antiquarian
by some historians.
Some people consider him the first
official archeologist.
I think that's got to be crazy because
because there were lots of earlier kings
who were into digging up,
you know,
earlier versions of their civilization.
But this guy is portrayed as somebody
who almost prefers it to being a king.
He'd rather be out there,
Indiana Jonesing,
some old Babylonian stuff from the
previous kings and then dealing with the
day to day government.
He also looks like a guy who doesn't
mind getting out of Babylon.
I have this image for the movie of some
I want to use like the guy who played
the the scientists,
the doctor,
and back to the future and have him be
nab rhinitis and just have him sort of
did finding the hustle and bustle of
Babylon too much in those young kids and
they're loud music and all that stuff.
So he and the priesthood of Babylon,
especially the main important God Marduk
begin to have these disagreements.
Now understand something in the world
before modern times.
There is really only one reliable
counterbalance to the power of a king or
an emperor pharaoh.
And that's the priesthood and the
religion because the power that that
they have stems from the same source,
right?
You're,
you're king by divine,
right?
It's the gods who want you to be a king,
but who has a special relationship with
the gods and who helps placate the gods
and who does the work of the Gods and
who knows what the God really wants
while the priesthood and the religion.
Right?
So the only other source of legitimate
power in these societies before modern
times are often,
you know the priest and the priest and
Martech don't like this nab.
Tonight is guy,
and part of the reason why is he seems
to be kind of will favoring another God
over.
There's.
This is what I mean by it's hard to get
your mind around Nabonidus because he
may be like an [inaudible] type
character.
You know the Egyptian Pharaoh that may
have been a monotheist and may have
tried to change Egypt's religion.
Another similar story,
right?
Where you have the autocratic ruler
opposed by a powerful priesthood and
after Aka not died,
things returned back to normal and they
kind of were carving his face off of all
of the old things.
Trying to forget he ever lived.
Now,
urbanite is may have been one of these
guys to the one of the change,
the religion.
His mother was supposedly a priestess of
a religion devoted to a god named sin,
a Moon God,
and so nab tonight is right before this
time period,
gives the ultimate middle finger to the
priesthood of Marduk by leaving Babylon
and going to some Arabian oasis.
Now,
historians in modern times if found all
sorts of really good logical patriotic
reasons why the king might do that.
In past times it was much more portrayed
like this guy is a mystic,
either a mystic or an old man or a
combination of the two and he just wants
to get away from is unworthy people and
he appreciates it more in these Arabian
oasis.
It's probably what modern historians
think.
He's probably,
they're doing important work for the
country,
but he's missing important work.
At the same time,
the Babylonians required their king to
be there once a year for a New Year's
festival.
It was important he had to physically
grasp the hand of the God in front of
the population once a year to ensure
success and good things and all these
kinds of deals and he stayed away for
like a decade on the Babylonian records
will say every year the king was not
here for the ceremony or what have you,
and they're getting pissed that he's
putting more money into creating more of
these temples for the other religion,
denying some money that the people of
Marduk expect and and you can just see
it boiling over.
Right.
And then the kings not even there.
His son Belshazzar is ruling as a region
and he's not popular either,
so the king is part of it,
but Babylon is going through tough
economic times two and that's putting
the squeeze on people.
They're having problems with disease and
that's causing unrest.
Archeologists,
Dr Joan oats describes,
you know the down and dirty parts of,
of,
of day to day suffering and let's
remember something.
Babylon's banking system and financial
system was developed enough so that they
had great banking houses there that were
very powerful and lived on long after
this period and the end,
and that's just another one of those
dynamics that makes us think about
modern times.
These are powerful interests that have
some authority in the state.
What happens when things seemed to be
falling apart and people are losing
money and times are bad and and you
start getting Persian propaganda about
this king who sounds like things are
going his way,
which remember during this time period
might have caused a lot of people to
figure the gods are smiling on that guy
and our kings not even showing up to
shake the God's hand every New Year's.
Right.
Here's the way Dr Joan oats describes
the situation in Babylon considering
also remember that this king looks like
a guy who's trying to change religious
traditions,
trying to change a bunch of other
things,
and Dr.
oates writes,
quote clearly Nabil [inaudible] is
religious and administrative reforms
provoked great resentment.
While the wars and extensive building
programs of his predecessors had proved
a severe burden on the country's
resources,
large numbers of economic texts reveal
severe inflation.
A situation now made worse by the spread
of plague between five slash 60 bce and
5:50
bce,
prices rose by up to 50 percent and from
five 62,
four 85 bce,
the total increase amount of some 200
percent and not just that,
but again,
take this with a grain of salt.
It's argued about but,
but there are people inside Babylon who
might be considered,
shall we say,
vulnerable to propaganda that created
descent.
There are a lot of people in Babylon who
are there because they were forcibly
taken once upon a time from where they
came from and some of the propaganda
afterwards.
Certainly the post,
but maybe some
of the pre propaganda to from Cyrus told
these people that if the Persians were
to take over,
they get to go home.
Start with the deportees from Judah.
Jewish people today.
There are,
there are still,
I'm sure still,
you know,
even with all the troubles Jews in that
part of the world today that are
descendants of people who were forcibly
removed after the Babylonians sacked
Jerusalem.
What if Cyrus was telling those people,
if I get a fight,
could empower you,
can go home,
and what if he was telling all the other
deportees the same thing.
Now in historians refer to Cyrus and the
Persians propaganda.
The first idea that comes to mind is
like negative propaganda,
like the Nazi stuff designed to lie to
people and get you to believe things
that aren't true,
but you could make a case that that
since we know that Cyrus and the
Persians will eventually actually do
what they're saying here,
right?
That they will,
for example,
allow the Jews to go back to Judah and
reestablish their religion and even
eventually pay for some of the
rebuilding of the second temple.
What will be the second temple with,
with royal funds,
when you know that they're actually
going to do that?
Maybe you could say that this propaganda
is a lot more like dropping leaflets
over enemy military lines that say
something like,
you know,
surrendered to us.
We don't hurt prisoners and we'll give
you a hot meal and you know,
a few bucks in your pocket and some
cigarettes.
What would they have done in the old
days?
Maybe this is like telling the people
inside Babylon do not fear.
I may be coming,
but I'm going to send you home now.
Real experts on this Ip embryonic
caution us against thinking about this
the way that I just described to you
that this is a a conscious policy of
toleration.
He says,
the way the marketing really is is a lot
more like cyrus's,
Assyrian and Babylonian predecessors
where he's essentially promising
continuity and because continuity means
allowing these people to do things the
way that they're accustomed to do it,
it seems like tolerance and he points
out that it's normal for conquerors in
this region even before this time period
to come in and promise to restore
everything that's wrong.
The gods are upset.
I will fix that.
The economy is bad.
You are kept away from your home and
your gods are just,
you know,
I will fix that,
the restore and recreate her of order.
So whatever you want to call this.
In 5:39,
cyrus and the Babylonian army meet and
in a battle where there seems to have
been a really nasty massacre.
At the end,
the Babylonian army was defeated the
rest of the troops that are run back to
the very formidable defenses of the city
and within two days,
somehow the gates of the city are opened
and Cyrus's general is marching through
the streets and triumph in Babylon
falls.
And now tonight is fleas and he's
eventually captured and supposedly
treated well by Cyrus.
Just like all the other kings were
Hurghada.
This of course has to give us a
stratagem story of how it happened this
time.
It involves,
you know,
waiting till they can get the river
down,
the flows through the city to a certain
length or to a point where the troops
can go through the marshes or what have
you and capture the city.
And I think he's one of the ones that
say that the city didn't even know it
was being captured because there was
some,
you know,
revelry going on attached to a religious
cult and the city so big anyway mean
modern excavations put the city size is
over 2000 acres and the wall
circumference at about 11 miles.
So it's possible that in one part of the
city where they were partying it up and
the Persians got in,
the natural thing to do would be to
throw out a story like that and blame it
on typical,
you know,
Greek stereotypes and whatnot.
But it should be pointed out one that
oftentimes in these ancient religions
there was an awful lot of decadent or
fun or depends on your point of view,
I guess stuff that was part of the
religious rights.
And you'll see this in Greece and Rome
and a ton of other religions the world
over,
especially in the ancient period.
And these people are immensely
religious.
The Babylonians especially,
it's a holy city of Mesopotamia,
right?
These are very religious people.
So imagine people with the commitment of
like a Taliban,
right?
The seriousness with which they take
this in stride and militancy and all
that,
but you might be commanded to party.
It's a party for God and if you're not
there,
the ramifications could be huge.
Right?
I'm inclined to think that it's a Greek
stereotype of course,
but there's a part of me that wants to
believe it's the latter.
Now,
the one thing,
this conquest,
if that's even the right word of Babylon
is known for is the fact that it's
generally considered to be bloodless and
forget that battle we talked about with
the nasty potential massacre at the end
when the city of Babylon is taken,
it's taken essentially voluntarily.
I mean it's like the Babylonians open up
the door and Cyrus says,
general comes in and 17 or so days
later,
Cyrus himself comes in and we're told
that the population,
you know,
gets in front of his chariot and lays
down palm fronds and stuff,
which some historians in the old days
used to be sure was a sign of how much
people wanted them.
They're more modern day historian's.
Point out that that's generally how you
get treated when you come into a city
that's trying to show that they're no
threat at all and please don't hurt us.
That's perhaps what the Persian takeover
of Babylon is most known for.
Cyrus didn't hurt anybody,
and as I said earlier,
Naba is his life is spared,
which supposedly is the same fate that
Cyrus has made it out to all the kings
he's faced,
which by the way is not only unusual,
but it's not even maybe true.
Who knows?
There are always little hints somewhere
that maybe Cyrus killed these kings and
the propaganda covered it up.
Nonetheless,
historically and traditionally,
he supposed to have spared and given
good lives to all these other kings.
He defeated osteotomies of the medes
creases of the Lydians.
Now,
now benign cysts of the Babylonians.
What is the message Cyrus is trying to
send here?
I mean,
that's what I find interesting.
You want to know a little bit about the
guy himself and maybe what he was trying
to do.
What's the message when he does that?
Because the Assyrian King,
who last conquered Babylon brags about
how he tied the king of Babylon up like
a pig and display them in the center of
Nineveh.
So this is not standard operating
procedure.
It's one of the things,
by the way,
that fascinates me about Cyrus,
because the outcomes razor approach to
history,
which is the right way to go.
I mean,
what else are you going to do is to
assume the most logical things,
right?
You don't assume illogical things.
So the assumption always is that someone
like Cyrus is playing a hardcore cynical
propaganda game.
And again,
odds are probably is most people would
be,
but occasionally you're going to get
some different kind of human being
because we see them,
they exist.
It's just if you're using the alchemist
razor approach to try to determine,
you know,
what a gone Gandhi was really like a
thousand years from now,
you might be looking at listened.
Gandhi was really,
um,
you know,
this was a cynical attempt to figure out
a way to gain power to level.
I mean,
you could figure out all these real
logical reasons why a guy might do this.
Sometimes people who are doing things
for mystic reasons or morality reasons
or humanistic reasons or any of these
things.
Sometimes those people slipped through
the cracks because it's just so easy to
assume they had a more real world,
terra firma reason for doing things.
Is it possible that cyrus was kind of a
humanist?
Maybe you know,
this is how he's portrayed by the way,
by his real fans and a lot of people
back in Iran.
I mean as the guy who invented human
rights sort of at least as a ruler is
concerned.
And Babylon is one of the number one
pieces of evidence,
you know,
that gets trotted out in defense of this
idea that this isn't just some sort of
policy of tolerance for expediency sake.
That this is how Cyrus really believes
you can govern.
And it should be pointed out that that
not only has babylon kind of surrender
without a fight.
There's another Babylonian city or two
that kind of opens their doors to Cyrus.
And it's interesting because,
you know,
resists Origami has an interesting take
on something that the Babylonian King
did as part of the,
the,
the fighting with Cyrus for Babylon
supposedly,
and this is a way to look at nab
tonight,
is showing that maybe he was this really
responsible king after all,
before Cyrus gets to Babylon nab night,
it goes around to all the surrounding
towns and,
and takes their gods,
takes all their little,
the statues and the representations of
their gods and takes them to Babylon.
And traditionally this is considered to
be an act of safekeeping,
right?
You know that you don't want your statue
of Liberty falling into the hands of the
elamites and ending up in their trophy
case,
right?
So you take all these village,
God's back to Babylon for safekeeping
reasons are gone.
Me Though has an interesting take on
this in his book,
discovering Cyrus,
he does a great job reminding us of the
interesting,
uh,
belief systems of the people who have
these gods.
And then how maybe you could see what
nab and knight is doing is the
equivalent of perhaps kidnapping the
gods of these towns.
And holding them hostage for good
behavior,
right?
Stay loyal to Babylon or your God gets
it in the neck.
Something like that.
Here's what's our gummy rights,
and remember,
this only makes sense if nab tonight is
a seriously worried that some of these
towns are just going to go over to cyrus
because of the propaganda or whatever he
writes,
quote,
faced with the very real prospect that
is,
cities would open up their gates to the
conqueror.
Nab Tonight is settled upon a drastic
policy.
He decided to hold hostage.
The sacred idols of Babylonia is
outlying cities to ensure the loyalty of
their inhabitants.
So when Cyrus in his army resumed their
march in the late summer of 5:39
bce,
a series of caravans laden with divine
images and other religious artifacts
made its way to Babylon.
Living today,
we can hardly grasp the full
psychological impact of nab.
Unitus is action.
The idol was the centerpiece of the
ancient Mesopotamian cult and the most
important symbol of the community.
The inanimate statues were treated like
royalty,
bathed,
perfumed,
groomed,
and even fed lavish meals by an
entourage of domestic servants.
Priests and personal attendance,
Ancient Mesopotamian cults were
geographically centralized and the God's
power's territorially limited.
That is why Cyrus could not receive the
divine approval he desired with the gods
concentrated in Babylon.
He then continues,
but nab unitus was playing a dangerous
game by emptying is cities have their
idols.
Proximity to the cult statue meant
everything to the superstitious masses
who believed that the sacred images of
their gods could perform miracles,
cure illness,
and most importantly,
protect their settlements.
Cities last divine protection when
they're God's left and quote,
one of the first things that Cyrus will
brag about doing when he takes over
Babylon is returning all those gods to
the outlying communities,
and those people freaking out at,
you know,
having their gods back.
Once again,
as Pierre,
Brianna says,
Cyrus's portraying himself as the
restorer of order of things as they
should be.
He's beginning to tie himself to the
ancient Assyrian tradition.
Some historians suggest consciously,
he'll talk about repairing something in
the city and coming across some
proclamation by Asha,
Bonnie Paul,
the Assyrian King.
He'll tie himself to Assyria and this
ancient in a royal tradition.
When he starts calling himself king of
kings and King of the universe,
these are old,
a Syrian and even acadian terms,
but if cyrus was starting to use these
ancient titles for himself,
you can see why he thought he might
deserve it because 80 or 90 years after
you know the ancient kingdom of Assyria
fell,
Cyrus had put Humpty dumpty back
together again with sort of a different
form and different marketing and
different branding,
but all of a sudden,
once again,
just as head existed during later a
Syrian times,
one power had had Gemini in that part of
the world.
Now trying to rule immensely different
people.
People from you know everything from
from deeply urban environments and
places like Babylon,
to Phoenecian cities.
Two tribes that existed off in the edges
of the Eurasian Steppe and incorporate
all these different people into one
empire.
Much is made of the different strategies
that the Persians used over the
Assyrians.
Instead of trying to shoo everybody into
one,
you know,
cultural style,
convert everybody to your religion.
Make Good Assyrians,
have these conquered people.
The Persians used a much lighter touch
that the idea of toleration really was
to allow local customs to continue.
The Assyrians wouldn't have tolerated
that the fact that the Persians didn't
try to change all that,
whether it was a question of religion or
language or anything else.
In fact,
when the Persian empire gets up and
running,
Persians will be put in all the most
important positions,
but Persian will not be the language of
the empire.
There will always be only a tiny
minority of people actually speaking
Persian.
All of the official proclamations will
be multilingual,
so the different people can read them.
All the local gods are respected and
supported.
Now,
again,
is this some sort of,
you know,
humanitarian gesture on Cyrus's part or
is it a guy who is a humanitarian and
thanks.
Listen,
I'm just telling you this is the best
way to treat people and it will work out
best.
In other words,
a guy who believes his own humanitarian
beliefs and morals dove tail into good
outcomes,
or is it somebody who cynically looked
at this and just says,
listen,
I'm just telling you,
if we do it this way,
we'll have less revolts.
It'll be much better than the way the
Assyrians did it.
Who knows?
It's tempting to think of Cyrus as
brilliant and visionary,
regardless of which one of those things
is true.
He organizes this empire.
He starts creating things that are
called satraps in sat trapeze,
which are administrative units that will
be built upon by his successors,
and then the next major thing we hear
about Cyrus,
it's almost like you know when these
people live that far back,
you get the highlights of their lives
right?
Highlight number one,
you know conquest of Medea.
Highlight number to conquest
of Lydia.
How that number three conquest of
Babylon highlight number for the
expedition against a queen of one of the
most powerful tribal coalitions in
Central Asia.
Now the fact that there is a clean
involved in this story should tip you
off to the idea that it's going to be a
good one,
and Hurghada test by the way knows this.
He's eager to get to this story and he's
going to spend a ton of time on it.
He's been setting it up.
He knows his audience is ready.
He's got a little moral twists that may
or may not have anything to do with
reality,
but you get a look at that 2,500
year old mind that your mind melding
with one way at this point in the story,
but it becomes the time where Heraclitus
is at his least reliable too.
I mean,
he jumps from highlight number three to
highlight number four in Cyrus's life in
one second.
If you look at the actual dates involved
though,
you'll see that there is like nine years
between highlight number three and
highlight number four and nine years
when Cyrus is well to use his own
marketing and branding king of the
universe.
What the heck was this guy doing for
nine years while he was putting out some
propaganda?
We know something called the Cyrus
cylinder is a famous,
and it's this piece where first cyrus
has the Babylonian gods saying I was
with him the whole way,
and then he introduces himself as this
good guy
again,
propaganda and makes it easier to rule a
subject.
People,
if you make it feel like it was your God
that wanted me here
I came because he took my hand.
Right,
so so you're legitimizing your rule and
tying you into the to the age old power
structure and basically saying that king
you defeated was the real weirdo that
the god didn't want.
I am restoring,
you know,
the kingship to the people that mark
wants to have it.
You can see that the same is true in a
lot of the other religions that Cyrus is
involved with.
This is why a lot of people think his
whole propaganda tolerance thing was
much more of a political move because
look at how it helps him politically in
a way that by the way,
he could not have foreseen it made them
immortal.
This is from peer Brown's book from
Cyrus to Alexander,
but at the translation from the Bible
that he uses in the same way that the
cyrus cylinder says,
the Babylonian God,
Marduk took Cyrus's hand and swept away
all the opposition.
This is what the Israeli God,
Yahweh did,
according to the Bible quote that says
y'all way to his appointed to Cyrus,
whom he has taken by his right hand to
subdue nations before him and stripped
the loins of kings to force gateways
before him that their gates be closed no
more.
I will go before you leveling the
heights.
I will shatter the bronze gateways,
smash the iron bars.
I will give you the hidden treasures,
the secret hordes that you may know that
I am your way.
And so once again,
cyrus has these gods on his side.
Why are they on this side?
Well,
he's always helping,
isn't he?
He's always doing what the priesthood of
Marta would like.
In general.
It's interesting how Martin follows
along.
He likes if you treat as priests well in
the case of y'all way.
Well,
according to the Bible again and Pierre
Briana,
skeptical of the details but says in,
in,
in the bigger picture,
at least,
it was consistent with what actually
happened.
The Bible says that in the reign of a
king to kings,
after two official kings after Cyrus,
they found the actual order that would
have made y'all way pleased with
investing,
shall we say in the Cyrus conquests,
according to the Bible and Pierre brands
description of it.
This is from Ezra,
by the way,
out of the royal archives,
a baton.
Ah,
the order said,
quote,
in the first year of Cyrus,
the king,
King Cyrus decreed temple of God in
Jerusalem,
the temple will be rebuilt as a place at
which sacrifices are offered and by
which offerings are brought to be burnt.
It's height as to be 60 cubits.
It's width,
60 cubits.
They're going to be three thicknesses of
stone blocks and one of would the
expenses to be met by the king's
household.
Furthermore,
the vessels of gold and silver from the
temple of God,
which Nebuchadnezzar took from the
sanctuary in Jerusalem and brought to
Babylon,
are to be restored so that everything
may be restored to the sanctuary in
Jerusalem and put back in the temple of
God and quote that dovetails nicely with
that story of the ghostly hand,
doesn't it?
Because what that Guy Belshazzar was
drinking out of that made you know you
always so mad to begin with are all
these sacred vessels from the old temple
in Jerusalem,
Solomon's Temple.
Now Cyrus was decreeing that you rebuild
Solomon's Temple and you pay for it out
of the king's treasury and you bring
back all these things that are still
around and restock the temple with them,
and then you send the people who have
been deported here,
back home.
Now here's the thing,
this reconstituted area that will become
a sad trap by the way,
does not have its political freedom.
They're not going to be the way they
were.
You know when the Babylonians and
Egyptians were arguing over them,
but you got to see that they're pretty
darn far ahead.
They went from a people that might have
died out religiously.
In fact,
the book I had,
the places Cyrus has one of the top,
most 100 influential people of all time
says that that's one of the things.
Maybe you credit him with the fact that
if he doesn't do this,
there's a chance Judaism doesn't
continue over the long haul.
In this case,
he builds what's known as the second
temple,
and if you want to see continuity,
the wall that is still one of the
holiest,
if not the holiest sites,
I guess the Temple Mount will be holy or
but,
but it's part of the temple.
Mount is the famous Western Wall.
The Western Wall is a Roman era addition
to the
second temple,
which cyrus allegedly according to the
Bible,
paid for and authorized.
It's so interesting,
isn't it?
To consider how connected the stories of
the ancient Iranians,
the ancient Persians are to the ancient
Jewish folks,
especially considering the current
antagonism between them.
You know,
as late as the 19 seventies,
the shah of Iran was,
was touting this ancient closeness
between the peoples and their
relationship.
If not for the ancient Persians and
Iranians,
there's a chance there wouldn't be
Judaism today and depending on when it
died out,
there's a very good chance you wouldn't
have had the religions that sprouted off
that branch.
You wouldn't have had Christianity,
you probably wouldn't have had Islam.
In other words,
is Cyrus the great actually did do this
and he had never lived to do it.
What would the world look like today?
Another thing it says in that 100 most
influential people of all time that I
thought was interesting is that many of
the people that get credited as being
very important and dynamic and
instrumental human beings in terms of
their effect on history,
did something that would have been done
anyway might not have been done at that
time or that way,
but a lot of this stuff would have
happened.
Someone else would have discovered the
light bulb probably the author thought
it likely that if cyrus the great had
never lived,
none of this stuff happens.
He was a unique individual and even
though you can't get your mind around
the specifics of how he was a unique
individual,
you can sort of look at what built up
even if he ever wants.
Right,
and you have to assume that there was a
lot of foundation bubbling up up under
the surface for Cyrus to work with.
This is still a pretty incredible human
being.
I think you could probably say with a
decent chance of being right that he is
in the five thirty's bce,
the greatest geo political figure who's
ever lived,
which makes the next thing I'm going to
say no.
So hard to believe.
You know?
Why should I say it?
How about letting historian 80 olmsted
in a book published in Nineteen Forty
Eight?
Say it again.
Is there any more of a telling example
that these people live at the very tail
end,
the black and white era of recording of
human history because how can this guy
be as big as he is and yet this next
line be true?
Olmsted said,
quote here,
we must leave Cyrus for suddenly and
without warning.
Our information comes to an end and to
quote 200 years after this period,
we will know Alexander the Great's
symptoms to such a degree that doctors
today try to diagnose what he may have
died of and they still don't know.
I'm not saying everything's perfect,
but you know where when the how's the
why's,
how can you not know how this guy dies?
Highlight number four in his life as
portrayed by Heraclitus is Hurghada
tells a story of how
he dies and I love the fact that
Hurghada does goes to the trouble to
point out that he's heard several
different versions of this story,
but the one he's going to give you is
the one he thinks is most likely and
maybe it's just a coincidence that the
story that Hurghada thinks is most
likely is the one with the most exotic
interesting movie like elements to it.
You can imagine.
I can't imagine he left a better version
on the table somewhere saying,
nope.
You know,
I just don't believe that because the
one he used is so awesome.
Now,
is it believable?
That's the problem here.
Nobody knows what's believable off the
top of my head,
if you asked me what percentage bought
into the general idea of Hirata story,
I'd say it's like 80 percent.
Most of them don't believe any of the
details,
but the broad idea that in 5:30
bce,
cyrus the great died somewhere out in
this step area as Hurghada to said
details,
probably unknown about 20 percent I'd
say,
of the historians,
don't think he died a completely
different way.
Something against different tribes than
Hirata says in different areas.
Others that he didn't die that way at
all.
Xenophon renting a couple centuries
afterwards,
we'll say died in bed peacefully.
So there are some historians who buy
that too.
In Iran,
it's a generally,
I think a higher percentage of
historians that think he didn't die the
way Heraclitus says,
and in part you,
you can understand why you'd be a little
skeptical.
It's just too darn interesting the way
he does it.
You can see,
you know,
the admonition that I got when I was
starting in journalism,
the one that said,
you know,
tell what really happened in the most
interesting way possible.
What happens to an admonition like that?
If there's no way you could possibly
know what really happened,
but you have to tell it anyway.
What are your standards?
Then?
You're pretty much left with the most
interesting way you can at that point,
right?
The story is herodotus tells,
it involves this little twist.
You're going to end up leaving his
theatrical presentation with a deeper
message.
Again,
the deeper message may or may not be
true Hurghada this couches this story
now into the ID of overreach.
Maybe the idea of absolute power
corrupts absolutely,
and before we write this off,
as many historians do right away because
it's just such an obvious moral message.
Remember,
you could make that case about Hitler.
You know,
with the absolute power turning you mad
after awhile with Alexander,
you can make that case.
I mean,
I guess there are historical figures
where this is both a motif because it's
this recurring theme you see all the
time,
but it also happens to be true.
Maybe after years of being king of the
universe,
Cyrus got a little full of himself.
Who knows,
but that's the way this is portrayed,
right?
There's going to be an object lesson
here and the person that is going to
stick it to cyrus and teach him this
lesson is going to be a queen,
you know,
but you have to think of like an
Amazonian Queen.
This isn't some woman who's walking
around in velvet,
you know,
on a throne being fan.
I mean this is a person who probably
once upon a time was killing
men in hand to hand combat.
Now,
did this woman really exist?
Who the heck knows?
There is no historical confirmation that
I've ever seen that says that they found
anything that proves this queen who's
name,
by the way,
I used to call her tomorrow when I was
growing up,
but I've seen timorous,
Tom Morris,
number of different pronunciations.
I think Shakespeare might've used her as
a character,
one of his plays.
Nonetheless,
you can say a couple of things.
One,
it wouldn't have been outrageous to
think of her as a female warrior because
these tribes actually had them.
It may have been the actual root of the
idea of Amazon's in sort of a mythology,
so she could have actually been a killer
warrior and also the tribe she was
supposed to have lead was real all too
real to some people.
They were called the master guitar or
the message tie.
A dangerous,
powerful,
numerous tribal coalition that,
you know,
Hurghada is in his writings.
He has to set it up and tell you what he
knows,
which isn't much.
He,
he says,
I hear there a skiffy in people,
which they kind of were.
You'd have to think of Mongolia type
culture,
but with people who were probably
predominantly light skinned and ranging
on the scale of looks from like a Turkic
kind of look all the way up to people
with blonde and red hair,
blue and green eyes tall.
There's a little viking side to them,
a little bit of the Viking Ethos and
building little sword worshiping and
things like that.
Supposedly once a year these people
would have a scaffold erected and they'd
put a sword on top of the scaffolding.
Then they would march in,
meet the scaffold.
One out of every 100 prisoners that they
captured over the year and execute them
as a sacrifice to the sky.
God,
the son,
God Mithras,
I think it was.
These are colorful,
scary people.
Just what you want in a story like this.
Iran,
this has already talked about their head
hunting.
The fact that they make,
you know,
drinking cups out of skulls and the
really nasty warriors are the ones with
the most cops.
He talks about their cannabis use.
Again,
this was the exotic barbarian.
You want to hear what they do.
He says they found this fruit that they
can burn and then they sit around the
fire,
burning the fruit and it gets them
intoxicated like wine gets Greeks
intoxicated.
So another little bit of that barbarian
colored to throw in.
He also points out according to him that
they are very promiscuous.
You might call them free love types or
swinger is maybe anybody can sleep with
anybody else's wife.
He just has to put his bow,
you know,
alongside their tend to let them know
you're interested I guess.
So weed,
smoking,
headhunting blood drinking,
wife sharing,
Viking types.
Who would not want that in a good story
if you don't know anything and you're
just trying to make the best story,
make sure you include these people are
test that Cyrus leads
and army up to this queens territory and
then basically proposes marriage to her
so it would be like a diplomatic
alliance thing.
And in Hurghada this says that she sees
through this reus immediately saying
that he just wants to conquer her people
by marrying her.
So then when she says no,
he begins to try to set up what we would
call today an amphibious river crossing.
There's a big river that divides the
territory.
He's coming from,
from the territory of these Central
Asian horse nomads up in places like
Kazakhstan and places like that today.
And as Cyrus and the Persians were told,
are building these boats,
some of which have like towers,
like fighting towers on them.
She sends him a message.
Now remember,
she's going to be like the voice of
Avenging Karma here in teaching cyrus a
lesson.
So her voice and the words that are
brought,
it just puts in her mouth from a screen.
Writers show runners point of view are
designed to set this idea up right?
You should know,
but you don't.
You know you're going to get what's
coming to you.
Here's what Hirata to says.
This is the discipline core translation
of her audit.
This,
by the way,
quote King of the Medes,
I advise you to abandon this enterprise
for you cannot know if in the end it
will do you any good rule your own
people and try to bear the sight of me
ruling mine,
but of course you will refuse my advice
as the last thing you wish for us to
live in.
Peace listened.
Then.
If you are so bent upon trying your
strength against the massacre tie,
give up the laborious task of building
that bridge and let my army withdraw
three days,
March from the river,
and then you come over yourself or if
you prefer it,
retire the same distance yourselves and
let us meet you on your side of the
river and quote,
this barbarian Warrior Queen is
basically saying to a guy whose title
includes king of kings and King of the
universe to come and get it,
or I'll come over and take it from you.
That's a pretty strong female character,
isn't it?
And I was thinking that it makes
Hurghada to at times look a little pro
feminist,
right?
Like he like he's been looking for a
good,
strong female character.
There's another reason maybe that would
play well,
maybe some of the people in his audience
are women and it would be good to have a
character that they can both relate to
in cheer for.
Finally,
it might just be a dig at the manliness
of the Persians,
right?
I mean,
here's the greatest king that Asia has
ever produced and he's about to be
beaten and killed by a woman.
Nonetheless in the story when she says,
you know,
do you want it over here?
Do you want it over there?
Cyrus in his generals and whatnot,
sit down and have a conference about
this.
What do we do?
Which choice do we take in?
All his advisors say,
let her come to our side of the river.
One advisor though,
says,
no,
no.
Go over to her side.
That advisor is our old friend,
the king of Lydia
creases,
who instead of being killed Hurghada.
This has,
you know,
going in the story,
sort of acting as advisor to Cyrus all
the way through
increases.
His advice is totally different.
First of all,
he says,
you can't let her come over here and
give grounded in front of her.
It's a woman.
It would look terrible.
So there's that other little dig.
He says,
go over to her side.
And then he says,
and how about we do a little trick and
he proceeds to tell Cyrus that they
should essentially do the same thing to
these people that the medes did to
either these people are their cousins a
generation before in a story you may
recall,
get them all drunk and kill them.
My discipline core translation has
creases,
telling Cyrus to do it this way.
Quote here then is my advice crossed the
river advanced to the limit of the
enemy's withdrawal and then get the
better of them.
Buy a piece of strategy.
I have heard that these people have no
experience of such luxuries as the
Persians and joy and know nothing about
the pleasures of life.
Let us take advantage of this fact and
set out a banquet in our camp on the
most generous scale with a great many
sheep slaughtered and dressed all sorts
of other dishes and bowls of strong wine
in liberal quantities.
Then when the banquet is all prepared,
he says,
let us March back to the river,
leaving only a detachment of inferior
troops behind.
Unless I'm very much mistaken when our
enemies.
See all those good things they will set
to work upon them and that will be our
chance to distinguish ourselves by a
bold stroke and quote again,
is that a recurring motif or is that
just a tactic that seems to work quite a
bit?
Who knows,
but in the story we're told that the a
third of the army shows up,
kills the inferior troops,
sees all the food and the wine proceeds
to get,
you know,
very full and very drunk,
and then the Persians come in and kill a
bunch of them and capture some others.
About a third of the army according to
Hurghada tests included amongst the
prisoners a general who also happens to
be this barbarian queens son.
So now in this scenario,
Hurghada is playing with his movies,
turned into a little bit of a thriller
with little chest match and all of a
sudden the cyrus's side is captured a
major piece,
the son of the Queen.
And so she issues one of these.
I'll let you go now if you give me back
my son kinds of speeches from the
pervious translation.
I brought it to says,
quote,
when to my wrist learned what had
happened to her army and her son.
She sent a herald to Cyrus with this
message,
blood thirsty cyrus.
Do not gloat over what has happened
here.
You Persians.
Indulge yourself with the fruit of the
vine to the point of madness so that the
wine into your bodies,
ugly words flow up and out of you.
By such means you have tricked me and
you've taken my son,
prisoner,
but not by supremacy and battle.
Well then I urge you to follow this
advice.
Return my son to me.
And despite the damage you have,
cunningly wreaked upon a third part of
the army of the massacre tie.
You may leave this land unharmed if you
do not do this.
I swear by the sun,
the Lord of the massacre.
Tie that I will satisfy your thirst for
blood in.
Well as you are in quote.
So what Cyrus going to do with this
interesting,
powerful chest piece.
He doesn't get the chance to decide
because we're told that as soon as the
queen's son sobers up finds himself,
you know,
hands tied or bound.
He beseeches cyrus to undo his hands.
Somehow Cyrus is convinced,
and I like the way my relevance and
translation puts it.
The minute his hands were free,
Rawlinsons Hurghada to says he destroyed
himself,
so he committed suicide.
Now all of a sudden,
cyrus just lost his piece,
and this is when we're told the battle
happens.
This from the discipline core
translation quote,
the queen on hearing that Cyrus ignored
her terms,
engaged him in the field with all the
forces she possessed,
the battle which followed,
I judged to have been more violent than
any other fought between foreign
nations.
According to the information that I
have.
The engagement began with the two armies
coming to a halt within range of each
other and exchanging shots with bows and
arrows until their arrows were used up,
after which there was a long period of
close fighting with spears and daggers,
neither side being willing to retreat.
Finally,
however,
the massacre Gutei got the upper hand.
The greater part of the Persian army was
destroyed where it stood and Cyrus
himself was killed.
He had been on the throne for 29 years
years,
and to quote,
of course that doesn't quite twist the
knife enough and have you leaving the
performance,
really thinking about some of the
greater themes in life.
So hirata tests from my pervious
translation adds a Coda to the story.
He writes,
quote,
queen terrorists then filled a wine skin
with human blood and searched for the
corpse of Cyrus amongst the Persian
dead.
When she found him,
she thrust his head into the wine skin,
and as she does abused the corpse,
she declared to it,
I am alive and if conquered you in
battle,
but you have ruined me by taking my son
through guile.
Well then just as I threatened,
I will slake your thirst
blood and quote.
So if as the recurring Greek motif will
later show that the Persians are surreal
overreaches,
I'm sure Hurghada does.
His attitude here is that they should
have learned their lesson with cyrus by
the time cyrus exits the scene,
though he's built an empire that
stretches from modern day Pakistan all
the way to the Mediterranean.
I've been to Turkey down by the Red Sea
to the borders of Egypt and out to the
Central Asian step when he's taken you
know,
efforts and spent years organizing it in
putting it in a form where it has a
chance to live on after he's gone.
Nonetheless,
you cannot lose a person of that
magnitude.
You cannot lose an Alexander.
You cannot lose an Napoleon.
You cannot lose and have these people
from such lofty heights removed from the
scene without there being this huge
vacuum a couple of hundred years after
this time period,
one of the people who will fill a vacuum
and play a similar role and maybe
eclipse this person will visit his tomb.
Alexander the great along with some
influential colleagues will go to the
spot and the building that is assumed to
be the tomb of Cyrus the great.
That tomb is still standing by the way,
in modern day Iran,
if indeed it was the tomb.
It's interesting to think of Alexander
climbing up there in a fully colorized
historical era now,
by the way,
bringing with him people who will write
about it afterwards.
We actually have through another guy,
the writings of someone who was with
Alexander and kind of describes what the
tune looked like,
a lot of clothing,
a lot of souvenirs,
a lot of things that just sort of helped
the guy into the afterlife sort of deal
and then a body that was preserved in
wax.
We're told this,
this was kind of a Persian custom too.
Now this might just be me,
but I had this feeling that if the queen
of the massive Gd or the Messa di had
taken his head or something,
that's a mutilation that they would have
probably told us about.
It's probable that the body looked
pretty darn good because no one talked
about it looking any other way.
We're told that there was an inscription
on the tomb.
Now some historians think it must've
been in front of the tomb because it's
missing,
but they were a couple of different
descriptions from people who supposedly
saw them.
Some are more flowery than others.
One that I liked that has a couple of
different versions says quote mortal.
I am cyrus son of Cam by ses who founded
the Persian empire and was King of Asia.
Grudge me not then my monument
and the quote,
but there are other traditions also from
eyewitness accounts originally that
record a very different sort of epitaph.
Some of the historians are like say it's
much more traditionally Iranian to it's
much more pithy and right to the point
the Persians,
when they were leading the empire,
could put on the airs as well as any
Mesopotamian dynasty ever did.
They could heap on all the traditional
titles.
Queen Victoria had the empress of India.
The kings of this area had king of the
universe,
King of the four corners of the earth,
King of lands,
and the Persians could do that,
but sometimes when they were just
recording for eternity,
which is what a tomb inscription like
this is,
they adopted a different style.
When the tomb inscription supposedly
from an eyewitness that I liked the
most,
and I like to use Cyrus's Persian,
he creek ish form of the name Kourosh or
Kourosh.
It says here I lie Kourosh,
king of kings.
The Persians grew up in the equivalent
of a tough neighborhood
to show.
You just heard,
involved a lot of context.
It didn't it where we discussed the
background,
where they sprung from,
because this does a bunch of things.
One,
it makes their achievements all the more
astounding.
I mean they arose in this world with all
these amazing competitors and manage to,
you know,
climb to the top of the heap.
Anyway,
it also helps us set a baseline for
comparison.
When we say things like the Persians are
tolerant or lenient,
you want to immediately say,
compared to what the show you just heard
gives us some idea what they might be
compared to.
Finally,
it's a fantastic story.
This story that's usually relegated to
dead air between two other stories,
right?
Somewhere between the fall of the Syria
and the rise of Persia is the,
you know,
latter part of the six hundreds and the
high five,
85,
95,
five,
85.
What's going on during that era.
Normally it's sort of just a transition
point between,
you know,
two chapters in a book.
Whereas all by itself it's twisted and
fascinating.
And I love the idea of the great power
like the US or the Soviet Union
collapsing and the rest of the world
sort of looking at each other over the,
you know,
smoke and ruins,
trying to figure out who gets what and
what are the things look like.
Now.
I love that.
The key to this whole story at this
point is,
you know,
when it took such a singular figure to
put this improbable,
you know,
event together.
What happens when that figure exits the
scene?
What are the odds of getting to Cyrus,
the greats in the same family,
one right after another.
Remember this is the largest empire in
world history.
The distance from one part to another is
daunting.
Then you have all these different
people,
people that are very independent minded
and fractious and who gave the Assyrians
fits all the time.
So many different religions,
so many different languages.
How is in a one small minority of people
going to rule this giant entity,
especially without the specially gifted
guy who built the whole thing.
In the next episode we'll examine how
you combat isis.
The son of Cyrus manages all this and
they will be coups and there will
potentially be armies disappearing in
sandstorms.
There will be far too many Greeks
probably for what the story really
warrants,
but you have to understand while we all
know instinctively there important
things going on in the east and the
north and the other parts of the Persian
empire that don't touch Greek lands.
They only people writing about it in any
sort of extended colorful way are the
Greek,
so just like everyone else will talk
about the Greek and Persian wars will
give some context of that battle of
their monopoly movie scene with the
Spartan.
Say,
come and take them
and then we'll deal with the guy.
The next guy really in this story,
who's personal talents are such that
he's a game changer all by himself.
The natural successor to Cyrus the great
and the person who finally puts the
stake in the heart of the black and
white world,
the son of Philip of Macedonia.
All that and more in the next episode of
kings of kings.
If you think the show you just heard is
worth a dollar,
Dan and Ben would love to have it.
A buck a show.
It's all we ask.
Go to Dan Carlin.com
for information on how to donate to the
show.
You want to help the podcast just by
your Amazon.com
products through the Amazon search
window on Dan Carlin Dot com,
and Dan and Ben will get a percentage of
what you spend.
It doesn't cost you a penny more and it
helps these guys out because they are
nice young Fella's.