How much time do you put into explaining
the development of a gap?
That's a perfect example of the sort of
question that bedeviled us in this
episode,
which covers by the way a ridiculously
short span of time,
but one of the most important,
let's just say month or so's in human
history.
It represents the greatest mass
outpouring of organized violence that
the world had ever seen and I don't
think there's ever been anything quite
like it.
You know,
the Second World War begins with a
German attack on Poland and fighting
between Germany and Poland.
That's over rather quickly and it's like
eight months before the major powers
actually come to blows.
This war starts with all the major
powers coming to blows head on instantly
on multiple fronts with casualties that
no one had ever even seen in their
wildest dreams.
At the same time at speed.
And I started to realize as the program,
you know,
it was happening that you can't get into
the minds of the people in the human
stories and the drama in the story
without getting into the military
affairs.
And it's.
It's day to day progression because
that's the driving force.
That's what sets the timeline,
that's what determines the turn in
fortune and that's what creates,
you know,
the human impact on the ground.
When we quote a reporter talking about
what it looks like in the hospitals in
France,
there's a reason that the hospitals are
full of hurt people and that's because
the events on the ground continue to
dictate what's going on,
but the military affairs are complex as
all get out.
How much time do you spend on a gap mean
the battle of the Marne,
right?
The famous miracle on the Marne is
determined by this gap in the enemy
line.
How much time do you spend on?
You know why there's a gap.
I mean,
if that really is a war,
losing situation to have developed,
you get into that.
Well,
if you get into that,
you're starting to follow a line of
detail that just will take you off into
the weeds.
The difficult story to decide when to go
off into the weeds and when to stay put
on the main road.
This is our attempt at explaining this
most complex and yet,
you know,
filled with human drama and great events
and larger than life figures and really
a changing of the guard in terms of,
you know,
one century to another as best as we can
do it.
The Dan Carlin approach to the first
world war,
it's called blueprint for Armageddon and
this is part two,
be some bus seven,
19,
41 date which will live in infamy.
It's history.
Perfect.
The events
that dude
figure it out from this time and place.
I take pride in the words,
been the Alina,
tear down the drama.
Hi,
welcome.
This kind of examination because people
have got to know whether or not their
question well,
I'm not a crop if we dig deep in art,
history and art and remember that we are
not descended from fearful of man.
It's hardcore history.
What year did humankind acquire the
capability to destroy itself?
I think that's an interesting idea,
isn't it?
The idea that every civilization in the
universe,
if it continues to progress
technologically down the road,
we'll reach a period when it can kill
itself,
either on purpose or accidentally.
This fits into something,
some physicists theories on what's
called the Fermi paradox,
and this idea of reaching a danger point
in your civilization is called the great
filter.
The fermi paradox is a famous paradox
that was,
um,
initially talked about supposedly by a
bunch of the great physicists in the
world on their lunch break where they
had done the math,
trying to figure out the possibilities
of intelligent life being elsewhere in
the universe.
And the math is so overwhelmingly in
favor of the idea that there must be
right.
There's hundreds of billions of stars in
our galaxy,
hundreds of billions of galaxies in the
universe.
It just seems like a slam dunk,
right?
So then Enrico Fermi,
famously one of the great physicist ever
famously then says to the group,
so where is everybody?
And that's the Fermi paradox.
If the math says they should be there,
but they're not there,
what's the reason they're not there?
And that's where the great filter comes
in because some of these people who
study this stuff have suggested that
there might be a point in every
intelligent civilizations development
where they acquire this ability to
destroy themselves and have to get
through the period where they have that
capability and get to the point where
they figure out how not to do that.
And it's kind of like a pass fail test
for intelligence,
civilizational growth everywhere in the
universe and sort of by its very nature,
most civilizations don't pass it.
And so maybe that's the reason they're
not all out there.
And guys like Nick Bostrom who study,
you know,
global catastrophic risk and stuff like
that.
And you know,
what,
if a comment hit the planet,
what if nanotechnology goes out of
control?
I mean,
it looks at all these issues.
He suggests that the earth entered this
civilizational phase,
this great filter period in our own
history in 1945 when the atomic bombs
were first used.
Now I think about this in terms of the
first world war because I think that's
when people first realized that human
beings had acquired a military
capability that was frightening,
not frightening because your enemy had
it frightening because human beings had
it.
You can go back and look at history and
there are lots of times when people were
afraid of the deadliness of weapons,
but they were afraid of the deadliness
of weapons either because they were
afraid themselves of getting killed or
their country of getting taken over
whatever.
They weren't afraid for the species.
They weren't afraid for civilization as
a whole.
In the closest you'll see,
um,
you know,
with that coming is you'll have like a
Mongol invasion or invasion from the
step and it,
it,
it strikes the subtle civilizations a
bit like a wave and it washes up a
certain amount of civilization up on the
beach,
but it doesn't destroy everything in the
19th century.
That's the first time period where you
can read writings from people who are
asserting that maybe what they're
developing battlefield capability wise
can destroy everything.
Now their version of everything is a
little bit different than ours.
When we talk about things like
existential risk,
we're talking about the survival of life
on the planet.
That's a post atomic you no idea of what
existential risk means.
We understand,
you know,
you have a nuclear war amongst all the
great powers and you can kiss life on
earth goodbye or certainly our level of
civilization.
You've heard that phrase bomb someone
back to the stone age.
What we modern people have the
capability to do that,
right?
But it was in the 19th century that the,
that the idea that that's what a major
war between the major powers might
amount to.
That's when that idea takes hold.
Those people are worried about
definition number two of existential
threat.
You know,
guys like Nick Bostrom have two
definitions.
One is the one we think about wiped out
life on earth,
but the other definition of what an
existential threat is,
is being knocked back down a few rungs
on your level of civilization and then
never finding your way back to your
former greatness.
You know to have a statue of liberty in
the sand moment design,
I like to call it where you look up and
you see the statue of Liberty,
like in the planet of the apes coming
out of the sand and you instantly
realize in a blinding flash of light
that you're living in an era that is off
the civilizational highs and that's what
the people writing in the late 19th,
early 20th century,
especially in places like Great Britain
and the United States where everything
seems just great.
Why don't we have to screw up with a war
and really nothing to gain and
everything to lose.
Those people are writing about living in
a golden age that they believe is
fragile and that these giant war
machines that are equally deadly in
terms of their abilities to kill people
on the battlefield,
but also their ability to simply
bankrupt the societies that have to
maintain them is causing consternation
and end the very weapons systems
themselves and the arms races that
they're having.
Create more opportunities for some sort
of violent outbreak of war that will
then see these things employed.
The funny thing about human history,
if you study military history,
is that up until about 200 years ago,
you can imagine armies from a very long
time ago fighting and beating armies
from.
Not that long ago.
I mean Alexander the Great's Army I
think beats the Carolingian army of
Charlemagne,
which is,
you know,
a first rate army a thousand years
later,
I don't think they must.
The Macedonians must their hair.
I mean there are books like Arthur
Pharaohs,
the origins of war,
where that,
that credible historian can't help but
play with the battle of Waterloo
inserting Alexander and his Macedonians
from the thirties bce in the place of
Napoleon and his French sending the
Macedonians up against the Duke of
Wellington and his British and their
coalition allies and having Alexander in
the Macedonians do at least as well as
Napoleon.
So what does that show you?
Well,
it shows you how all of human military
history changes at about the time of the
Napoleonic wars because all of a sudden
a new law of historical nature takes
over,
which says that earlier armies do not
beat later.
Armies mean the rules changed a thousand
percent.
First of all,
think about today,
if you took the US army from today,
how to fight a battle against the US
army of 1945.
Today's US army destroys that Second
World War Army,
mid 20th century army and maybe doesn't
lose a man when they do it,
but that 19,
45 us army would defeat easily any army
from the first world war.
Any army from the first world war of the
major powers would easily defeat the
United States in the US civil war and
those civil war armies,
if they went back to waterloo,
you know,
beat Napoleon.
So that's sort of the rule of the law of
technological battlefield development
for the last 200 years.
And that's what the people in this story
have had to try to suck up and
understand.
In 1700 some ruler can decide on a new
musket design and not change it for 100
years.
And he still probably okay.
In the 19th century,
if you miss 15 years of development in
rifle technology,
you might lose a war because of that.
I mean,
think about something like the naval
arms races and how this just destroyed
everybody's treasuries and everything
else,
but at the beginning of the 18 hundreds
you are using ship of the line type
stuff.
I mean,
you know,
the same naval technology of giant
wooden ships with cannons all in the
side that's been the way things had been
done for a couple centuries and when you
build a ship and spend all that money
and all that time,
it's good for a long time.
If it doesn't get destroyed in battle,
that ship conserve you for 20,
30 years and just be fine.
Great investment.
Pay off over time.
If you amortize and call siloed over the
decades,
um,
that goes away at the end of the 19th
century.
And yet
the cost explodes.
You look at a battleship from 1900 and
it doesn't look like anything from
Napoleon's time.
It looked like a thoroughly modern
battleship.
The problem is is technology is changing
so fast now that in the time it takes
you to design that new battleship,
the two or so years it takes to build
and launch and finish it,
it may be outdated by the time it's
ready to be used.
You take a first class,
first rate,
you know,
fleet from a global power in 1914 and
you pitted in battle against a first
rate top of the line fleet from a mere
14 years ago,
and the one from 1914 destroys the one
from 1900 and maybe doesn't lose a major
surface vessel while doing so.
That is mind boggling to the people who
lived back then because that means if
you can't keep up technologically with
what your neighbor is doing at great
expense,
you can negate all the money you spent
on that fleet in the first place.
Better to not have that fleet from 1900.
If you're just gonna lose the whole
thing and not even sink one of your
enemies ships.
The need to keep up with the killing
power of everyone else was impacting the
treasuries of these countries in ways
that created just as big of a threat to
their continued existence as the threat
of all these dangerous armies did.
There was a catch 22 for them.
Take the role that the Russian czar
found himself in in 18,
98,
a guy named Nicholas the second maybe
the single most powerful person on the
planet,
he's got a shaky regime,
is a lot of revolution.
There's a lot of discontent and a lot of
it is exacerbated by the costs of trying
to keep up a modern military and even
with all these costs,
he's falling behind rushes to
illiterate.
It's industries are too small.
It's society still needs so much
modernization before it can keep up with
places like Germany and France and Great
Britain and even the United States.
The problem is is that the czars power
is all in the country's size and the
population and that's becoming less and
less important as technology begins to
determine who wins and who loses
battles,
and that's being demonstrated all
through the 19th century as these small
colonial armies from the technologically
sophisticated powers destroys,
sometimes giant armies of tribal natives
all over the world.
I mean that line,
a famous one that says whatever happens,
we have got the maximum gun and they
have not is about using machine guns on
tribal peoples.
The Russian czar is looking ahead and
seeing that if he can't keep up with
this technological arms race,
that seems to be never ending and
endlessly expensive.
The Russians are just going to be the
new tribal peoples and yet he has to
have this modern military machine
because if his adversaries have it and
he doesn't,
he's going to lose any war he gets into.
He loses his dynasty potentially.
Either way.
How do you get out of a mess like that?
In 18,
98?
The Russians are things he finds a way
and he issues a public invitation to
representatives from the other great
powers who are one degree or another in
the same boat he's into.
No one knows what the next major war
will look like,
but everybody's had a chance to see some
minor wars in the meantime and if you
sort of extrapolate what what they were
telling you,
the next war is going to be horrifying.
And Nicholas,
the second was actually reading the Guy
who turned out to be one of the most
accurate prognosticators of what the
next war was going to be like we talked
about in the last show.
I've been blocked.
Nicholas.
The second is reading Ivan Block and
blocks predictions are horrific.
So the czar wants out.
He wants.
He wants to figure out a way to stop
this dangerous cycle that the modern
world seems to be forcing all the great
powers into.
And I think it's a wonderful sort of
commentary on the attitude of the Times
that these guys thought that they could
do this.
It looks like rainbows and Unicorns to
we modern people,
but to then they must have thought,
reasonable people can sit down over
cigars and whiskey.
See this dynamic that we've got
ourselves caught up in,
realized that it's in no one's interest
in reasonable people can figure a way
out of this,
and in 18,
98,
the czar of Russia proposed something
that will be called The Hague conference
to deal with this.
There are many ways to look at the 18,
Ninety Nine Hague conference and
there'll be another one in 1907 by the
way,
and truthfully it looks like an early
version of arms control agreement.
You will see throughout the 20th
century,
which you can also view through multiple
lenses.
The first one is you can take it at face
value.
The way the czar sold it,
you know,
if you want to use modern terms,
the czars pr people when he issues this
invitation to the rest of the world
leaders,
you know,
couches.
This whole thing as a common sense
effort at a high minded idea.
He says,
the goal of this conference,
he wants to put together as quote,
seeking to make the great idea of
universal peace,
triumph over the elements of trouble and
discord and quote,
we might sell an arms control conference
today like that.
This is the era where you really see for
the first time in human history the
growth of what today we would
call the international peace movement.
It's had many conferences before the
Hague conference to promote these ideas
and there was a general feeling of
progress on these issues and so the czar
may have been playing into that.
Although the tsar was kind of an
interesting dude.
I'm very much a similar role on the
monarchy dice as the Germans got with
Kaiser Wilhelm,
a very mediocre sort of guy,
not the sort of person you could imagine
ever getting this job if it were merit
based.
He's the same czar,
the last czar,
by the way,
who will fall victim and under sort of
the sway of the person that is sometimes
called the mad monk,
Gregory Rasputin.
Although he's more interesting than
that.
It probably deserves more credit than
that,
but it kind of again shows you the Zar
as a kind of an idealistic romantic.
I mean he might have bought into this
stuff.
It might be legitimate on the czar's
part,
but like most arms control agreements,
there's a real politic side to this
thing.
The czar knows that his armies are
falling behind in this technological
race.
The old line about arms control
agreements is if you're losing an arms
race,
it's a good time to have an arms control
agreement and when the powers that are
invited to this Hague conference asked
for clarification of what's on the
agenda,
the tsar and his people give them eight
or nine points that are going to be
goals of the conference and the eight or
nine points to a 21st century mind are
fascinating because it really shows you
what the czar wants to come out of this
conference.
The is number two goal,
for example,
that the agenda gives to the rest of the
participants says quote,
to prohibit the use in the armies and
fleets of any new kinds of firearms,
whatever,
and have new explosives or any powders
more powerful than those.
Now we use either for rifles or Canon
and quote,
now this is a staple to some degree of
arms control agreements ever since.
I mean if the US and the Soviet Union or
having an arms control agreement or an
anti ballistic missile agreement or
whatever,
they may have rules on technological
progress,
but they aren't trying to stop all
technological progress.
What the czar wants to do is freeze
things where they are.
He doesn't want any more research to
increase the killing power that already
exist in militaries.
He doesn't want any more deployment.
If you accidentally discover that new
battleship gun that will shoot twice as
far as your current one,
you can't deploy it.
He wants the size of armies frozen and
then reduced.
He wants the size of military budgets
frozen and then reduced.
This is a person who clearly shows that
his main issue with the way things are
is the pace of change and he wants this
conference to address it now to modern
people who will often freak out if the
promised phone upgrade that's supposed
to be released today is late.
You know the Internet will blow up with
angry people who have had their pace of
change sabotaged.
The people in the late 19th
century can probably be forgiven for
thinking something we will assume is
impossible is possible.
The first time I ever encountered this
idea by the way,
was in James Burke's wonderful TV series
from the 19 eighties of the day.
The universe changed where he asked the
question,
if humankind looks,
you know,
down the road we're a particular branch
of knowledge seems to be taking them.
Can they decide if they don't like the
destination to just not learn that
branch of knowledge at all or to wall it
off so that no one learns it to modern
people.
That sounds impossible to people in the
late 19th century.
They would have been able to show you
multiple historical examples where that
had been done.
The Catholic Church was very good at it
in medieval times.
For example,
there have been Chinese emperors who
could do it well.
Um,
the idea of creating forbidden knowledge
and then preventing people from having
it or using it was not unusual in this
time period.
That's what the czar wants.
He wants to slow or retard the pace of
change and I always try to remind myself
how whipsawed all these people were in
this time period by the pace of change
too.
That's really what the 19th century is
the era where it all speeds up.
If you could,
for example,
graph human technological progress the
way you would a stock market performance
graph starting at the beginning of human
history ending yesterday,
you know,
and having your ups and downs all
throughout history,
you'd noticed a couple of things right
off the bat.
The first thing you notice is that there
are ups and downs.
One thing the modern mind seems to find
incomprehensible is that progress ever
moves backward.
The people who lived in 1900,
for example,
we're reading history books that made
that sound like a historical law of
nature.
They had every reason to believe that
the era they were living in might be the
last of a golden age before a fall,
because after all,
that's what had happened to every other
golden age that they look back on.
The first thing the modern mind sees
when it looks at the historical stock
performance charts showing human
technological progress is that there's a
bunny hop sort of dynamic going on two
steps forward,
one step back.
You might get a big upturn.
You know when the new kingdom Egyptian
come on the scene,
maybe another uptake when the Han
Chinese arrive,
another uptick when the Roman Empire
arrives,
but after your Roman Empire highs,
you get your Roman Empire bubble,
don't ya?
And a couple hundred years later when
it's gone,
you have dramatic barbarians and
formerly Roman territory looking up at
crumbling aqua ducks and wondering what
sort of giants once roamed the earth
that could build stuff like that.
So the first thing you're gonna notice
as a modern person is the technology
doesn't always move forward.
The second thing you're going to notice
is the throughout most of human history,
whether it's going up or going down,
it's moving at a glacially slow pace.
The amount of change from the beginning
of time too about
the renaissance is nowhere near what you
would expect if we were anywhere near
the pace of change.
We have now very little overall growth
until you hit the renaissance and then
you see a little uptick and then the
century after that a little bit more,
and then about 18,
10 slash 1820,
the graph becomes almost vertical
overnight.
It shoots up and instead of ever
plateauing,
as we all know,
it goes ever more vertical every day.
Now we're used to this because it's been
going that way for awhile.
The czars generation.
Yeah,
that century,
that's the first time it really takes
off and those people are looking at that
as an extremely destabilizing force.
The czar thinks perhaps an arms control
agreement will help Russia from falling
too far behind.
They're more technologically
sophisticated neighbors now,
as you might expect,
they're more technologically
sophisticated.
Neighbors see this as an artificial
constraint on the fact that they're
winning.
Take the Germans as a perfect example of
people who are trying very hard to make
up for what they see as the rest of the
power is treating them like dirt.
They're the ones building more ships
than anybody and trying to catch up to
Britain.
They're the ones modernizing their
military every day.
They're the ones who instead of being
panicked by the pace of change or taking
advantage of it to them,
this looks like an agreement that will
lock in their inferiority,
and by the way,
that's a situation that will repeat many
times after this period in arms control
negotiations,
trying to gain an edge on your opponent
if you are losing the arms race,
as I said,
good time to have an arms control
agreement.
Finally,
there's an interesting group of people
and they really don't exist anymore.
Not openly that are on the opposite side
of the ledger from say,
the international peace movement.
That's,
you know,
ramping up during this era.
The people who think that war is a good
thing,
forget about international,
you know,
goals or real politic people that
literally believed that humankind
thrives on war and without war we will
drown in materialism.
It's the only thing that keeps us
focused on the higher things.
That's an idea that has sort of gone by
the wayside in Western culture today.
It's peace activists who argue against,
you know,
real politic people in the 18 eighties
for example,
you have guys like the elder Helmut von
Moltke who tries to explain to people
why peace is not even a good idea.
You're diluted.
He said,
quote,
perpetual peace is a dream and not even
a beautiful dream,
and war is an integral part of God's
ordering of the universe.
In war,
man's noblest.
Virtues come into play.
Courage and renunciation,
fidelity to duty and a readiness for
sacrifice that does not stop at giving
up life itself.
Without war,
the world would be swamped in
materialism and to quote others will
point out that if you decide to try to
make war,
you know a thing of the past.
What happens to all those people that
are in situations where you know they're
struggling against four and oppression,
for example,
you're going to tell someone they can't
free themselves from a oppressor because
you know violence is bad,
but finally you also have the people
that the modern peace activists would
recognize very well.
Those who adhere to a belief system that
is difficult to argue with in terms of
you know historical proof.
You're going to use history as your
guide.
You're going to argue that the best way
to keep the peace is to be so strong
that it is almost suicidal to fight with
you.
Best exemplified perhaps by British
admiral Sir John Fisher,
who tries to explain to a friend of his
that when he sounds horrific,
he's really an advocate of peace and he
said,
quote,
I am not for war.
I am for peace.
That is why I am for Supreme Navy.
Did I not write in your autograph book
at The Hague,
the supremacy of the British navy as the
best security for the peace of the
world?
My sole object is peace.
What you call my truculence is all for
peace if you rub it in both at home and
abroad,
that you are ready for instant war with
every unit of your strength in the first
line and waiting to be first in and hit
your enemy in the belly and kick him
when he's down and boil your prisoners
in oil.
If you take any and torture is women and
children,
then people will steer clear,
review and quote,
well,
as harsh as that is,
it has a certain amount of historical
evidence to back it up,
doesn't it?
When asked how to make war more humane,
the nephew of Helmut von Moltke,
the elder,
that would be Helmut von Moltke,
the younger the field marshal in charge
of Germany's war effort at the start of
the first world war famously said,
the only way to make war humane is to
make it short.
Hence the Schlieffen plan.
We talked about this so called
Schlieffen plan.
In the last episode of it.
It's the almost mythological prewar plan
for how Germany was going to deal with
this terrible to front problem.
My analogy is like a bar fight.
Isn't there a meme online that I saw is
comparing world war one to a bar fight,
but it's a little like,
you know,
Germany knows it's going to have a bar
fight with France and Russia,
but they know that France is going to be
there five minutes before Russia,
so they get to the bar right on time,
knock France out and five minutes later
when Russia shows up late,
they get to fight the Germans
one-on-one.
That's the war plan in a nutshell,
but the questions surrounding this war
plan have become maybe the number one
most controversial issue that historians
argue with each other and froth at the
mouth over and yours truly.
You know,
I don't have a dog in this fight.
I'm just gonna sit back,
eat popcorn and watch the very
entertaining discussions on the
Schlieffen so called Schlieffen plan
because it's not just a this or that.
It's like a Kennedy assassination thing
where,
I mean every different theory you can
think of is out there.
There was a Schlieffen plan.
No,
there wasn't.
The schlieffen plan wasn't even planned,
but
it was modified.
It was modified by Mocha.
Then why not call it the Schlieffen
plan?
I may just goes on and on and on,
and the people often on multiple sides
of this issue are very credible,
so I'm not getting.
It's like trying to weigh in on a
discussion with scientists.
You just have to sort of watch
sometimes,
so I'm not going to take a position on
this so culturally even plan,
and we'll call it the Schlieffen plan
because that's what everybody knows it
by them,
but suffice it to say this shall Ethan's
retired for quite a long time before the
first world war breaks out.
So whatever plan the Germans were going
to use are in the hands of Helmut von
Moltke.
The younger,
the guy who's leading this whole,
you know,
early war on the Germans part and he's
been the one designing this plan for a
long time.
After the first world war is over,
you will get a bunch of German generals
writing memoirs,
sort of castigating this multiple guy
for deviating from Schlieffen is
amazingly brilliant.
Plan is the way it was pronounced if
you'd just stayed with the plan that
way.
It was supposed to be,
you know,
we win the war and so it's worth talking
about the plan a little bit from a
military history standpoint,
the sleep and plan,
and again I have to say as it's normally
understood because somebody out there's
going to have a very good piece of
evidence showing it was totally
different than I'm saying right now,
but as it's as it's commonly understood,
the Schlieffen plan is a fantastic
military gamble.
It involves taking troops from basically
everywhere else.
You might have to fight and taking as
many of them as you can and sticking
them on that one part.
That's going to be the sledge hammer.
The head of the sledgehammer and your
superiority in numbers at the head of
that sledge hammer is going to be so
overwhelming.
It's going to crush everything and then
you can swing it around and trap all the
French armies that are sitting on the
French border.
You know,
waiting to fight the Germans on the
other side of the German border.
But the head of the hammer's coming
through Belgium,
a neutral country.
It's going to swing from above and then
it's going to collapse down on all those
French armies facing the Germans and
trap them in the rear,
but it's a huge gamble.
What if you screw up?
What if the Russians mobilized faster
than you think they're going to?
Well,
they'll be mowing down your tiny little
forces left there to stop them and
they're not that far from Berlin and the
first territory they're gonna take over,
happens to be the ancestral home of
Prussian nobility,
including Kaiser Wilhelm,
so nobody wants to see the Russians
anywhere near Prussia,
but they happened to be kind of near
Prussia anyway,
so that's a problem.
Also,
everyone knows the French are going to
want to retake those territories that
the Germans took a generation before
which is down at the Franco German
border,
which means the French are gonna attack
there with a lot of forces.
You pull too many people away from
there.
The French could be breaking through
into southern Germany while the head of
your sledge hammers still working its
way around French flags.
I mean it's,
it's a.
it's a terrible gamble because if you
screw it up,
you could lose the war,
but let's remember things when she in
is writing the war plan and he
supposedly came up with this idea.
The conditions are different.
The German army is different in size,
so was the French army.
The Russians have almost seen a complete
collapse in 19.
Oh,
five of their whole dynasty mean they're
falling apart.
They just lost a war against Japan.
There are no where near as formidable as
they'll be,
you know,
10 years later,
right?
Nine years later.
But that's when von Moltke has to deal
with things and the situations are
different and he has to recalculate
things and the second part of that whole
equation is sleeping and could afford to
be a gambler because he doesn't actually
have to do it.
Schlieffen is a gambler on paper.
Mulch is a guy who has to make this work
in real time and not have the downside
happen and live through it and he's more
of a pessimist maybe you would say more
of a realist and he won't put as many
troops in the sledge hammer.
Part of the attack as Schlieffen would
have dictated you should,
he won't denude the other fronts too,
is greater degree and leave them that
wide open.
He can't assume that the war will be
one,
so automatically that you can just know
that Germany will be safe and won't be
broken through in all these areas you've
denuded,
in other words,
mold because a more conservative guy.
But if this plan is true,
I'm going to keep saying that
disclaimer,
so don't get in trouble.
If this plan is true,
um,
it puts Mocha in a position of accepting
a gamble of a plan for a guy who's not a
gambler,
but that's the plan.
And in order to understand the sledge
hammer side of this plan,
you have to have some sort of conception
of the size of the army's involved for
comparison purposes.
And again,
it sort of demonstrates how much things
have changed in a military sense and how
they've exploded since napoleonic times.
If you look at assumptions made by
people who study the Roman Empire,
one of the favorite subjects that they
will debate is how many human beings
were in the military of the Roman Empire
at its height to police and take care of
that massive ancient state,
and I don't mean in any one battle.
I mean the total military power of the
Roman Empire at its height,
and you will get numbers anywhere from
450,000
men at the low end and about 750,000
men at the higher end.
Now the numbers of Germans that are
making their way through Belgium in
August 1914 as part of the sledge
hammers head is at least 750,000.
Some numbers put that up to a one point
$2 million.
That means that the flanking force,
the head of the sledgehammers,
we keep calling it.
That's moving through Belgium to smack
the French like a door.
Swinging on a hinge is at least as large
as the entire military of the Roman
empire at its.
And if those lower numbers are actually
closer to the truth for the empires
total military capability,
than you might have a German army moving
through Belgium that's twice the size of
the entire Roman empire at its height,
that totally justifies all of the worst
fears of these people in the 19th
century.
Worried about this,
to kind of folks who would call a Hague
conference and and write about peace and
all that kind of stuff.
And the people who understood what the
growth in the military technology was
going to do.
I haven't blocks ideas are about to be
proven true in no uncertain fashion.
I mean these people were used to
Napoleon,
well,
Napoleon's in a giant gamble of invading
Russia may have had at its highest
750,000
men across the entire front from a giant
front of Russia.
That's what you have moving through the
tiny little road system and railroad
system of Belgium.
Napoleon's grand army is your flanking
force.
Wow.
No,
I keep trying to remind myself that what
the Germans are trying to do here is not
perhaps as much of a of a weird gamble
as you might think,
and we also need to remember that most
of the people in the higher leadership
positions in the German military have
done all this before.
In fact,
they fought France before.
It's probably the most important war
that happened between Napoleon's times
and the first world war and most people
outside of Europe.
No,
nothing about the Franco Prussian war of
18,
78 slash 71,
but essentially forget what it says,
you know,
in the history books because it makes it
look like a nine month war.
Essentially.
The Germans smash the French in a month
and a half.
It's a fantastically interesting
conflict and it's shaped the perceptions
and views of these people in the higher
leadership positions because they were
junior officers who fought in that war.
Right?
They watched two amazing things happen.
They watched the German army's trap and
entire French army of like 80,
90,000
men in one of the French fortresses that
was there to,
you know,
keep the Germans from crossing the
border.
And then the actual emperor Franz
himself,
a guy named Napoleon,
the third,
another one of those interesting roles
of the monarchy dies,
leads a relief army.
He's going to break the seeds,
right and rescue his other army of
another 80 or 90,000
guys and the Germans manage to surround
the whole army with the emperor and
forced them to surrender,
which then of course means that entire
army that's also trapped nearby has to
surrender to,
I mean the French fault on for a long
time doggedly,
um,
the,
the people of Paris rose up.
I mean,
there was a fantastic resistance after
this,
but the war was over in a month and a
half.
That was the way the Germans wanted to
do it again.
This time.
And the people who did it last time are
the ones in command of a lot of these
cores and armies.
And in the general staff
now,
as the Germans try to make their way
through Belgium and not this important
time schedule screwed up,
the French on the other side are trying
to figure out what the heck's going on.
Part of what we modern people have to
remember and I always try to try to put
myself in their position very hard
because when we're in an era where the
battlefield,
especially to western powers and most
especially to the United States,
the battlefield is totally visible for
the most part.
You can hide yourself and foliage
sometimes.
Maybe we're nearby.
We're going to have know thermal sensors
and stuff,
but the battlefield is visible to us now
and we're used to this in most of human
history.
The fog of war as it's known,
is huge because it keeps you from seeing
what's about to happen until it just is
about to happen.
You don't get a lot of advanced notice
to plan.
That's why aircraft start becoming
really important because they take the
eyes of the military,
put them up in the air and extreme
extend how far back you can see if you
see armies moving to another area,
you can safely assume,
oh,
I better move my arm,
you to another area.
Something's going to happen over there
during this early part of the battle.
No one is sure what's happening on the
allied side,
the French or is worried about how they
get the British over here to fight with
as many men as they can bring over as
they are about where the Germans come in
and,
and in what sort of strength you see the
French have suspected for a very long
time that the Germans were going to do
this outflanking move in Belgium that
was not totally unexpected.
The part that may have caught them off
guard is what they were out flanking.
You know,
the French through Belgium with the guys
running the French military at this
time,
working on their own war plans.
Assumptions simply won't believe that
the size moving through Belgium is as
big as it is.
And let's remember,
mold guy will be criticized after the
war by other German generals who are
mad.
It's not bigger.
I mean,
and the,
the French have huge problems here
because they have one of the loosest
agreements I've ever run into in my life
for,
you know,
military cooperation there,
battle plans call for the British army
to guard their entire lines.
And when we talk about a line,
the French military line runs from
Switzerland in the south to Belgium,
in the north,
millions of men in multiple armies.
And by the way,
on the other side of the border,
the Germans had the same thing,
first time in human history that you've
had millions of men squaring off against
millions of men,
but the French left flank is counting on
having the British army there to anchor
it.
That agreement has less paperwork
attached to it than you would normally
generate when you buy a house.
For all intents and purposes,
as we said,
it's a handshake deal,
a handshake deal that we will go to war
with you.
If war breaks out and a handshake deal
with only one government in a country
where governments can come and go and
we're public opinion isn't unified and a
nation that you've had
centuries of antagonistic history with
and only like five or eight years of,
you know,
friendly cooperation,
what's more when Britain gets into this
war and then the first thing that the
British people here is we're going to
send the troops that would defend us if
the Germans decided to land on our
coastline to France.
There's a lot of questions over how many
troops despair.
Eventually the BDF we'll get to France
with 70,000
men,
five divisions for infantry.
One cavalry to give you an idea of what
70,000
men are.
Five divisions means on this front,
the Germans are deploying like 85
divisions on the western front.
70,000
men seems like nothing.
That's the tiny little,
you know,
it's the army of a sea power,
isn't it?
That's the tiny little force that
bismarck.
A generation before that iron and blood
German diplomat had famously said,
when one of his aids said,
what if the British land,
their army on our coast,
he says that,
then I'll have them arrested.
This is the army that was so small you
could joke about arresting them,
but here's the difference.
Unlike all the other major armies of the
participants in this war,
the British army or professional long
standing regular force with a lot of
people in the specialty,
the noncommissioned officer ranks who
were lifers and who when this war
started immediately called up there
reservists guys who served 10,
15,
20 years before and had fought in places
like South Africa and the Boer War and
the turn of the century.
The institutional memory of these units
was deep.
The quality of these forces was intense.
They used to have,
you know,
unlimited marksman practice and get
financial rewards for winning it.
They'd actually,
you know,
a lot of the people in these units
fought in actual combat with modern
weapons.
My favorite source from this early
period is an Irishman.
You know,
as you might imagine,
a WHO's actually fighting in the BDF,
his name is John Lucy,
and he's one of the few British side
reporters,
I guess you could call him,
but he's a soldier who writes from this
very early period because he was right
in the first wave and he explains,
you know,
the difference between his unit and the
rest of the continental troops and he
does so in a very chauvinist stick,
a very proud fashion,
but he claims quote,
the British army in 1914 was more used
to battle than that of any other nation.
It possessed the highest and bravest
traditions that can be engendered in a
fighting force and its experience of
wars was such that our own regiment
though a young one in the army,
had so many battle honors that they were
difficult to memorize and quote.
Now John Lewis is only 20.
He doesn't have a long service history
under his belt,
but when the reservists arrive,
he watches men who appear to be just
regular folks off the street,
transformed themselves into grizzled
British veterans.
Quote
are reservists came streaming into
makeup,
our war strength,
cheerful careless fellows of all types,
some in bowler hats and smart suiting
things,
others in descending scale down to the
garb of tramps soon like us.
They were uniformed and equipped with
field kits,
and the change was remarkable.
Smart Sergeants and corporals and beer
ribbon veterans of the South African war
hatched out of that crowd of nondescript
civilians and took their place in duties
as if they had never left the army.
They were an excellent lot,
but their numbers increased our strength
to an uncomfortable extent and quote
what John Lucy found to be an
uncomfortable increasing of numbers when
they arrived at the continent.
Seemed like a tiny little trickle of
British soldiers,
but the quality of this army that came
to be known as the old contemptible was
of the highest level matching the top
German units.
It was ironically under the command of a
British general name,
French,
who didn't very much like the French Sir
John French will lead the B,
e,
f the British expeditionary force onto
the continent just in time to play their
historic role in what Sir Arthur Conan
doyle called the most terrible August in
the history of the world.
There'll be involved in several battles
that are all called the battle of the
frontiers.
There's a bunch of little battles that
are all sort of wrapped up into this one
big event called the battle of the
frontiers.
What it really means is,
is all the fighting that was going on
along this front,
and there are several sort of thrusts
and Perry's encounter thrust that go on.
I'm going to spend a little bit more
time than I normally plan to for the
rest of this series on this battle
because this,
this battle of the frontiers is in so
many ways the most interesting moment of
this war.
First of all,
it's what we've talked about for an
episode and a half.
Now.
It's the rubber meets the road moment,
the testing moment for all this military
theory and hypothesis that's been
happening in some cases,
you know,
for the last hundred years,
you get to see if people's assumptions
about how this weapon system would work
or that tactic would fare.
You get to see which of those turn out
to be correct and which ones don't,
and a lot of the time these armies will
go into combat hamstrung by decisions
that were made a decade before in terms
of what the army's doctrine's going to
be or the tactics or how they're going
to be.
You know,
dressed and equipped.
I mean,
take the French.
The French will go
into this modern war and it is almost
impossible to understand this today
because there's a ludicrousness to it
that shows off another century.
You want to see the 19th century clash
with the 20th century.
It happens in this battle of the
frontiers.
In August 19,
14,
the French go into combat with almost
the exact same uniform.
Their grandfathers war in 1870,
a blue jacket with tails wide red pants
that look like targets and acted like it
to their officers would have white hats
and white gloves.
I mean again,
targets.
They will send cavalry to go fight that
look like.
I mean you can go look at your history
books in 1914 and they often have
pictures of this cavalry.
I told my friend who was always asking
for,
you know,
I would love to see a picture of
Napoleon's queer sears.
You know,
his famous cavalry with the breast
plates in the horse hair,
plumed helmets,
you know,
when the sabres and the whole thing.
And I said,
you don't have to wish for a picture of
Napoleon's queers ears.
They're going off to war in 1914.
They look identical armor and all.
That's the old world going off to war.
And you can see it visually.
Think of how the French soldiers
hamstrung by that.
The British had been using khaki,
you know,
for themselves since the colonial wars
in the 18 eighties.
The French are going to go into this war
looking like walking.
Peacocks and a ton of French soldiers
will pay the price for that.
They'll pay the price for not having
much in the way of heavy artillery to.
Again,
these were all ideas that you could
logically back up.
The French decided they wanted to have
more mobile army,
so we don't need that big,
heavy,
cumbersome,
slow artillery to slow us down.
By the time that gets anywhere,
the battle's going to be over anyway.
Sounds great.
In theory,
until you try it and you find out your
soldiers are in terrible trouble on the
actual battlefields because they don't
have any heavy artillery.
There's a reputation.
The French have militarily in the United
States that is in ordinance influenced
by the way the Second World War went.
I always try to tell people,
you misunderstand Francis military
reputation then because for hundreds of
years they're considered one of the
finest,
if not the finest land army in the world
100 years before this time,
a little coarser can guy is using,
you know,
especially as the hardcore of his armies
to conquer the majority of the world
that mattered at this time and the one
that owned the rest of the majority of
the world is colonies and did it with
French troops.
They will often heroically throw their
lives down to try to overcome these
deficiencies that they enter war width.
I think you could make a case that in
all three wars,
that over 75 years,
the French and Germans fought with each
other from 1870 to 1945,
that the average French soldier on the
ground was hamstrung by his leadership
in all three of those conflicts in the
Second World War.
I mean historically,
tragically,
but I would suggest that the war out of
those three in which French leadership
performed the best was in the first
world war.
There are a bunch of different generals
that I think Second World War France
would have given their right arm to
have,
um,
led by a guy who is iconic.
I've always thought of him as like the
French Churchill,
you know,
what Churchill was to Britain in the
Second World War.
This guy is to France in the first world
war and he has all these same
stereotypically interesting anecdotes
and characteristics that Churchill had.
But instead of them being
stereotypically British as Churchill's
were their stereotypical Golic,
they're French.
You know,
Churchill had this thing with alcohol
that was part of his image and part of
the fun with this guy.
It's food and that's because it fits
perfectly with his physical sort of
image.
He's huge in every way.
He's tall,
he's fat.
He's got a giant,
bushy white mustache and a placid look
on his face all the time.
His name is Joseph.
That,
and if I mispronounced that again,
that's just going to be the first of
many,
my apologies because he still,
you know,
the lion of France in a lot of French
households.
He's a fabulously interesting guy.
But you know,
I've read a significant amount on this
person and I'm not sure I understand him
any better than before I started.
And what's more,
I'm not sure these authors did either.
He is like an obelisk and he is
imperturbably.
Good luck scratching the surface of
figuring out what you have there.
And even his contemporaries felt that
way.
One thing when you read quotes that
people who knew him say about him is
one,
they,
they say different things sometimes and
to sometimes they didn't know what this
guy was up to.
I mean,
you know,
sometimes you look at something and you
wonder if he's just a little doll or
slow or receive,
you know,
sly like a Fox and just hiding
everything.
I mean it's,
it's,
he's an interesting guy.
You could probe this guy a long time and
still not really get a good idea about
what you're dealing with here.
The one thing you can say about him is
he,
he's got one of those qualities of
generalship that's just going to be a
perfect match for what's needed at the
time.
And I've always said that you general
generalship is absolutely an art and in
the same way that art,
you know,
sees the manifestation of the artist's
personality sort of translated in its
own unique way in the art form.
Generalship is like that too.
You can see all these different kinds of
generals who all have these different
kinds of personalities and they command
that way.
And the key is to try to find your
strengths and then you know,
figuring out a way to make those
strengths work for you on a battlefield.
Take for example,
these really aggressive commanders,
these quick thinking,
hard pushing,
dashing sort of guys.
Hind Scuderia in the famous guy who
basically created the German tank
approach in the World War.
He was that kind of guy.
The Guy,
by the way,
who's commanding the most important army
on the German side in this war,
the Sledge Hammer,
head army first army's a guy just like
this too hard driving,
aggressive kind of guy.
That sort of approach is perfect in some
situations and in some armies.
But then you need the bean counter guy
sometimes too.
That's what von Moltke is.
He's a bean counter.
He sits there and and plans everything
out to the nth degree and make sure all
the t's are crossed and the i's dotted
and you don't have anything,
and those guys are very useful to the
inspirational general,
like an Alexander the great who get out
there and get your troops to perform
feats of heroism that may be a lesser
man or a woman couldn't have gotten them
to perform this.
There's all these different kinds of
generals.
Jennifer is the kind that doesn't ever
get ruffled.
That's what he brings to the table.
He refuses to panic.
He's almost frightfully calm in
situations that he's about to experience
that,
that are not only stressful to the point
of panic,
but the perhaps panic is the right
emotion to have.
Now,
there are historians out there who
suggested that we should not look at
that as such a great quality to bring to
the table because it might be Jennifer's
own shortcomings in some of the other
arts of generalship that made it
necessary for there to be a guy who
wouldn't panic at the top to begin with.
Wouldn't be needing to panic if you'd
have been a better player of that blind
chess game that we talked about earlier
and maybe offer is not that good at that
game.
Hence the situation becomes panic
inducing.
Hence a leader that's very good at
stopping.
Panic is just what you need at the time
anyway,
might be a self reinforcing sort of
thing,
but I think it's hard to deny that
France would have given up a right arm
and both legs to have this guy in the
second world war and the reason that
this guy is going to be so necessary
this imperturbability is going to be so
necessary is because of how this first
round in this heavyweight championship
fight that's gonna go on for four years
is going to go.
And if you're going to use a boxing
analogy here for this,
this is gonna be a boring fight.
As the fight goes on,
you know,
we're things slow down to a dull roar
and everybody's looking for tactical
opportunities and,
and but the first round is wild.
Massive haymakers swings.
Mrs.
dropping the other guy for,
you know,
an eight count.
I mean,
it's going to be a wild first round and
if you lose your head you could lose the
war.
So having Jennifer at the,
at the French high command shows that
the French are not going to lose their
head.
I can't help but think about the German
commander at this point though.
Von Moltke [inaudible] a very
interesting guy in the sense that he
almost looks like a guy who doesn't want
to be there.
You know,
he is the nephew of one of the greatest
heroes in German military history.
It's almost like he went into the family
business,
but whereas those guys thought about
nothing but war all the time.
And remember Schlieffen,
the legendary writer of the Schlieffen
plan is supposed to have died.
Still saying stuff about the Schlieffen
plan.
The last words on his lips are
supposedly make sure to keep the right
wing strong.
I mean,
these are people who have no hobbies
other than war von Moltke.
The younger is a guy who famously said
that art was what he lived for,
and I think about this guy in the most,
one of the most stressful positions in
all history.
Once this war breaks out,
remember he has no illusions about what
the stakes are.
He's the one who famously said that the
war that he's launching will decide the
course of history for the next hundred
years,
and it certainly has.
Think of the pressure on that though.
Think about the fact that his plan that
he's operating with is a terrible
gamble.
And then watch how every flip of the
coin so far in this conflict has gone
against him.
I mean,
if you're judging this fight based on
who landed the latest punch,
von Moltke and the Germans are losing
right from the very beginning when
thinking about the Conan flips that have
already happened.
I mean,
think about the Belgium one to begin
with.
I mean,
you were hoping that when you invaded
Belgium,
they just sort of stood by the side of
the road and let you go through.
Maybe it would feed you and everything,
right?
You would.
That's what your hope was.
It could have been a flip of the coin.
Instead,
the Belgians resisted you.
They destroyed the communication and
transportation system you were hoping to
use and then to make matters worse,
some of them were shooting at you,
allegedly,
so your troops had been executing
Belgians,
which makes you look terrible on the
world stage.
So that coin flipped the wrong way.
And then you flip the coin again.
Maybe Britain won't get involved when we
violate,
you know,
the neutrality of Belgium,
right?
It's just a scrap of paper.
As the German diplomat,
famous Luke said,
oh,
that landed on the wrong side of the
coin to the British came in and you lost
that flip.
Another flip happens starting on August
15th and the timetables going to get
weird now because there's stuff
happening on multiple fronts that
overlap with each other because while
this is going on,
you know,
the first maneuvers are going on in the
West do,
but,
but on the 15th of August,
if you're on multiple watching how your
planned attack is,
is going,
and you haven't even gotten your sledge
hammer head through Belgium yet.
So you're still a ways away from your
attack doing anything,
but you've got things starting to
collapse around you.
On August 15th,
the Serbs remembered this as a moderate
country fighting a great power.
You know,
some Serbian gunman killed the Austrian
archduke and that's why we're here,
right?
I mean,
the one thing everyone was sure about is
that no matter what happens in this
conflict,
Serbia is going to get their butt kicked
because they're fighting Austria,
Hungary,
who is right next door,
and they're a global power.
The austro-hungarian are camped out sort
of on a hillside by a river on the 15th
of August.
One hundred and 80,000
serves.
Attack them.
The Austria.
Hungarian army has about 200,000
people and it,
it's morale just collapses.
And we told you before,
the Serbs are one of those people
historically who in the military sense
kind of punch above their weight class.
They're ferocious fighters.
They were aggressive,
aggressively lead.
And the Austro-hungarian forces were
apparently more riddled with problems
than anyone knew.
And a lot of them will drown routing
across this river,
um,
pursued closely by 180,000
Serbians in three armies.
Think about what this does if you're von
Moltke in terms of stress,
because you're hoping that the ostrow
Hungarians can help you keep the
Russians off your neck until you're done
in France.
Remember,
you've got to deal with enemies on each
side here.
You're hoping your ally right there is
going to be able to help.
And yet they just got their tailed
kicked by a moderate size power.
What's going to happen when they face
the Russians?
And then on the 17th of August,
the biggest disaster at all,
if you're von Moltke occurs and the
Russians arrive early,
talk about flipping the coin before the
war,
assuming you can get all this stuff done
before the Russians mobilized and then
they mobilize early.
So by August 17th,
von [inaudible] has problems everywhere
and,
and it becomes a real question whether
or not he's ever going to be able to use
his war winning sledge hammer because
maybe he'll have lost the war everywhere
else before that even happens.
I mean,
there's writings you can,
you can read from this time period in
1914.
They think that the war is almost
already over.
Meanwhile,
on the 14th of August,
Jennifer and the French launch and
attack into Alsace Lorraine,
the first real attack I should say,
they,
they sent it token force in there on the
seventh of August.
Um,
which is,
you know,
you gotta remember seventh of August is
four days after France and Germany
declared war on each other.
They send a token force in there,
you know,
with messages from the French leadership
about,
you know,
here we're home.
You're back in the bosom of France.
All these wonderful things,
kisses,
picnic baskets,
flowers,
wine,
the whole deal,
you know,
welcomed with open arms.
And then all of a sudden that little
token for us with the roses and wine and
everything has to run back across the
French border because the German force
that's nearby is not a token force.
So on August 14th,
the day before the Serbs smash that
Austro-hungarian Army,
um,
that so discomforts,
von Moltke,
the French,
launched two armies into Alsace
Lorraine.
And it's serious now.
Now it's on,
now we have to have the best armies in
the world clashing head on with
significant numbers of people and the
French push the Germans back
and then the next day they push them
back again and then the next day they
push them back again.
Now it should be noted that while the
rest of the world thinks,
this looks like just one more disaster
for Germany side and you have all these
other problems,
the Russians are already in east Prussia
and now look at the French.
The first time they launch a significant
attack.
The Germans are backing up,
but that's one thing I'm sure von Moltke
wasn't stressed about because that
retreat by the Germans was all part of
the plan.
The Germans of course,
for decades knew that the French would
involve Alsace.
Lorraine in any war effort,
and so they put troops there who had
orders to retire to just sort of keep
the French engaged,
but move backwards as they move forward.
Let them even into Germany,
shoot them as they're pursuing you.
Take your toll on them as they're
pursuing you,
but retire in good order.
Take your guns with you and just sort of
pull them away from all the parts of the
war that matter.
You see when the French figure out about
this sledgehammer.
I've also compared it to a door on a
hinge because you have all these German
armies stretching from the Swiss border
all the way up to Belgium and most of
them are just there to keep the French
occupied.
The damage that's going to be done.
It's going to be done by that door sort
of in Belgium and Luxembourg that swings
closed on top of the French nation.
The other German army's job is to keep
the French in front of them occupied so
they can't turn around and move in a
different direction and do anything
about that hammer and those French
army's way down south in Alsace and
Lorraine,
which are down by the Swiss border that
are,
you know,
pursuing German armies back into the
interior of Germany are just getting
farther and farther away from where they
can help.
Once the French realize they need every
army they can get their hands on to deal
with that threat.
So fond [inaudible] not upset about
this.
This is part of the deal and that starts
on August 14th,
15th,
16th,
17th.
That continues there.
The Russians are in east Prussia now.
The Austrians have been defeated on
their front since the seventh of August,
but really big on the 11th and twelfth
of August.
The British Expeditionary Force has been
arriving on the continent and they keep
saying they're not going to be ready to
fight until maybe the 26th of August,
but the French would like them there
sooner.
One Frenchmen in particular is desperate
to have the British show up as early as
possible.
This is the French general who was
commanding the army on Francis left
flank,
right?
The last army,
you know,
so it's kind of facing.
So to Belgium,
where if you look to your right,
they've got several armies,
millions of men all the way down to the
Swiss border,
totally protected from anybody
penetrating our ranks and hitting us in
the flank.
But if that fifth army under a general
name,
Lynn Rasic looks to the left,
looks north,
there's nobody there.
There's open land,
there's maneuvering room for an enemy to
get around his flanks and destroy him
and roll the whole French line up all
the way down to Switzerland if
necessary,
so he's got a vested interest in being
aware of any potential threats out there
because he's going to take it in the
flank,
you know,
when,
when it shows up and he perceives even
before the war starts,
he's sending messages in July to
Jennifer saying going all signs point to
a German advanced through Belgium
basically,
which is one reason you knew the high
command knew about it.
They just,
nobody knew how big it was going to be,
but this general and resit keeps telling
them every couple of days he's sending
messages to the high command going,
you know,
latest reports are or you know,
huge attack.
I mean he basically,
the Way History will vindicate this guy,
is he correctly perceived the power and
destination of this German blow long
before anyone else does and one of the
historical what ifs in this time period
is what if Jennifer had taken what he
was saying?
Seriously,
sooner again,
maybe you don't need to be such a
wonderful,
um,
stability factor when panic is all
around you if you don't make a mistake
like not listening to this general in
which creates the panic inducing
situation to begin with.
Gioffre basically thinks the guy's
panicking and then he starts saying,
you know,
as it becomes apparent that something is
moving through Belgium and those forts
are going down,
he starts thinking this is going to be a
good thing for the same reason.
It's a good thing for the Germans to
have those French go through Alsace
Lorraine and keep advancing away from
where the action's going to be.
A offers ideas.
Listen,
even if the Germans are going through
Belgium with a large force,
all the better.
Our plans going to be to cut that large
force off.
If this is a swinging gate or door,
we will hit it at the hinge and then we
will roll up behind it all the way up to
the water,
you know,
in the,
in the North Sea or the English Channel
right there.
And then your cutoff.
And then this wonderful sledge hammer
blow becomes a surrounded,
trapped cream of your army.
So he turned a negative into a positive
and basically would tell len rasic that
you have nothing to worry about.
One resnick thought different and
figured his chances would be improved if
that British force would hurry up and
come up on his left so that even though
the British might have an open left
flank,
he wouldn't have one anymore.
And it's at that point that the battle
of the frontiers breaks out.
Now the battle of the frontiers is named
that because it's the time where the
general eruption of violence,
um,
on the Franco German border happens.
And there are a lot of different
encounters that are all a part of this
larger conflict essentially though is an
umbrella term that covers all the
violence on the Franco German border.
That breaks out almost simultaneously.
And it turns out to be a really
important thing for the German war
effort that it did.
Because,
you know,
by about August 19th,
the German situation really is bad as we
said earlier.
But things I've even gotten worse.
Those Russians in East Prussia that had
shown up sooner than expected had
defeated some German forces that went
out and tried to deal with them.
All of a sudden it looks like that flank
might be collapsing.
It's hard to get really excited about
anything if you're Molko whose nickname
you know,
given to him by the Kaiser was something
that translates loosely,
too gloomy.
Gus.
Anyway,
not exactly an optimist.
he couldn't have been feeling too good
about the situation.
On the 19th or 20th,
he receives a request from one of his
generals in the field.
It's the guy who is retreating from all
those French forces,
retiring in good order,
taking his guns with them and sort of
drawing them away from the action.
He's one of the wonderful German royalty
that's part of this.
This isn't in the Wehrmacht.
In the Second World War,
you didn't have any of this and this
first where you have all these guys like
Prince Rupert,
prick of Bavaria,
and he commands the forest that's
retreating.
He doesn't like retreating.
You know,
you don't get a lot of metals for
retreating.
It's not exactly what he was hoping to
do with an army in this war,
so we requests to von Moltke can I
attack now?
This goes against the idea of what he
supposed to do,
right?
He's the retreat or he pulls his French
force away from where the hammer is
going to hit,
but he makes a pretty good case.
These French are asking for it.
They're sitting ducks.
They have been sort of like getting more
and more disordered and strung out after
days of pursuing us and we'd been
shooting them with artillery and
weakening them.
They are ripe for a counter attack,
will crush them,
and this is one of several incidents
that will happen literally in the next
few days that some historians have
pointed to for years as the moment when
the Germans lost the war.
In this case,
some historians say that mold because
responds to Crown Prince Rubric Dot
Riveria last him the war.
He told group raked that he could
counter attack.
The French were strung out and
disorganized and asking for it,
and on August 20th he does.
He crushes them.
Now,
this is the time where you get to see
perhaps from a soldier's perspective,
the thing that had changed battle and
warfare the most really coming into its
own machine guns made a huge difference.
Make no mistake about it,
and there were a lot of things that seem
relatively benign when you look at them
that made huge differences too,
like barbed wire,
but the element that technology in land
warfare had altered the most in terms of
something that would change the face of
warfare and how it was fought and
experienced by human beings on the
ground.
Artillery had come leaps and bounds
beyond anything anyone had expected and
it's artillery that on August 20th hits
the French when they're still in tight
columns marching and mustering and just
sitting around.
I mean later in the war,
Ernst,
young or German soldier will write about
the effect on a shell.
One single artillery shell landing in a
group of people that were just,
you know,
sitting around a town square 150 of his
soldier comrades.
And he said,
the one shell killed 70 of them
outright.
Now imagine if you're in March column or
if you're gathered around a a mess,
a senator or a taking a religious
service in,
in the field or whatever when you're
closely matched with your buddies and
then modern artillery hits you and
remember part of this is the technology
of the guns.
The other part of it is the science and
engineering that goes into,
you know,
making artillery effective,
not just shooting the gun up in the air,
but you should see the,
the scientific calculations,
these soldiers on the ground,
so the mathematics they had to do to
make sure that everything was honed in
the right way and everything and that
really differentiated by the way the
good armies from the less good armies.
The Russians had a ton of artillery.
They didn't have good engineering people
shooting it,
so it was often inaccurate and not
effective.
The British and the French and the
Germans had exceptional people working
their artillery and it was very
effective and the German artillery was
bigger and better than anything that the
French had.
This is where they find out that that
idea of that light mobile,
75 millimeter artillery getting the job
done in every situation was horribly
flawed.
In fact,
it was outraged by the German pieces.
The Germans could hit it when they
couldn't hit the Germans.
When the German army under Crown Prince
Rupert hits the French in a counter
attack on August 20th,
the artillery just devastates them.
As historian Eric burroughs writes,
quote,
the first furious fighting occurred in
southern Lorraine were the French second
army having progressed 35 kilometers was
hit at Marangu by the German army,
the counterattack with superior
artillery fire from 105 millimeter and
150 millimeter howitzers.
The barrage crushed second army
formations that we're assembling in
tight ranks for the day is March,
forcing it to flee and thereby
compelling and exposed first army to
retreat as well.
End Quote.
Now what Bros is talking about there is
that when the Germans crushed the French
second army and it has to retreat,
it creates a hole in the line and that's
the most dangerous thing for any of
these armies.
They want to main maintain an unbroken
line because if there are places that
can be penetrated by enemy forces,
those forces can move into those gaps
and then if they turn right or turn
left,
they're hitting another army in the
flank where it's terribly vulnerable or
they could continue to go deeper into
the interior and strike at logistics and
supply and rear areas.
I mean the whole point is don't allow
you know,
a gap to open up in your line and do
whatever you can to create or exploit,
you know,
your enemy doing something like that
with their forces.
So when second army gets smashed and has
to retreat backwards,
first army has to go with them just to
make sure that the line stays unbroken
and nobody can get into our interior.
Now there's a lot of different things
you might be able to draw a conclusion
wise from what happened,
you know,
in Alsace and lorraine were those two
armies were hit by the Germans.
Gioffre decided that this allowed him to
see where the Germans were weak.
As we mentioned earlier,
this is about playing chess without
knowing,
you know,
where the other guys pieces are.
Part of what [inaudible] offers got to
do as a commander is some detective
work.
He has a rough idea how many forces the
Germans have.
If he can identify,
you know,
where those forces are,
he can start to figure out where the
rest are.
He figures if he's getting so hammered
down in the south on August 20th,
and if he believes that general on his
flank,
the fifth army general that keeps
telling him the Germans are making a
major effort through Belgium,
where are all those troops coming from?
They have to be pulled from somewhere.
You offer.
Figured the Germans are weak.
At that point he decided that they had
been pulled from the German center,
so there's strong down in Alsace.
Lorraine by Switzerland.
They're strong up in Belgium where
they've knocked down those sports in
there.
They're coming at us like a door on a
hinge,
so they're weak in the middle.
Shot for made a major mistake here and
the major mistake was assuming the
Germans would treat their reserve forces
the same way the French did,
the reserve forces are those forces that
are not as competent,
not as highly trained as the regular
military forces and the French practice
with those forces was to keep them in
the reserve,
you know,
keep them back away from the action,
use them to support people when you need
more troops thrown in,
but don't put them anywhere vulnerable
where you could lose the war with
inexperienced,
you know,
not up to standard troops like that.
The Germans totally integrated their
reserves into their armies and it
planned for this for a long time.
They were using all their reserves so
they had greater numbers actually
involved in all these combats.
Then Jennifer's estimations,
and this will cost him dearly when he
attacks the center of the German line in
the battle of the frontiers on August
20,
first 22nd.
And the center is a weird area because
if the left is up by Belgium and the
right is down by,
you know,
Alsace Lorraine and Switzerland.
The center is the part where the terrain
is hard to fight in.
You know,
the giant Ardin forest is there and it's
hilly terrain with not a lot of roads,
difficult country,
right?
It's the same country that everyone was
so shocked when the Germans came through
it with tanks in the second world war
because it was thought to be
impenetrable.
Well,
in the first world war,
that's where the Shatford decides to
attack because he's determined that they
must.
The Germans must be weak there.
What's more,
this is how he's going to deal now with
this sledgehammer issue.
If it really exists,
he's going to cut it off.
He's going to launch his attack at the
German center,
right where that hinge point is with a
door swings between the forces of the
Germans that move and the forces of the
Germans that stay stationary.
There should be a gap smashed through
there.
Get behind them,
drive all the way up until you hit the
North Sea or the English Channel and cut
off that sledge hammer head.
It's not a bad idea if he can make it
work.
It's like judo.
You just took that great enemy advantage
of so many good troops in one location.
They're like a steam roller and turned
it into a negative because now you're
going to cut off the best part of the
enemy army surrounded and kill it.
You know in one place.
It's a great idea if you can make it
work.
The French are totally incapable at this
point in the war of making something
like that work
because they hadn't learned what kind of
war they were in yet.
That's what the battle of the frontiers
is going to be.
This first round of this fight where
where everybody's throwing haymakers and
getting smacked on the jaw.
It's going to teach a lot of lessons to
people.
Jennifer will fire more generals in this
first month of the war than anybody's
ever fired in history and a lot of the
other militaries will do similar things
because this is where we find out,
you know,
which generals can really fight in war
time and which ones are more peace time
kind of generals and within a couple of
months you'll have much more competent
people you know,
at the helmet a lot of places,
which makes it a little less fun.
I mean,
right now it's,
you know,
the wild west out here and you have all
kinds of different quality people.
Take the Russian generals that were
going to deal with in a minute.
I mean there's variable quality and this
becomes a real live fire test for a lot
of these people
on the 21st of August and the 22nd of
August,
I'm Jennifer launches his big offensive
in the yard.
Dan,
he assumes he's running into an inferior
number of German forces based on his
calculations.
He's instead walking into a situation
where he's facing almost equal numbers
of troops and their dugin.
I'm waiting for him and this is where
the idea of bay and net attacks and
charging machine guns and not digging in
with your red pants.
I mean,
we didn't even mention the fact that
none of these armies,
none of them are going into this war
with helmets.
There are no helmets,
folks,
they're wearing caps.
Okay.
You know how many people are going to
die because of that mistake.
This is all kind of when that romance in
war gets shot down,
literally,
I mean to people of a 19th century sort
of worldview and attitudes about honor
and duty and the things that are
expected of,
for example,
officers in the field,
this idea of French officers standing up
with a sword and in a white gloves and
often the white hat in a storm of steel
in a move that is absolutely suicidal
and those brave people must have known
it.
Imagine how the soul gets conflicted and
knowing to do your duty and live up to
the standards and expectations of your
countrymen and your people during this
time period.
You were expected to stand up there and
and essentially face sure death when you
might survive simply by laying on the
ground and throw away that white hat and
just just kind of hide behind that tree
or whatnot,
but at the top permitted is a romance
and certain standards and this is a
heroic death.
This is what the elder von Moltke was
talking about.
You know that we quoted earlier where we
talked about how perpetual peace was not
even a good dream because you lose all
these wonderful values that warfare
brings out to him,
that officer,
those officers,
those many hundreds of officers dying on
these fields in their white gloves
because they wouldn't take cover.
We're doing something beautiful,
an admirable.
Remember he said in that quote,
we used that in war man's noblest.
Virtues come into play.
Courage and renunciation,
fidelity to duty and a readiness for
sacrifice that does not stop at giving
up life itself.
To him,
this is the charge of the light brigade
over and over and over again.
Modern people look at this as foolish to
us.
It's a waste of that officer's life and
potential.
Use Him in a way that will achieve a
useful and if he has to give up his
life,
sell it more dearly than that.
Two people of the time period.
You know that that ends really with this
war.
There was value in what those officers
were doing simply by dying like that and
upholding the standards,
you know,
that they were upholding by doing so a
higher fidelity to duty and readiness to
sacrifice as von mold cassette.
One of the things that this war changes
is that whole view,
the people in 1918 at the end of this
war would feel very similar to the way
we do about how stupid it is to stand up
in a hailstorm of steel and just,
you know,
sacrifice your life for nothing.
The generation that does that in 1914
and most of which doesn't make it
through the war.
They had a different way of looking at
things and older way and that's why this
war is often seen as a separation point
in history between one world and
another.
The running into this new world as part
of this attack against the giant center
of the front,
through the yard in forest and
everything comes off sounding like a dry
affair.
Um,
when historians write about it,
not that they're dry,
but listen,
history sometimes takes the emotion and
the blood and everything out of it.
I mean,
David Stevenson has a great one volume
work on the war and here's how he
describes these offensives by genre and
the French to strike against what is
certainly a week German center,
right?
He says,
quote,
the result was a multiple disaster.
The French forces entering the arden
were weaker than the Germans in
reconnaissance cavalry.
And on the morning of 22nd August,
missed grounded their aircraft groping
forward in echelon along the few roads
through the forest,
they blundered nodding to weaker forces,
but into 21 divisions against their own
20.
They're 75
millimeter field guns were ineffective
in the hilly terrain and poorly linked
by telephone with the infantry.
They were no answer to the German
machine,
guns and field howitzers which retallack
and quote,
what is wreaking havoc.
Mean.
Historian Peter Hart's book on the Great
War has many wonderful firsthand
accounts of what these experiences were
like and hard himself writes about the
stumbling into each other that are these
battles in the middle of the front,
through this forested hilly terrain
quote in these battles,
few people at any level of command had
much idea of what was happening and for
the troops on the ground.
It was all utterly baffling.
Prewar tactic seemed to have no impact.
Bayonet charge is lead only to more
slaughter while calling up artillery.
Support was often doomed to failure.
He says,
quote,
sometimes the gunners were too far
behind,
sometimes too close and caught under
fire from the longer range.
German guns,
whatever the reason he writes.
The infantry were often left in
desperate straits,
and then he quotes a captain from the
hundred and third regiment who was
caught in desperate straits.
Quote,
my company was sustaining heavy losses.
Evidently,
it's action was hampering the enemy who
concentrated the combined fire of his
infantry,
artillery,
and machine guns on us.
We were surrounded by a heavy cloud,
which at times completely veiled the
battlefield from our eyes.
Little Burger guy or sprang up shouted,
Viva La France at the top of his voice
and fell dead among the men lying on the
ground.
One could no longer distinguish the
living from the dead.
The first were entirely absolved by
their grim duty.
The others lay motionless.
The wounded offered a truly impressive
sight.
The quote continues sometimes they would
stand up bloody and horrible looking.
Amidst burst of gunfire,
they ran aimlessly around arms
stretching out before them,
eyes staring at the ground,
turning round and round until hit buy
fresh bullets.
They would stop and fall heavily.
Heart rending cries,
agonizing appeals and horrible groans
were intermingled with the sinister
howling of projectiles.
Furious contortions told of strong
youthful bodies refusing to give up
life.
One man was trying to replace his bloody
dangling hand was shattered wrist.
Another ran from the line holding the
bowels falling out of his belly and
through his tattered clothes.
Before long,
a bullet struck him down.
We had no support from our artillery,
and you have to Reagan's in our division
and in the army corps.
Besides those destroyed on the road.
Where were they?
Why didn't they arrive?
We were alone in quote
27,000
freshmen will die on the 22nd of August.
Many,
many more will be badly,
badly wounded,
and maimed and scarred for life.
Now,
let's put
this in perspective.
One hundred years before this time,
Napoleon used to brag to his opponents
that you cannot stop me.
I spend 30,000
lives a month as though that was a big
deal in back when Napoleon said it.
It was the French had just lost 30,000
lives that day and their contact against
the other major army that had
precipitated all those deaths has only
been about 24 hours long.
What's tomorrow going to look like?
And the next day
already troops were dealing with,
you know,
a new phenomenon created by this
artillery,
the bigger heavy guns,
the extra ammunition and the fact that
battles are going on for a long time now
and people stay in place for awhile mean
that people are staying under artillery
barrage for longer and longer periods of
time.
This is a frightfully upsetting
experience,
as you might imagine,
and it begins to drive people insane,
right?
As the war starts,
a French sergeant wrote in his diary
about these offensives and Dr Dan on
August 20,
first 22nd,
and he said,
quote,
the guns recoil at each shot,
night is falling and they look like old
men sticking out their tongues and
spitting fire.
Heaps of corpses.
French and German are lying every which
way.
Rifles in hand,
rain is falling.
Shells are screaming and bursting shells
all the time.
Artillery fire is the worst.
I lay all night listening to the
wounded,
groaning.
Some were German.
The Canon nading goes on.
Whenever it stops,
we hear the wounded crying from all over
the woods.
Two or three men go mad every day
and quote,
a man who will turn out to be one of
France's greatest public figures in the
20th century was at these battles too.
He had been indoctrinated like everyone
else in the romance and the heroism and
the ideas of the band at charge and the
offensive and all these military ideas
from another age.
It took him one bottle to learn the
lessons that it would take commanders on
all sides in this war,
quite a bit longer to learn.
Lieutenant Charles de Gaulle wrote of
these battles and his experience in
them,
quote,
suddenly the enemy's fire became precise
and concentrated second-by-second the
hail of bullets and the thunder.
The shells grew stronger.
Those who survived the lay flat on the
ground amidst the screaming wounded in
the humble corpses with affected calm.
The officers let themselves be killed,
standing upright.
Some obstinate platoons stuck their band
that's into their rifles.
Bugle sound into the charge.
Isolated heroes made fantastic leaps,
but all to no purpose.
In an instant,
it did become clear that not all the
courage in the world could withstand
this fire,
and to quote
the machines that had always been
important on the battlefields of
humankind had become the dominant
factor.
What had become a tool to be used by man
was now something that was so
devastating in the hands of each other
that the entire ideas about warfare that
had been in play in most societies
during those time periods up until this
era are all of a sudden no longer
viable.
The Battle of the frontiers in just a
couple of days manages to completely
change the whole complexion of the war.
What it seemed to be leading up to a
German defeat all of a sudden looks like
maybe the Germans are going to win this
war and quickly nobody expects the
French to lose and a couple of days more
than 75,000
men killed and more than 250,000
wounded.
That stuns everyone but the French
especially,
and you have to understand how many
people this is the American still
celebrate.
You know,
in a morbid sort of way.
The famous civil war battle of Antietam
famously called the bloodiest day in
American history in terms of warfare and
partly because it's a civil war and
everybody dying on both sides happens to
be American,
but those casualty levels for comparison
purposes are about 6,000.
A little less than 6,000
dead,
I think,
and a little less than 20,000
wounded.
6,000
dead,
20,000
wounded compared to more than 75,000
dead in 260,000
wounded in the first couple of days of
action on the western front.
The French are just stunned and now if
you're the German general,
put yourself in von Moltke shoes.
Remember the stress we talked about and
all of a sudden you are presented with a
dilemma.
If you just did this to your opponent
and you've stunned them in,
they're on the ropes and they look like
deer in the headlights for a minute.
What do you do?
Do you stick with the original plan and
say,
listen,
we're not supposed to attack here.
We have the sledge hammer going.
Stick with a sledge hammer and just let
the French recover in front of you
because it's part of the plan,
or do you say,
as the uncle of unmold Qa so famously
did that.
No battle plan survives first contact
with the enemy and look at this as an
opportunity,
a battlefield opportunity that presents
itself multiple has to make some
decisions here and it becomes another
place in the story where historians have
argued ever sense whether or not he lost
a war here?
No,
those who didn't believe you lost it
earlier in the story.
A lot of them believe he lost it here
and a lot of German generals writing
memoirs after the war,
you know,
needle him about this savagely making
bad decisions,
weakening the plan.
What we all have to understand about the
plan as it's normally thought of and
some very good modern historians have
done a great job of pointing this out,
is that the plan was probably flawed
from the get go and was probably never
meant to be implemented in the way a lot
of these German generals portrayed it.
And even more important than that,
evidence seems to show that members of
the general staff,
maybe von Moltke included,
never thought the plan was going to win
the war anyway,
which means it becomes your plan for
starting the conflict.
And then once everything is in motion,
you know,
you look for opportunities,
you try to create some,
you try to exploit French mistakes.
That's traditional generalship,
right?
So what the French are doing on their
side.
And so von Moltke make some decisions
based on having slammed the French so
hard.
He's got prince rubric does very,
uh,
down in the south screaming that now
that he's pushed the French back all the
way to the French border.
Why did he,
why did he just slammed them?
He could collapse the whole southern
flank and if the whole southern flank
collapses and you still get the northern
flank collapsing because of your sledge
hammer,
my gosh,
you've recreated the battle of cannae.
It's like the Romans and handle all over
again.
It's every generals dream.
A double envelopment,
a total surrounding.
I mean it von Moltke.
We're less of an art fanatic and more of
a military,
um,
you know,
hobbyist.
I would think he would find that
irresistible.
Who knows,
maybe he's just looking for
opportunities to outflank French forces.
As historian David Stevenson suggests
here,
um,
quote,
mold,
because actions at this juncture suggest
that he was determined to protect
Germany's territory,
whether in east,
Prussia or Alsace,
but willing to strike wherever the enemy
seemed weak rather than staking
everything on his right flank and to
quote.
So the staking everything on the right
flank idea is just what you do.
If no other better opportunities
develop.
And when Crown Prince rubrics suggest
attacking the French down in the south,
again,
fun Mocha thinks about it and says,
okay,
and agrees to take some forces that
would be used to bolster the sledge
hammer head and instead use them on the
total other side of the flank down south
to help rubric in his offensive against
the French in the south,
to the plan is now being diluted in the
minds of the purists and they may be
right.
I'm not taking sides,
I'm just saying the traditional ideas,
but the Maloca screwed up the war here
now and some very good historians are
saying,
not at all.
This is what you were trying to do.
Look for opportunities and exploit them
without losing the war elsewhere,
which creates a situation though that
Malacca himself even says after the war
was a mistake and it involves his
attempts to try not to lose the war
elsewhere.
But again,
if you put yourself in his position,
it's hard not to do this.
Multiple looks at the western front and
it looks like it's going pretty well.
Know the battle of the frontiers and the
battle in Alsace Alsace-lorraine.
All these things seem to show that the
Germans are better than the French.
As I said in the last episode.
This is,
in my opinion,
one of the great armies of all time and
what they just showed is that they
dominate another great army,
you know,
pretty easily.
And if you're von Moltke you could sit
there and look at that and go,
okay,
well all of our calculations are out the
window.
Maybe we don't need such dominance in
numbers.
You know,
where quality is such that maybe we
could get away with taking a few troops
from here and taken them to
the east because the Russians are taken
towns in east Prussia
and that's what Malka did.
First he changed the commander's over
there.
He's sack the guys he was having
problems with and he puts an old retired
guy who is more known for the Franco
Prussian war services and in fact calls
him out of retirement so quickly that he
has to put on his old blue uniform
because he doesn't have one of the newer
gray ones.
The blue ones date back to the earlier
war and combines this older retired guy
whose name is Hindenburg,
Paul von Hindenburg with the hero from
the German point of view of that attack
against,
you know,
the Belgian city of Leanne and the
fortress there who banged on the door of
the fortress with the hilt of a sword
and took the surrender of the city kind
of by himself,
sort of Erich Ludendorff,
Ludina,
orphan Hindenburg get this job or sent
to the east to figure the situation out.
And then von Moltke sends them these
troops,
which,
you know,
historians later said,
well,
it really needed those troops in the
west.
He shouldn't defend them and he
shouldn't have sent him,
but he didn't know that.
He said after the war was one of his
biggest mistakes,
he shouldn't have them because it'll
turn out that by the time the troops get
from the west to the east on the trains,
they are no longer needed.
Now again,
you know what?
I'm not a historian,
although historians debate this and
argue about it ever since.
So who knows?
Maybe we can all take a position on
this,
but looking at it from the sources that
I have,
looking at von Moltke as decision here
looks like prudence.
I mean the Russians are taking towns in
east Prussia,
forcing the little teeny German forces
that are there to retreat.
It looks like they're going to be
threatening Berlin.
Meanwhile,
on the western front,
it looks like the force you put there to
simply keep the French occupied while
the killing force maneuvers around their
flank may have defeated the French all
by themselves.
What happens when you beat the French
before the killing thing even gets
there,
and then someone wanders.
If you can spare a couple of cores for
the eastern front in von Moltke
supposedly even asks one of the
commanders of one of the armies that
makes up this sledge hammer swinging
gate thing.
You know that flanking force that's the
size of Napoleon's grand army or the
size of the Roman Empire's complete
military at tight.
He asks the commander of Second Army von
Bulow,
can you spare a few core for the east?
And von Bulow says,
yeah,
you know why?
He says,
yeah,
in part because he just matched a French
army in front of him during the battle
of the frontiers,
which happened to be the poor fifth army
commanded by that one French general who
saw the sledge hammer forming even
before the war started.
Poor General Len resnick,
and because he argues with the high
command to let him just shift his army a
little bit to protect its flanks.
Some historians think he saved Fifth
Army from total annihilation.
He does have to retreat though,
move backwards once again to keep in
line with the rest of the French forces
that are retreating.
Sort of all along the line.
Meanwhile here,
the British.
Now this is a source of contention and
legend like all this stuff.
Isn't it funny how much of this early
war is,
but the French had been badgering the
British since the beginning of the war
to move faster,
move faster,
move faster.
We need someone up here on our left
flank.
It's critical,
right?
The French territorial,
a units together which are like an old
man and reservists and stuff and put
them out on the flank just so that
there's something out there,
but against what's coming.
I mean it's nothing and so they,
they hurry the British and the British
rush up and they,
they run into Belgium so that they can
take the position on the left flank and
protect,
you know,
poor general [inaudible] army.
And before they even get their lead
resnick's moving the other direction,
he's backing up to stay in line with the
French armies exposing the British
army's flank.
Again.
You can read the British historians
who've been mad about that ever since
being left in the lurch by the French.
What's so funny is I read all these
accounts,
like the Irishman's account,
Lucy's account of a,
of arriving in France and how much the
French loved them and these wonderful
welcomes and then you read other
accounts,
you know from later in the war where the
soldiers are going,
yeah,
the French don't much like us.
We don't like them.
They don't like us.
And the leadership in the British army
didn't seem particularly pro French or
vice versa.
There seemed to be a lot of arguing
between them and then some weird order.
Although it's totally understandable by
the head of the British military right
before the f goes to France,
complicates everything,
Lord her ratio,
kitchener,
the British legend from the colonial
wars.
You've never seen a guy like this,
by the way.
I always look at his picture and wonder
what he would look like without that
Victorian era,
waxed mustache thing he has going.
But.
But he's a.
he's a fantastic figure,
a character in his own right.
But he famously tells the British
commander,
who's going over to friend's something
to the effect of,
look,
this 70,000
men is 90 percent of all.
We have France and Germany.
They got millions of men in the field.
This is our army.
Don't lose it.
In other words,
be careful.
The problem is he's in a war where men
are thrown into meat grinders in very
large numbers.
The French will lose the equivalent of
the British expeditionary force often in
this war in a short period of time.
So will the chairman's,
so the British are moving up into
Belgium to have their first real contact
with modern war.
They fought in South Africa against a
bunch of bore farmers and guerrilla
fighters got an idea of what,
you know,
the rifle,
fire and all that stuff could do.
They haven't moved up against an army
that can fight like Daikin fight and
that outnumbers the many times over.
They stumble into this army at a place
called the battle.
That shaping up will be a legendary
British battle.
It's called the battle of moms.
And um,
it will be mythologized in a very
similar way to the dunkirk affair in the
Second World War.
You know what that was right when
Germany smashes France in 1940,
the British managed to evacuate their
army.
Miraculously every ship that can float
comes across in.
Every little rowboat comes across the
channel,
takes British soldiers away and the
Luftwaffe has held at bay.
And then they can flip the Germans off
from across the English Channel.
Say,
ha ha missed us.
Technically it's a defeat,
right?
But you sort of a it and spin it in a
way that makes it look like a glorious
victory that ends up biting,
you know,
the enemy in the rear end,
in the long run.
There is some truth to that,
right?
You can,
you can work with that as the publicists
say,
the battle of Mons is very similar.
One of those things that's technically
no matter how you look at it,
a defeat.
But there are heroic narratives that
sort of come out of it.
To me,
it's like the moment where the cloaking
device is removed from the German
flanking attack because up till now
there's been this uncertainty about is
it coming in and what strength is it
coming in and how many men are we
talking about here in where exactly is
it going?
All these different kinds of things that
British run in to the tip of the spear.
They run into the most honored,
um,
of the armies that are involved in this
attack.
The one that has the,
the important,
most important position.
The one that the great schlieffen
famously said that these guys should
brush their sleeves against the English
channel,
meaning that that's how wide a flanking
maneuver they should make through
Belgium.
They should make it so wide that they
actually almost touched the last man on
the right,
touches a sleeve into the water and it's
commanded by one of these great German
generals.
A guy named Alexander von and
[inaudible] is one of these guys that's
like Hind Scuderi and I think I said in
the Second World War,
he's an aggressive general.
He's a hard driver.
He seizes the initiative.
He gets you off balance.
He keeps pushing and he moves.
It's all about speed and deadliness when
he gets to the place where you don't
expect him yet,
he's commanding 320,000
men in Germany's first army right next
to him as Germany,
second army also moving through Belgium.
Also part of this outflanking maneuver
to 160,000
men under von Bulow on housing.
Third Army below him as 180,000
men.
This is the flanking maneuver.
The British run into the German army on
the farthest right flank.
They only run into a part of it
actually,
but 160,000
men who are surprised to find the
British waiting for them behind
defensive positions along 25 miles of a
canal,
which we call a defensive obstacle,
right?
This is something that magnifies the
power of the defense because now the
Germans have to cross this canal under
fire and everything.
Now the British think they're going to
face a core of Germans maybe to instead
they're facing four plus cores and
they're doing it in this kind of another
worldly setting.
Uh,
again,
Barbara Tuchman's good for this kind of
stuff.
And she explains that,
you know,
you might think that this is like the
wonderful Belgian farm countryside in
the canal with blue water going through
it.
But she explains that this is a mining
town and the water that runs through
this canal is more of a sludge and it's
black and it gives off chemical fumes.
And she said it amongst the flower
gardens and vegetable gardens are these
slag heaps that are pointed and looked
like tall witches hats all around the,
the landscape,
and she says it doesn't look like a bad
place for a modern battle.
It's gone down in history though,
uh,
with one narrative.
And then of course,
as in everything else you're going to
get tired of me saying this.
But as everything else with this war,
there's a whole nother counter
narrative.
The original narrative is the dunkirk
one that,
that turns this thing into something
that is so legendary that within a year
or two legends,
popular legends will spring up.
That there are angels on the British
side of this battle,
which,
you know,
to me,
I wouldn't push that rumor because even
though it makes it look like God might
be on your side if you've got the angels
on your side and you still end up having
to move backwards in retreat after the
battle.
That doesn't speak too well about the
fighting power of the particular angels
involved.
But let's not go there.
Let's talk about,
you know,
the parts we can confirm about this
battle.
It's a 25 mile front that these 70,000
guys have to hold most of it behind this
canal as we said,
and it starts with encounters between
cavalry because remember they're trying
to use these aircraft and and,
and the Germans are better than most
adults to look at things and see things,
but every time anything's misty or
foggy,
they can't see anything from these
things.
So it's still cavalry that does this job
and while you're cavalry's out front
trying to be the eyes and ears of your
army,
the enemy's cavalry is out front being
the eyes and ears of their army and they
fight.
This is what you normally have.
Your reconnaissance forces get into it.
And so the first stuff that goes on here
is the British eyes and ears and counter
the German eyes and ears.
There's some cavalry skirmishes and John
Lucy or are Irishman in the BDF talks
about this.
He says,
you know,
we run into are cavalry and there's some
wounded people,
but they,
they,
they beat the Germans at a little
cavalier engagement.
But the Germans are coming and so the
British and his unit all get ready.
The they kind of scratch them out.
Dig would be too strong of a word
scratch themselves out,
a little depression in the soil and they
wait for the Germans to arrive and I
should point out something that maybe
I'm estimating here,
but I would say between 85 and 90
percent of all the accounts you read
from soldiers going off to war in 1914,
and it doesn't matter which army you
choose.
Most of it is overwhelmingly positive in
terms of the emotion that these young
men feel going off to war.
Now,
there were some Russian accounts,
especially when you know people are
pulled off of farms and don't want to go
do this,
but most of the young men going off to
war here are excited.
It sounds like an adventure.
Full Romance of war is still in bloom to
them.
This is excitement.
Remember,
a lot of these people have pretty dreary
lives and now all of a sudden they're
caught up in,
in,
in world affairs that are huge,
momentous,
biggest thing that's ever going to
happen to most of these people.
Right,
and they know it and they're,
they're caught up in the excitement that
they don't have a lot of negative
stories yet that have filtered into the
public realm.
You know,
explaining what's happened to the guys
who came before you because there are no
guys that came before you are Irish,
British,
Expeditionary Force soldier,
John Lucy is moving up towards malls in
the period right around August 22nd,
August,
23rd and says that when he first heard
the guns,
it was a queer,
thrilling sort of feeling that it
brought on,
but it also worried him but maybe not
for the reason we would think of as an
adventurous young man who finds all
this,
you know,
interesting and exciting.
He had a different reason to be scared.
He writes about his unit as he comes up,
you know,
toward the situation at models like this
quote,
we swapped news with the nearest men in
the ranks and learn that nothing
exciting had happened to the battalion
in our absence,
except that a line of trenches had been
dug as a defensive measure about a mile
behind and then abandoned on the orders
of a staff officer who wish the
battalion to move forward toward the
town of Maus now visible through the
slag,
heaps of many minds on the right front
of the marching regimen.
This dirty looking factory town had no
particular interest just then for us
until suddenly above the sound of the
tread of our marching feet.
We heard the blooming of field guns,
a queer,
thrilling,
and menacing sound about which there
were many conjectures,
the most popular being that they were
French,
70 fives and that they were giving the
Germans hell.
This notion greatly depressed us.
We should really hurry up now.
Otherwise we would miss the battle.
The French would get all the glory while
we with our capacity for deadly rifle,
fire and dash,
and the attack would miss that crowning
moment of victory culminating in a
sweeping,
bayonet charge,
relentless and invincible,
the grand assault that would drive the
enemy off the field so we dammed the
French were not waiting for us.
And to quote,
there's that romance of war again,
the great adventure.
It's going to be fun.
We're going to be heroes.
And it's funny when he first gets to the
line,
he and his men take up positions and
what they call knee trenches.
These shallow little kind of holes and
they're not too happy to not be moving
forward and doing something offensive,
but,
but they sit down there and then the
first shells come by them and again they
find it more interesting and they kind
of have fun with it.
He says,
quote,
the salvo of shells passed over our
heads and burst about 80 yards in the
rear with a terrific clattering crash.
We were highly interested,
more came and still more all going over
the heads of our curious men appeared
above the trenches.
Looking back to see the burst,
look,
they shouted a black one or one only,
or for more whites,
some laughingly imagine themselves on
duty at rifle ranges at home and shouted
advice to the German gunners,
wash out another miss and lower your
sights.
One wag simulating great terror,
cried,
send for the police.
There's going to be a row on here and
another in mock despair.
Oh mother,
why did I desert you?
Than the enemy gunners shortened and the
shell is exploded above our trenches and
the men already taken in hand for
exposing themselves.
Crouched low.
So it's getting real,
right?
But it shows you the attitude that they
had at the time they are having fun with
it.
It's a great adventure.
And you read accounts from every major
army of this period.
As I said,
the Russians have a little bit more
people that were sort of dragged into
this kicking and screaming.
Um,
and,
and the country people always more than
the urban people,
but the 20 year olds who are marching
off to do this,
it's hard to find accounts where they're
dreading it.
Yet,
there'll be accounts down the road where
you know everyone has a good idea where
they're going and there's a lot more of
planning for your own death and worrying
about that kind of stuff.
Right now,
as I said,
John Lewis,
Lucy's worrying about missing the fun.
He doesn't have to worry because the
funds come into him.
Field Marshal,
Alexander von Cluck is aiming the German
first army,
the tip of the spear,
right?
Adam
and Alexander von cluck is like the
German general,
that central casting in the TV Hollywood
world would've put together scarred
face,
you know,
iron cross carrying a soldier's rifle
and a pistol at the same time while he's
walking around.
Fearsome is a great description of him
where a French observer,
you know,
during the early stages of this combat,
you know right around now,
ends up witnessing the arrival of von
cluck somewhere and says it reminded
them of Attila the Hun.
And he said,
quote,
an automobile drove up from it,
descended it,
an officer of arrogant and impressive
bearing.
He stopped forward alone while the
officers standing in groups in front of
the villa made way for him.
He was tall and majestic with a scarred
clean shaven face,
hard features in a frightening glance in
his right hand.
He carried a soldier's rifle and his
left rested on the butt of a revolver.
He turned around several times striking
the ground with the butt end of his
rifle and then halted in a theatrical
pose.
No one seemed to dare to approach him
and indeed he wore a terrible air and to
quote,
and as we said earlier,
he's like the Hind Scuderi of this war.
He's the hard driving impetuses.
Everything commanding 320,000
men,
commander of the first army and he's
going to have with German generals who
are not as aggressive and hard driving
as he is.
It's his army.
Well,
about half of it that will run into the
British at mom's and the traditional
story is that they're in for a shock
because as we said earlier,
the British are good rifleman,
but even this,
just so you know,
even this is contested in a second.
I'll read some stuff about this same
battle from the military historian of
Britain's imperial war museum who will
kind of go after every single point
that's traditional in this narrative,
but traditionally Alexander von
[inaudible] forces in sort of an
encounter battle,
stumble in to the British lines and take
it on the Chin and are hit by so much
rifle fire that is so precisely aimed
and so quickly,
you know,
fired that the German supposedly think
they're under machine gun fire.
John Lucy's very proud of this moment
and describes what happens to the
Germans thusly quote.
Finally,
the shelling ceased and we put up our
heads to breathe more freely than we
heard.
Conch like sounds strange.
Bugle calls.
The German infantry,
which had approached during the shelling
was insight and about to attack us.
Not a shot had been fired from our
trenches up till now,
and the only opposition to the Germans
had been made by our field gun battery,
which was heavily engaged behind us and
making almost as much clamor as the
enemy shelling.
To my mind,
it seemed that the whole battalion must
have been wiped out by that dreadful
reign of shells,
but apparently not an answer.
He writes to the German bugles are
trumpets came,
the cheerful sound of our officers,
whistles and the rifleman.
Casting aside the amazement of their
strange trial sprang to action,
a great roar of musketry rent the air
varying slightly in intensity from
minute to minute as whole company ceased
fire and opened again.
The satisfactory sharp blasts of the
directing whistles showed that our
machinery of defense was working like
the drill book and that the recent
shelling had caused no disorganization.
The clatter of our machine guns added to
the den for us.
He writes,
the battle took the form of well ordered
rapid rifle,
fire at close range as the field gray.
Human targets appeared or were struck
down the enemy infantry,
advanced according to one of our men in
columns of masses which withered away
under the galling fire of the well
trained and Cooley lead Irishman,
the leading Germans fired standing from
the hip.
Let me interrupt him here.
Now that's John Wayne style walking
toward the enemy.
Shooting from your hip,
so they're coming toward the British
trenches doing that.
The leading Germans,
as he said,
fired standing from the hip as they came
on,
but they're scattered.
Fire was ineffective and ignored.
They crumbled up mown down as quickly as
I tell it.
They're reinforcing waves in sections
coming on bravely and steadily to fall
over as they reached the front line of
slain and wounded behind the death line,
thicker converging columns were being
blown about by our field guns.
He then says,
our rapid fire was appalling even to us,
and the worst marksman could not miss as
he had only to fire into the Brown of
the masses of the unfortunate enemy who
won the fronts of two of our companies.
We're continually and uselessly
reinforced at the short range of 300
yards.
Such tactics amazed us,
and after the first shock of seeing men
slowly and helplessly falling down as
they were hit,
gave us a great sense of power and
pleasure.
It was also easy.
He says,
the German attack had to be broken off.
Quote,
the German survivors began to go back
here and there from align the attack had
been an utter failure.
Soon all that remained was the long line
of the dead heaped before us motionless
except for the limb movements of some of
the wounded and quote
as a person interested in military
history,
this era of the conflict is the one most
interesting to me because you know later
in the war,
everybody's pretty experienced,
you know,
with what you're dealing with.
It's at this point in the war that
everybody's learning the reality of
modern warfare at the same time,
through bloody hard experience.
The British expeditionary force and von
[inaudible] First Army are both kind of
getting a real initial taste of what the
new weaponry can do.
And as you heard from John Lucy,
the Irish rifleman in the BDF,
he and his compatriots were actually
appalled at how effective and deadly it
was.
It's a whole different thing,
you know,
firing it live people than a parade
ground,
but if you happen to emerge unscathed,
it almost seems to bolster that idea
that this is fun,
heroic,
romantic.
I'm Lynn Mcdonald in her book,
1914 quotes a bunch of people who were
there,
including Lieutenant Chapman,
who as the British are dealing with the
battle,
tells what's going on to a compatriot of
his and says about the repulsing of the
German human wave attacks.
Quote.
They came at us over a bank directly in
front of us and as soon as they topped
it,
we let them have it.
The range was 70 yards,
so we were firing at them.
Point blank.
I've never seen anything like it.
Legs,
arms,
heads.
They were flying all over the place.
We absolutely smashed them.
They simply melted away.
Then the blighters got some machine guns
into action and at that distance we were
like sitting ducks.
So we had to get out of it.
And by Jove it was a close shave.
And to quote as though it's a fun story,
right?
There was a 16 year old trumpeter and
that's not unusual.
Going back a very long time.
They always would have boys,
um,
you know,
as drummers and trumpeters and on the
ships they'll have,
you know,
they actually have a position in,
in Britain's navy called first boy,
second boy,
and they are,
they're kids,
but a 16 year old British trumpeter at
Moz describes how he just admired what
the British were doing.
It,
it.
He never forgot the fire discipline of
these rifleman.
He says he was sitting,
watching an officer countdown the range
of this advancing gray human wave and
getting very nervous as it got closer
and closer and closer.
And he was saying that the British
officer was holding the rifle fire until
the Germans got really close and he was
counting down the range.
Trumpeter j Dot Naylor from the third
division reports quote he was saying at
400,
at 3:50,
at 300.
The rifles blazed,
but still the Germans came on.
They were getting nearer and nearer and
for the first time I began to feel
rather anxious and frightened.
They weren't an indeterminant mass
anymore.
You could actually pick out details,
see them as individual men coming on and
coming on.
And the officers still cool as anything
was saying at 2:50,
at 200,
and then he said 10 rounds rapid and the
chaps opened up and the Germans just
fell down like logs.
I've never seen anything like it.
The discipline,
the fire discipline of these troops.
I've never forgotten that.
I was so impressed.
As a boy of 16,
I was simply astounded.
I thought,
what a marvelous army we are.
The attack was completely repulsed,
probably not for long,
but it was long enough for us to get the
guns away.
It saved us and
now I probably have more than 20 books
sitting around me here from historians
talking about this same event.
And it is amazing to go from historian,
historian,
historian and see the different ways
this is viewed,
interpreted.
I'm a perfect example is Peter Hearts a
wonderful book.
He's a historian at Britain's imperial
war museum and he's one of those
contrarians who says all this is a bunch
of nonsense
and let's understand quickly that it's.
It's normal in war time for this to
happen.
There's not a single power involved in
the conflict that wants to talk about.
Defeats or bad things.
Everybody wants propaganda victories.
Everybody wants stuff that helps
recruiting.
You're looking for stuff that you can
play up,
maybe a,
as Peter Harte suggests,
that's what this miracle at malls is,
but he shoots down a number of the
typical arguments pointing out that the
Germans handled themselves very well and
in fact,
if the casualty numbers or what he
thinks they are probably deserve a
victory at the battle of Mons.
In fact,
the French and the Germans both thought
the British were defeated there at the
time.
He writes,
quote,
when Yvonne Glucose First Army smashed
into Smith Dorian and second core at
6:00
AM on the 23rd of August.
The battle that ensued was to enter
British military folklore.
The myth is one of the heroic successful
defense with well trained British
Tommy's mowing down hordes of Germans
repeatedly attacking in mass formations.
Finally,
the British would be forced to retreat
only because the fickle French had given
way on their right flank.
This view of the battle is a great yarn
he writes,
but like the angels have moms at its
heart,
it is the product of wishful thinking
and quote.
He then goes on to deal with every
single reality.
We've talked in this battle,
shooting down each one of them.
Again,
as best he can.
It's controversial,
but he's a fantastic historian who's
qualified to do this.
I should like to point out though that
this was no different,
you know,
manufacturing of victory or playing up a
victory and and magnifying the very real
heroism on both sides.
There's not only nothing wrong with
that,
that's pretty standard behavior for
every military and every war you can
think of.
I mean,
for example,
he'll say,
I'm quote as to the second core,
being undefeated and forced to fall back
only to conform with the French on their
right flank.
This is pure nonsense.
He says,
the reality is that on many occasions
the Germans seemed to have been all too
successful in forcing a retreat and to
quote.
In other words,
probably the best army in the world is
operating that way in the field and it's
disconcerting.
If you're on the other side,
for example,
he says,
quote,
it is undeniable that several of the
British battalions fought well,
but modern scholarship has revealed that
the Germans maneuvered skillfully to
secure a local superiority against the
weak points in the British defenses
wherever possible they operated against
the flanks,
forcing the British to fall back or risk
being cutoff and totally destroyed
throughout the Germans seemed to have
handled their artillery and machine guns
with a great tactical dexterity born of
long practice,
operating them in tandem to dominate the
British and the firefight effectively
rendering rifle fire of secondary
importance.
The British were turned out of their
defensive positions in a matter of a few
hours and even failed to destroy several
of the canal bridges.
End Quote.
He then goes on to take issue with the
casualties that are often cited.
One of the things that British uses,
claiming that this is a major victories,
how many more Germans they killed versus
the casualties they suffered themselves.
He suggests that even the interpretation
of what those casualties are are
overblown.
Again,
this really doesn't matter in the grand
scheme of things.
Every nation was doing this for me,
what's most interesting is to watch
these nations and these militaries try
to learn on the fly while they're being
shot at and translate years of theory
into practice.
By the 24th of August,
the French will change their mind about
this whole idea of,
you know,
the offensive at all costs.
When did offer is force to say,
listen,
we need to go on the defensive a while,
which is,
you know,
like heresy a Amir,
five,
six,
seven,
eight days before.
The reality of the situation on the
ground is changing.
Everybody's mind about,
you know,
those tactics we thought before the war,
we're going to be good.
Yeah.
In practice,
not so good the British,
whether you want to believe that they
were forced to retire because the French
left them in the lurch or whether you
want to believe as a heart does that the
Germans were just really quite good at
turning flanks and employing combined
arms as it's called to,
to,
to get the British in an untenable
position as it's called.
It doesn't matter.
The British have to retire,
just the French.
They have to get out of there.
The first armies,
um,
leader von Luke writes in his memoirs,
the British fought excellently,
but that if he had been allowed to sweep
as widely around the flank as he had,
wanted to and has as he requested it at
the time,
that the British would have been in no
position to fight at all,
he would have outflanked them and
smashed them from the rear.
Remember,
there will be a lot of finger pointing
after the war,
over whose fault all of this stuff is,
and a lot of the generals who were still
alive,
we'll write things to defend their
reputation.
The one thing that you could actively
say is going on here though,
is that neither the British or the
French were able to stop this movement
through Belgium that's coming down on
them now and they're all retiring at
speed and this is the part of this,
you know,
early war narrative that's known as the
great retreat.
The great retreat is a wonderful example
of one of those moments where I try to
get in the minds of these people and you
know,
that's a fruitless task.
I mean there's no reason to play with
history and study history if you don't
want to try to do that,
but we all have to recognize how
impossible it is,
but at the same time you try to put
yourself in their shoes.
If you are one of the commanders of any
of these armies and you're over about
the age of 58,
59,
this entire affair is beginning to look
horribly familiar to you.
If you're on the German side,
wonderfully familiar to you,
it looks like 18,
70 18,
71.
It looks like 44 years ago.
It looks like,
you know,
when the Germans managed to surround to
entire French armies and get them to
surrender Sir John French,
the British commander is already making
plans to get his army to the other side
of Paris and then starting to think
about the challenges,
the logistical challenges of getting the
army,
the British army out of France
altogether and back to the safety of
Britain.
He's worried about a completely
legitimate threat that the British could
end up like two French armies ended up
in the last war completely surrounded by
the enemy and forced to surrender.
Imagine if 90 percent of Britain's
military forces are on the continent and
have to give up to the Germans and go
into captivity.
That's quite a hostage situation.
You have pretty easy to get a pretty
good.
Our Miss Disagreement,
wouldn't you think if you're holding 90
percent of the British army hostage
and French.
It's confusing,
isn't it?
The British commander named French,
but French is not confident in the
French.
He hasn't been impressed,
you know,
with his dealings with them so far,
and he's complained a lot to his
superior who I think we said was the
military leader in this war.
Lord Horatio's kitchener who happens to
be a field marshal,
but in fact at this time he's a cabinet
member,
the secretary for war,
but kitchener at times will feel the
need to discard his bowler hat and his
suit and tie and throw on his field
marshal's uniform.
Jump on a destroyer,
go across the English Channel and know,
give French a little piece of his mind,
bolster his confidence a little bit,
but French has a legitimate worry.
This great retreat that's going on is an
extremely precarious moment because and
organized retirement can easily turn
into a disorganized,
panicked route and everyone knows that
in fact,
only a couple of days after the battle
of Mons British forces will be required
to turn around and beat off German
attacks against them,
which is wild when you consider that the
Germans are trying to catch people that
move away from them at the same maximum
speed.
If you're a military history,
not like I am,
the one thing that's interesting to
follow at this point in the war is
something that that is very unusual and
military history because if you were
going to take a class on military
history,
this is the point in the war where they
would tell you if you're the Germans
that you need to send out your mobile
units now and destroy the enemy.
That's why you have cavalry right now.
You go talk to a Genghis Khan or at any
medieval or ancient general in history,
and they're going to tell you,
go Ghanim sends your cavalry after them,
harassed them,
just organize them.
Never give them a moment's peace cutoff.
Stragglers.
I mean if you look at where people die
in premodern warfare,
but even modern warfare,
they die in the pursuit.
The job of the battle is to get the
other side to turn and run,
and when they turn and run,
you crushed them.
I mean,
look at the Iraqi highway of death,
right?
We're so many Iraqis died fleeing
Kuwait.
What were they doing?
They were fleeing throughout most of
human history.
The casualty,
I mean Alexander the great supposedly
only suffered less than a thousand
casualties in his entire career,
although I don't know if I believe that,
but that's.
That's what some military historian side
and the reason those numbers are so low
is because comparatively few people died
in the battles they died while being
pursued after the battle,
and since Alexander never lost a battle
of his troops,
never had to face that.
This is the moment when the German
cavalry should be unleashed and finish
the job.
The problem is is we had this tiny
little window in military history where
the cavalry is so vulnerable that even
disorganized,
which the French and the British aren't
by the way,
but even retreating forces can turn
around form of firing line really
quickly and destroy the pursuing
cavalry.
Add a few howitzers in there and it will
be carnage.
Now in the next war,
mechanized forces,
armor and aircraft will recreate the
ability to do what light cavalry did
before this period.
But in this weird little interim era,
the cavalry can't pursue and destroy
forces like this.
So the Germans have to do this same job
with infantry.
The problem is the German infantry
maximum speed is the speed of a marching
man,
which is the exact same speed of the
people they're trying catch.
And yet nevertheless,
and even though the Germans had marched
along way already,
they get darn near to catching them
several times.
In fact,
on the 26th of August,
the British have to turn around and try
to get a little breathing space from
these German pursuers by,
you know,
fighting them again.
Can we get them to slow down,
cause them to form up and have to
reorganize again and get a little,
you know,
distance between us and them.
On the 26th of August,
the British,
including our friend John Lucy from the
AEF fight,
another battle with the Germans this
time in about 11 hours,
the British suffer 8,000
casualties.
Now,
8,000
casualties in the war that's about to
happen isn't going to seem like that
much.
And my goodness,
the French have suffered 260,000
wounded in the last few days.
But to the British army,
which is historically small,
as we said,
this is a naval powers army.
That's a lot.
In fact,
when Lieutenant General Sir Archibald
Murray who is with the general staff
behind the lines is informed of the
8,000
casualties.
A couple hours later he collapses,
just faints and collapses.
And what this shows you mean these are
hard bitten military men,
but it shows you the stress and the
tension that these people are under and
you add to that the fog of war.
No one knows what's going on and it's
happening so quickly.
There's a huge amount of stress.
A German general shoots himself on
August 20th.
I mean all these administers the real
supreme test.
It separates the men from the boys as
the old saying goes,
this is the moment of greatest danger.
Winston Churchill who was a high
official with the Navy,
writes about this period in this
retirement,
this great retreat,
and says,
quote.
Then came the days of retreat.
We saw that the French armies of the
right,
we're holding their own,
but all the center and left was marching
southward toward Paris as fast as
possible while our own five divisions
were for several days plainly in the
very jaws of destruction,
he says that the admiralty,
we received requests to shift the base
of the whole army from Avera to send
those ear,
and with this complicated business,
we had to cope.
The process of retreat,
continue day after day.
A seemingly irresistible compulsion was
pressing and forcing backwards the brave
armies of France.
Why should it stop?
Would they ever be able to turn?
If France could not save herself,
nothing could save her and quote,
the Germans are coming toward Paris and
the allied soon to be officially allied
armies are moving back in that
direction.
Here's the thing though,
remember the war plan and you know that
the French military leaders offer has
not forgotten the plan.
Even if the Germans get within sight of
Paris,
they're going to lose the war.
If at the same time that happens,
the Russians from the east are marching
through the streets of the German
capital in Berlin has to offer and the
whole allied higher command realizes
that they're on way.
The war can still be won.
Even with allied forces in the west
retreating.
They just have to prolong this conflict
long enough to let the Russian smash the
Germans in the east and the war will be
over.
No matter how well the Germans in the
West are doing,
enter Hindenburg and Ludendorff arriving
even as all this is going on by train in
the east to take command of that one
lone German army that got to hold off
the Russian steamroller as it approaches
now,
the Russians biggest victory at this
point is the fact that there's an army
there to fight it all.
Remember the entire German prewar plans
assumed a certain speed for everyone's
mobilization and the Russians are the
slow ones and here they are,
you know,
in two weeks,
and they're already taking towns in east
Prussia.
East Prussia,
by the way,
is this area that was conquered a in the
14th,
15th century.
By the famous Teutonic Knights,
which included a large proportion of
Germanic nobility,
who eventually will settle down in those
areas.
And so this is where some of the
historic German nobility,
you know,
has their biggest states and everything.
The Kaiser himself,
you know,
this is,
this is historic German territory with
an abnormal number of the aristocracy
there.
It's an important area and it's a
gateway to Berlin and it's not far from
Berlin and the Russians manage within
like two weeks of the war.
Start,
forget the six weeks that guys like
Schlieffen accounted on.
Within two weeks they've got half a
million men operating in that area and
they've got even more down south against
the ostrow Hungarians.
And,
and it's one of those things where,
I mean there's an author,
there's a professor named Shawn mcmaken
who's written a whole book called the
Russian origins of the first world war
where he says,
the Russians are the ones who should
bear the entire lion share of the guilt
for starting this war.
They wanted it.
They planned for it.
And part of the reason that they
surprised everybody with their quick
mobilization is because they were ready
for this war.
They wanted it and they put up two
fifths of their army in Poland,
which is right next to east Prussia
ahead of time.
So that when the war starts,
when they have to mobilize people,
they're not coming from all over Russia.
There's a ton of them right there and
good units to.
It doesn't make any difference.
The Russians are a mess,
an absolute chaotic disaster.
And you know,
if you look at Russian history,
Soviet history too,
I mean,
you know,
just consider that a,
a piece of Russian history that's so
traditional.
It's crazy.
I mean the Russians always start these
wars as disasters.
I mean in the Second World War,
they can hardly deal with the fins in
Finland,
which is crazy when you think about the
disparity in everything from resources
to size of the numbers of troops,
everything.
And they can hardly deal with the fins
in the very early part of Second World
War.
But six years after the second world war
starts,
they're feeling one of the greatest
armies in human history,
very typical for the Russians.
Takes them a long time to get started,
but they can be extremely formidable
once they get going.
Hindenburg and Ludendorff aren't going
to let them get going.
When Hindenburg and ludendorff arrive in
the east.
Remember,
these guys are probably a little.
What would you call jet lagged.
Train lagged.
I mean Hindenburg is 66 or something and
just out of retirement a couple of days.
Ludendorff has been on the western front
since about the start of the war room
where he banging on the door of Leah and
accepting the surrender there a couple
of days ago.
He's helping push land resnick's army
back on the western front and now here
he is in the east trying to get
acclimated to what's going on.
There's a lieutenant colonel,
which is a pretty low rank for a guy to
make the history books like Max Hoffman
did on the scene though,
who's an expert on the Russian army and
of course has been there the whole time.
So quickly fills ludendorff and
Hindenburg in on the situation,
which is this,
there's about a half million Russians
nearby and about 175,000
Germans to deal with them.
The Russians are divided into two
armies,
the first and the second army,
and they're making their way across a
really difficult piece of terrain.
It's a series of lakes and forests and
marshes and rivers that just is going to
make these two armies have a hard time
helping each other out.
You know,
while they're on opposite sides of this
big terrain feature.
He also tells him to Bergen Ludendorff
that they have a pretty good idea about
what the Russians are trying to do
because the Russians had been
broadcasting radio messages and
telegraph messages to each other without
using any code.
They also find a Russian officers body
after they killed him and it has the
plans on it.
In fact,
there is so much information that's
giving the Russian plans to the Germans
that they start to wonder whether or not
it's just a reus.
Maybe the Russians are trying to trap us
and they're just broadcasting all this
to fool us because it's so obvious.
I mean,
who would make these kind of mistakes?
Well,
it's not the greatest time in Russian
military history.
I wrote down a list of 12 mistakes that
were made or or areas that the Russians
were having terrible problems and it's
not only understandable because of the
Russian tradition of starting wars,
a little chaotically and disorganized,
but also because you know,
even the really best armies are trying
to figure out,
you know,
how to deal with all this new technology
in 100 years of theory.
Returning into fact the British and the
French and the Germans are all dealing
with this on the western front,
so it's understandable that an army
that's I'm really not up to those
standards is dealing with it all too.
In fact,
even though the numbers on paper say
there's half a million Russians here,
they've been leaving guns and soldiers
all along the way to get here.
I mean there are actual strength when
they get to combat is going to be a lot
less than it looks like.
The logistics and supply situation is
disastrous.
The troops in some cases aren't eating.
They have rags instead of shoes on their
feet.
Some don't have rifles.
The two commanders,
a guy named Brendan,
Brendan comp will command the first
army.
I'm the second arm is a guy named
Samson.
I'll they hate each other,
which is going to be a problem because
the plans that the Germans had become
aware of through all these different
methods say that the Russians are going
to try a pincer movement on them.
There's only one German army in the
region,
so this first army will come from the
north.
The second army will come from the
south,
surround this German army and destroy
it,
but at the commander's hate each other
and the communications is awful and they
have to pass this terrain feature for 50
or 60 miles that will keep them from
working together.
This pincer movement is going to be
tough.
The German reconnaissance is so much
better.
I mean,
the Russians aren't even using aircraft.
The Germans have air airplanes and
Zeplin is up there watching what's going
on.
The Germans have an advantage with
railroads because railroads help armies
move fast obviously,
but the problem is is that attacking
armies,
once they leave their railroads almost
never get the ability to use the
railroads in the territory they are
going through.
Whereas the defenders in their own
territory can.
This is one of those things that makes
the defensive more powerful than the
offensive.
In this war.
The Germans are able to use railroads to
reinforce points where they need to be.
The Russians are past their railroads
now they're walking.
Finally,
the Germans know this country.
They know the terrain and they know the
geography.
This is an area where sometimes the
German army conducts peacetime
maneuvers,
so they set a trap for the Russians and
it's a very napoleonic strategy.
Indeed,
they're going to attack these armies
while these armies are separated by this
terrain and unable to help each other
and smash them individually.
They're going to nullify that
disadvantage and numbers and the
Russians,
you know,
make this a lot easier because they
don't know what's going on.
They literally are clueless as to what
they're facing and the high command
isn't helping the situation.
They're telling General Samson off at
the second army,
listen to.
We don't see any German forces.
We don't expect an attack.
I mean Samson was taking his time blind
to what's going on around him.
Whereas the Germans are moving very fast
and seizing areas to the flank and
taking up positions and setting a trap.
This historians,
Michael Nyberg and David Jordan,
you know,
pick up the narrative about springing
the trap on the Russian Second Army.
They write,
quote,
nervous,
intense hours,
followed as the rest of the trap was
sprung.
By the morning hours of the 28th of
August.
The Germans had control
of almost all the main roads leading to
Samson offs.
Forces combat began in the north when a
Russian core advancing without support
ran into a German core.
The Germans who were fully aware of the
Russian presence and we're lying in,
wait for them,
smashed the Russians,
and sent them reeling back in,
panic,
surprised at the unanticipated presence
of German forces in the area.
Samson off ordered a general withdrawal
that night.
The full severity of the situation came
slowly to him as he realized that he was
completely cut off.
His men began to panic throwing down
weapons and running east as fast as they
could,
only to end up trapped by strong German
forces already sitting on their lines of
retreat.
Confusion and panic reigned in the
Russian lines without supplies and
without communications.
Panic spread quickly run in comms.
Forces were more than 70 miles away and
would obviously not provide any help at
all.
On the 29th of August,
Samson off himself gave into the panic.
He told a staff officer,
this is our trusted me.
How can I face him?
After such a disaster,
he then headed off into the woods where
he committed suicide rather than face
capture by the Germans.
He was one of the lucky ones.
Samsonov powerful army of 150,000
men had suffered one of the most
lopsided defeats in military history,
more than 30,000
Russians were killed and almost 100,000
injured prisoner of war camps where they
faced a dismal future of forced labor
and appallingly bad conditions.
The German's needed 60 trains to move
all of the Russian equipment they
captured.
German casualties were less than 20,000
and quote,
the Germans had this fantasy of maybe
emulating the famous battle of Kony
Hannibal's victory of total encirclement
over the Romans and the ancient world,
but instead they got that in the east
and right after defeating Samsonov
second army.
Those troops that had been taken maybe
at great cost very soon from the western
front arrived not in time for the
initial battle,
just as lieutenant had told Melissa
earlier,
but in time to take on the first army of
rent income,
which the Germans then smash with
similar nasty casualty numbers.
Now Renon comp will do a better job of
pulling his forces back and saving his
army from total destruction.
He won't get totally surrounded like the
battle of [inaudible],
but it doesn't matter.
The results are the same.
All of a sudden in shocking fashion.
The Germans have removed the threat of
the Russians coming in and taking Berlin
before the Germans can take Paris.
All of a sudden,
the whole strategy that the French and
British were delaying and operating
under the assumption of,
if we can just hold on a little longer,
the Russians will solve this war problem
for us.
All of a sudden the French and the
British are going to have to manage to
be victorious on the western front if
they want to save themselves.
That helps not coming from the east
in the West.
As the great retreat continues,
you know,
you begin to see what the level of human
suffering is going to be in this
conflict,
and I have to keep reminding myself
about this.
You know the old Joseph Stalin line is
so true.
One death is a tragedy,
a million deaths,
a statistic,
and these numbers that we will
constantly throw out in this conflict,
which are enormous numbers.
They fail to register after a while.
You become numb.
We take what the last several days on
the western front have done to France,
as we said,
75,000
dead,
more than 250,000
wounded in a couple of days.
How would our modern medical
establishment deal with a crisis like
that?
You forget what it's like on the ground.
That's why you need these reports that
come from people who were there in one
of the most famous books ever written
about the.
It's called now.
It can be told,
or British reporter named Philip Gibbs
went over to the continent right when
this whole conflict breaks out and he
reported from it,
you know,
during the great retreat.
Now what he reported that made it into
the media is not what he put in the book
because what he put in the book,
he can't.
He couldn't tell during the war.
This is the kind of nasty stuff that
none of the governments would allow to
be published because it was too raw and
too real.
That's why gibbs named his book.
Now it can be told [inaudible] after the
war,
he wrote it and he describes the
conditions during the great retreat and
the human suffering,
and he reminds us,
you know what it means to have that
level of death and destruction and
injuries and what kind of injuries we're
talking about.
Remember,
this is like having what?
Five,
eight football stadiums worth a people
in a few days injured and we're not
talking about hangnails and sprained
ankles here.
Gibbs wrote in August 19,
14 for publication.
Later,
quote
for Emea at night had come,
a French army in retreat there were dead
and wounded on their wagons.
Queer c stumbled as they lead their
tired horses.
Crowds of people with white faces like
ghosts in the darkness,
stared at their men retreating like this
through their city and knew that the
enemy was close behind.
No Som pedeu whispered a woman and gave
a wailing cry.
People were fighting their way into
railroad trucks at every station for
hundreds of miles across northern
France.
Women were beseeching a place for the
sake of their babies.
There was no food for them.
On journeys of 19 hours or more,
they fainted from heat and hunger and
old woman died and her corpse blocked up
the lavatory.
At night they slept on the pavement in
cities invaded by fugitives at fornay in
Belgium and at Dunkirk on the coast of
France.
There were columns of ambulances
bringing in an endless tide of wounded.
They were laid out stretcher stretcher
in station yards,
500 at a time.
Some of their faces were masks,
have clotted blood.
Some of the bodies were horribly torn.
They breathed with a hard snuffle.
A foul smell came from them.
That shout tread.
They were swilling over the station hall
with disinfecting fluid.
After getting through with one day's
wounded.
The French doctor in charge had received
a telegram from the director of medical
services make ready for 40,000
wounded.
It was during the first battle of the
Marne.
It is impossible set of French doctor.
Four hundred thousand people were in
flight for man twerp into which big
shells were falling.
As English correspondence flatten
themselves against the walls and said
God in heaven to 150,000
people coming across the shelf in rowing
boats,
sailing crafts and rafts invaded one
village in Holland.
They had no food.
Children were mad with fright.
Young mothers had no milk in their
breasts.
It was cold at night,
and there were only a few canal boats
and fisherman's cottages.
And in them were crowds of fugitives.
The odor of human filth exuded from them
as I smell it now.
And it sickens me in remembrance and
quote.
This is a human tragedy of monumental
proportions.
And I have to keep telling myself it's
just getting started.
The French have lost in a couple of days
what the United States,
more than the United States lost in
terms of killed and wounded in the
tenure involvement they had in the
Vietnam war in a few days.
That right there should put the lie to
the idea that the French are somehow to
quote,
um,
you know,
one American surrender monkeys,
they're not surrendering their standing
and dying on French soil.
Um,
you know,
for the sake of just buying their
comrades a little extra time,
Francis showing not only that the French
can take a punch,
which I think everyone at this time
period was fully aware of,
but that modern nation states can.
It's a mixed blessing though in the same
way that boxers say that a clean early
quick knockout is more merciful than
along punishing fight.
There are historians who say maybe it
would have been better for European
culture,
civilization standards.
They are golden age,
if you will.
If the Germans,
he just won this war quickly,
you would have had sort of a changing of
the guard of the great powers,
the Germans moving into a more prominent
position.
Remember there are a new country only
about 44,
45 years in existence and they've been
moving up the power chart ever since
with a bullet as they say in radio.
But it works here too.
Maybe this just seems like a natural
progression of things and if you could
save all the casualties that we know are
coming in a multiyear long carnage fest,
which we'll get to later and maybe save
countries from communism and Nazi-ism,
maybe prevent a second world war and the
Cold War after that.
I mean the dominoes that fall.
If you talk about this war maybe ending
here,
well you can play that game forever,
can't you?
But you can see knowing how bad it's
going to get and how bad it already is.
Why some historians have wondered how
anything it wouldn't be better than what
they're going to experience.
If you are French,
you may say to yourself,
we would never have wanted to live under
the German boot.
You know,
victory was all important.
Yeah,
but what if you could have all those
freshmen who die in the rest of the
story back?
What if you can avoid the second world
war?
I mean,
when does it become worth it?
Same thing to the Germans.
I mean,
you look back and you say,
what if we could have those people,
but what if we could have that wealth
back now?
What if we could have that time where we
were in 1900 back?
That's called crying over historical
spilled milk,
but it doesn't prevent historians from
doing that all the time and it has even
less of a inhibition on people like
yours truly who aren't historians at
all.
The question of what decision should
have happened is obviously a
historically moot point.
The question of what's going to happen
is about to be determined now and one of
the things that sort of makes this
battle,
what it is that shaping up if battles
even the right word for it,
is that everybody kind of knows it's
coming.
It's either coming or the war's over.
Basically the Germans are moving forward
across almost the entire line and the
French and British or moving backwards
across almost the entire line and at
some point they've got to turn around.
They've got to make a stand.
They've got a punch.
The Germans in the nose or there's
nothing that's going to stop them.
And the problem is,
is that everybody's at the end of their
rope.
Everybody has been marching and fighting
for days.
These units that weren't missing a
buckle,
you know,
in parades across Belgium as the Germans
started this war,
or missing a heck of a lot more than
that as are the other allied armies.
This is why it's so important.
If you can actually get fresh troops
into the combat who don't look the way
you know.
For example,
these soldiers that had been in contact
now for almost two weeks,
look at one point during his
inspections,
Jennifer's riding around and he runs
into some French soldiers and Barbara
Tuchman describes the experience quote
on this same day,
August 30th is you offer a visited the
front of the third and fourth armies to
look for forces he could assign to
Foshe.
Another French general talk man
continues on the road.
He passed the retreating columns who had
fought in the den and on the heights of
the muse,
red trousers had faded to the color of
Pale.
Brick coats were ragged and torn shoes
caked with mud.
I's cavernous in faces dulled by
exhaustion and dark with many days
growth of beard,
20 days campaigning seemed to have age,
the soldiers,
as many years they walked heavily as if
ready to drop it.
Every step,
emaciated horses with bones sticking out
and with bleeding.
Harness sores sometimes dropped in the
shafts were hurriedly unharnessed by the
artillery men and dragged off to the
side of the road so as not to obstruct
the way guns looked old and blistered
with barely a few patches of their once
new gray paint showing through the mud
and dirt
and quote,
our Irish friend from the BDF,
John Lucy entitles a whole chapter of
his book,
sleep marching,
and he talks about how there were people
that would just stop at the side of the
road and not care if the Germans were
going to capture them.
They wouldn't move for anything.
Everybody was exhausted and you know,
we had talked about how the Russian
supply and logistics and all that was
falling apart because they weren't one
of the best armies out here.
Trying to cope with the new modern
realities.
Well,
the Germans probably are the best army
trying to cope with the new modern
realities and their logistics aren't
keeping up either.
I mean,
a perfect example is the number of
shells that they're using in the number
of bullets they're using is so far
greater than anything anyone had
predicted that they're running out.
They're rationing.
Some of these generals are are limited
to a few shells a day for their gun.
It makes it very difficult to fight the
battles that you know on paper.
The German prewar planned had sort of
depended on this is where the
operational plans designed before the
war,
whether you want to call them the
Schlieffen plan or their sleep and
multichip plant or just whatever it was
the German generals thought they were
going to do,
doesn't ever take into account enough.
The human element and the variables.
It's wonderfully planned and you know,
t's crossed and I's dotted,
but there are things you just can't
know.
You can't know how tired people are
going to get,
how quickly you can't know how many
times they can fight battles before they
can't fight anymore and you can't
predict when they're going to be things
like hold ups in food and supplies.
The schlieffen plan or whatever you want
to call it,
is falling apart due to the human
variables.
The number one human variable is clues
and von Bulow first and second army
troops cannot March 15 or 20 miles a day
every single day while fighting battles
and getting far ahead of their supplies
and not eating.
I mean they're just,
they're worn down by the time they
reached this stage in the war.
These vaunted,
you know,
tips of the spear are worn down to a
dullness.
In fact,
they're almost down to 50 percent
strength.
What's more,
remember they've had units pulled from
them,
you know,
for over the last several weeks.
Multiple took some and put them down
south and gave him to Prince Rupert.
He,
he sent a couple to the east to help
against the Russians.
Just when you kind of want some nice
fresh troops to throw into this thing,
they aren't there.
The troops you do have though are very
excited about the prospect of ending
this war and capturing Paris.
A member of staff talks about how
getting nearby Paris has reenergized
exhausted.
Men are soldiers are worn out for four
days.
They'd been marching 40 kilometers a
day.
The ground is difficult.
The roads are torn up.
Trees felled the fields pitted by shells
like strainers.
The soldiers stagger at every step.
Their faces are plastered
with dust.
Their uniforms are in rags.
One might call them living rag bags.
They marched with closed eyes and sing
in chorus to keep from falling asleep.
As they march.
The certainty of victory close at hand
and have their triumphal entry into
Paris sustains them and whips up their
enthusiasm.
Without this certainty of victory,
they would fall exhausted.
They would lie down where they are to
sleep it last no matter where,
no matter how and to give their bodies a
drunkenness like that of their souls.
They drink enormously,
but this drunk and this also helps to
keep them up.
Today,
after an inspection,
the general was furiously angry.
He wanted to put an end to this
collective to botch.
We've just persuaded him not to give
severe orders.
It is better not to be too strict
otherwise the army could not go on at
all.
For this abnormal weariness,
abnormal stimulants are needed in Paris.
We shall remedy all this end quote
indeed.
When they saw signs saying that Paris
was 20 slash 22 slash 23 miles in the
distance,
it was as though they've been given a b,
12 shot one German officer on September,
third road,
quote,
one of our battalions was marching.
We're really forward all at once.
While passing a crossroad,
they discovered a sign post on which
they read Paris 37 kilometers.
It was the first sign posts that had not
been erased on seeing it.
The battalion was as though shaken up by
an electric current.
The word Paris,
which they have just read,
drives them crazy.
Some of them embrace the wretched
signpost.
Others dance around,
it cries,
yells of enthusiasm,
accompany these mad actions,
this sign post.
Is there evidence that we are near Paris
that without a doubt we shall soon
really be there.
This notice board has had a miraculous
effect.
Faces light up.
Weariness seems to disappear.
The march has resumed.
Alert cadenced in spite of the
abominable ground in the forest.
Songs burst forth louder.
End Quote.
One can only imagine the disappointment
those soldiers must've felt,
and probably a little bit of
bewilderment went on August 30.
First they changed course and instead of
heading toward Paris,
they make us sort of a left hand turn,
so then they're going to march by Paris
and they're gonna see it on there,
right?
And supposedly according to the
accounts,
some of Von cluck soldiers were able to
see the Eiffel Tower in the distance.
Imagine the confusion and disappointment
and there must've been some
bewilderment,
like what are we doing?
There's Paris where we're right there.
Believe me,
the government in Paris realizes it on
September second,
they flee.
They had to Bordeaux,
which is as far away as you can get from
where the Germans are without,
you know,
not being in France anymore.
It's on the Atlantic coast,
basically the Bay of Biscay,
so they leave a lot of refugees leave
and the soldiers who think,
okay,
the city is basically wide open for us
and we're heading
in a different direction.
This turn by these soldiers in a
different direction.
We'll create a million questions and a
million opportunities and it will make
this story almost impossible to
understand if you're even able to follow
it to this point.
The battle that is shaping up here is
the most complicated I've ever
encountered.
It takes forever to really try to
understand this and then once you think
you got it,
you can't figure out how to explain it
to anyone.
It doesn't even really meet the
definition of battle at all,
but let's understand why it's possible.
Remember,
we've been comparing this little
conflict here to a heavyweight fight and
you know they often have three knocked
down rules,
which means you know,
if you're knocked down three times in
any one round,
the fights over the French at this point
have been knocked down twice in the
first round.
There's nothing seemingly to keep it
from happening again,
except that giant of a man who comes
into his own.
Now,
you know,
the first world war,
his version of the second world wars,
Churchill,
but for France,
Joseph,
Jennifer,
and this is where he makes his name.
This is his moment in history.
This is his destiny right here.
You know,
as Churchill had said,
I felt like I had lived my whole life
just for this moment.
Gioffre is exactly what France needs now
and what they missed in 1940.
This is when he takes charge and
performs miracles and his one of his
generals later said,
I don't know what we would've done
without him.
As we said earlier,
it's possible there are only in this
situation because of poor decisions by
the guy earlier during the blind chess
playing side.
Of this thing,
but now when everyone's panicking and
the French government is moving as far
away as they can and the British
commander on the scene's pretty sure the
war's already over and is worried about
how he gets his army out of here and the
Kaiser's slapping everybody on the
backend,
as Churchill says,
is in a horrible mood.
I mean everything looks really good for
the Germans at this point and the French
could easily lose heart here except
Jennifer is taking charge and starts by
firing generals that aren't within about
a week or 10 days.
He fires a 140 of them to have five army
commanders,
nine corps commanders,
38 of 82 divisional generals and he's
replacing them with much,
much better people.
He even said,
you know,
a lot of these guys were great
professors and they taught at the
academy while,
in other words,
good peace time generals.
He's replacing them with people who've
already demonstrated in this short
period of time that they can get the job
done.
They're fighting generals,
they're names are famous,
they're false.
They're pitocin there,
golly,
any,
and they're going to help him turn the
tide here as soon as they get some
troops to with,
and that's what you offer does next.
He gets involved in figuring out ways to
get troops to the crucial points in the
battle.
He changes his strategy right after the
battle of the frontiers,
you know,
to have all this offensive operations.
He has people sit down,
you know,
hold off the Germans on the defensive
while he figures out a way to get enough
truth to the important place to make
things happen.
And during all of this,
the guy is absolutely freakishly calm,
which is exactly what France needs at
this time.
Remember we said the art of generalship
is kind of bringing what qualities you
bring to the table to bear at the right
time.
And of course there's a little luck
involved in that too,
but this is your first time
and while all the panic was going on as
Gj Meyer says,
Jennifer was imperturbable quote,
but in the midst of it all for remained
impassive,
maddeningly,
silent,
calm.
No matter how alarming the situation,
how terrible the emergency,
the tall and road ton to generalists and
Mo never seemed disturbed.
He became famous for the care he always
took to have a good lunch,
followed by a nap in the day with a good
dinner and always get a full night's
sleep in bed at nine back to work at
five even when things seem to be at
their worst Meyer rights.
He made his staff understand that under
no circumstances was his rest to be
disturbed,
but between meal times in bedtimes,
he was steadily on the move using a big
touring car driven by a grand prix
racing champion to make repeated visits
to his generals,
especially those on the left,
meaning the left flank.
Thus he was able to keep himself in
touch with events and observe his
subordinance inaction and quote and
fire.
A lot of them obviously,
but what this is doing is steadily
creating better leadership in key
positions,
learning from mistakes and taking real
time knowledge,
not theory,
and applying it and taking men who could
inspire troops in hopeless situations.
Of course,
Jennifer doesn't command all the
generals in this war on his side.
He's fighting a coalition battle and
there's a British army that makes up a
part of his battle line that is hesitant
about involving itself in anything
involving combat at the moment,
Sir John French,
the ironically named leader of the
British Expeditionary Force,
doesn't trust the French.
He thinks he's already had his flank
exposed once and didn't put in great
danger.
He doesn't see any evidence that the
French can be trusted to win this war.
I mean the Germans have basically thrown
a the Schlieffen plan if there ever was
one out the window here and attacked
along the entire Franco German border,
which is that area that is so well
protected by forts that the Germans
thought it worth violating Belgium's
neutrality and bringing the British into
the war just so they could avoid that
area and those forts.
Well now you know,
three weeks into the war,
they're attacking along that entire
front and if they break through,
they will completely surround the French
and destroy their armies.
The problem is is that those forts were
originally avoided for a reason.
They're formidable and all of a sudden
the French troops in that area are doing
a pretty decent job on the defensive.
They're still losing lots of people,
but all of a sudden they get a chance to
find out that this war that we're going
to call the first world war is the one
where the defense has the temporary
dominance over the offense and the
French.
In the last battle.
Only days ago,
we're doing band net charges and
advancing in close order and all those
things you're not supposed to do
standing up during the shrapnel attacks.
Now they get a chance to be the ones
behind the machine guns and behind the
field guns firing behind them,
into Germans,
advancing in the open while the French
gunners dig themselves a little holes
that are almost deep enough to be called
trenches already and see what the power
of defense means.
You know,
for them,
the good news is they don't get over run
by Germans.
The bad news is it looks like they can
spare a few troops,
which is what Jennifer is doing now.
This is where the real miracle comes in.
The guy can scrounge troops from
everywhere.
He pulls them off of the line in all
these battles near the French fortress
line where the French needed every man
they've gotten.
Jennifer's taken people anyway.
He needs them elsewhere more.
He's taking newly returned wounded back.
He's got know colonial troops coming on
boats.
He's taking people from the far west of
France and he's.
He's using the rail system to get them
to an important concentration points
fast.
He creates a new army.
He calls the sixth and he puts it over
by the,
the flank of the British expeditionary
force.
He creates another one called the night.
He puts it over as a reserve kind of by
Paris.
He doesn't want to have an army in
Paris,
which is a great fortress actually,
but the government of France makes him
have one,
so they put Jennifer's old commander
Galliani.
I'm in charge of it and put him in Paris
and basically everyone thinks he's just
going to stay there and you know,
man,
the walls with his men.
That's the plan anyway.
Theoretically and day after day,
more French trains are arriving and more
troops are,
you know,
de training and moving over to the front
over by Paris,
facing,
you know,
the projected direction that this sledge
is gonna fall.
And remember they're losing troops
everyday they're down to half their
original strengthened.
Here's Shawfer everyday bringing in more
French troops to face it.
All of a sudden the numerical advantage
begins to diminish.
And then on August 31st aircraft,
yes,
aircraft again starting to make an
impact already in this early 20th
century war aircraft,
notice that the Germans have changed
direction.
The same thing we told you that those
troops have been bewildered
by all of a sudden they're not heading
toward Paris anymore.
What's going on?
And more importantly,
when they changed direction,
they present their flanks to the newly
created forces,
especially the one in Paris.
There's a chance for a counter attack
here,
a chance to turn around,
you know the entire great retreat and
attack Joffrin needs to convince Sir
John French of the BDF that now's the
time,
the opportunities there,
we need you,
and he gives one of these great
speeches.
This is the way he recorded himself and
remember Sir John French doesn't speak
French and Gioffre doesn't speak
English,
and the translator is another British,
generally guy named Wilson who's much
more diplomatic and likes the French,
much more than Sir John French does,
and so there's some fun moments there
too.
Here's what Jennifer's own account of
his encounter with French to try to
convince them that now is the time to
strike.
This was our opportunity.
It's the last chance.
All the cards are on the table.
Shows that there was another side to
this man.
He wasn't just the impenetrable obelisk
where you couldn't figure out what that
placid look on his face meant.
Sometimes he could be positively
Churchillian,
and this was one of them.
He told French,
a suspicious and pessimistic French
quote.
I put my whole soul into the effort to
convince the Field Marshal,
I told him that the decisive moment had
arrived and that we must not let it
escape.
We must go to battle with every man both
of us had and free from all
reservations.
So far as the French army is concerned,
I continued.
My orders are given and whatever may
happen,
I intend to throw my last company into
the balance to win victory and save
France.
It is in her name that I come to ask you
for British assistance and I urge it
with all my power I have in me.
I cannot not believe that the British
army will refuse to do it.
Share in the supreme crisis history
would severely judge your absence.
Then as I finished,
carried away by my convictions and the
gravity of the moment,
I remember bringing down my fist on a
table which stood at my elbow and
crying.
Ms Dot Marshall,
the honor of England is at stake.
Up to this point,
French had listened imperturbably to the
officer who was translating what I'd
said,
but now his face suddenly reddened there
ensued a long,
impressive silence and then with visible
emotion,
he murmured.
I will do all that I possibly can not
understanding English.
I asked Wilson,
what's her?
John had said,
he merely replied,
the field marshal says yes.
I had distinctly felt the emotion which
seemed to grip the British commander in
chief above all,
I had remarked the tone of his voice and
I felt as did all the witnesses to the
scene that these simple words were
equivalent to an agreement signed and
sworn to tea,
which was already prepared,
was then served.
Barbara Tuchman,
of course,
related a little bit more dramatically.
She says that a tear welled up in Sir
John French's I and it rolled down his
cheek before.
He said,
I don't know how to tell him.
Just tell him.
We'll do everything we can to one of
those critical dramatic moments in
history when you want that you want the
guy who would have been the real best
first house of hardcore history,
I think if it weren't hg wells,
would have to be Churchill winded and in
his account of the first world war,
which you know,
is full of Churchillian bias,
all,
all the things that you normally get
with him,
but what's fun about it is no one
explains it like he does even with the
biases and he was there.
Churchill's histories are always a
combination of romance,
um,
history,
and if he's in them in a personal memoir
too,
I love the way he sort of explains how
many things had to line up.
Right?
All along,
you know,
the war for this opportunity to be
presented to the general in Paris who
sees fun,
Cook's First Army turned their flank to
him.
Here's how Churchill puts it,
quote,
assuredly,
no human brain had conceived the design
nor had human hand set the pieces on the
board.
Several separate and discrepant series
of events had flowed together first.
The man Galliani is on the spot fixed in
his fortress.
He could not move toward the battle,
so the mighty battle has been made to
come to him.
Second,
the weapon has been placed in his hands,
the army of mental re.
It was given him for one purpose,
the defensive Paris.
He will use it for another,
a decisive maneuver in the field.
It was given him against the wishes of
buffer.
It will prove the means of gioffre
salvation.
Third,
the Opportunity Cook,
swinging forward in hot pursuit of as he
believed the routed British and
demoralized French will present his
whole right flank and rear as he passes
Paris to Galliani and men are in his
hand.
Observe,
not one of those factors would have
counted without the other two.
All are interdependent.
All are here and all are here.
Now,
Galliani realize the position in a
flash.
I dare not believe it.
He exclaimed.
It is too good to be true,
but it is true.
Churchill writes,
confirmation arrives hour by hour.
He vibrates within through Z.
Asm and quote,
this is what sets up the famous battle
of the Marne.
The most complicated battle you'll ever
find,
the battle of the Marne is so hard to
understand for a couple of reasons.
The first one is just like the battle of
the frontiers that just recently
happened.
These World War One,
battles are modern in scale and scope.
They are so much larger and so much
longer than battles in the past were,
I mean a hundred years ago,
Napoleon is being defeated at Waterloo,
a giant battle involving three global
powers and you could from one end to the
battlefield to the other in no time.
You could see one side from the other
with those little telescopes.
They would just put two there.
I the battle started in the morning and
was over at the end of the day.
I mean that's 100 years ago now.
The battles last for,
well this one will last for officially a
week,
but really last longer than that,
the battlefield is at least 100 miles
long depending on who you believe or the
entire front.
You know,
according to other historians,
you could legitimately have fought at
the battle of the Marne and not know it.
Turn to a buddy that fought there with
you and say,
now where are we at?
The Marne was fighting officially part
of that or not,
because really it's a catchall term for
all the fighting that is going on when
what really the Marne is all about
happens,
which is that the great retreat ends and
the French and British armies turnaround
and launch into contact.
Again,
not to be fair,
there are parts of the front that have
never not been in contact in the south.
They've been fighting pretty much since
minute one and it's never stopped.
That's why he told them that they were
in the battle of the Marne.
They might not even understand it
because they've never not been fighting.
Historians like Eric Bros suggests that
the battle of the Marne is everything
that was fought in this one area.
You know from the center of France up.
He describes it this way,
quote,
what has come to be known as the battle
of the Marne should really be thought of
as the battle of France for all
together.
50 six allied and 43 and a half German
divisions engaged one another in a
titanic struggle along the line,
stretching from Paris to the eastern
frontier and quote in a sense what
really happened is the opportunity that
was presented by an open flank as we
said,
fun first army turns,
shows his flank to Paris.
Paris now has an army that can hit him
in the flank and here we're going to
have a battle,
but that just becomes the opportunity
that everybody was waiting for before
they turn these armies around.
Anyway,
this had to happen at some point.
This is Francis last throw.
Everybody knows that this has to occur.
The problem is is that the commanders
who are actually with the troops,
not these guys,
that the general headquarters and the
highest staff officers,
the ones who are marching with the
actual soldiers,
are appalled that this is being
considered with the exception of a
couple of notable commanders.
I mean,
one commander,
one general supposedly looks like he'd
been hit in the head with a club when
somebody said that they were going over
to the attack.
His troops had been retreating for days
and days and days at an amazing pace.
They're closer in rags.
They're weapons hardly fire.
Their shoes are falling off their feet.
They can't stand because they're so
sleepy and then you get the word that
you're going to attack.
But several these French generals
that Jennifer has put in,
commander tough,
hardcore fighting generals.
I mean,
Ferdinand Farash says,
right.
You know,
during this encounter,
quote,
attack,
whatever happens,
the Germans are at the extreme limit of
their efforts.
Victory will come to the side that
outlast the other,
and to quote the French general who
takes over from land resnick at the
fifth army,
when Jennifer fires him famously comes
to the phone like one second after he
takes command.
Here's from a commander in the scene
that says it's impossible.
His troops are falling down,
tired.
They can't march and he says,
March or die and offer issues.
His famous notice to the army's when he
tells them that the great attack is
beginning and it's a classic stand or
die exhortation.
This is France,
leaving it all on the table.
Jaffra announces the turnaround and the
attack.
Really the recommencement of contact
along the entire battle line,
and we've seen how deadly on a day to
day basis contact with the enemy in 20th
century warfare is he announces it
thusly quote,
we are about to engage in a battle on
which the fate of our country depends
and it is important to remind all ranks
that the moment has passed for looking
to the rear.
All our efforts must be directed to
attacking and driving back the enemy
troops that can advance no farther must
at any price hold onto the ground.
They've conquered and die on the spot
rather than give way under the
circumstances which face us.
No active week,
yes can be tolerated and quote when the
general in charge of Paris Gal Yanni,
and I think I pronounced his name
differently every time I've said it,
but Galliani famously is asked by the
general of sixth army what their plans
are.
If they're overrun,
you know what a Paris gets over running
the enemy over runs.
Where are we going to go and go?
Yeah,
and he looks at him,
just says nowhere.
This is it.
Imperial War Museum,
oral historian Peter Harte describes the
crux of the battle of the Marne about as
well as anyone can in the short space of
words.
He says,
quote,
what followed was a complex battle that
defies easy explanation.
By this time,
the German right wing was actually
outnumbered by the French divisions
rushing up from the south as the German
first army tried to turn to face the
assault from the French sixth army along
the line of the river ORC,
a huge chasm of some 30 miles opened up
between cluck and the second army on his
left flank amidst the chaos,
the men of the B,
e,
f having beautifully about turned,
found themselves advancing alongside the
French fifth army into the gap between
the German first and second armies.
There was no great battle,
no huge drama,
but the penetration between their armies
threatened utter for the Germans
and on the ninth of September,
von Moltke ordered his right wing to
retreat and to quote
now Peter Hearts,
a great reputable modern historian,
and that's about as,
as wonderful a passage there as you
could ever hope to get from one of those
folks,
but see if they would jettison some of
their wonderful history,
Asante and throw a little juror and
drama,
um,
maybe little exaggerations and romance
in there.
You could get something like this from
Churchill who describes the same thing
as only he can.
And he says this about the British army,
along with the fringe advancing into
this crucial gap that will change this
whole conflict and turn the battle of
the Marne,
which let's be honest,
the French are once again taken it on
the Chin when they're in full contact
with the fabulous German army.
This is what we'll decide the occasion
though,
and Churchill puts it in Churchill,
Ian terms,
quote,
no human genius planned that the British
army should advance into this gap.
A series of tumultuous events had cast
them into this position in the line.
When they advanced,
there was a gap in front of them on the
whole front.
It was the line of least resistance
along it.
They board and punched and it led into
the strategic vitals of the German right
wing.
Hi Destiny.
Blind fate regulated the nun too
vigorous but nevertheless decisive
movements of this British army.
It marches on wondering what has
happened to the monster which has
pursued it with weapon yell since Mom's
von Bulow finds his right wing being
rolled back by the fifth French army and
himself cutoff continually from his
right hand to comrade Kluk by the
British advance Kluk.
Just as he's got himself into a position
to fight machinery finds his left and
all the rear of his left hopelessly
compromised and exposed and quote.
It's a crazy moment.
It reminds one of,
of of warfare in the 18th century.
They used to call it positional warfare
where a lot of the fighting was simply
trying to,
you know,
March around a flank or or get to a
point where you forced your enemy into a
place where they had to retreat just
because of positioning by accident.
As Churchill so eloquently put it,
the British army had almost accidentally
probed its way into the German liver.
Doesn't get much better than that in
terms of the high drama does it,
and it completely obscures the soldier's
perspective on the ground of which we
have very little more and more firsthand
accounts,
especially from the German side,
will be made available as the war goes
on.
I keep having to tell myself that a lot
of the people fighting in these battles
will never make it home to write their
memoirs.
These are people who don't get to go
home until either the war is over or
there are so vitally injured.
They can't fight anymore,
and a lot of the German soldiers on this
frontal might leave memoirs that someone
like yours truly might be lucky enough
to have translated into English,
leave their bones on.
Some of these battlefields nonetheless,
you know,
one thing's clear,
I remember reading an account once and
there's lots of accounts like these and
you can specifically find them in
publications that came out not long
after the war.
I remember I have one in my house
actually in many of you do too.
It's in a great series of books written
just after the war and you read it and
it's an account of this unbelievable
battle.
It sounds like something out of the Lord
of the rings or some Napoleonic thing
with charges of 10,000
cavalry mowed down by canons.
These amazing,
heroic moments,
German heroism,
French heroism,
really thrilling moving stuff,
and it turns out that that's just one of
the little battles.
Well,
I mean comparatively that formed
something called the battle of Nancy.
The Battle of Nancy is just something
that formed a part of the battle of the
Marne.
There are individual stories,
many battles whose names have been
forgotten by almost everyone that form
the whole here.
The Battle of the Marne is that human
tragedy,
as we said earlier about what the
civilians are suffering on a mass scale
and the drama and the suffering and the
heroism and the stories that would break
our hearts if we knew them are going on
up and down the line from Switzerland to
the Belgian border.
In fact,
they're going on in the eastern front
to.
We haven't even talked about the
simultaneous events that are happening.
While this is going on,
the armies of Luton,
Dorfman,
Hindenburg,
and the east are wrapping up their
conflict.
They're against renon comps army after
Tannenberg in Galicia,
which is over kind of were
austro-hungarian,
Poland and Russian interests meet.
There are terrible battles going on.
The Austro-hungarian Hungarians are
getting smashed in a way that they will
never recover from,
and this is all happening at the same
time.
Part of what makes this conflict so
disorienting for everyone who's facing
it is how quickly it's all happened.
When you think about the Second World
War,
for example,
realize that there's no big fighting
between the major powers for about eight
months after the Second World War is
declared.
Hitler goes into Poland,
Poland falls fast.
I mean that's all quick and relatively
painless by world war standards.
It'll be eight months before the Germans
are in,
you know,
real big contact with French and British
armies.
This was three weeks old and all the
major participants have clashed head on.
There's more than a million people dead.
This is the worst nightmare of every
prewar profit predicting what was going
to happen when you combined the mass
armies that the Napoleonic era unleashed
on steroids by the way,
with the modern technology and weapons
and systems that were being developed
all through the 18 hundreds.
This is a great filter.
When you lose more than a million people
in the first blink of an eye and the is
now
obviously going to last a while,
how many people are going to die before
this thing reaches a resolution?
What is the resolution
again?
To simplify it?
What really happens is when the entire
French and British line turns around and
smashes back into the German line,
there's one spot where they just
penetrate.
There's nothing really in front of them
and that's the spot that the BDF,
the British expeditionary force and some
French forces go through and see head.
Vaughn and von Bulow not already been
fighting somebody they could have turned
and crushed these forces that we're
penetrating into that gap,
but they are fighting other people
that's known as pinning the enemy.
Clucas fighting those forces that are
coming at him from Paris.
Von Bulow is fighting other armies so
they can't turn,
and if they do turn than the armies they
were fighting or hitting them in the
back,
they're trapped.
The only thing they can do to alleviate
this open flank issue is to pull back
von Moltke when all this is going on,
falls apart,
and if you ask me,
understandably so,
this is a guy who's been under
tremendous pressure already and as he
watches this plan,
so important that for years it had been
known as dare tog the day when this plan
is finally used.
You know,
whatever the heck the plan was.
Really,
this day means the day that the Germans
launched the war,
he's watching it collapsed in front of
his eyes,
realizing also that this will all be
blamed on him.
He's coming apart at the seams
he writes to his wife.
Has all of this is becoming clear quote,
I cannot find words to describe the
crushing responsibility that is weight
upon my shoulders during the last few
days and still weighs on me today.
The appalling difficulties of our
present situation.
Hang before my eyes like a dark curtain
through which I can see nothing.
And to quote one of UNMOLD costs.
Staff officers,
a colonel named Bauer wrote,
quote,
desperate panics seized severely the
entire army or to be more correct.
The greater part of its leaders.
It looked at its worst at the supreme
command.
Multaka completely collapsed.
He sat with a Pallid face gazing at the
map dead.
Do all feeling a broken man.
End Quote.
Churchill was sympathetic when he wrote,
quote everything now converged upon
[inaudible],
who was [inaudible].
He was the shadow of a great name.
He was the nephew of the old field
marshal and had been his aide de camp.
He was an ordinary man rather,
according air,
a man about the palace,
agreeable to the emperor in the me of
peace,
the sort of man who does not make too
much trouble with the sovereign who
knows how to suppress his own
personality,
what there is of it,
a good harmless,
respectable,
ordinary man,
and onto this ill fated being crashes,
the brutal remorseless,
centripetal impingement of tides and
compulsion's under which the greatest
captains of history might have blanched
and quote Multaka had later written
while he still lived that in the moment
of supreme crisis,
he had grown quite nervous and quote
lots of sources.
Report that von Mold Cup went to the
Kaiser at this point and said,
majesty,
we just lost the war.
I have never been able to confirm that
though,
and truth be told they didn't lose the
war here.
What's just happened is the chances for
an early knockout blow an outright
German victory.
That's what's been compromised,
and I'm going to say compromise because
it's an open question.
Whether or not the Germans blew this or
the French simply rallied and gain the
victory.
There are lots of mistakes on the German
side that people will point to basically
insinuating that without those mistakes,
the French go down and yet look at the
fact that they were still there after
suffering unprecedented levels of
casualties and punishment
and forget about that for a minute and
understand the condition that those
armies are in before they turn around at
the battle of the Marne.
They are falling apart,
dead on their feet,
you know,
wearing rags and unable to keep their
eyes open and that's who the general
from the first army,
von Cluck,
that's who he singles out when he talks
about the part you know of this war so
far that surprised him.
He wrote quote that men will let
themselves be killed where they stand is
a well known thing and counted on in
every plan of battle,
but that men who have retreated for 10
days sleeping on the ground and half
dead with fatigue should be able to take
up their rifles and attack when the
bugle sounds.
It is a thing upon which we never
counted,
it was a possibility not studied in our
war academy and quote.
So he was obviously impressed.
There's no way to deny and,
and listen,
we don't want to shortchange the British
expeditionary force either,
that they proved to be potentially
crucial to this whole thing and as
Churchill pointed out,
sort of providential he at the right
place and at the right time sometimes,
but this is one of those victories where
you just have to tip your hat a little
bit to what the French achieved.
This is monumental stuff.
Um,
it is truly heroic.
It's a little like the Alamo for
Americans,
but on an enormous scale.
And at the same time I want to remember
the Germans in all this too.
As we said earlier,
they get a bad rap from a lot of us
because of the Second World War and
rightly so,
but a lot of that is connected to the
first world war in a funny way.
I see them,
you know,
not to bring up some sort of science
fiction reference.
I mean,
where would that come from?
But,
but they're a little like an akin
skywalker,
this,
this nation that's new and young and has
so much promise and potential.
Hg Wells had the greatest name for them
I've ever heard at this point.
He called them the best and the
wickedest nation in the world.
You know,
the militarism that so scared him in his
socialistic sensibilities was balanced
out by the fact that the Germans were so
admirable in so many respects what the
Germans called color tour,
their music and their and their writings
and their sophistication and and and
their science,
my gosh,
and their education.
We wells is overflowing with all these
wonderful things to say about Germans,
but they've got this flaw and it's this
militarism and they're the best and the
wicked is people in Europe and somewhere
along the line and akin skywalker turns
into darth vader in the poor.
Germans get that to be their image for
the 20th century.
You wonder again what the enormous
stakes of this in a German really defeat
our.
If unmold can.
The Germans had been victorious here.
The entire German history in the 20th
century is different and perhaps much,
much,
much more positive,
almost certainly for Germans and for
everyone else too.
I think
it's a very interesting what if
scenario,
and it's important to remember that when
you think about these soldiers dying on
the ground in these nameless awful
battles,
whether they be French,
British,
German,
or very soon,
a lot more people from Canada and South
Africa and Australia and India,
China,
I mean this is going to become an
internationalized war soon.
All these people are good people caught
up.
Well,
they're just people caught up in,
in,
in the grand plans and grinding wheels
of of nation states.
They went into these conflicts for
reasons that are understandable today,
patriotism duty,
love of country to protect your family,
all those kinds of things.
They also went for reasons that were
really important still in the 19th
century,
but that are a little different today.
Glory heroism,
Romance,
as I said,
they still exist but not quite like they
did back.
You know,
from the beginning of history,
until right around this time in
September 19,
14,
a general named von [inaudible] talked
about the changes that this first month
of the first world war and created in
that facade of romantic war when he said
quote,
if war was once a chivalrous dual,
it's now a dastardly slaughter and
quote,
the suffering on the ground,
regardless of which side you're on,
is pitiable and horrific.
And you know,
I always try to make sure,
and I hope I'm successful at this that
were never exploitive of the,
of the terrible things that are going on
to the people in these stories.
We retell.
The reason that I use them is because
for me,
these stories intrigue me because I
always put myself in them and then I try
to imagine handling these things and as
a person who's interested in the
extremes of human experience,
there are almost no exceptions to the
stories we talk about on this program.
I can't imagine it.
I mean,
I just feel like I would wilt under the
pressures that these people lived
through.
I mean,
when you talk about being interested in
the extremes of human nature and
wondering what I would do in the same
situation,
I think about the worst places in the
world you can think of.
Um,
and if there's a top three or four or
five lists out there,
one of them on my list is the western
front in the first world war and we're
about to get there.
And it is about the worst experience in
the world.
I was joking on the hardcore history
twitter feed,
which by the way,
you can follow it at hardcore history
that it's taking us longer to get the
episode you've just heard released and
to you.
And by the way,
thank you for your patients.
It's always appreciated.
Then the amount of time that was
actually covered in the episode itself.
And I think if you were crunching the
data and projecting outward based on how
long the show you just heard was,
you've probably figured that it's going
to take us about 250 episodes to cover
the first world war.
And God forbid we go afterwards and to
19,
19 and the treaties and all that,
we'll be doing this the rest of our
lives.
We're obviously not going to do that.
Um,
the episode you just heard focused on,
to be honest,
I'm a series of events,
the prewar stuff and the,
the first and opening moves that's
common in almost all the approaches of
the first world war because they set the
stage for what comes afterwards.
For example,
already,
you know,
as this story ends,
the trenches are cropping up organically
along the western front.
It's the iconic image of the first World
War,
right?
Trenches have always been known.
Fortifications always been known.
Going back to ancient history,
but never on this scale,
never this long,
never in positions,
you know,
that we're on as almost immobile as
this.
Never under these sorts of conditions.
It's going to create an almost unique
experience for the people who have to go
through it.
And again,
something fascinating when I consider
how I myself would have behaved in
similar circumstances,
but it's going to make the battles
somewhat similar,
you know,
so you'll be able to a little bit about
the big ones,
but not have to go too much into the
experience over and over again because
it becomes similar in each of the
battles.
The people fighting in the trenches in
one battle often have similar sorts of
day to day experiences from people
fighting in the trenches in another
battle.
So we will have the opportunity as the
program moves along to zoom in and zoom
out as needed.
This is going to allow us though to
focus on a bunch of other things,
including how the generals managed to
deal with the fact that they're no
longer operating with prewar plans.
They have to actually think now learn,
apply their thinking in novel ways.
We're going to find out how flexible
these 19th century men are as they try
to adjust on the fly in real time to the
challenges of 20th century warfare,
which no one's ever really tried yet.
They're going to have to contend with
and we are going to deal with questions
like changes in the air,
changes at c,
changes involving WMD and things we're
still dealing with today and changes
involving the scope of this war that
encompasses,
you know,
the rest of the world basically in one
way or another.
The first world war is about to go
global and underground.
In the next episode of blueprint for
Armageddon,
we just want to make it clear that we
are bought and paid for around
here@DanCarlin.com.
Thanks again for all your bucket show
donations.
They're the reason we're still here.