Then let him come
in to this house.
We're board top papa ladies and
gentleman
of sourdough.
That's your nickname.
I love that.
I saw that this morning.
Shower.
It's really bad Ass New York Times.
They mentioned you in the New York
Times,
the New York time.
I talk about the New York Times.
I'll keep my mouth closed.
The New York Times.
I,
uh,
I'm now friends with the New York Times
because of your podcast.
And what does he like a,
he's a great guy.
The gray old lady.
Old Lady.
Uh,
so I,
when I was in New York,
I went with my daughter.
They gave us a tour of the New York
Times.
They invited anytime you want to come
because of the sour dough,
because of the sour dough.
It's incredible story.
And because of they saw it on this show.
That's incredible.
Yeah.
Wow.
This show brings me riches to this show.
Got An article written in the New York
Times about sourdough bread and starters
was absolutely fascinating though.
And was.
I had no idea.
Yeah,
that's the new world.
I read an article today in the New York
Times.
It was so disappointing though.
It was some woman wrote an article
blaming the Patriarchy on women drinking
too much sexism on women during the.
I'm like,
is this the fucking New York Times?
Like how desperado are they for ratings
or for reading or sourdough starter
Americans rising pen.
There it is.
You have a high.
There's a better picture than that
though.
I don't remember what it was there.
It was
my little starter sitting on my counter.
That's awesome.
I was just stirring it up today.
There's a fucking really disturbing
article that I read in The Washington
Post this morning.
The news is getting fucking super wacky.
Glenn Greenwald tweeted it.
The Washington Post wrote an article
about this settlement in Israel
settlement that Israel wants to knock
the settlement in Israel that they want
to bulldoze,
and they called it a miserable town,
miserable town that Israel wants to
bulldoze this miserable town,
and they're like,
whoa,
whoa.
Who fucking wrote this article?
Like,
how did you.
How'd you like naming the language?
I'm going to write miserable article.
You're dealing with like dirt poor
people that are living in these horrible
conditions and they just decided to go
with that as their title.
Look at this title.
Tell me like,
this is your wants to bulldog.
Oh,
they changed it to ramshackle village.
they changed fucks.
But Europe is providing life support.
Wow.
They call it was miserable village this
morning.
Ram shackled sounds Kinda cute.
Ramshackled is still.
It's like they're trying.
Yeah.
Ramshackle is like,
okay,
if it's white people,
if you're talking about white people
that live in trailer parks,
he's got a ramshackle trailer park,
corncob pipe and he hangs out
drinks from his jug at night.
He's got a bunch of cars on blocks in
the yard it,
so it's not fancy but assures
ramshackle.
Yeah,
that makes sense.
But this morning it was the,
the title was miserable.
Don't you feel that?
Uh,
writing and all of journalism,
like it's all leveled out.
Like sometimes you read an article in
the Huffington post and they suck you
into like some article and it's written
by like a high school journalism
student.
It's just sensational.
It,
it just goes like three paragraphs in
before it even comes out,
like the heading.
It's a.
It had been.
Then you read some stuff from the New
York Times or other places and some of
it,
some of it's definitely much smarter,
but some of it is a little opinionated.
Has these little things in it and it's
lazy.
It's so.
It seems like it's because there's such
a rush.
You can't spend as much time on stories.
People get lazy and careless.
While I also think that when people are
at their best,
they write about what they love.
Like if you read a really lazy Article
From The New York Times writer about
something,
yeah,
maybe that guy would write an amazing
article about handmade furniture.
You know what I'm saying?
Because maybe he's like into it into
handmade furniture,
but there's a lot of articles that have
people writing.
They're just fucking just trying to get
them done.
Yeah,
but the problem is that a lot of that's
in the news.
It's not,
you know,
but don't you feel that way about the
new.
Sometimes like,
enough,
I just,
I can't do this anymore.
You need to digest the news.
Yeah,
forget it.
Yeah.
That's one of my crusades for real.
I have a thing.
I get the newspaper in the morning
because I want to spend maybe 20
minutes,
maybe a half hour,
looking at some news stories and then
that's it.
That's all Tom Papa needs to know about
the world's events because I can't do
anything about it and if I just check in
another half hour check in another half,
a 24 hours of that day's gone and you
feel sick,
you're paranoid,
you're sick,
you're upset.
I turn the news off.
It's a barrage and I need to talk to the
fucking New York time about what
constitutes breaking news.
Listen New York Times just because
Anthony Wiener got busted sexting again.
That's not fucking breaking news.
It's pretty great story though.
It's a good story,
but it's not the New York Times the
saying this is war.
Yeah,
war is breaking,
right?
Earthquake,
breaking news,
breaking news stories.
The other shit is just a story.
Yeah,
breaking,
but it's not super critical.
It,
it's.
But you know,
you have to keep feeding the beast 24
hours a day and they got to keep you in
so they have to make it urgent.
They have to
watch this video on sexual desire for
content.
Sock away.
I've heard the earth is flat
content and how they gonna make you pay
attention to the content by scaring the
shit out of you,
scaring the shit out of you or making
you angry or writing something
ridiculous
like sexism is why women like to drink.
That is ridiculous.
Are you sure?
That was a near 100 percent.
One hundred percent find it.
Jamie.
Jamie's on it.
Because I was at the New York Times
building because of the sourdough
article and I saw no such thing.
It was pretty cool to watch.
I mean it was cool to like be inside the
New York Times.
Well this was my point about Huffington
post when you were saying that it's like
it's written by a high school kid.
It could easily have been like there's a
lot of contributors to the Huffington
Post.
A Lot,
a lot of contributors to a lot of these
online news sources.
Yeah.
How Wall Street pros talk,
talk women down.
That's on it now.
It was out today.
It's about sexism and drinking sexism
and drinking a that the patriarchy makes
women drink.
It was like the pressure of dealing with
sexism all day.
It makes women drink.
That is.
It's so unbelievably ridiculous.
But for anybody who hates those
arguments and it's beautiful because
it's so stupid that it's like self
parody.
It's like,
it's so dumb.
Oh really?
That's what makes you drink because
everybody who doesn't drink,
how come it doesn't work on them?
It's almost like that headline is to a
level of this will piss them off.
Yes,
exactly.
And here we are talking about it.
Yeah.
So she might be right.
You know,
I mean,
yeah,
definitely.
Women must face sexism because a lot of
men are sexist for sure,
but many pegs you have to work with a
guy for eight hours a day for five
years.
If he's not gonna try to fuck you.
He's going to be thinking about fucking
you all the time and he's definitely
gonna play like little games.
Yeah.
See how far he can go to say,
see what you say when he says this.
Look,
we work with guys when they are
completely free when we're alone with a
guy like when you're in school or
whatever and working with people,
you know,
you get jobs with these men,
and when we're alone with them,
the shit is sad.
I mean,
right.
I mean it's filtered is brutal about
everyone in the office about their
wives.
They're pulling out their parts.
It's not the same story.
This is the opposite of that.
Says sexism isn't driving women to
drink.
I found something.
I'm not seeing something from the times
though.
Okay,
I'll send it to you.
I'll find it here.
But the,
it doesn't matter.
You don't even need to look at it.
It's just an article.
But you know what I mean?
Men are such pigs,
pigs.
You can be in an office with another guy
and you know,
the coast is clear the stuff.
So for him to look at each other and go,
you know,
this never leaves this room.
Right,
and that would be it.
I would do to her
conversations and then they walk out
among all the people and they that they
can keep it together.
Like knowing what we know that they can
keep it together when they're mixed with
everybody else is kind of astounding.
I've,
I feel like the more likely a man is to
wear loafers with those tassels,
the more likely has to have these deep
dark visions fantasies.
I'm sadly,
you get out of him if you just get a
couple of cocktails in him yet because
he's probably pretty wealthy,
probably makes a good living and
probably is been married to the same
woman for quite a long time as children.
Probably has some sort of religious
affiliation.
Yeah,
most likely you're in
deep desires
if you're living or working well,
if you're working with that guy,
it's almost crazier than living with
them.
You think about it like if you,
if your wife works all day,
so if you work all day,
your wife works all day,
you're not seeing each other for nine
hours out of the day,
right?
Travel time.
If you're.
If you're super lucky,
then you come home.
How long are you awake for?
Three hours.
Four hours at the most.
How much is this really good time with
exactly how much time is like,
stop fighting.
Don't do that.
That's not yours.
No,
no,
no.
Yours looks like that,
but yours is different.
This is being.
That's the reality is if your wife works
with some fucking creepy dude,
that creepy dude sees her more than you
do.
Yeah,
and I think work environments are very
strange for human beings.
Not saying that we shouldn't engage in
them,
but what I'm saying is that being in a
traditional work environment where
you're working your way up the corporate
ladder,
so everybody's full of Shit.
Everybody is at certain point in time
saying the thing that's the right thing
to say for their career versus what they
really feel about things.
Oh yeah.
It was probably not a lot of room for
opinion.
A lot of it is about the company and how
important that company is.
And then fucking,
if you're lucky,
you get to like crack a joke by the
water cooler,
right?
That's like your little freedom of the
day or maybe they'll let you dress your
cubicle up.
You could have like a little fucking
star wars guy in the cubicle.
Joe's a wild man.
Show them your socks.
Look at the death star my cubicle.
I'm a big star wars fan.
I can't wait for the next step.
So he's the guy.
When you,
when people come up to go,
oh,
there's a guy in my office.
He is so funny.
Yeah,
it's star wars.
It's like that.
Thoreau quote.
Most men live lives of silent
desperation.
I'm sure.
Most women too.
I think most humans,
there's a lot a lot of doing shit.
You don't want to do what?
You know,
what I find though,
like people who are in those jobs,
you know,
and they get pretty high up and they
were creative people.
Whatever.
They don't,
um,
they don't question things as much as we
do that,
can't you?
You.
Yeah,
but I think that's why they're able to
get into it.
Also.
I don't think their heads are.
I wonder if you know,
if that's what causes it or if that's
like a mindset that one sort of like
boxes themselves into it.
An early age.
It's probably a little of both,
but I definitely have a couple of
friends who are just fun guys.
They work,
they've been in corporations
their whole careers and they just don't
question it.
There's never a part of them that's
like,
that's ever thought,
oh,
what am I doing?
It just got out of school and said,
let's go.
We're going to go do this and then you
go watch the rangers and it'll be fine
and they don't think about it.
And he was always that way.
Like he just kind of slid in and it's
almost like ignorance is bliss in those
situations.
Those guys generally like to drink.
Yeah,
that's a big one because the drinking is
the best way to say who gives a fuck at
the end of the day when you're done with
your work,
you have a couple of pops with the boys
and all of a sudden you're laughing.
Who gives a shit about the stock
profile?
Yeah.
Who gives a shit about the lawn?
He gives a shit.
I would be in that environment like,
oh my God,
he's acting like a dick to me.
What is he trying to do and why do they
hate me so much?
Those guys are just like,
screw him,
he's an asshole.
And then he'd go and go and get to work
with a guy.
Right,
exactly.
What are they going to do that's done?
That's one of the things that separates
alcohol from marijuana.
Like that's like the dividing line
between how it makes you look at things
in your life that aren't desirable.
It changes them like really radically
because alcohol way God gives a fuck,
but marijuana will go,
dude,
you gotta do something about this.
This is fucking with your head all the
time and you know what's fucking with
your head.
It's in the background of everything you
do.
It's.
It's constantly looming over you,
shadowing you like a backhand ready to
do.
This is why you don't read philosophy.
You're just opening up,
opening up and there's no way to solve
it.
It's the pot God damn pot.
That's why it's illegal.
It would ruin this fucking society.
It would ruin the fiber of society,
would stop all these jobs.
I would hope in that pot legalization
coincides with excellent new robots to
conduce shitty jobs,
so it all flows together the way you do
with all those people that are now
running through the streets.
Oh good.
Let the robots killing the robot's gonna
eat them.
They're going to use them as fuel.
You see the Matrix,
each robot that kills most people,
whereas it's face going to have a Taco
Bell Fan club and whoever shows up,
those are the first people to get eaten.
You know,
like things like that.
They'll take like really obvious robot
traps like donor parks.
No,
but this is your kids.
I'm talking about fully grown adults.
There's got to be some real traps.
You got to take care of robots,
just eat people.
You have to look at them.
Over here.
There's a few rogue robots like there's,
you know,
viruses that computers catch a few rogue
robots found out they can eat people and
they just go off and eat people,
but they're very ethical about it.
They,
they eat the dumbest fucking people they
could find.
It's like a crocodile doesn't go after
the fastest gazelle.
It goes by that wounded motherfucker
lips up to the waterhole and just gets
jacked.
Wounded.
Old One can hear anything anymore.
It's got one gray.
I see everybody running.
The crocodile gets and so much like much
like the crocodile,
the robots that eat people will become
like the natural predators.
The weeders.
It's great of the week just walking
there.
They're no,
they're no better than just gang up and
attack a city because we just make it
rain on him or something and they're all
rusty.
Explode or something.
They will shoot them.
We have,
we have guns.
We know they're coming.
We can keep an eye on them,
but if they can just talk really fucking
stupid people into traps and then just
eat them and do our bidding.
Like a Taco Bell Fan club.
Are you a fan of Taco Bell?
We are to come celebrate Taco Bell Fan
night and you go there.
Come on town.
It's not even free food.
I just give away like Taco bell tee
shirts and hats and shit and people are
fucking socked about Taco bell broad.
Our three choices on my corner got
birthed here and got Wendy's.
I always go to Taco Bell,
Taco Bell's my shit.
Look at this free tee shirts.
They're the best to the burst that the
quality of their ingredients is
unprecedented.
They get me,
man.
We'll get fucking seriously into like it
would be ridiculous to get that way
about Taco Bell,
but it's not ridiculous to get that way
over apple.
Right.
Do you want me to put fucking people?
When I was working on news radio,
that was like during the days before
Osx,
so this was like the days of like
windows 95 and the operating system for
Mac was all like it wasn't that good and
the way I've seen it be described like
the interface is really cool,
like the way you use it was very simple
and easy to remember and a lot of
creative type people like to use it for
a bunch of different reasons,
but there was no memory protection.
There was no preemptive multitasking.
It was like a clunky operating system
for like high end users.
Like they didn't code video games on
them.
People that really needed them.
And obviously this I'm regurgitating
regurgitating because I don't know shit
about computers so what I've read,
I'm blaming it.
These people that I was working with on
news radio,
we're fucking radical Mac fanatics.
They were radical and like the news will
come out when we're going to get them
with this new operating system,
this new operating system,
spending less sex was coming out.
I was like,
go,
we're going to get them with sex
was actually pre Osx I believe.
I want to say Osx came out in the early
two thousands.
What was before that?
Shit.
It's terrible.
Yeah,
I used to.
well I used to use it too because I
remember there was no viruses for it,
like no one had figured out how to make
a virus for macs yet.
There was a ton of them for pcs and I
caught one once I caught one a codified
bro.
Dude,
somebody sent me a Microsoft word.
I'm a package of a script or something
like that and I read it.
It had a virus in it and then I sent
something to friend of mine and it had
the virus in it.
It had connected to all my Microsoft
word documents.
So.
But my friend was like a super genius
tech guy.
He's like,
Hey,
fuck face.
He's sent me a virus.
You stupid cunt.
Right.
He scans all his email.
He's like super paranoid.
So he scanned to shit and was like,
yeah,
same,
the same working bro.
I'm disseminating fibers,
but yeah,
my had to bring my daughters in to a
apple because someone hacked all the
browsers and just couldn't do anything
and he went in there.
This guy,
the browsers,
what they do.
Yeah.
They hacked the browsers,
put a a malware called malware.
You get there from porn sites.
I hope not.
It's my daughter's 14.
Probably porn sites.
Probably only gay
dudes fucking each other.
If I was a girl,
I'd want to know what are they doing
over there and do I like it,
you know,
because like guys have guys stumbled
across a video of two girls fingering
each other while making out like real
softly.
Like we get very excited about it.
Like,
Whoa,
whoa.
You know,
like you feel like you've stumbled
across something but you stumble across
to dude motherfucker and you're watching
a crime
watching a violent encounter.
Even if they love each other,
we love each other.
They just probably say,
look,
I love you.
You love me,
but we're going to do some dirty shit to
each other for the
next whatever minutes takes it's gonna.
Get ugly up at this bitch.
Well,
the guy at the genius part did not seem
to think that's what my daughter was
watching.
He said probably spotify or
spotify,
and they're gay porn obsession,
but he just went in and ripped it all
out.
He was just like,
went in a couple of files like malware.
Yeah.
Look,
look out,
look out there directing you.
Look where they put this stuff in your
extensions.
You ain't got it all out.
Fucking geniuses.
Well,
that's a real genius at the genius bar.
He was.
He was pretty good because that's a
pretentious title.
Genius Bar.
I work at the genius bar at Apple.
Trust me,
I'm right.
There was this flat.
Stop it
here.
It's not flat.
Not Anymore routing itself out over the
years it's gained weight like all of us.
Um,
what we're talking about.
Oh,
so this a malware thing.
They don't know where she got it from,
but they could just pull it out.
Yeah.
They just go in and Kinda Kinda tore it
all out.
They didn't have to re,
uh,
installing the operating system or
reformat the hard drive now.
Nope.
It's all good.
One.
If it's.
Hmm.
I wonder if it shows up in like time,
machine time,
machine backups.
I wonder if time machine backups have
malware in them.
Uh,
no.
I don't think so.
No.
They just backup critical.
Yeah.
And then it's another backup.
But if the files are infected,
I mean there's gotta be a way like how
does windows do it?
Do you know how windows does their,
their backups?
No idea.
Is it something that never used on the
operating system?
Everybody looks like.
I'm asking do you want to do Morse code?
Smoke signals?
No.
Windows.
It looks great to me.
I'm so confused and I know I'm an idiot.
Okay.
Don't get me wrong.
But um,
I went to the store the other day
because a,
I'm buying a TV.
I wanted to look at the newest tvs which
are fucking suit with the curve.
The curve.
That's a gimmick.
It's gonna go away.
Trust me.
The new ones.
The PTI.
Oh,
the forecast?
Yeah.
Good Lord.
They look good.
Do they?
Yeah.
Well they get you at the store first of
all because what they're showing you is
a loop.
And that loop is like super hard
definition stuff.
It's all leopards and shit and fucking
perfect snakes and flowers and
waterfalls.
You're like fuck amazing music to stare
at it all day to look at this all day.
But if you went home and watched like
fucking game of thrones on it,
it's not going to look that good.
Game of thrones is not filmed like that.
It's not filmed in that super four k.
yeah.
What is very few things on Netflix is
doing their specials in it though.
They are my new netflix specials in four
k.
You can see how shitty I look in real
life.
Yeah.
It's a little too real,
real deep,
slow deterioration of the aging process.
He has a lot of motherfuckers getting
skin on his face is sort of loose.
See how it's like it's there,
but it's not.
It's not like cleaning on this is like
this.
You don't go like from here to like uh,
like Ted Kennedy.
It's not Ted Kennedy.
Before he died,
he had a basset hound.
You don't go from this men manly
chiseled face to that.
Will you?
Do you go from this to what I got going
on right now?
We just a little too much elasticity.
Little loose,
not tight enough.
Now I want to say elasticy.
Yeah,
because the last test would allow to
snap back.
It's a little too little elasticity.
It's just getting kind of late and
fluffy anymore college into my diet.
It's kind of fallen off your face and
there's no way to stop it.
There is apparently no,
it's not.
Apparently the same doctor who invented
Regena King,
which is a process that I used to deal
with a bulging disc,
so they take your blood out and it's
kinda like platelet rich plasma in a way
except the heat it up and by heating up
your blood,
your blood produces a response to the
heat and it creates this yellow serum
and his yellow serum.
They spin in a centrifuge and then
extract that yellow car and it's one of
the most potent anti inflammatory
medicines ever discovered.
Scott discovered he discovered a lot of
inventions ever discovered in your body.
Doesn't reject it because it's your own
blood and it has a great effect on
people with like inflammation injuries
and helping healing times would it do
for you.
You had the disrobe bulging from
repeated use from Jujitsu,
from just too much sparring and not
enough time off and getting injured and
not taking enough time off in between
the injury and getting right back into
Jujitsu is really fun.
It's really fun.
It's like a video game like that kind of
fun or like I like to play pool.
It's,
it's,
but it's way more exciting than that and
the only way you could do it,
you gotta do it with your body.
So it's like you have this game piece
that you're playing with and his game
piece get banged up all the time.
It's an old controller.
Yeah.
And so,
uh,
I was developing some back issues from
numb fingers and usually those indicate
that your disc is pushing against the
nerve so it means a disc is bulging out.
So then I went through a bunch of things
with spinal decompression
and Regena keen was a big part of that.
So this guy who developed Regena King,
all these athletes like Peyton Manning,
coby Bryant,
they all flew to Germany to get this
procedure and then slowly they brought
it up to the United States and now they
do it in California.
Um,
and they do it in Santa Monica is where
I had it done,
but I think they'd do it also in Dallas
and they do it a couple other places
maybe in Las Vegas,
the same doctor who came up with this
procedure has some new procedure that
they're preparing to release which is
going to kickstart to production of
Collagen and people.
And that is the thing that makes your
skin look like shit.
That's the thing that makes your face
sag and your wrinkles appear and your
body just looks like an old bag what
your college and goes away.
Exactly.
You're stuffing in your face basically.
You're more,
she's stuffing Collagen is responsible
for a lot of the elasticity of your
skin.
It's responsible for a lot of other
things as well.
But the elasticity of your skin is
apparently a lot of it's based on your
body's healthy production of Collagen.
So we're losing it now and we're getting
just a little loose.
We'll loosen up this hill,
right?
Thermitight.
What is this injectable?
What is this?
What is this,
Jeremy?
This is what?
College and injection.
Yeah.
It looks like just a little video of it.
Oh,
this.
This looks like they're tightening you
now.
That's a college,
right?
People get college and just injected
into college and injected.
How long does that last?
I don't know.
This is all new stuff that has been
taught to me by people who have gone
over to Germany and talked to this guy
and had procedures done by this guy.
And uh,
did it help your spine?
Like a huge.
It did a big difference.
Big,
big difference.
Yeah.
Big Difference in relief.
Big Difference in recovery time.
I did a bunch of different things.
I was pretty proactive about it.
The spinal decompression.
I did a lot of Rolfing,
which is super painful.
Torturous method of massage where
they're like,
they're manipulating your limbs and
digging their elbows and you're back in
the fucking.
The guys did.
It was this football player dude.
He was huge.
Big,
giant dude.
And just beat me up.
It was rough.
There's nothing worse than when you get
a massage and it's just like this little
girl hands,
just like,
I hate that I'm used to the painful
ones,
but those are the ones,
the painful ones,
the ones that like break up the tissue
and allow it all to relax and heal
better.
And that helped a lot.
The decompression helped a lot.
That was a big.
So are you able to tell how much this
process help?
Oh yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
Well I don't know how much that process
helped overall because I did them all
together.
Right.
But everything together worked awesome
sounding.
I don't have a bulge at all anymore,
which is really important to talk about
because there's a lot of people to get
bulging discs and they immediately want
to go get surgery.
And in some cases that's the right move.
In some cases like Eddie Bravo,
my,
a good friend of mine had a discreet
place on his back and uh,
Eddie is a longtime Jujitsu guy and his
disc,
it's been squashed and deteriorated so
much that it was essentially like bone
on bone was lower back,
constant state of inflammation,
inflammation.
So in that case the doctors decided it
was a very smart move to replace the
disk with these new titanium disks that
they have.
They have some pretty cool artificial
discs,
but there's other specialties.
His was really bad for a long period of
time,
but there's other injuries where you
could mitigate all the issues without
surgery.
It's just going to take a little time
just like it took time to create the
injury.
It's going to take time to heal it.
Right.
And spinal decompressions big.
Like even those things we hang by your
ankles.
Just doing that a little bit every day
is really good for pain,
really good for relief of your lower
back.
There is also the other ones you could
do with your neck.
I have one that's like a harness as
straps to my neck and it hangs from a
door.
Oh yeah.
Yeah.
And then you can actually pull.
It stretches your neck out and they're
like.
You could feel it like relaxing your
neck.
It's attached to the door.
Yeah,
it's actually the thing for your head.
Yeah.
It's like this metal bracket that clamps
down on the top of the door and then it
has like this arm that comes off of it
and then a rope comes down from the arm
which is attached to this velcro like
face thing.
Put it on your velcroed in place so it's
tight,
and then he pulled on the string.
It's like click,
click,
and it's just like a poll on your neck
and could use that right now.
That's great man.
I'm not lying.
That's it right there.
That's what it looks like.
Oh,
you look cool too.
And it looks like a diaper was like
pulling that thing.
I can like feel the relaxation and if
you do it on a regular basis it really
does offer you some nice relief.
Again,
no affiliation with any of these
companies.
You can just some things I used
instilled,
you can put it in the door jamb and not
have it land on your head is your hand.
Yeah,
you gotta be careful because one time it
didn't fucking Ding me in the head.
It did.
Yeah.
I was an asshole.
I didn't tighten it down.
Right.
And that's what I be worried and when it
came down it,
it fucking in the forehead and left this
big cut and I was doing all this press
for a spike spike tv because it was at
the same time where I was doing or Scifi
rather because it was the same time I
was doing a Joe Rogan questions.
Everything is TV show.
So all the pressure I did with a divot
in my head like this,
but for spike it probably helped.
It was Saifai helper,
Psi Phi.
But anyway,
um,
those things were all really good.
I was just,
something happened just in the last two
days,
sleeping and woke up.
It can happen.
Just Yoga.
I Love Yoga.
Yoga is the thing,
man,
hot yoga.
That fucking clears
all that up.
I don't the strength in who knows how to
do it.
You've got to be.
I like this.
The regular yoga where I'm sweating like
a pig over hot yoga just opens you up
baby.
Just the extra little millimeter of
stretch.
You get out of it all.
No,
it's too hot too.
Yeah,
but it's also mental toughness to get a
build mental toughness.
Ninety minutes net class tough enough,
or you are at.
What do I need it for?
I don't know.
Tough.
Do I have to say I just got to pick my
kids up and these are all rhetorical
questions not to drink.
Sexism is causing you to drink.
I've been meaning to talk to you.
Really.
I mean,
look,
we all know that men are awful and we
attack and do horrible things and we've
been.
You've yelled at us now and we're
dealing with it now.
Back off.
We know there's a problem.
We're working on it.
The right art is 12.
Okay.
Is it okay to only want to work with
men?
So say if you start a company,
at what size can the company be before
you've got to start hiring women?
Like right now,
Joe Rogan experience enterprises,
very small company.
There's only a couple employees and they
happened to be male.
Now one of the more higher.
What if we keep going with eventually I
hire 50 people.
Who is anybody gonna say,
why do you have 50 dudes?
How come?
Because you're.
You're,
you're not meeting the quota.
Is that really the case?
Or is it that these are the people that
I want and I just happened to find out
they're all men.
You have to at a certain data now you
have to hire and meet these numbers.
What number is probably probably like 40
percent of your staff?
No,
no,
no.
I mean at what number does,
you're like,
I can do it.
Get Away with it.
With two people I think.
Yeah.
I think if you bring in one more person,
really it's going to be a problem.
Yeah.
It's.
If I bring in one girl,
it's going to be a problem.
Going to hear some of the shit.
Jamie says the mics off,
she's going to go,
what the fuck?
She's going to be quietly building a
case against Jesus Christ.
Dude,
that does happen,
man.
Yeah,
look at.
Look at Anthony Wiener.
Well,
that's a different.
That's a different case,
but I know this girl who worked with
this guy.
This is actually the sister of a good
friend of mine.
Why am I giving you all the details?
You're going to know who it is.
Anyway,
she worked with this guy for years.
Writing down anytime he said anything
inappropriate and building a file,
but all total.
I mean all clearly her,
her word against his that he said all
these things,
but she made this file of all the
inappropriate things that he had said at
picnics included everywhere.
Company picnics.
She wrote a bunch of things down and
she's thinking about suing the company.
They are going to burry you.
Are you out of your fucking mind?
My God.
Like what?
What w?
What were these things?
Unless they were like really fucked up.
But that's the.
The thing
about the corporate or like white
working in a corporation would be so
bizarre.
He thinking that he has a good
relationship with her.
They're like,
she's probably doesn't not dislike
him,
like,
you know what I mean?
Like there's this play acting that
they're doing all the time.
No one's really being honest ever,
but there's also the real possibility
that you could make some money if you
sue them.
Yeah.
Like that kids grow up today and knowing
about like,
here's a,
here's the lawsuit example.
That's insane.
There was a woman who was a single
woman,
a single mom,
and she had this kid and she brought the
kid over my house and the kids stayed
over my house for a long ass time.
Like she was supposed to pick the kid up
at four and then she didn't show up
until eight.
It was weird as weird.
One of those weird ones and she was also
just slightly sketchy.
It was just something.
And this isn't one of the things you
deal with when you deal,
you know your kids are going to school a
bunch of different people you run into
and then you have to interact with these
people.
You're not exactly sure what to get out
of it.
So she left her kid at this other lady's
house and the other lady had a little
dog.
I mean a little fucking dog.
The dog jumped up and did the pawing
thing and left a visible scratch on the
girl's leg.
She sued them for 100,000 dollars.
What?
Attacked her daughter might be 50 grand.
Maybe she got $50 gross trying to
remember what the numbers were,
but it was like,
whoa.
Like that was good.
This was this lady saying we're in,
you know,
we gotta,
we gotta get a shot here,
got a shot here at some money with
people you go to school with and see all
the time.
That's how awful you are.
It was just the dog didn't bite anybody.
It just jumped up because he got
excited.
Is being a dog.
Dogs do it.
You know,
I could get if,
if I was my dog and he did to someone's
door,
I'd be very upset.
I do whatever the fuck I could do to
make it better.
But um,
it's not like the dog was a biter,
but bad dog.
Yeah.
Legally does she have a case?
The issue is with a lot of lawsuits,
it will cost you more to fight it than
it will for you to just settle.
Right?
So a lot of people just settled,
like say it'll cost you $10,000 to
settle,
but it'll cost you $50,000 to fight it.
Like that's all.
That's all real.
People have to consider those things.
You should fight it though.
Just to stick it to her.
Well,
the UFC told us to not take photos,
choking people like people ask you,
Hey,
put me to run naked choke because two
people got sued.
One of them was chuck Odell and one of
them was Matt Hughes,
the Matt Hughes One.
Crazy because this guy says to ask Matt,
he used to put him in a choke hold.
People do that shit all the time that
obliges him.
Then the guy uses the photo,
tries to sue Matt Hughes,
says Matt Hurt Him.
And here's the evidence,
the photo evidence that you heard them.
Then here's where it gets even crazier
than they do an investigation in this
guy.
Find out he's a cop.
Then they go deeper.
Find out he's a dirty cop.
Nah,
he gets arrested and kicked off the
force.
Well,
he's a scam artist.
It's a scammer.
I mean,
he's a scammer
that just happened to figure out how to
become a cop.
Oh No.
He hadn't fucked up enough.
By the time he was,
you know,
x amount of years old that he couldn't
get disqualified for being a cop.
She's credited as gross.
Yeah,
I know.
That is a,
that's an awful.
That's another reason why you shouldn't
let your kids play with other kids.
Yeah.
You gotta keep me at home.
Right.
Don't ever let him out,
man.
Just the having to talk to everybody
when they're picking up the kids and you
know,
it's great.
They don't want to talk to you.
You don't want to talk to them and the
kids won't put their shoes on and you're
standing there for a half hour just
staring at each other,
trying to get through it.
Leave the shoes on it,
stay inside.
You know what?
I mean,
it's hard,
but don't you love it when you find a
parent that you actually like for sure.
That's an oasis.
Yeah.
It's an oasis in the fucking desert.
Oh,
thank God.
They're think they're laughing.
They're normal.
Oh my God.
They can talk to me.
Yeah.
I can drink with this guy.
No problem.
To them.
We're going to be friends.
Holy Shit.
I can't believe it would be friends with
a parent who I knew they were out there.
Then do have me parents who you know,
don't like you.
Yo.
Yeah.
You just feel it.
You can.
Yeah.
It going to have that man.
This.
Can it be parents who want to fuck your
wife?
What?
For sure.
They're going to meet her.
They're going to say maybe if Tom dies.
Oh Man.
Yeah.
I just know that there's a better job
and he doesn't understand.
She's the.
She's complicated.
She's not difficult.
You just requires more and more back.
That's so.
I'm not saying it's bad,
it's just.
I mean he goes on the road a lot.
I'm just saying I wouldn't do that.
I mean,
I wouldn't go on the road.
What would I do?
I'd be a stay at home dad that adjust my
income accordingly.
I mean,
because I just feel like being with you,
it'd be more important than,
you know,
getting the applause from strangers.
Well first and foremost,
I'm a feminist and as a feminist I
always do what women want me to do.
He doesn't tell you you're beautiful
every day.
I mean,
I'm not judging them.
I would do it.
That's a requirement.
That's something you have to say.
It's just something you want to say
anyway.
And I would want to say especially since
it's true,
but it's true and you say it okay,
you just do,
do better.
Just do better period just to better.
You know,
what I'm finding is the older you get,
the less you run into people because
once they're in high school,
they start to just.
They don't involve the parents at all.
They don't want their parents around.
Now you have to make an effort to be
like,
Hey,
I want to see some of these parents
before I let you go over to their house,
because now it's getting.
It's good point.
Yeah,
because they're.
When they're little and Weirdos and the
little they really have you.
There's some weird stuff that goes on
like people having parties that my
daughter had.
She was 12 I think,
or 13 and the party,
the kids party was held at the stand.
Not The standard.
The Strand,
you know,
the fancy hotel on sunset.
Really what's at the stamp.
I think it's the standard standard
standard.
Thank you.
Cool.
I am.
I've gotten there twice.
We work.
We work on.
We started across the street literally
across the street on that diner there.
It's open.
Really.
It might be 24 hours.
Oh yeah.
Yeah.
It's amazing.
It's really good food,
but it's also a place where when you're
new to Hollywood you have parties there
and there's a lot of people with coke
and running around.
Naked Dude.
I took a picture.
I was there once.
Rampage Jackson came out of the back
with sunglasses on.
No shirt on and a fur coat and two super
hot Chinese checks and I took a picture
of him.
It was back in the day before instagram
and twitter.
I put it up online somewhere.
It's probably.
Yeah,
I don't.
I doubt if you can find it,
if you could find that you're a fucking
wizard,
but with that is the standard is
probably from like 2004 or something
like that.
It's still the same today and my
daughter's like,
they're having a party in the one room
and the parents are having a party in
the other room.
That's ridiculous.
It's just parties that want to get
fucked up and then we'll put the kids in
that room.
We can.
Oh my.
So my daughter was going to go to A.
I'm not dropping you off at the status.
So stupid.
Definitely fucked up.
Things are going to happen because
parents aren't paying any attention
trying to bond each other.
La,
you know,
there was another,
there was a,
there was an incidence of parents bone
each other.
Oh yeah.
Not In my kids' school,
but one of my kids' friends,
school,
the moms.
We're all talking about it at good
stuff.
Parents got together,
they got date frake on the side.
You notice the sign,
what?
When they want to travel with you,
that's where it all goes down with the
swapping happens a lot on those
vacations.
When someone comes to you is like,
hey,
you want to go uh,
to the Grand Canyon with me and Carol.
We all camp
camping,
camping stuff.
You gotta do like hotels where there's
like a gym that's 24 hours and it's like
the middle of the night.
Like I just feel like,
you know,
lifting
to one of those massage rooms,
I think camping would be an easy one to
just go into the bathroom in the woods.
The problem is the woods are quiet.
You're going to hear everything.
You're going to hear it all.
It's just the woods.
It's not the best sleep either.
Write up real easy.
You're all,
you're kind of on edge.
And was sleeping on the ground with
animals laying on the ground where
animals live.
I.
Hey,
I,
I just got back from Africa.
Oh yeah,
you're right.
Yeah.
You slept in a,
in a tent like that.
It's not a,
not a floppy template.
Like a wall tent.
Wall tent.
Yeah.
When,
where did you go and listen to lions?
All night long.
Literally.
Oh,
it sounded like it was like literally in
our bed,
just like safe for hours.
He was about about 300 yards away with a
dead zebra and he was basically through
the night telling his family
for miles where the zebras.
Hey,
that's the line I took.
that's my thing.
That's your,
a instagram page fellow.
Tom Papa.
Literally like hearing it felt like they
were literally in our,
in our tent.
And what part of Africa did you go to?
Tanzania.
See I was going to go to Tanzania,
but I was scared that I would have to
give my kids a shot.
Yeah,
he did.
How old are you?
Kids?
Uh,
11 and 14.
And they had to get a typhoid shot.
They didn't have to get malaria.
We took malaria medication once a day
and a.
How bad is it?
It gives you crazy vivid dreams.
People had said it might give us
nightmares.
We would just come down in the morning
like,
what did you dream last night?
Wow.
I mean like so crystal clear for k vivid
dreams.
Really wild.
And as soon as you'll go,
as soon as you went off the dreams went
away.
And how long do you have taken for?
Two days before you go the whole time
you're there and then a week after the
whole time you're there.
You take it.
Yeah.
Does it fuck you?
Larry is real.
It's around.
It makes your stomach a little.
Didn't.
My wife's stomach was a mess because of
it,
but that's it.
Just stomach ache.
Excuse me.
Yeah.
Which can definitely fuck up your
enjoyment of this experience,
right?
Yeah.
But you know what?
Go to the bathroom a couple times to be
six feet from Lyon is like,
yeah,
you just do it.
You know,
I don't like that stuff.
I always feel like I'm going to get bit
by a bug and I feel that I'm too young
for that.
How old are they?
Six and eight.
I just don't want to give him malaria
medication.
They are minor.
Eleven and 14.
And this was the perfect time to take
them.
The 14 year old was aware of.
Certainly in the younger one at 11 is
like,
she's good.
She can travel,
she can eat food,
she could swallow pills.
She's like a person any earlier than
this.
It would've been,
it would've been hard.
Yeah.
It's,
um,
it's got to be amazing though.
Huh?
It's amazing.
It's kind of,
it's,
it's mind blowing.
You definitely have a,
you know,
it's like,
well,
those things like you go on vacation,
you're like,
oh,
it's just going to blow me away.
Like why,
you know,
you're kinda like always this patient.
But then it's always becomes a little
more simple than that.
You just kind of hang in this place and
by the end of it you come back,
you're like,
I'm still thinking about it.
You know what I mean?
It's like seeing a great movie and you
can't get it out of your head.
It's like these things are going to.
Africa was pretty.
It's pretty deep,
you know,
like you really see just the beginning
of,
of everything.
It's kind of,
it's kind of a.
and then it's just cool just being by
these animals,
I mean,
you're literally by all these animals
about Africa.
It's not just the beginning of
everything,
but in a lot of ways it's still like
that.
Yeah.
Like it's one of the few places where
you can go and there's indigenous tribes
essentially all over the continent yet
that are living in a,
you know,
really kind of primitive way complete.
We took a balloon ride and balloon guy.
This isn't dangerous enough.
We're going to ground with lions.
And uh,
this was right after the crash.
And.
But anyway,
we got in the balloon,
it wasn't the safest and he got off
course.
So we drifted out of the Serengeti and
the grammatic river and we're just kind
of going for a little bit.
And we,
he brought it down in this clearing we
ended,
we ended up fucking movie,
brutal upside down.
A tribe that lives there,
comes running out,
they cut,
they saw us coming down,
they started running,
it got sticks and robes and they come
running and we land.
They've never seen this before.
They've never seen us before.
They've never seen this before and
they're like,
my daughter held up a cell phone and
boys who were older than her probably 15
ran,
literally ran at the site of a cell
phone and uh,
it was like,
and they're so primitive,
they're so basic.
They're living in these little places,
just raising cattle and just doing the
primitive things.
But I think I was more scared of them.
Then the kids running from the cell
phone,
like I didn't know.
I've only heard like Rwanda or the boat
room thing and I'm like,
I don't know these people,
they can eat you.
They've got a robot,
but I've got two daughters with me.
You know,
who,
who knows.
He took guy just gets in my face.
She went on a route and getting crazy
and like I'm taking that one.
You landed in my territory.
I'm taking that one dude.
You know what I mean?
Would you be uneasy?
I bought Kia.
I was uneasy.
Yeah.
Well you don't know how to speak their
language.
Now think if you land on a fucking
balloon and south central Chicago or
South South side of Chicago,
you're in trouble.
Right?
Right,
right.
You could learn a bad neighborhood
anywhere in America and a fucking
balloon and getting a heap load of
trouble,
but I felt bad about myself that I'm
assuming that I'm landing in that these
people must be trouble,
but instinct kind of kicks in.
You know what I mean?
You're just kind of landed in the swamps
of Louisiana and nobody can hear you
scream.
You don't.
You wouldn't be weird if you landed in
some fucking strange little swamp town
or a bunch of people just gator hunting.
That's what it is at skaters.
That's what it is.
It's the unknown.
It's not knowing.
All I needed was someone to say,
have the balloon guy be like,
these people are cool.
Yeah.
These are my friends.
Hello.
Right there.
But no one was saying that one was a
little nervous too,
that cut hands and do the blood brother
thing like outlaw Josey Wales.
He is my brother,
my brother of the jungle.
They do the fake thing where they're
about to fight,
then got terrible movies and they're
like a Crocodile Dundee type movie.
But you know what the people like the
guy,
the safari guy that came to pick us up
and drive us back and he was,
he wasn't cool with being there either.
Oh really?
No.
He was a little nervous.
He was Kinda like checking around and
like,
okay,
let's go and oh God.
He's like,
you don't know,
you don't.
You don't know.
They could ask for money because you
landed on their bushes.
You know what I mean?
Anything could go down.
I know a dude who went there and he went
there for a hunting trip and while he
was there he got sick and the nearest
hospital from where he was hunting was
like six hours in a truck.
And so he got so sick he had to go to
the hospital.
Wow.
So they put them in the back of this
truck.
He's lying down like trying to like not
throw up and just trying to relax over
the six hour drive to the hospital and
they stop for gas along the way and in a
gun fight breaks out and the truck he's
in gets hit with gunfire.
Where,
what part?
Fuck notes.
Some Africa like place this dude out
there.
Dirt roads for six hours.
He gets it a fucking gun fight at a gas
station at a gas station.
There were some rebels disagree with
something and they shot at.
The guy was driving the car and it's,
that's the,
it's so primitive.
It's so you don't.
We went to a little town and you come
into this town,
it's just like steel siding put up and
chickens running around and I mean it's,
it's not a town,
it's,
you know,
it's what you picture in your head of
like a crazy African,
like bizarre,
you know?
And there's guys on motorcycles mean up
and down the street and you don't know.
I don't know how this is going to go.
This is,
you know what I mean?
This is most of the time in those parts
of the world,
everything goes fine and that's right,
but there's a high percentage of the
time in those places as opposed to an
America where things don't go well.
It's like when they don't go well,
they unraveled really quickly and it can
just not come back.
Then people stuff happens here.
The cops show up and it'll.
They'll get,
they will get controlled by reading the
cops just shoot you right.
Yet again,
getting control.
Cops listen to right?
No fuck you move,
but you go into those towns.
I feel like,
you know,
I want to be the photo journalist who
like comes in and just as cool with
people and presumes these people are
kind and gentle and a lot of them are
kind and gentle of a scarf.
A lot.
I could get one.
He needed like some sort of a knit
scarves like,
like it's been like almost like
transparent.
One of those scarfs in the.
Like the mirrored sunglasses,
the wire mirrored sunglasses.
That's kind of a Douche move.
Scarf.
The scarf.
Well,
and
scarf makes you look worldly,
like were talking before the podcast
started about those leather bags that
you put your pop your laptop in that
Amanda like six saddle leather develops
a fine Patina over time.
Fucking pounds.
Damn piece of shit.
It weighs 20 pounds.
You know,
it's the best thing for carrying your
backpack.
Your laptop.
It's a backpack.
Yeah.
Everybody knows it so well.
Cool.
No,
it doesn't look like Clint Eastwood with
Abbott.
Yeah.
If you have a shoulder strap and it's
pitino leather and you could smell the
leather on.
Yes.
Yes sir.
Let's look at his shoes.
They're suede with a thin bottom thin.
How's it heal?
But it's a very small heel,
very thin under nondescript Suede shoe.
He's where?
It's gray of course that he rolls his
own cigarettes.
He does roll his own cigarettes.
You're amazing.
And he does it well.
A man who controls on cigarettes quickly
and very.
So look at that.
It looks professional.
It looks like a machine did.
Oh,
that guy.
Yeah,
so I'm reciting poetry to that girl.
Before that guy was embedded with a
tribe of cannibals for a year and didn't
even speak their language.
He's amazing,
but I do feel that it's my American
paranoia is part of it and that I want
to be a better person and and assume
that these gentle people raising cattle
are kind
or you should just assume that all that
shit you read every 20 minutes when you
get up in the morning and the New York
Times about people eating people over
there.
It's true.
Jesus Christ,
fucking white liberals,
they're all.
We just want to think the world is a
diversity is awesome.
I felt I did have a conflicting thing
like lucky and they had already eaten
some.
They're like,
fuck you.
We don't need people
joking around folks,
but that is how I was acting.
I want it to be like,
it's all cool,
but I was not.
I was keeping my daughters by me.
I was like,
let's go.
This little girl came up,
will you give me some juice?
I'm like,
screw you.
Fuck you.
Let's get out of here.
We got our.
We got our fabric that we wanted.
Let's leave.
I really,
I was that way.
I was like,
I'm not having it.
I'm not cool.
I'm paranoid and I'm territorial and
let's get back to the,
to the van.
I got a buddy of mine who's had malaria
three times,
and he goes to the Congo for months at a
time and a builds wells for the pygmies
in the Congo.
Oh my God.
He's a salt of the Earth z names Justin
wren.
He actually had met him when he was
fighting for the UFC.
Wow.
And he took,
he took a long time off of fighting.
You just recently returned to bring
awareness to the pygmies.
Oh,
real hand to speak,
to help money to help us gather money
to,
uh,
to build them wells.
And they build like,
I think 42.
Well,
so far.
Wow.
It's amazing.
Yeah,
it works.
Amazing.
Works with this company called water for
and you can donate.
There's a website called fight for the
forgotten.com.
That's him.
That's my friend.
But uh,
he goes down there for months and months
at a time and lives with these people in
like one of those.
He looks happy.
He's the happiest guy ever.
He looked so happy.
He's so fucking Nice,
but I wouldn't feel great too if I went
to a land where of pygmies and there I
was just like,
I am your God.
I am big and I can dig just a guide or
God,
they're little right?
Pygmies,
they just call them the big pygmy.
Yeah,
he looks like the gnome on my leg.
He's a big guy.
He's a UFC heavyweight,
so he's 250 plus pounds.
Wow.
He's a big dude.
Big Boulder of a man.
But,
um,
it looks like one of my tattoos and
he's,
he really does.
He's,
I think he might be over there now or if
he's not there now,
he's going back soon.
He goes there all the time.
He's an amazing guy.
But that guy has had malaria three
fucking times.
And he said,
there's types of area.
Yeah.
Well,
he said there's types of malaria that
you can get that can last years.
What do you say?
Like 30 fucking years.
Oh my God.
One of them was like five months.
One of them was 10 years and there's a
type that lasts for like 30 years and he
just didn't want to take medication.
Well,
he did.
He didn't take medication for some of
them.
He did for other ones.
There's other people that he knows that
took medication and still got malaria,
but he's in the fucking heat of it,
man.
No,
that's.
Yeah,
he's in the Congo.
The Congo,
yeah.
Do you know that malaria has killed half
the people that have ever died ever.
Really?
Yeah.
Out of all the things that have killed
people and all the history is the
biggest lols and fucking earthquakes.
Wagons,
drowning malaria.
Half of them,
half of them died because of malaria.
That's not going to last though because
we were able to go in and affect
mosquitoes and the mosquitoes are going
to go and take all that out.
I've seen that genetically modified
mosquitoes all.
Where are you now?
You're GML pussies.
Scared Gmo.
What we have is everything is non GMO.
It's super important to me to be clean,
to eat,
clean writing,
smoking cigarettes,
taken acid on the side,
a dirty hippy day,
Gmos,
Gmos have been with us forever and it's
not a good idea for here's,
here's what's not a good idea.
It's not a good idea to put pesticides
on your food.
You know it and I knew it and the
problem with things like GMO round up,
everybody knows that roundup was created
so they could spray it with evil
chemicals because it makes it easier to
grow plants,
but it's not how it's supposed to be
done.
Like you can't.
These shortcuts that people have created
for industrial arts farming to kill off
weeds and things like that.
Pesticides,
that shit is fucking terrible for you
and it gets in the water and that stuff
gets in the water.
I know a dude who has bone cancer and he
has bone cancer and a bunch of people in
his neighborhood have cancer and they
all got cancer because they were near a
fucking golf course and they had wells
and so they were down down water from
the golf course and the golf course
constantly sprayed pesticide all over
the grass.
They wanted to keep that grass clean.
It's seeped into the ground water.
These people all drank that groundwater
and they got cancer.
Fuck,
fuck.
Load of people in this guy's
neighborhood got cancer.
He has instead of a thigh.
His femur is a rod.
It's like a metal rod and they like
rebuilt his leg had cut his femur out of
that or remove your leg.
You want to try a Rod?
Yeah,
let's go with the rod and he's a fucking
rod in his leg like a gmo mosquitoes,
but here's the thing.
That's terrible,
right?
But genetically modified foods,
the more I've looked into it,
the more I understand it now.
First of all,
they've been with us forever.
Everything you fucking eat from oranges
to corn to tomatoes,
all those things have been genetically
modified.
Most of those things have been
genetically modified by traditional
methods,
traditional agricultural methods that we
don't think of as genetically modified.
We have like this ignorant view of it,
like we think it's all being done with
the going into the DNA and injecting
dangerous chemicals and we don't know
the consequences of.
They'd been like splicing plants
together forever.
They've been doing certain aspects of
naturals of selection and selecting the
type of traits in foods that they want
and taking seeds and figuring out.
Like that's the other thing that I know
most of the foods that you buy,
the seeds aren't going to even work on
them.
Like if you buy like tomatoes and those
tomatoes,
like then they're probably not even
going to grow tomatoes from them from
the seeds and those plants.
That's what's the thing that freaks me.
Like you hear Gmo and you just think,
I think okay,
someone big is messing with our food and
then there's only.
There's smaller number of big people who
are manipulating food supply and they
don't care about you.
They don't.
They don't even allow those old ways of
modifying stuff because there's so
taking seeds out away from regular
farmers and I mean it's really that
part.
It's like the big brother part of the
food industry that really scary and when
I hear Gmo I just think,
okay,
who's doing what?
You know what level?
I think the same way when we were
talking about how many employees do you
have to have before you have to hire a
check.
You don't.
You're okay if you have to,
if you have more.
I think when you're a part of a big
corporation,
how many people do you have to have,
but where no one feels responsible for
the consequences of the actions of the
company.
Like if you working for Monsanto,
you're working for a fucking enormous
monster of a machine that needs to make
more money every month and the previous
month.
Bigger than a lot of countries.
It's bigger than a lot of countries and
it's,
it's the amount of money that it
generates is substantial worldwide.
Yeah,
and then here's the thing with the
universe or infinite growth,
which is this thing that a lot of
corporations operate under.
They have stockholders.
People want returns on their
investments.
You want to make more money every
quarter then you did the previous
quarter.
That's crazy.
Insane.
You can't sustain that.
Keeps going and going and going,
and when you're a company like Monsanto,
I'm not making any excuses for them.
I'm just saying the way giant
corporations operate,
they are.
The CEO has.
He has an obligation to stockholders to
generate more income.
It's important that he made and if they
don't,
they'll write them out.
The a new guy in here who's going to do
the job.
So if you take on the job of a CEO of a
major corporation,
your job is to make more fucking money
every time and it's a very high pressure
job,
which is why it's worth so much money.
Like there's no you.
No,
you get it,
but that's.
But that's why you need someone like the
FDA to keep an eye on it and keep them
small and break them up,
make sure they're not putting that stuff
in the wells and doing all that stuff.
They're all bought and paid.
You can't.
Yeah,
but you need.
If,
if the corporation's goal is to just get
bigger and make more,
they're not going to put the brakes on
and say let's not put the bad water in
the.
Well,
yes.
True.
Somebody has to do it.
Somebody's gotta do it.
Right.
But the government is far from doing it.
But the FDA with food that they let so
much stuff slide.
There's so much stuff in our food that
isn't allowed in Europe.
Yeah,
well that's what I'm saying.
Like they're bought and sold.
Like if they were looking out for us,
the first thing they would do is look
into cigarettes.
There would be like some major
investigation as to why politicians
haven't spoken out against cigarettes.
Are Cigarettes killing 500,000 people
and no one's doing anything to stop it.
That that would be one of the first
things they would do.
Because if you tried to exist at all,
if you had to see a new product like
cigarettes,
it was kind of a half million people a
year and it wasn't doing anything good.
Yeah.
How the fuck is that going to stick
around?
Right.
You make a bubblegum that's killing half
the people.
Here's what it does.
Do.
It makes you need that gum.
Yeah.
And then you want to get that gun back.
Anybody who created that gun would be
thought of as a monster monster.
But like you could be like,
what does your dad do?
Oh,
well he runs a tobacco company.
cool.
Oh cool.
Yeah.
So does the rest of the state everybody
in North Carolina?
He,
uh,
he employs a lot of people in this
state.
Oh,
excellent.
What does your dad do?
Oh,
he makes his addictive gum.
That kills you.
Piece of shit.
Oh yeah.
He wears a cape and he lives in a dark
castle.
It's never sunny.
Weird.
Just mysteriously goes around the
basement and it's about killing people.
He's so happy with his product killing
half a million a year and he has all the
money in the world.
He buys off politicians.
Yeah,
with his evil gum money.
I mean,
that's what they're doing.
Yeah,
exactly.
Exactly.
So much difference.
That's.
You know what I think I was trying to
think of why like your buddy goes and
helps the pygmies and all these people
are like,
you got to just go into these
places and help these people,
and part of me was when I was there was
thinking that it's almost like in this
liberal,
arrogant way offensive to be like,
I'm here now.
I can help you.
You live like this.
Let me make it better.
But as I was thinking about it,
I don't think that desire to go to work
with the pygmies and the go to help
these people with their water and all.
It's not that we think we're better.
You just see people that need help,
but unlike here in the county in this
country,
you see people that need help.
It's a mess to be able to help them.
You don't know if you're really there.
It's like a build a well and these
people are happy,
right?
I say I give them education and it's a
clear path.
There is no FDA.
I know going against what I was saying
before,
but there is no government regulation.
There's no complex corporations.
If I want to help somebody here,
it's like,
how do you help people in Detroit?
Where do you start?
How does it make an impact?
There he goes and sees pygmies.
He helps the pygmies and at the end of
the day he's helped pygmies.
Right.
You know what I mean?
There's a direct way to help people
there.
There is that thing though.
Whenever you do something charitable
that people think that you're.
You're like peacocking your charitable
ways.
You're doing it for yourself and your
own ego.
Yeah.
But then there's the other side of
looking at it like who cares?
As long as the good work gets done.
Like even if you have kind of Shitty,
selfish,
right.
Ambitious sort of feared intentions
behind it.
If I do something good for people,
I want other people to know I did it.
I'll admit it.
I really like,
like it's,
I know it's a shitty motivation,
but I did help somebody,
you know what I mean?
They got something out of it for sure.
I got something out of it.
Praise Tom Papa.
I'm a pretty good guy.
Look what I did.
Good.
I do.
You know what I mean?
I really,
I will admit it.
If I go back,
if I went back to Africa and help these
people out with their drinking water.
This one wants to do a documentary on it
makes them cash.
Oh yeah.
I do a special and Kilimanjaro on my way
home and I would market it.
And what kind of comedy would you do on
Kilimanjaro?
Oh Man.
These rebels folks who's dressing him?
No,
it's safe in Tanzania.
There's no conflicts.
There's no rebels.
It's nice and peaceful.
These people are kind of Nice.
They're good Kilimanjaro's like that.
[inaudible].
What would you do?
What kind of jokes would you.
When you're in Kilimanjaro,
they don't understand English very well,
so you have to be to get a little
physical.
Do the old grandpa and grandpa running
from the lion gag?
A couple boob jokes.
That sounds good.
I saw the lion king,
not the lion king.
Jungle book last night.
Yeah,
I saw it on the plane.
Spoiler alert.
All the animals can talk in the kid
lives.
I wanted to like it.
It just took itself.
So as soon as I heard Liam Neeson in the
beginning,
taking themselves too seriously,
I was out well,
and also they had a gigantic pithy gus
in it.
It was just.
I thought it was fascinating,
but they made it an orangutan.
They decided that a gigantic Pythius
wasn't orangutan an enormous orangutan
that knocked over a building.
It was just 10 foot tall orangutan that
can talk.
Spoiler alert.
Sorry.
Is it bad that I still want to say
Orangutang because it's sounds familiar.
Were you saying it wrong?
It's neander tall also by the list.
It's not fall too tall.
Some of the oldest human remains were
Tanzania.
Really?
Yeah.
Which,
uh,
how old were they?
I don't know.
Well,
they think that's where people evolve.
If you believe all that evolution
nonsense and not the Bible,
I do.
I do believe it.
I pity you.
I put your soul because you're going to
burn in a fiery pit.
Whoops.
I pity.
Or twitter,
I guess you fucked up.
That's where people evolved,
right?
Or one of the main places.
I think the original place where human
beings.
Ethiopia and then.
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
And then obviously they branched out in
different species of human,
different branches of human evolved.
They're always keep finding over the
last few years a bunch of new one.
I know these new branches,
you know,
they finally some teeth and go what us
and then they,
I think we got a new job bone here guys.
And then they do some DNA on it and
like,
holy fuck stick.
Did humans have tails?
Maybe I'll do via Tanzania.
Hmm.
Yeah.
This site in Tanzania that holds the
earliest evidence of the existence of
human ancestors.
You gotta go,
Joe,
you got to go.
You would love it.
Holy Shit.
Look at that.
They found hundreds of fossilized bones
and stone tools in the area dating back
millions of years leading them to
conclude that humans evolved in Africa.
Wow.
Millions of years.
Millions.
I didn't know they had stone tools,
millions of years ago,
million.
One of their saying fossilized bones and
stone tools.
Also millions.
Like how old was the oldest?
If you had to guess right now,
without any looking,
how old do you think the oldest stone
tool ever found was?
The oldest stone tool was discovered by
Benjamin Franklin in Philadelphia.
You're talking about his wife.
It's his,
his beard,
his old tool.
That's what we call this stone tool.
I'm very bad with thinking about,
uh,
about,
numbers like back into the past and,
and things out into the universe.
Like these billions don't make any
sense,
but I would guess I'm in my dumb way.
I would say,
uh,
a tool would be about a 2 million years
old.
Old.
Yeah.
I'm going to go with you.
I'll say about 2 million years.
So I'm impressed.
Let's say two point 8 million.
Wow.
Holy Shit.
That's a long time.
It's so long.
The artifacts are by far the oldest
handmade stone tools,
yet discovered the previous record
holders known as the older ones.
Don't tools.
We're about two point 6 million years
old,
so I was hunting reasonably in Nevada.
You got to go to Africa.
You.
You're built for this.
I was in Nevada though.
I was in the mountains in the high
country,
the high country desert hunting mule
deer doing this.
Archery,
hunting,
hiking,
backpacking,
camping out there.
Have found a.
found a stone.
Arrowhead.
You did?
Yeah.
While hunting.
I've found an ancient era.
That's the coolest.
It was the coolest shit ever because who
knows how old it was.
You keep it.
Well,
you're not supposed to,
so yeah,
of course.
You're not supposed to walk out with it.
They're the fuck outta here.
Fuck off is.
How big was it?
Tiny.
Small.
About that big.
It's amazing.
I've always wanted to find that.
I left it there.
I buried at Tom.
I buried it so someone else could find
it.
You're a good man.
I am a good man.
I want everybody know I buried it today.
You would.
I know you would want everyone to know
if I got a deer there.
I was going to take a photo of the new
arrowhead next to the old arrowhead,
not take a photo of him,
but glue them onto a piece with a photo
of the animal and then have it framed
for this thing.
It's a dope thing to find while your bow
and Arrow hunting.
You find an arrowhead from probably
Indian.
Yeah.
I'm sure.
Native Americans or indigenous people,
I mean engines in
scans,
you know that kind of Powwow,
eagles,
Eagle feathers,
you know them dudes.
You know,
whenever I say Indians,
my daughter always goes,
dad.
Yeah,
don't say American.
I'm like,
Oh,
I'm okay.
But then I was reading an article in the
New York Times about,
you know,
they're trying to put the pipeline
through North Dakota and they call them
the Lakota Indians.
They don't say the Lakota native
Americans,
so I'm not being offensive.
The lakota people I think is what
they're supposed to be calling
themselves.
I think they called them Indians in the
article.
Do you know that other Indians called
them?
The Su.
Su means enemy who the Lakota people
were on notorious war like people.
Right.
Tough.
Do you ever hear the Nez perce?
No big time.
Cannibals.
Oh yeah.
The Great Lakes areas.
Yeah.
They did a lot of killing and eating
white folks,
not.
They didn't like the white invaders,
so they ate them.
Took to killing them and eating them and
take their soul.
Oh,
here's something I found out that's very
important.
The revenue.
It's all based on bullshit.
No,
it's not fucking bullshit.
Here's what actually happened to that
guy.
No,
no,
no.
I read the account of the actual event.
Oh,
okay.
Here's a bunch of shit that never
happened.
It's first of all,
he never had a son.
You know?
His son was murdered by the guy who
wants to go up to the guy.
Never had a sense.
Not In the book,
by the way.
Second of all,
they never left him.
They never tried to bury them alive.
He was fucked up.
You got mauled by a bear and they left
him to die.
That he was going to die it in Barium.
They didn't bury them.
The guy crawled that sound in the book
either.
He never killed anybody.
He didn't kill anybody.
That guy never didn't kill anybody,
made it back to camp,
crawl back to camp,
got pissed.
Nearly go.
Sorry.
Um,
yeah,
it just ended.
He never killed him.
I know book either the guy who left him
to die,
wound up dying.
They all die really young back then.
But he,
uh,
the only thing that was true is he
survived.
He found an animal,
I think it was a moose or an elk that
had been killed by wolves and he ate
some of that and he killed and ate a
snake and that's all he had to eat his
entire way back and his body's all
fucked up.
And he did crawl his way back to
wherever the fuck he was going.
He actually,
yeah.
And then he,
uh,
then he got a horse you've got,
you've got a horse swimming Indian and
wrote it to a fort and then it just kind
of ends.
And when he fell off the cliff and
landed in the tree,
bullshit never happened.
Made up the book is pretty accurate to
the real account.
Oh yeah.
And my buddy told me to read it.
So,
uh,
putting together a little summer reading
list,
I threw that into the pile.
I hate that phrase.
Pretty accurate.
You're talking about like historical
events,
you have an obligation to have zero
bullshit that you add in there,
the story better,
but I think the book is,
I couldn't tell you 100 percent,
but all that stuff,
like as I was reading it,
it's really good book because it really
gets into the smallness of like what you
have in your,
in your utility bag and like walking
through and with this Indian would do.
And this is all,
it's very little subtle day to day stuff
that makes the book great.
Um,
but uh,
it just,
yeah,
it just kinda like drifted off in and
ended.
There was a,
there was a lot less drama.
The book was pretty dry.
Yeah.
Well that's the real life story,
right?
No.
So this is the account of all the stuff
that they carried with them,
like flint to start fires and things
along those lines.
Exactly.
The Flint,
what did they carry with them?
A little rope,
a little less fat,
fat,
fat.
I don't know,
to oil up their,
uh,
their tools.
Oh,
to make sure that their tools didn't get
rusted.
Probably a lot of stuff for their gun,
for their gun maintenance.
I'm what they call it,
a supplies bag or it was a cooler name
than that.
And so they had muskets back then.
Right.
So they would have like black powder and
they would pour it into the barrel.
Then they would have to pack it down and
put a primer in and they had a little
piece of flint they would drop down on a
hammer and the spark from that.
What had caused the explosion.
Yep.
So fucking primitive.
It's amazing.
Amazing.
It really is.
To me,
it's amazing how people just not just
got by back then,
but actually would go out into the
woods,
like barely,
barely supply.
Nothing.
Almost nothing.
Just against the weather.
Yeah.
Not Prepared.
You'll one pair of clothes I want to.
How much food they would bring and how
much that we just rely upon the land
because they didn't really know what the
hell was ahead of time.
They would
salt a lot of meat right?
They would salt it and jerk it and carry
that stuff,
but you know,
that was like,
you ate that when you were in a fix,
you know,
you had no food for awhile,
but they didn't.
They couldn't carry a lot of stuff.
We couldn't refrigerate stuff,
you know,
you're just living out there.
It's quite.
Think about a scary.
It would be just like sleeping there and
knowing that,
you know,
native Americans are coming through the
woods.
Well,
I got really stuck that you're on their
land.
Oh,
insane.
You know,
and you really are on their fucking
land.
Like you're really not supposed to be
there.
Brian Invading Army.
Yeah.
I put this article up yesterday that
somebody tweeted that I retweeted.
It was just a shocking article.
I started reading it about all of the
northern,
uh,
all the,
um,
southern California murders that
involved Indians and then California in
general,
like how many native Americans were
murdered when,
in establishing California when they
were pioneering,
like when they were first coming,
oh my God did this.
But these accounts were horrific.
Like firsthand accounts of thousands of
people are getting slaughtered,
including children,
babies,
women,
yeah.
This.
This all happened a couple of hundred
years ago.
After reading the revenant,
I decided I was so excited about reading
about the west I wanted.
I'm like,
let me learn about how the Indians
actually live.
Let me see.
They're small bags.
What did they carry and what was their
day to day?
I really wanted to kind of get into that
like an idiot.
I pick up a barry may have wounded knee,
which is the most horrific account of
the slaughter of native Americans.
It's just,
you know,
tribe after tribe.
It just takes you through our expansion
and going into each state and lying and
destroying and killing men,
women and children.
It's unreadable.
You literally can't get through it.
It's so recent.
I'm like,
I want to read a nice Indian story where
a white guy comes out and they know he's
cool and he gets a girlfriend and he's
like the one cool white guy and hangs
with the Indians.
I love Indians.
Dancing with wolves is my favorite
movie.
When the beautiful white man becomes the
best Indian,
I love it.
That's what I want.
Fucking horrible movie.
The best of the group who gets the
hottest woman is a beautiful white man
with a ponytail,
starts off slow.
He gets his ass kicked early.
Some of them,
some of the young guys don't trust them.
Yeah,
it's A.
There's a lot of rivalries.
Here's the story arc.
It's going to take a long time.
We need three plus hours,
three hours kind of fucking movie as
well.
He has to win the Indians.
Respect.
It's going to take time.
It's an amazing movie.
And Kevin Costner's onboard,
so Kevin believes in this.
Sold.
Kevin is.
First of all,
Kevin has been researching this for a
long time.
Okay.
It would be within your best interest to
make this film because if you don't,
someone will just tell you that now.
Okay,
we're
here out of respect because of our
previous relationship that we have with
universal getting made.
This is getting is getting made.
This is an amazing film.
I'm.
Kevin becomes the best Indian at the end
of the movie.
He kicks everyone's ass and Fox,
everyone's Pocahontas fucks their wives
and think about all the Indians you're
going to employ in this movie.
You won't have to hire black people for
the rest of the year,
and there was a young man at one point
in time in the film who seemed like he
and Kevin would be rivals.
Eventually he worships Kevin.
Thanks.
Kevin is amazing.
Kevin begins to dress like them.
Somehow or another though goes to a
barber and gets his haircut perfectly
around his ears.
It's weird like,
have you looked at St Louis?
He wasn't waterworld.
It's sort of melody,
but whatever's going on at the top,
he's obviously got some product in that
hair,
right?
I mean,
what's.
What's happening big time?
He's like,
yeah,
he's in a.
In a hair metal band.
Yeah.
My favorite is Wyatt earp.
Did you ever see when he played wider
up?
So he played wider and wider.
Was Young.
They just put a wig on a 40 year old
Kevin Costner.
You're like,
yeah,
I just make them one of these aging and
give him a fucking word.
And so I was like,
gee,
Mr. I don't know,
why did you beat me up?
This guy beats him up and he's got this
fucking.
He's a 40 year old guy with a wig on and
no one's.
No one's freaking out.
Everyone's like,
oh,
your kid's weird looking and then
fucking 25 years later it looks exactly
the same.
It's just so strange.
Voices a little deeper,
but he's got the loose skin thing going
on,
but he's got a mop of hair crazy fast.
Nobody cared.
They didn't have CGI back then.
You couldn't make it look like an 18
year old.
It wasn't four k.
no one was really looking back.
It looks so bad.
It looked like not even the healthiest
40 year old guy,
like 40 year old guy that probably does
a little coke every now and then I lose
it up.
I let him,
Gee,
Mr. I don't want that trouble.
That's him in wider,
but that's not him.
When he was the youngest,
that's him in the movie somewhere,
but he had an also lazy bitch.
Didn't even bother losing any weight for
that moving because he has a little bit
of a double chin.
You're a movie star.
Well,
you know,
he's like,
fuck it,
I'm directing,
I'm acting,
I get tired,
I want to snack.
I'm dealing with a lot.
All right.
By the way,
I love Kevin called and dances with
wolves is a fucking awesome movie.
I loved it,
but that is what happened.
But when you're going in thinking like
you're going to get that level of Indian
fun and then you read bury me at wounded
knee,
the first chapter alone is like a
Holocaust.
It's like it's really rough.
It is incredibly fucked up.
And you stop and think about the time
period of the 18 hundreds and then
previous to that how,
how recent.
That was incredibly fucked up.
It's incredibly fucked up and it's
incredible.
How much has happened is has happened up
till now.
Like I mean walking through this area in
like in the dark with no lights and it
was like being in Africa.
Right?
And now they didn't have overnight.
These guys camped at night and they
didn't have flashlights.
Nothing.
They couldn't even light a fire because
they thought it was going to track the
enemy.
Crazy.
This is not long ago,
dude.
Yeah.
Not long ago at all.
What people do when they find new spots
and so what they've done throughout
history to find out who's owning those
bots.
What's all the good stuff in those
spots.
All right.
We've got to kill those people to get
that good stuff.
Yeah,
and then they just jack them.
I don't understand why more parts of
Africa were exploited.
It's tough to it to.
First of all,
it's enormous.
If you think about the sheer size of
Africa and then there was also a lot of
stuff they tried to exploit.
I just.
One of the famous things about the Congo
is that European settlers tried to.
They tried to take the Congo and they
tried to colonize it.
You tried to move in and they tried to
gentrify the Congo.
They tried to like build houses and
they're still the remains of a lot of
these incredible mansions.
He tried to put like plantations up in
the Congo.
You go through all of it.
It was of.
That's when the Germans were here.
That's when the French owned it.
That's when the British owned it.
I mean that's the way it was.
People just came from Europe and took it
over and owned it.
The difference is they didn't come in in
most cases and slaughter everybody and
try and take it over for some reason.
They came in and just try to adapt those
people,
but people weren't moving down.
It's a hostile environment and there's,
you know,
I mean there's diamonds and all that
stuff and.
But there's no,
there's no real like minor thing that
you could exploit and bring to the rest
of the world in these areas that are.
There is in some areas and those areas
of deep trouble,
that's where you get like conflict
minerals.
A lot of that is they're getting some of
these minerals that they need for cell
phones and for some different things to
get a lot of those from Africa,
you know,
it was coming in big in Africa is China.
China is going in and building stadiums,
building football stadiums,
soccer stadiums,
really going in and building them for
free so they get and then they get in
with the government and they get all
these contracts because they see Africa
as the place that's going to be
exploited in the future in China's going
big.
Yeah.
I've heard that.
I heard they're buying up enormous
swaths of land.
Yeah.
It's kind of weird.
Bended.
The thing that China has gone on is that
they're kind of capitalists now.
Yeah,
a fiercely.
Yeah.
But they're also not in that they can
completely control their people can shut
down aspects of the Internet.
Like I had a friend who was an executive
at Google and they were going over there
and trying to talk with the Chinese and
trying to negotiate,
bring google,
but they had like some really bizarre
demands as far as their ability to enact
censorship.
And then on top of it they have no
laws when it comes to enforcing
copyright protection and um,
and,
and fraudulent items like they have full
apple stores in China that are all
fakes.
It's 100 percent counterfeit.
Yup.
It has a giant apple logo.
You go in there,
you buy apple laptops,
they all have the right names,
the right specifications.
All of it's fake and apple can't do
anything about.
I can't do a damn thing.
There's nothing they can do and the
government's not going to do shitty
there.
There's just what they do.
Look at this.
This is a fake apple store.
It's in China and it looks exactly like
crazy.
It has the same images on the wall.
They copied the images.
It is top of the logo.
Now that you know it is off just a
little bit.
Not really.
I wouldn't think so.
I wouldn't think so at all.
Look to it.
It has all the same ads.
They steal everything.
They steal all the ads.
They steal the font,
they steal the same sort of tables,
the thick,
you know earthy wooden tables that make
you feel good when you sit down on those
are our children and it's spelled store
wrong.
S t e r s t o u r get away with it.
That's the one thing we do.
No,
no,
no.
Your apple store.
Apple store.
This can't be common though.
Oh yeah.
It's common.
It is.
Yeah.
It is common.
They,
they just do this constantly.
There's a problem with this.
In the archery world,
there's a company called rage.
They make probably the most popular
broadhead for hunting.
It's called a rage hypodermic.
It's a very complicated design because
it's what's called a mechanical
broadhead.
And what this means is with archery,
a lot of the accuracy in archery
involves drag,
like how little drag you have,
meaning how much air impacts the Arrow
wind drift things on those lines.
And uh,
when you have an Arrow that's cutting
through the air,
like it has to be aerodynamic and it has
to operate in a specific way.
So the most accurate ones are these,
these arrowheads that are called
mechanical broadheads.
The problem with these things is they,
um,
they open up on impact,
so they hit and then they open up and
they create this huge wound channel.
So it goes open to like two inches.
But everything has to be like high
quality steel,
razor sharp blades that it has to fit
perfectly.
The tolerances are incredibly small
because everything has to be.
You're talking about like to be an
ethical hunter,
you have to not just be good at it.
You have to make an accurate shot,
you have to practice and you have to
have the best equipment.
Right?
So this is like one of the best pieces
of equipment you could buy if it's real.
But the problem is they're making fake
ones in China.
No blades are dull and the metals cheap
and they break off.
Are they selling them here?
They don't know.
People don't know.
They don't even know if they're buying
him.
I mean you could buy them from a
disreputable company that's getting them
from China and they look exactly the
same.
She,
it has the same logo,
the same fonts.
And when you buy
these things,
you're shooting amount on animal,
like it's entirely likely you're
shooting a cheap piece of steel against
China.
And for this company that's put all this
money,
this company a rage that's put
incredible amounts of money and
resources and designing this incredible
piece of archery hunting equipment
there.
They're fucking pissed.
Of course China is ruthless.
I mean with us like that with all that
stuff we're saying that like if
she's dead right,
she died,
she did die.
She was nice.
She was a,
the whole poaching problem in Africa.
China.
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
They don't get what they want.
They want Rhino Horn and uh,
they'll pay millions of dollars for
seeing what it does to your Dick.
No,
it doesn't do anything.
Let's check and see if they're paying
attention.
So funny.
Are you really happy for a second?
Because they were saying because they
were talking about how they work in this
whole like Serengeti area.
They have like a place just for rhinos.
It's the only animal that they've walled
off because they were in there trying to
protect it from these poachers.
Credible.
And uh,
I was like,
the only explanation is do something
here to.
Well,
do you see that they three d printed a
fake rhino horns.
Oh,
use cellulose and all the different
things.
I guess it's cellulose,
right?
Like what are they used to make them.
But they are three d printing,
fake rhino,
Horn.
Brilliant.
That literally the seemed to be rhino
horns to,
to collectors.
They're going to flood the market with
them.
That's great.
It is great.
But it's.
They should also put chips in.
I'm in busted with people buying it.
Yeah.
But you don't tell him don't give a
fuck.
Who Cares?
Yeah.
So you've got another dude who kills
rhinos.
We're gonna.
We're just.
So we'll just go to the Tigers,
get some tiger dick next.
I went by a in Tanzania next to the
Serengeti,
like the Serengeti is this huge national
preserve and the place where I stayed,
this Guy Paul Tudor Jones,
who's a focusing is a guy in New York
because in New York,
Hedge Fund guy who a philanthroper now
and uh,
he bought all the land next to the
Serengeti where people were poaching and
people were destroyed.
The whole population.
There were no animals and he went in,
bought the land,
bought up all the hunting licenses from
the,
from Tanzania for 99 years,
and in 10 years time it just exploded
with animals.
The whole population is back.
Wow.
Poaching is major,
Major,
major problem.
Here's the problem with poaching,
um,
the word poaching [inaudible].
A lot of it is really fucking poor
people that are just trying to survive.
So like to say that like poaching is an
issue in Africa.
Poverty is an issue in Africa,
right?
Poaching is a symptom of the poverty in
Africa,
getting lunch,
not even necessarily talking about like
the big money stuff like the ivory trade
and the Rhino Horn trade.
That can be applied to that as well.
But a big part of poaching
is just meat is just eating.
Stealing meat.
Yeah.
They call them poachers,
but what they really are is that they're
hunters.
They're aren't property owners right now
and these guys,
they run around,
they,
they do snares to catch these animal and
snares.
They,
they have these really shitty,
almost like musket,
like guns that they've devised,
like really similar to take a rifle and
they,
but they don't have bullets so they uh,
rocks in it.
They put things in it and then they pack
in gunpowder and they light it and make
it blow like a,
like a fucking rifle or like a musket.
It's,
yeah,
they use some really shitty.
I mean some of them.
Yeah,
I know you can't put your western.
You can.
I know there's a tendency to put
everything through our western prism and
be like,
you know,
this is just a horrible thing,
but when you go through these villages
where they literally are walking a mile
for water and you know,
you get meat,
that's like a big thing.
I mean look,
these people,
it was my wife's birthday when we were
there.
They don't have the phrase happy
birthday.
They don't celebrate birthdays.
Like they said,
it's because you'll have to have gifts,
will have to take time away from
working.
We'll have to do.
They just never came up with the concept
happy birthday because their life is
hard.
They don't have a lot of,
uh,
a lot of,
they don't have a word for dessert,
they don't celebrate,
they're hardworking,
surviving people.
So just to the point that you're right,
there are a lot of people that just need
meet for their family and they're not
thinking that a tourist from La is
coming in and wants to take pictures of,
of the Zebra,
you know what I mean?
But there's gotta be a way to Parse it
out because China's still is a huge
problem and they're taking all these
animals for endangered animals,
not for meat.
You know what I mean?
They're coming in and taking rhinos are,
they're taking cheetahs,
were not many survive.
Even just the nature taking Cheetah's
just for the coats they'd like to make
hats out of them.
Really?
Cheetahs,
I don't know,
probably jockstraps.
It's all jockstrap.
All the steps in China.
You don't know that well,
you've seen the Cheetah judge
jockstraps,
right?
Most of the articles I'm finding on pull
it up,
three d printed rhino horns.
Yeah.
That,
uh,
they have them in their make or there is
a couple of companies that aren't going
to start making them the,
but there are people that are saying
it's not a good idea to have them
introduce because it's going to cause
more problems than they're already
having with just the real ones.
They look real.
But the thing is,
is that a real.
Are those real or fake?
These are the picture I'm showing is
real ones,
but a national geographic problems that
are going to come.
It's so fucked up that what's killing
these crazy animals.
So we're going to miss so much.
I know a dinosaur.
It's a dinosaur.
It's,
it's like a stegosaurus or something.
It might as well be.
But what's killing them is this
erroneous idea that the horns make your
dick hard.
I mean,
if that's not symptomatic or symbolic of
how fucking bizarre humans are.
And meanwhile at the same time there's
plenty of fucking pills that actually do
the job.
It's not like you're asking these rhino
horns to do something that no pill could
do.
We've solved this problem to see Anna
Nicole Smith,
j Howard Marshall,
that old guy who married a creepy dude.
He's like in his eighties and he married
that big titted sloppy slut.
Why did he do that?
Because they had Viagra finally.
You could fucker.
It's right on a bit of money.
He just fucking kept his cowboy boots on
and that is a great point.
It's like why?
Why the Rhino thing?
Exactly.
But it's,
but it's not probably not just for their
hard on.
It's probably also because they think
they can cure cancer with it.
No,
no.
It's really more.
There's j Howard Marshall and Anna
Nicole.
It's really,
I think more of anything.
A status symbol.
You come over a man's house,
you have some rhino.
T both were,
you know,
expense.
Cheetah,
expensive to leap.
Watches,
you know,
you drive a Ferrari.
He has a Rolls Royce.
You talk about real estate.
You're buying and you do something.
You would pull out a Cuban cigar.
Tom,
where'd you get the Cubans?
Hey,
I got a buddy who lives in Miami and
let's,
let's sit out on the back porch and
pretend we're gentlemen.
I mean there's so many people that never
fucking smoke cigars and it gets so
pumped about getting a Cuban Cuban Cuban
on what?
Gun?
With a gun to oil de Monterrey double
corona.
Lots of fat.
When I looked at afterwards today,
it's just a fake with a label on it.
Going to do a whole lot of those.
I can tell the difference.
I used to box,
I was buy real ones,
but I used to buy real ones that would
pretend they're fake from London.
That's to order them from London.
They would send them to be from a
tobacco.
Is that what they call them in London?
Tobacco.
They would send me the actual labels.
Like weeks later they'd send these
things to me in boxes and they would
just be labeled Dominican cigars and
then I get it,
but I,
I had specific cigars that I would ask
for such a stupid.
As soon as I started smoking weed at
dumped that habit.
Don't you like this nonsense?
You don't find it enjoyable.
I do.
But it's just.
There's something about it that's very
fetishy.
effected.
It's like you're putting on airs.
Definitely.
Yeah.
When I smoke.
So a guy with a fat face and he's got a
cigar.
I'm like,
Oh,
what is this dip shit have to say,
yeah.
Everyone on the cover of Cigar
Aficionado.
It looks like an asshole.
I have you stand this Myelin.
Yeah,
come on,
but when you're just being that asshole
like night,
ever make it onto the cover of cigar
aficionado.
Please find out if that's a good
question.
He always had a cigar.
He was a good spokesman for the brand
that
that is the part of the appeal.
You do sit back and just say,
you know what?
Yeah,
yeah.
I'm all right.
Sit back.
Everything's good.
Yeah,
I'm here.
All right.
I got a guy when I got my family back
from that vacation and nobody had
malaria or cuts or any emergencies and I
got them all the way back from Africa.
I sat out back with one and I was like,
yeah,
yeah.
Back here in California,
back here.
I might vote Republican.
I don't give a fuck.
I am a lion.
How about we give Donald Trump a chance
to make America great again?
No,
you're going too far.
You're taking them to Sean Combs.
Look at them looking like an asshole.
Everyone looks like an a little tiny
hands.
Jack Nicholson is the only one that
doesn't look like an asshole.
Hands are.
Yeah,
Jack.
Jack was made for it,
but Jack Nicholson also looks like you
didn't pose.
Is there something wrong with his hands
or is it me?
Is Puff.
Daddy's hands are very small.
They're in front of him.
They look weird way out in front of him.
The perspective looks weird,
but they're small,
so like if you put it up to his chest,
he got a little baby hands with the guy.
He played sugar Ray Leonard and that
knew Roberto Duran movie.
Usher can box apparently.
No.
Yeah,
yeah.
Hands of stone.
Yeah,
he played.
He played sugar ray and everyone looks
like an asshole.
Let's pull up the most foolish covers of
popular cigar,
cigar aficionado.
Jack Nicholson looks great.
Vince Vaughn looks pretty douchey right
there.
Yep.
Click that.
What the fuck?
What do you plot and things?
Hey,
as brothers kind of thing that we have
together.
Hey,
you cannot look.
Do you all look like an idiot?
Oh,
Charlie.
Charlie Sheen,
cigar smoking aids.
I don't give a fuck.
Everybody was waiting until he got HIV.
They smell so bad.
You can't have one without thinking.
What is this?
Screw everybody.
You know what I mean?
Oh,
you smoke a cigar.
You're saying,
fuck you guys.
I'm smoking this.
I know it's awful,
but I'm enjoying it.
So when you see a guy with it,
that's what you're seeing in his eyes.
He looks pretty good.
You know,
he purposely adds weight.
He puts weight on and keeps weighed on
because it fills his face in and he
keeps him from looking wrinkly.
That's how rooker should take that
advice because.
Well,
I'll broke her.
Did the opposite.
You know Joe Manchin's pretty good.
Do you know that guy has a gun nut?
Izzy?
He's got a gun show.
I've watched his gun show.
He's got a gun show in the sports
channel.
Yes,
he does.
I watched it.
You're thinking of Joe Montonya?
No,
no,
no.
Joe Montana.
He has a fucking gun history show and he
shoots guns constantly.
That's great.
These are gun nut,
like a full on second amendment.
No,
no,
I don't say that in a negative way.
I like guns.
I do too,
but it's like a helix,
right?
I'm sure he's not going to be open to
any ideas.
Maybe see gun stories.
Is the name of his show bad?
It's great.
It's a gun nut.
It's got a gold pistol there.
I bet he's rock hard right now.
I bet he's like Anthony Wiener.
Rock hard,
like strapped down inside his boxer
shorts,
so fucking angry.
Hog.
Ready to go.
He really loves guns.
It's a fucking show.
It's on the outdoor channel.
Watch the show.
Does it make me less of a man that my
passion is bread?
No,
no.
You're the salt of sour dough.
It's not just that you're passionate
bread.
You take it to a whole new level.
Thank you.
You were featured in the New York Times.
Thank you,
Joe.
This Joe Montana thing is interesting
though because I haven't seen him in
movies in a long time and he's a
brilliant actor and now this guy has
been in some fucking amazing movies.
Now what he does,
he took all that money.
Just shoot shit.
He golfs a lot too.
I think he's always looking in those
golf tournament.
It might be one of them,
Arizona dudes.
You know,
Arizona,
Arizona to this day is the God damn wild
west.
It's the Florida of the southwest.
You know what I mean?
A lot of people end up there with their
own ideas.
Oh,
they've got their own ideas.
Yeah,
and that's why they had that sheriff
that put everybody in pink underwear.
Yeah,
he's still there.
Aleppo.
So a power pio.
Joe Arpaio.
Yeah.
He just got in trouble.
He's good buddies with Steven Seagal.
He'll get them out of trouble.
Steven will get them out of trouble.
Was that video reel with Steven Seagal?
Was like Brando size now.
He was doing movies and yeah,
he's enormous.
He's really big.
He's enormous.
Yeah.
I've run into with the UFC a bunch of
times.
He has the skills just
well.
Um,
what low skills are he's good at?
He's good at those things that he's
doing
in those movies.
Would those things actually work?
No,
they would not work.
Right.
What you're seeing in those things is a,
some what you would call active
compliance,
so voluntary compliance maybe where
someone look up videos.
It's hilarious.
It looks like you're running around.
He's riding around with this.
A bunch of people I've got to kill and
he's just got this enormous gut.
He's huge.
He keeps making these movies and I'm
sure they do really well and foreign
markets,
you know?
Yeah.
It's probably one of those things where
if you're in Bulgaria,
it's like Steven Seagal night every
Tuesday.
It almost looks like he's kidding,
right?
Like the way he holds the gun and so
big.
Joe Montana,
by the way,
was in criminal minds when sharp 105
episodes and just stopped this year.
Who is this guy that I've seen this guy
before?
Who's The guy?
The White Guy,
that guy.
Oh yeah.
I have seen him,
uh,
say that code of honor.
Whole 2016.
Oh,
it's coming.
It's coming out now.
Is a bomb about to go off and I have a
knife.
Ooh.
Watch me walk away.
Do the classic dyed his hair is to walk
away without looking back as the bomb
goes off.
Yeah.
That is original and awesome.
Who's The guy?
Who's the other guy that,
uh,
that other guy that's in those movies?
Say Craig Schaeffer.
Okay.
Oh,
you know,
that guy is,
that guy's in movie a river runs through
it.
You know?
Does that him?
He was Brad Pitt's brother in that
movie.
There's a hell that some actors fall
into.
Yeah,
that's him then.
Oh yeah.
There's a hell at some actors fall into.
Wow.
I think that dude's nutty though.
I think that guy's very nutty.
I think he is nutty.
I was at a restaurant once and that guy
was like a talking to a couple.
He's eating by himself with a Bandana
on.
He was talking to a couple about someone
being an old soul.
Oh God.
Just one of the things.
Is that him?
Wow.
He looks so different.
He's got a wig on.
It's definitely not hair.
Yeah.
But what's going on there?
Back Up.
Jamie.
Why you getting away from that wig?
What's happening there?
What's going on?
Let's put a wig on it.
Is he crying?
Is that a mouse?
Oh,
that's your cursor.
Um,
yeah.
That guy was in a lot of good shit
though.
Then now he's doing these weird movies.
Joe Montana works.
Yeah,
I'm sure.
Criminal minds.
He was in a really big series.
Oh yeah,
yeah.
Going to yes.
Just like.
Oh,
that's right.
He was in that fucking,
that horror movie to that Craig
Schaeffer Guy was in that horror movie.
Remember that weird horror movie that
was based on the Fox?
His name?
No,
no,
no.
Not that one.
What movie was that?
Uh,
I don't know.
Johnny.
Scary face.
I forget the fucking movie man.
But it was a,
it was.
There was a guy who wrote tales from the
crypt.
So is it night?
Read ascension night.
Read.
He's best known at horror fans is to
starve nightbreed.
Nightbreed might read he.
Sure that's.
That might be reading goodnight moon and
that seems like a Typo.
It's really serious.
Go try nightbreed.
I hate breed.
Yeah.
Night.
Who made that movie man?
Because it was one of those.
We'll look at that.
Who is the,
uh,
the director and writer,
that movie.
It looks like a Halloween show because
he was a famous sort of a,
a clive barker.
Clive Barker.
That was clive barker.
Yeah.
Clive Barker made a bunch of like really
freaky fucking movies,
like really interesting,
weird takes on horror and apparently a
very good writer.
Right.
Like his books.
My,
I'm not making that up.
Right,
right.
You don't think so?
I don't think you're making it.
Okay.
Yeah,
I think that's where it all started out
as from his writing.
Uh,
I think he was a famous horror writer.
Yeah.
And then they did a few of his movies
back in the day,
but for whatever reason they didn't
catch on.
But nightbreed was a really interesting
one and that Craig Schaeffer guy was in
that.
He was he.
Was He ever on Cigar Aficionado?
No.
Never made it.
But Brad probably did.
You probably get mad bought,
bought the issue.
Fucking Brad on this shit out here is
fat guys throwing kicks at me.
Fucking hell man,
because I.
Bryan County is a great guy to talk to
the stop because Brian Cowen knows a lot
of those actors.
He knows a lot of actors,
right?
And he's had friends that were like
really famous actors at one point right
now.
They have been forced to take these gigs
whenever they can get them right and you
know,
they're away from their family for
months at a time and they don't make
much money and their hope is that this
does well.
And then eventually it's like you're in
a holding pattern hoping that you catch
fire with a good,
a good film and then it gets you into
another film and then you're back.
But when you drop off,
and especially if there's a
transitionary period between you being a
30 year old man,
be in a 50 year old man,
those 50 year old guys are Foxville
further fucked right.
Nobody wants you until you're 60.
And then if someone's dad it,
there's like this period of time where
you're not quite old enough to be a dad,
you're definitely not old enough to be
the.
Not Young enough to be the hot guy.
Yeah.
You can't be really an ass kicker.
Nobody's going to believe it.
You know,
like Steven Seagal has to do all kinds
of crazy shit to be maintained as
kicking status.
All dying.
His beard,
his beard died.
The hares,
the hares have a masterpiece.
It's a lot going on.
Maybe it's doing the shatner thing.
Maybe he's like,
I'll just put the weight on and just be
a bigger guy.
Good move.
Apparently Schachner says keeps your
face fall.
It's like the opposite of hits his
version of Collagen.
Just fill it up.
It's pretty smart.
Just fill that.
He doesn't on purpose.
He really,
allegedly,
he says he might just be an excuse for
why he just drinks every night.
Right?
He can't stop drinking.
I,
uh,
but I,
he looked pretty good on cigar fishing.
I would.
Jack Nicholson,
I think agreed is the best.
If they called you tomorrow,
would you do it?
Yeah.
What would you do?
Oh,
that's a good wolf.
Is there a way to do it and uh,
not be wacky or Douchey?
Just you holding it is.
Do you feel Douchey?
Yeah.
How about you just stand there and it
just says,
trust me,
I smoke cigars and there's no cigar
insight.
Look at that.
Yeah.
Does not work.
Yeah,
I know how many takes that was.
If that was one picture.
Oh,
if he was just there,
he pulled up in this car.
Hey,
how y'all doing?
And they took a picture and he had the
cigar.
Bam.
Cool.
Let's see.
The problem with those photos is there
not candidate?
Not.
If you're an intelligent person that
understands that and you're watching
these fucking magazine stands,
you know that there was some douchey and
evolve and making this cover.
That's one of Andre's Lee.
Hey y'all.
I got a white hat on because I'm a good
guy.
You want me to go with the black hat
now?
You want me to have a white hat?
Sort of a guy according to my record
label.
So that Jeremy Pivot down there.
Oh,
does he have a glass in his hand or was.
No,
no,
they changed outfits.
There was a makeup lady.
You know what I mean?
It's good for Sutherland.
Oh,
what's this?
No Cigar.
Cute.
There's no fucking cigar.
Yeah,
him and Deniro.
Hey,
what the fuck is this Kiefer?
Listen,
Pussy.
You're scared to pull it off.
We'll get cramer bond.
No,
Sukar White.
Go to a Kramer's over.
By the way.
Best James Bond by far,
right?
Daniel Craig.
No one's even close.
He's the coolest.
Oh,
Kramer.
Kramer is lovable.
You know he's thinking when he's holding
that cigar.
I love black people.
Yeah,
just thinking,
thinking,
thinking.
That word rhymes with bigger.
Danny Devito.
He's got something going on.
What is he doing?
He's lighting it.
There's too many.
Too many takes there.
There's no.
There was more than one take.
I can pull it off on the inside.
I don't care.
This is good for publicity.
This is good for my image.
When I smoke is the God gives you the
feeling.
Prosperity.
I live in a mansion in the palisades and
I fuck my maid Dai
gum inside them.
I don't leave your wallet with me.
I come inside her as well.
Is cover works.
Adrian Brody,
I'm just sitting here wondering what
happened.
No,
you're right.
Arnold is the perfect person at
investors to loan.
Seems fairly candid photos,
but I'm worried there was too many
takes.
I'm worried.
They took several takes.
There's a guy who looks pretty fucking
Jiffy for seven years old.
Even if you are still on and you let it
go,
you let them put stallone zone as
you're.
No,
no,
no.
You can't do that.
No,
no,
no.
No.
Zone is pretty good.
I like what you're doing by the way.
I met that guy.
Fucking super friendly.
Nice normal self deprecating guy.
Varying.
He might've been turned on the charm
because I had to interview him for this
thing,
for the UFC once,
but he was fucking.
I met that guy to Laurence Fishburne.
Fuck.
Super friendly.
Is that Rob Lowe?
Rob Lowe have a cigar in his hand.
He pulled it off.
Rob [inaudible].
He's kind of not fiduciary numb by it.
Yeah.
Look at his jacket.
He's got that fucking bouncing jacket on
that country club jacket that just did
the rest of the rob lowe this weekend,
right?
Yeah.
Why is you have so many layers on?
I'm confused about is white tee shirt
than polo shirt than jacket.
Can someone turn the fucking heat on?
Why does it robs inside?
Why is it,
why does he have to dress like he's
layering for a backpacking trip in the
Andes?
But you know,
you hit on something if you,
if you embrace your.
Do sheree?
Yeah,
it works if you're,
if you're,
uh,
trying to not be a Douche with it,
it doesn't work.
Cause go down there.
Oh Jesus.
Oh look.
And he's got a glass of something.
An Espresso.
That's what he jammed them with.
Right?
Didn't eat.
Jam Him up with like Cappuccinos.
He put it in a drink.
He did.
His cappuccinos tastes kind of shitty.
Kind
of pretending it taste good.
Get it fucking roofie in it.
Can't.
Oh my God,
there was one above that.
There was one above that.
Jeremy,
um,
that I didn't recognize.
The gentleman right to the upper left
with the black blazer on upper left.
Above that one,
right above that one.
No,
no,
no.
Back where you were,
right.
Go cosby and then go to the left to the
left.
And that guy.
Who's that fucking guy?
The bomber.
Oh,
what the fuck is that?
it's a,
it's a fake.
It's a matter of looking at.
Oh,
well that will,
that.
What that's doing is that's mocking the
rolling stone cover because rolling
stone put him on the cover and he looks
like a fucking teen.
Heartthrob was douchey.
Well,
it was weird.
It was really weird,
but isn't douchey.
Here's my question.
It's just a photo of them and it is
curious that he,
they took a tremendous amount of
criticism for this cover.
Okay.
Well,
I'm looking at this.
What is,
this is just what happened.
Um,
you,
you're looking at this.
This is just a young man man,
but he has.
I mean he has a cover of a magazine.
It's your job to put things on rolling
stone and you know how to look at things
that make people feel a certain way,
so maybe they were trying to make them
feel like,
hey,
he's a monster.
Can look like this.
Yeah,
but recent listened to the heading.
Highly popular,
promising student was fueled by his
family,
but what was failed?
Oh,
it was failed.
Was failed by his family,
fell into radical Islam and became a
monster.
Yeah.
You're making that seed now with the
headline.
I dislike it even more because now
you're making him seem like he's just a
vulnerable.
Not.
It's not his fault.
You're excusing him.
I think with that photo and that
headline combined,
it feels to me like you're.
You're letting them off the hook.
Well,
that is a weird question.
Why is it that you do that where you
read a couple letters of a word and just
fill it in for yourself?
I do that all the time.
Yeah.
Where I find myself,
even if I'm wearing reading glasses,
I fill in a word and then I go,
oh,
what's that word?
For whatever reason I don't.
You just saw the whole world I saw
fueled.
Yeah,
because I was thinking,
okay.
They would say is fueled by hate or
fueled by his radical religion.
I wouldn't have been so douchey and
corrected you,
but it didn't change the meaning of it.
Yeah.
But how old is this kid at the time?
Because I think if you're looking at it
like an 18 year old kid,
I mean that's relevant being you have a
14 year old.
Imagine if your kid grew up in some
fucking radical,
crazy fuck had religion.
You could look there.
There's,
there's a good question though,
like how did this kid become this
monster?
How did he become this monster?
His when his brother,
right.
His brother was a big influence.
His brother definitely was an influence,
but I mean he's,
he's in there,
right?
So he's in this magazine,
he's on the cover and they have this
picture of him that makes you go,
wow.
Yeah,
what?
What the fuck is wrong with that
picture?
Is What's wrong with it is that he looks
like a cute young guy that shouldn't
have that problem.
They're not saying young heartthrob
contact him behind bars,
they're just showing an actual picture
of what he actually looked like.
How is that any different than the Ted
Bundy photos?
Because the Ted Bundy photos.
One of the things that was most striking
about Ted Bundy was that he's a very
handsome guy,
so it's kind of fucking crazy
man,
but you don't put them on the cover of
rolling stone,
which is a space for the people in our
culture that you worship,
right?
They didn't put Ted Bundy on the cover
with the rolling stone logo around you.
You know what I mean?
That's.
That's a good point.
A good point,
but should they bear the burden of that?
Should they be able to be flexible
enough with their covers,
their ideas to just say what happened
here?
We take this guy who could be on our
cover because he's a pop star.
He could be on the cover because he's a
star.
If some new Sitcom.
It's Hilarious,
right?
He looks right.
He looks like a star.
He looks like a star and that's what I'm
saying.
Like these people know,
they know what they're doing when
they're putting that cover on.
It's you are provoking,
hey,
this is a regular kid that going this
way could have been on the cover of
rolling stone.
Maybe it's.
They're definitely creating it to be
thought provoking.
Bang them in prison.
They put that picture on the bag.
They've got to want to know,
look,
I'm fucking making it here.
Banging this guy.
Yeah,
he's beautiful.
it is kind of fucked up,
but I don't like they're saying there's
something wrong with that photograph.
Particularly like they could have had a
picture of him being handcuffed in look
terrified,
look on his face,
shock covered blood or anything along
those lines and everybody would
been okay with it,
right?
Yeah.
Wouldn't they be?
Yeah,
for sure.
It's because of it because it's a
psaltery innocent.
Yeah.
That isn't that a problem with static
images in the first place,
like static images as such.
Poor representations of what a person
actually looks like and who would that
person actually is.
You know,
it's one of the weirder things about
photos and then you see like a bio below
the photo and you're standing there,
oh,
Tom.
Papa has been doing standup clubs in
colleges all throughout the country.
Like what is.
This is a a portrayal of two dimensional
pull portrayal of a person.
There is a picture of me out from when I
hosted this game show on Fox just for a
summer and there's this shot of me in a
suit.
I look so douchey.
I'm leering at the camera.
I looked like a magician
for some reason.
That picture is every.
Any time I go to a city and you go to go
to perform.
Anytime someone puts an ad out for a
show,
that's the.
That's the picture.
I would not buy a ticket to see that
guy.
I can't scrub it from the Internet,
but what'd you buy a ticket?
I wouldn't buy a ticket to see any comic
ever based on any fucking shot have ever
seen.
That's a good point.
That makes me feel a little better.
Yeah.
Bill Hicks,
Bill Hicks's headshot was him lighting a
cigarette with American flag.
You will rebel.
So fucking clown.
Oh,
do you?
You're on the edge.
It's true.
There's no.
Yeah,
there's no way to look.
Cool.
Yeah,
that was,
that was bill's head shot.
Yeah.
But you know,
in his defense in 1988,
that was a radical thing to do.
That was.
And that was back when there was like a
big problem with people burning the flag
he had during the Bush Bush one.
Bush one.
Yeah.
I remember that.
They were like trying to take measures
to stop people from burning the flag.
We're burning the flag.
Bill Hicks had a bit about it.
Yeah.
Know my daddy fought for this flag and
Korea.
He was.
What a coincidence.
My fly was made in Korea rape joke.
You hear about the controversy about the
football player this week and not
wanting to stand during the national
anthem for Nick.
What did he,
what was he protesting?
The country hidden and hit whole.
If flat earth.
He doesn't want to stand in for a
country that allows a violence against
people of color.
Is that what it is?
So black or white guy?
Oh,
good.
Mostly who's a white guy.
Fucking hate him.
I kinda looks pretty white to me.
You show that to black.
Okay.
That's very healing for me.
It was a little
boy.
He's where?
He's the biggest trouble maker around
the pyramids.
And
uh,
so he.
What is he saying he wants to end?
Did he have a statement?
Always.
They always have a statement.
You have some fucking respect for
people.
Especially people who says that it's on
him.
Boone,
someone's really upset drives me knowing
about it.
My view is that the anthem is about
honoring the people serve.
This is another person to find out what
his actual quote.
What was his quote?
I'm here to play games out here to
salute symbols.
You fuck heads.
It's not a requirement by,
for NFL players to stand during the
singing of the national anthem.
It's suggested.
Oh really?
They do not a requirement.
Right.
That's probably constitutional.
Probably constitutionally can't require
someone to be patriotic.
Which is kind of ironic,
isn't it?
The freedoms that you get.
But a company could probably in this
country,
could they require that other of their
employees.
You could put the American flag on her
clothes maybe.
Yeah,
maybe that's the big team putting on the
uniform.
Big Team goes to war.
We all get together.
It's like people go state the first
thing,
legal local or like Husky highschool
team versus highschool team.
Right.
Then they go statewide where it's like
state college versus other colleges.
Then they go nfl and once it go nfl,
Dan,
it's like state franchises.
That's the big league,
but the real big league was an all teams
get together and they'd go to armies and
armies.
The biggest big team and then we go to
fuck up other teams.
So it's very important that we keep an
active organized sports program so that
we are investing in this idea of teams
so that we can fuel the big team.
Yeah,
but the other part of it is if you
didn't have the NFL,
Pittsburgh would be marching on
Cleveland,
right?
Problem.
They would be right.
If you didn't have.
If you didn't have sport,
people would wear like taking that
aggression.
They would.
They'd March across and go after
Cleveland.
Well,
it's,
well,
that's how we keep ourselves from going
to war inside the country,
inside the boundaries,
but it doesn't keep us from doing it
outside the boundaries.
No.
There was a whole radio lab thing about
the invention of football and what it
really was was the.
They had a bunch of men that came back
from the war and they were looking for
something to do to alleviate some of the
stress,
the creative football.
One of the motivations for them creating
football in the first place.
It makes sense.
Totally makes sense and you need it.
You need that.
You need an outlet.
Yeah,
like guys just run around like maniacs.
Eighteen minutes long,
but here's something I'll let you read.
His men was 18 minutes.
It's him talking in the locker room
afterwards because all the reporters
were asking him questions.
I want him to explain himself.
He says,
I am going to continue to stand with the
people that are being oppressed.
Capper,
nick,
that's his name.
Yeah.
This is something that has to change
when there's significant change and I
feel like that flag represents what it's
supposed to represent.
This country is representing people the
way it's supposed to.
I'll stand her.
He said,
I don't know if I did,
was write A.
I said he hasn't heard from the NFL.
Anybody else about his actions won't
matter if he does.
No one's tried to quiet me and to be
honest,
it's not something I'm going to be quiet
about it.
He said,
I'm going to speak the truth when I'm
asked about it.
This isn't for look,
this isn't for publicity or anything
like that.
This is for people don't have the voice
and this is where people that are being
oppressed,
that need to have equal opportunities to
be successful,
to provide for their families and not
live in poor circumstances.
Okay.
That's a lot.
He's added a bunch of shit there too.
Yeah,
you got.
It's important.
You get your message out in just a
phrase.
Yeah.
Well we'll also.
This is.
This is where it gets people being
oppressed that don't have the equal
opportunities to be successful,
to provide for families and not live in
poor circumstances.
That's one sentence.
The word to provide for families and not
live in poor circumstances is one
sentence.
Yeah,
that's idealistically.
That's interesting,
but America is supposed to represent
like the entire group experiment.
This experiment in self government
that's still ongoing and it's not.
It's not perfect.
It's not done and it's definitely got
some dark aspects to it,
but if you don't think it's the best
thing going,
he should go look around this.
There's some dark parts of America.
There's some dark parts about how what
we're talking about today.
I mean how we were founded and how this
land was acquired in the first place.
It's acquired by fucking murder mean.
Do you ever think that that's when we
have problems that maybe it's Karma?
Well,
no,
because I don't think it's us.
It's not Uri,
but there is something incredibly fucked
up about a country that is so willing to
look at some aspects of our society that
are discriminating or discriminatory.
Like the article that I pointed out
today where this woman was writing about
how women are drinking
because of the patriarchy,
because of sexism is forcing them to
drink and the suppression.
The American Indians were slaughtered,
the native Americans were fucking
slaughtered and they never come up
genocide.
It almost never comes up when you talk
about equal opportunity in America,
it's very few conversations begin with
we've got to do something about the
poverty and extreme alcoholism on these
native American reservations.
You know why it doesn't come up because
we wiped out so many of them.
There's just not that many left.
Well,
there's enough left that they have a
voice and they talk,
but it's not something that people are
concerned with.
I mean slavery.
Absolutely.
It was fucking awful and is something
that we absolutely should pay attention
to and we should absolutely look at the
impact of slavery over a long period
like where these people lived as slaves
for hundreds of years and then they were
finally freed into this area where
there's massive amounts of racism.
Not just racism,
like,
you know,
I like to stick to my own car,
but racism,
like where people are denigrated in
their thought to be like a lesser human
being.
Systemic.
It's systemic and it's deep and it's.
And then it's going to take hundreds of
years,
like many generations to get past that.
Right.
And we still definitely haven't gotten
past that,
a lot of those places and we concentrate
on that and it's a big part of our,
our national discussion conversation and
yeah,
but it ain't shit compared to what the
native Americans went through,
slaughtered,
and their land just taken.
Just taken,
you know,
I mean,
if you read this article that I read
today,
I'm sure first of all,
again,
is not taking anything away from the
people that suffered from slavery or the
genocide that was committed on black
people.
Exactly to that.
A lot of people gone.
But I feel like the,
it's not that I want less attention
being paid on what happened to African
Americans.
I think they,
there's not enough,
but w we should have way more than we
have right now on native Americans.
It's,
yeah,
it's,
you know,
it's really crazy.
You know,
it's a real violation.
No,
it felt really dirty when I saw it was
on my,
uh,
on my motorcycle and went through the
Dakotas and saw the mount rushmore and
when you're going,
when you're driving through these areas
and you're stopping and you're reading
about the native Americans that were
there and what they were doing and how
many there were,
and then to know that that all that land
was taken and all those,
the civilization was killed and then we
carved in the side of the mountain.
These heads.
It's really,
I mean like dudes,
we couldn't find a single black guy.
I am,
you know,
I am pretty patriotic to the,
to a fault.
So like a naive level,
but seeing that Mount Rushmore of just
felt me too bad.
Look at my phone cover.
I like that patriotic.
It's fucking.
But seeing Mount Rushmore was just
wrong.
And then there's a guy,
there's a native American carving,
carving a crazy horse in the side of the
mountain to counter it inside the
richest
native American tribe in the U.
S work Asino CNL profits pay $1,000,000
a year to every member.
Wow.
How many members says between the mystic
lake and the six casinos,
travel revenues are thought to be nearly
one point 4 billion,
so that would mean that there's at least
a thousand.
There's 460 people in the tribe.
They got about $84,000 a month each
person.
So there's only 460 of them,
one in this particular one right outside
of Minnesota,
but that's,
that's the reparations.
Meanwhile,
the ghosts of their ancestors were in
the woods.
Every time they go outside to take a
leak at night,
I just hear screams and see people with
by them,
but no heads.
It's like it's crazy,
but you know,
it's disproportionate for the people
that lived there for sure.
Has there,
has there been any culture in the world
that didn't go in at some level and wipe
out the other people to take the land?
I don't think so.
I mean it's pretty.
I mean,
yeah,
but yeah.
Yeah,
it's pretty standard.
It's what people do and it's also super
convenient when you don't know what the
fuck they're saying.
You know,
when you pretend that they're not even
one of us there,
this tournament,
gobbly Gook,
we're gonna.
We're gonna fucking kill them.
They're sitting on their house,
made a gold jacket.
Yeah,
it happens everywhere.
It's just,
I think this is the first time,
um,
over the last several hundred years,
especially the last 200 years since
slavery has been abolished,
less than 200 years,
which is crazy,
right?
18,
65.
You think about that.
That's so recent.
Insane.
But these last few hundred years of the
printed word being distributed,
reading,
becoming more and more common,
which is really a very important point.
He had up until the 100 or so years ago,
it was not that common to be able to
read,
you know,
in a lot of parts of the world.
There's a lot of people that are
illiterate,
so they know information to 100 years
before that.
Super common to be illiterate.
I mean,
remember David used.
I'll always have that in those cowboy
movies.
We used to have to write your,
your mark.
Make your mark on this contract.
Right?
They couldn't write.
Well,
I don't know how to write.
No Sir.
We'll make your mark.
They would make a mark member that
little X.
nobody taught me how to write my name.
So what we have in comparison is now you
have a phone in your pocket and you
could talk to him and he'll answer
questions for you.
I mean,
I was in Seattle this past weekend and I
just pressed the button on my phone and
I said,
Siri,
navigate to the SEATAC airport,
right?
It goes,
here's the directions to the Seatac
airport and just starts going.
It's amazing.
Within seconds,
I know the amount of access to the
information that,
uh,
that you need to sort of form your view
of the world accurately.
It's just so much different now than
it's ever been before.
So now I think we're looking at like
what happened to the native Americans
are looking at what happened to the
slaves are looking what happened?
Like this whole Columbus Day thing.
They're just now starting to decide that
they're not going to call it Columbus
Day anymore.
They're going to call it native American
appreciation day or something like that.
G about time,
but I have to say as an Italian that
grew up in New Jersey,
I hate to see that one go.
First of all,
I don't trust him.
He's he's.
He's not a real Italian.
He's like me.
He doesn't have a vowel.
Is the last name Papa.
Why is it.
How come it's Columbus?
What's with the ass bitch?
Yeah.
You're good point at Brown university.
Columbus Day is now indigenous people's
Day.
It's right after white privileged day.
It's weird.
It's like they have white privileged
day.
When did you see what you're.
Yeah.
Chicago University said,
fuck you.
Fuck you.
Safe spaces.
Trigger trigger warnings.
You little fucking babies.
The ortho world.
Yeah.
Well Great.
They've watched enough youtube videos.
They gathered the information like a
good institute of learning and they go,
oh,
the data's in and you guys are retarded.
Yeah.
You guys are closing down free thought
and discussion in the sense where it's
supposed to foster.
Yeah.
You're.
You're not just stopping racism,
which will be a wonderful thing to do
while you're.
What you're doing is you're controlling
the way people address ideas,
the way they behave and think and you're
creating words that are dangerous,
like,
that were normal,
like words that used to be able to use
with no problems.
Now they're demanding things like,
you know,
don't call someone a spokesman,
call them spokeswomen.
There's no more fresh man as first year
students.
Like there's a whole list of them that,
uh,
I forget what university put it out,
but Dave Rubin put it up the other day,
this law,
some university that made this new list
of all the things that would not be
tolerated anymore.
Uh,
in,
in the nomenclature.
All man's speak.
It's called speak.
Yeah,
they saw it coming.
Mankind.
How come it's okay?
How come?
How come you can't be?
How come a human could be a man or a
woman,
but mankind,
we assumed that means male or it's a
masculine side of what a woman is in
that to mankind.
Woolman special kind of man.
Good point.
It's like,
man,
that makes babies.
It's like it is a man that human part of
these creatures that came out of
Tanzania.
Why are we so Goddamn fucking sensitive
and I wonder if I would think that way
if I was a woman,
maybe I'm fucking tired of being a
freshman,
not a man piece of shit.
I'm a girl who's a first year student.
You can't face fucking freshman year.
He and Sally.
Oh my freshmen.
You don't look like a man.
Stupid Bitch
living with all women happens.
I'm sorry.
Living with all women as we do a.
You get an idea around the house of like
what's what's truly like something that
they would carry as an offense and wes
are.
You also get a sense of how they feed
off each other and convince each other
what they're saying.
Makes Sense.
That's a part of the problem,
right?
Yeah.
I agree.
Nail Polish to be mandatory and the next
thing you know,
they're fucking passing laws.
Whether you get.
This is Clinton broad and office would
fucking wacky medication she's on.
Who knows if she's even seeing straight
bro.
Dude will work out perfect because the
vps at.
Dude,
here's a perfect example of people
writing for a,
like a lot of different people write for
publications,
huff post,
he,
they band to have daymond David Seaman,
our board,
David Seaman.
They banned two of his articles and
suspended as account.
Why?
Because he wrote articles questioning
Hillary Clinton's health,
which is also.
That's true.
Yup.
Which is also the same reason what Dr
drew show got canceled.
That's what they say because Dr Drew,
he was questioning Hillary Clinton's
health.
Now what I've heard about Dr drew from
actual doctors in regards to what he
said,
I'd like they didn't agree with some of
the things you said.
One of the things that he said about
armor,
thyroid,
armour thyroid hasn't been prescribed.
I haven't heard about it being
prescribed since 19 seventies.
I'm on armour thyroid and I've been on
armour thyroid for about 10 years.
He's out of his fucking mind that it is
for hypothyroidism.
I have something called Hashimoto's.
It's a,
it's a,
um,
a thyroid disease.
No,
it's not.
It sounds like it's a thyroid disease
that is an autoimmune disease that's
hereditary.
My mom has it.
My sister has it.
And I have it too,
and it just,
uh,
your thyroid doesn't work so well and
for me it manifested itself in like
headaches.
I was taking this thing called synthroid
and it didn't work as good.
It worked okay.
It was definitely better than nothing.
But then when I got on this armor,
thyroid armour thyroid is thyroid
medication that has been made from pigs
glands and uh,
it's very bio similar or are a bio
identical to your actual hormone.
So it's very clean and easy.
My body has zero problems with it.
Like it really is a phase of.
Yeah.
So I've been on this for 10 years and my
doctor is one of the best hormone
doctors in all of the country.
Yeah,
you should meet my wife.
He said he'll just shoot her,
say we can't fix this one,
but I mean,
my point is this guy's a state of the
art doctor and he.
And also I've told people about it that
had a problem with synthroid and they
got on it and then thanked me so much
because the armour thyroid works so much
better for them.
So I didn't know why Dr Drew said that
because you said that Hillary Clinton
had a thyroid problem,
but he thought it was weird.
They were prescribing armour thyroid.
It's very common.
There's a reason why they still make it
and it and he should know more than
anyone being a fucking doctor.
Is he a real diaper or not bioidentical,
whereas you have one person is allergic
to peanuts.
Another person can't be around cats.
You know?
One person responds very well to certain
medication.
Other people like Jamie,
Jamie can eat pot and nothing happens to
them so we're fucking Weirdo.
But the point being,
if I ate with Jamie eight,
I'd be curled up in the fetal position.
Call and girls I dated in high school
go.
I'm sorry.
I don't know what the folks that spend
so long,
but I'm still feel bad.
You know what I mean?
We're all very different.
So you think he doesn't say,
well hold on,
let me keep going.
I'm sorry.
But my point is people that I know that
her doctor said that what he did was
essentially malpractice.
You're not supposed to do that.
You're not supposed to diagnose someone
without any personal understanding of
their case.
You haven't talked to them,
you haven't studied their their blood
work.
You're not privy to their insight
information about their health,
how they feel.
You're taking this guess based on what's
been what's been released and on top of
that you're doing it kind of to get
publicity and attention,
you know?
Yeah.
I mean that's essentially what you're
doing.
If he did it in a respectful way where
he was speculating where he said,
well,
I don't know about the specifics of this
is how I would handle it.
Me being a doctor,
I would say.
I don't know about the specific
specifics of Hillary Clinton's case,
but I do know here's what can be
problematic about brain injuries similar
to the one that she apparently suffered
right here.
Could hear.
It could be some issues and this is what
some people experience from brain
issues.
Like if you say something like the
information that is a doctor talking
about a nonspecific,
you're not talking about a specific
person.
You're talking about like safe.
Tom.
Papa breaks his leg and Dr drew reads
about a Tom Papa was riding a motorcycle
in Africa.
I broke his leg.
Well,
here's what happens when your leg breaks
and when people break their legs,
your body has to heal it and here's some
of the complications that come along
with that.
Now,
if he did that,
that would be a doctor on television
informing us about some real issues.
Maybe he thought as a voter and as an
American,
as someone who's genuinely concerned,
knowing what he does know,
maybe he felt like he had to speak out
about the dangers of someone who's had a
traumatic brain injury.
Having a position like being the
president and what could be a problem,
and then he looked at her medication
list and he disagreed with it.
Doctors will disagree with.
I've talked to some doctors will say
like we were talking about the bulging
disc issue.
I talked to one doctor wanted me to get
an operation.
Are you going to have to get that cut
out?
It's not going to get any better,
and he's convinced clearly he was wrong
because it got better,
but he really.
He didn't know shit about Regena King.
He had never heard of it.
He didn't want.
He's like,
well,
I wouldn't put any my eggs in that
basket.
I mean,
it's just a no,
there's no research and there's a reason
why it hasn't been approved yet by the
FDA.
No,
no,
no.
There isn't.
You fucking done.
And it works.
People are wrong all the time.
All the time.
So according to my friend who's a doctor
who he said,
you're never supposed to do that.
And then what he did by diagnosing her
publicly like that,
you just don't do.
So.
If that's true,
then they're probably justified in
taking these canning and.
Right.
Yeah.
So then would you say that that kind of
eliminates the idea that it's a
conspiracy?
Like when
I'd say he's lucky he's alive because
she just kills bitches.
That's what I hear.
Hillary's is out there,
whack it fools.
I mean if you pay attention to the same
websites that tell you about chem trails
and the flat earth,
which are the ones that are truth,
hashtag truth,
they'll tell you she's whacked like 100
people.
Wow.
She's,
she's like,
she's like Seagal,
like a lighter Seagal.
Do not know this.
Do you not know about this for real?
I really don't.
Oh,
okay.
There is at least 48 or 49 people that
have had dealings with the Clintons
who've been mysteriously murdered,
including the guy who released all those
emails about the DNC favoring hillary
over.
He released him to wikileaks,
favoring hillary over Bernie.
Remember that?
Yeah.
Well,
that guy got shot at 4:00 in the morning
in front of his house,
in the back.
Murdered when?
Somebody recently.
Yeah,
like really recently,
and he's one of several people who had
been murdered that had ties to the
Clintons Clinton body count or left wing
conspiracy three with ties to the DNC
mysteriously die.
Yeah.
Yeah,
dude,
this is.
This is not die all the time.
They do die all the time.
And here's the thing.
You're not saying that she killed him
either,
but here's what you do need to know.
This is like,
this is what's really important to
consider.
You're talking about when you're talking
about someone like the Clintons,
especially if you talk about for a
second,
you've confused the shit out of me.
If you're talking about just keeps
clicking on links.
Start doing that.
What's going on over here?
What about our click this when when
you're talking about someone like the
Clintons who run the Clinton Foundation,
not I don't know if you've paid
attention to the Clinton Foundation,
but I have been slowly but surely going
down a rabbit hole with the Clinton
Foundation over the last couple of
months and it is crazy what they got
away with.
It's crazy and there's some pretty
direct evidence.
There's some people that were involved
and they donated to the Clinton
Foundation and they got arms deals.
Now whether or not they got arms deals
because they donated or whether they did
that as a thank you for the arms deal
that they would have had anyway.
Who the fuck knows?
But that's just one aspect of what's
problematic about this.
Now I'm no expert and I don't know what
the fuck I'm talking about.
Let me,
let me just state that for a fact,
but what I've been reading about,
what people find problematic about the,
the about of profit that's been made off
of this and the amount of influence that
is being sold with this and that.
How many of these people that they're
involved with these dealings are
donating to their foundation and then in
return they're getting these deals past
and like is shady as fuck.
Okay,
and the people that you're dealing with,
in some instances you're talking about
weapons.
Talking about arms dealers,
you're talking about countries that kill
people,
countries with poor civil rights records
like Saudi Arabia.
You're talking about decisions that you
make you fucking know for sure people
are going to die.
Right?
And we know that about her.
That's just what looked at video of her
laughing about the death of Omar Kadafi
received that.
Yeah.
I interviewed just like we came,
we saw he died.
Like
the fact that the bar for being a
president is so low that you could have
a video like that out there and it
doesn't freak people the fuck out
everybody back off.
And then on top of that,
with all the evidence of all this weird
shit that it's probably just standard
operational procedure.
So here's my point,
you're involved with this,
this interconnected web of death of
killers,
of war,
of tough questions that demand tufts
solutions,
and then you're involved with all these
people that are used to killing people
right now.
If something like this dnc leak comes
out and it's possible that this could
bring down a ship and this ship is huge
and there's thousands of people involved
in this ship and you might be one of
those people involved in this ship.
Remember,
like I didn't think I know how to take
care of this.
And you step in and,
and someone dies and everybody else
shuts the fuck up.
And everybody panics and nobody gets
caught.
And there's no ties to hillary because
Hillary didn't ask for it to be done.
But it's a part of a fucking giant
machine.
Right?
So it might not even be that she's out
there doing it,
but it might be the fact that
her influence political power.
You're talking about,
you're talking about the presidency of
the United States of America,
you talking about a gigantic amount of
the world that that controls and she's
in there,
right?
Hasn't every president,
most likely hasn't.
Every leader of whatever.
Sure.
That's it's the job.
It's a job.
That's the thing that I keep.
What's us?
What are you showing us?
This is one of the three guys that
they're talking about that just recently
died.
Okay.
Former president of the United Nations
General Assembly,
John Ash mysteriously passed away on
June 22nd,
a few days before he was scheduled to
begin pretrial meetings involving shady
financial dealings regarding a former
Clinton crony.
Local police officer said he died from
dropping a barbell on his throat while
working out,
but the UN oddly first claim he died of
a heart attack.
The 61 year old was supposed to testify
against Chinese real estate developer.
Oh God.
He's dead as fuck.
Nick lap saying who was implicated in
the China Gate scandal for funneling
money to the DNC for Bill Clinton
through Arkansas restaurant owner
trolley try.
Ash was arrested last year for allegedly
taking over $3,000,000 in bribes from
the Chinese businessmen,
including over a half a million from
nick see in exchange for building United
Nations Conference Center in Macau.
There's a lot in there,
and he was arrested.
He was arrested for taking 3 million
bucks in bribes and then he was going to
testify he was going to spill the beans
and they killed him like a fucking like
a movie.
What's that source?
Website websites.
Townhall.com.
What's townhall.com?
While the information I'm sure is not
made up,
we should just go just google his death
and find out Clinton body count or left
wing conspiracy three with ties.
That's just one article in one website
to the of these people dying is
undeniable.
They've definitely died whether or not
they were murdered or whether it's on
some crazy coincidence that all of these
people were about to testify or had
secret information or leaked information
to wikileaks and then were murdered.
Right.
Fuck it,
man.
And there was a woman too.
What did,
what did she,
some woman involved in DNC was also
murdered recently.
The staffer who dropped off the lawsuit,
I believe is who it was.
They're like filed the lawsuit in August
or maybe in July.
He was dead in August.
He was found dead in his bathroom step.
What lawsuit against?
For the DNC?
For Bernie Sanders or something like
that.
I believe so.
He was killed too,
along with the kid who released the
documents.
It was.
He probably did it.
They don't know if he for sure did it,
but an analyst that had access to that
information,
I believe it was him and he was
murdered.
Look,
they're killing people.
Everyone's killing people,
right?
I mean not are.
You can't.
Are we on?
Well,
the selten,
no,
just occasionally to make dirty Mus.
Think about what people do for just a
small amount of money,
right?
The horrible things people do to other
people for small amounts of money.
When you get up to that level of
billions of government size money,
come on,
right?
You see all the accusations against a
poot and over the weekend I was like,
those people are dying.
Porter,
just yesterday,
yesterday,
a guy got shot in the head.
Guy was critical of Putin.
Suicide.
Yeah.
Definitely.
Suicided himself.
What the fuck,
man?
It's scary up there.
It's really scary up.
You see that video of that.
A guy took a surveillance camera at this
millionaire who's having some or
billionaire.
I guess it's happened.
Some big dispute with his girlfriend.
He broke up with her and so she led.
She beat him up.
She wants money and he has surveillance
video of her lying on the bed.
Punching herself in the face.
No,
I tweeted it today.
You did a wonderful,
wonderful listen folks.
It's not an us or them thing.
We have to stop this.
There's a thing that women do whenever a
woman is involved in any sort of a
domestic violence,
abuse,
rape type situation,
there's a thing that women automatically
do where they think that that woman is
not guilty and that woman has been
abused and that women is definitely not
lying and most of the time you're right,
but there are a lot of fucking liars out
there and some of them have penises and
some of them have vaginas and that this
is something as human beings,
we have to stop being on these fucking
gender based teams.
Yeah,
it's stupid because there are nutty
pitches out there and some of them are
men and some of them are women and this
woman is just sitting there as a video
of her hitting her side in the face,
hitting herself in the face,
screaming and yelling and wailing
herself in the face.
Look at her.
She's fucking bananas,
man.
Oh my God.
So she gives herself marks all over her
face and then she calls the cops and
she's having a temper tantrum and
storming around and she doesn't realize
that she's being filmed.
It's crazy.
But meanwhile,
I don't even know how much of this is
admissible because she's fucking hitting
herself in the face so hard.
I don't know how much of this is an
admissible in court in divorce court?
I don't know.
Or in.
Well,
well not even divorced court,
but if he's being prosecuted for it.
Yeah,
it was his fiance.
But you know,
this is what everybody said.
I mean this has been a lot of these
cases and this is the what Johnny Depp
is claiming happened where his ex
girlfriend was saying that he beat her
up and he said I.
He didn't do it and she just did it to
herself or faked it or something like
that.
End Up.
Who knows?
There's still disputing it.
She's suing Doug.
Stan hope she it.
Doug's Dan,
because he was defended them.
She's Doug Stanhope wrote an article
saying that he knows that she's a liar
and that she was blackmailing him and
that Johnny Depp.
It told him about it before any of this
came out,
that she had some demands.
I don't know who's telling the truth.
I don't know if Doug really knows.
I don't know who the fuck knows I wasn't
there,
but here's the thing,
man,
there are people like that nutty bitch
that you just saw in that video hitting
herself in the face.
There's people like that.
They're real people.
It's crazy.
They have vaginas and some of them have
penises.
They're not be men or women.
No one's infallible.
We got to get off these teams is because
this is a real problem.
This is very divisive.
It really separates people.
Is this idea that anytime a woman
accuses a man of something,
it must be true.
It's not true.
That's not right.
Like we have to be sure we have to and I
don't know how to do that,
but I don't think the way to do that is
to automatically assume that even like
shady pitches are all telling the truth
always,
and then every woman who's accusing
amount of something without a doubt
can't be lying.
That's crazy.
It's case by case by case.
Lately different,
and again,
you don't want to.
You don't want to blame the victim.
If someone is a victim and you go around
and you know you,
you say,
I don't believe a fucking word you're
saying,
and meanwhile that actually did happen
to them.
It's horrible,
brutal,
but we have to be able to figure out
what is what.
Yeah,
it's hard to cut to not come up with a
general generalization because those
cases,
that's the.
That's if there's some way that you can
get the people that are dealing with
these situations to break through that
barrier and look at everything as a case
by case basis.
I don't know how you do it.
We don't have enough knowledge of
whether or not a person who's being
truthful and then there's also an issue
where people in their own minds changed
reality.
Like you could have an argument with
someone and they can decide in their own
mind over the course of whatever weeks
have passed that that argument was a
completely different beast than what was
happening while I was going down.
Your ego lies to you start telling the
story to other people with distortions.
Those distortions become a part of the
reality.
It becomes the narrative you get,
it gets more and more exaggerated.
Every time you talk about it becomes
real.
It becomes real.
Yeah.
Most people,
it's really hard for them to accurately
and objectively
talk about like a very traumatic
situation.
Like if you did get in a fight with a
guy and you're a woman and you're
engaged this guy and he really did beat
you up.
Like,
fuck.
Yeah,
like just trying to relay that
accurately.
It's got to be terrifying and bizarre.
And fleetingly.
Yeah.
Out of your mind.
And then you've got to parse these tiny
little details about it.
How much is this dude laughing?
The studio has this video right now
though.
Like when he saw,
when he knew he had his like,
oh fuck yeah,
and that's the thing.
She'll come,
she'll realize that.
Oh No,
about that show.
Rationalize it.
She'll be like,
yeah,
well,
you know,
I just never caught him in the act.
Who knows what she'll do,
but she's crazy enough where she will
have a working system in her head of why
that's okay.
Well,
this is also what you get when women
fuck us for their money.
You get people who are mad,
like if you want to fucking a guy for
his money,
say if you're an attractive woman like
this girl is and the guys,
but she could probably do better.
She's beautiful that you get mad at
that,
right?
Powerless.
Never fuck over your head,
right?
Just stay within your means.
Yeah,
no,
I know what you're dealing with.
People are not really attracted to you,
man.
It gets.
It gets ugly.
It's ugly.
It's true.
It's not good.
You know,
everybody has this idea that got to get
a supermodel.
That's the dumbest move to it.
Oh,
you not do it.
Don't do it.
Don't fuck over your head because you'll
have to pay.
There's a deficit.
It's like buying a corvette when you're
still in college,
but you got the student loan or I'm
going to spend it on the car.
I'm crazy.
Bob bought a corvette.
Get the fuck out of here and you go
outside.
This fucking guy's like jump.
Start delivering it dominoes and I'm
going to pay this car off.
Brawler drove in a car.
It's,
well,
that's what the guys dealing with.
It takes a super hot wife if he's a
fucking fat,
ugly,
Rich Guy.
Crazy.
You have to know if that's what you're
getting.
Now you're competing with everyone who
wants to sleep with that and that is a
supermodel.
Just genetically,
you've now increased the number of other
Alpha males coming for this person.
Plus,
I think a good move is to always go
foreign.
It's like that's how I feel about sports
cars.
That's how I feel about trophy bribed
you.
If you're gonna,
get a trophy bride.
Get one from some war torn regions of
the world.
She don't know no better.
Happy.
She's got food.
She genuinely loves you for taking care
of her.
She's so psyched and if you move her
family out of the ramshackle village,
the ramp that the Jews are about to plow
down,
you can move her whole family are your
family.
You guys will have a wonderful
relationship based on actual
appreciation,
but just like running water,
but if you date some blonde and Florida
with big tits and she does coke,
who's come up through the minors,
she know she doesn't want to fuck you,
you and your mediocre Dick.
She doesn't do it.
She's with studying and how to get this
done her whole life.
She's trying to think of how the fuck
she can close this deal and make the big
money and right when she was at the
finish line,
you cut it off.
That's what happened.
He broke up with the fiance and she's a.
she's like,
there's got be a
way to make money out of this deal.
Bang,
Bang.
She's just.
She's just going.
She's fucking throwing a hail Mary.
Will they have whole clinics like that
for,
for young athletes,
right?
Of that there's.
It's a business for do they,
but yeah.
It's a business for women to come after
these young,
get pregnant and get pregnant and all
these things.
They literally are counseled.
Then this is one of the threats to your
life.
Yeah.
We'll definitely to your livelihood.
Yeah,
yeah.
Well it's real and look,
it's also,
it makes sense because it's.
There's an imbalance,
right?
If you're.
Yeah,
if you're like some baller,
rich dude who's worth billions of
dollars,
you got private jets,
you're pulling up everywhere in the
Rolls Royce of people open the door for
you and you walk out with your
sunglasses.
Walk Straight to your private jet.
Oh my God,
this is me this week.
Yeah,
he's so unattainable and the resources
are so ridiculous that people are in
some way,
some strange way attracted to them.
Right?
Everyone around him like Mr Papas
coming,
Mr Bob was coming to see ms dot brava.
Don't make eye contact with Mr Papa.
Uh,
if he talks to you and be polite and be
egregious,
but whatever you do,
don't ask Mr Popper for money and just
pop up right there just above us here,
Mr. Hi everybody.
How are you?
And you just get the best of the best
out of these people and they think of
you as like,
wow,
if I could just get closer to Mr Pompa,
my whole world would change and it makes
sense because everybody's trying to be
nice to you.
Which is like weird.
Totally weird.
If you're some super billionaire Richard
Branson type character,
everywhere you go,
everybody's kissing your ass and trying
to be nice to you.
You get this really distorted version of
humans and women are attracted you.
That shouldn't be attracted to you.
That's right.
It's natural,
but you think they should be.
You should think they should and they
get to fuck you.
And they get to smell you and realize
how what you,
what you really are and who you really
are like you need to get this guy to
fucking pain is terrible,
man.
Where's my Ferrari?
Stupid.
You know how come on,
I'm a villa.
And then next thing you know you get
this guy buying you shit.
And other women are coming after him.
So he's probably mad men like that.
Donald Sterling girl,
the girl who required down sterling St,
all that racist shit.
He bought her a Bentley or a Ferrari,
a fat condo.
He bought her a gang of shit and she was
like,
it wasn't enough enough.
You fucking disgusting bag of meat.
A whole leather saddle bag filled with
rotten hamburger.
Fuck you.
I can't believe I sucked your Dick.
Hey me.
Motherfucker pay me.
What do you think,
honey?
What do you think of?
Black people don't like it when they
fuck you.
Wait,
wait,
hold on,
let me.
I didn't press record.
What do you think of?
What's record?
What are you doing over there?
And that person bought?
Yeah.
Awful.
Could you imagine when you hear stories
like that and aren't you just happy that
it's not you?
Yeah,
but you just have like got married,
have some kids.
You're just like,
there's a lot of things that aren't sexy
about,
you know,
all of that stuff.
Just being simple and just breaking it
down to just like I go to my kid's
school and I do my stuff.
Like having a smaller world is a relief.
It definitely is.
There's a certain level that you can get
too big and then things become like a
giant,
big,
fat,
crazy problem to complex.
Yeah.
Well,
if you're at that level,
if you're at like a Richard Branson
level.
Yeah.
It's kind of a john or Johnny Depp level
even.
Yeah.
It's got to be God damn problem Heti oh
yeah.
Heady.
Lots of heady.
Yeah.
You've got to be real disciplined person
and like come up with a structure for
yourself of working and taking care of
your life without spinning out of
control.
So I love of people lose it.
Yeah.
I was talking to this dude in Seattle
this past weekend.
Who knew this guy who sued Paul Allen?
The Microsoft Guy?
Yeah.
And one.
And now scared to be in Seattle.
No,
he never goes to Seattle anymore.
Yeah.
Oh my God.
Super Paranoid after he won.
Yeah.
So that's what I'm talking about.
You got for what you wish for.
To too high a level of the game,
son.
I want to unwind.
I don't want to look into it.
God that are worth $100.
Million Dollars.
Well,
we were owns islands.
Yeah,
they have stupid money.
We were at the um,
there's an area called the locks where
the salmon swim through these ladders.
It's really dope because you actually go
underground and there's a wall glass
wall and you can watch the fish swim.
Literally the wild fish swim up these
locks.
It's super fucking cool.
It makes you want to go fishing right
near Seattle.
Yeah.
It's Ballard.
The ballard locks.
Cool.
Ballard is like a small area.
Seattle,
which is a really,
really fucking cool area with a lot of
great little restaurants and bars and
great community.
And a friend of mine lives there and him
and his family took us to this place and
so we went to this ballard locks thing
and we were checking around and we're
looking at it and one of the guys that
was there,
there,
that's it right there.
So you get to look at it through this
wall and those salmon are all swimming,
um,
up up this little ladder going home,
they're going to die.
That's where they were in Morton,
right?
Yep.
The Women Salmon,
the female salmon,
they pump out the eggs.
And the dude's just stand over him and
whack off.
They just on the eggs and then they die.
That's how they,
they don't even get to fuck right.
Have you ever caught a fish that's,
that has come in it?
No.
When I was a kid I used to do a trick
question when I was a kid.
I used to go fishing all the time.
It was big into fishing and I would do a
lot of rainbow trout fishing and when it
was really great fun to catch them is
when they were responding and you would
throw out your lure and they would just
attack anything.
They were super aggressive.
But then when you would pick them up,
they would be jizzing like you had
pulled them out of the water and they
took a chance.
Maybe there's x near me because they
know it's over arches.
I don't taste it.
Tasted arches either.
Trick question.
You almost got me.
You motherfucker.
But um,
they would,
you pick them up and they literally
would be orgasming as you're pulling
them out of the water.
There's just been all over the place.
Yeah,
it's apparent.
Was pretty common,
but I remember a lot from when I was a
kid.
I haven't had it happen in any sense,
but I do remember it a lot when I was a
kid,
but I don't do nearly as much fishing.
So wait.
So Paul Allen,
this guy suits and has um,
this guy at the locks.
This is a circular sort of a thing.
The guy at the locks who I was talking
to it as asking them some questions
about some of the fish he was pointing
out the bays and how they change this
lake because there was a lake,
there's a lake there and they didn't
realize that when they cut this channel
that it lowered the level of the lake
and then that made it so the fish
couldn't get back to the lake.
And it was a real issue.
They had said they were stacks of dead
Salmon,
the like 20,
30 feet high.
She's crazy that they would just go to
the area where they had always gone,
but now the river didn't go all the way
to the end where the lake was and they
would just wind up dying.
She's but he was saying that Paul Allen
and Bill Gates both have these insane
$150,000,000 houses on this leg.
Wow.
Imagine them what a hundred and
$50,000,000 house looks like.
I know.
What the fuck are we even talking about
it and it's great Wifi.
I bet the Wifi is dog shit.
I better get viruses every time.
A lot of malware and every time he opens
up a room,
a new virus,
because everything's on computers.
You wear a tie clip at least this is the
way it used to work.
You would wear a pin and you put that
pin on the pin and this is like many,
many years ago,
so I'm sure the technology is far more
advanced now,
but the way Bill Gates had it set up,
every time you'd walk into a room,
the pin would recognize the user,
set the temperature to your preferences
and play the kind of music that you like
and put certain type of lighting on.
Oh my God.
It's got to be amazing.
Yeah,
but it's probably all outdated,
which is kind of funny.
Unless he's updated it constantly.
Dates,
it gets a new lighting system.
Bill Gates,
did they ever do a tour of Bill Gates
House?
I heard that the.
That it was mostly because of the
technology that it's not that massive.
Oh really?
That's what I heard.
Well,
that probably be a smart move.
It's not stand out too much.
I already asked like a summary that he
could escape in.
We'd drop it a pod and dropped below.
Look in the basement because in case
somebody breaks into the house,
you just shoot out out of a tube and a
submarine.
Six thousand square feet,
and that's kind of big.
Sixty six.
That's a little bigger than normal.
Sixty $3 million to build Jesus Christ.
It's worth at least 100.
Twenty 3 million.
According to the King County public
assessors office,
the property is worth 123 point five,
4 million.
As of this year,
Gates purchased the lot for 2 million
bucks in 1988 before windows 95
reportedly pays around a million dollars
in property taxes each year.
Oh my God.
Half a million board feet of lumber was
needed to complete the project.
Wow,
the house is built with.
Scroll down a little.
The house is built with 500 year old
Douglas Fir trees.
300 construction workers labored on the
home,
100 of whom were electricians.
50 died mysteriously.
That part,
that part.
What does it look like?
The House has uses natural surroundings
to reduce heat loss.
What's it looks like?
It's covered in woods stage,
like the side of the thing and there's
trees.
Dad added all around.
What's above it?
What are those?
That wall above it.
Is that a wall of China?
It looks like an apartment building.
Probably other houses.
The house can't be that close.
Bill Gates lives that close to his
fucking neighbors on the lake.
Maybe.
Come on.
It's weird.
That's a house right above him.
He probably owns it to.
I would bet.
I would bet he would own everything.
Anyone fill it up with mercenaries?
He's worth too much money.
Yeah.
Well it keeps the music system.
He did.
He did give a lot of money away.
There's a trampoline room with 20 foot
ceilings,
24 bathrooms.
He has a reception hall that can
accommodate 200 guests,
kitchen,
Jesus Christ,
enormous library.
How's the manuscripts?
Gates paid more than $30,000,000 for.
What is the manuscript?
Great Gatsby.
Wow.
Well,
I don't know if that's it.
And so you'll find a quote from.
I'm sorry.
Yeah.
What is the manuscript Codex license?
What is that?
Yeah,
what is that?
The 16th century?
It's a Davinci.
Oh man,
you paid $30.
Million Bucks for a leaner Davinci
sketch.
Let's go get that.
Let's go find it.
Well,
apparently that is,
that was talking to this real estate
agent who told me that that is a big
issue with houses that are,
um,
that are listed,
that are expensive houses and they are
framed up meaning,
you know,
like inside you go in there,
everything's already like there's really
nice sheets and artwork on the walls and
staged is the right word.
Uh,
so they,
they have this artwork.
There's a lot of these houses,
like if it's expensive house,
they have expensive artwork and so
people break into these houses while
they know that they're selling the house
and no one's living in it.
And take the stuff,
take the artwork.
Let's do it,
dude.
Dude,
artwork is where a lot of money part of
it.
Our official stream is stocked with
fish.
Wonder if he gets in there and fuck
those fish.
He has a favorite tree that's monitored
electronically 24 hours a day.
He reportedly became fond of 40 year old
maple tree.
That glue grew close to the homes
driveway.
It's monitored by computer.
If at any point it becomes too dry,
water is automatically pumped into it.
Whoa.
He's in love with the tree.
He loves trees.
Tesla was in love with a pigeon.
It's not that weird.
Yeah.
Nikola Tesla fell in love with a pigeon.
Oh,
sand on gates is beach is imported from
the Caribbean.
Want to continue?
Ooh.
Thirty five grand at tour it.
Wow.
Microsoft holds an auction each year.
Employees donate products and services
to bid on proceeds.
Go to the company's charitable fund.
Gates is private tours of Zana.
Dude.
That's what he calls it.
Zana do two point.
Oh,
you have to wear leg warmers when you go
in and fuzzy slippers.
According to the puget sound business
journal,
a Microsoft employee once one tour on a
bid,
$30,000.
He's an employee.
How about you give your fucking employee
a break?
You twat
he wants to give.
Well,
it actually goes to the charity.
That's nice.
He also has a 228 Acre ranch complete
with a horse racing track.
He's got a lot of cash.
When you read stuff like that,
as you go,
man,
I got to become more of a baller,
like everything's free now.
Him and his wife say,
we're going to try and size down.
We're going to try and solve the world
hunger.
That's not gonna work,
but we're going to applaud their
efforts.
Fixed malaria.
Oh,
well.
With the genetically modified
mosquitoes,
yes.
That might be possible.
Or 28 days later zombies.
They might happen to.
Could be.
He had another.
The mosquitoes become even fiercer and
just come and kill us all.
Where mercy came from.
Who Murcia Mrs. Say
Medical Medication resistant.
Staph,
old cockup office.
It's essentially medication resistant,
staph infections that are ruthless that
tear through people and kill a ton of
people.
That's the campaign I was going to bring
this up when you're talking about the
mosquitoes earlier in China and like the
19 fifties,
they were having problems with a couple
of different paths,
mostly sparrows that said in this case
there were hundreds of millions of
sparrows,
so there's a government mandate to try
to get rid of them.
So people were literally going outside
and banging on pans for hours at a time
so that they couldn't land and they
would die from exhaustion,
exhaustion a 10 years later.
So there was a giant famine because
these,
all the pes were stopping eating.
Uh,
all the bugs,
the bugs start eating all their bamboo
and rice and $30,
million people died in China from 19
six.
And I'm like,
God will not.
They did
have a butterfly.
Can become the beginning of
really what it is.
Yeah,
you can't mess with nature.
But,
uh,
on this mosquito thing that this
emergency they're doing in Florida,
they want to,
the officials are asking to skip a field
trial and they want to just go right
into it and not not test these
mosquitoes,
but whatsoever besides like that could
be a bigger problem where if Congress
had funded,
had funded this a year ago,
they would have
all those tests.
Well there's a lot of fucking people
getting the Zika virus and on top of
that,
the latest thing is that now they find
out that men who don't show any symptoms
can dismiss.
They can transmit the Zika virus
sexually,
right?
So you could have no symptoms and you
just drop a load on walls in some
portraits.
A trial who we found no people.
The people I'm with a girl not yet
affect girls and Florida.
And apparently was another thing that
was an unlikely ally.
I was reading this.
An unlikely ally of the Zika virus is
high rise luxury condominiums.
For some reason,
high rise luxury condominiums make
excellent grounds for Zika viruses to
start breeding live in the vents.
I don't know.
I don't understand why,
but they,
there's areas where the CDC is thinking
about roping them off and going,
okay,
we got to fucking property really well
dude.
That the repercussions are the
repercussions.
What's the big ones?
Reproductive for women when they have
kids.
The kids develop this.
A horrible disorder with their heads.
Yeah.
But uh,
what if you could just like get a
balloon there and pull it up place?
Sure.
Zika is accidental ally.
Miami's luxury high rises,
low flying planes,
urban wind tunnels and imprecise
applications raise the risk of
mosquitoes.
Developing Resistance to insects
decides.
Whoa.
Oh,
interests.
So it doesn't kill you.
It just gives your baby's little heads.
Low flying planes.
So that's a wind issue.
Aerial spraying with ultra low volume
can only
come down,
can only be done when there's not much
wind.
So the wind and then the probably the
high rises are in the way and so around
the high rises they can't spray
and they can't get low enough.
Whoo.
You got to get in there with like a,
like a bubbles one.
Wow.
This is scary shit though because this
is just one.
And I'm sure the other thing,
yeah,
that's the thing.
We went to the CDC,
Duncan and I did for this episode of my
Scifi show.
We talked about um,
weaponized diseases and they were pretty
frank about it.
They said,
we are not worried about someone coming
up with a disease.
We're worried about nature,
right?
Like no one has ever been able to
successfully come up with a disease.
And there's all this,
these fears and all these conspiracy
theories,
what you should really be terrified of
is just regular old nature taking a
terrible disease.
And it becomes airborne.
It mutates or changes.
And they do it all the time.
And they had Ebola.
They had all these crazy diseases locked
up in this lab where they had like these
four foot cars and giant glass windows
he looked through and everyone,
they spacesuits on their,
attached over these exhaust vents,
walking around with vacuum tubes hanging
off of him.
It was really creepy.
Oh my God.
Inside anyone.
Yeah,
just one,
one little sample of anything.
And these are hurricane proof buildings.
So the buildings designed because it's
right in Galveston.
It's near the gun.
So these,
these buildings are designed to impact,
get impacted by gigantic,
100 foot waves and shit and survive and
keep all the bacteria and tack.
Why are they saving this stuff where
they want to study it?
They want to trigger,
figure out how to solve it,
what they figure if they keep studying,
it might be able to find different ways
to keep it from killing all of us.
Good.
Tom Papa.
Just take malaria medications.
The dreams are awesome.
No,
no,
no.
So clear.
But it's not just that malaria
medication doesn't work against the
Zika.
They don't have Zika medication.
You Fuck?
Well those people.
Bad Advice.
What about Ebola?
Again?
Malaria medication.
You can dream that you have,
you taken the dreams are so vivid.
You believe you're actually don't have
it.
And then the placebo effect.
When I was,
when I was in the Africa with my,
uh,
you can't say like that when I was in my
privilege.
The Africa,
Africa in Africa.
Like I said,
the malaria medication gives you a
little,
uh,
upset sometimes or you shit yourself.
So when we were stopping through one of
those little towns where I said I was
all paranoid and uh,
I went to go use a restroom.
Was it a hole in the ground now?
Almost a pretty much you kind of like a
Porta potty kind of thing.
But as you go running in this a little
boy,
this little boy,
probably around eight went,
hey look,
white tea man.
That didn't help with my paranoia that
hey,
white tea man should be the cover.
The title of your new special.
Hey,
look white.
They look like that.
It is pretty good.
I like,
that's catching me in a suit.
You would like Colonel Sanders type
Sudhana
white tea man to man.
See,
you can't really offend people by
calling them yet though.
I know why he doesn't bother me at a
cracker that none of that bothers me.
Not at all.
Anything that calls out my whiteness is
like,
Yo,
sorry.
I'm awesome.
Why are you pointing out my advantages?
Why should one older kid said,
look at these motherfuckers.
Whoa.
Yeah.
Yelled that on her way into town.
Winter.
We're in our little open safari via
really.
Was he saying that like in a mad way or
laughing?
Oh,
like a mad way.
Like what?
What do you drive?
What are you looking at?
Oh,
what are you looking at it?
I didn't feel comfortable.
Huh?
Now just keep driving.
Keep driving by people.
Just keep driving through this area
where people go and look at this mother
fucker.
Yeah.
With the name of the resort of the
place.
You're staying on the side.
They know that you know.
You got some money there.
Fencing.
Yeah.
Some money.
People coming from another country.
Fancy man.
Motherfucker.
Woo.
Yeah.
Did you close your kid's ears?
Cover their ears.
I just went up.
That was nice.
Yeah.
That guy.
Like if I went to Tanzania and I would
like to go,
um,
I would want to think about how much
time to spend there.
How much time did you spend there?
Ten days.
That seems like a right number.
It was perfect
because your,
it's,
it's a big,
it's far.
Twenty four hours of travel.
And
what do you,
what do you fly into?
Do you find the Holland or did you go to
Amsterdam?
Dubai is another one.
Went to Amsterdam and I left from New
York
from here it's like a 11 hour flight and
then you switch and then it's another
eight to nine hours to Kilimanjaro.
Then you've got to get a puddle jumper
and get into the Serengeti,
get into grammatically.
So did you,
um,
did you stay in Holland for now?
I just went.
Wow.
I've done trips where you stopped and
like,
well just for a day,
just get it over with,
just go,
just push it and get there.
We did.
I did them this weekend or this weekend
to summer.
Other.
It's the best.
We did Rome first and then we went to
the mafia coast.
Now he did both of those.
I've never been there.
I was in a room.
We were thinking about just staying in
one place,
but we fucking mix it up.
It was the right move was a great.
Great.
Both of them were awesome in different
ways.
Yeah.
Amalfi coast is awesome because you
can't even believe it's real.
So yeah,
so pretty and so nice.
It doesn't even seem real or just and
then Rome is just the artwork and the
Vatican alone is worth the trip.
It's amazing.
What I love about Rome too is that it's
still have a vibrant city.
It's so old and so much change in
history,
but it's a young hip city.
People are working hard and doing stuff
where like you go to Florence and places
like that.
It's like it's beautiful,
but it's kind of like a museum.
Young people aren't going to make it
right there.
Yeah,
they are in room.
Another thing that I felt was crazy was
that the Vatican is its own country with
its own rules.
That's why the pope's all stay there
after they leave because otherwise they
can't.
Like Pope Benedict,
they wanted to try him for crimes
against humanity and he's being shielded
by the Vatican.
This company,
there's countries rather that are
actively trying to extract him like
they're trying with legal action to get
him out of the Vatican.
Try Him.
Because the last pope was a really bad
guy.
I know you know the whole shielding
child molesters.
I went onto rape deaf kids.
He was a big part of all that.
He was one of those cheap,
not just allegedly one of the key guys
when it came to relocating child
molesters where they would.
Yeah.
He was the new kid and a lot of the
people around.
Right?
Yeah.
Is there ever been an organization
that's fucked as many kids as the
Catholic Church didn't?
Wasn't there a party that kind of felt
at the Vatican like this is obscene?
Yes,
yes.
Yeah.
Well,
it's,
it's human.
It's human creativity and human ambition
and human.
This overwhelming desire to create
someone something magnificent.
Some these massive fucking temples,
these enormous cathedrals.
You know,
like St Peter's Basilica,
you wander around,
they like this took how long have years
to make hundreds.
It's amazing.
Amazing.
But it's also that same psychotic
behavior that make someone create
something like that is also responsible
for all these bizarre behavior traits
that suppressive people that are in
those sort of situations.
Press people and what's the difference
between
the people that are creating it and the
people that are paying for it to be
those people that were just went in and
took countries over and slaughtered
people.
It's very similar to what we were
talking about with the native Americans.
It was so weird there time
that no,
that shit's even in the Bible that you
have to have a pope right this day.
I'll make that up.
That's a completely made up thing by
human beings.
That's the hardest part.
When you go to Rome and you start trade,
there was a place is great.
I forget the name of it,
but it has a church and active church
and then you can site so you can go
below.
That is a really old church that you
know,
just things you know in Rome,
things just set on.
They just build on top,
so it's this active church than
underneath a really old church and below
that way in the way underground is this
Pagan Temple and they weren't worshiping
Jesus.
They were worshiping these strange pagan
gods and you just see this was just man
interpreting this feeling and using it
for their advantage,
whatever at a pagan level to this level
to today it's the same.
And the thing about Rome is like if you
go in there wanting to hold onto your
Christian beliefs or any of that stuff
and you look at the history like
literally right there in the landscape
that this has just come from us trying
to figure stuff out as there's no one
truth.
Yeah.
It breaks all that down.
I don't know how you can withstand it
without just pure faith.
They just put blinders on.
Yeah.
That mean it's the enemy that faith is
without a doubt the enemy of objective
thinking.
It really have to have faith in order to
buy into a lot of these stories and once
you have faith,
you just like,
I'm on the team no matter what.
No matter what Hillary did,
I am on the team.
It's the same thing.
You being a loyal Democrat,
being a loyal Republican,
being a fucking loyal Mac user,
being a religious nut,
it's a lot of it is the same thing.
It's like this desire to just settled on
this.
I identify with this.
I'm locked in.
It's comforting.
You feel like you belong.
If this is a right way,
I don't have to think about this stuff.
They're going to do that part of the
thinking.
That's why that pussy,
the football player should have just
stood up.
Put your hand over your heart,
Pussy.
I don't want to hear all this black
lives matter bullshit about equality and
put your hand over your hair,
your heart,
whatever it is.
Your heart.
You're going to be a quarterback.
You act like quarterback.
Listen to this American.
You want to.
You want to play soccer?
We won't.
Do you want to play cricket?
Like how about you go play cricket.
You get yourself some freedom,
fries and shit,
Bro.
I gotta get in this fucking thing.
I gotta to get out of here.
Tom,
Papa.
I always enjoy talking with you,
my friend.
I love coming by man.
I have to say when I was out there on
Safari,
you know,
cruising around for all this time,
I thought about you often.
I was like,
he would love to see.
I mean just animals,
eating animals anytime.
Something like extreme it was like.
And it's controlled and your family
would be safe.
I can't recommend enough.
They're too young right now,
but a couple of taking medication,
but I think the older I think I'm going
to definitely do it.
It seems like it seems like something
that should be done,
like I said,
of the Vatican was something that after
I did it,
it took a long time to get there and all
that jazz,
but I was like,
I'm so glad I did it.
I needed to see that.
When you get home,
did you bring your family?
When you get home?
Don't you feel like,
yeah,
I did that.
I got those kids there.
That was the same thing with Africa.
It was one of those felt like for them,
they had a lot of questions too,
so it was really cool.
Like looking at all this art and means
you're going one insane room filled with
sculptures to another insane room filled
with other things and still the hallway.
It's filled with incredible ancient
maps.
There's so much going on.
Amazing.
It's really amazing.
Then you get home.
You light a big fat cigar here.
That's right.
I did that a pretend a month car vishing
pose.
So then when I am one day I'll get it
right.
I'd be like,
goodnight everybody.
See Tomorrow,
Donald Cowboy cerrone will be here
tomorrow.
Tom Papa on twitter.
Go watch him.
He's fucking hilarious.
He assumed.