Boom.
Hello Ben.
Hey there.
Good to see you,
man.
Yeah,
it's a pleasure to be here.
Thanks for doing this.
Yeah,
yeah.
Thanks.
Thanks for having me.
I've been.
I've been looking at some of your shows
in the last few last few days just to
get a sense of how you're thinking about
ai and crypto and the various other
things.
I'm involved in this.
It's been interesting.
Well,
I've been following you as well.
I've been paying attention to a lot of
your lectures and talks and different
things you've done over the last couple
days as well.
Getting ready for this.
It's a Ai is a.
either people are really excited about
it or they're really terrified of it.
Those are the sort of.
It seems to be the two responses.
Either people have this dismal view of
these robots taking over the world or
they think it's going to be some amazing
sort of symbiotic relationship with that
we have with these things.
It's gonna evolve human beings past the
monkey stage that we're at right now.
Yeah,
and I,
I tend to be on the leather more
positive side of this dichotomy,
but I think one thing that has struck me
in recent years is many people are now,
you know,
mentally confronting all the issues,
running ai for the first time and I mean
I've been working on ai for three
decades and I first started thinking
about ai when I was a little kid in the
early,
late sixties and early seventies when I
saw ais and robots on the original star
Trek.
So I guess I've had a lot of cycles to
process the positives and negatives of
it where it's now like suddenly most of
the world is thinking through all this
for the first,
for the first time.
And you know,
when you first wrap your brain around
the idea that there may be creatures
10,000
or a million times smarter than human
beings at first.
This is a bit of a shocker.
Right?
And then,
I mean it takes a while to internalize
this into your worldview.
Well,
it's that there's also,
I think there's a problem with the term
artificial intelligence because it's,
that's,
it's intelligent.
It's there.
It's a real thing.
Yeah.
It's not artificial.
It's not like a fake diamond or fake
Ferrari.
It's a real thing and it.
It's not a great term and there's been
many attempts to replace it.
Would synthetic intelligence for,
for example,
but for better or worse,
I get ai is there.
It's part of the popular imagination
that seems that it's an imperfect word,
but it's not going away.
Well,
I,
I.
my question is like,
are we married to this idea of
intelligence and of life being
biological,
being carbon based tissue and cells and
blood and or insects or mammals or fish?
Are we married to that too much?
Do you think that it's entirely possible
that what human beings are doing,
what people that are at the tip of ai
right now that are really pushing the
technology where they're doing is really
creating a new life form that it's going
to be a new thing that just the same way
we recognize wasps and buffaloes and
artificial intelligence is just going to
be a life form that emerges from the
creativity and ingenuity of human
beings.
Indeed,
so I've long been an advocate of a
philosophy I think of as,
as pattern isn't like it's the pattern
of organization that appears to be the
critical thing and the,
the,
you know,
the individual cells and going down
further the molecules and particles in
our body or our turning over all the
time.
So it's not in this specific combination
of elementary particles which makes me
who I am or makes you who you are.
It's a pattern by which they're
organized and the patterns by which they
change over time.
So if we can create digital systems are
quantum computers or femto computers or
whatever it is,
manifesting the patterns of organization
that Constitute Intelligence.
I mean then then there you are there,
there,
there is intelligence,
right?
So that,
that's not to say that you know,
consciousness and experiences just about
patterns of organization.
There may be more dimensions to it,
but when,
when you look at what constitutes
intelligence thinking,
cognition,
problem solving,
you know,
it's the pattern of organization,
not,
not this specific material as as,
as far as we can tell.
So we can see no reason based on all the
science that we know so far that you
couldn't make an intelligent system of
some other form of matter rather than
the specific types of atoms and
molecules that make up human beings.
And it seems that we're,
we're well on the way to being able to
do so.
When you're studying,
when you're studying intelligence,
you're studying artificial intelligence,
do,
did you spend any time studying the
patterns that insects seem to
cooperatively behave with?
Like how leafcutter ants build these
elaborate structures underground and
build these giant colonies.
And did you study how it did?
I did,
actually,
yes.
So I,
I,
I sort of grew up with the philosophy of
complex systems which was championed by
that,
by the Santa Fe Institute in,
in,
in the 19 eighties.
And the whole concept that there is an
interdisciplinary complex system science
which includes,
you know,
biology,
cosmology,
psychology,
sociology.
There's sort of universal patterns of,
of Self Organization and you know,
aunts and ant colonies have long been
the paradigm case for that.
And I,
I used to play with the ant colonies in
my backyard.
Wow.
When I was a kid and you'd lay down food
and certain patterns,
you'd see how their answer down.
Pheromones in the colonies are
organizing it in a certain way,
and that's an interesting self
organizing complex system on that zone.
It's lacking some types of adaptive
intelligence that that human minds and
human societies have been,
but it has also interesting self
organizing patterns.
This reminds me of the novel Solaris by
Stanislaw Lem,
which was published in the sixties,
which was really quite,
quite a deep novel,
much deeper than the movie that was made
of it.
Did you ever read that book?
So there is.
So what?
I'm not familiar with the movie either.
Who will say where there was an amazing
brilliant movie by Tarkovsky,
the Russian director from the late
sixties.
Then there was a movie by Steven
Soderbergh which was sort of clammed up
and Americanized and that was fairly
recent,
right?
Ten years ago,
but that wasn't.
Didn't get all the deep points and
novel,
the original novel.
In essence,
there's this,
there's this ocean on coating the
surface of some alien planet which has
amazingly complex fractal patterns of
organization and it's also interactive
like the patterns of organization on the
Ocean respond based on what you do and
when people get near the ocean,
it causes them to hallucinate things and
even caused them to see Simulacra of
people from their past,
even the like the person who they'd most
harmed or injured in their past appears
and interacts with them so clearly.
This ocean has some type of amazing
complexity and intelligence from the
patterns that displays and from the
weird things that reeks in your mind so
that the people on earth try to
understand how the ocean is thinking.
They send a scientific expedition there
to to interact with that ocean,
but it's just so alien.
Even though monkeys with people's minds
include these doing complex things,
no two way communication is ever is ever
established and eventually the human
expedition gives up and goes home.
So it's a very Russian ending to the
novel.
I guess it's not.
I saw that,
but that the.
The interesting message there is,
I mean there can be many,
many kinds of intelligence,
right?
I mean,
human intelligence is one thing.
The intelligence of an ant colony is a
different thing.
The intelligence of human society is a
Ecosystem is a different thing and there
could be many,
many types of ais that we could build
with many,
many different properties.
Some could be wonderful to human beings,
some can be horrible to human beings,
some could just be alien minds that that
we can't even relate,
relate,
relate to very,
very well.
So we we have a very limited conception
of what an intelligence is.
If we just think by close analogy to to
human minds and this.
This is important if you're thinking
about engineering or growing are the
life forms.
They're artificial minds because it's
not just can we do this?
It's what kind of mind are,
are we going to engineer or evolve and
there's.
There's a huge spectrum of
possibilities.
Yeah,
that's one of the reasons why I asked
you that if we'd created,
if human beings had created some sort of
an insect and this insect started
organizing and developing these complex
colonies like a leaf cutter and building
these structures underground,
people would go crazy.
They would panic.
They would think these things are
organizing.
They're gonna.
They're going to build up the resources
and attack us.
They're going to try to take over
humanity.
I mean this what,
what people are worried about more than
anything when it comes to technology,
I think is the idea that we're going to
be irrelevant,
that we're going to be a antiques and
that something new and better is going
to take our place,
which is a,
which is almost double,
so we're thinking worried about it
because it's sort of the history of
biological life on earth.
I mean,
what is there as complex things?
They become more competent with single
cell organisms to multicellular
organisms.
That seems to be a pattern leading up to
us and us with this unprecedented
ability to change our environment.
That's what we can do,
right?
We can manipulate things,
poison the environment.
We can blow up entire countries with
bombs if we'd like to,
and we can also do wild creative things
like send signals through space and land
on someone else's phone on the other
side of the world almost
instantaneously.
We have incredible power,
but we're also.
We're also so limited by our biology.
Yeah.
The thing I think people are afraid of,
I'm afraid of,
but I don't know if that makes any
sense.
Is that the next level of life,
whatever artificial life is or whatever
the,
the human symbiotic is that it's going
to lack emotions.
It's going to lack desires and needs and
all the things that we think are special
about us,
our creativity,
our desire for attention and love,
all of our camaraderie,
all these different things that are sort
of programmed into us with our genetics
in order to advance our species that we
were so connected to these things.
But there's so the reason for war that
the reason for the lies,
deception,
thievery.
There's so many things that are built
into being a person that are responsible
for all the woes of humanity,
but were afraid to lose those.
I think it's almost,
and by this point that humanity is going
to create
synthetic intelligences with
tremendously greater general
intelligence and practical capability
than human beings have.
I mean,
I think I know how to do that with the
software I'm working on with my own
team,
but if we fail,
you know there's a load of other teams
who I think are a bit behind us,
but they're going in the same direction.
Now.
I feel like you're at the tip of the
spear with this stuff.
I do,
but I also think that's not the most
important thing from a human
perspective.
The most important thing is that
humanity as a whole is quite close to
this,
this threshold event.
Right.
So how far do you think?
It's quite close by my own gut feeling.
Five to 30 years.
Let's say that's pretty close,
but if I'm wrong and it's 100 years,
like in the historical time scale,
that sort of doesn't matter.
It's like,
did the Sumerians create civilization
10,000
or 10,050
years ago?
Like what?
What difference does it make?
Right.
So I think we're quite close to creating
super human artificial general
intelligence and that's in a way almost
inevitable given where we are now.
On the other hand,
I think we still have some agency
regarding whether this comes out in a
way that respects human values and
culture,
which are important to us now given who
and what we are or that is essentially
indifferent to human values and culture
in the same way that we're mostly
indifferent to chimpanzee values and
culture at that at this point.
Completely indifferent to insect values
and culture.
Not Completely,
but if you think about it,
I mean if I'm building a new house,
I will bulldoze those a bunch of events,
but yet we get upset if we extinct an
insect species.
Right?
So we,
we carry,
we carry it to some level but not but
we.
But we would like the Super Ais to care
about us more than we care about insects
or,
or grade.
Absolutely.
Right.
And I think this,
this is something we can impact right
now and to to,
to be honest,
I mean in a certain part of my mind,
I can think,
well like in,
in the end,
I don't matter that much,
my four kids don't matter that much,
my granddaughter,
it doesn't matter that much like we are
patterns of organization in a very long
lineage of patterns of organization and
they matter very much to you and other,
you know,
dinosaurs came and went and neanderthals
came and went.
Humans may come and go,
the Ai that we create may come and go
and that's the nature of the universe.
But on the other hand,
of course in my heart,
from my situated perspective as an
individual human,
like if,
if some ai charged to annihilate my,
my 10 month old son,
I would try to kill that Ai.
Right?
So as,
as a human being situated in this
specific species,
place in time,
I care a lot about the condition of,
of all of us humans.
And so I would like to not only create a
powerful general but,
but create one which,
which is,
is going to be beneficial to humans and
other life forms on the planet even
while in some ways going,
going beyond every,
everything that we are right.
And there can't be any guarantees about
something like this.
On the other hand,
humanity has really never had any
guarantees about anything anyway.
Right?
I mean,
since,
since we created civilization.
We've been leaping into the unknown one
time after the other in the somewhat
conscious and self aware way about it
from,
you know,
agriculture to language,
to math,
to the industrial revolution.
We're leaping into the unknown all the
time,
which is part of why we're where we are
today instead of just another animal
species.
So we can't have a guarantee that Agi,
artificial general intelligence is we
create,
are going to do what we consider the
right thing given our current value
systems.
On the other hand,
I suspect we can bias the odds in the
favor of,
of human values and,
and culture.
And that's something I've.
I've put a lot of thought and work into,
alongside the,
you know,
the basic algorithms of,
of artificial cognition is the issue
that the initial creation would be
subject to our programming,
but that it could perhaps program
something more efficient and design
something like if you build creativity,
you have to create,
I mean,
general generalization is about creative
writing,
right?
Yeah.
But is the issue that it would choose to
not accept our values,
which it might find clearly will choose
not to accept our values and we want it
to choose not to accept all of our
values.
So it's more a matter of whether the
ongoing creation,
evolution of new values occurs with some
continuity in respect for the previous
one.
So I mean,
uh,
with I've,
for human kids now one is a baby,
but the other three are adults,
right?
And with each of them I took the
approach of trying to teach the kids
what my values were,
not just by preaching at them,
by entering into shared situations,
but then,
you know,
when your kids grow up,
they're going to go in their own
different directions.
Right?
And these are humans,
but they all have the same sort of
biological needs,
which is one of the first place.
Yeah,
there's still as an analogy,
I think the ais that we create,
you can think of us as our mind children
and we're starting them off with our
culture and values if we do it properly
or at least with a certain subset of the
whole diverse self-contradictory mess of
human culture and values,
but you know,
they're going to evolve in,
in a different direction.
But you want that evolution to take
place in their reflective and,
and,
and caring way rather than the heatless
way.
Because if you think about it,
the average human a thousand years ago
or even 50 years ago would have thought
you and me,
we're like hopelessly immoral miscreants
who had abandoned all the valuable thing
things in life.
Uh,
my,
my hand.
I mean,
I'm,
uh,
I'm an.
I'm an infidel,
right?
I don't know.
I haven't gone to church,
uh,
for I,
I guess I mean my,
my,
my mother's lesbians,
right?
I mean,
there's all these things that we take
for granted now that not that long ago
were completely against what most humans
considered maybe the most important
values of life.
So I mean human values itself is
completely a moving,
a moving target.
So think in our generation,
moving in our,
in our generation pretty radically,
very radically.
When I think back to my childhood,
I,
I lived in New Jersey for nine years of
my childhood and just the level of
racism and antisemitism and sexism that
were just normal,
ambient and taken for granted.
Then this was,
this.
Was this when you're between.
Because we're the same age.
We're both one.
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
Born in 66.
I lived in Jersey from 73 to 82,
so I was there from 67 to 73.
Oh yeah.
Yeah.
So yeah,
I'm in my,
I'm in my sister went to the high school
prom with a,
with a black guy and so we got our car
turned upside down,
the windows of our house smash.
And it was like a human hugh mungus
thing and it's almost unbelievable now,
right?
Because now no one would care care
whatsoever.
It's,
it's,
it's just,
it's just life,
right?
Certainly the,
some fringe parts of his sculpture here,
but,
but still the point is there is no fixed
list of,
of values,
human values.
It's an ongoing evolving process and
what you want is for the evolution of
the AIS values to be coupled closely
with the evolution of human values
rather than going off in some other,
the different direction that we can't
even understand that this is literally
playing God,
right?
I mean if you're talking about like
trying to program in values,
I don't think you can program in values
that fully you can program in a system
for learning and growing values and here
again,
the analogy with human kids,
it's not hopeless like telling,
telling your kids these are the 10
things that are important doesn't work
that well,
right?
What works?
What works better is you enter into
shared situations with them,
they see how deal with the situations,
you guide them in dealing with real
situations and that forms their system
of values and this is what needs to
happen with ais.
They need to grow up entering into real
life situations with human beings,
so the real life patterns of human
values,
which are worth a lot more than the
families that we annunciate formally
wrote,
the real life pattern of human values
gets inculcated into the intellectual
DNA of the AI systems.
And this is part of what worries me
about the way the AI field is going at
this moment because I mean most of the
really powerful,
narrow ais on the planet now are
involved with like selling people stuff
they don't need spying on.
People are like figuring out who should
be killed or otherwise abused by some
government.
Right?
So if,
if the early stage Ai's that we build
turn into general intelligences
gradually and these general intelligence
is our,
you know,
spy agents and advertising agents.
Then like what,
what,
what mindset do these early stage ais
have as they grow up?
Right?
If they don't have any problem morally
and ethically with manipulating us,
which we're very malleable,
right?
We're so easy to manipulate what we're
teaching them.
We're teaching them to manipulate tape
on where rewarding them for doing it
successfully.
So this is,
this is one of these things that from
the outside point of view might not seem
to be all that intelligent it,
it's sort of like gun laws in the U.
s living in Hong Kong.
I mean most people don't have a bunch of
guns sitting around their house and
coincidentally there,
there are not that many random shootings
happening in Hong Kong.
So yeah,
you look in the UK.
Yeah,
you look in the US,
it's like somehow you have laws that
allow random lunatics to buy all the
guns they want and you have all these
people getting shot.
So similarly like from the outside you
could look at it like this species is
creating the successor intelligence and
almost all the resources going into
creating their successor intelligence
are going into making ais to do
surveillance like military drones and
advertising agents to brainwash people
into buying crap they don't need.
Now what do you think?
Well what's wrong with this picture?
Isn't that just because that's where the
money is,
like this is the introduction to it and
from then we'll find other uses and
applications for it.
But like right now,
that's where the thing is,
there's a lot of other applications,
financial app,
financially viable applicant.
Oh yeah.
The applications that are getting the
most attention are the financial lowest
hanging fruit.
Right?
So for,
for,
for example,
among many projects I'm doing with my
singularity net team,
we're looking at applying ai to diagnose
agricultural disease.
So you can,
you can look at images of plant leaves,
you can look at data from the soil and
the atmosphere,
and you can project whether disease and
a plant is likely to progress badly or
not,
which tells you do you need medicine for
the plant,
do you need pesticides now this,
this is an interesting area of
application.
It's probably quite financially
lucrative in in a way,
but it's a more complex industry than,
than selling stuff online.
So the fraction of resources going into
ai for agriculture is very small.
Then like a ecommerce or something very
specific aspect of agriculture to
predicting diseases.
Yeah.
But there's,
there's a lot of specific aspects,
right?
So I mean ai for medicine,
again,
there's been papers on machine learning
applied to medicine since the eighties
and nineties,
but the amount of effort going into that
compared to advertising or surveillance
is very small now.
This has to do with the structure of the
pharmaceutical business as,
as compared to the structure of the tech
business.
So you know,
when you look into it,
there's,
there's good,
there's good reasons,
there's good reasons for,
for everything,
right?
But nevertheless,
the way things are coming at coming down
right now is certain biases to the
development of early stage.
Ai's are,
are very market and,
and you could,
you could,
you could see them and I'm in,
I'm trying to do something about that
together with my colleagues and in
singularity in that.
But of course we're.
So we're sort of a David versus goliath
thing.
It seemed,
well of course you're trying to do
something different and I think it's
awesome what you guys are doing,
but it just makes sense to me that the
first applications are going to be the
ones that are more financially viable.
It's like,
well,
the first applications were military,
right until about 10 years ago,
85 percent of all funding into ai was
from us plus plus Western Europe
military.
Well,
what I'm getting at is it,
it seems that money and and,
and commerce are inexorably linked to
innovation and technology because
there's this sort of thing that we do as
a culture where we're constantly trying
to buy and purchase bigger and better
things.
We always want the newest iphone,
the greatest,
you know,
a laptop.
We don't want them,
the coolest electric cars,
whatever,
whatever it is,
and this fuels innovation.
This,
this desire for new,
greater things.
Materialism and a lot of ways fuels
innovation because this is
those.
But I think there's an argument that as
we approach a technological singularity,
we need new systems because if you look
at that,
things have happened during the last
century.
What's happened is that governments have
funded most of the core innovation I'm
in.
This is well known that like most of the
technology and the,
the smartphone was funded by US
government,
a little about European government,
GP,
gps and the batteries and everything.
And then companies scaled it up that
they made,
they made it user friendly,
they decreased cost of manufacturing and
this process occurs with a certain time
cycle to it or like government spends
decades funding core innovation and
universities and then industry spends
decades figuring out how to scale it up
and make it palatable to users.
And you know,
this matured probably since World War
II,
this sort of modality for technology
development,
but now that things are developing
faster and faster and faster,
there's sort of not time for,
for that cycle to occur where the
government and universities incubate new
ideas for awhile and then technology
scales it up.
So genie's out of the bottle
essentially.
Yeah.
But we still need a lot of new amazing
creative innovation to happen.
But somehow or other new new structures
are going to have to evolve to,
to make it happen.
And you can see everyone's struggling to
figure out what these are.
So I mean this is why you have,
I mean you have big companies embracing
open source,
Google releases,
tensorflow,
and there's a lot of,
lot of other different things.
And I think,
I think some projects in the
cryptocurrency world had been looking at
that too,
like how do we use tokens to
incentivize,
you know,
independent scientists and inventors to,
to do new stuff without them asking to
be in the government research lab or in
a big company.
So I think we're going to need the
evolution of new systems of innovation
and of,
of technology transfer as things are,
are developing faster and faster and
faster.
And this is another thing that sort of
got me interested in the whole
decentralized world and in the
blockchain world is the promise of new
modes of economic and social
organization that can,
you know,
bring more of the world into the
research process and accelerate the
technology transfer
process.
I definitely want to talk about that,
but one of the things that I want to ask
you is when,
when you're discussing this,
I think what you're saying is have one
very important point that we need to
move past the military gatekeepers of
tech.
Not just military,
no.
It's big tech which are at advertising
agencies in social media.
The things that are constantly
predicting your next purchase,
right?
Yeah,
because if you,
if you think about it,
and I'm in even in a semi democracy look
like we have in the US,
I mean those who control the
brainwashing of the public in essence
control who,
who,
who votes for what and who controls the
brainwashing of the public is
advertising agencies and who
increasingly are the biggest advertising
agencies or are the big tech companies
who are accumulating everybody's data
and using it to,
to program their minds to buy things.
So this is what's programmed the global
brain of,
of,
of the human race.
And of course there are close links
between big tech and the military.
Let's look at Amazon has what?
Twenty 5,000
person headquarters in Crystal City,
Virginia,
right next to the Pentagon and in China
it's even more direct and unapologetic,
right?
So it's a new like military industrial
advertising complex,
which is his guiding the evolution of
the global brain on the planet,
which with this past election,
right,
with all the intrusion by foreign
entities trying to influence the
election that they have these giant
houses set up to write bad stories about
whoever they don't want to be in office.
Yeah.
In a way that's almost a red herring,
but I mean they're Russian stuff is
almost a red herring.
But it revealed what the processes are,
which,
which are used to program because I
think the whatever programming of
Americans' minds is done by the Russians
is many minuscule compared to the
programming of Americans' minds by my
advisee,
American American corporate and
government elite.
So it's fascinating that anybody's even
jumping in as well as an elite.
Sure.
It's,
it's,
it's interesting if you look at what's
happening in China that's like,
yeah,
yeah.
They're,
they're way better than the,
than we are much more horrific.
Right.
And that's all.
It's more,
it's more professional,
it's more polished,
it's more centralized.
On the other hand,
for almost everyone in China,
China is a very good place to live and
you know,
the level of improvement in that country
in the last 30 years has just been
astounding,
right?
I mean,
you can't,
you can't argue with how much better
it's gotten there since shouting took
over.
It's,
it's tremendous because they're not,
they,
they embraced capitalism to a certain
extent.
They've created their own unique system
with what labels you give.
It is,
it's almost arbitrary.
They,
they've created their own unique system
as a,
you know,
crazy hippie,
libertarian,
a narco socialist,
freedom loving,
maniac.
That system rubs against my grain in
many ways.
On the other hand,
empirically if you look at it,
it's improved the wellbeing of a,
of a tremendous number of people.
So hopefully it evolves and it's one
style.
But the way it's evolving now is not in
a more positive freedom.
Love.
Well,
it's not in the more freedom,
loving and an archaic direction.
One would say it's positive in some ways
and negative and others like most
complex Hong Kong.
Why do you live there?
Um,
I fell in love with a Chinese woman.
Hey,
go.
She's crazy.
She has great reason.
We had a baby recently.
She,
she's not from Hong,
she's from mainland China.
I met her when she was doing her phd in
computational linguistics and Shaman,
but that,
that,
that was what sort of first got me to
spend a lot of time in China,
but then I was doing some research at
Hong Kong Polytechnic University and
then my good friend David Hansen was
visiting me in Hong Kong.
I introduced him to some investors there
which ended up with him bringing his
company,
Hanson robotics to Hong Kong.
So now after I moved there because of
falling in love with a rating,
then I brought my friend David there
than Hanson robotics.
Grew up there and there's actually a
good reason for Hanson robotics to be
there because I'm in the best place in
the world.
The manufacturer complex electronics is
in Shenzhen,
rarely across the border from Hong Kong.
So now I've been working there with
Hanson robotics on the Sophia robots and
other robots for,
for,
for awhile.
And I've accumulated the whole ai team
there around Hanson robotics and ai and
singularity in that.
So I'm in by,
by now.
I'm there because my whole ai and
robotics teams are there.
It makes sense.
Um,
do you follow,
uh,
the State Department's recommendations
to not use walway devices and they
believe that they're all know,
even heard that.
I mean if the Chinese are spying on us,
you know,
I'm sure.
You know,
when I lived in my lived in Washington
DC for nine years,
I did a bunch of consulting for various
government agencies there.
And my wife is a communist party member
actually.
Well,
just because she joined in high school
when it was sort of suggested for her to
join.
So I'm,
I'm,
I'm sure I'm being watched by multiple
governments.
It doesn't,
I don't have any secrets.
It doesn't really matter.
I'm not in the business of trying to
overthrow the government.
And I'm in the business of trying to
bypass traditional governments and
traditional monetary systems and all the
rest by creating new methods of
organization of people and information.
You understand that what you personally.
But it is unusual if the government is
actually spying on people through these
divides out.
It's unusual.
It's unusual at all.
I mean,
I,
I mean without going into too much
detail,
like when I was in dc working with
various government agencies,
it became clear there is tremendously
more information obtained by government
agencies than most people realize,
well,
this was,
this was true way before snowden and
wikileaks and all these revelations and
what is publicly understood now is
probably not the full scope of,
of,
of the information that governments have
others.
So I'm in privacy is,
is pretty much dead.
And David Brin,
do you know David Brin?
No.
You should definitely interview David
and he's an amazing guy,
but he's a well known science fiction
writer.
He's based in southern California,
San Diego.
But he wrote a book in Oh,
years ago called the transparent society
where he said there's two possibilities,
surveillance and sousveillance.
It's like the power elite watching
everyone or everyone watching everyone.
I think everyone watching everyone.
Well,
yeah,
but he.
So he articulated this as the
essentially the only two viable
possibilities and he's like,
we should be choosing and then creating
which of these alternatives we want.
So now,
now the world is starting to understand
what he was talking about.
But back when he wrote that book,
you wrote the book.
Oh,
I can't remember.
I mean it was well more than a decade.
That gets weird,
but some people just nail it on the head
decades in advance.
I mean,
most of the things that are happening in
the world now we're foreseen by a
stanislaw lem,
the Polish Arthur mentioned volunteer
church.
And a friend of mine who was the founder
of Russian Ai.
He wrote a book called the phenomenon of
science in the late sixties.
Then,
you know,
in 1971 or two when I was a little kid,
I read a book called the promethium
project by a Princeton physics called
Gerald Gerald Fund Berg.
You've read a physical book when you're
five years old.
I started reading when I was two and my
grandfather was a physicist,
so I was reading a lot of stuff then.
But he Feinberg in this book,
he said,
you know,
within the next few decades,
humanity is going to create
nanotechnology,
it's going to create machines smarter
than people and it's going to create the
technology to allow human,
biological immortality.
And the question will be,
do we want to use these technologies,
you know,
to promote rampant consumerism or do we
want to use these technologies to
promote,
you know,
spiritual growth of our,
of our consciousness into new dimensions
of experience and what fonder proposed
in this book in the late sixties,
which I read in the early seventies,
he proposed the UN should send a task
force out to go to everyone in the
world,
every little African village and educate
the world about nanotech life extension
and an Agi and get the whole world to
vote on whether we should develop these
technologies toward consumerism or
toward consciousness expansion.
So I read this from a little kid.
It's like,
this is almost obvious.
This makes total sense.
Like,
why?
Why does everyone understand this?
Then I tried to explain this to people.
I'm like,
Oh shit,
I guess it's gonna be awhile till the
world catches on,
so.
So I instead decided I should build a
spacecraft,
go away from the world at rapid speed
and come back after like a million years
or something when the world was far more
advanced.
So covered in dust.
Yeah.
Right.
So now we'll.
Then you go another million years or so
now,
pretty much the world agrees that life
extension,
Agi and nanotechnology or plausible
things that may come about in the near
future.
The same question is,
is there that that Feinberg saw like 50
years ago,
right?
The same question.
Is there like,
did we develop this for rampant
consumerism or do we develop this for
amazing new dimensions of consciousness
expansion and mental growth,
but the UN is not in fact educating the
world about this and pulling them to
decide democratically what to do on.
On.
On the other hand,
there's the possibility that by
bypassing governments and the UN and
doing something decentralized,
you can create a democratic framework,
you know,
within which you know,
a broad swath of the world can be
involved in a participatory way in
guiding the direction of these advances.
Do you think that it's possible that
instead of choosing that we're just
going to have multiple directions,
that it's growing in that there's going
to be consumer.
There will be multiple directions and
it's that that's inevitable.
It's more a matter of whether anything
besides the military advertising complex
gets a shake.
So I mean if you look in the software
development world,
open source is an amazing thing,
right?
Linux is awesome and it's led to so much
ai being open,
open source now.
Now Open source didn't have to actually
take over the entire software world like
Richard Stallman one and in order to
have a huge impact,
right?
It's enough that it's a major force.
So I mean it's very hippy concept,
isn't it?
Open source and a lot of ways in a way,
but,
but yet ibm,
IBM has probably thousands of people
working on Linux.
Right?
So like apple began as a hippie concept,
but it became very practical.
Right?
So I mean something like 75 percent of
all the servers running the Internet are
based in Linux.
You know,
the vast majority of mobile phone oss
is,
is Linux,
right?
So this Hippie,
vast majority being android is Linux.
Yeah.
So I'm in this hippie crazy thing where
no one owns the code.
It didn't have to overtake the whole
software economy and become everything
to become highly valuable and then
inject a different dimension into
things.
And I think the same is true with
decentralized ai,
which we're looking at with singularity
and that it doesn't have,
we don't have to actually put Google
and,
and the US and Chinese military and
tencent out of business.
Right.
Although if that happens that that's
fine.
But W we,
it's enough that we become an extremely
major player in that ecosystem so that
this,
you know,
participatory and benefit oriented
aspect becomes a really significant
component of how humanity is,
is developing general intelligence.
W is accepted,
generally accepted that human beings
will consistently and constantly
innovate.
Right.
It just seems to be characteristics that
we have.
Why do you think that is and what do you
think that,
especially when it,
in terms of creating something like
artificial intelligence,
like why build our successors?
Like why,
why do that?
Like what is,
what is it about us that makes us want
to constantly make bigger,
better things?
Well,
that's an interesting question in the
history of biology,
which I may not be the most qualified
person to answer.
It is an interesting question and I
think it has something to do with the
weird way in which we embody various
contradictions that we're always trying
to resolve locally.
You mentioned ents and answer social
animals,
right?
Worse.
Like cats are very individual.
We're like trapped between the two,
like we're somewhat individual and
somewhat social.
And then.
And then since we created civilization,
it's,
it's even worse because we have certain
aspects which are,
which are wanting to conform with the
group and the tribe and others which are
wanting to innovate and break out of
the.
And we're sort of trapped in these
biological and cultural contradictions
which tend to drive innovation.
But I think there's a lot there that no
one understands in the roots of the
human psyche evolutionarily.
But as an empirical fact,
what you said is,
is,
is very true,
right?
Like we,
we're driven to seek novelty.
We're driven to create new things.
And this is probably one of the factors
which is driving the creation of Ai.
I don't think that alone would make the
creation of ai inevitable,
but the thing,
why don't you think it would make it
inevitable if we consistently innovate?
And it's always been a concept.
I mean,
you were talking about the concept
existing 30 plus years ago.
Well,
I think a key point is that there's
tremendous practical economic advantage
and status advantage to be gotten from
ai right now.
And this is driving the advancement of
ai to be incredibly rapid,
right?
Because there are some things that are
interesting and would use a lot of human
innovation,
but they get very few resources.
So for example,
my,
my oldest son's Arthur Oostra,
he's doing his phd now.
What is this Zarathustra?
My kids are Pfister,
Amadeus,
Debbie lawn,
ulysses Shaharazad.
And then a new one is corky qrs,
which is an acronym for quantum
organized rational expanding
intelligence.
So I was never happy with Ben.
It's a very boring name.
So yeah.
Yeah.
I had,
I had to do something more interesting
with my kids.
Anyway,
Zarathustra is doing his phd on the
application of machine learning to
automated theorem proving basically make
ais that can do mathematics better.
And to me that's the most important
thing we could be applying ai to because
you know,
mathematics is the key to all modern
science and engineering.
My Phd was in math originally,
but the amount of resources going into
ai for automating mathematics is not
large at this present moment,
although that's a beautiful and amazing
area for invention and innovation and
creativity.
So I think what's driving our rapid
pushed or dozing ai,
I mean it's not just our creative drive,
it's the fact that there's tremendous
economic value,
military value and human value.
I mean curing diseases,
teaching kids,
there's tremendous value in almost
everything that's important to human
beings in,
in building ai,
right?
So you put that together with our drive
to create an interface and this becomes
an almost unstoppable force within,
within human society.
And what we've seen in the last,
you know,
three to five years is suddenly,
national leaders and Titans of industry
and even like pop stars,
right?
They've woken up to the concept that
wow,
smarter and smarter ai is real and this
is going to get better and better like
within years to decades,
not centuries to millennia.
So now the cat's out of the bag,
nobody's going to put it back.
And it's about,
you know,
how can we direct it in the most
beneficial possible way?
And as you say,
it doesn't have to be just one possible.
We were like,
what will I look forward to personally
is bifurcating myself into an array of
possible Benton's like it.
I'd like to get one copy of me fuse
itself with a superhuman ai mind and you
know,
become,
uh,
a god or something beyond the God.
You wouldn't even be myself.
God,
I wouldn't even be myself anymore.
Right.
I mean,
you would lose all concepts of human
self and identity,
but it would be the point of even
holding any of it,
you know,
that's,
that's for the future.
That's for the Mega Ben to decide,
right?
Yeah.
On the other hand,
I'd like to let me remained in human
form,
you know,
get,
get rid of a death and disease and the
psychological issues and just live live
happily forever,
you know,
in,
in the peoples who watched over by the
machines of loving grace.
Right.
So,
I mean,
you can have,
it doesn't have to be either or because
once,
once you can scan your brain and body
and three d print new copies of
yourself,
you could have multiple of.
I mean,
that's there's a lot of mass energy in
the universe and the universe,
so that's assuming that we can escape
this planet because of you.
If you're talking about if you're going
to make themselves,
how can you live in a world with a
billion donald trump's
because literally that's what we're
talking about,
talking about people being able to
reproduce themselves and just having
this idea that they would like their ego
to exist in multiple different forms.
Whether it's some super symbiotic form
that's connected to artificial
intelligence or some biological form
that's immortal or some other form that
stands just as a normal human being.
As we know in 2018 have you have
multiple versions of yourself over and
over and over again like that.
That's where you're.
So once you get to the point where you
have a super human general intelligence
that can do things like fully scanned
the human brain and body and three d
print more of them.
By that point,
you're at a level where scarcity of
material resources is not an issue at
the human scale of doing things.
So I actually have human resources in
terms of what
mass energy,
scared scarcity of molecules to print
more copies of yourself.
I think that,
I think that's not going to be the issue
at that point when people are worried
about is environmental concerns of
overpopulation is people are worried
about what they see in front of their
faces right now,
but people are not.
Most people are not thinking deeply
enough about what potential would be
there once you had super human ai is
doing the calculation manufacturing and
the thinking.
I mean,
I mean the.
The amount of energy in the single grain
of sand,
if you had an ai able to to
appropriately leverage that.
That energy is,
is tremendously more than than most than
most people think.
And the amount of computing power in a
grain of sand.
It's like a quadrillion times.
All the people on Earth put together.
So I mean,
what do you mean by that amount of
computing power?
There's.
Well the amount of computing power that
could be achieved by reorganizing the
elementary particles in the grain of
sand.
Yeah,
there,
there's,
there's a number in physics called the
beacon stone bound,
which is the maximum amount of
information that can be,
can be stored in a certain amount of
mass energy here,
so that that if the laws of physics as
we know them now are correct,
which they certainly aren't than the
[inaudible].
That would be the amount of computing
you can do in a certain amount of mass
and energy.
We're very,
very far from that limit right now.
Right,
so I mean,
my point is once you have something a
thousand times smarter than people,
what we imagined to be the limits now
doesn't matter
too.
The issues that we're dealing with in
terms of environmental concerns,
that could all potentially be almost
certainly going to be irrelevant,
irrelevant.
There may be others problem issues that
we can't even conceive at this moment,
but the intelligence will be so vastly
superior to what we have currently that
they'll be able to find solutions to
virtually every single problem with
Shima,
a ocean,
fish,
deep population.
All that stuff will just arrangements
of molecules freaking me out.
But to hear that though,
environmental people don't want to hear
that.
Well,
I mean I
also on the everyday life basis until we
have these super ais,
I don't like the garbage,
Washington from the beach near my house
either.
Right?
So I mean,
but on an everyday basis,
of course we wanted to promote health in
our bodies and in our,
in our environments right now,
as long as there's no measurable
uncertainty regarding when the
Benevolent Super Ais will will,
will,
will come about still,
I think the main question isn't whether
once you have beneficially disposed
super ai,
it could solve all our current petty
little problems.
The question is can we wade through the
mock of modern human society and
psychology to create this beneficial
super ai in,
in,
in the first place I got,
I believe I know how to create a
beneficial super ai,
but it's a lot of,
a lot of work to get there and of course
there's many teams around the world
working on vaguely similar projects now.
It's not obvious what kind of super ai
we're actually going to get once we get
there.
Yeah,
it's all just guesses at this point,
right?
It's more less educated guesses
depending on who's doing the guessing.
You say that it's almost like we're in a
race of the the primitive primate
biology versus the potentially
beneficial and benevolent artificial
intelligence that this.
The best aspects of this primate can
create that it's almost a race to get
who's going to win.
Is it the warmongers and the greedy
whores that are smashing the world under
its boots or is it the scientists that
are going to figure out some super
intelligent way to solve all of our
problems?
Let's look at it more as a
look at it more as a,
as a struggle between different modes of
social organization than individual
people.
I mean,
look what when I worked in DC with
intelligence agencies,
most of the people I met there were
really nice human beings who believed
they were doing the best for the world.
Even if some of the things that we're
doing,
like I thought were very much not for
the best of the world.
Soon I'm in military mode of
organization or large corporations as a
mode of organization are in my view,
not journaling can lead to beneficial
outcomes for the overall species and and
for the global brain and the scientific
community.
The open source community I think are
better modes of organization and you
know the,
the better aspects of the blockchain and
crypto community have a better mode of
organization.
So I think if,
if this sort of open decentralized of
organization can marshal more resources
as opposed to this centralized,
authoritarian mode of organization,
then I think things are going to come
out for the better and it's not so much
about bad people versus good people.
You can look at like the corporate mode
of organization.
It's almost a virus that that's
colonized a bunch of humanity and is
sucking people into working according to
the,
to this mode and even if they're really
good people and the individual task
they're working on isn't bad in itself.
They're working within this,
this mode that's leading their work to
be used for ultimately a non good end.
Yeah.
That is a fascinating thing about
corporations,
isn't it?
That the diffusion of responsibility and
being a part of a gigantic group that
you as an individual don't feel
necessarily connected,
are responsible to the.
Even the CEO isn't fully responsible.
Like if the CEO does something that
isn't in accordance with the high higher
goals of the organization,
they're just replaced.
Right.
So I mean there's no one person who's in
charge.
It's really like,
it's like an that column.
It's like its own organism and I mean
it's us who have let these organisms
become parasites on humanity in this
way.
In some ways the Asian countries are a
little more intelligent than western
countries and the Asian governments
realize the power of corporations to
mold society and there's a bit more
feedback between the government and
corporations which can be for better or
for worse,
but then in in America there's some
ethos of like free markets and free
enterprise,
which is really not taking into account
the oligopolistic nature of,
of,
of modern markets,
but in Asian countries isn't it that the
government is actually suppressing
inflammation as well.
They're also suppressing Google and
South Korea?
No,
I'm in South Korea.
If you look at my only ones,
well Singapore,
I'm in Singapore is ruthless in their
drug laws and some of the archaic,
well us far worse though,
Singapore,
it gives you the death penalty for
marijuana.
They do it.
South Korea is an example which has
roughly the same level of personal
freedoms as the US more in some ways
less than others.
Massive electronic and innovation.
Well,
interesting thing they're politically
is.
I mean they were poorer than two thirds
of sub Saharan African nations in the
late sixties and it is through the
government intentionally stimulating
corporate development toward
manufacturing in electronics that they
grew up so that,
that,
that now I'm in,
I'm not holding that up as a paragon for
the future or anything,
but it does show that there's,
there's many modes of organization of
people and resources other than the ones
that we take for granted in the US.
I don't think Samsung and lg are the
ideal for the future either though.
I mean I'm much more interested in,
you know,
your son in blockchain.
I'm interested in.
I'm interested in open source.
I'm interested in,
in blockchain.
I'm basically,
I'm interested in anything that's,
you know,
open and participatory and disruptive as
well because I think that's,
I think that is the way to be ongoingly
just disruptive and open source is a
good example of that.
Like when the open source movement
started,
they weren't thinking about machine
learning,
but you know,
the,
the fact that open source is out there
and there's been prevalent in the
software world that pave the way for ai
to now be centered on open source
algorithms.
So right now even though big companies
and governments dominate the scalable
rollout of Ai,
the invention of new ai algorithms is
mostly done by people creating new code
and putting it,
putting it on,
on get hub or get lab or other open
source repository.
Retired repositories been sources self
explanatory in its title.
Pretty much people kind of understand
what it is that means that various
coders get to share in this,
this code and the source code and they
get to innovate and they all get to
participate and use each other's work.
Right,
right.
Um,
but blockchain,
and it's confusing for a lot of people.
Could you explain that?
Sure.
I'm in block block.
Block chain itself is almost a misnomer,
so we're confused.
Things are confusing,
uh,
at every level,
right.
So we can start with the idea of a
distributed ledger,
which is basically like a distributed,
an excel spreadsheet or database.
It's just a story of information which
is not stored just in one place,
but there's copies of it in lots of
different places.
Every time my copy of it is updated,
everyone else's copy of it has,
has,
has got to be updated.
And then then there's various bells and
whistles like sharding where you know,
it can be broken in many pieces and each
piece is stored many places or
something.
So That's a distributed ledger and
that's just distributed computing.
Now what,
what makes it more interesting is when
you layer decentralized control onto
that.
So imagine you have this distributed
excel spreadsheet or distributed
database.
There's copies of it stored in a
thousand places,
but to update it,
you need like 500 of those thousand
people who own the copies to vote.
Yeah.
Let's do that update,
right?
So then then you have a distributed
store of data and you have like a
democratic voting mechanism to determine
when all those copies can get,
can get updated together,
right?
So then then what you have is a data
storage and update mechanism that's
controlled in a democratic way by the
group of participants rather than by any
one central controller.
And that that can have all sorts of
advantages.
I mean for one thing it means that you
know,
there's no one controller who can go
rogue and screw with the day without
telling anyone.
It also means there is no one has some
limitation go hold a gun to their head
and shoot them for,
for what data updates were made because
know controlled democratically by,
by everybody,
right?
It has ramifications in terms of,
you know,
legal defensibility and I mean you could
have some people in Iran,
some in China,
some in the US and,
and updates to this whole distributed
data store are made by democratic
decision of all the participants.
Somewhere cryptography comes in is when
I vote,
I don't have to say,
yeah,
this is Ben Gursel voting for this
update to be accepted or not.
It's just ID number one,
three,
five,
seven,
two,
six,
four.
And then encryption is used to make sure
that,
you know,
it's,
it's the same guy voting every time that
it claims to be with without needing
like your,
your passport number or something.
Right.
What's ironic about it is it's probably
one of the best ways ever conceived to
actually vote in this country.
Yeah,
sure.
It would be kind of ironic.
There's a lot of applications for the,
the,
the.
That's the,
that's right.
So the,
so that.
I mean that's the core mechanism though
where the block chain comes from is like
a data structure where to store the data
in this distributed database,
it's stored in a chain of blocks or each
block contains data.
The thing is not every so-called
blockchain system even uses a chain of
blocks and I'd like some use a tree or a
graph of blocks or something.
So that term,
I mean it's,
it's an alright terms like ai,
like just one of those terms were stuck
with.
It's one,
it's one of those terms were stuck with,
even though it's not quite technically
not quite technically accurate.
I mean anymore.
I mean w w,
W,
I don't know,
another buzzword for it,
right.
What it is is a,
it's a distributed ledger with
encryption and decentralized control and
blockchain is the buzzword that's come
about for that.
Now what,
what got me interested in blockchain
really is this decentralized control
aspect.
So my,
my,
my wife,
well them with for 10 years now,
she dug up recently something I'd
forgotten,
which is a webpage and made in 1995,
like a long time ago where I'd said,
hey,
I'm going to run for president on the
decentralization platform for which I'd
completely forgotten that crazy idea.
I was very young then.
I had no idea within an annoying job
being president would be.
But the so that the idea of
decentralized control seemed very
important to me back then,
which is well,
before bitcoin was invented because I
could see,
you know,
a global brain is evolving on the planet
involving humans,
computers,
communication devices,
and we don't want this global brain to
be controlled by a small elite.
We want the global parent to be
controlled in the,
in a decentralized way.
So,
so that,
that's really the,
the beauty of this,
a blockchain infrastructure.
And what,
what got me interested in the practical
technologies of block chain was really
one etherium came out and you add the
notion of a smart contract,
which was the theory etherium.
Yeah.
So what is that?
Well,
so the first blockchain technology was
Bitcoin,
right?
Which is a well known cryptocurrency now
if theory.
IOM is another cryptocurrency,
which is the number to cryptocurrency
right now.
That's how the loop I am.
Did you know about it?
You did.
However,
ethereum came along with a really nice
software framework.
So it's not just like a digital money,
like bit coin is,
but it theory.
IOM has a programming language called
solidity that came with it and this
programming language let's you right
where they're called smart contracts and
again,
that sort of a misnomer because a smart
contract,
it doesn't have to be either smart or a
right,
but it was a cool name and then if it's
really a smart contract,
it's a contract.
It's like a programmable transaction so
you you can program a legal contract or
you can program of a financial
transaction.
So a smart contract,
it's a.
it's a persistent piece of software that
embodies like a secure encrypted
transaction between between multiple
parties,
so pretty much like anything on the back
end of a bank's website or a transaction
between two companies online,
a purchasing relationship between you
and the website online.
This could all be stripped it in in the
smart contract in this secure way,
and then it wouldn't be automated in
this simple and standard way.
So the vision that Vitalik Buterin who
was the main creator behind the theory
had is to basically make the internet
into a giant computing mechanism rather
than mostly like an information storage
and retrieval mechanism.
Make the Internet into a giant computer,
but making it really simple programming
language for scripting transactions
among different computers and different
parties on the Internet where you have
encryption and you have democratic
decision making and distributed storage
of information like programmed into
this,
this world computer.
Right?
And then that was a really cool idea.
And the etherium blockchain and solidity
programming language made it really easy
to do that.
So it made it really easy to program
like distributed secure transaction and
computing systems on the Internet.
So I saw this,
I thought,
well,
like now we finally have the tool set
that's needed to implement.
Some of this is very popular.
I mean,
I mean basically almost every ico that
was done the last couple of years was
done on the ethereum blockchain.
What's an ICO?
Initial coin offering.
Oh,
okay.
So for Bitcoins,
for,
I'm sorry,
cryptocurrency,
cryptocurrency use this technology
brings.
Right?
So what happened in the last couple of
years is a bunch of people realized you
could use this etherium programming
framework to create a new
cryptocurrency,
like a new artificial money.
And then you can try to get people to
use your new artificial money for
certain types of artificial coins.
It may be more popular.
Is Bitcoin,
right?
Bitcoin is by far the most popular.
The most delirium is number two.
And there's a bunch of others.
I mean Hartwick comparison,
like how much bigger is bitcoin and
ethereum?
I Dunno.
Five factor of three to five.
So maybe just a factor of two.
Now it's actually last year at theory
and almost took over bitcoin when
bitcoin started crashing.
Yeah.
Now if their room is back down,
there might be half or a third of the
fluctuating value of these things.
To My,
to my mind,
creating artificial monies is one tiny
bit of the potential of what you could
do with the whole blockchain tool.
Set it.
It happened to become popular initially
because it's where the money is,
right?
I've been right writing it is.
It is money and that's interesting to
people,
but on the other hand,
what it's really about is making world
computer.
It's about scripting with a simple
programming language,
all sorts of transactions between
people,
companies,
whatever,
all sorts of exchanges of,
of information.
So I mean it's about decentralized
voting mechanisms.
It's about Ai's being able to send data
and processing for each other and pay
each other for their transactions.
So I'm in,
there's,
it's about automating supply chains and,
and,
and shipping and ecommerce so that
there's an in,
in,
in essence,
you know,
just like computers and the Internet
started with a certain small set of
applications and then pervaded almost
everything,
right?
It's the same way with blockchain
technology,
like it started with digital money,
but the core technology is going to
pervade almost everything because
there's almost no domain of human
pursuit that couldn't use like security
through cryptography,
some sort of,
you know,
participatory decision making and then
distributed storage of information.
Right?
So these things are also valuable for
ai,
which is how I got into it in the first
place.
I mean,
if you're making a very,
very powerful ai that is going to,
you know,
gradually through the practical value
delivers,
she will grow up to be more and more and
more intelligent.
I mean this ai shouldn't be able to
engage a large party of people and ais
and participatory decision making.
They,
I should be able to store information in
a widely distributed way and,
and ai certainly shouldn't be able to
use,
you know,
security and encryption development,
who are the parties involved in this
operation and I mean these are the key
things behind behind blockchain
technology.
So I'm in the fact the fact that
blockchain began with artificial
currencies to me is a detail of history.
Just like the fact the fact that the
Internet began as like a nuclear early
warning system right then.
And it did.
It's good for that.
But it's,
as it happens,
it's also even better for a lot of other
things.
So the,
the solution for the financial situation
that we find ourselves in.
One of the more interesting things about
cryptocurrencies that someone said,
okay,
look,
obviously we all kind of agreed that our
financial institutions are very flawed
system that we operate under is it's
very fucked up,
so how do we fix that?
Well,
sending the super nerds and so they
figure out a new number,
get ascend into super,
a super,
super nervous super.
Obviously.
Who is the guy that they think that this
fake person maybe not real,
that came up with bitcoin.
Komodo.
Do you have any suspicions as to who
this is a,
I can neither confirm nor deny that you
wouldn't be on the inside.
We'll talk later,
but that,
this is,
it's very,
it's very interesting,
but it's also very promising.
I,
I've like high optimism for
cryptocurrencies because I think that
kids today are looking at it with much
more open eyes than uh,
you know,
grandfathers,
grandfathers are looking at bitcoin and
the father.
You're exceptional one,
but there's a lot of people that are
older that just,
they're not open to accepting these
ideas,
but I think kids today in particular,
the ones that have grown up with the
internet as a constant force in their
life,
they're.
I think they're more likely to embrace
something along those lines.
Well,
yeah,
so there's no doubt that you know,
cryptographic formulations of money are
going to become the standard.
The question,
do you think that's going to be the
standard that will have been?
Yeah.
However,
it could happen potentially in a very
uninteresting way.
How's.
You could just have the dollar.
I mean the government could just say we
will create this cryptographic token
which counts as a dollar.
I mean,
most dollars are just electronic.
Anyway,
so,
so what,
what,
what habitually happens is technologies
that are invented to subvert the
establishment are converted to a forum
where they help bolster the
establishment.
Instead,
I'm in and in financial services.
This happens very rapidly,
like pay Pal Peter Teal on this guy
started paypal thinking they were going
to obsolete Fiat currency and make an an
alternative to the currencies run by by
nation states instead.
They were driven to make it a credit
card processing front end.
Right.
So,
so that's one thing that could happen
with crypto currency is it just becomes
a mechanism for,
you know,
governments and big companies and banks
to do the things more efficiently.
So what,
what's interesting isn't so much the
digital money aspect,
although it is in some ways a great way
to do digital money.
Wow.
What,
What's interesting is with all the
flexibility it gives you to script,
you know,
complex computing networks in there is
the possibility to new forms of,
you know,
participatory democratic self organizing
networks.
So blockchain,
like the internet or computing is a very
flexible medium.
You could use it to make tools of
oppression or,
or you could use it to make tools of
amazing growth,
growth and liberation.
And obviously we know which one I'm more
interested in.
Yeah.
Now what,
what is blockchain?
What is blockchain being currently used
for?
Like what,
what different applications,
because it's not just cryptocurrency,
they use a bunch of different things
now,
right?
They are.
I would say it's very early stage.
So probably the how early.
Well the heaviest users of blockchain
now are probably inside large financial
services companies actually.
So if you look at it theory in the
project I mentioned,
so it theory,
ms is run by an open source,
an open foundation,
ethereum foundation.
Then there's a consulting company called
consensus,
which is a totally separate organization
that was founded by Joe Lubin who was
one of the founders of ethereum in the
early days and consensus as you know,
it's funded a bunch of the work within
the ethereum foundation and community,
but consensus has done a lot of
contracts just working with governments
and big companies to customize code
based on the theory to help with their
internal operations.
So actually a lot of the practical value
has been with stuff that isn't in the
public eye that much,
but it's like back end and in,
in,
in inside of companies.
And in terms of practical customer
facing uses of,
of cryptocurrency.
I mean,
no,
the Tron blockchain,
which is different than the theory that
has a bunch of games on it,
for example,
and some online gambling for,
for that matter.
So that,
that's uh,
that that's gotten a lot of users,
but the online games like how,
how do they use that?
Oh,
that's a payment mechanism.
But that there,
this is one of the things there's a lot
of handwringing about in the
cryptocurrency world now is gambling.
No,
just the fact that there aren't that
many big consumer facing uses of,
of,
of cryptocurrency.
I mean,
I mean everyone would,
everyone would like there to be.
That was the idea and this is one of the
things we're aiming at with our
singularity in the project is to,
you know,
we,
we by putting ai on the blockchain in a
highly effective way.
And then we're also,
we have these two tiers.
So we have the singularity net
foundation which is creating this open
source decentralized platform in which
ais can talk to other ais and you know,
like ants in the colony group together
to form smarter and smarter Ai.
Then we're spinning off a company called
the singularity studio,
which will use this decentralized
platform to help big companies integrate
ai into their operation.
So with the singular these studio
company,
we want to get all these big companies
using the ai tools in the singular unit
platform and then we want to drive,
you know,
massive usage of,
of blockchain in the singularity in that
way.
So that's if we're successful with what
we're doing,
this will be,
you know,
within a year from now or something.
By far the biggest usage of blockchain
outside of financial exchange is our use
of blockchain within singularity unit
for ai basically for customers to get
the AI services that they need for their
businesses and then for ais to transact
with other ai is paying other ais for
doing services for them.
Because this,
this,
this I think is is a path forward.
It's like a society and economy of
minds.
It's not like one monolithic Ai.
It's a whole bunch of ais carried by
different people all over the world with
not only are in the marketplace
providing services to customers,
but each ai is asking questions of each
other and then rating each other of how
good they are sending data to each other
and paying each other for the services.
So this,
this like network of ais can emerge and
intelligence on the whole network level
as well as there being intelligence city
in each,
each component.
And is it also fascinating to you that
this is not dependent upon nation?
So this is a world that ever.
I think.
I think that's going to be important
once,
once it starts to get a very high level
of intelligence.
So in the early stages,
okay,
what would it hurt?
Like if,
if I had my own database to central
record of,
of everything.
Like I'm,
I'm an honest person.
I'm not going to rip anyone off,
but once we start to make a transition
towards artificial general intelligence
in this global decentralized network,
which has component ais from every
country on the planet,
like at that point,
once it's clear,
you're getting toward a gi,
a lot of people wanting to step in and
control this thing,
you know,
by law,
by military might,
by any means necessary.
By that point.
The fact that you have this open,
decentralized network under underpinning
everything like this gives an amazing
resilience to what you're doing.
Who can shut down Linux,
you can shut down Bitcoin,
nobody can right you,
you,
you want Ai,
you want ai to be like that.
You want to be a global,
you know,
upsurge of,
of creativity and,
and mutual benefit from people all over
the planet,
which no powerful party can,
can shut down even if they're afraid
that it threatens their hedge.
Amani.
It's very interesting because in a lot
of ways that's a,
it's a very elegant solution to.
What's an obvious problem?
Yeah.
Just as the Internet is an elegant
solution to what's in hindsight and
obvious problem,
right?
It's the distribution of communicate
this,
but this is a extra special to me
because if I was a person running a
country,
I would be terrified of this shit.
I'd be like,
well,
this is what's going to.
That depends which country.
If you're a person running the US or
China,
you,
you would have a different relationship
than if you're a person.
Like I know the Prime Minister of
Ethiopia,
I'll be Ahmed who's a,
has a degree in software engineering and
he,
he loves this,
but of course Ethiopia isn't in any day,
any other countries.
Right.
And they're not in any danger of,
of individually like taking global ai
hedge.
So for the majority of countries in the
world,
they like this for the same reason they
liked Linux,
right?
I mean,
I mean this,
this is something which they have an
equal role to anybody else,
right?
The superpowers,
and you see this among companies also
those.
So a lot of big companies that we're
talking to,
they love the idea of this decentralized
ai fabric because I mean if you're not
Amazon,
Google,
Microsoft,
tencent,
facebook,
so on.
If you're another large corporation,
you don't necessarily want all your ai
and all your data to be going into one
of this handful of large ai companies.
You would rather have it be in the
secure decentralized platform and I mean
this is the same reason that you know,
Cisco and IBM,
they run on Linux.
They don't run on Microsoft.
Right?
So if,
if you're not one of the handful of
large governments or large corporations
that happened to be in a leading role in
the ai ecosystem,
then you would rather have this,
this equalizing in decentralized thing
because everyone gets to play.
Yeah.
What?
What would be the benefit of running on
Linux versus Microsoft?
Well,
you're at the behest of some other big
company.
I mean,
imagine if.
Imagine if you were cisco or gm or
something and all of your internal
machines are all your servers are
running in Microsoft.
What Microsoft increases their price or
are removed some feature.
Then you're totally at their behest and
with ai the same thing is true.
I mean,
if,
if you put all your data in some big
company's server farm and you're
analyzing all your data on their
algorithms and that's critical to your
business model,
what if they change their ai algorithm
in some way?
Then I'm in the.
Then your business is,
is basically controlled by this other
company.
So I'm in having a decentralized
platform in which you're,
you know,
an equal participant along with
everybody else is,
is actually a much better position to be
in.
And I think this,
this I think is why we can succeed with
this plan of having this decentralized
singularity net platform than the
singular,
the studio enterprise software company
which mediates between the decentralized
platform and big companies.
I mean it's because most companies and
governments in the world,
you know,
they don't want hedge.
I'm one of a few large governments and
corporations each either.
And you can see this in,
in a lot of voids.
You can see this embrace of,
of Linux and etherium by many large
corporations.
You can also see like in a different
way,
you know,
the Indian government,
they rejected an offer by facebook to
give free internet to all Indians
because facebook wants to give like
mobile phones that would get free
internet,
but only to access facebook,
right?
India is like,
well no,
no,
thanks.
Right,
and India is now giving.
They're now creating laws that any
internet company that collects data
about Indian people has to store that
data in India,
which is so the Indian government can
subpoena that data when,
when,
when they want to.
So,
so you're,
you're already seeing a bunch of
resistance against hedge pneumoniae by a
few large governments or large large
corporations by other companies and
other governments.
And I think this is very positive and is
one of the factors that can,
that can foster the foster,
the growth of a decentralized ai
ecosystem.
Is it fair to say that the future of ai
is severely dependent upon who launches
it first?
Like whoever,
whether it's singularity,
the bottom line is official general
intelligence.
The bottom line is as a scientist after
say,
we don't know,
right?
It could be there's an end state that
Agi will just self organize into almost
independent of the initial condition,
but we don't know and given that we
don't know,
I'm operating under the,
you know,
the,
your ristick assumption that if the
first ai is beneficially oriented,
if it's controlled in the participatory
democratic way and if it's oriented at
least substantially towards like doing
good things for humans,
I'm operating under the eucharistic
assumption that this is going to bias
things in a positive,
positive direction.
I'm in chorus in the absence of
knowledge to the contrary.
But if the Chinese government launches
one,
they're controlling.
We don't pop it off first.
I mean,
I liked the idea that you're saying
though,
that it might organize itself.
I mean understand the Chinese government
also.
They want,
they want the best for the Chinese
people that they don't,
they don't want to make the terminator
either.
Right.
So,
uh,
I mean,
I think even even Donald Trump was not
my favorite person doesn't actually want
to kill off everyone on the planet.
Right.
So he might,
if they talk shit about them.
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
You know,
you never know it was just him.
I told you all.
I mean,
I,
I think,
you know,
I wouldn't say we're necessarily doomed
if big governments and big companies are
the ones that develop ai or Agi first
big government,
big companies essentially developed the
internet.
Right.
And it got away from them.
That's right.
So there's a lot of uncertainty all
around,
but I think,
you know,
it behooves us to do what we can to bias
the odds in our favor based on our
current understanding.
And I mean toward that end we're
developing,
you know,
open source,
decentralized ai and singularity in that
process.
So if you would explain some singularity
net and what,
what you guys are actively involved in.
Sure,
sure.
So singularity and that in itself is a
platform that allows many different ais
to operate on it and these ais can offer
services to anyone who requests services
of the network and they can also request
an offer services among each other.
So it's,
it's both just an online marketplace for
ais,
much like no the apple app store or
Google play store,
but for ais rather than phone ups,
but the difference is the different ais
in here can outsource work to each other
and talk to each other and that gives a
new dimension to it,
right where you can have,
we think of as a society or economy of
minds and it gives the possibility that
this whole society of interacting ais
which are then they're paying each other
for transactions with our,
our digital money or are cryptographic
token,
which is called the Agi token.
So these ais which are paying each other
and rating each other of how good they
are,
sending data and questions and answers
to each other,
can self organize into some overall ai
mind?
No.
We're building this platform and then
we're plugging into it to seed it.
A bunch of ais of our own creation.
So I've been working for 10 years on
this open source ai project called open
cog,
which is oriented toward building
general intelligence and we're putting a
bunch of ai agents based on the open cog
platform into this singularity in the
network and you know if we're successful
in a couple of years,
the ais that we put on there will be a
tiny minority of what's in there,
just like the apps made by Google or a
small minority of the apps in,
in the,
in the Google play store.
Right.
But my hope is that these open cog,
ai agents within the larger pool of Ais
and the singularity net can sort of
serve as the general intelligence corps
because the open ai agents are really
good at abstraction and generalization
and creativity.
We can put another,
a bunch of other ais in there that are
good at highly specific for forms of
learning,
like predicting financial time series,
curing diseases,
answering people's questions,
organizing your inbox so you can have
the interaction of these specialized
ais.
And then more general purpose.
You know,
abstraction and creativity based.
Ai is like open cog agents all
interacting together in this
decentralized platform and then you
know,
the beauty of it is like some,
some 15 year old genius and Azerbaijan
or the Congo can put some brilliant ai
into this network.
If it's really smart,
it will get rated highly by the other
ais for,
for,
for its work,
helping them do their thing.
Then it can get replicated over and over
again across many servers.
Suddenly a this 16 year old kid from
Azerbaijan or the Congo could become
wealthy from,
from their copies of their ai providing
services to other people's ais and be,
you know,
the creativity in their mind is out
there and is infusing this global aid
network with some,
some new intellectual DNA that you know,
never would have been found by a ten
cent or a google because they're not
going to hire some Congolese teenager
who may have a brilliant ai idea.
That's amazing.
So this is all ongoing right now.
And the singularity that you guys are
using,
the.
The way I've understood that term,
correct me if I'm wrong,
is that it's going to be the one
innovation or one invention that
essentially changes everything forever.
The singularity isn't necessarily one
invention.
The singularity,
which is coined by Wong,
is coined by my friend Vernor vinge,
who's another guy you should interview.
He's in San Diego to the other guys.
The other brilliant guys down there,
but vernor vinge military down there.
Yeah,
vernor vinge.
Uh,
he,
he was a math professor.
The San Diego University actually,
but well known science fiction writer.
His book a fire upon the deep,
one of the great science fiction books.
So v I n g Vernor Vinge,
GE,
brilliant guy,
fire upon the deep Vernor v e r o v e R.
Yeah,
he's brilliant.
He coined the term technological
singularity back in the 19 eighties,
but he,
he opted not to become a,
a pundit about it because he'd rather
more science fiction.
That's interesting.
Than a science fiction author.
Ray Kurzweil,
who's also a good friend of mine.
I mean Ray Ray took that term and
fleshed it out and did a bunch of data
analytics.
Trying to pinpoint like when it's,
it would happen,
but the basic concept of the
technological singularity is a point in
time when technological advance occurs
so rapidly that the human mind,
it appears almost instantaneous.
Like,
like imagine 10 new Nobel Prize winning
discoveries every second or something.
Right?
So this is similar to the concept of the
intelligence explosion that was posited
by the mathematician,
Ij good in 1965.
What Ij good said.
Then the year before I was born was the
first truly intelligent machine will be
the last invention that humanity needs
to make rent.
So this is an intelligence explosion is
another term for basically the same
thing as the technological singularity,
but it's not just about Ai.
Ai is just probably the most powerful
technology driving it.
I mean there's ai,
there's nanotechnology,
there's femto technology which will be
building things from elementary
particles.
I mean there's life extension,
genetic engineering,
mind uploading,
which is like reading the mind that if
your brain and putting it into a
machine,
you know,
there's advanced energy technologies so
that all these different things are
expected to advance at around the same
time.
And they have many ways to boost each
other,
right?
Because the,
you know,
the better Aiu have,
your ai can then invent new ways of
doing nanotech tech and biology.
But if you invent amazing new nanotech
in quantum computing,
that can make your ai smarter.
On the other hand,
if you,
if you could crack how the human brain
works and genetic engineering to upgrade
human intelligence,
those smarter than humans can then make
better eyes and nano technology,
right?
So there's so many virtuous cycles among
these different technologies.
The more you advance in any of them,
the more you're going to advance and in,
in all of them.
And it's the coming together of all of
these that's going to create,
you know,
radical abundance and the technological
singularity so that,
that term,
which Vernor vinge,
he introduced ray Ray Kurzweil borrowed
for his books and further singular the
university educational program.
And then we borrowed that for our
singularity net,
like decentralized blockchain based ai
platform and in our singularity studio
enterprise software company.
Now I want to talk to you about two
parts of what you just said.
One being the possibility that one day
we can upload our mind will make copies
of our mind.
You're up for it to upload into here.
I could use a little Joe Rogan them on
my phone.
You can just call me dude,
the organic version,
but the what do you think that that's a
real possibility inside of our lifetime
that we can map out the human mind to
the point where we can essentially
recreate it,
but if you do recreate it without all
the biological urges and the human
reward systems that are built in,
what the fuck are we?
I mean,
well that's a different question I
think.
What is your mind?
Well,
I,
I think that those two things that are
needed for,
let's say,
let's say human body uploading to
simplify things,
body uploading.
There are two things that are needed.
One thing is a better computing
infrastructure.
Then we have no to host the uploaded
body and,
and the other thing is a better scanning
technology because right now we don't
have a way to scan the molecular
structure of your body without like
freezing you,
slicing you in scanning you,
which you probably don't want that at
this point in time,
right yet.
So assuming both those are solved and
you can then recreate in some computer
simulation,
you know,
uh,
an accurate simulate Chromo of,
of,
of what you are,
right?
That's where I'm getting this,
where I'm getting at an accurate
simulacrum is,
that's getting weird because the
biological variability of human beings,
we vary day to day.
We're very dependent upon it.
And your simulator and will also vary
day to day.
So the DVA program and into have flaws
because while we vary dependent upon how
much sleep we get,
whether or not we're feeling sick,
whether we're lonely.
So all these,
if you're upload,
we're an accurate copy of you than the
simulation.
Hosting your upload would need to have
an accurate simulation of the laws of
bio physics and chemistry that allow
your body to,
you know,
evolve from one second to the neck.
My concern is though would change second
by second,
just like just like you do and it would
divert from me.
Right?
So I mean after an hour it will be a
little different.
After a year it might've gone in,
in a quite different direction for you.
Probably a month.
Some Super God monk living on the top of
a mountain somewhere in a year.
Have it,
keeps the whole right.
Depends on what virtual world it's
living in.
True.
I mean if it's living in a virtual
world,
your world will be a virtual world.
If we're not talking about the potential
of downloading this.
Again,
in sort of into a biologic,
there's a lot of possibilities,
right?
I mean you,
you,
you could,
you could upload into a Joe Rogan living
in the virtual world and then just
create your own fantasy universe or you
or you could three d print and alternate
synthetic body.
Right?
I mean,
once you,
once you have the ability to manipulate
molecules at will,
the scope of possibilities becomes much
greater than we're used to.
Thinking about.
My question is do,
do we replicate flaws?
Do we replicate depression?
Of course,
but we knew that when we want to cure
depression,
so depression it.
Here's the interesting thing.
Once once we have you in a digital form,
then it's very programmable,
so then the dopamine and Serotonin,
then you can change what you want and
then you have a whole different set of
issues.
Right?
Yeah.
Because once you've changed,
I mean suppose you make a fork of
yourself and then you manipulate it in a
certain way and then after a few hours
you're like,
well I don't.
I don't much like this.
A new joe here.
Maybe we should roll back that change,
but the new joe is like,
well,
I liked myself very well.
Thank you.
So then,
yeah,
there's a lot of issues that that will
come up once we can write,
modify,
and reprogram ourselves to the point
that the ramifications of these
decisions are almost insurmountable d
once,
once the ball gets rolling.
Well,
the modifications of the ramifications
of these decisions are going to be very
interesting to explore.
Yes,
you're super positive band,
super positive of your optimism.
Many bad things will happen.
Many good things will happen.
That's a very.
That's a very easy prediction to me.
Okay.
I see what you're saying.
Yeah.
I've just a one day thing.
Think about like world travel,
like hundreds of years ago,
most people didn't travel more than a
very short distance from their home and
you could say,
well,
okay,
what if.
What if people could travel all over the
world,
right?
Like what horrible things could happen.
They would lose their culture like they
might go marry someone from from a
random tribe.
You can get killed in the Arctic region
or something.
A lot of bad things can happen when you
travel far from your home.
A lot of good things can happen and the
ultimately the ramifications were not
foreseen by people 500 years ago.
I'm in,
we're going into a lot of new domains.
We can't see the details of the pluses
and minuses that are going to unfold.
A W,
it would behoove us to simply become
comfortable with radical uncertainty
because otherwise we're going to
confront it anyway and we're just going
to be nervous.
So it's just inevitable this,
this,
uh,
it's almost inevitable.
I mean,
of course.
Sorry.
Any natural disaster.
Yeah.
I mean,
of course trump could start a nuclear
war and then we're resetting to ground
zero where we get hit by an asteroid,
right?
Yeah.
I mean,
so barring a catastrophic outcome,
I believe a technological singularity is
essentially inevitable.
There's a radical uncertainty attached
to this.
On the other hand,
you know,
in as much as we humans can know
anything,
it would seem common sensically there's
the ability to bias this in a positive
rather than the negative direction.
We should be spending more of our
attention on doing that rather than,
for instance,
advertising spying and making chocolate
chocolates and all the other things
people are doing now.
I mean,
it's prevalent,
it's everywhere,
but I mean how many people are actually
at the helm of that as opposed to how
many people are working on various
aspects of technology all across the
planet.
It's a small group and in comparison,
working on explicitly bringing about the
singularity is a small group.
On the other hand,
supporting technologies is a very large
group,
so think about like gps.
Where did they come from?
Accelerating gaming,
right?
Lo and behold,
they're amazingly useful for training
neural net models,
which is the one among many important
types of Ai,
right?
So a large amount of the planet's
resources are now getting spent on
technologies that are indirectly
supporting these singular attarian
technology.
So as another example,
like microarrays and let you measure the
expression level of genes,
how much each gene is doing in your body
at each point in time.
These were originally developed,
you know,
as an outgrowth of printing technology.
Then instead of squirting ink after
metrics figured out you could squirt
DNA.
Right?
So I mean the amount of technology
specifically oriented toward the
singularity doesn't have to be large
because the overall spectrum of
supporting technologies can be subverted
in that direction.
Do you,
do you have any concerns at all about a
virtual world?
I mean,
we may be anyone right now,
man,
you know that's true.
But as far as my problem is,
I want to find that programmer and get
them to make more attractive people.
I would say that that's part of the
reason why I attracted people are so
interesting as that they're unique and
rare problems with calling everything
beautiful.
Yeah.
You know,
everything we're saying,
everything is generous.
Beautiful.
I was like,
well,
you just have to get realistic.
If I get in the right frame of mind that
can find anything beautiful.
Well you could find it unique and
interesting.
Oh,
I can find anything but.
Okay.
I guess I guess.
But in terms of like.
Yeah,
I guess it's subjective,
right?
Really it is.
We're talking about beauty,
right?
Yeah.
Now,
but very existential angst just on the,
the.
When people sit and think about the
pointlessness of our own existence,
like we are these finite beings that are
clinging to a balls.
It spins a thousand miles an hour
hurling through infinity.
And what's the point like?
There's a lot of that that goes around
already.
We've.
We create an artificial environment that
we can literally somehow
under the download a version of us and
it exists and this block chain created
or or powered weird fucking simulation
world.
What would be,
I mean
it be the point of what I really
believe,
which is a bit personal and maybe
different than many of my colleagues.
What I really believe is that these
advancing technologies are going to lead
us to unlock many different states of
consciousness and experience than,
than most people are,
are,
are currently aware of are I mean you,
you,
you say we're,
we're just an insignificant species on
the,
on the,
you know,
a speck of rock hurtling in the other
space were insignificant.
There's people that have existential
acts because they wonder about what the
purpose was.
I go that category tend to feel like we
understand almost nothing about who and
what we are and our knowledge about the
universe is far small,
extremely minuscule.
I mean,
if anything,
I look at things from more of a Buddhist
or phenomenological way,
like the sense perceptions and then out
of those sense perceptions,
models arise and accumulate including a
model of the self and the model of the
body and the model of the physical world
out there and by the time you get to
planets and stars and blockchains,
you're building like hypothetical models
on top of hypothetical models and then
you know,
we're,
we're building intelligent machines and
mind uploading machines and virtual
realities.
We're going to radically transform,
you know,
our whole state of consciousness,
our understanding of what mind and
matter are.
Our experience of our own selves or even
whether it's self exists.
And I think ultimately the state of
consciousness of a human being like 100
years from now after a technological
singularity is going to bear very little
resemblance to the states of
consciousness we have now.
We're just going to.
We're going to see a much wider universe
in any of us know,
imagine,
imagine to exist.
No,
this is my own personal view of things.
You,
you,
you don't have to agree with that.
To think the technological singularity
will be valuable,
but that is how I look.
I know Ray Kurzweil and I agree there's
going to be a technological singularity
within decades at most and ray and I
agree that,
you know,
if we biased technology development,
we can very lightly,
you know,
guide this to be a,
a world of abundance and benefit for
humans as well as ais.
But Ray is a bit more of a down to Earth
empiricists than I am lucky.
He thinks we understand more about the
universe right now than that than I do.
So.
I mean there's a wide spectrum of views
that are rational and sensible to have.
But my own view is we understand really,
really little of what we are and what,
what this world is.
And this is part of my own personal
quest for wanting to upgrade my brain
and wanting to create artificial
intelligences is like I've always been
driven above all else.
Borrowing to understand everything I can
about the world.
So I'm in.
I've studied every kind of science and
engineering and social science and read
every kind of literature,
but in the end the scope of human
understanding is clearly very small,
although at least we're smart enough to
understand how little we understand,
which I think my,
my dog doesn't understand.
He understands.
Right?
So and even like my 10 month old son,
he understands a little.
He understands which is interesting,
right?
Because he's because he's ready to
because he's also a human.
Right.
So I think,
I mean,
everything we think and believe now is
going to seem absolutely absurd to us
after there's a singularity.
We're just going to look back and laugh
in a warm hearted way as all the
incredibly silly things we were thinking
and doing back when we were trapped in
our,
in our,
you know,
our primitive biological brains and
bodies.
Stunning attack.
In your opinion or your assessment is
somewhere less than a 100 years away
from now.
Yeah.
That's requires exponential thinking.
Right?
Because if you.
It's hard to wrap your head around,
right?
I don't know.
It's immediate.
It's immediate for me to wrap my head
around,
but for a lot of people that you
explained it to him,
I'm sure that that that's a little bit
of a roadblock.
No,
it is.
It is.
It took me some time to have my parents
drop their heads around it because they
didn't.
They're not,
they're not technologists,
but I mean I find if you get people to
pay attention and sort of lead them
through all the supporting evidence,
most people can comprehend these ideas
reasonably well just to computers from
1960,
just hard to grasp.
It's hard to grab people's attention
then.
Yeah.
Mobile phones and made a big difference.
Like I spent a lot of time in Africa,
in Addis Ababa in Ethiopia where we have
a large ai development office and you
know,
the fact that mobile phones and then
smartphones have rolled out so quickly
even in rural Africa and if it's such a
transformative impact.
I mean this is a metaphor that lets
people understand the speed with what's
exponential change can happen.
When you talk about yourself,
when you talk about consciousness and
how you interface with the world,
how do you see this?
I mean,
when,
when you,
that we might be living in a simulation.
Do you actually entertain that?
Oh yeah,
you do.
I'm in the,
I think the word simulation is probably
wrong,
but yet the idea of an empirical,
you know,
materialist physical world is almost
certainly wrong also.
So I mean,
that's so.
Well,
again,
if you go back to a phenomenal view,
I mean you could look at the mind this
primary and you know,
your mind is building the world,
uh,
as,
as a model,
as a simple explanation of it,
of its perceptions.
On the other hand then what is the mind?
The self is also a model that gets,
that gets built up out of its
perceptions.
But then if I accept that your mind has
some fundamental existence also based on
this sort of feeling that you're like a
mind,
there are minds are working together to
build each other and,
and,
and to build this world.
And there there's a,
there's a,
there's a whole different way of,
of thinking about reality in terms of
first and second person experience
rather than these empiricist views like
this is a computer simulation or
something.
Right.
But you still agree that this is a
physical reality that we exist in,
or do you not?
What does that word mean?
That's a weird word,
right?
It is women.
Is it your interpretation of reality?
If you look in,
in modern physics,
even quantum mechanics,
there's something called the relational
interpretation of quantum mechanics,
which says that there's no sense in
thinking about an observed entity,
you should only think about an observed
comma observer pair.
Like there's no sense to think about
some thing except from the perspective
of some observer.
So that's,
that's even true within our best current
theory of modern physics as,
as induced from empirical empirical
observations.
Right?
In a pragmatic sense,
you know,
if you take a plane and fly to China,
you actually land in China,
I guess.
You guess,
why don't you live there?
I live in Hong Kong.
Yeah,
well,
close to it.
I,
I have an unusual state of
consciousness.
That's what I'm trying to get at.
If you think about it,
like how do you know that you're not a
brain floating in a vet somewhere which
is being fed illusions by certain evil
scientist and two seconds from now he's
going to pull this simulated world
disappears and you realize you're just a
brain in a vat again,
you,
you don't know that you run on your own
personal experiences of falling in love
with a woman and moving to another,
but these may all be put into my brain
by the evil scientist.
How do we know?
But they're,
they're very consistent.
Are they not the,
the possibly illusory and implanted
memories are very consistent.
I guess.
I guess my own state of mind is I'm
always sort of acutely aware that this
simulation might all disappear at,
at,
at any one moment,
uh,
uncertain,
acutely aware of this consciously on an
everyday basis.
Pretty much really,
really?
Why is that?
That doesn't seem to make sense.
I mean,
it's,
it's pretty,
it's pretty rock solid.
It's here everyday.
So you're possibly implanted memories
led you to believe?
Yes,
possibly.
Implanting memories need to believe that
this life is incredibly consistent.
This is incredibly consistent.
This is your problem of induction,
right?
From philosophy class and it's not and
it's not solved with you in a conceptual
sense.
I get,
I just feel this philosophy,
but you,
you embody it,
right?
This is something you carry with you all
the time.
Yeah.
On the other hand I'm in,
I'm still carrying out many actions with
longterm planning in mind or like I've
been,
I've been working on designing ai for 30
years and I'd be designing it inside.
I might be and I'm working on building
the same ai system,
you know,
since we started open cog in 2008,
but that's using codes from 2001 I was
building with my colleagues even even
earlier.
So I'm in.
I think longterm planning is very
natural to me but.
But nevertheless I don't.
I don't want to make any assumptions
about what sort of,
what sort of simulation or reality that
we're living in.
And I think everyone's gonna hit a lot
of surprises when once simulate singular
they can,
you know,
we,
we may find out that this hat is a
messenger from after the singularity,
so it traveled back through time to
implant into my brain.
The idea of how to create ai and bring
it into existence.
What?
Whoo.
It.
Oh,
that was mckenna that had this idea.
That was something in the theater tried.
Yes.
To this attract terence.
Terence Mckenna.
Yeah.
He had the same idea,
like some posts,
posts singularity intelligence,
which actually was living outside of
time somehow is reaching back and
putting into his brain the idea of how
to bring about the singularity novelty
itself as being drawn into this.
Yeah.
There were the timewave zero that was
going to reach the apex in 2012.
That didn't work.
No,
he died before that.
So he didn't get a chance to hear what
his,
what his idea was.
He,
uh,
you know,
I had some funny interactions with some
Mckenna fanatic 2012 whites.
This was about 2007 or so.
This guy came to Washington where I was
living then.
And he brought my friend Hugo de Garis,
another crazy ai researcher with them,
and he's like,
the singularity is going to happen in
2012 concerns.
Mckenna said,
so I need to be sure it's a good
singularity so you can't move to China
then it will be a bad singularity.
So we have.
So we have to get the US government to
give billions of dollars to your
research to guarantee that the
singularity in 2012 is a good
singularity.
Right?
So he,
he led us around to meet with these
generals and various high who has an in
DC to get them to fund Hugo.
The girl says in my ai research to
guarantee I wouldn't move to China and
Hugo wouldn't move to China.
So the US would create a positive
singularity.
Now the effort failed.
You Go,
you go move to China.
Then I moved there some years after.
So then this,
this 2012,
he went back to his apartment.
He made a,
a mix of 50 percent vodka,
50 percent robitussin pm.
You'd like drank it down.
He's like,
all right,
I'm going to have my own personal
singularity right here,
and I haven't talked to that guy since
2012 either to see what he thinks about
the singularity.
Not happening then,
but Terence Mckenna had a lot of
interesting ideas,
but I felt,
you know,
he,
he mixed up this,
the symbolic with the empirical more,
more than than I would,
I would prefer to do.
I mean,
I mean it's,
it's very interesting to look at these
abstract symbols and cosmic insights,
but then you have to sort of put your
scientific mindset on and say,
well,
what's a metaphor and what's,
what's like an actual empirical
scientific truth within,
within the scientific domain.
And now he's a little bit half baked.
Right.
I mean the whole idea was based on the
teaching.
He had a,
he was a mushroom trip.
IOWASCA was.
No,
Oscar I think led him to the teaching.
I don't believe it was maybe.
I mean it was silicide assignment.
It might've been.
Okay.
Yeah,
I mean,
I know you know his brother,
Dennis Mckenna.
Very well.
Yeah.
So,
so they.
Yeah,
you read.
Thanks.
At the time we have zero was a little
bit nonsense,
but he read their,
their book with true hallucinations.
Yeah,
right.
The very,
very,
very interesting stuff and there is a
mixture of deep insight there with a
bunch of interesting metaphorical
thinking problem and get involved in
psychedelic drugs.
It's hard to differentiate like what
makes sense,
what's,
what's this unbelievably powerful
insight and what is just some crazy idea
you can learn to make that
differentiation.
You think so?
Yes.
Yeah.
But,
but,
uh,
yeah,
I'm in granted,
Terence Mckenna probably took more
psychedelic drugs then I would generally
recommend also he,
he was speaking
all the time and there's something that
I can attest to from podcasting all the
time.
Sometimes you just talking,
you don't know what the fuck you're
saying.
You know,
and you become a prisoner to your words
and in a lot of ways,
uh,
you,
you get locked up in this idea of
expressing this thought that may or may
not be viable.
I'm not sure that he was after empirical
truth in the same sense that say ray
Kurzweil when ray is saying we're going
to get human level ai in 2029 and then
you know,
massively superhuman ai in a singularity
in 20,
45.
I mean ray ray is very literal.
Like he's plotting charts,
right?
Terrence.
Terrence was thinking on an
impressionistic and and symbolic level
is a.
It was a bit different.
So you have to take that in a poetic
sense rather than in the literal sense.
And yeah,
I think it's very interesting to go back
and forth between the,
you know,
the symbolic and poetic domain and the
either concrete science and engineering
domain,
but it's also valuable to,
to be able to draw that,
draw that distinction,
right?
Because you can draw a lot of insight
from the kind of thinking Terence
Mckenna was,
was doing and certainly if you explore
psychedelics,
you can gain a lot of insights into how
the mind and universe work.
But then when,
when you put on your science and
engineering mindset,
you want to be rigorous about which
insights do you take and which ones do
you do throw out and ultimately you want
that you want to proceed on the basis
of,
of what works and what doesn't.
Right.
I mean that Dennis was pretty strong on
the terence was a bit less than that
empirical direction.
Well,
the dentist actually career scientists,
um,
how,
how many people involved in artificial
intelligence are also educated in the
ways of psychedelics.
Yeah.
That's all you have to say is that
unfortunately,
the illegal nature of these things,
it's a little hard to pin down,
I would say before the recent generation
of people going into ai because it was a
way to make money in the AI field was
incredibly full of really,
really interesting people and you know,
deep thinkers about,
about the mind.
And in the last few years,
of course ai has replaced like business
school is what your grandma wants you to
do,
to have a good career.
So I mean,
you're getting,
you're getting a lot of people into ai
just because it's financial environment,
it's,
it's cool,
it's financially viable,
it's popular because I can,
you know,
in our generation,
ai was not,
ai was not what your grandma wants you
to do so as to be able to buy a nice
house for the family.
Right.
So you got into it because you really
were curious about how the mind works
and of course many people played with
psychedelics because it also,
they were curious about,
you know,
what it was teaching them about,
about how their mind works.
Yeah.
I had a nice long conversation with Ray
Kurzweil and we talked for about an hour
and a half and it was for the Song Scifi
show that I was doing at the time and
some of his ideas.
He has this,
uh,
this,
this is number that they had people
throw about like 20,
42,
right?
Isn't that,
is that still 2045,
a 45 now.
Now you're being the optimist.
Now you're combining that with Douglas
off status for the two,
which is the answer to the universe.
No,
the 42 thing was the New York conference
that will take place in 2,245.
Was it?
I was at that conference that was
organized by Demetrius Gov is another
friend of mine from rush something off
by three.
It's 2045.
So that was,
that was,
that was raised prognostication.
Why,
why that year?
Um,
he did some current methylations yeah.
I mean he looked at Moore's law.
He looks in the advanced and the
accuracy of brain scanning and look at
the events of computer memory,
the miniaturization of various devices
and like plugging a whole bunch of these
curves.
That was the best guests that he came up
with.
What course?
There's some confidence interval around
that.
What do you see as potential monkey
wrenches that could be thrown into all
this innovation?
Like what were the,
were the pitfalls?
Well,
I mean the pitfall is always the one
that you,
that you don't sit you very.
I'm in,
of course it's possible there's some
science or engineering obstacle that
we're not foreseeing right now.
I mean it,
it,
it's also possible that all major
nations are overtaken by like a
religious fanatics or something which
which,
which slows down development somewhat a
few thousand years.
I think it would just be by a few
decades,
but yeah,
I mean in terms of scientific pitfalls,
I mean one possibility which I don't
think is luckily one pass,
but it's possible.
One possibility is human,
like intelligence requires advanced
quantum computers,
like it can't be done on the standard
classical digital computer.
Do you think that's the case?
No,
but on the other hand,
because there is no evidence that human
cognition relies on quantum effects in
the human brain,
like based on everything we know about
neuroscience now,
it seems not to be the case.
Like there's no evidence it's the case,
but it's possible.
It's the case because we don't
understand everything about how the
brain works.
The thing is,
even if that's true,
like there's loads of amazing research
going on in quantum computing and so
we're going to have,
you know,
you'll probably have a qp new quantum
processing unit in,
in,
in your phone and like a 10 to 20 years
or something.
Right.
So I'm in,
so that would,
that might throw off 20 slash 45 date,
but in a historical sense it doesn't
change the picture,
like I've got a bunch of research
singing on my hard drive on how we
improve open cogs,
ai using quantum computers once we have
better quantum computers.
Right?
So there's,
there could be other things like that
which are technical roadblocks that
we're not seeing now,
but I really doubt those are going to
delay things by more than like a decade
or two or something.
On the other hand,
things could also go faster than than,
than raised prediction,
which is,
which is what I'm pushing towards.
So what are you pushing towards?
What do you think I would like to get a
human level general intelligence in five
to seven years from now?
Wow.
I don't think that's bad by any means
impossible because I think our open cog
design is adequate to do it,
but I mean it takes a lot of people
working coherently for awhile to build
something,
something big like this,
being in a physical form like a robot.
It'll be in the compute cloud can use
many robots as,
as user interfaces,
but the same ai control.
Many different robots actually and many
other sensors and systems besides
robots.
I mean I think the human like form
factor like we have with Sophia and our
other Henson robots,
the human like form factor is really
valuable as a tool for allowing the
cloud based ai mind to,
you know,
engage with humans and to learn human
cultures and values.
Because I mean getting back to what we
were discussing it at the beginning of
this chat,
you know,
the best way to get human values and
culture into the AI is for humans and ai
is to enter into many shared,
you know,
like social,
emotional,
embodied situations together.
So having a human embodiment for the AI
is important for that.
Like I can look you in the eye,
you can share your facial expressions,
it can bond with you,
it can see the way you react when you
see like a sick person by the side of
the road,
there's something right and,
and you know,
can see you ask the ai to get,
give the homeless person the $20 or
something.
I mean the ai understands what money is
and understands what that action means.
Some in interacting with an ai in human
life form is going to be valuable as a
learning mechanism for the ai and as a
learning mechanism for people to get
more comfortable with ais.
But I mean ultimately one advantage of
being,
you know,
a digital mind is you don't have to be
why the Dandy particular embodiment.
Now I can go between many different
bodies and they can transfer knowledge
between the many different bodies that
it's occupied.
Well,
that's the real concern that the people
that are,
that have this dystopian view of
artificial intelligence hub is that ai
may already exist and it's just sitting
there waiting to Americans.
Too many bad movies in Asia and Asia.
Everyone thinks ai will be our friend
and will love us and help us.
Yeah,
we're very,
very,
very much.
That's what you're pumping out there.
No,
that's been as their philosophies I
guess.
I mean you look in Japanese anime.
I mean there's been ais and robots for a
long time.
They're usually people's friends.
There's dystopian aesthetic and it's the
same in China and Korea.
The general guests there is an ais and
robots will be people's friends and
will,
will help people and then some other
general guests in America is.
It's going to be some big nasty Robo
soldier marching down the street
beyond musk who we rely upon no smarter
than us and he's fucking terrified of
it.
Sam Harris terrified of it for very
smart people that just think it could
really be a huge disaster for the human
race.
I guess not just bad because know it's a
cultural thing because the oriental
culture is sort of social good oriented.
Most orientals think a lot in terms of
what's good for the family or the
society as opposed to themselves
personally and so they just make the
default assumption that ais are going to
be the same way whereas Americans are
more like me,
me,
me oriented and I say that as an
American as well and where they sort of
assumed that ais are going to be
possible.
Right.
Well whatever is in your mind,
you impose on this ai when we don't
actually know what it's going to become
bright,
but there it is.
There are potential negative aspects.
Of course,
artificial intelligence deciding that
we're the logical and unnecessary.
Well we are a logical and unnecessary
yes,
but that doesn't mean that ai should be
badly disposed towards us.
I'm in.
Did you see x Mokena?
I did you like it?
Sure.
It was a copy of our robot.
So it was,
I mean our robots.
So fear looks exactly like the robot in
the American.
So it was a good video that online.
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
Would tell Jamie how do you get the good
video or just search for Sophia Hanson?
Robot on Google?
Yeah,
how advanced is Sophia right now?
I mean how many different iterations
have there been?
There's been something like 16,
so fear robots made so far.
We're moving towards scalable
manufacturer over the next couple of
years,
so right now she's going around sort of
as an ambassador for humanoid robot
kind,
giving,
giving speeches and talks and various
places.
So she.
So fear used to be called eva or we had
a robot like the current Sophia that was
called Eva and then x meshing that came
out with the robot called Eva that
exactly like the robot that that my
colleague David Hanson and I made.
I think it's a coincidence.
Of course not.
They just copy that.
I mean of course the body they have is
better and the AI is better in the movie
than our robot ai is.
So we changed the name to Sophia,
which means wisdom in instead.
Was it freaky watching that though with
the name eva?
The thing is that the moral of that
movie is just if you know,
if associate path raises a robot with an
abusive interaction,
it may come out to be a sociopath or
psychopath.
So let's,
let's,
let's not do that.
Right.
Let's raise our robots with love and
compassion.
Yeah.
You see,
the thing is that we have.
I haven't seen this particular
great.
What is she saying?
She's not happy she was on Jimmy Fallon
or something.
That's David.
This scope.
How much is it actually interacting with
them?
It has a chat system.
It really has a nice ring.
Now I have to make clear that I didn't.
So yeah,
so fear we can run using many different
ai system so that there's a chat bot
which is sort of like,
you know,
Alexa or google now or something,
but with a bit a bit better ai and
interaction with,
with no emotion and face recognition and
so forth.
So it's not human level ai,
but it is responding to a no.
It understands what you say and it comes
up with an answer and it can look you in
the eye and make more than one language.
Well,
right now we can load it in English
mode,
Chinese motor Russian mode and there's
sort of different different software
packages and we also use her sometimes
to experiment with their open cogs
system and singularity now so we can.
We can use the robot as a research
platform for exploring some of our more
advanced ai tools and then there's a
simpler chatbots software which is used
for appearances like,
like,
like that one and in the next year we
want to roll out more of our advanced
research software from open coggin
singularity that rolled out more of that
inside these robots,
which is one among many applications
we're looking at with our singular unit
platform.
I want to get you back in here in like a
year and find out where everything is
because I feel like we need someone like
you to sort of let us know where,
where it's at,
when it's run,
when the switches about to flip.
It seems to me that it might happen so
quickly and the change might take place
so rapidly that we really will have no
idea what's happening before it happens.
We think about the singularity,
like it's going to be some huge like
physical event and suddenly everything
turns purple in this cover with diamonds
or something.
Right?
But I mean there's a lot voice.
Something like this could unfold,
so I can imagine that with our
singularity,
not decentralized network,
you know,
we get an ai that's smarter than humans
and can create a new scientific
discovery.
The Nobel prize level,
every minute there's something that that
doesn't mean this ai is going to
immediately like refactor all matter
into,
into images of a bucket head or do
something run and I'm in.
I mean if the AI has some caring and
wisdom and compassion,
then whatever changes happen,
but it's the artist human
characteristics,
not necessarily in fact human passion
just as humans are either the most
intelligent nor the most compassionate
possible creatures that that's.
That's pretty clear.
If you look at the world around us and
one of one of our projects that we're
doing with this Sofia robot is aimed
exactly at ai.
Compassion's this has got the loving ai
project and we're using this sophia
robot as a,
as a meditation assistant.
So,
so we're,
we're using so fear to help people get
into deep meditative trance states and
help them breathe deeply and uh,
achieve more,
more positive state of being.
And part of the goal there is to help
people part of the goal as,
as the AI gets more and more
intelligent.
You sort of getting the ai locked into a
very positive,
reflective and compassionate state.
And I think,
I think there's a lot of things in the
human psyche and evolutionary history
that hold us back from being optimally
compassionate and that if we create the
ai in the right way,
it will be not only much more
intelligent,
much more compassionate than than human
beings are.
And I mean this,
we'd better do that like a.
otherwise the human race is probably
screwed to be blunt.
I mean,
if I think human beings are creating a
lot of other technologies now with a lot
of power,
we're creating synthetic biology,
we're creating nano technology,
you know,
we're creating smaller and smaller
nuclear weapons and we can't control
their proliferation.
We're poisoning our environment.
I think if we can't create something
that's normally more intelligent but
more wise and compassionate than we are,
we're probably going to destroy
ourselves by some method or another.
I mean,
with something like Donald trump
becoming president.
You see what happens when this,
you know,
primitive hindbrain and when our are
unchecked,
you know,
mammalian emotions of anger and,
and you know,
status seeking and ego and rage and
lost.
When these things are controlling these
highly advanced technologies,
this,
this is not going to come to a good end.
So we want compassionate general
intelligences and this is what we should
be orienting ourselves toward.
And so we need to shift the focus of the
AI and technology development on the
planet toward,
you know,
benevolent,
compassionate,
General Intelligence.
And this is subtle,
right?
Because you need to work with the
establishment rather than overthrowing
it,
which isn't going to be viable,
so this is while we're creating this
decentralized self organizing ai
network,
the singularity net,
then we're creating a for profit
company,
singularity studio,
which will get large enterprises to use
this decentralized network.
Then we're creating these robots like
Sophia,
which will be mass manufactured in the
next couple of years,
rolled these out,
this service robots everywhere around
the world to interact with people and
providing valuable services in homes and
offices,
but also interacting with people you
know,
in a loving and compassionate way.
So we need to start now because we don't
actually know if it's going to be years
or decades before we get to this
singularity and we wanted to be assured
as we can that when we get there,
it happens in a beneficial way for
everyone.
Right.
And things like robots,
blockchain and ai learning algorithms
are our tools.
Toward that end.
Ben,
I appreciate your optimism.
I appreciate coming near explaining all
this stuff for us and I appreciate all
your work.
It's really amazing.
Fascinating stuff.
Yeah.
Well thanks for having me.
It's really fun.
That was a wide ranging conversation,
so yeah,
would it will be great to come back next
year and update you on the state of the
singularity once a year and just by the
time you come from maybe who knows,
a year from now,
the world might be a totally different
place.
Maybe a robot.
A robot now.
Oh,
thank you.
Thank you everybody.