Hello freaky bitches.
I feel like if you created a situation
where Iran saw that there was much more
to be gained from joining the Economic
Community and playing ball in accordance
with its laws is then in getting
weapons of mass destruction.
They're all scared that those chicks
are going to find out they don't have to
wear burkas in America.
Votes cover your cover,
your come over on boats and the
seek out black dick like a magnet,
like a magnet to steal filings.
Perhaps they're tired of being suppressed.
They want a torque on some dude in a club,
maybe no crazy funky religious
outfit on and they can escape.
You know why?
Because no one knows the fuck they look
like they could just blend right in.
Good luck in your passport photo when
it's looking through a fucking lit of a
garbage can like Oscar the
grouch and that's what you're,
that's what you're fucking passport.
It looks like he's here eyeballs.
I mean they have to take their
shit out for their basketball,
right?
Don't they are they are loud too.
It's like stealing
their soul or something.
Right?
Well,
I,
the minute that a lot of Saudi women goes
to places like London and quite guess
what comes off immediately
their head dress,
the whole burden of thing and then go
shopping and they dress sexy outfits and
they're just like,
yeah cause Russian man.
It's just amazing that you're,
you've got countries that in 2015 still
make women dressed like they're in star
wars.
This is not the reason for it.
Another reason for it.
There was not there very
logical reason for it.
Logical.
Well I'm just saying if you're,
if you're,
if you're really,
if you're a,
if you're a living,
I'm just saying if you're a religious
man and if you are trying to create a
productive society,
the logic went,
if you have women walking around
looking all sexy and naked,
which was a lot of the Middle East,
well if you have that,
what happens is we're thinking
about fucking and not producing.
Yeah.
So you've got it covers your chicks up
jam and she want to get any work done.
That's not true though.
I come to America producers
like a mother fucker about that.
How he got hot freaks over the hill.
It's so true.
Freedom.
Is that what you really
Prince Princess Leia.
Is that a real body?
Yeah.
Damn Shit.
A banging body as she did those
real to those pre pre suck and Tuck.
God bless her.
You know,
she didn't have no light Po
couldn't look more board.
Um,
she was beautiful at the time.
Very exotic.
I must say.
Bruns Leo,
what does steel bro I
made out with her brother.
I remember that Shit.
I love it.
She kissed her brother and Ellipsis tick.
Is that true?
It had to.
He didn't know that it was his sister.
That's rude.
You sister comes along and gives you a
real kiss since he got some Univision
cheesy,
even bother telling you that she's,
did she know at the
time she knows she was?
No,
no one knew.
I don't know if
you've experienced this yet,
but for me,
you know,
I've hunted a lot and so I almost
like to punish myself and some,
I like it to be hard.
I like to be a challenge.
So I will actually create it to be,
I just this hunt in New Zealand
where I was hunting these,
these fallow deer and at any given time
for the first few days I could have shot
a deer.
Well if hunt a lot of people
don't realize as hunters,
it's not always the goal
to just go shoot something.
It's part of the experience.
And so for me,
I just kept passing up animals because
the experience wasn't right until the
last day when I was supposed
to leave early and I end up,
oh,
I'm just going to be hunting for
two hours and don't bring any water.
And I ended up hunting all day and going,
I don't even know how far,
18 miles maybe.
And I didn't bring any food,
any water and I'm hurting.
And I ended up shooting a deer last light.
And,
and now is to me is awesome experience.
It made the trip and made that memory,
the hardship made the memory and something
that I as a hunter that non hunters
don't really maybe understand is
like having these antlers around.
And when the meets long gone,
I can look at that and remember the
hardship and the journey and the adventure
and these other things
about the experience and the
meat was a bright product.
But these are the memories that I like.
You look at that Moose and you think of
something completely different than I.
Do you remember how it went down?
You remember,
you know,
maybe the struggle or carrying
the meat back or whatever.
So I've may have a rack in my house
that's sitting up on the mountain.
Why is that one on the mantle on that one?
Well,
that one I had to work real hard for.
So I look at it and I think it reminds
me constantly of what I went through.
When you say that the
experience wasn't right,
what,
what do you mean by that?
Like I feel sometimes it
just wasn't a challenge.
It was I would have
been shooting an animal,
not the adventure wasn't there.
The challenge wasn't there.
It just wasn't the right time.
I wanted to keep going until it,
until it happened.
I don't know.
It's a weird,
but for me hunting's about the
adventure and everything behind it,
and so as well as obviously getting meat,
but there comes a point where you know,
okay,
if I didn't get a deer this week,
well maybe I'll,
I'll get one next week.
I'm not going to starve to death.
I've got a freezer with meat,
but I also want to keep that freezer full,
but so it comes to a point for me
where it's about other things as well,
the experience,
the adventure,
the meat,
all combining into this.
If it's too easy,
I just don't like it that fast.
I don't know.
It'll come.
It'll happen.
You know?
For me it happened.
I started when I was younger.
I never wanted to stop hunting because I
liked the experience of being out there
so much.
So I would do it.
A lot of people call trophy hunting and
I'm air quoting that because it means
something different to me.
Or I would look for a bigger deer because
I wanted to keep hunting and make it
more of a challenge for myself.
I find that quite remarkable that people
worry about this simply because it's
not the way that people
actually think about anything.
Let's remember that the longevity aspect
of all of that work is a side effect.
I don't work on longevity.
I don't,
I work on [inaudible] the way you
might think if you read the papers,
I just work on health.
I'm just interested in stopping people
from getting sick when they get older.
Now if you think about it,
oh medicine is like that.
All medicine involves stopping people
from getting sick or fixing the other.
If they I affec and all Madison had a
side effect that people live longer than
they otherwise would have done.
So the only real difference between the
work that sensory effect foundation dove
and the work that everything,
everyone else in medical referral
is a difference of degree.
The fact that the longevity side effect
of our work may be substantially greater
than the longevity side effect
that we're familiar with.
It's still a side effect.
So if we come to the question,
how will I might one to live,
you know,
it's not even a meaningful question to me.
It's like saying what time would you
like to go to the toilet next Sunday?
You know,
we know that that's a dumb thing
to have an opinion about us.
It's a dumb thing to have an opinion
about because we know we're going to have
more information on the topic nearer the
time we were going to be able to act on
the information and it's the same Dell,
you know,
nobody makes decisions on the basis
of how long ago they were bought.
People increasingly make decisions as
they get older on the basis of how long
they think they've got to live,
but that's because the amount of time
they think they've got to live is going
down,
which it won't be going down anymore.
If you've got an arbitrary amount of time
behind you and other arbitrary amount
of time ahead of you,
you're deficient backing.
It's going to be based on more
short term considerations.
You know,
like peer pressure and thought.
I thought I'd point
out when people ask me,
they things oftentimes say,
okay,
take yourself back to the
first time you got laid.
Oh yeah.
All right.
Now think about what you
were thinking at the time.
What are you thinking?
Oh my God.
Oh my God,
I have to get this person into bed right
now because I've only got another 60
years to live.
I mean,
it's just ridiculous.
Okay.