[inaudible]
all
right.
[inaudible] just spoke to
some of these
boy
[inaudible] [inaudible]
[inaudible]
just spoke to
some of these beliefs
Ahla has right now.
[inaudible]
Huh?
[inaudible] [inaudible]
awesome. That's a good goddamn song.
That is the first time I heard that song,
isn't it great? Yeah. First Time I
heard it and it got me. I love it. Yeah.
Even the video. Have you ever see
the video? It's just words in it.
Like it's just words, but yet you get
into the words. You know what? I really,
I'm masterpiece. I'm not into
soulful music like that usually,
but that's a good song.
I'm already thinking about like remix it
into like a disturbed or prong remix or
something. Would you want to fuck these
gentleman's podcast sponsored once?
Always. Every time by the
podcast, by the fleshlight on, uh,
it's a Saturday.
This is an impromptu podcast.
We decided to put together and Brian
just throw on that song. He said,
you have to listen to it.
It was so good just listening to the
first couple seconds of it that we had to
play the whole thing.
I fucking love that dude.
Remember when he first heard the song
crazy. Yeah, that was [inaudible].
Oh Shit. That's not
all sparkly, Goddamn C,
whatever his name is. I remember when
Bj Penn, I forget who he was fighting.
I think he's finding Matt Hughes,
but he came out to was that crazy
song and I was like, God damn,
that's a good song. Cee Lo green
is his name from Gnarls Barkley,
but I am guessing,
you know,
I wonder what the edited
versions going to sound like.
Are they just going to meetings or are
they just going to bleep it out or change
the words are such, you know what? I
don't think they need to do that anymore.
Radio is dead. Yeah. I mean, the
people that are on radio right now,
a lot of them are doing podcasts and it's
eventually going to go to that regular
terrestrial radio. They've
just fucking, they've gotten,
they've gotten so busy with it and fucked
with it so much that they've crushed
it because there's no, you can't
fuck around on the radio anymore.
You can't have fun. He gets sued.
It's like, why can't you say fuck you?
You remember the, the, the WHO song.
Remember what was the song that had
fucking in it? I don't remember who are,
you know, who the fuck are you? Right.
They played that shit on the
radio when I was a kid. Really?
Because it was the WHO.
Wow. Because, whew, whew.
Whew, whew. You get to the
puck goes, oh the fuck are you.
They kept that on the radio,
right. You can't do it.
But with this song you could probably
just put like cat sounds instead of fuck
and it would still work. I
listened. I listened to that.
Who the fuck are you song?
I listened to that. Who Song the
other day and they did get it.
It was on the radio and they did get it.
They got really fucked.
They twisted the fuck. They took
like a pace out of the fuck. So, Oh,
who the fuck are you? You know there's,
yeah, it's, it's sort of there,
but it's not there.
You can get away with
it. Hmm. It's just good. Fuck it man.
Just let it get on the Internet. Get it.
Make it become mp3s and playing clubs.
It'll be gigantic. A satellite radio,
you know, Eddie, how much money did
you spend last night on junk food?
$250 but it wasn't all junk for,
there was some bar that was uh, uh,
two 12 packs of water. Wow.
So that's like $6, right?
You had,
you had a picture on your Twitter,
you guys gotta check it out
where it's just like junk food.
Tons and tons of junk. Yeah. That was,
no, I didn't set that up. I decided,
I realized I never go
grocery shopping ever. And,
but when I did back in the day,
you never do it stoned and hungry because
you ended up buying a bunch of shit
you would never eat. It just stacks
up and just stays in your house.
Everything sounds good.
You know what?
I'm gonna get some fucking
hamburger helper, every flavor,
all the shit you would never eat.
So I ended up doing that last night
and spent 250 bucks on just shit
pictures. Great. It feels so bad about
yourself after you bought a lot of cereal,
a peanut butter captain crunch.
I mean,
that was the big box of lucky charms.
A huge box was two 99 how the fuck
are you going to turn that down?
I hate three Krispy Kreme donuts in one
sitting the other night. The big ones,
chocolate cream filled. It was so
fucking good. There was so good.
But it's right away. As soon as you're
done, you feel like such a piece of shit.
Oh yeah. You never feel
good at done to my body. Oh,
you're always feel like shit.
You just throwing sludge in the machine.
That's like fucking a fat check.
You never going to feel good after,
after you feel like jumping out of
lumber. If you love her, Eddie. Well,
if you're in love with her and because
she's on the back because she got
pregnant and that's where you can get
you gotta do what you gotta do with some
dudes. It's not worth it for them to
get skinny to fucking skinny girl.
They're like, you know when I like being
fat, I just fuck a fat chick. Yeah,
that's cool. Thank God. Well, there's,
everybody's got different tastes, man.
Someone's going to some girls like
really heroin looking dudes that's like a
look like that bitches
are angry enough man.
We had to tell their bang that
shit out of him. Calm down.
Some of them are angry too, Tom or
were just sad. They just lash out.
How would you like it?
How about the bad check that's hanging
out with three hot chicks at a club on
Trump? Love about that
chick, which is monster.
The path for everybody just destroying
the night to crush the night.
I used to do a bit about them,
about girls cock blocking,
need to bring that shit back.
I don't think ever recorded that.
God Damn it cock blocking a show
excepted for women. It's accepted.
Like if you don't cock block then you
had like no honor almost, you know?
But for guys if you cock block you
can get punched but you can cock block
another guy if he's trying to fuck your
girlfriend. That seems to be acceptable.
I've seen a lot of that where if a guys
hanging out with a girl but they're just
friends and the dude, we'll try to cock
block anyway. I've never seen that happen.
Say that again.
Explain it to is friends with the girls.
Say you are a young single man out in
the town and you meet a young lady and
she's attractive and she's here.
Oh,
these are just my friends and she's
with a girlfriend and a guy friend.
The guy friend will almost always cock
block unless he's like super cool and
thinks you're super cool.
Mostly guy friends hanging out
with a girl or just due to,
haven't really been successful
in fucking that girl.
You're going to be very upset if you
are and it's usually if she's pretty,
for sure if he's around, if
he's young, what are the odds?
He has his shit together enough that he's
cool with her being attracted to other
people other than him. If he's handsome
and she's pretty, what are the odds?
This fucking zero, the odds. Zero.
They're just, there's some twisted rub,
love triangle with her friend and
he really wants to fuck around,
but he can't know.
Well, it's your friend.
It's cruel person. Do it.
They'll be friends with checks so long,
like hot. I've done that too. For decades.
I was friends with the chick from like
1994 and I finally fucked her in 2000
[inaudible] the whole time I wanted to,
I was waiting, but she was so
funny and so cool. We actually,
I like hanging out with that.
Eventually I brought the game afoot
with some smart women,
some smart women just,
they're so tired of the
bullshit that guys do that they,
they will fuck with you and we'll drag
you around if you want to fuck them.
They just want to see how
much effort you put in,
how long you will stick around and to
them it's like it's almost a commodity
they're giving up. Like if you
fuck, if she fucks you now,
you're not going to take
her seriously anymore.
You're just going to be like one
of the other girls that she fox.
But if she just strings you
around forever, then you're
her little play thing.
You're her little buddy and we kiss
every now and then. What's the big deal?
Well. How about if you haven't
kissed and then you think like, fuck,
I'm going to make that move after being
friends for four years and you make a
move and she turns you down to, and
that's Bruce. I thought we were friends.
Yeah. You mean this whole time
you've been trying to fuck me.
So like a crazy I was in the
moment. Yeah, that's never good.
You go out there and you tried
to kiss and she just turned.
She hasn't turned out that all the
way. Just a little bit. It's like Bam.
She just gives you the jaw. That's
always that moment. You're like, damn,
she didn't respond the
way I wish she would have
weird thing with human beings. When one
person wants to be with the other person,
whether it's friendship or whether it's
sexually, any other persons on into it,
that's the worst.
So the worst thing to watch in a movie,
it's the most uncomfortable
thing to watch.
When you see a friend of yours that's
getting fucking just done over and you see
it coming, man, I gotta just
watched this happen. Shit. Yeah,
it's the worst.
It's like if you love a check and all of
a sudden she doesn't love you anymore,
there's nothing she can steal from
you that hurts more than that.
Like my fucking house on fire.
Now I'll be like, there's a hotel.
I'm going to be okay.
I'm a little disoriented.
I can't believe my house is burnt to the
ground, but I'm going to be okay. Yeah,
pull that fucking deep love away and
he'd give it to someone else. Uh,
did that happen to my
babies with someone else?
Last time that happened was in
1995 and it fucking crushed me.
I wrote are terrible and
put her on a cassette and left it on a
doorstep begging her to come back to me.
It was dogmas, dude. I would,
I had to sleep with value
during this to get it out.
She, she just left me. Aren't you glad
she didn't have a Twitter back then?
Could you imagine like, oh my
God, check out on my Facebook.
Facebook doesn't have a
limit is much of a limit.
Can write a lot of shit when people
break up on Twitter. Stupid thing.
Celebrities break up on fucking Twitter
because they come together on Twitter
and they're back on. That's a good one
babe. All sweet baby. Love your baby.
And they go back and forth while the
whole world is watching him go back and
forth. Does that all the
time? Tito and Jenna Jameson,
that's what I'm talking about.
Back and forth all the time.
And then when they break up,
they have to make an announcement.
You have to say something because
they're not twitting together anymore.
They're not hooking each other up in the
twit. So then they have to announce it.
They're no longer going out.
That's working hilarious.
Can you have Twitter?
What happened to Steve adgs Twitter?
He just deleted his whole entire account
and it was like, fuck Twitter or if I,
you know, and I'm deleting my Facebook
also. And then the other day I'm like,
why haven't I heard from him in awhile?
And he just got it back on the Twitter
like a month later or something.
He's like, I had to get
back on Twitter to uh, uh,
talk about this movie I just saw
and now he has like 2000 friends.
But didn't he like have like a
million? Yeah, something like that.
He just deleted all,
did Twitter suicide. I
was there a reason.
I don't know.
There's some people that feel
like we're too connected, man.
There's some people that don't like it.
They resent it.
They want the old school way where
people just like you, they like you,
they like you, you know you don't,
and when I have to talk all day,
I don't have to be fucking tweet
and back and forth with you.
I'll do a Johnny Carson interview and sit
down with them. And if you're like me,
like me, you know, they don't want to
get into the whole social media thing.
I disagree with that. I
mean, I disagree with it too,
but for some people it's like
their privacy is just, um,
there's people that aren't on Twitter,
aren't on a fucking barely on computers.
They are, they're not even on
the goddamn computer. They still,
you could live that life if you want.
You can totally sure.
My mom doesn't even know how to get texts.
I sent my mom a text like a month ago
and she finally just responded Oh mg.
I didn't know I got texts.
My mom doesn't get text messages.
My mom just figured that out.
Like last week she,
she'll send the same text
twice cause she's not sure how.
Maybe you didn't go through
and let me send it again.
Maybe they didn't go through it. Let me
send it again. It's like a fucking letter.
My mom is scared of the
price. I'm like, mom, it's $5
for like 500 text messages. You could
just do that plan. And she goes, no,
I just can't afford $5 on my thing. I'm
like, mom, think of all the stamps cards.
You cave. She doesn't
understand it. You she has,
I'd have a tech seminar to
go to or something. Yeah.
Some people just don't give a fuck about
technology. So maybe that's what it was.
Maybe he just felt like too compressed,
you know, maybe two to attach to people.
So it wasn't too long where it was all
about fucking fan mail and like opening
up like a and going that
stuff for whatever reason,
that stuff always creeped me out.
But, but this does not creep me out.
Like communicating with people
on an even level and boards and
you know, and Twitter and stuff like
that. I like that. That's fun. It's fun.
It's interesting, you know,
I mean, you can't respond to
everybody. It's impossible.
It's virtually impossible.
And some people get mad because of it.
And I understand you getting annoyed,
but there's no way I could respond.
Everybody.
I wouldn't have time to do shit.
I wouldn't have time to write anything,
wouldn't be able to work out with
enough time to get anything done.
There's just no fucking way you can keep
up. There's just no way. But it's still,
it's a fun way to give what you can
give, you know? And, and it's a fun way,
not money. Not that that's anything you're
giving. It's so special. But you know,
just to be able to communicate with
people and just the amount of information
that you get now.
It's just so much different than when
you know our parents were growing up.
There was nothing like fucking ghetto
gaggers.com that someone could just click
a link to you. You remember when
that guy did that to me on Twitter?
Some guy goes, hey, is this triangle okay?
This has got doing this triangle. Okay.
I click on it and this little skinny
white dude who's got this chick who truly
side, she's like this really
ghetto looking chick and
he's fucking her mouth and
there's a whole site dedicated to skinny
white dudes fucking the shit out of
these ghetto black checks. There's a
whole site. There was no nothing like, oh,
what's that side? Oh,
gaggers.com email me that. Yeah.
[inaudible] it's the strangest fuck
it that. I'll work back and watch it,
man. That's like watching
dolphins get harpooned and shit.
How hard shit like that was for your dad
to see how shit like that. My Mom, what?
For my mom to see how hard that was when
they were growing up to get a ghetto
gaggers photo.
It was impossible.
You couldn't find it and if
you tried looking for it,
you'd probably get arrested. You'd
probably get locked up in some FBI sting,
you know? I mean how many, how hard
was it to get like really obscene shit.
It's really hard time. I think that then
you see these like historic photos of,
you know, bondage houses from the
1910 did shit. They still did shit.
But I don't think it was easy to see it.
I think you had to get deep into that
world before you got into the bondage
houses.
You had to be trusted into the circle
of fucking freaks and Weirdos willing to
tie each other up and fuck their
faces and do whatever they do.
It's probably a lot of drawings
back then of that though,
they would have to be me right before,
before 1835 there was no cameras.
So there was all drawn. Yeah, there
are stacks and stacks of drawings and
maybe it was just all talk. Maybe it
was just all written word, you know?
I know they did. They did have
like some sort of light porn,
like literature came at 10 how happy
people are when they invented Morse code.
What's the thought that was like magic,
right?
[inaudible]
technology.
You know what I mean? They'd send a wire
in the old west. Remember that shit?
That's crazy. She sent a
letter by y. How crazy is that?
I wonder how complex smoke
signals got [inaudible].
I mean, how many symbols are
there can you make with smoke?
Whether there's this dude
that lives in Alaska,
there's this dude that lives
in Alaska and he was on a, um,
Jack Carolla show on the road, whatever
it was called. What was it called?
Do you remember that show?
No,
it was caught on the road
and it was like a CBS show.
Scott would go on all these different
places and he went to Alaska to talk to
this prospect or,
and this guy spends like five,
six months alone by himself in Alaska and
then comes back into town and he says,
when he comes back into town, he can read
people's minds. It doesn't last forever.
Buddy can do it for a short period of
time because he's not talking to anyone
out there and it learns how
to tune into thoughts, Huh?
What the fuck
can you prove this? Yeah.
Right. I mean, no. I mean,
I know this deal with this and
the tooth in the woods again.
Yeah. I mean, it's ridiculous, but
I think there's something there.
Not that there's, this guy can actually
read your mind, but I think there's,
there's obviously something else going
on just besides words he needs to be on
that show.
Uh,
Stanley's superhumans try to describe
what it feels like when you know someone's
full of Shit. We know when
someone's lying to you, you know,
that weird feeling when someone's
lying to you. Pantomimes yeah, yeah.
But even not even
pantomimes just something,
just something you just a hunch, you
know, just a weird vibe, a feeling.
You're tuning into something,
you know,
what is it that you have to do to get
really super sensitive to be able to do
that all the time though, is they're like
exercises that you can do to try that
tuning, paranoia, paranoia. I
seriously, if you're paranoid,
you're watching every single Flint of
every single move is something else is
making, you know, cause you're
paranoid about everything.
You're watching every hand motion, you
start getting overly sensitive, you know?
Yeah.
But that's not good.
But I'm saying is to be able to read
it like all the time to be able to tune
into it all the time. It's gotta be
something that people get in close to.
You know, long time ago I was
reading that there was this one guy,
I forget who he was,
some saint character and um,
he was one of the first guys that
knew how to read without talking.
And there was one of the ways that they
thought this guy was divine because he
could like look at the,
the uh,
the scripture and he could close
it and then speak of the words.
And they were like, well, this is proof.
This guy's divine because he
doesn't even have to read it aloud.
And what it was is he was just the first
guy who figured out how to read without
talking. So Thomas, it's
like a totally normal thing.
We think that's what we always
do, but a long time ago, you know,
thousands of years ago,
I mean who knows how long.
That was like really hard to do.
Like you couldn't just look at something
and just like in thinks in your head.
Oh, that's a poster for the ultimate
doom. You have to say the ultimate doom.
You'd have to spell it out. How
strange is that? It's ridiculous.
That's like a technique.
That's the technique somebody figured out.
We just take it for granted. Just
reading. Imagine if everywhere you go,
people had a real loud,
okay,
how God damn annoying would that be?
You're on a plane and everyone's got
their own book and you got to tune in to
whatever these fucking people are reading
stupid romance novel and you're trying
to read your shit.
You know what I'm picking up.
I'm picking up when was toilet paper
and invented and what the different
cultures use to wipe their ass over
the centuries. The day is considered
the way to go everywhere.
But here I'm talking about ancient England
ass wiping ancient ass wiping, moldy,
musty use, rivers, sticks,
rocks, twigs, faces of hope,
maybe nothing by a river
nearby and no one did.
You have a shit back.
Maybe the whole reason why people wipe
it all is because they want someone to
eat their ass. We're the only animal
understands how good that feels.
That's why we keep our ass clean.
We used to drag them by the hair.
Don't you think they would make would
make them clean your ass? You know,
clean my ass. You know that's how
the cavemen probably wipe their ass.
You know like,
I mean they used to try drag would force,
they were tools to the women were
tools. Yeah, the one that works.
That's why they would drag him
by the hair. They didn't care.
I don't think that's right.
First guy to wipe his ass probably it
was some problem was a gay guy who's gay.
Cavemen just trying to let me just
clean this place up. It's such a mess.
Do you ever walk it lathered
it up palm for and shit.
Never walk into a public restroom and
think it's like we're part of like a gay
joke. You know what I mean? Cause they,
why do we all have to pull out our dicks
and everyone is so no matter how old
you are, if you're standing
next to a bunch of people
and you pull out your tick,
it just, there's still, there's a little,
there's a touch of insecurity. Right.
Just a little touch I
miss too. It's like why?
Why can't we have compartments? Like
[inaudible] whole weird thing is that,
you know for sure the dude's
have sucked other dudes.
Dick's in these very
bathrooms. Yeah. I was like,
why don't we play out a Dick's
gay dudes must love going.
That's what public restaurants
are such a turnoff.
Don't you think they're doing a bath?
Cause dudes do all pulling Dixon's
dicks on everywhere for them.
It's just like if you could go
into a chick's room. Exactly.
That's what I'm thinking.
There's a big fucking gay joke.
Gay Dude design the first public restroom.
Yeah,
but don't you think locker rooms or worse?
Way worse because at least peeing.
You have something to do.
Locker rooms are just kind of like
getting dressed and talking about
clothing.
No locker rooms are bad too.
I mean you should have
your own private booths.
Some urinals have walls where
you can't see other dudes, Dick.
But then some brand new
brand new stadiums, the brand
new stadiums and they are,
you have a trough was
pulling out their dicks
did. I used to do taekwondo with back in
the day and he was a male dancer and he
always used to creep people out
because he would be like, he would get,
he would take a shower and then he would
just like stroll around the bathroom
was chest out like this stroll around.
Sometimes he would stretch out naked.
He'd be fucking naked Bro.
And this company like stretch his
legs out and his fucking, his deck.
I mean he probably had like a hundred
fat chicks suck at a day. And some guys,
you know,
I mean this guy was a male dancer and he
definitely had guys that that asked him
to dance because he told me that's
the best way you can make money.
He doesn't like to do it.
I don't want to do it man.
Thanks to like road show around
the bathroom and his elephant Dick.
He'll look at elephants trunk just flop.
It was like three,
three quarters hard all the time.
This dude would just walk around.
Nothing's gayer than that.
That's
what about that hour that you posted
on Twitter the other day with that and
some Mexicans talk about that
shit. That's crazy. Yeah.
Apparently it's some crazy owl.
It's um,
there's a bunch of different names for it.
I think someone said it's a frog owl
and someone said it's a thorny hour or
something like that.
I guess it's a from Australia.
I posted some video up on my Twitter,
some, some dudes sent it to me. It's a,
a Mexican news story about
um, this, this animal.
They don't know what it is and they
think it's a wedge and it's just as crazy
owl. It's a really weird looking at second
and by slight here, let me pull it up.
I'll pull it up on my,
on my Twitter while we're talking so
he could see it because it's just so
strange. It doesn't look like
a real animal. Less light bird.
It looks like a little dragon from a
Harry Potter movie, like a half Lizard,
half bird that's come to
life. And it's like, you know,
finding you fleshlight should make one
of these birds [inaudible] totally legit
picture. Oh no, it's a video man.
It's a real animal. And there is,
there's videos of them. Oh,
they found more than one.
Oh, you know, it's an animal.
It's a real animal in Australia.
It's just, is freaky looking owl?
It's called like a tawny owl or
something like that. And people,
why was it in the Mexican
news? Uh, because I guess
they didn't know what it was.
Whoever it was. I mean, it's, you know,
the Mexican version of like some local,
you know, news story where a bunch
of Yahoos are out there with cameras.
Like we have cup today, which we get this
fucking thing. They're holding it down,
but let me, let me pull it up real quick.
He's like, why can't it be Mexican? Man?
Eddie got very sensitive. Any bravos
and Mexican. I don't know if you need,
I don't appreciate some of
their marks. Did the tone. Yeah,
just think you were joking with me.
When I first moved here,
he used to always tell me you
were Mexican. And I was like, oh,
that's his joke here. Like
she never believed it. Well,
what's really funny is when
he makes chicks and tells
him he's half Japanese and
half Eskimo, he says, yeah, I'm a
Jap. Oho stories always different.
It's always like, you know, my
father was a, you know, a soldier.
His father was in World War II,
just only like some crazy. As a kid,
I always used to tell people I was half
Japanese, half Eskimo as all right.
Kind of like sweat shop our sweat this.
Brian,
can you turn slide strange
reptilian bird found in Mexico?
[inaudible] microphone on it. That'd be
no, but it'd better if you do it though.
You know you can plug into it.
Remember? Yeah. I thought you meant no.
Just so that people can hear it
because Eddie's speaks Spanish.
He'll know what they're saying. It
says Mexico. Yeah, no, it is in Mexico.
I thought you said it was an
Australia. Well, it's just an animal.
I mean it lives in Australia and
someone found one in Mexico. Oh Shit.
I mean animals that live in Australia can
surpass the guy on a cargo boat. Yeah.
Probably something like that. Right? Yeah.
It's amazing how many different
animals come from everywhere.
There's so much of sparrows in
Hawaii then aren't from there.
All the pigs and Hawaiians.
Enough from there.
Okay. You got it. Okay. Here we go.
[inaudible] can you translate
Mr Rob [inaudible] microphone.
[inaudible] I know what she's saying.
Let's just say big Gaudy [inaudible].
Okay.
It's a wedge
Lopez.
[inaudible] they speak
really
don't understand proper.
Did you keep it so street?
You know what I'm going to give you.
You know what I'm saying? There it
is. There it is. Look at this thing.
This is the burden. It really does look
like a lizard now. It looks like a,
yeah, it looks like a flying
lizard, but it's called the,
I think it's called a tawny owl look.
Awesome.
It's a real bird man.
I want to see it fly.
Look at it. It's pretty dope. I mean,
what's really funny is I put, I put it
up on Twitter. All right, kill it Brian.
I think we're done.
I put it up on Twitter and dudes,
most people were like,
what the fuck was that?
And in some people out an
answer for what the fuck it was.
You fucked one of those. If it was
drugged up and now we went and bite you.
No problem. Frogs figured it
out. If it was really drugged up.
Have you ever seen people, Eileen frogs
and the frogs and the chimp? Fuck it.
That's what I meant.
Frog fucking how smart fucking chimps.
If somebody wants a Twitter
this while we're live here,
if someone wants to Twitter's,
tell me what the fuck that
apple is so I can look it up.
Cause it's not a tawny owl.
It's something else. Tony owls.
Just a pretty normal looking out.
But I know at some kind of fucking
freaky owl that we didn't know existed.
That shit up.
I'm putting tion how crazy is it?
The chimps figured out how to fuck frogs.
10 chimps are super smart chips,
smoked cigarettes, man. You ever see
that? No, I haven't seen that at all.
I'm smoke cigarettes. You give
chimps cigarettes. They like them.
You see the video the other day,
somebody credible stimulates, have it.
Somebody dropped a game boy into the
chimp cage and San Francisco and there's
like video and photos of like just chimp
just sitting there playing game boy and
like a baby chimp lake sitting on the
board are watching. They're like really,
really, really, really, really,
really, really stupid people. Yeah,
but way stronger and way more violent.
Way more violent.
They're like nine year olds can't
even understand how strong they are.
Apparently like, oh, 150 pound champ
is as strong as a 500 pound man.
Just try to wrap your head around that.
What a 500 pound man would feel like.
It sounds stupid. That is, no, that's
500 pounds like fessel or five.
Right,
Brock Lesnar 500 pounds,
his body Sheldon has there been
like a dude all yoked, no fat,
totally shredded and 400 pounds.
I'm sure there must be. Yeah,
I would imagine at this point not power
would imagine there's somebody that's
doing that, like the biggest bodybuilder
ever. I'm sure we could find it.
We'll Google it.
Brian Google the biggest bodybuilder ever.
We're going to find this out,
Brian. It's totally possible.
Vegas,
like the average bond petted a bodybuilder
when they're competing or they what?
5%
body fat. What do you, what? What's
the average? To be totally ripped,
it's you gotta be really good.
5% or 2% or 3%
when I was doing taekwondo and when
I was cutting weight to make a high,
I was fighting at 140 pounds and I
really didn't weigh 140 pounds and I was
really skinny. I was very thin at the
time to a very lean, low body fat.
I was four and a half percent body fat.
When they told me like,
this is getting kind
of low. Like, you know,
you can't really get much lower than
that and be like competitive in anything.
Well, one place says those guys steer.
Those guys don't do anything. No,
they're not.
You know what I'm saying?
They're just posing so they can get
really low, like unhealthy loan.
They get to like 3% I think they're like
about to pass out or did you pass out?
They pass out all the time. Those guys
are dehydrated as fuck, man. It's like,
it looks, I mean, I'm not
into the bodybuilding look.
It's a little ridiculous.
But you know, as just an aesthetic, just
like looking at it like, it's like, like,
wow, look what that guy has done with
all his work and sculpted his body.
It's kind of fucking freaking.
That's Quincy Taylor.
That was 2009 largest wine
at least. And how much? Uh,
one 10.
No,
340 pounds with a 5% body fat.
Whoa. That's pretty low.
Probably the biggest right
there. That's pretty big. Well,
Bob Sapp was,
what was he like three 75 was Bob Sabaj.
It was about three 75 three 50 but he
had a lot of fat. He was never shy.
Well, he wasn't, and when he first
came out and thought, Oh, Gary,
I would not say you had a lot of fat. He
wasn't trying to, he had a little bit,
a little, but he was so swole. Do you
remember how big Bob Sapp was? Fuck yeah.
For people who hadn't,
who don't know what we're talking about.
There was a dude who fought out of
Seattle, Washington, and he only had,
he had a run of only a few years because
it was just this chemically fueled
fucking suicide mission. There was no way
he could keep it up. There was no way,
no way. You could be that big for that
many years. How long can you keep that up?
He was,
he was a fucking nightmare for awhile.
And then 75 18 months. It was a Bob
Sapp going to take over the world.
He was so big.
He crushed Ernesto,
who's twice in a kickboxing match,
straight kickbox. He beat her nest,
a host.
That's how strong he was and his sheer
might was enough to bully who's to know
corner and just smash him. He was more
feared than Brock Lesner is today.
Yeah, he was before that
car went fine. He was,
he was feared and it was cool
because you would lose, you know,
he would come really close to smash and
guys like Noguera and then he would gas
out. No, Garrett got that harmed by
like, oh shit. What that, no terrified.
I remember we watched it here. We had a
party here and we were all, oh no, no, no.
It was that we were all at Larry's house.
Larry's Larry's house.
We were watching this shit live and right
when that started I was just, no way.
He right when he was getting his
ass kicked at the first 45 seconds.
I like no way he's going to win. He's
too big. He's too big. He's done.
He's too big. I said that like the times
we just too big. It's too freaking out.
It was the craziest fight ever because
here Nogueira was the pride champion at
the time, you know, and Nogueira back
then was the number one heavyweight,
the world.
Nobody had beaten him yet.
He was strangling everybody in the Jiu
Jitsu community. Fucking loved him.
Exactly.
Here's this guy was a big heavyweight,
200 3,240 pounds and he was strangling
like high level wrestlers like Mark
Coleman off his back.
Just was the first big guy to
have a very dangerous car. Yeah,
he started jacking the high level
guys. Yeah, you can take it.
He can take it son.
No was the Jujitsu Savior.
How about new Giro Cro cop? How about
that fight. Take sit for that first route.
Takes it. He got took
before minute round, Bro.
This is the,
the pride system is a 10 minute round.
Wasn't unusual rules was there was a
regular 10 minute round, right? Yep.
And Nogueira before
it'll get a busted out.
The whole like the general consensus in
the MMA community was the guard ain't
shit. No, no, you can't. You
can't tap guys off your back. Yet.
People believe that people
believed that the God is dead.
People actually said that they believe
in in a large percentage of the
population. Should you see the
WC? Yes. Sued Anthony Pettis.
How about pat about that fucking
mother? Fuck Jackie Chan. Yes,
please. Touches two rounds doing
chat. Yeah. Yeah. Real Nick Cage.
He does. It's effective that a
lot of guys don't like to do it.
Is that double roundhouse kick
Shogun does that sometimes.
I've you seen me do that one. Don't
move. That's an old school setting.
A lot of styles have it,
but that's like always thought to be
like really flashy but it's kind of high
percentage if you can touch
them with the first kick.
If you hit the guy with the first kick,
the second kick is right there. Yeah.
Just most guys don't want to do that in
MMA because they're going to get taken
down. Thank God. Doesn't give a
fuck. The knee pad has is amazing.
He's fucking guard is so nasty.
It's so quick like how he throws up that
trying like every time Shane roller had
his harm in their peds threat, threatened
with a triangle, like real tight,
real tight and rollers. No
joke, no joke. Strongest fuck.
And Shane Roller tested him too.
He clipped him up a couple of
hard times and chased him down.
But pet has kept his shit
together. Just fraught. SMART,
didn't get in any silly brawls. When
he got tagged, he moved away. You know,
he was a great fight.
They didn't show it on the card,
but it was on the undercard.
I don't know why they didn't show it.
Hobby Vasquez against the Mackins. What
happened? I don't even know what to do,
Dude. Hobby Vasquez is
going to tear some ass. Oh,
he's telling me he's going to test
them as Hobby Vasquez and me grew up,
uh, you know, in the southern
California Jujitsu scene,
he was the most feared guy in my
division to my category. We were rivals.
I went against him four times and he
beat me all four times. He was amazing.
And I'm one of those four times.
I think I won. You know, it's the,
the match and on my DVD, but he
technically won on points, but whatever.
But anyways, I always knew, I knew
about explain. What do you mean?
Why did you think you won when he won?
Well, that was the match where, uh,
I pull up, I pulled guard and he passes
my garden, puts the neon, the belly.
So that was five. Nothing right
away. And then I recovered God.
Then I put them right into the truck.
Now caught in the twister,
you know, I was, um, it was a five.
Nothing, but I'm a, I'm in the truck.
So you had them in the, for folks who
don't know when, when you're in the truck,
when you're in a twister,
you're,
you've got the guy in a very
vulnerable situation is the position.
It's like there's a few positions did,
you did too,
where you're in a lot of trouble when
a guy has your back. When I got eyes,
your mouth for anybody
who doesn't know Jujitsu,
but one of them that's really
weird is this position called the,
it was originally the guillotine
from wrestling, right? Yes, but um,
Eddie has turned it into a pretty high
percentage submission move for guys who
don't understand the position. Hobby
understands the position. But yeah,
but the referees and the rules were
not set up to think that that was a
dangerous spot.
Exactly.
And so he's got five nothing because he
passed my guard and putting the on the
belt and then I from from him
passing, he over committed. I took,
I went and put one hook in,
ended up on the truck is a guy I have to
get tapped in that position before they
recognize that that's a dangerous
position for someone to be in.
If I'm trying to get to someone of,
I'm trying to get to a position that
we call a 10th planet Jiu Jitsu,
we call it a truck and this is a step
right before you lock a guy up in a
twister.
How many times do guys get,
have to get tapped from that
spot before they recognize that?
Or do you think that if there's like
a lot of like old school shit going on
where they don't want to add
any new dangerous positions?
It takes a lot of time to add the
truck to your game and to master it.
It takes,
a lot of times you're going to have,
the only way you're going to master
it is a, for some personal reason,
you fall in love with it and you just
attach yourself to it and you just want to
do it or you got to have an instructor
shoving it down your throat and a in a
curriculum that eventually, you know,
he understands is all about the numbers.
That's for someone developing them,
but what I'm talking about
incorporating it into like if you,
you have a a Jujitsu competition.
Why or why do they not recognize
that position as a position?
Because not enough people are doing it,
but still if you tell,
if you explain to them
what you're trying to do,
like it seems like Jujitsu community
should be the [inaudible] position.
They don't understand
what, that's silly, right?
There's that many people are
doing it. It takes, it's v.
That's the what I was talking about.
If every few people are good at the time,
but it's commonly
acknowledged at this point,
that's a significant submission move.
That's a real move.
Everybody knows a twist is a real move.
You know what,
it's starting to get legit now
because cut some Maura in Japan.
He just twisted somebody on,
there've been four or five twisters
I think now and everybody's kind of
acknowledged that it's a real position
and once you acknowledge it's a real
position, it's like
here, here's another one.
How about when Matt Hughes
got Ricardo Elmeda in that um,
that Schultz headlock, you saw
that right? It's kind of sleep.
We talked about that. Now if a
guy gets that now that had an arm,
if he knows that position, he's
like in a near submission, he,
if he's like a mad huge type character
that was never like a near submission
position.
It was like a position of control that
front headlock you could do their front
head lock. I mean you could
switch cars in Anaconda. Yeah,
there's a lot of shit there but
that's a new one. But again for,
for that move to really take off. I
mean, you're seeing it, you're smart guy,
you see it,
it's the jet.
But to get to that legitimacy personally
with that move is going to take a lot
of practice and people,
especially MMA fighters,
they just don't have the time to add,
to spend,
to add new techniques to their arsenals.
Yeah, they got to do kickboxing.
They gotta run,
they got a slam tires with sledge hammers.
I got a rug roll of pills. They
got drag logs, all that shit.
To add a new system to your,
your ground game,
you can have to find some time and
uh, you know, 20 minutes a day,
an hour a week, maybe they're
just not doing it. That's all.
I talked to Jake shields about this.
We had a long interview for that thing
I'm doing for ufc.com it's a thing called
a UFC ultimate insider and
it's me interviewing a lot
of guys this week is Dana
White. Next week it's changed Tony.
Now that one was fucking hilarious.
But I'm interviewing Jake shields.
We talked about the idea of a specialist.
We talked about the, and I said that he,
you know, he's a specialist, you know,
Anderson Silva's specialists, Cro, cop
specialists, these guys who are really,
really good at one thing and then they
start learning the rest of the things,
you know, and he said that he believes
that that's the best way to go.
What do you think about that? What's
the best way to go to be a specialist?
To be awesome at one thing instead of
trying to learn mixed martial arts,
learn Jujitsu, learn kickboxing,
learn wrestling, find one thing,
get fucking awesome at it.
I mean,
are you trying to raise a
kid to become an MMA fighter?
Are you 30 years old and do you just
want to do like, no, no, no, no.
What I'm talking about is
what he was talking about.
And then they fight for MMA is that he
believes that the best way to go is to be
a specialist or something like that.
He's like,
the level of Jujitsu that I'm at is
what he said. It's like, you know,
it's going to take these guys.
They're not,
they're not going to reach that
level is basically what he's saying.
They're not there. They're not regular
training director and reach that level.
So if it turns into a ground game, he's
always going to be able to dominate them.
And you know, and with the Jake
shields style, like Jake shields is a,
he's a powerful fucking dude. If he
gets guys down in a in a nasty position,
he can squash people,
you know, and he's a,
he's a powerful motherfuckers between
Jake shields and other wrestlers that
we've seen come and go,
is that he got really good at passing
the guard and getting to the mount and
getting to the back and mastering chokes.
He understood that that's the way
you're going to survive in this sport.
You can be a wrestler and when you
know you've been an all American,
every goddamn ear,
maybe a champion every goddamn here,
if you don't learn how to
submit people and pass,
the Guardian will never survive.
If you don't learn how to pass the guard,
you will never survive.
If you're an MMA fighter,
if you're not doing what George
Saint Pierre is doing, if that,
that is the ultimate game plan,
he trains and the ultimate optimal way,
you know, you've got to, if you're a
wrestler, if you're a wrestler college,
also anger and not doing what
GSP has doing after the down,
you're never gonna make it look at,
there was a school at [inaudible] school
of thought where Tito just stays in
God's garden, smashes him from that
position and he's really good at it.
As far as got guys who are good
at beating guys up in the guard,
like Prime Tito in his prime. He's one of
the very best that it's very hard gone.
Tito's a bad motherfucker.
But if you look at his fights,
he's not grounding and pounding anybody
in his last. He hasn't, that hasn't worn,
he doesn't want to do that.
He's had some real issues with his health.
I mean who knows how he's going to be
when it comes back. But for me again,
what about Chael Sonnen and Anderson
Silva? This, there's a perfect example,
part two or one the fight.
Yes. That's a perfect example.
Lingered in. The guard didn't
pass. Kayla, Shut Kale.
Simon's been in the game at least
eight years. If from day one,
if he woulda just fell in
love with the art of passing.
It's just like the art of down. Let me
propose this just as devil's advocate.
What about guys who say that you know a
guy's garlic? Anderson Silva is a very,
very difficult guard to pass and Cheo was
pushing a fucking pretty furious pace.
What if he was thinking that this
would just expand too much energy,
worried about getting caught so
he's not even going to try to pass.
He's just going to hold him down and
tried to beat him up until he finds his
opening. Well, if he, if,
if you're asking what his strategy should
have been at what point and how much
training,
like if he would actually worked on his
passing and master the passing and he's
been doing it for five years.
If he's been working on mastering passing
for five years, I go to pass his guard.
But if he says,
I'm about to fight Anderson Silva,
I haven't really been working on
passing. I'm like, staying in guard. You,
if you try to pass,
you're probably fuck up.
Just if you could stand half
guard to stay there. Don't try.
I wouldn't advise someone to pass
if they weren't good at it. Right,
but I mean just for MMA,
I mean just for the sake of arguing,
you get a guy like Chael Sonnen who's this
badass wrestler. It was a power house.
One of the very best guys had taken dudes
down and beats a lot of guys up like
that first round. He stayed
inside Anderson's card and
he beat him up. You know,
he beat him up from inside there.
[inaudible] he worked him over
and he's really good at that.
What if he thinks that he's good enough
at defending and they fucked up and made
a mistake,
but he's good enough at defending to do
that to the very best in the world and
he's got it down right now.
He knows what he's doing right now.
When he starts adding a bunch of stuff
to it, like passing, he's worried about,
you know,
maybe this will take too much energy.
I mean just devil's advocate again,
five round fights he hasn't been working
on is this is what I would do. I'd go,
you know what,
the rematch is coming up within six
months and you think so much time,
maybe a year or whatever it is.
Whatever it is. Well the, if ever,
we don't really know if whatever
rematch. Yeah, well they might,
they might not have it.
Okay, well we'll let,
let's assume you have to prepare
for it because he's out there.
People want to see it.
So you would say,
I would got to work on passing your guard
if you passing the garden like now and
then by the time the
fight happened I would,
I would analyze his passing and if this
passing was still lacking and within a
year I'd go, okay, just do the same shit
you did last time. We'll try to pull it.
So your thought is that anybody who's
as good as Chael Sonnen is at wrestling
could get that good at Jujitsu.
And be even more dominant.
Just be be a guy who could,
if you could hold you down to your guard,
he could really mount you too. He could
really take your back to her. Look.
Liquid GSP is doing after the takedown
look Jake shields is doing after the tech
down and look what you know.
Even then there's wrestlers
that got really good at passing.
The guard got good at getting to the out,
but they haven't really mastered any
submissions yet and that will maybe now
today, yes, but so far,
you know Sean Sherk is one
of the best passers in Nma.
That motherfucker was slicing through
black belts guards. He's a great passer.
He just needs to develop more. Go to
chokes. Real simple. That could happen.
You just got to put the time
and John Fitch, same thing.
John Fitch is out the the stage of his
development where he's getting really
good at passing and getting that
the back and getting them out.
He just needs to keep going. Keep
working. You're, you're almost there.
Get two or three moves,
put a thousand reps in each and boom,
they're on your in your pocket.
It's science I think doing, yeah.
He's just seems like development.
Yeah.
Eventually you're going to see John
Fitch have one or two really good
submissions that he's killing people with
and then you're like, damn, he's, it's,
it's coming along. It's going
to take shield is already there.
He's going to be breaking guys to Jake
Shields is the furthest wrestler so far
right now in Nma.
All the wrestlers.
Jake is not only mastered passing but
Jake gets to the back beautifully,
gets to them out beautifully
and has some go to shit is good.
Teens are Badass. He's got,
uh, I mean is from hell.
Does that crazy one arm guillotine where
you grabbed the guy's channel and you
post out in front of his
head and he pulled it up.
That's Tito Ortiz used that way
back on Yuki Kondo. Remember that?
And then Jake is still looking to
expand his game because even at the,
at the point where Jake is the future is
going to be Jake standard after people
see it.
That's going to be the standard and the
people that are gonna pop through are
the ones that not only have Jake shields,
but then they got like seven,
eight other little transitions
that end up in kills too.
You know that the future,
these kids that are training now,
like those Rufo brothers, Holy Shit,
those Rory Macdonald, there's a,
there's a perfect example. There's a dude
who grew up doing mixed martial. Yeah,
there's a lot of kids right now,
like 40 Victor Song.
Holy Shit. Adabola. He's my,
he does my job for the Spanish broadcast.
This is the coolest fucking guy.
He has three sons. One of them is named
Bandler lay. He's the Spanish Joe Rogan.
One of them is named Vandelay. His name
is victor is one of the greatest guys.
One of his sons are awesome. They're
just, they just worship and I may,
he's got one 10 year old son Doherty
and then he's got two younger sons,
like three and four that really,
really young,
but before they could walk there
were already throwing combinations.
He has a raising three killers and body.
Holy Shit.
He's 10 I'm talking to a 10 year old
and he's breaking down other people's
performance and how,
like at tournaments he's breaking down
other people's performance as well.
How they miss the electric chair,
why the old school didn't work.
He's pointed out chair and old
school or old techniques. Yeah, yeah.
And I'm sitting there having
a philosophical conversation
with a 10 year old.
He's a very, he's a very good
father and he's all the time with
his kids and he's genuinely
enthusiastic about his kids.
He takes his son all over the place.
He's a super fucking cool human being.
That's not a great time with that guy.
That's when I got really into Mexico
when I got really into all this border
violence,
when I really,
really got into it was talking to to
him because when we first met him,
he was a,
victor was living in Juarez,
which is like the bad town,
the bat border town.
And he said it was horrifying.
They say,
I have to drive at night with their dome
light on so that people can see inside
your car and they know there's no,
no enemy in your car because there's just
all this drug violence back and forth.
He said it was terrifying. Yeah. And He,
it took him a long time to
get to the United States to
get to them, to move here,
to work for the UFC.
He was like working for the UFC
and then going back to Juarez,
just fearing for his life.
Like so close to like the,
the perfect fucking Gig ever. He's the
guy who was a huge mixed martial arts fan.
Oh, he's always fun times. An
MMA fighter, good martial art,
martial arts school in Mexico
and he's rolled at Eddie's
Jim, uh, a gang at times.
He's opening up 10 planet in El Paso,
Texas.
That's the Spanish Joe Rogan is going
to be the head instructor to 10 pound at
El Paso that's in the works right now.
And he's looking for,
could not meet a nicer human being.
And this guy was living when we met him,
he was living in a war zone essentially.
He's living in the middle of the
drug war zone. Solon teacher.
He translated for me in Argentina when
I did a few seminars down there and the,
we worked together like fucking
Abbott and Costello. Man,
it was fucking perfect. How have this,
that's awesome because my Spanish sucks.
I need that. I would throw an
occasional Spanish here and there,
but I didn't want to, I didn't want to
go too deep and sound like an idiot,
so I kept in English, but victor
was right there. It was like, man,
we worked together like a broadcast team.
It's like not stepping over each other.
He knew that the punctual,
he would add some shit that I missed,
that I would hear him
like, Damn Dude, he's a bad
motherfucker, man. What his sons,
these raising some nightmares.
Yeah,
but very respectful and very cool.
They're not going to be thugs.
They're just going to
be a little killer's.
He's just such a nice guy and that's
the one of the coolest things about this
job. Working for the UFC. We work with
so many cool people, man, that those,
those road trips are fun as
fuck. Oh yeah. That's like,
it's a giant family of like a hundred UFC,
um,
employees and everywhere you go,
like the story is,
I mean there's the in the cage,
everybody sees in the cage,
but there's so much shit
going on and allow the UFC,
the production or the different people
that work for them when they argue with
each other. I'm on nine.
I'm on line right now.
What the fuck do you get your shit
together? We go in five, four. I love,
I love it when the producer Bruce
Conner and or the director, Anthony,
Jared, Donald, when they, you,
you missed a flight. I started
fucking with goalie. No,
when they start yelling at each other,
it's hilarious. They fucking goalie.
Cause sometimes I hear Goldie literally
next to me even though he's pressing the,
you know, the direct directly. I can
hear his voice because he's go, no,
you fuck told me I'm fuck I'm here
right now. What the fuck? Oh yeah.
I love those arguments. I just sit
in the back just dying of laughter.
Tell everybody's friendly. They're,
they're like, they like little, you know,
wives and husbands bitching at each other,
but they love each other. It's like,
oh yeah, super, super cool relationship.
There's no one that goes just
fucking guys here. Again,
like there's not one guy like that.
Everyone was super fucking cool.
The whole crew was awesome. Everybody,
all those guys in the production.
It's a greatest traveling road
road show ever. I mean we're like,
it's like a carnival, you know,
it's like a traveling carnival now.
It used to be a Vegas thing
for the longest time we
were doing most of them in,
in Vegas. Yeah. Man, I
can't believe that. Uh,
I almost walked away from it
almost. Huh? What Eddie does,
if you don't know is Eddie when, when
the fights are going on, there's,
there's always like a really important
position and move that we want to show in.
Um,
in the replay transition.
Transitioning setups could be striking
to you cause you do that too, right?
You don't just do not striking dental.
Need me for the striking.
I'll add my 2 cents on different angles,
but they don't need me.
What was the ground stuff?
If you watch like the one that he wasn't,
that was the one where Brock Lesnar
fought. Shane car went in the truck,
missed this really important transition.
They missed him getting out of the
half guard and going, this is one,
this is when I quit initially I've been,
I worked for the UFC for seven years.
It's been wonderful. I love
everybody. Dana, Lorenzo,
frank, their kids, everybody.
I love them to death.
They're the greatest motherfuckers on the
planet for doing what they did for MMA
in my life. I've been working with
them for seven years, you know,
and then I thought it was
time to move on and um,
I thought it was time to
leave the production truck
and started asking my fire.
I just want her to court,
you know,
it's time I had guys in the main card
and they started blowing up and I'm like
showing them because you're going
to help truck. Right, right. Well,
we found a way to let you do both,
which is really the ideal thing because
I quit for one shot. But the, the,
the play by the, uh, rather the
playback, you know, the replays,
they were missing like a lot
of the transitions. If you
don't understand Jujitsu,
if you don't know it,
then you're not going to be able to pick
up what was important about a series of
moves. All you're going to see
is, Oh, here's the checkmate,
but there's all this shit that's
going on before the checkmate.
And that's like what makes
MMA so interesting. Yeah.
You see like a guy setting
a guy up for something.
You see a guy goes for the single and
he grabs his leg and this is where he
fucked up.
He got his arm through and
here's the cinches it and
he rolls into the, you know,
the gator roll whenever,
whenever the technique you're looking at,
like what's cool is to be able
to see though all the steps,
especially when it's a difficult path to
see all the cool steps that the guy had
had to get through to get to what,
to what the final submission is.
Before I started supervising the replays,
if someone got caught in a
triangle that's a submission move,
the replay would be the guy
tapping and the triangle.
And I just got used to watching the
UFC. I would just rewind it, you know,
if you want to see the setup,
you can't wait for the replay.
You got to rewind it manually and check
out the setup. But when I started,
you know, the guys in the
truck, they're awesome guys.
They just don't train Jujitsu.
They just, they're just not,
they just don't understand. Yeah. And
like other sports, I mean, you know,
like if you're watching a boxing match,
you really need to see
the combination that finished the guy
off. That's what you need to say. Yeah,
well the Jujitsu, it's like it's,
you're never sure where to start it.
You know it as he started here too,
while here's where he ends it.
So let's just do it a couple of seconds
before that and then show the ending.
Yeah, yeah. Jujitsu for
people who don't know, it's,
it's one of the most
interesting things to,
to try to learn and get good at because
it's one of the most humbling things
where you realize that no matter what you
do, you're never going to know it all.
It's impossible. Like you can think,
you know all the punches in the world,
you know, you can box and
you know, you, you know,
there's only a certain amount of ways
you can move your hands when you're
hitting things with your
knuckles. You know, there's a,
there's a finite number and there's a
bunch of different combinations and a
bunch of different ways to set people
up and to hit people with things that
aren't expecting. There's no
taking away from the art of boxing.
But what Jujitsu is,
it's so weird.
It's like there's so many
positions to fuck somebody up.
There's so many ways to choke somebody
to take an arm to fuck their leg up to.
There's so many different counters.
There's so many different positions.
It's really never ending and that sounds
ridiculous when you tell people that
it's never ending,
but there's always new moves.
I've been doing Jujitsu now
since 98 and there's always,
there's shit now that nobody had then.
Nobody was doing anything. Just changing.
It's always evolving. Yeah.
It really is like chess.
It really is like a a like a game of
chess where you're trying to kill each
other. It's like chess,
but like the chess board,
like who's your boss? Alive grew
and it changed and always changing.
The shapes and the powers of the different
pieces always change and it's growing
in different directions and that's what
Jujitsu, he's like, yeah, that's also,
it's like it is like sense does make sense
because it's like it's super tactical
changes. Yeah. You might go row
with some big Chai wrestler, dude,
you got to roll a totally different game.
You know,
you go against some Jeff Glover character
and you're going to watch your p's and
q's.
Then next thing you're going with some
big giant gorilla guy and kind of try to
figure out how to attack them off your
back. There's totally different moves.
20 different people because they're new.
There's a new moves than the
actual world of chess is there.
Cagney winds come up. Now there's
like certain long shoulders, right?
There's no new moves in poker. There's
no new moves would be their strategies.
I think they probably, they, they're,
they're creative with their strategies.
I don't think,
I don't know chess enough to understand
how many different moves there are,
but I understand there's like
thousands if not millions.
I know forms even chat
like it's like chess,
but it's different and
they have different,
the pieces have different powers over.
So a Chinese checkers
version of chess really,
or just any,
I wonder this Chinese 10
times a hundred like it's super
crazy and super technical.
Watched a video once where
the gerd was in a whole room.
He's that guy that runs that.
A website with Marcello Garcia.
Marcel Garcia has their website with
God. Josh, I forget his last name. Well,
he was in the movie searching for
Bobby Fisher was based on his life.
I forget Josh's last name,
forgive me,
but he's a brown belt
under Marcello and he, uh,
he's fanatical about Jujitsu and he talks
about Jujitsu. He was a chess master.
So he talks about Jujitsu the same way.
He talks about chess.
And he was talking about
playing chess at one time.
He did a demonstration where he played
40 fucking games at the same time.
There's all these people in a room, I
think it was 40. Forgive me for them.
I have the wrong number. It's incred eat
a bunch of different games altogether.
I believe he said it was 40.
And he was wandering around this
room playing all these games.
Like you would move to the next table,
make his move, move to the next table,
make his move.
And he said that all these things just
kind of flowed together and they all
became one giant big game. So
yeah, if that's your answer, yeah,
you can pay play 40 fucking different
bad start stacking your chest.
That's a dude is taking
it to another level.
He was talking to my brain just started
hurting. I just wanted to take a nap.
I was listening to him talk about it. I
was like, I just want to take a nap at.
That dude has bad breath.
I bet he doesn't.
Everybody's fucking
perfect because a genius,
but he brushes and flosses.
He never skips a day. Uh,
and he's becoming a Jujitsu master
now too. He's obsessed with Jujitsu.
Can I say to him, can I plug? Is it a
good tug of pluck short seminar? Yeah.
Where's your job?
My next seminars in Rochester,
it's going to be a 10th planet Rochester,
the name of the Nma academies. Empire,
September 18th Saturday,
September 18th my new website's up
and running. 10th Planet, J J. Dot.
Com three techniques till October
1st all the techniques for free,
the whole world can happen.
Everything that's on the website,
so a that's till October
1st that's about it for me.
This website or this podcast is always
a strange podcast for people who don't
know anything about MMA or Jujitsu.
And you get into these conversations like
the ham sandwich in the truck and the
Douche bag. These are all a Jujitsu moves.
One of the funniest things about, uh,
you know, uh, training at 10th
planet is all the moves are,
almost all of them are ridiculously
named. I mean, some of them make sense,
you know,
but we have quite a few ridiculous names,
some names that I'm practicing control.
Anytime someone says that, I'm like,
dammit. Well, there's her crack and
control, which has come up in the WEC.
Frank Mir had to call it crack at it
controls. Yeah, he called it. He said,
this is what a Eddie Bravo refers to
as crack head control. Why is that?
I can control so bad of a, well, how
about when I said rape choke when I say,
but he got upset.
But that's what it is.
Why is anything upsetting if that's
what it is? What crack had controlled.
The reason why we called
the crack and controllers,
the idea was that it's a very
good position from the bottom.
You've got the guy tied up
good and proper, and that was,
it's a good position that you'd want
to be in if there's a crazy crack head
trying to beat the fuck out of you because
when you lock them up and crack head
control, he really doesn't have
any options to beat. He can't move.
He's completely helpless. So that's
why I was crying. He's tied up tight.
So we call it crack a control
and then there's retard control.
If the crack had controlling
working, right. Um,
torque control and crack head control,
probably around the same,
equal equal, but you used to think
that retard was better because of it.
Gable grip, maybe. I, you know,
when I should test, I should test.
There's a move that's going to get done
in the octagon eventually called the
Douche bag.
And it's one of the best ways to take
a guy's arm when you're in what we call
spiderweb. When you're in the, um,
when you're inside mount on a guy.
And you're trying to attack his
arm and you've got an arm and you,
you're lying on your back and he's
on his back and you can't get his arm
straightened out.
This is awesome.
Move called the Douche bag where you
take your foot and he'd stick it in the
dude's face like a Douche bag lit right,
isn't that his neck?
And then you pop it
out and it works great.
And eventually people are going to
figure it out and we were going to see a
douchebag and MMA and you know it before.
Wherever Deason happens,
I'm going to have to say this
is, I'm sorry, ladies and
gentlemen, hide your kids.
This is called the Douche
bag and that's what it is.
It's funny that Douche bag is a
bad word. That's hilarious. Well,
it's kind of unpleasant.
Jina cleansing device once
a clean someone's old PC.
Well it affects women commercials. I
think it offends some women. Women.
Some women just don't want you
talking about Vaginas, period dudes,
or very rarely upset when chicks are
talking about dicks and Dick Products,
and even if you're making fun of the
side of the size of Dicks do's don't get
upset. But any conversation that
a man has about a woman's vagina,
it better either be technical. He better
be the father of her children are,
you know,
and I'm saying like you can't just talk
about chicken posties so you call up
Douche bag. That's something
that cleans out of posting.
That's a fucking terrible insult.
Don't talk about my emptiness
all of the time. It's just empty.
There's no sac, there's no
ball. There's a whole empty, no,
that's a terrible way to look at it.
Emptiness. No, it's into enveloping.
It's just love covering your cock
and it's nothing. It's not nothing.
It's getting rid of the death thing.
It's closing in on the deck.
It's not nothing. That's
a very significant thing.
It's a trays. That space.
It's like a Venus flytrap. There will
be no space once the union has made.
That's why a girl with a, an excellent
pussy is always going to need a deck.
That was beautiful.
Thank you.
He's definitely standing up for women
like I represented the fucking scumbags
IMT brother. It's a beautiful thing.
Go like faking out the tree on you.
It looks like it's empty,
but really my grandmother raised me and
she's basically my best friend and I
just fucking can't see you
talk about women like that man,
that while she's still alive,
that was a move that dude's would do
where they would stand up for women.
Just just to be a con when
it didn't make any sense.
There was one time where I was at a bar
with a cup of comics and this one dude
who wasn't very funny,
but he was very self righteous.
These girls were drunk as fuck and
they were just being really loud and
obnoxious at the comedy show and then
they decided to drive home and I'm like,
oh, check out these fucking pigs. That's
what I said, you know? That's what I felt.
I felt like there were pigs.
There were loud angry,
mean chicks heckling at the comedy show
and then they were getting into a car to
drive home and the guy's like,
hey man,
I don't want to be around you if you
want to talk about women like that,
what are you talking about that
talking about women in general,
I'm talking about these three shitty
human beings that had been yelling and
they're drunk as fuck and they're going
to drive and maybe slam into a fucking
family and you know, blow a
car up. They were heckling
in. You smashed him. Oh yeah.
Well I don't remember if I smashed him
cause he's are the early days of my
heckling. Heckling skills
were not that good back then.
This was 1991
90 91 I only have been doing
comedy a couple of years.
What do you personally think about
chail son's ability to talk shit fucking
unprecedented. I've never seen a
professional athlete talk as much shit.
Get me to laugh as much.
Chill son and made me laugh.
More than 90% of the comedians I know
when he would start talking shit.
How about with fucking Jim Rome? He
chill son says that he thinks that lamb,
Lance Armstrong took drugs
and he cheated and you know,
he took steroids and that's why
I lost the ball, the cancer.
So he realizes after he said that, that
you probably shouldn't have said that.
Like he's saying all kinds of
crazy shit to get attention.
It's a fucking genius ploy. I mean, the
guy's a smart dude, right? He's running,
he runs for office as a Republican.
He says crazy shit. Like, you know,
I'm a Republican and I don't lie on
my back when a man between my legs,
like he says crazy shit like
that and it's funny. So anyway,
he says all this shit about Lance
Armstrong and then he realized it's fuck,
what do I do? What do I do?
So he brainstorms, says,
I'm just going to deny it.
So he gets on Jim Rome show.
He goes, I did not say that.
Lance Armstrong and I
have known lance. I, uh,
worked out with Lance at
the Nike Training Facility.
It's already pleased them for the
fucking tape. And she'll send, he goes,
maybe I have a bad connection,
but that doesn't sound like me.
That fell a sounded Hispanic fucking home.
He's still her dude.
When he,
when he gets up and does those
question and answer things,
nobody's better than handle. He's, he's
got prepared material. He's good. Wow.
He's a fucking genius man. He's the best
shit talker ever. If he won, God damn,
that guy would be witches.
Fuck that guy is the UFC middleweight
champion would be the richest,
the biggest draw in all of MMA because
no one could talk shit like him.
But Brock Lesner is always going to be
the biggest just cause he's Brock Lesner.
He's just fucking larger
than life monster character.
But Chael Sonnen would be right up there
with all those Sarah Palin punch bags,
all those fucking crazy
tea party assholes.
And you think you'd have water lock on?
Yeah, I would hate it if I had to go.
No Shit talking contest with shell son.
And I was like, damn, this might get ugly.
This guy's got a paddling. Shit. Got a
battle. I'm like, wow, this would be on,
I don't know man. I wouldn't
like it. I don't like it.
That's it. That's a tough one
I would like is there,
is there a sport like that where he
just talks shit on someone like can just
come at them.
You can just contact your mom hurt
someone you can't hurt someone here knows
themselves like real shit.
Like talking like a Yo Mama show but
you're really required and shit talking
really is is calling somebody out on
something or getting somebody on some shit
that they're not addressing.
But if you are addressing
everything and you're honest,
it's very hard to talk shit on someone
who was pretty honest about themselves
cause you talk shit on like a,
like a good comic, you know,
Talk Shit on a Doug Stan
hope or something like that.
Doug will tell you what's wrong with
him a hundred times worse than you could
ever tell him what's wrong with
you and then he'll fuck with you.
Like if you pick on like Doug, Doug will
go, you know about being an alcoholic.
Doug,
we'll go deep into how fucking crazy he
has deep into what's wrong with being an
alcoholic. Deep into how wiki fields, when
he takes that six beer of the morning,
he'll go deep into it and
then he'll turn on you.
You'll fuck cause he just took away.
You're not going to say anything
better than what he said about himself.
And then he's going to shred you cause
he's a hundred times smarter than you and
he's done this everyday of his
life for the last 20 years.
It's really like doing Jujitsu against a
white belt. It's like ever take a break.
I don't think monster dogs. Yeah, he
takes a little breaks. He goes to Bisbee.
He's been talking about moving to
Austin, Texas. We're talking about Doug,
Stan hope, fantastic comedian
and good friend of mine.
And we were cohosts on one of
the worst shows on television,
the second version of the man show.
A couple of haters on the internet or on
a thread about my website or something
like that.
And one guy comes on and says,
why don't you post his match with Leo
Vira to ask to watch a real ass whipping
or something like that. How
come he doesn't post that? Oh,
this is your match with Leo
Vieira. Yeah. And I'm like, dude,
why don't you check out
the intro to my DVD? I,
I show me getting fucked up. I put it on
my intro. Dude, why don't you watch that?
That's funny. How many
people do that is, um,
drug Galinos speaking of which is fighting
tonight. He's on the strike force.
Yeah, he's, he's making a comeback.
How old is that dude? You know what?
I didn't even know I
heard about Broccolini.
My whole like a whole
Jujitsu crew shock stage.
Someone 42 or something and he's not
that old. Okay. How old John Shock? Yeah.
I guess John Talks about 42 as well.
And I didn't know who the whole seeing
all these old school Jujitsu guys.
It's cool seeing all these good
guys and, oh, and you know what?
Who the fuck if there's another fight
that just got announced that it's a
fucking awesome fight. Oh,
Efrain Escudero is fighting that.
That sick Jujitsu kid, who's that kid
who just fought recently on versus
the Brazilian, Really Young
Kid, 20 years old, hot, which
I don't know who this is. What some
of you folks out there in la La land,
you know who it is?
Put that shit up on Twitter.
I don't know what the guy's name was,
but anyway,
he's going to fight Efrain in Austin,
Texas. See Spikes in Austin. Yeah.
There's a couple of Brazilians coming
out on the prelims that people don't get
to watch generally.
Sometimes they throw them up,
but I think I know you're talking about,
there's a couple of lightweight
Brazilians that are on fire right now.
I forget their names though.
Yeah, I forget the dude's
name. I think one is like,
like Charles Oliva Charles all the
bat. Is it that? Is that dude? Okay.
That's exactly the kid we're
talking about and he submitted,
who the hell are they submit?
I forget. God was good though.
He locked him up quick. Anyway,
dude, I'm the worst fucking
the worst with, there's so many different
names are so many different dudes.
I want to give a quick shout out to Matt
Horowitz for choking out Talis latest
last week. For those of you who missed
it, it was the biggest win of his career.
Nobody deserves it more than Matt.
He works harder than anybody I know.
And he has, you know, no one has
an open mind like a Matt Horwood.
So I love you man. If you don't
know who Matt Horwitz was, Mara,
which is one of the weirdest guys
ever that's fighting. And he uh,
he was in the UFC for a bit and lost a
couple of squeaky close decisions and got
the boot, but he's just the strangest,
coolest, nicest, friendliest guy.
And every time you talk to him it's like,
well,
the universe is a beautiful place and
stars and galaxies are all connected
together and one,
uh,
timely pulse all bringing us
closer to love and to the future.
Yeah. And you're like, oh, okay. All
right man. He's like, but he believes it.
Like he says shit like that.
Like that's really what's on his mind.
The Universe is a beautiful thing.
Fucking who has,
who has less ego than that guy? No
one. He has zero ego and his ground,
I mean this standup needs
a lot of work still,
but his wrestling and his Jujitsu
especially is looking dangerous.
He didn't tell us late,
does not just to catch him and
take his back and strangle him,
but to put them in bad positions
over and over again and survive.
When he was in that arm trial,
he had his back a couple of times.
He had him in the Juke
claw. He, he, he did great.
[inaudible] did not expect him
to be that good on the ground.
I think he underestimated
how good his ground game his,
I think he looked at some other fights
and he thought he was gonna be able to
stale mate with them in the ground.
But you know, Harwich just attacks.
He attacks his fucking guard looks
so good. Matt, when he went to that,
the Hayzlett,
which is the move off the Omoplata,
which is a shoulder lock
rolling with him is amazing.
He calls out,
like in every position he'll call
out and we'll talk about what the,
what's going on in the position,
what he should do and what I'm
gonna do those whales right now,
he's got me in crack at control. He's
trying to get my hand to the mat. Oh,
dissolve B work.
And now he's probably going to try to
clear my neck and get me in to invisible
call. I should probably keep my
posture up. I mean he'll know.
Narrate the whole role. It's
incredible. Yeah. He's uh,
maybe he does that all the time. I want
to give a shout out to the frogmouth owl.
The frog mouth. Did you find it? Yes. The
pup on frog now, is that what it's called?
Yeah. Did you get a picture of
it? A p. U. A. N. A. P. U. A. N.
This is what we were talking
about earlier in the show,
ladies and gentlemen is fucking Mexican.
Which p you what?
P? A. P. U. A. N. Frogmouth.
So if I can give a shout out to Tyrone to,
what does that mean,
Tyron? Oh, well, here's the thing. Okay.
It doesn't really look like that. No,
not really.
I mean it looks weird but it doesn't look
nearly as weird as the one that was in
that video. Look, this just looks
like a fucked up like an hour.
Maybe the one was just an extreme
version of it. Yeah, it's kind of like a,
I don't know if you saw that picture
that's floating around right now,
that pig that looks like the faces
like gotten in a car accident,
but that's actually what the face looks
like. It looks speak in a car accident.
Heidi montages,
plastic surgeon died this
week cause he was twittering.
That's about his dog and he fell off
a cliff. That was his last Twitter.
It was last quarter,
if that was his last Twitter was
right before he fell off the car.
He was on top of a mountain with his
dog and he took this photo of a his dog
like overlooking this sweet like hill
on PCH and that was his last Twitter.
And then he, uh, something happened
where he fell off the side of the road,
probably involving a
cell phone, but, well,
how do you know that it wasn't everyone's
saying that he was twittering right
when the crash happened,
which most likely he was twittering
and he fell off the cliff.
You don't just fall off the exact,
the exact quote was moments before he
twittered and then they showed that.
So you say no.
What are you saying?
I don't think he was
twittering while I was driving.
Is that what you're saying? She
was, what are you talking about?
What other explanation do
you have for the [inaudible]?
You show crazy, Brian. You just argued
that you don't even have any evidence.
Of course he was doing,
what's your evidence
[inaudible] off a cliff?
The evidence is he twittered
when he was in his car. Right.
That means he was driving and
twittering for sure. Okay.
If you're in your car and that's when the
Twitter goes off and it's right before
you crash the fucking,
but he's saying,
he's saying how do you prove that the
trial wasn't right before he got what
calls? No, no,
so so the proof is he drove off the cliff.
That's the proof is in the moments here
earlier, he was triggered that together.
Even if the Twitter making the Twitter
didn't cause him to drive off the cliff,
the type of person that would be in his
fucking car twittering about his dog,
that type of person is not
paying attention and if
it's not that it's going to
be something else.
It's going to be him trying to make a
phone call or him getting a phone call or
him changing the station or him looking
for something on the navigation system.
He's a fucking idiot or he would have
a lot of hatred for this guy that died.
That Twitter makes me crazy when I
see people texting and twittering when
they're driving,
it drives me nuts.
Some fucking lady did this
when she was working for,
to the Improv and she was
taking me to the publicity.
She was a very nice lady and in
the middle of fucking the highway,
this bitch starts steering with her
knees to hands on under the texting.
I go, hey, hey, hey, you got to
stop. Like you can't do it. She goes,
I'm really good at this.
I'm like,
the fuck you are the fuck you really
good at this? Like stop. Pull over.
Get me out of the car. There's no way
you're not paying attention. That's nuts.
You're going to have two hands
off the fucking steering wheel.
You're going to be steering with
your knees while you do this.
She just touching it with her knuckles,
like kind of like sort
of steering like this.
If you're going to text while you drive,
you got to do it with one hand.
You can come on. What the fuck
are you thinking? You know what?
I'll be honest with you,
man. I'll be honest with you.
I text through fucking Mulholland.
Ah.
I tend to go into my hall and
stoned as fuck. Stop doing that. No,
no. I'm listening to is what you
gotta do, man, is what you gotta do.
That's what I do when I get in my car.
I throw my fucking phone in the seat.
I don't even look at that shit. And if
it, if it rings, it goes through the boot,
your system. If it rings, I can press a
button and talk to somebody, but I don't,
I don't fuck with
[inaudible] like this in La.
It's way different than it is in your,
like this probably is because you did it.
There was,
there were times that you did do it and
you fucking looked up and you're on the
other side of the fucking road.
Well, I've never done that.
Never got to those points. No,
I've never done that. But there's,
I don't like the temptation to do
it because when I'm at home and
my phone is just sitting there,
I want to check Twitter, but I'll
find myself checking Twitter. I,
there's a million things
that I should be doing,
but because I have the access to it,
because it's right there,
it's very hard to avoid. For me.
I'm very indulgent like that.
So I don't want to be in my car, like
looking through Twitter. I know me, I,
I would do it. I would start
replying to people in Ohio though.
That driving was so boring
that you could read a book.
Seriously do that because
anything can happen.
I try to time it and red
lights led lights them up.
12 you can get one out at a red light.
That's totally off the record as long
as long as you're not doing it while
you're actually driving. They'll
try to finish the last three words.
Just call you the last three words.
We're almost there.
We're almost there and then you're
driving. Dude. It's, it's very dangerous.
They got to have voice activated.
They do. That's the future they do.
Then the Android, the new android system.
Apparently it works not just for that.
It works for navigation and worked
for a bunch of different things.
You can write notes to yourself. Iphone
is going to handle that shit. Maybe. Well,
you know what I phone does a
lot of cool shit that I like.
I liked the fact that you can record
notes. The the, the little recording icon,
what is it called? Can I see your
notes? The one that's on the front page,
record voice memos. Voice memos and that
shit. That's what it is. And voice memos.
Keys up to your computer.
So I record shows and then I'll have to
do is stick it into my computer or if I
have an idea I recorded on that,
I stick it into my computer and I have a
record of it and then I back it up with
mobile meme. It's like you can't fuck
with that. Convenient really quick.
It's the convenience you could
have if you want it to. Yeah,
I mean if you want to make a really shitty
CD and release it for free, this car,
you can drive around and listen
to it unless you got it all.
Know Apple does a lot of cool shit,
but this Google android man, those,
those fucking things are coming close man.
They've got a lot of cool new
features that apple doesn't have yet.
Does iPhone or apple, do they make
like a, like a Badass car system?
That is, no, that's a good middle
of the Red Apple Car Stereo too.
That would be the shit.
Well you kind of already have line.
It's called the iPhone. I don't use
that at the same way. You don't,
can't just put down,
I mean, yeah, you can,
can't just tell it like my Lexus,
I can just press a button and tell
it where I want to go. I could say,
you know Irvine well yeah,
using gps software on the iPhone.
I have navigation where it has like,
you know,
but you have to touch your phone off
to just touch a button on the steering
wheel.
If we could get it so that everything
was voice operated and you didn't have to
take your hand off the steering
wheel ever. That would be the move.
The problem with the Va,
the iPhone is you've got to fuck around
with this little tiny device and focus
on this little thing that's right in front
of you as opposed to this whole world
that's you're headed towards
you going 70 miles an hour.
That's what fucks you up
about driving and texting.
You focus on this little thing and
then every time you look up you have to
regain all your bearings.
Is that
we've accepted, um, talking while we're
driving. You know what the other one,
if he got a headset or you got to assist
system like yours, we're allowing that.
As long as you got your eyes on the road,
you can talk because then they would
have to outlaw talking the guy sitting
shotgun, right? Like you
can't talk in the car.
And the worst thing when dad's in that,
if you couldn't talk in your car,
it was too dangerous. When you have
it over your loud stereo systems,
it's like you're in their rural listening.
So if they're downtown and it's like busy
or you wouldn't be allowed to sing to
a song, um, I listened.
It should be blown.
I talked to [inaudible] on my phone
all the time. She just started.
I don't think it's any different than
me having a person in the car that I'm
having a conversation with.
What about,
what about outlawing plan drums on your
steering wheel? Doesn't do that, right?
They're going to have to outlaw that
shit, right? You're not fully controlled.
The vehicle cop can pull your hopes,
your fucking listening to some rock.
You don't have to have two hands
on the steering wheel, right.
You don't even have to have two hands.
You don't have to be 10 and
two you have to be seatbelt.
And that's about it really.
I never really knew.
I mean they assume that you're
going to control the vehicle,
but I don't think that you have
to control in any particular way.
If you want to get fruity and have like
a little ring that you stick your finger
through and drive around town like this,
you can't wear shades while you
drive all the suicide wheel.
Do you remember a thing called the
suicide wheel? When I was a kid, well,
you know a couple of dudes who had hot
rods had a little thing called a suicide
wheel and it was just like a little tiny
wheel that was on the steering wheel.
And you would, you would steer
with this little tiny wheel.
But that wheel spun
itself. Yeah. So like you,
this fucking car would spin all over
the place holding on to this thing.
They called it a suicide wheel. That's
crazy. I think that's the Cholo thing. No,
no. Hot Rod steering wheels.
When I was a kid, I a chain,
you know the little chains,
all any of my friends want wanted was
one of those fucking stupid old American
hot rods. That's all anybody wanted.
All my old cars, my first cars,
my first car was a 1973 Chevelle
and then I had a 68 four, four,
two and then I had a Buick
Skylark and I had a Chevelle all,
all and a Barracuda.
All my cars were like old hot rods.
All of a sudden I think them
changed still also the fucking dope.
Those old cars, man, they suck.
Like my Barracuda sucks driving it.
It's the handle like shit. They're,
they're totally dangerous. They don't,
they don't break as well as very, cause
they're super, super heavy. You know,
there's this, it's like a
really antiquated sort of a
way of constructing a car.
But,
but there's something about a man,
there's something about those cars to
rappers bling out their steering wheel
ever. Totally. Yeah.
Diamonds on their standing tall kinds
of bees on their steering wheel. Man.
You can watch movies on their stand
where ever watched MTV cribs nine I the
steering wheels on there fucking with a
big like seven inch screen where they're
watching videos on their steering wheel.
That should be illegal, not illegal.
Can fucking town driving around some
other joint watched Scarface had you
fucking steering wheel off.
It's bad that Eddie Bravo's texted this
motherfucker's watching scar face for
the 1 billion of time.
That was like the best episode of curb
my enthusiasm when I'm crazy eyes. Kyla,
you remember when Larry David met crazy
eyes killer and he had him over the
house. He's explaining this floor
is my floor is made out of some,
some flow of shit, so I'm just, we got
a big flat screen. We play Ska phase
24 hours a day,
like 24 seven do you ever see the one
where he gets caught with a hooker while
an weed in the car? No. That's the
best way I saw that one. That's,
that's a good one. Yeah, the old
ones. The best ones because a genius,
it's not that many dudes like that.
It's so hard to get really good at
making those kinds of comedies. You know,
it's like every time there's
a new sit comments out, she's,
I want to give it a shot.
I want to give him a chance.
But how many people are good at that? You
know, so hard. Especially on regular TV.
It's so hard to do anything
controversial on regular TV.
Now have you heard bait car? What does
that then they show bait car bait car.
Yeah. It's where spell it
[inaudible] see ar. Yeah.
It's where they take a
car and they set it up.
They've done it in like cops before
where they take it and set it up and then
like these people go to steal it and
everything locks. I saw that. Good.
It sounds great. That's a great
pitch. But they can't, um,
they don't want to go
on high speed chases.
So what they do is they just turn off
the car. Yeah. But that's kind of cool.
Just pull that trapped in cars like that
though. I don't want a high speed chase.
Yeah. Slamming into some fucking kids.
Chase, man. No, it's not. What I tivo
watched one, I go, I erased all that
shit. Like, oh, this is boring. Tivo.
Steven Seagal law man. No.
Oh, you've got off. Yes.
You've got to get that on DVD or
get it on iTunes. You gotta get it.
You got to get it. It's Jeevan Seagal.
He's a real cop. Steven Seagal was a cop.
That's incredible.
Now what do you think,
what do you think about Anderson
Silva walking out at Stevenson,
I think as a seal was awesome.
It was a co like a funny thing.
If it was, he will never tell
you. He would never admit it,
but we are like a genuine fan too.
When I went to interview Anderson
Silva at Black House and Silva,
I'm not bullshitting for a half an hour,
was in character as Helio Gracie
for half an hour. I would love to.
They said that he had done it for the
last two hours and he was yelling Jujitsu
and he starts talking in Portuguese,
all these different things
yelling out and he's doing it.
No bullshit for 30 fucking straight
minutes. He's a, he's a joker.
Man thinks everything is funny.
That guy has always playing around.
So what do you think Steven Seagal thought
you thought he was like, damn it was,
he honored like Shit.
He really wants me badly think
to Anissa Silva's taking notes.
Why Steven Seagal is telling
him how to kick people in India.
That's the dumbest thing in the world.
The Anderson Silva may very well be the
greatest fighter that has ever graced
the face of the planet.
There may not be another guy ever that
has ever lived that is on that guy skill
level. And that's no bullshit.
That's, that's some real shit.
And you really think that he
wants to listen to Steven Seagal,
tell him in a twist wrist and shit.
That's crazy shit. That's his,
he was going to do it. Someone's got
to walk out with fucking Chet leads.
It's funny, but I think he
probably respected him as
a martial arts maybe. Look,
people can tell you all kinds of
things and they might be retarded.
They might be half crazy,
but every now and then they'll say
something that you can use. You know,
every now and then p I've had a lot of
dumb people say some really useful shit
to me. I just, it's like a matter of
being able to cherry pick that out of the,
out of the other diarrhea they're spewing
man with all the crazy techniques that
are being proven that were
once thought of as jokes.
Like we were talking about this before,
all the weird shit at first we never
thought that head kicks whatever work and
then you know Marco, who else? Uh Oh
no, no. Margolis was the leg kicks,
leg kicks in work mark who ask him prove
that now everyone liked kicks, judo,
judo before Caro and then there was no,
there was no head of was Judah shall
we spent was the first guy to head kick
everyone. At one point we thought
head kicks would never work.
They would never work in real fights
like that was all for the movies.
No one kicked anybody. They had that
you're going to get taken down there.
Low percentage.
Now people are not getting knocked off
a bunch of different things and then
those balls that the new one is done.
Yeah. Kuda kicking with the front kick.
We thought those kicks were jokes like
a few years ago and now have never did
because semi shield has been taking guys
out with that in k one forever and I
think most people look at the fact that
he was so tall like that's why they work.
That's what I thought. I go,
you know what? He's so tall.
He's making these weird kicks work.
He's just going to poke people.
I didn't quite think that.
I thought it was real because he uses
it on high level guys and most people
thought Badr Hari with that.
Most of the stuff on those
traditional karate kicks were a joke.
Do you know there's a thread
where people are fighters?
Only magazine said that he's going to
come back to the UFC and he's talking
about, I read that, I don't know, and
then make to 65 and then the latest huge.
Now we've had turning sidekicks
proven turning like Kung Lee.
He's proving the turning side kicks are
legit after other people have done it
too.
But now it's totally legit.
Now you've got Anthony Pettis doing
the fucking Jackie Chan kicks. Yeah,
they're crazy kick that he did was he
came down literally where he was like
touching the ground and kicked like
a split over his head and, and, and,
and fucking caught Shane Roller. It was
one of the craziest kicks I've ever sold.
I mean,
who the fuck knows?
Maybe that Akiko grab your fucking hand
and twist it and dude flips a Kito Shit.
Does that have a chance?
A practicing it?
There's people [inaudible] got a guy
who was like a real good wrestler with a
real good bass who really understood a
Kiddo and you let them grab a hold of you.
Yeah,
I bet he could do it.
It's just not that high
percentage grabbing risks and
twisting them and flipping
people by twisting. Is
that possible? Why not man?
Look if they can do it in demonstration.
If a body can physically move that way
in the right scenario with the right dude
who's the right amount of skill and
strength and he pulls it off in the right
dude who's not suspecting it and
gets caught and goes with it. Yeah,
it can happen.
Anything can happen.
Do you think we're going to see it in
the next couple of years? Probably not.
I think we'll see some wing Chung,
some fucking chain fists.
Someone someone's going to win Chung
from the mountain could work like some
trapping hands from the mouth
back to us from the mount.
We really haven't seen that cause remember
in the amount everybody punched the
same way,
but then the day they punched with hooks,
like just this sloppy hook wing Chung
actually makes sense to practice from the
amount because it's all that little close
hand fighting and you can't move and
Bob and weave like you can't inboxing.
You really kind of stuck in a
rigid position while you're,
while you're jacking a guy.
So he's really probably maybe the art
for it.
If a guy was a really bad ass wing Chun
Guy and he got awesome entry Jitsu and
developed a sick mount, he'll
probably, what I'm talking about,
wing Chung from the mouse trapping hands
from the mountain might work only makes
sense if you look,
there were like lost records and
that's what wing Chung was for.
Just people just started
doing it. Standing. It's
never going to work. Standing.
If you imagine,
imagine we'd see some dude mounts somebody
and just fucking do what are these?
Their Hammer fisting. Remember?
Then the hammer fist came in,
so people were starting to hammer fist
from the mount. No one does that before.
Eel Hammer fisted jaws put people out
left and right all over the place.
There's jumping hammer fist on
a guy that just got knocked out.
Those are the deadliest ones.
This is something that you, uh,
you tweeted me about the other day that
I wanted to talk about. Um, you, uh,
you watched that, uh, Bryant Gumbel
thing on brain damage. Oh my God.
Whoa.
I didn't realize how common brain damages,
the crazy thing is you expect it from
football players because they're, they're,
you know, getting a concussion in football
is totally normal. They, you know,
like Steve Young had like five or six
concussions, you know, Troy Aikman,
they finally go cause they have
too many fucking concussions.
They go like MMA fighters do quarterbacks.
Like how many more times can
this guy get knocked out?
And then they finally just
can't do it no more. You know,
and when they get knocked out too,
it's like they got hit by a bus,
but now they've proven this is the
Bryant Gumbel thing. They just proved.
You would think that, you know, there's a
lot of these, a lot of football players,
they end up losing all their, they get
end up going through a slow paralysis,
a slow,
it's the slowest desk sentence ever.
Steve Smith used to be the running
back for the Raiders. I remember him.
He can't move at all. He stares at
a computer and spells out words.
It was amazing. That's, you've got a
Tivo. It's Bryant gumbles real sports.
They finally found proof
of why this is happening.
Because every time you get jacked in,
the brain are getting knocked out.
There's some toxic proteins that form
on your brain and if they leak into your
spine, you're fucked. It's like Lou
Gehrig's disease. It's the same thing.
I think it's a l s or something like that.
And you were telling us,
you were telling me that Lou
Gehrig has knocked down like, like,
like it doesn't make sense.
Lou Gehrig play baseball.
Like he's not playing football too.
Well that's the most gentle sport ever.
But it turns out that he had,
he got knocked out brutally
six different times.
They reported it in newspapers,
brutal concussions where
he got beamed by fastballs,
slid into second base and collided heads
with the other guy where he's knocked
out for five minutes and
they needed smelling salts
to wake him up six different
times. And he never took a day off. He,
you know, I don't want to talk about,
they always talk about a strict and Lou
Gehrig streak where he played like over
2000 games straight. So he knew when he,
he would come back from the concussion.
Always play the next game. Oh,
we never took any time off.
So that's why he died of what he died.
He had some protein talks and stuff.
I could be, I don't remember a total,
either people get it by the way,
who've never had, we should just clarify
it. People who've never had impact.
Like Stephen Hawking's.
Stephen Hawking's has Lou Gehrig's disease
and obviously nobody fucking beat the
shit out of that dude. You never know.
Maybe as a kid he got smacked around.
[inaudible]
a kid.
Imagine that smart world. You Ain't
smart. You think you're fucking smart.
The fuck. Shut the fuck up. Steven.
Go to your room before I beat your
ass with those fucking science books.
I will beat your ass if you read
another fucking physics book.
He probably got his ass
beat. Stephen. Stephen.
I don't think that probably happened.
I'm just going to state my opinion.
Probably. Did you think it
did Brian? Yeah. Have you
ever been knocked unconscious?
No. Never. We'll check this out.
Soccer players from me get from, uh,
the collisions with like
60 mile an hour balls.
They're hitting them with
their head all the time.
Soccer players go down left
and right from the ship.
They go through a slow process
where there's certain death,
there's no way you can load that.
People need to realize,
is this not even concussions?
It's just repeated blows to the head.
Jarring blows the hat. And the
crazy thing is check, check,
check out this coincidence
and how common it really is,
is there's this football player,
they would have, you know,
gathered diseases of slowly dying.
His best friend was a boxer,
a great white hope boxer that fought all
the greats. Larry Holmes, George Joseph,
I forget this guy's name.
He had a mustache famous white box or
that got knocked down. Canada. Yes.
George Avala. Yes. That guy. His best
friends, his football player. Uh,
you know, he watched them. He fucking
watched him go through the chimney,
still not dead, but now he finally
can't move. Nothing slowly. No, no.
He died and as soon as he
died, this motherfucker gets
it. The boxer has it now.
He can walk slowly.
He's still walking in is slowly
losing control of his muscles,
tend to flatter crazy,
you know,
then they really need to take that into
consideration when it comes to MMA and
boxers, MMA fighters, you know, we, we
don't, we haven't seen that happen yet.
We haven't seen the one case of a
guy getting really fucked up. But if,
if people keep fighting,
it's going to keep happening.
There's no way to avoid
it in boxing and boxing.
They get hit so hard in the head,
they just die on the way after the
fight on the way to the hospital.
They don't even go through Lou Gehrig's
disease. They just die away quicker.
Well you actually know what
I'm [inaudible] actually,
no, they're unrelated.
That's a different, different
type of ailment. When you, um,
the problem with these guys
that are dying is there,
almost all of them are cutting
weight. No, but what I'm saying is,
I'm not saying it's the same thing.
I'm just saying it's totally different,
but it's worse than the
slow death cause they just,
whatever it is from cutting weight and
all that shit, that means you die out.
Some guys get the slow death, but the
guys who get the slow death aren't,
it's a different sort of a damage. Gerald
McClellan. Mcclellan, what about that?
Yeah. Mcclellan cut. Uh,
nasty amount of weight.
Mcclellan was like famous for
being like one of the biggest guys.
I think he was fighting one 75, right?
One 75. And he was so, he was a crock guy.
It was his fight with Nigel
Benn. Yeah, Nigel Benn.
He hit it and Nigel band with
everything but the kitchen sink.
But Nigel band wouldn't
go away until there.
He's a black guy with the Jheri curl. I
remember that Shit. He's said Jerry curls.
What? His dreadlocks. Well No, no,
he didn't have dreadlocks and
may have just the sweat and
it looked like a Jerry curl.
Let it look like he was
fighting with the Jerry crowd.
Didn't much blood green fight with
a Jheri curl. I think you did. Yes.
And the Mike Tyson with Jerry curls.
Those are old school man.
You remember with the, they had to
make that shit illegal though, right?
Jheri curls getting in
everyone's eyes. Oh, it's greasy,
isn't it? Yeah. Oh yeah man.
Yeah, that's tough. It's
really nasty. Hey, any of your,
straighten your hair with ah,
like conditioner or are straightening
black person hair straightening.
Know it's craziness. I just blow dry
it straight. I think it's dreads, bro.
I'm gonna need to simply,
yeah, he's got like dreads.
He's just got like some crazy natty hair.
Does that Nigel band?
He was a bad mother
fucker. Yeah, you're right.
He got knocked down like shit
like twice in the first round.
The first round was a war
watch. Nigel Benn, Gerald
McClellan. Watch that fucking,
that's the fight that
change Roy Jones style.
A lot of people think Roy
Jones like saw that fight.
It was like fuck it and hurt. You know,
watch his friend get all fucked up.
He's the guy who's going
to fight eventually.
That was like a super food that
was being talked about. You know.
Who Do you think had the best defense
ever? Inboxing. Pronounce Whitaker. No.
Hopkins huddled than pronounce. Yeah.
I think Hopkins has the best defense.
Pernell Whitaker could stand in front
of guys. Yeah. And he could, you know,
he could keep from getting
hit roll with guys,
but he wasn't doing that
to a guy like Hopkins.
You know what I liked about what I like
about Hopkins is Hopkins doesn't take
any stupid chances. You know, a lot of
guys think that certain styles are boring.
You know, like, like some people you know,
think that, you know, like, like, like,
like the John Fitch Style, uh, John
Fitch wins ugly takes guys down.
Pizza my pounds on them.
But sometimes it goes to decision,
but I think that still beautiful.
That guy's imposing he shit on that guy.
And what I like about a guy like Hopkins,
he shuts everybody else's bullshit down,
hardly ever gets hit,
stands right in front of you.
And if you're like a Felix Trinidad,
that opens up too much on him.
He'll break you,
break you into knock you the fuck out. And
if you tighten up like Roy Jones, okay,
you'll get to decision, but that
guy just beat you, you know?
And he does that to everybody.
I like John Fitch,
but I'll like them a lot more once it
gets really good with submissions are
going to be a giant always fighting
though he's fighting monsters.
She fought Tiago owls to Tiago
is so fucking hard to finish.
He's so big and strong and
powerful, you know? I mean,
just even hold that motherfucker down.
It's getting like near impossible.
If he didn't come in overweight
and looked so fucking drawn out,
you know who not. This guy's a beast, man.
You gotta try the fought Koscheck.
That guy's a fucking savage.
You got to strive to be.
If you're grappling and you want to
maximize your crown fighting skills,
strive to be as good as Marcella Garcia.
It's real simple.
Marcella Garcia is the greatest
Nogi grappler of all time.
No one's even fucking close.
He's a master of many submissions.
Speaking of which Jack Arrays
fighting Tim Kennedy. Tonight.
We're going to watch the shows by,
of course,
right afterwards we get some pizza
shop your way. Another motherfucker,
but technically,
even though Zachary beat Marcella Garcia,
he's just my overall Marcella
Garcia has more polished,
mastered weapons, so should strive.
Yeah, but it's pretty close. I agree,
but or is still fucking incredible.
He is awesome.
Definitely top five in the world
at submissions. Heart is crazy too.
Here's the guy who got his arm broken
by Hydro Gracie [inaudible] Gracie broke
his arm and he finished the
fucking match and won on points.
He was willing to let his fucking arm
get broken and it's Hugh Jitsu match.
I mean, what do they get paid for
a Jujitsu match, you know, nothing.
And this guy's like, go ahead,
snapped my arm, get a tree. Asai
free siu would row meal.
I get to mix that.
The top guys get granola too with them.
Not everyone.
There's savages competing in a fucking
one of the best sports in the world that
nobody cares about. It's one
of the weirdest things that
people don't care about.
Submission, grappling. You would think
that, you know, boxing is pretty popular.
I mean obviously hugely popular on
its own and it's a segment of MMA.
Why isn't submission grappling?
Why hasn't someone figured out a way to
promote high level submission grappling
lacks Jocko raid like Marcella Garcia,
Jake shields,
those types of dudes who just
attack guys and finish them off.
That shit's excited. Or Rico chipper
rally, the professional submission league.
It looked great and he needed
Randy couture to uh, you know,
be the poster boy and it would've
worked with Randek a Turk is Radica tour
retired for a minute and
Radica tourists that, okay,
I'm retired but I'm going to still want
to compete and submission grappling as
the way to go. And Rico
trip, I was like, man,
I'm going to make this
guy headline every show.
And he did a couple shows
and they're awesome.
Rico chip really had an awesome show.
He just needs a, he needs a headline.
Ricoh, Ricoh, if you're
listening out there,
anybody that knows Rico get Marcello
Garcia to headline your shit.
The revolve it around Marcello Garcia.
Yeah, but that's the differences.
Randy coture is huge with
the general population.
You can have reacted to her
grappling in general population.
You could make it successful with Marcello
Garcia. He's that big. It's huge. No,
but he's not with regular people.
Randy couture,
successful with regular human things.
Definitely the initial, the initial blow,
you know, it would be from the [inaudible]
tour event that the problem is,
that's what you need in order
to get something off the ground.
You need a guy like that.
You can't just take chances and let
people eventually grow to love it because
you're running out of money. I think
you could do that with Marcella Garcia.
You can't. You can't do
something like, you know,
you have to have something that people
are gonna look at all these fucking guys
that are fighting and Bella tour,
they got killers and Bella Tor,
they got these distro get Hector Lombard
is fighting and Bella to our crushing
people. Nobody's paying attention. No
one's talking about it. Hector Lumbar,
if he was in the fucking UFC would be
on in sports illustrated. Right now.
He's a fucking Cuban immigrant who was
fighting for the Cuban Olympic judo team.
I believe it just fucking destroy
your five 985 pounds, shredded,
ridiculous muscles move so fucking fast
blasted Jason Silva out in like six
seconds. He's crushing people,
Dude. Quashing people in Bella tour,
nobody gives a fuck. You know why? Cause
it's Bella Tor and nobody's paying.
Nobody knows what it is.
You go ask a million people on the street,
what's Bella tour?
Well he might be there for 10 years and
still people might not know where Bella
is and that will be the end of his
competitive prime. That's the problem.
You can't just say like,
oh we're going to start this thing and
because we have Marcella Garcia going to
be huge because no one's going to
just fucking pay to see Jujitsu.
You know they're not going to do it
if they're not practicing Jujitsu you.
So you'd be limited to only practitioners.
So you have like a tiny percentage of
the population is willing to buy your
product on television and much less than
we'd be willing to buy an MMA fight.
Cause MMA you get the fans,
you get people who actually trained in
it themselves and then you get all these,
wow, who's who want to see people get
the fuck beat out of him. All right,
so you get a,
you get the whole cross section.
But if you get a guy like Marcello Garcia,
you're only going to get people into
Jujitsu unless surely you've got to row.
You know how many stars wear nothing one
day and they blow up the next day with
them.
Right.
The reason the UFC is huge as they have
the money for the marketing and they put
faces out there,
if someone came along with that kind
of money and that kind of power,
Marcella Garcia could be
an instant star overnight.
All of these guys were nothing.
One day they're stars the next day
just cause they, they're on TV.
But you've got to be an example.
I'm talking about guys getting
knocked the fuck out, Mike Fox Sports.
No one watches that Bella
tool was on be on Fox sports,
but I've bought a Bella Bella.
You we're going to have grappling.
You would have to be on what
ESPN to become successful.
Well is towards successful,
I guess it's on.
If it's on successful then you started
off this conversation with saying
submission,
grappling should be fucking Houston.
It's really hard to make something
popular. [inaudible] successful hard.
The hard part is mothers
are enough to keep it on.
Television part isn't actually get in
the cage and putting the show on the hard
part is marketing like.
Exactly. That's what I'm saying.
Like market on having a great product
for us has got a lot of great fighters.
I've watched Beltre and there's
some fun fights to watch,
but if you want there are
they getting sued by the UFC?
I probably shouldn't
be talking about them.
The other story you want to start
with Ken babby that's fucking strange.
Can have happier.
I don't know what really happens so
we probably shouldn't talk about that.
Crazy fun. No know nothing. I know. Now
I know. Is the UFC fucking rules. Yeah,
exactly. It's rules, but I'm looking
forward to strike force tonight and Brian,
you're gonna stay over.
I'm gonna Wrestle.
You're going to get in your underwear so,
so I think I'm going to see that movie
night. Date. Night. What? Eat. Pray.
Love my dick
rather than good pick out after this man.
Yeah, everything's great. I actually,
have you seen the movie date night
about build birthday? Are you,
are you talking to me for real birds
by seeing the movie date night? Yep.
Go bears as well. I love bill burn,
but that's not a nice, that cop in it.
I've done a lot of shit. I'm not
proud of either. Phil. I don't know.
Maybe it's good. I'm just kidding.
It's just comedy date nights.
The one that Steve Carell one,
right? Yeah. You'll be funny.
Tina Fey or I'm only fucking around. I
saw the, did we talk about the, the uh,
the fucking Stallone movie? Oh No,
no. [inaudible] I saw what the fuck,
I'm blanking out. My loud hall called it.
I'm trying to delete it off my hard drive
and look, I love Randy. Go tour. Okay.
I love Randy couture and I think Randy
couture has a definitely possibility for
a giant career as an action star.
I mean the dude he got out of real life.
Plenty good. Plenty good
to me. I'm, I bought it.
All I want to see is him beating the
fuck out of people. He's a real badass.
He's fucking, he's clean and healthy
and fucking looks great for his age.
You guys,
Goddamn movie star.
I think for sure Randy couture could
be a giant movie star for sure.
I think he's beloved.
After that guy retires,
if he just decides to do giant
fucking action, who's what?
Arnold could act better. Shit.
Shit. Romantic comedies. Maybe not.
Anyway,
it was,
I think he could do a romantic
Canada chicks want to fuck him.
That's all he needs to just needs to
be funny and how they want to fuck him.
He's a fucking gladiator, right? Look
at that year. So the movie was a,
that said the movie was
wretched. It was. It was. It was.
It was like you are than
the 18 this is what I said.
I didn't see the 18 it was like you took
every cliche in an acting movie through
it together.
He had a 12 year old piece it together
and then you just ground it up and
stuffed it up.
Stallone's asshole with like one of
those pastry bags and he just diarrhea
splattered onto the screen. That
was the movie. It was so dire.
Would never want to see that below.
Actually tried to get
more shit than anything.
So that's just the loan actually tried
to steal the script from one of my
students. Yeah. Tell that's one
the reason why I brought this up,
tell this whole the whole story,
by the way,
that motherfucker should not be proud
of that script. Yeah. What the fuck?
[inaudible] said they butchered.
I'm sure they did.
I'm sure that they have an ugly,
you know,
we'll tell the whole semester's Stallone,
put out his management team or
whatever, allegedly allegedly. Well,
they went to court. This is what
happened. Okay. They went to court.
You say a little while, just so you don't
get sued, allegedly. Just say allegedly,
allegedly. This is what you're right.
I'm helping you. I'm [inaudible] alone,
put out an APB area.
He's looking for an action thriller
or whatever, and action movie.
I'm sure you had a lot of guys come
through his office. Dave Callahan,
he looked at the credits. He's my
purple belt. Low Pan is his nickname on,
on the internet. Anyways, he writes
scripts he met with Sylvester Stallone.
They rejected the script,
but then for some reason he decided to
keep the script and not give Dave cal him
any credit and he was shopping
this, you know, he was, he,
he was basically going around
town saying he's got a script.
He wrote the script and he's
getting all these stars,
make you work and all of these guys to
do it. And so he seems like a big shot,
you know. And, and then, uh,
Dave Callahan's people found
out they took them to court.
So as long tried to fucking fight it
and they usually win according to Dave
Callahan. Writers usually lose
in these kinds of situations.
And the evidence was so clear that,
you know,
did court or when, and court ain't going
on. And yet if you look at the credits,
it says original story by Dave
Callahan, screenplay, Dave Callahan,
Sylvester small money from the film also.
I'm sure,
I don't know what his deal was,
but basically Sylvester Stallone
tried to steal his script.
You know what killed me when I read
all these people that loved it. Yeah.
I read all these people online that
loved it and I was like really?
Like you didn't see like everything
and like the thing with Arnold
was kind of funny. It was kind of
funny with Bruce Willis and on,
what's his problem? He wants to be
president [inaudible] that shit was funny.
That was a funny line. It was good.
But that's it. Other than that,
it was like a bunch of shit that you
saw come on a million miles away.
You know the is never going to die.
This is ridiculous.
When he went back to save the girl,
you like,
what the fuck you should have saw Scott
pilgrim and he went back to see if the
girl, and he didn't even fuck
her and that's just an American.
You're going to go all the way to another
country and risk your life and your
friends' lives and she loves
you and she hugs on you.
You don't even fuck are you
leave her there on the island.
That shit's ridiculous.
You just came back in a plane with
guns and fucked up everyone in her town
risking your life,
rescued her while her father was murdered.
You don't even fuck her. That's
ridiculous. That was offensive to me.
That as a fence that offended me. I'm
like, what kind of a movie are you making
here? Should have fucked her
like he saved her life. Exactly.
That's fucking communism, man. You
fly into a country and your risk,
your life for the hottest
chicken, the planet and she doesn't
even fuck you when it's over,
but you just flew from another country
to land in this shitty little island and
get shot at you. Don't even fuck
her and she wants to fuck you.
Pretty sure she got nothing to live for.
She got nothing going on there.
Get drunk and be a cool thing
to text your girlfriend. Right?
I'm going to fuck you tonight. Like I
saved your life. Wow. You could pretend
I tried. I tried to trends without
your role. Rope roleplay. Yeah.
You ever do real plan? No. No. Yeah,
I don't get that. I'm the telephone
repairman that that kind of shit.
You gotta like dress up and
shit and some dudes do it man.
They go out and buy outfits and
shit. Wiffle. Where? Something crazy.
The pretend they're shooting a cooking
show in the kitchen. He just comes in.
He's crazy.
He's raped her in the kitchen.
I remember when our one
friend that could be hot,
I can't remember her when friends or one
friend. I brought up a threesome though.
Little hope of his friend. Yeah.
I don't have to say that. Fuck.
He used to come up to
me. He goes, hey man,
you should really try to put diapers on
and slapped around a little and he was
being serious.
Yeah. We have this one friend that
uh, he talked to me about how,
how hot it was too. Ball gag has chicken
Wipper yeah, he likes to whimper. I go,
how hard cause I leave marks.
He speaks here leaving marks and
stuff. Do you? I'm a fan of that.
I like beating up like the ass. I like
beating and beating and beating it up.
Really Punch it. What do you do with it? I
don't punch it. I just, that's strongest.
You've probably me fucking iron
palm from the Shaolin Temple. Bam.
You slap them that hard in the
ass as hard as I can. Whoa.
Serious white girls like wow.
Some girls,
most girls, like most girls
like that. That is a strong
most, okay. Let's clarify.
Most girls who are willing to fuck you.
Right? I see. I do. Can't say most.
It's natural. I think it's natural.
The girls liked it to get, you know,
fucked rough. No girls, girls that
I've fucked do, I've never had
verbally. They don't like it really
has. Eddie has this very specific type
that he dates and he thinks that that,
that's like a,
a generous section of the population,
but it's not, oh no, no. I've, I tried.
I think so. It's your percentage
percent. No. I was like, okay.
Some girls do.
Some girls,
I'm going to say I'm going to
say 75% of women, like at Ross.
75% of women willing to fuck
you. Yes. Okay. Exactly.
But that's not 75% of all
women, Bro. I'm just saying.
That's what I think. Standby.
They're attracted to you.
There's certain girls who
you're the ideal guns.
What are you saying about the
girls that are attracted to me?
I'm seeing those girls like to be
smacked around a little bit. Yeah, look,
it's natural. Look, what do you, this
is a wild fucking musician. Characters.
A trained killer. Jujitsu expert
teaches people all around the world.
What do you think they want from you?
They want some exotic, crazy killer dick.
I want you to do something nutty with
them. They want to feel threatened.
Those bitches are nuts.
They might be stuffed in a corner
and want to be putting a cradle on.
Forced them to shock your Dirk.
And just so you're saying once I'm crazy,
so you're saying a larger percentage of
the population likes it nice and smooth.
Who think about who you are.
Think about who like it's all the girls
I dated like smooth. I've tried it.
Those are the clothes you
[inaudible] wouldn't it?
Don't be threatening with that.
[inaudible]
I'm not attacking you at all.
I'm pumping you up.
Look what you are is a very specific,
tight, I'm not attacking you in any way,
shape or form. I liked quality opposites.
Quite. Yeah, but quite the opposite.
I'm not attacking you at all.
What I'm saying is those bitches want
the Ganga is Khan treatment. Right?
That's why they're coming. Don't
want it with me. They're not.
They're not there for the shop guy who's
going to watch fucking cat videos with
them. They make me scissor cats. I love
cats too. Scissored them. They're like,
just put your hands, pull your dick
up and scissor me and I'm like,
is that what you doing? Scissor assholes
with girls they ever get from the like,
I like to hold you from behind.
No, I want to take you back.
They tried to take her now
and it's more romantic.
Defend yourself against a bluebell
girl. At what? A blue belt girls.
If a girl was a blue belt,
do you think? Not sure.
Like [inaudible] CIF rule one
rules or USC Fujitsu's no,
just just to do too. She's just trying
to chase you down. I'm going to hit you.
It's just going to trust anyone.
Could you do to, I don't.
I think if you know a little bit,
you just to,
you're going to be able to fight somebody.
That's the girl Jujitsu to get your order.
Boy.
Pretty power. Some bad ass bitches. Yeah.
To the Wilson bluebells ladies out there,
we are willing to give you $20 if you
will engage in a Jujitsu submission
grappling match at 10th Planet Jiu
Jitsu against the video. You have to be,
this is what Yahoo Bell.
You have to be a blue belt with less than
two years of training and under 120 oh
eight no way. You want to do a brand? No.
No reason to do that and I'll give you
some lessons. It's not Brian give lesson.
It's not Brian. I'll play the UFC
video game against a girl. Well,
if you want to look, I
wouldn't, if it was MMA,
I'm sure you'd beat the shit out of her
because all you have to do is punch her.
Right.
The real thing is like put Jujitsu.
Remember when we did that thing with um,
uh,
Seymore butts and Felicia remember
that at the old legends? Yes,
yes. But the reality, yeah. Felicia, Oh,
who was one of John Jacques
Machado is black belts,
is a friend of ours and she's a really,
really cool chick and she's a killer.
She's like 135 pounds. She's strong as, as
she sees like, oh, the kettlebells. Yeah.
Crazy crossfit grow and a serious jujitsu
black belt. Like she will fuck you up.
She's the legit and uh,
and Seymour Butts was filming a reality
show and Seymour Butts as, as porno star.
And he came to,
he came to the bomb squad and we had
him roll with a girl and he came up,
he got ahold of me because he wanted,
you know, for the shot, for the show.
I'm going to go learn Jujitsu for the
show and I'm a go against a girl or
something. And they film the
reality show at the bomb squad. Yes.
They came down in one of my classes.
That's where the original 10 planet
was located on the bomb squad.
So we filmed it. He, he didn't
want to roll with thirst,
right? Or he did one. He did not
know what was going to happen.
What happened is he didn't use any of it.
He didn't use any of them rolling
with her in the actual show.
He only came down a couple of times.
You can't learn Jiu Jitsu in a
couple of dollars, but he didn't.
I thought the idea was that he was going
to get humiliated by the girl and that
was going to be fun. But I don't remember
seeing any of that. Did they put it on?
They never, they never ever did.
Never. She killed she crushed room.
She just strangled him, choked him
armed Bardem she did everything to them.
But if there is no lot rules than he
would have won. Now with Felicia. Felicia,
maybe it was a blue belt girl.
No, Felicia is a black belt dude.
You're not going to be able to be, odds
are in her favor. Anything can happen.
A big man can like, yeah, you might see
on the picture even trying to know. Yeah,
anything could happen.
You're right,
but the odds are she's going to get you
put money on the black belt check if you
don't know how to fight. It's one
thing if you're a fighter, girls,
black belt girls go through guys
that are really good at Jujitsu. God,
it's crazy to watch belts and stuff.
A blackbelt chick can run through a guy
that's been trained two or three years
easily.
It's crazy.
It's really high end girls like
attack dudes like here at Gracie.
I hear crazy stories like embarrass his
guys all the time. I'm sure for sure.
She's a fucking savage.
She's awesome and she's hot as fuck.
How ridiculous is that?
Hot as fuck in a trained killer
and a Gracie who's kid is at,
is that Hickson's kid? No, Borea hens.
Those sisters daughter.
Enzo sends a sister.
Flavio is like a famous actress in Brazil.
She had a Kiera, Kiera. The
father was never around and Kiera,
it just kept the Gracie name.
Her mom's, she's a Gracie.
Her mom's like legit racing. You know
her mom's super hot to one of the,
when I went to Brazil and in 2000
for the moon, Diaz as a purple belt,
John, jock and Hanzo, we're actually
tried to hook me up with Flavio Heroes.
Mom. Oh my God. When I was 30 Oh my
God, cure was 14 at the time. What?
Kira was never together. We're all hanging
out. Have you should put a hit out on,
you know that's true here. You fucking
kissing and tell him to the hole.
I didn't just spank, that was out 10
years ago and nothing ever happened.
You know what we,
she couldn't speak English.
I didn't speak Portuguese
are the attraction lasted
for five minutes and then
that was it. I think it's really
cool when you go to those worlds,
you just championships and even Abu
Dhabi at a level that the chicks are
fighting at the two level is
really, really high. Yeah.
That's so fun to watch, man.
Chicks become like really dangerous
killers cause Jujitsu is one of the things
are,
it takes some strength to do,
but it really takes technique
and practice and you know,
a girl can get to the point where she
could fucking kill a man where she can
dominate a man doesn't take that much.
It doesn't take that much.
Especially when you think about your legs.
A girl has legs that are willing to carry
around her hundred and 30 pound body
all day long and he puts it,
doesn't, Cyborg doesn't count.
That's a set of accounts
like Shana Baseline. I mean
she does count, but she's,
you know, obviously she's a broad end
of the spectrum. If you had to guess,
what would you say that's all about
what cyborg she does. You know, she,
she does everything she can.
She can enhance her strength.
Yeah. Or She's just unusually,
very strong genetically. That's
possible too. Probably isn't an awesome,
prissy boner. You know what's going to
take to beat her some crazy Samoan chick,
another chess. Tom Check, some
justice stirring or 14,000 train.
Some fucking big German bitch
with big broad shoulders and shit.
You know someone, someone from a hardy
Viking fucking bloodline something strong.
How crazy is so bad ass fighter?
Like what the fuck is her name?
Gina Carano hot and can fuck you
like that's a rare combination.
Cause usually the girls like a fuck
you up or ugly. It's never hot chicks.
They could fuck him except Kira.
Yeah, she's like the fuck up.
A lot of dudes in a street fight
or standing brawl street fight.
She'll kick off her pumps and fuck you up.
Leg kick you punch you in the face.
You don't know how
to get your ass kicked in front of all
your friends at a club by some hot showed
by a hot chick. Fucking Kael you too.
She could easily Kao a dude. Yeah. Hey,
how about this man? Why is it that
there's not that many black chicks in MMA?
How many black chicks are there on
MMA every time I want strike force it.
So either Cyborg or there's
some white checks. It's, I mean,
you don't see that many a time
check a black chick to be cyborg.
They can't force him for short classes.
That might be it.
I mean obviously this black chicks
can afford it, but the ones who can,
they didn't want to fight.
You know, it's like it's,
it hasn't permeated into the ghettos the
way it has in other cultures in other
countries, you know, in Brazil and
it's permeated into the lower end.
People look at it as a way
to like, you know, and then
also, you know, even the, the,
the people who are educated in,
in like Damien Maia comes from
a wealthy background. He comes,
but just the sheer desire and
drive to fight for him, you know?
So it became exciting and interesting to
him. It's not necessarily with chicks,
it's, it takes a very special check
to want to go in there and throw down.
Right now at the level the sport is
for women's MMA right now it's so tiny.
There are so few girls that are doing
it that like Venus and Serena could jump
into on a mountain and fuck chicks
up light away within a year.
You know the biggest one can
fight cycle within a year
they would fuck up. Ticks had been traded
six years. Her legs are like football,
like male football player.
Let's make it happen.
Could you imagine her leg kicking you?
Just digging in.
You know boss Wooten styled big in
that fucking Shannon. I'll tell you.
Imagine what kind of damage she could do.
The amount of distance she
could cover so quickly.
They could consistently get tennis.
They can easily get bored.
A fucking tennis match so well I,
you know what they could do?
It could enhance their training for
tennis. It could make them more explosive.
If they decided to get into
MMA just into Moy Tai and shit,
just enhance their tennis turtle.
It would definitely enhance their movement
and then they fall in love with it.
That's the hope.
Some MMA for training and then have the
fall in love with it and then someone
offers like a big money fight to imagine.
Imagine their knees,
the knees would be like, God fucking
insane. There is a grip on that.
Tennis racket must be death.
Right,
but we didn't use that shit over the back
of your neck and need him the fuck up.
I was going to train them. I go,
let's, let's just start with the knees.
Get really good at the,
at the Thai clinch.
Get really good at that and then we'll
expand from there. Yeah. What'd you say?
The booty clinch, Judy Chu's. Yeah,
man. I had double leg after a year.
Giant asses from all right. Jumping.
They're double legs would be like GSP.
Jesus fucking Christ
pitches the cashed checks.
They would probably be the greatest MMA.
Imagine if they,
if they fought together like Minataro
and his brother do. Yeah, that'd be,
they would be in sand.
There would be the crushers.
They would have to
eventually fight each other.
That'd be the only way they is kind
of black chicks out there. Fine.
There's got to pee.
There definitely are.
I've definitely seen
black chicks fight in MMA.
I just haven't seen the percentage
is much lower than than girls.
For some reason.
Within a white girl's brother.
For some reason it seems like more
white girls are doing a lot of Spanish.
Girls are doing a lot of Japanese
checks. Japanese. Very popular. Right?
There's a Badass Japanese chicks.
We're going to be Fuji that bitches bad.
She's young. She's bet. What you
just making people up, Brian,
you let me know what the
fuck you talking about?
Zalia Fosto isn't she fighting tonight
too? I don't know. And start a course.
I don't know.
We could find out real quick is going
to get mad at us for pumping up strike
force.
Yeah.
So Brian, what goes through your mind
when we're talking about all this?
How will you know? I always get
something every year I start liking,
like I just recently
started liking ice tea,
but I haven't got to the grapefruit
part and I'm just wondering if that's
something that happens later in life.
You start liking grapefruits.
One Who fucking likes?
My Dad likes to eat grapefruits.
Do you like to eat grapefruits?
Well, I love grapefruits.
I think they're delicious. Oh, you got
a good one. I think. Did you, your wife,
you'd like grapefruits
or did it come later? No,
I kinda liked him when I was young.
I used to drink a lot of grapefruit
juice cause I heard it was even higher in
vitamin C than an orange juice.
That might be not true. Yeah.
Bobby Lashley is fighting. Who'd you say?
Who you ask? What's Phyton? Zalia frosto
maybe she's not fighting. I
thought, I don't see that.
I don't see any girls in the car.
Andre Galvao was supposed to be fighting
McCargo but Macaca didn't show up.
Who was gonna fight him?
Um,
yeah.
Oh, um, Andre. Dan
have been awesome. I love Andrea Kako
and Macaca was banished Jujitsu. Oh,
legend man. Yeah. I wonder what happened.
I don't know. It happened not on at all.
It was on the undercard anyway,
and there's no way to see the undercard,
which sucks because some of these
songs singing about the UFC too.
I mean you can watch them
online after the event is over,
but then she'd be away that you could
just tune in to just the whole undercard
like from the moment that first fight
starts the first fight at four o'clock in
the afternoon. Show me that
shit. Why are you saving?
They don't have that like
on like a certain channel
on the ufc.com which I love
the fact that you can always get any
fight you want on ufc.com that's the shit.
But me as a fan, you know, if I find out
that the first fight of the night is,
you know, fucking two guys
that I know, I know their name,
they're not like mainstream guys, but
I know they're both bad ass. Like,
like Hayzlett and uh, and Rick Story.
Here's a perfect example. That one aired,
right? Did that air? I don't
remember. Okay. But if it didn't air,
imagine what that fight was on
the undercard. It wasn't airing.
I would want to fucking see that
fight, man, when it's happening.
I don't want to go on the underground
and find the results out right after it.
And I can't see the video and then click
on ESPN three d if it's being filmed in
three d, they, whoever, I
don't know. That's a good
idea. I mean, I guess there's,
there's must be a method to their
madness, but the reality is, man,
you could just overdose on MMA if
they wanted to show you everything.
The people that are putting this together,
like the people that are making
these decisions don't realize,
realize how important all of these fights
are to the fans, the hardcore fans.
We want to see all of them.
It's not like box.
It makes me sick when I look at this car,
like this card is nasty.
Like I'm looking at the car,
there's great fights in the car
and I'm looking forward to it.
But then when I looked down and I see,
I know it didn't happen,
but I looked down and see golf valve
versus fucking Macaca. I go, Oh shit,
that's a bad ass fight.
Venetia is Magallanes Draka
Coleen. Oh versus rocky long.
I want to see that fight.
How come I can't see it?
You know the crazy thing and Macaca most
people newbies don't understand that
the [inaudible] and then they was at,
that's right where MMA was that back in
the late nineties and that the dark area,
the dark period Macaca and pay late Landy,
they were considered like the shit,
the shit to weights out there.
There were insane palae knocked out
Matt Hughes in Kuwait. I remember that.
You know another legend
volleyed [inaudible] can I show,
can I show everybody this shirt?
What do I do?
How do I show the people the back of the
shirt? If you just turn around and say,
well,
why would look so you did.
There's this dude named while lead
Ishmael who is a a legend crossing grab.
When I was trying to across some
Gracie's place way back in [inaudible] 98
that's when I first met him.
When I started working for the old UFC.
He fought Takahashi at that
UFC and UFC 12 and Dothan,
Alabama and this dude is just one of the
all time characters. Badass Jujitsu Guy,
choked, hoists, Gracie unconscious, but
he's famous for his terrible English.
He had a few with high end Gracie,
this high end. He's cook, he's Faggot,
Cook, kill him. He's cook. He's
fuck it. That's all even so hook.
Fuck a ton Chrissy. You know I'm saying
he's not damn man. I got to the pizzas.
I just walk with me and my girlfriend go
to beach. I see that cook,
that faggot stemming there.
You need to find this Brian TV if you can
find this. Volleyed is mile. It's no w.
W. W a. It's, it's Waleed
but it's spelled with a w.
W. A. L. L. I. D. Yeah.
I. S. H. M. A. L. Yes.
I. S. I. S. M. A. I. L. Yeah.
And go on Youtube and find like a famous
interview. Yeah, it was like hard.
Hi Gracie. Mile high end
rot. Lion, Gracie, r.
Y. N. Gracie. You got to listen to
this guy talk cause it's got again,
I'm hilarious.
Anyway,
he's one of the coolest guys of all
time and a Badass Jujitsu guy and he uh,
he's famous to you and you
can say whatever you want.
When I mentioned it, Tracy,
hi.
Is that chicken and let everybody in the
light beat the he one minute they have
no, I don't want to talk about this
chicken. You'll see those guys are weak.
I told you, I told the by
everybody. I remember the
last time I come here and say,
Hey, this guy's nothing. Is that a week?
You'll know everyday say
read the question everyday.
Say before the fight happened,
the fight.
I just want everybody who remind
everybody to remember everything they say
before the fight. The happy, the fight.
You know what I mean? You'll see.
Like I told Dave about I ready to
fight so hard. I showed with the bike.
Can imagine
better to the rest time much
better because at 10 hertz
and though why not go to
party? I don't know my foot scrub
out to, but I'll do, I go to trade.
I guess it is. Oh right. Let's go
through. You know I go twain, I'm ready.
I it didn't bubble. You don't instead of
having gotten, have a good [inaudible].
I know I have hard. No, I
have your heart to fight.
There's no doubt about, you'll see
there'd be a lot of guy stuck. A Lotta no,
she shit serious like you, this Guy
Hicks on grace yet. So Hi Baba Baba Baba.
Stay inside the home not to go show
up. You know what I mean? You know I,
I'm, I'm fighting all the
time on stand. I'm fine. No,
I'm ready to fight.
I'm say I am not staying
inside my home as a here.
Wait Stacy. Yeah, he talked
about, she's crazy to hear.
Almost in tears one day asking me who
got you want to fight this guy up with a
fight because you image a bit for
greatness. I beat high and Gracie,
he Kasi. I bet how you Gracie, he's,
he's got he's guys Cozzie I bet.
Here's a greater, he skies it.
I beat the highest degrees that he's
abroad there. What they're gonna do. Neti.
C'Mon man. Show up. Yeah.
He was talking shit to Hixon this wall
over the god that was a different video
actually that was got
that one before we talk.
He wouldn't after Hixon in that role.
The time shit about Hixon.
I can't believe that. For people
who don't know Hixon Gracie is like,
he's like the god of Jujitsu.
If you named one guy that everybody
says is just head and shoulders above
everybody
else, it's Hixon. No, it's hard to
see man. Hold on there. It says,
what it says is don't be coward.
Don't run off the fight.
That's a Waleed Ishmael tee
shirt. It's odd. We got it.
Don't be coward. Don't run off the
fight. Then he had that printed. Yeah,
and like you sure you want to spell it
this and this is my fin for you say don't
be coward sir,
but it says don't be cowered on a stand.
I know. Don't be a coward. No,
don't be coward. Not A, okay.
I'm going to have to have you
initial this really quick for me.
Just put your initials right here
and right there and right there.
I'm not scared. You want to take a look
at it one more time? One more time.
It's perfect for him. He probably looks
at it and goes, that's exactly what I,
I say, don't be coward. Don't want have to
fight. That's fucking nonsense. Proliant.
I would never had one and I lost her
and I'm so sad that I lost it. Now does
he go home and just be like, hey hon,
how's it going? I'm home.
He's a super cool guy.
Okay, cool. Then it's like a
character could sorta camera comes on.
He's playing the camera camera.
Sort of like Chael Sonnen.
He's the Brazilian channels something.
He's talking shit and sell fights.
But he's also talking shit
cause he's a bad mother fucker.
And this guy chose buddies. Really?
Gracie. Completely unconscious. Yeah.
He caught hoists.
Gracie and a clock choke in a
Jujitsu match and putting the sleep.
This is after hoists became huge.
Voice was giant because of the UFC and
he did this on the beach in Brazil in
front of everybody.
Remember that? Exactly what?
I'm gonna be Super Nice every time I run
into him backstage at the FCA happens.
Friendly hugs. Super, super happy guy.
I mean he said you did two legend
for sure. There's a lot, there's a handful
of legends in Jujitsu, but while he'd,
Ishmael is definitely a legend.
Just the,
just the fact that he choked
out hoists Gracie like
Ah, you know what? As a brown belt,
he won against our master John
Jackman shadow and he lost,
but it was a close match and
Jon talk was a black belt. No,
everybody was scared of John Shock at
that point. No one wanted to step up,
but volleyed as a brown belt stepped up,
he lost. But Dad was a battle. It wasn't,
it wasn't.
His Jujitsu is very strong.
He's just helped.
Bull is a bull of a man and he will not
give up and he gets cuts through dudes.
Man, he's strong as fuck and one of the
nicest guys ever. We had a great picture.
It's still on my mom's face page.
My myspace page is like,
it's like a abandoned playground,
but if you go to my photos
is one of us with Waleed.
We're all screaming Jujitsu.
Yeah, it's on my mind. It's on my mind
space too. I got it up there. It's a
classic. My space.com/the twister.
Yeah, and if they want to find Eddie,
that's where it's at.
Damn.
This show's been going on for an hour
or two hours and 20 minutes. By the way,
Joe, you gotta check out pet seaman.
Terry? No, I don't scare you.
I don't want to know about that. Finding
or die. No, it's on funny or die.
You don't have to be redone.
I'm fucking hooked on Stephen King's son.
Stephen King's son is named Joe Hill
and he's a horror writer as well.
Really fucking good. I'm reading this
book called the heart shaped box.
Somebody put it on the message board.
[inaudible] they put the, you know the,
his son's a writer, so I said,
fuck it. I'll buy it on the IPAD.
You know I the kindle thing on the
IPAD. It's fucking great book, man.
Just like his dad. It's like he
inherited his dad's brain. I mean,
it's fucking good. I'm halfway
into this book. It's a total page.
Maybe he wrote it for his son.
You would love it.
It's about a a fucking rock star.
Who a is like a goth dude who's like
into all kinds of creepy, weird shit.
Like he's got like a head from a guy who
had been tortured and he puts fucking
like pens in the, in the
skull. Sounds like Marilyn
Manson. Exactly. That kind of,
it's just a crazy old goth dude
and he buys a ghost online.
Someone's selling a dead man suit.
And this woman who is selling it as saying
that there's a ghost that comes along
with it.
This guy thinks for a goof,
he's going to buy this fucking suit
and it's going to be kind of cool,
but the dead man actually does
Honda. Dude, it's fun man.
It's a fucking Paige Turner.
It's a good God damn well written book.
Fucking something about
books, man. You know,
you can get so deep into
a story with a book,
you know that you just can't get in a
movie. I want to see everything. You know,
I love movies.
I love the fact that it's like a two
hour ordeal and it's over and I'm out of
there like that. It was pretty
cool. They wrapped it up nicely,
but there's something fucking
killer about books, man.
I didn't appreciate that for a long time.
For a long time,
I didn't appreciate just the, the flat
imagination of sitting there reading text,
but there's something cool now.
I like how you build your own characters
in your head saying this person has a
certain look to you in your head.
That is your own unique way of
thinking about what this person,
yeah,
and they can make some really exciting
shit that's just completely unrealistic
for a regular movie.
You don't have to have giant
fucking special effects
budgets and then have to be
crazy off the charts,
but they're just describing it with
their words and creating this incredible
picture in your, in your own head. You
know, what am I saying? Reading is good.
Reading is fundamental.
Ladies and gentlemen,
this show like all shows bitches brought
to you by the fleshlight Hollaback.
If you buy it online on Joe
rogan.net I believe you get 15% off.
And one of the reasons, there's two
reasons why we have the sponsor,
our podcast one is because a, we met
with Krista, one of the guys who run set,
we're going to hang out somehow with an,
we're going to hang out with
them in Austin, Texas when
we go there for the UFC.
Just a super cool chill dude.
And it just seemed like,
and the other thing was that I think it's
a, it's for real, legit good product.
I use it and it's,
it's way better than just beating off
and cause I think it's ridiculous that
people think that it's, um,
there's something taboo about
it. I think that's silly.
You know, I don't know what it is,
but there, there's something, uh,
that I think is absolutely ridiculous
that people think that something silly
about pursuing pleasure
and we can use it in the
shower. Fuck yes, totally.
I think that's the best spot we should
really talk to though about getting a
fleshlight out version of it.
It could be your own personal flashlights.
Yeah.
I was talking about this book and this
is the book that I talked about with Dane
Cook and I've talked about
it with other people before.
I've given this book to a bunch of my
friends. I'll give it to you, right Brian?
It's called the war of art.
I want to give it to you.
I want you to read this shit.
Have you ever given us this
book for creative people?
It's one of the best books and
I'm not getting paid for this.
This is just my own recommendation.
It's a fucking fantastic book.
If you're an artist, if you're
a comedian, if you're already,
and I were just having a conversation
about this today because Ari a took a um,
uh, what are those Adderalls
it took an Adderall,
which is why he can't be here today
cause he's cleaning up his house.
That's awesome. Really? Yeah. Yeah. Our,
he's been on a positive kick lately, man.
You've been having some
really cool conversations.
We had a really cool one today.
We were talking about like burning,
like pass enemies,
like letting old grudges go and he's
trying to be more healthy with his mind.
And we talked about um, how, you know,
it takes like he is on his Adderall,
he takes an Adderall now he wants
a fucking cleaning his house up.
He wants to write some material.
And he was like,
what's so crazy that if you worked
as an accountant you would want,
while you're at work you would want to
sneak away and write jokes, you know?
But when you're not,
when you're a comedian,
you don't ever sit in front of the
fucking computer and actually write jokes.
It's like you find a way
to fuck off and not do it.
And it's all explained by this book.
This book is a fascinating look
into the psychology of creativity,
not just about writing,
but I think it applies to any kind of art,
any kind of thing where you're supposed
to be dedicating a certain amount of
time to thinking about things.
It was fucking fantastic.
So I bought a stack of
them cause I was on,
I wanted to give Dane Cook one
when he was here and uh, I,
I couldn't find it so I just bought a new
stack. So just, just Google that shit.
Buy It online. I'm telling
you it's a quick, easy read.
It's only like a hundred pages or some
shit. It's not my much to it. Yeah.
163 pages. It's not
that much. And you know,
you can get a lot out of it just
from a couple of chapters. You know,
you have to read the whole thing.
Just listen to what that fucking
guy says and just try it.
Just force yourself to create, you know,
there's a lot of shit going on that you,
you, you, you distract yourself with.
It's not really that necessary. So
that's my message for the day. Thank you
very much. That's my positive message.
Brian, do you have anything
to say before we wrap this up?
No. Check out my video though.
Pet Cemetery. Is that, did
you make this video? Yeah.
Oh, okay. It's only a minute long.
Funny or die one guy. One Cup,
sort of a subset of trouble
with it already got in
trouble with already getting
in trouble. The police spelled this
video out for our friends. Hit P,
e t and then the next word is
cemetery, but seamen as Amy, m,
e n, t, a, r y. Seaman, Terry
Seaman. Terry [inaudible].
And what is it about, uh, two young
guys finding love. Really? Yeah.
It's funny. Yeah. I'm getting
one to watch it right now.
How long has it put it on your computer
and as long. Is it one minute long.
One minute long? Yeah. Okay. We're
going to watch this then we're going to,
we'll give you our thoughts about this
and that's how we're going to end the
show is a gentleman. This is on a
youtube, funny or die funny or die? I can,
I'm not putting on Youtube cause
will get fucked up. What will happen?
You'll see it this illegal.
Am I doing something illegal
that it's not illegal at all,
but it's edited to look illegal.
Yeah.
Let's type in pet cemetery.
Pat Seaman. Terry, here it is.
We're going to watch it.
Hmm.
But I can't turn my volume on.
All right.
I can't talk while this was going
to ask, what's going on. Oh,
I don't watch it and close your eyes.
See,
okay.
What we're watching
is and his friend Ari and
they're fucking animals.
Oh my God.
Fuck is wrong with you guys. Oh
my God. You shouldn't be in jail.
You should be in jail for that
and I mean you've got to see that
ladies and gentlemen, that was
just, I don't want you to see this.
I don't want you to watch it because I
know you'll feel less about Brian and I
know you feel you'll think less about Ari.
Glean out for me.
Why is it pet cemetery?
Because there were fucking animals
and shooting semen inside of them.
Then you watch the video semen,
but it's like cemetery. Oh my God,
that's so strange.
You don't know what we're talking.
They played that live in front of a, the
last night he, Cheryl did it. Really?
How do people react?
People just went crazy.
I guess they cheered that people
are in discussed cheering, laughing.
It was just pretty, and it's pretty
funny though. TMZ was there too.
It's pretty freely.
What a TMZ you have to say about,
you didn't say anything about that
shit. What the fuck, dude? You almost,
you were almost there and asked me did
you guys talk about being naked and I
should've just done it for that. Now Aria
has actually took it too far. Like, yeah,
I just wanted to fuck your cat for
real. Yeah. He went to the bathroom.
I thought the cat and the dog afterwards
and he said he was just like giving
them love and petting them
both. Shut up Ryan. I know.
When you're making things
up you can't trick.
Did you play dicks out for real ever?
No. No. Ra did put us all legal.
He pulled down his pants and
yet boxes you could have hit.
You coulda hit your cock with a dog.
You know you're caught right dog.
It's all about [inaudible] music
is going to give you advice.
This is how you get away with this.
It's not about editing.
If you're going to make sure,
yeah.
Oh, hide your cock with
the dog. All right. Okay.
W if you saw the raw, the raw video of it
is just as like give us laugh. Oh yeah.
Love. But we're like rocking my,
we're doing it. You're making,
when you're making out with the cat and
you've got your mouth over her. Nice.
Actually, it was on the side of his mouth
and I was just like, I'm bored. Blah,
blah, blah, blah, blah, blah,
blah. Time to watch, man.
Feel like you're doing something wrong.
Not that are just giving them a
loving lovings almost best reality.
It's, it's told the best reality. It's uh,
it's so time beastiality showtime
beastiality I was dating a girl once.
It was in one of those movies,
did her, and you know,
we, you know, we broke it.
We only dated for like
a short period time.
And then I saw her on this movie like
many, many, many, many, many years later.
She was on one of those fucking crazy
late night porn slash movies where she was
getting banged. Some dude was banging her
in a bed, but the position was all off,
you know, like his dick
was like, way down here.
I was like sticking it in that
pussy close, but it was like,
look at this dirty bitch. What a
weird job. Those chicks that only
do that kind of porn. Yeah, that's
all they do. It's like, you know,
it's just terrible acting. It was never
goes inside. It never goes into town.
She doesn't let you go. No penetration.
Sorry your pussy. And it's totally cool.
Dudes just like rabbit is taped balls,
closeup on her and she's like,
they take their dick to the side.
I wonder what the dudes get hard.
A buddy of mine did,
one of those he had,
he had to do a scene like that
with a check and she goes,
you can fuck me if you want
to know. And he was like, oh,
how many times have you said
that? That's like, think of,
we're actually going to have sex in those
movies, want, we'll do it all the time.
Apparently. If you see there was that
movie, uh, the, what was the, um,
there was nine and a half weeks and
Mickey Rourke and then there was the, um,
the sequel velvet violet, some
wild orchids. What now? That's it.
I say why would work very
strong, very strong. Anyway.
Apparently Mickey Rourke and
his girlfriend were in that
movie and make you work.
Really fucked his girlfriend and yeah,
everybody saw it.
Said [inaudible] happened. [inaudible]
showtime probably doesn't happen too much.
Very often at all.
I think Mickey work was just
completely out of control then he was,
he was boxing. He had his
fucking face implanted. He
was going crazy. You remember,
remember when he had cheekbones put in?
I still think you have to get
them removed. Yeah, for sure.
He doesn't look the same anymore.
If you go and look at, there was,
there was a period of time,
a dark period for Mickey Rourke.
He was in this Tupac movie and he was
on steroids. It was gigantic. Just Jack,
like a fucking professional bodybuilder
and he was playing like some street
fighter boxing character that was
like the beat the bottom, you know,
he like completely bottomed out and then
came back and I was in like iron man
two and shit and he's said, you know,
giant blockbuster movies and shit.
He's like doing awesome. But for a
long time he was like off the deep end.
Crazy after he was a
huge challenge to star.
Then went like kiss when kiss went
into boxing at the end of kiss,
whatever a joke. He became a joke.
Nobody wanted to work with them.
And then apparently Robert
Rodriguez said like, you know,
like Quentin Tarantino and those dudes,
they like to bring in like, yeah,
weird character. John Travolta. He
resurrected John Travolta's career. Yeah,
same thing. John Travolta was kind of
the joke before, cause up bad ass actor.
He's a bad motherfucker.
I've been in this fucking the Steven
Seagal go home though. Stephen Skull, um,
Stallone movie, which was a
silly movie. Even in that movie.
Mickey Rourke stole the scenes when he
was in the scenes. He's so real. I mean,
he's such a,
you know,
there's some dudes who are just so
good at that acting thing, you know,
and he's one of them. He's a,
he's a bad motherfucker at it.
He quit in the middle of being a
giant movie, started becoming a boxer.
He couldn't get any parts.
Was that what it was? I think,
I think didn't he the story
as who knows if it's true,
but the story is he got blackballed
because of Robert De Niro Angel Heart.
They had like such a feud or whatever
that Robertson and Ariela said,
this is the story.
It could be all rumors that Robert Dinero
said like basically if whatever movie
company he was signed with,
if you work with that dude again,
I'm not going to work with you.
It's so people what?
That's [inaudible] have a story like that.
You've got to research that shit on the
Internet. [inaudible] heard this story.
That's like the Rod Stewart
Stomach pucks though.
We have to find this out before
we're going to end this show.
But before we end the show, he must
find out if this is true. Otherwise,
we're spreading some crazy rumor. I said
about why you work for like that up.
I know, but let's find out what
their actual gear. There's no,
I know there is a real room or I'm
sure somebody actually told it to you,
but what it was just
someone in high school
at Rit. Mickey Rourke. Robert De Niro. Uh,
blackball blackballed. Yeah. That's
good. Blackball from Hollywood.
I don't believe this.
What? Say Ye Twitter.
I will let you people answer cause I
know there's some fucking movie buffs out
there. I am following you. I'm following
the Twitter feed right now. Someone,
please tell me if this is true or if this
is horse shit was Mickey Rourke really
blackballed from Hollywood ready and it's
not coming up with anything on Google.
I wish nobody gives a fuck about
this show. Dude. Don't spend,
I'm asking for help of getting
nothing. Let's try it. Everyone's out.
Yeah. Maybe. Maybe the show ended a long
time ago. Maybe we don't realize it,
but my wife won't eat shitty
all week at east guys.
Everyone's going out to the bars per
right now to watch strike force. Yeah.
So what's happened in Brian?
It is Strikeforce starts
in a half an hour. Oh Shit.
Pom Pom Pom. Yeah. Nothing. So I'm not
seeing shit. No one has an answer for me.
All right, you fox. That's how
you guys want to do it. All right.
No one's helping me, man. How many
people were watching the show?
Brian is 900 last night.
That's as good as we ever got to do ladies
and gentlemen. And on that note, um,
anything else to say?
What do you got there?
What does is, is is I was just going
to have some Indian music for you.
What is it? Is a gay, no.
Sounded Gay. Let's hear it.
Oh my,
no tracks.
I was just talking with a woman today
who says that she believes that Michael
Jackson was castrated.
I believe it.
She says there's no way a man can
sing like that. She was like a,
a woman who would know this kind of thing.
Like someone who's very
wise and in the business.
She said she believes he was frustrated.
What a great excuse for someone who
wants to be a transsexual. Yeah,
I cut my dick off and I'm not gay.
What do you know?
There's a thing called the cost.
Stratos.
There's a type of singing in in Italy
like opera singing where they castrate the
boys and sell them into like an
indentured servitude to work as a CA.
Strato that's like a
real thing. They, they,
I don't know the entire details of it,
but they take out your testicles so
you can reach higher higher notes.
Is it a certain sound that they have?
Hit that again and Billie Jean. Yeah. No,
I mean, just stop and think about,
you're just out there surfing you. Fuck,
I was looking for different songs.
This, that's a good one. Okay,
here we go.
Don't you think it's a good one?
[inaudible] think about this
and if someone told you, hey,
this is my favorite man.
I love how he sings.
Think about this. Think about Michael
Time. Pick about this. Listen to this
take about, if you never knew
Michael Jackson, Everett,
you were raised in a fucking island and
then you come to La and you hear about
this fucking singer up out with,
you'd
be tripping. Fuck, how
the fuck is this crip?
He's always a Marilyn Manson
type pop. Guys like Marilyn
Manson. They go, no, no, no,
no. He's our Marilyn Manson.
He's people already good.
Keep it playing in the
band did he went through,
he went from black to white in front of
the whole world on album covers you the
biggest albums in rock history
or music history. He did it.
You just put the album covers
to and go, oh yeah, but that's,
that's a disease that's,
he's got little likable.
What the really crazy thing is he turned
himself into a freak in front of the
world. Yeah, cut his face
up. She changed his chin.
He was the biggest music stars ever.
Bigger than Elvis.
Bigger than the Beatles. Michael
Jackson is number one with a bullet.
No one has been more talented.
No one's been more striking.
And the guy became a freak and fire
the world and he had an excuse.
He became a white guy. I mean,
look at the nose. Look at the hand,
look at the colors again.
I know a black girl who has the same
as going to see disease. He has,
she has dark brown makeup. She has dark.
He, he did a bunch of crazy shit too.
I mean he did a lot of shit to his face.
He would never admit it.
He said he only had like his nose fixed
cause it so he could breathe better.
Yeah. He had like a gang of shit
and when he was on Barbara Walters,
Barbara Walters was checking him. Gone
Horde. Michael, what do you look at?
What do you see when you
look in the mirror? He goes,
I don't look in mirrors blog.
He said he don't look in the mirror,
but he was so fucking talented that
it wasn't enough to creep people out.
People still want to hear this guy sing
and watch them dance. Don't buddy ever.
You can get away with a lot of shit if
you write good music, look at like Queen,
look it up, John. You can get
away with a lot. People will like,
you'd get away to Spain gay now, like a
lot of singers are coming out and saying,
okay, well no one cares. Like
fuck, that sounds awesome.
With Michael Jackson came out before he
died and said, here's some people will,
but most people don't need
him. Most Inalfa won't. Yeah,
but no one had never moved
like Michael Jackson.
Like remember when we watched
that James Brown video with Joey?
James Brown was a totally on another
place in another dimension and another,
but his was a very masculine
way. You know his was, oh,
oh, you know there was some, there
was sex in masculinity to it.
This was like feminine and beautiful
and the way he moved was like so like so
pure.
Like his movements were so fucking crisp
and he would hit them Fang like who
knew when he would pull his pants
up enveloping the tip of his toes.
It'd be like Damn, when he would moon
lock. When you moonwalk and dude,
just glide so gracefully.
I'd met a thought.
I had never been a fan of
Michael Jackson's music ever.
I listened to all the songs a million
times. It's not going to grow on me,
but listen to the song and then it's
never been a fan of went to go see that
Michael Jackson movie. This is it.
To make fun of it. Just to be like,
I thought it was going to
be just a freak show. Mad.
I am a fan now of that
motherfucker's creativity,
the way he commanded that whole show,
all these producers that they're just
bowing down him everywhere he walked,
he had command of everything
and he's an amazing performer.
I went in there to laugh at him.
I came out.
A big fan still won't buy any of his cds.
It's just not my vibe that God put in
something was that song you want to be
starting something with.
Which one is that? If you
want to be starting something,
I think the end of the end of thriller,
the end of it,
he breaks into this groove live that's
fucking amazing. That I would take,
I would fucking, I mean that shit is
just an amazing, and he played it live.
I'd never heard it before.
I don't think I've ever
gotten to the total end of
thriller, but I was impressed.
I became a fan. How's it performer?
He really took things too,
like a crazy place where
you are so confident that
he was absolutely in control
of every move that he made. That was
like, it was jaw dropping to watch.
It was like the way he would move was so
fucking powerful. Grabbed all his shit.
His dancing he had, he would,
he would make everyone,
when they auditioned motherfuckers,
they all had to be they,
they told him straight up, because you
are an extension of Michael Jackson.
You're not trying to bring no flavor.
Don't try to bring your
own flavor into this.
You are an extension of Michael Jackson.
So there's certain parts of the songs
where everyone's doing the same thing he's
doing and then they go off
and then Michael Jackson
has is he's got like 16 bars
where you could freestyle. No
one tells him what did, he goes,
I'm going to be right here going off.
And then it gets back into the show and
then it's all around and then he comes
out and goes, this is just my shit I'm
just going to do. It was all his shit.
He had the craziest dance style ever.
No one's ever dance like Michael
Jackson to songs and performed them.
There's never been
anybody like that model.
It's almost like he had more inside
him that he had the lead out,
so he was so tortured, like that's
what your sense from his performance,
like it was so powerful and
Crispin electric and it was
almost because he had so
much in return Moyle that it had to.
That's how it came out.
It came out in his movements.
There was something about watching
it where you felt for him,
you felt what he was doing,
but you didn't.
It wasn't just a guy
dancing and a guy singing.
It's like the intense expression
that he was using to dance and sing.
It's like he was reaching
these emotional points,
these emotional peaks that you like,
fuck man, that dude is out there.
That motherfucker was so talented.
The people who dislike, you know what?
He might be fucking with kids. So what?
You know what I mean? Put on his album,
his house people forgave his
Eddie all clarify something.
Sleeping over with kids and locking
the door. People are like, whatever.
There's no proof. There's
no video. Whatever. Eddie,
you didn't like him up until
watching that movie though.
I never was a fan of his muse
has been so shitty. I can't,
are you talking about this amazing that
movies when the dumbest movies that you
like, Nacho leave rests or shut the
fuck. C'Mon. You're like Nacho Levi.
Okay,
well let's not get upset at each other
for liking one thing to the other person
doesn't like this is, it was amazing.
I did not watch the whole thing,
but I watched a part of it while I was
getting tattooed and I found it pretty
fascinating.
I thought it was interesting.
I thought it was an in depth look at
him talking and interacting with people
that you don't get a chance
to see in like real time.
Seen it like 10 times different
documentaries in the past.
I haven't, I mean, well,
I mean it was, you know what? Maybe
maybe I liked it a lot. And you didn't
because I'm a musician.
Yeah. You know what I mean?
And I look if it was about Gulf,
like if it was about tiger woods in the,
you know you might not like it
but this golf fan worshiped it.
Cause you know if that movie was a came
out when Michael Jackson was alive,
he would be pissed off cause
that's how bad that movie was.
I don't know about that man.
A lot of people liked it.
Joey Diaz rants and
raves about that movie.
To him it was an enjoyable experience.
It's like you got to send me back
Brian to show to that who put together,
I've seen a lot of documentaries that
Michael Jackson, that was the worst one.
That's all I'm saying.
I understand it was the worst you,
but what I'm saying is there's a lot of
people that thought it was fascinating.
It was done very quickly in slap together
but I think that's part of the trouble.
That's part of the interesting aspect
of is there's a lot of raw with them
looking at the production I was looking
at like all this lost footage of him
backstage and practicing and rehearsing.
There's a lot of putting it
all together and the auditions,
that was amazing shit. The way it was all
put together. Dude, I may be a retard,
but when I left that I cried a couple
of fucking times and I was like,
this mother fucker is when he started
breaking down and he's like, I'm like,
I can understand why you
wouldn't like it Brian,
cause you're not gonna do that shit.
But I could also understand why he would
love it because he really is into the,
no, no, no.
I'm a big Michael Jackson fan of every
single album right here on my computer.
It's just that I found that most piss
water production and I'll have a dog in
this race because I honestly
did not watch the whole thing.
I only watched like maybe 2030 minutes.
So I'm just saying,
I was just amazed his whole
career that you didn't like them.
But then seeing that movie,
I still don't like the music.
What documentaries have you,
I'm not liked that I liked.
Was there anything that I
really loved and you hated?
Is there anything that I
really love that you hit on?
So we have pretty similar taste. What
movies annoyed you? That didn't annoy me.
Anything you can think of a,
I know there's been some,
I'm more tolerant for
retarded movies in are,
you know what movie I just saw for
the first time, but, and that I liked,
I was shocked. I'm not a Zombie
Movie Fan at all. Ambulance? No,
no resident evil one. Oh, that's pretty
good too. I liked it. Did you like it?
I liked it. It was the first, there
was the best excuse for Zombie.
Did you watch and I like
checking like, okay. Was that,
did you watch what you check? Did
you uh, did you not see Zombie land?
I saw that too. I was cool. It was
cool. The excuses for the zombies.
Like I'd like the scientific one from
resident evil. It was like a hot dog.
You know, the cutting edge of size. Only
one. There's only one 28 days later.
Every other Zombie movie needs to shut
the fuck up. Shaun of the dead. Yeah.
But that's kind of funny.
That's not not the same as far
as like scary Zombie movies.
28 days later is the shit. You seeing
that I'm not just the English movie.
I don't remember who the sequel wasn't
bad either. Not Bad. Yeah. Not as good,
but not bad. Pretty fucking good man.
True. That's a realistic scenario.
It's a, a biological, a
weapon that they're creating.
They're testing out on chimpanzees in a
bunch of animal rights activists come in
and break into the testing lab and release
the champs, the champs of tack them.
Just start ripping them apart
and some new drug called rage.
It's a biological weapon.
Takes off from the chimps,
gets into people and if anything happens,
a spit gets in your eye,
blood from a person,
they bite you,
they get infected instantly and you become
all these fucking crazy zombies like
super steroid rage.
Really zombies though their
eyes turned total red.
They're fucking just trying to your dead
flesh. You got to watch it there. It's,
it's dope. It's dope. And it's believable.
If you think about the diseases that we
have, just think about rabies, rabies,
we'll turn some raccoon into
some crazy mother fucker.
The ones who are coming to your
house and tried to kill you.
People been attacked by
raccoons when they're on rabies.
They kill dogs when they're on break,
but that,
can you think that's Zombie though?
That seems like if they came
up with anything, look, if,
if there's a way that you can change
people's behavior through a parasite,
through introducing some sort of a,
a bacteria or a disease into their system,
which we know you can, you know,
we know about that cat, Paris, I,
we've talked about that from Brazil or
the isn't as the definition of a Zombie.
Someone who was dead and then
later came back to life somehow.
That's the part where you gotta you gotta
have a good reason for you were dead.
Well, if a parent side came
in and took over your body,
and if it wasn't killed parasite,
you'd be dead. If it's using,
if it hijacks your central nervous system
and kills your mind and your mind no
longer exists.
Literally there's a parasite living in
your brain connected to all your nervous
system and running your shit remotely.
[inaudible]
I'm sure. Yeah. When you think sick,
sick, I just have some questions here.
I don't know. I don't know the definition
of a Zombie. A realistic possibility.
There's a fish that has a parasite,
a bunch of fish rather in this parasite
takes the place of the fishes tongue and
eats the tongue.
It's the craziest thing to look at.
I forget what the name of it is, but
if you Google fish, Tom Parasites,
if you're ambitious,
I tongue is eating our racing thing.
The fish stay alive
because the fucking this,
this parasite becomes its tongue
and it helps it swallow food.
It literally cleans to the inside of its
mouth and takes the place of its tongue.
The fish no longer has a tongue.
Instead it has a parent's eye that helps
it eat cause it needs it to get food
down his throat. So he just,
some of the food eat some food.
So the fish swims around,
catches all this food and the
parasite eats it with them.
But if the parents I died or left, the
fish is fucked. It says a China autonomy.
Novelis something,
but h it eats your stuff,
your tongue and leaves you with nothing
there. So the fish, if the parents,
I decided to commit suicide and leave the
fish's mouth, the parents, I'd doesn't,
there's no tongue anymore to
parasites have parasites. They most,
it's an endless cycle.
That's a good question.
But I would Amazonian hot butches have
vaginal parasites. Did you see that?
Imagine that walked the entire length
of the Amazon. Did you see that?
I heard about it. What the fuck?
Somebody get that guy a hobby, right?
There's a 14 year old girl
from Holland, I think. Yeah,
from Holland who was just got
permission to sail around the world.
She's 14 she gonna to sail around the
world. The fuck is wrong with people.
She's done the fuck is wrong with
by herself, by herself. She's done.
What the fuck is wrong with people?
Why do they want to do such crazy
dangerous shit storm and you're fucked?
Well just why do it if you want to get
over to Brazil or if you know you want to
get to China, why don't you get
in a plane? Why do you want to,
why do you want to go buy a
rowboat? Is that, is that really
going to be more of a journal on the edge?
Yeah.
That's like that's a difficult plane.
You're not even going on a good boat.
You're taking a boat that has to get
there by the wind. That's so stupid.
That's the dumbest,
you know what I think is stupid too is
people like me and like you who fucking
hate getting on planes
and we're like we hate,
we do it so much that we hate getting on
a fucking rocket ship with the craziest
whoever. We love these views from the
Hollywood hills houses and from the, the,
the, you know a top of Mandalay bay.
Look at this view. But we can get,
we get on a plane,
the crushes,
all those views smashes them
and we're like fuck this flight.
We get an awesome to you for two hours
and we hate it cause it kind of looks all
the same. It's boring,
it's boring usually.
But I try to retrain my thought and
try to appreciate that. Sometimes I,
I'm on a plane and I look out
the when and I'm trying to do,
I put my iPod on good music. I just
focus on the beauty that you'll never,
you'll never see again the
way the clouds are formed.
Like it's the ultimate in randomness.
Like clouds will never be that
moment will never be like that again.
The stars in the sun, they're like
clocks. They will always be there.
Clouds and all, you know, it'll never
be the same ever. Every moment is,
I'm right.
Some of my best shit
in planes.
I write some of my best shit in planes
looking out the window cause it's so
humbling. Yeah. There's
something about the experience.
It just gives me this little extra tingle
of fear that I think makes the writing
better. Tingle of humility. You know,
it's just like you bitch, you're,
you're in the tube flying through
air, you know, above everything.
How are we doing this?
Especially when you, if you eat
like a cookie right before,
before you take it
are some straight hash
oil. I took, I went to uh,
teach a seminar in the UK a long
time ago and drank this hash oil tea.
I wanted it to go to sleep and I had the,
I was so lucky.
I got the whole role to myself
is like fucking FirstClass.
I'm laying down in the whole role,
take this whole jar of Hash oil.
I'm going to sleep the whole way. I
didn't sleep, my eyes were closed,
but it was the brightest shit I've
ever seen. It was his pride is this.
No kidding. And Man, I, dude,
I came up with the craziest
shit all the way to England.
Just put together this stupid movie in my
head. And I talked about the gang bang.
I put put,
I ended up being a ripoff of Mamma Mia,
but it's like my version of gang bang.
And um,
I couldn't stop putting
the scenes together,
putting the whole story together and
developing characters and everything.
I couldn't stop.
I wanted to go to sleep.
But the movie had to be done in my
fucking Ed. Dude. It was amazing.
Do when you eat something,
when you eat weed and you are in
a humbling situation like that,
like when you're in in the air flying
through the air like that and you're at a
high altitude too. Like I think
when you're in a plane it's, it's,
it replicates being in like Denver,
like as far as like amount
of air that you can get.
So you get drunker and you get higher.
So if you're eating some shit and
you get on a plane, oh my God,
I've had some life changing experiences.
High as fuck on a plane.
Totally.
A lot of fucking ideas and
decisions get made high on planes.
A lot of life changes.
Chill Dude, which we travel
so much. And how many times have you and
I like right about to get on a plane,
eat a cookie, get on the plane. Like
you're feeling this yet? Not yet. Not yet.
But like we were going to
England, dude, that's a must.
When we went to England once for the UFC,
you'd gave me some shit,
like some breath strips or whatever and
I went to sleep and sometimes that shit
doesn't hit you for like eight hours.
I woke up in England.
That's probably what it was.
I woke up in England and while we were
going through customs, whoo. I'm like,
there's something wrong with me.
I thought it was something wrong with me.
All of a sudden hit it hit
like a fucking two term
worst time ever to be high cost. What are
you doing here? I'm like, I don't know.
Let me, Eddie. Eddie has a past. He got
pulled over having a gun in his car.
Totally legit. He was working
for a cat check cashing store.
He's supposed to have a gun.
He wasn't a criminal,
but just because they caught him
with a gun that shits on his record.
So every time we go to Canada for the
UFC, WWE, he gets pulled aside. Yeah.
What happened? What
happened? Microphones. Dad,
check, check. Your microphone stopped.
No, this should still working. Dude.
Your microphone stopped. I Dunno what
happened there it goes. Now it's back.
What happened Brian? Hello. Check. Check.
Anyway, that's a good way to end this
show. This is a fucking three hour show.
God Damn it.
God Damn Strike Forces an eight.
This is officially the longest
of our podcasts ever. I'm sorry.
I hope you enjoyed it. Um, uh, I'll give
one last plug the plug and plug it up.
Bob,
a new episode of 10th Planet Kush is,
will be out this week for the next UFC,
the Boston show starring Joey Karate.
It's hilarious.
I'm subscribe to my youtube,
youtube.com/ youtube.com/i forget.
Uh, what is your twist already?
Twist her last twist already.
Subscribe the new one.
We're going to change the name to MMA
wild so I keep forgetting that cause 10th
planet Kush is pretty bad ass I think I
say keep it because people know it. Yeah,
I think so. Yes, because you told me MMA
wild. I had to remember it three times,
but when I go looking for 10 planet Kush,
I always know,
I think it's perfect cause it's got
weed in there. It's got 10th plants.
Everything is that Sun. Well, that's a
totally, totally one at MMA. Wild Joe.
He's trying to get out of the tunnel.
We don't need to talk about,
we'd talk cocksucker.
I'm trying to get a sitcom trying to
get something on the discovery channel.
You think that's what it is and
cock sucker. The people at Disney,
they're that close. I don't want
to work anymore. I'm on the fuck.
I don't want to get on a plane. I'm
300 pounds. I got a breathing machine.
Any Bravo. I love you with all
my heart, but do me a favor.
Take the fucking Kush off.
Take the fucking push off wild.
It's fucking wild. It's MMA. Come on
to this. Those of you on Twitter land,
what do you think?
Should we keep a 10th
planet Kush or should we go
[inaudible] listen, the agents,
Joey's trying to do the right thing
and is trying to get a gig that's he's
trying to do. I was trying to get
a gig. He doesn't call it Brian.
Brian had some video him smoking weed.
What happened with that Brian?
We have one video where he was smoking
weed in it and he made me, uh, take it
down, take that down. And I'm like, wait,
don't you have a show that you interview
or interview pot stores and you smoke
weed and possible all,
we had them all taken down and I'm like,
yeah, maybe he's trying to clean this
shit up. No, nothing wrong with it.
It's beautiful. I think you should
embrace it. Only go with it, you know.
Well we got to do is figure out a way to
make Joey famous as a comic. You know,
it's almost a travesty when when we go on
the road and Joey, uh, in ours as well,
ours should be a headliner too,
but these guys are headliners.
They're both headliners and they're,
they're opening for me. You know,
did people should be
paying to see Joey Diaz?
They should be going and seeing
Joey Diaz do a 45 minute set.
I know Joey doesn't like to do long sets
like that. He's a monster for like 15,
20 minutes. That's what
he's best at. Crushes. Yeah.
Just opened when he opened for you
when you taped your last special.
I had never seen him dominate. If
we does anybody. Yeah, I have it.
I told him I go on the DVD. No, no,
this what we're going to do that wants
to make sure he doesn't have anything
except a couple of a showtime specials,
little 10 minutes out and shit.
He wants to make sure we're going to do
something with him I think at like Sal's
comedy hall or something like that.
Well we set up some
cameras and have Joey film.
They're like two nights in a row
and have a killer set and DVD.
I don't think it would be too hard to
convince Dana to produce like a Joey Diaz
as little special little
spike. Special man. Dude.
He was hard to do a spike special
because they need a name that he, yes,
he would crush.
You know what he would crush on in some
sort of a television show where people
get to know them but the
two a one off special,
you got to have a name that's
unfortunately the problem.
Well we need to do is get something
and promote it through my website and
promote it through Twitter and
get it out there, you know,
and get comedy central to do
something with them. That's,
that's what what Joey is,
is as rare down and dirty out there.
And then jungle comedian Joey will go
and do 20 minutes at a Mexican restaurant
tonight and like,
he'll like Joe Rogan.
I get this fucking new place I'm
trying done near Pasadena. You know,
it's always like this fucking Guy
Louis Alvarez send me down there.
It's the bomb. They got good pulled pork
and you fucking get a free sandwich.
You go on stage,
do 20 minutes and he'll,
he'll do fucking 20 minutes for
50 bucks here. He'll go, you know,
this guy tells me a hundred. I go
down there, I go to San Covina,
I'll go down there. I do a fucking
set. Let's fuck. He's a wild man.
He's like always working on his act.
He's always like hustling.
He's always going from place to place.
You know,
Joey's always putting new shit together.
He's always like piecing this out.
He's like, he's on the grind,
comic hustling. He's doing comedy,
hustling on the grind,
picking up twos and ones and the hundreds
and 50s and slap it all together with
some fucking residuals.
They're filling,
someone's filming a documentary
on him all this week.
The falling into all of these gigs.
Yeah. Yeah. He told me about this. Yeah.
That's what they should do. Someone should
do it. He's a real American original.
There's no did.
He should be gigantic.
He's not fucking funny.
This is what Joey looked
like when I met him.
This was Joey. When I met him, Joe,
he was like 200 pounds,
maybe,
maybe two 20 he was a fucking like a thug
looking big pussy lips and character.
It was like a big football player dude.
And in the time that I knew him in,
you know,
10 plus years,
he gained fuck almost 200 pounds and
then I lost a hundred they lost a hundred
which is incredible. That's
incredible. How many people do that?
I mean the Joey karate that did the
intros to DVD and the joy Crotty now.
Totally different human. Yeah. It's
half and half his size. It's ridiculous.
He was ginormous. What a unusual human
being that guy is. You know, I mean,
I am, one of the things
we're very fortunate about,
I mean I'm fortunate about everything.
Basically. I'm the luckiest dude ever.
But one of the things I've fortunate is
all the cool friends that I've managed
to meet and be friends with and keeping
my life all the years, you know? And,
and you guys too,
you know,
you guys are both good friends of mine
and I want to hug this out and just be
friends. Brian, pay attention. If you turn
on the air conditioning, you can look,
be your friends. Oh, I didn't turn it
on. Yeah, it's pretty warm in here. Um,
but Joey, Joey is one of those
rare dudes where it's like, wow,
I might not ever meet a guy like him
ever, ever in my life. Or You, I know.
I don't think I'll meet another you
and you ain't meeting another me bitch.
I doubt it. Another mini
either stupid Brian,
what does that had that it's like,
what is it? Legend of Zelda? Hey,
did you hear about that guy that is suing,
uh,
the Hawaiian guy who is suing
some South Korean game, uh,
company because he can't function.
He's so addicted to this
game that he can't function.
I could see that fucking
brought us, allowing the
lawsuit that I can see this as,
that.
I can see that.
But how the fuck can you sue someone
for making something awesome?
All you're saying is you've made something
so awesome that I don't want to do
the rest of my shit.
What if there was some kind of clause
in the software that's like, okay,
you've been playing for three
days straight. You know,
I had to play for an hour.
What if I got money?
What have I gotten money and I have all
the time in the world and I just say,
you know what I'm gonna do,
I'm gonna play this fucking crazy game
for a full month and I'm gonna make a
documentary on it.
And that's what I want to do.
I want to eat and sleep and play
this game. Why can't I do it? Well,
you can get special permission
from the game. Makes it,
you're going to make a documentary,
but some of these people are fucking
really like spending weeks at a time on
that's on them, dude.
If they weren't that,
they'd be picking scabs or sticking
things up their ass. People are crazy.
People are fucking crazy.
And if you came up with something that's
so awesome that they just want to do it
every day and they forget to eat, fuck,
fuck them. You can't sue for that.
That's like anti evolution
over that judges.
That's an anti-evolution motherfucker.
A judge who allowed that lawsuit.
That's ridiculous. He might be
allowing it to happen just so he,
so the video game maker will win and no
one else will be able to do it, you know?
Is that true? It might be like I
might be right. Yeah, but that's,
it seems like you would,
you'd want to just throw it out
then and set a precedent right away.
This is not going to be accepted. You
can't sue someone for that. I mean,
there's no legal battle,
but you're saying something so awesome
that I can't go back to regular life.
I can't function internet.
Getting to a point though where it's like
a drug like any other joint without a
dude for five days. All I did is
I and your Jones, our Twitter,
Twitter messages up. No, I was
okay. I was in Hawaii. I was, okay.
Let me just fucking hanging out all
day. I, I, all I did was go on Twitter,
look a little bit and look at some
fucked up videos and some pieces of up it
throws, you know why he still had to go
check, but you know what I did though.
I only did it with my iPad. I didn't
go online. I didn't fuck with my forum.
I didn't, I didn't go
on. I did. Maybe I did.
We'll go to the underground a little bit.
There you go.
But I didn't do it nearly as much
as I do during the day. It is.
But I think it's a good try to do
a week with zero. Okay. But why?
Just see if he can do it, but I could
do it. I mean people have done it. Yeah.
My grandfather live without his whole
life. He never got online. Yeah.
But their ticket to death.
You're in Hawaii. You could,
it could have done easily.
Sit down and you go,
I wonder what's going on on Twitter.
Maybe somebody posted something.
Life changing that type of information.
I must figure out nonsense.
Ghetto gaggers.com sign. I
want to see the next thing.
I'm going to hire someone to sue
me for being addicted to my music.
That's a good number. That's strong. Yo.
Seven o'clock strike forces on right now.
All right, we're going to end this.
Um, go to a, what is the website?
10th Planet J j.com.
Free Techniques Til October one.
All of them are free.
I mean if you never done some Jujitsu,
find a place near you. There's 10 flat
and affiliates all over the country.
If you can't find that fun,
another Jujitsu school,
it's the fucking most fun thing.
It's a great way to exercise.
You don't have to think about doing boring
shit like going to the gym and riding
a bike.
It makes it fun.
Brian Red band.com pet seen Terry on funny
or die. See Metairie. It is very funny.
It's very disturbing.
But Brian is a funny little character
and he always makes funny things.
And thank you very much for tuning
in my friends. We appreciate it.
This is the extended three hour version
of the podcast, never to be repeated.
And this is the one time we babbled all
the way to strike force. Uh, but, uh,
I hope you guys enjoyed it and as
always, I love you bitches. Thank you.