The joe rogan experience.
I,
one of the most uncomfortable moments
in my life was me sitting next to Kareem
Abdul Jabbar.
Actually,
I had to wildly uncomfortable moments
that involved Kareem Abdul Jabbar.
One is,
he just sat down on my
radio show and I was like,
you know,
you never see any,
any guys in their seventies
that are over six,
seven or six,
eight.
And I mean I,
you know,
I'm not trying to bring
you down you literally,
but is there some syndrome or have you
talked to somebody or how does it work?
Cause you just don't see seven footers
that are 80 years old but yet you seem
like you're in perfect health and I
don't know how it works and if there's
something that I'm not aware of.
And he's like,
what are you talking about?
And I was like,
you know how you don't
see a lot of old guys?
They're like over six,
five.
They seem to go a little earlier in life.
So my affect,
the little short Jewish guys,
the ones that go on forever,
is there some connection
correlation between the height
and the short longevity?
And he was like,
I never thought about it.
And I was like,
Oh shit.
Really?
And he's like,
yeah,
now I am this kind of comfortable.
Like I was like,
but no,
but I need to bring this up.
So he,
uh,
he did that to me.
And then we're like dodger
all star game or something,
celebrity game.
And we're sitting next to each other
waiting for the real dodger game to end in
like the,
you know,
the time it was Sorta,
dug out eating hot wings or something
like this up on the Lowe's level.
And some kid came by and said,
could you sign my baseball?
And I signed this baseball.
And then he handed it to Kareem
Abdul Jabbar and he said,
could you sign my baseball?
And he's like,
uh,
no.
And,
and the kid was like,
really?
Cause it just take a second.
And he's like,
I,
I'm not,
I'm not doing that right now.
And I'm seeing like right next to him.
And the kid comes back for a third,
like Ryan,
and he's like,
you know,
just real quick.
And he's like,
no,
I'm sorry.
Wow.
And I'm like,
just fucking sign it.
Just sign it.
And then he walks away and then his mom
shows up like 10 minutes later and she's
like,
I'm so sorry to disturb you,
Mr Abdul Jabbar.
But um,
DePaul for my son,
he's such a huge fan.
Do you think you could just take a moment?
It's like,
sorry.
No.
And she's like,
just,
just a moment and,
and she's like,
no,
thank you.
And I'm just like,
I'm sitting next to him wanting to crawl
out of my urethra and just go under the
carpet.
You know that thing,
having to pretend like,
you know,
that body language that
says I'm not listening.
Like we can all know
the fake body language.
I am listening,
but I'm trying to discover the,
I'm not really listening.
You start leaning a little in God and she
really asked like three or four times.
He's like,
sorry.
No.
And she's like,
well,
I'm really,
because we could have
signed it in this time.
It took,
no,
I'm sorry.
No,
just like Holly,
I want to go.
I'll fucking sign it.
I'll your pussy whatever.
Please go away with tape.
Thank your son somewhere
and then it's fucked up.
He is.
Yeah,
I guess was dead,
right?
No,
no,
no.
The point is,
the point at which will
Chamberlain is done.
Yeah,
we'll,
it's dead.
The point,
the point is,
um,
I realize the guy seven four,
there's not a place,
it's,
it's about height.
I mean your spot and you're stopped.
He gets stopped everywhere.
He goes.
I'm not defending the guy,
but that guy has probably
been bugged for autographs.
None stop for 50 years.
And I bet he's just fucking
hadn't impacted asphalt of it.
Betty has,
but he should reconsider
the way that in that case,
especially little kids,
some kid,
and you can make their day.
It's so easy to make their day.
You're going to have to communicate with
them and he's right there and you're
sure that I'm preaching to
the choir talking to you.
You sure it was him,
right?
It wasn't a guy who just look like,
yeah,
it's a six [inaudible] four black guy
changed his name from Lew Alcindor Doula,
who was Lew Alcindor.
Yeah.
I was thinking like I was,
I was joking about this
once where I was saying,
you know,
Cat Stevens,
uh,
Cassius clay,
Lew Alcindor all really bitch and names
like no reason to take the Muslim name.
It's true.
Trickle should take the Muslim name,
right?
Not maybe even Dick Butkus but
not cash is polite like cats.
Steve's like you guys already are.
We're blessed with some of the
coolest names on the planet.
You know,
much less pussy.
You're going to get cat.
Steven's going to ease left moves
lamb or whatever the fuck it is.
I mean that you're going to cut
the pussy spicket off imagining.
Imagine his agent.
How does that Hobos had the
phone call go with his agent.
Hey Marty.
Yeah.
No,
I'm not going by cat anymore.
That's uh,
that's my slave name now.
Non Cat Stevens.
Now I'm going to,
now I'm going to be shelling my neck
down is going to be the best of Yousef
Islam.
You're a fucking human being.