Is it recording?
Yes.
Good.
Okay.
Beautiful.
Yeah,
we always have these things where it's
three hours.
I'm like,
God,
it,
we can,
uh,
you know,
at least you don't have a 30 or 60
minutes show.
They have to put your commercials in the
middle and everything.
By the way,
I'll give a plug for legal zoom that
when I first came to California it took
me two days in a law library to get up
to speed so I could write my will and
uh,
I was glad to see that there's still a
discount with Rogan cause that's my
project this month is to Redo my will
and leave,
you know,
I've,
I've known about legal zoom for a long
time and is a really good group.
That's another thing that I think the
internet sort of made a lot easier
finding out what your rights are,
finding out how the law of lawyers
mainly know how to use the library and
have their secretaries type of things,
you know,
because they gotta go by so and so legal
zoom can take care of probably 95
percent of all your stuff.
Did you go from being a lawyer to
running a computer company?
Well,
I was,
uh,
I was practicing law in Houston and uh,
we had primarily a business law.
Uh,
my partner and I owned a title insurance
company and we're doing,
it was in the heyday in Houston when the
savings and loan thing was going on,
but,
uh,
one day our main client came in and he
had a big construction company and he
wanted to sue one of his subcontractors
and,
you know,
I looked at all and I said,
well,
Jeremy,
I know you,
you can file a lawsuit but you're not
going to win because he's in the right
here.
He says,
oh,
I know that.
I just want to hurt him.
So I said,
give me just a minute.
I walked around to the next office,
to my partner.
I said,
figure out what my share of the south is
worth.
I quit,
I'm going home.
And that was when I,
I just,
I,
it'd been building up to that because
I've been doing stuff that I didn't
become a lawyer to hurt people and do
stuff like that.
And so,
uh,
I just walked away from it and uh,
had gotten locked involved in multilevel
marketing.
Wow.
And uh,
yeah,
uh,
what I found out is,
is that if you say,
Hey,
I'm a lawyer and I'm doing this,
people just flock to you,
you know,
I have lots of people.
And because you're a lawyer doing well,
they say,
well,
if a lawyer is doing it,
you know,
it's got to be great.
So is it like a pyramid scheme?
Pyramid come.
Yeah,
we're selling a do it yourself at home
facelifts.
It was,
it was before anybody knew about aloe.
Vera was one of the first aloe companies
and it was really easy to sell.
We do a meeting and a bunch of people to
be there and you'd paint half their face
with this stuff and leave it on for like
30 minutes and take it off.
And it looked like there to patient one
side's a little higher.
And yet sort of like putting a,
what's that hemorrhoid medicine in your
face or something.
But what's hemorrhoid preparation?
Preparation H,
yeah,
it happens when you put.
It just tightens you up.
It tightens your skin up for an hour or
so.
When you put aloe Vera,
this was a whole bunch of it.
It actually did work.
It did tighten up your skin and get rid
of some wrinkles for the evening.
Yeah.
Oh yeah.
It worked for the evening.
For the evening.
Yeah.
It wasn't pretty.
But uh,
and,
and we sold a whole variety of things.
Why don't like actors do that before
they make movies,
I think get this stuff and you can't get
a hold of era anymore.
You can get elevated.
But this was,
this had some powders and stuff.
You use a chemical thing.
What happened to the surface now people
say no,
the company went out of business.
Uh,
you know,
there,
there's all these,
you know,
I,
I know a lot about these multilevel
companies.
They,
they all spring from a vitamin company,
a neutral light,
I think it's called.
And that's where the,
uh,
device and Van Andel it started a amway
came true light.
Yeah.
I think amway finally bought them or
something like that.
But what's that big one?
That's a big one with the leaves that.
Oh,
that's a uh,
I'll think of it in huge company.
Yeah.
Well,
anyhow,
herbalife,
in fact,
one of the first vice president came out
of this company.
I was in a ideal incorporated,
but there was a dare to be great and
cause caught.
And uh,
one that,
uh,
the California governor campaign,
that guy.
Anyhow,
I used to know a whole lot about this
and they all sprung from the same core
of people at one time.
They all knew each other and I got
involved in that for awhile and we were
selling all kinds of thing.
And then my partner and I started a
jewelry company and we kind of fell out
and I was into computers.
So I started a computer company.
It was a pyramid company and uh,
you know,
it,
it was a lot of fun.
But,
uh,
you know,
I finally lost the faith because for
awhile I really believed that you could
do these things.
You know,
we had a,
a woman who was a German refugee that
wound up making $20,000
a month and stuff like that.
And so those things did happen,
but they were so rare.
Finally,
uh,
you know,
I was able to see the light.
Well,
it happened after I started taking Mtma.
That's when I got out of the
motivational business and everything.
And the motivational business,
that's a slippery business.
It's fascinating to me.
People that have never been successful
at business but give motivational
seminars on how to be successful at
business.
After my computer company crashed.
That's what I got into.
That's a fascinating thing,
isn't it?
That people would.
It's sort of like,
you know,
like there's comedy classes that are
taught by extremely unfunny people.
I believe people that have never had a
career as a comedian,
but they decided to start teaching
comedy and then they started making more
money teaching comedy than they ever did
doing comedy itself.
Yeah.
It's like a lot of that.
Back in Boston,
there was a guy that was terrible
comedian who was teaching the local
comedy class.
I was like,
that doesn't make any.
Like,
what the fuck was going on here?
You couldn't get a real comedian to
teach a comedy class.
They didn't want to have any part of it
and you'd be surprised how many
motivational speakers are great
depression all the time.
You know,
we'd,
we'd go back after the thing would be
over.
We'd get off stage,
Oh gee,
my wife is leaving me and you know,
all these.
We had more problems than our audience
combined probably.
But you had some good ideas.
He just had to figure it out.
Yeah.
You know,
they were all,
you know,
from 100 years ago,
there's not much new in that field.
It's a.
well,
Anthony Robbins is another one.
Right.
Tony Robbins,
he's a super successful at that.
But what else has he done?
I mean,
is he like,
had like a successful real business.
You know,
when he first came in the scene,
I just started kicking myself because I
said,
gosh,
I was doing that and I'm better than
him.
He's very handsome or beautiful teeth.
Oh yeah.
He's in,
he's got.
He has a lot more confident than I was a
booming voice.
Throws karate kicks,
but you know,
eventually you kind of push yourself to.
Then he started doing all the
firewalking and stuff like that and
yeah,
that's firewalk hey,
my wife did it and did not get burned
the first time you could do it and knock
it burn to.
Oh well no.
You Walk Quick.
I could not do it.
I'm not going to walk on fire barefoot,
but if you did,
you'd be all right.
The whole idea is getting through
quickly.
If I did,
I know I'd get through all right because
I wouldn't do it unless I was sure I was
going to get through.
All right.
Um,
you could think that you are going to be
all right and not be all right.
But that's what happened the second
time.
How far did she walk longer?
The second time I think was probably the
same.
Real?
Yeah.
I don't know.
I mean I didn't know her then.
I probably shouldn't be talking about
it.
I get it symbolically.
You.
No,
but unless it's fuckery.
Like we all know fire burns are wise
finding out brand because I don't
believe it's going to burn.
Oh boy.
I'm not sure about that.
I think you might be playing games here.
Oh,
you know,
the three laws of taking psychedelics
are,
number one,
cars are real.
Number two,
fire burns,
and number three,
gravity is still a law.
If you lift as those three things,
you can't go wrong.
That's like the bill Hicks joke.
Did you ever the bill Hicks choke on
acid?
Thought he could fly,
jumped off the building,
and he's like,
if he thought he could fly,
what did he take off from the ground?
I didn't hear the last a moron.
I remember that.
That's.
It's so logical.
It is logical.
It's like,
wait a minute.
That guy was an asshole.
He was a Houston Guy,
right?
Yeah.
See I,
I left Houston by then when I was going
to law school in Houston.
Uh,
the only celebrity I saw that wasn't a
celebrity then was Glen Campbell was,
was singing for tips in this bar.
I used to.
But uh,
I,
I used to hang out and lightning hopkins
bar.
He was a black,
a blues guy and uh,
a couple of us would go down to Houston.
Yeah.
He was that down in the fifth ward
somewhere,
we'd have to go into a little group,
but we went regularly enough that we got
known were the only white kids in there,
you know,
and so,
uh,
one and he'd,
you know,
he'd wrapped with us and stuff and I
said,
hey,
I can play the spoons.
And he says,
give the boys some spoons,
get up here.
And so I started playing the spoons
while he's playing guitar,
you know,
and he stops and he says,
you're in law school right now?
I said,
yeah.
He says,
go back to law school.
You'll never make it as a musician.
What an asshole.
Oh No,
no.
He did it in a funny way and I know he
was,
he was actually right.
I couldn't keep a beat.
You know,
Houston had two of the greatest
comedians of all time come out of it.
Sam kinison and building it in.
Yeah,
that's right.
They had that whole Houston annex down
back and then they had like a real
creative group of young up and coming
comedians and they,
you know,
they started this thing that
Houston comedy outlaws.
And it was Hicks and Kennison and a
bunch of other guys.
Fascinating sort of a development.
I went to law school there in Houston
and I taught sailing at Houston Yacht
Club.
That's how I got there because of
Kennison.
They all had like this unique style
that's very aggressive in your face.
Thoughtful style of,
of breaking things down in a very
logical way,
you know,
but,
but making good points,
but also,
you know,
being like really bold about it.
I heard you and,
and uh,
I think it was mark Marin talking about
Kennison and boy,
that really gave me a whole new,
uh,
Marin sm,
amazing Kennis and stories.
When he was on his podcast,
he was talking about doing coke with
Kennison and you know,
how he was hearing voices for like a
year.
They did someone who was a young kid.
Then when you're with him,
you know,
but she,
can you imagine he did so much coke.
He was hearing voices for a year.
Whoa man.
Holy break.
Your Brain Batman.
I was lucky I never cook.
I was like,
you've never tried it.
I,
the same woman that gave me Mtma for the
first time.
I gave me my first line of coke and I
said,
oh,
this is awful man.
It's like being a dentist's office.
And she said,
Oh yeah,
it's always like that and beginning,
but you know,
after,
after you know,
10,
12 times,
she'll,
you'll get to like it.
And I said,
you know,
I went through that with Scotch and it's
cheap and legal.
I'm not going to go through that again.
Yeah,
there's weird things like caviar,
it's an acquired taste.
Why would you acquire it?
Why would you acquire something that
costs $10,000
in,
tastes like shit.
And if you don't like it to begin with,
why acquire it?
Why acquire that?
That seems really silly.
Yeah.
I never did the cocaine,
but uh,
I've had a bunch of people near me that
had problems with it.
I always associate cocaine with a lot of
negative things that I'd seen,
but one of the biggest ones was,
uh,
I was driving with some friends.
We were in revere Massachusetts and
there was this two lane road that we're
leaving this area that was like a,
there was this famous place.
We'd go to Kelly's roast beef and
everybody would go there and get clams.
They had like fried clams there.
It's like a famous spot.
People travel from far and wide to go to
Kelly's.
So we were driving back from that and
there's people behind us,
people beside us in this car,
we're doing coke and there was a girl in
the backseat and they had the light that
dome light on and she was doing coke and
she looks over and sees us looking in
there and she goes like this,
fuck.
She's like,
as they're driving by just looks at me
like anger and craziness and that's how
I view coke.
Have you is like that lady.
Look,
I was looking at her.
You're doing coke.
You have the Dome light on and I'm
looking at you and you're mad at me.
I didn't do anything.
No.
I've had a few friends that got into it
too far and it's.
It's devastating.
Yeah.
So another thing that's another one of
those things that your body connects to
chemicals and become,
it becomes a massive part of your life
or some really strange reason.
I've only done meth twice.
Oh,
that's a weird thing to say.
And,
and
the reason I would never do it again is
because it's the one drug that could hit
hook me is wow.
The first time I did,
I didn't even know what it was.
I was a crewing for racing sailboats
over New Orleans at Mardi gras regatta.
And a guy that owned the boat was from
Houston and I was in law school there
and he wanted me to drive his boat back.
Trail is on a trailer that dragon.
And I said,
oh,
I can't go back.
You know,
I'm sleepy,
I haven't slept in two days.
And he says,
here,
take this.
He gave me this and I drove straight
through from New Orleans to Houston.
I was wired,
you know,
and it was about a year later I said,
hey,
I want one more of those things.
And he gave it to me and I thought,
you know,
I could get really hooked on this stuff,
but I never drive her mess.
What truck?
Driver math?
Yeah.
That's the real math,
right?
I don't know,
but I never came near it again after
that.
I've had some people got in real trouble
with that to some friends.
What is the comedown light?
It's,
it's crash.
For me,
it was just a total crash.
I could,
once I finally came down,
I didn't go to class for a couple of
days.
You know,
when you were taking pure Mtma you had
no crash at all?
I didn't not,
you know,
because nobody knew that you're supposed
to.
I think that uh,
the other thing is I was working at the
time,
so maybe I was just so busy.
I didn't notice it.
But,
uh,
I'd never had to come down crash.
When I was in Dallas,
I had a big one.
I'll read it once.
The next day I had to perform,
I had to do a standup set and I went to
a coffee shop in the morning and I was
reading a magazine I couldn't read.
I was like,
I couldn't read.
I couldn't,
couldn't stay focused long enough to get
through a sentence.
I couldn't get through a paragraph.
I couldn't do it.
I just,
I did have it in there.
I was like,
wow,
I am stupid as fuck.
I was like,
what's going on with my brain?
I didn't know about five htp.
I didn't know about supplementing
afterwards to try to re re re kickstart
your brain's ability to produce
serotonin and dopamine.
But uh,
it didn't,
didn't sit me while I enjoyed the
experience as far as like what I got out
of it.
But I also thought this would be very
dangerous because that reality of the
loving,
warm ecstasy feeling when you're locked
into it is very appealing.
And you could want to do that a lot.
And then if you wanted to do that a lot,
you would experience that more or enjoy
it more than you would enjoy regular
reality.
And then it would,
you know,
it's sort of like a point of diminishing
returns,
build up a tolerance to it.
Yeah.
I,
I did more Mtma then is sensible and
because I didn't know what I was doing,
see,
that was the problem back then.
Nobody knew anything about it in Dallas,
you know,
and we know it's safe,
don't worry about it.
And there was just no literature.
There was no nothing.
How did it get started?
Uh,
well,
the,
I don't know if the story ever really
got out,
but this guy,
what he went by,
the name Thomas Crown,
he was the,
uh,
he was really the mainstay.
Although,
uh,
there's a guy that,
I'll think of his name in a minute.
Everybody thought was the number one guy
in Dallas,
but he was a good friend of Tim leary
and he's out here in La and Tim leary
says here,
try this.
And that's when he found him.
Oh,
this is great.
I'm going to take it back.
And He,
he lit up Dallas with this stuff.
So,
uh,
but,
I,
I actually did a motivational speech and
Mtma one time about two hours after I'd
taken it,
so I was still pretty much up there and
they'd pay me to do a 30 minute keynote
speech at this big corporate thing.
I was an hour into it when they finally
caught me off the stage,
I had people on their feet is one of the
best talks I ever gave.
Why they,
they cut you off,
but it was only supposed to talk 30
minutes and after an hour they said,
you know,
that's really enough.
Wow.
That's A.
Nobody was only one person in the room
that knew I was an Mtma.
It was one of the women there that uh,
uh,
actually she was one of my distributors.
And what did she think?
She,
she couldn't believe I was going to go
on first of all.
Wow.
I did a lot of stupid stuff.
Yeah.
Well that sounds like nobody really knew
what the hell was going on with that
stuff.
Chances.
Human Guinea pigs.
Yeah.
And in that little interview I did,
I told about the time that uh,
well I took an way excessive dose.
What does that mean?
What's the way?
Excessive 1500 milligrams.
What's the,
what's an average one?
Hundred and 20 is what is that what you
should take?
You shouldn't,
you should 120.
So you took 10 times and I still have
these two cassette to 90 minute cassette
tapes that I filled up talking that
whole time.
I've never had the courage to listen to
them again.
But from that time,
for another seven years,
I'd tried Mtma about five years ago.
Not long after nothing happened.
Five years after.
Nothing happened.
About seven years after I finally got
MDM aid work again,
only did it once,
a year after that.
And I haven't done it now and I guess
five,
six,
seven years.
But,
uh,
it,
it really fried my brain.
Now,
you know,
Oprah put this bad news information out
about the holes in the brain thing.
And the night before,
a couple days for that show aired,
her producer was informed by maps that
this is a totally bogus.
It was alive.
They put out there,
there's no holes in the brain.
It was a blood flow Mri or something
like that.
And I,
you know,
maybe I would be a genius today if I
hadn't done that,
but it,
you know,
it didn't really fry my brain now.
It was so stupid.
I had a monster headache for three or
four days and a did not work again for a
long,
long time,
but it didn't kill me and it didn't,
I don't think put holes in my brain.
The holes in the brain things,
what everybody said.
That was one of those,
well Oprah,
Oprah did that,
you know,
she had this Mri at this woman and the
woman knew that it wasn't a hole in her
brain maps.
So I got ahold of it and they really
gave her all the information.
What this is,
is about blood flow or something.
Uh,
but it was not a hole in her brain.
And Oprah's producer knew that going in
and she still let that hit the air.
Sort of like the Ben Gazi thing only
didn't get busted.
That's so silly.
Why?
You know,
why,
but you know,
I think they probably were trying to
save people.
They're probably trying to like scare
people off doing and maybe in this day
and age when you're dealing with
something that's ultimately,
you know,
cut with a bunch of other shit.
Now I went up,
I would never take something that,
that I got at a rave or a party or
something like that that you just can't
trust this stuff.
And a lot of it's,
you know,
you don't know who's making it.
And we at least had good sources,
good supplies.
We knew who the chemist was,
stuff like that.
But uh,
today it's really not safe unless you're
the chemist or friend of,
um,
unfortunately,
you know,
all,
all could be fixed in a way you don't
need to.
You've got pot.
Cannabis is really the miracle drug.
It,
you know,
the plant does so much things for you.
The hemp plant does that.
Cannabis is really a medicinal plant.
Certainly is.
But for ptsd there's nothing like MDM,
mdm a,
but see that would be used with a doctor
who knows his fly and stuff like that.
Now I'm not saying there's anything
wrong with dancing.
I've danced all night on it too.
It's really good,
but there you.
Oh,
that's wonderful.
How old were you when you were dancing?
All night on MDM and I was in my
sixties.
You were just learning?
Yeah.
I'm.
I'm just catching up.
You know,
your kids got ahead of me.
Everybody.
They're ahead of us.
Data you.
They're ahead of me.
The kids of today,
are they?
They're starting from the jump of the
information.
They just need to be cautious.
Don't have to be crazy about these.
It's just so unfortunate.
When we have so many dangerous drugs
that are labeled their prescription
drugs,
their,
their dosages clearly marked.
We know about them and yet there's these
illegal ones that are just floating
around out there and they're there in
commerce or in connection.
There's money.
Money's being exchanged back and forth
for taking him.
There's no way you can ever regulate
that unless you make it illegal.
You can't.
It is legal and then you get some kind
of a structure to take care of it,
but then again,
the argument is logo that's going to be
legal,
going to make meth illegal to like start
with cannabis.
Yeah.
And see what happens.
You know that uh,
Oh,
you down for legal truck or math?
Math was legal.
Well,
yeah,
because you could regulate it.
Yeah.
But still you regulate it and say,
you know,
who needs it?
Nobody.
But still people would use it like
crazy.
They'd be way fucked up on it.
They will go to the truck stop.
You know,
I really don't ever give much thought to
those kinds of things because,
you know,
I'm not an activist and drug policy or
stuff like that.
And so,
uh,
you know,
mushrooms you can,
you can grow at home now there's a new
method to chrome and hydrogen peroxide
so you don't have to worry about all
this,
you know,
sanitation stuff and grow mushrooms and
hydrogen peroxide as a bunch of youtube
videos about it.
Been out about two years now.
Thirty five hours every second goes up
there or something like that,
at least.
Right?
Yeah.
That's just amazing.
I'll tell you another thing,
not to try.
Not that it's not dangerous,
but you know,
when I first moved to Florida at a
little after several years after I moved
there and I lost all my connections and
stuff.
So the word on the street was that a
nutmeg was very similar to MDM and a,
and you could take some nutmeg.
So I got one of those little mccormick
tins of nutmeg and I,
it all and I took me and not the big
tin,
but the,
that me and putting them in capsules.
Yeah.
And I took the whole thing at one time.
Oh my God,
I got real sweaty,
got a horrible headache.
And today,
uh,
Christmas time I can't get near the
Eggnog if it's got nutmeg on it because
I'll throw up to this day.
To this day,
nutmeg will make me sick.
But I have heard of people getting high
from nutmeg.
So what's that?
That's what I heard too.
But.
Well,
maybe you have to get the big tin,
but the little tune a big tin of nutmeg
and we'll just get you sick,
but a big team will get you high.
Well,
I don't know.
I would not try it myself because a
little tin convinced me not to try it.
Yeah.
There was some guys in my message board
that we're experimenting with getting
high on that.
I've heard that.
I just don't believe it.
Is that on the airway they have trip
reports and getting high on nutmeg.
Maybe they do.
I don't know.
I,
I know earth and fire are friends of
mine and it's a release or erowid.org.
That's the first place to go if you're
going to do a drug.
Yeah.
Arrow,
widow and spend a lot more time there
than you spend doing the drug.
Yeah.
Arrowhead.
Nutmeg.
What's.
Find out if they have some horrible
stories about,
about,
um,
basketball sometimes.
Yeah.
When somebody asked me,
well what's this like?
Should I try this?
I said,
go to arrowhead and read the bad trip
reports and if you can't handle a bad
trip then don't go.
But don't read the good trip reports.
Anybody can handle a good trip.
Yeah,
there is.
Apparently there's a page on Arrow
would.
It's all about nutmeg.
If I love this.
Arrowhead provides information about
psychoactive drugs to educate,
to reduce harms and to support and much
needed policy change that,
that,
uh,
some of their big customers or not
customers or readers or dea agent,
police agents,
they have a whole separate section for
law enforcement and for parents and see
they started out as just a little
database for their friends and now it's
one of the most visited websites on the,
on the net.
It's a huge.
So what did the ages go there for?
Education is to find out more about,
you know,
the,
the new drug will hit the streets and
that's one of the first places they'll
go to find out what it's about.
That's interesting.
I wonder if that's how they found out
about bath salts.
I Dunno,
you know,
they'd find out about it on the street,
but to find out trip reports,
what do you know?
How do we know what these kids are on?
What's it doing to them?
And what do we do to,
we take them to hospital or put them in
jail and yeah,
there's gonna come a day when people
look back at this day and age and go,
God,
they were so nutty,
like they just made it.
Well we're just going to add oxygen to
it in front of them,
sell it.
You know,
we take this and this is illegal to get
you 38 years,
30 years in jail for one ounce.
This however is exactly the same effects
plus this other weird thing that it
does.
And you can just buy it as bad as
they're gonna go,
wait,
why didn't they fix that?
Why did they let that go on for years
and years and years,
right?
You know,
it's crazy.
People and poly drugging is a real
problem with holly.
Dragging a bunch of things together.
Candy flipping,
you know,
some of them are,
are safer than others,
but a lot of the poly drugging is going
on with the prescription drugs now.
That's really fucking well prescription
drugs just with the alcohol.
That's a scary one.
In the original hearing for cannabis,
when they're going to make it illegal in
37,
the only medical testimony was from the
Ama and that was in favor of cannabis
and they cut the guy off and throw them
out of the hearing.
The only medical,
a testimony in scheduling it or that
taxing it at the time was in favor.
Yeah,
we're in some weird time still.
It's amazing.
It's amazing that 1937 work,
you know,
in 1930,
whatever it was,
and they made cannabis legal was a 37 to
this day.
It still affected me a massive amount of
couple of generations.
You know,
they just had to just get grandpa and
grandma just get them and then they'll
get to tell their kids and they're going
to tell their kids and everyone's going
to be scared.
Well now there's a huge movement in
geriatric and geriatrics.
Geriatric medical marijuana real.
And I know some one geriatric doctor who
is prescribing it for his patients.
I,
I've,
I've know some anecdotal evidence of,
of older people in nursing homes and all
that have had some marvelous things
happen to them.
So it's finally getting into a GRANDPA
and grandma do.
Wow.
That's amazing.
It's amazing.
After all these years,
people are finally starting to catch on.
Yeah.
I've turned on people in their sixties
that were very anti anti-drug,
but they are all of a sudden all this
pain or they're,
they're going through cancer treatments
or something there,
you know,
they can't keep their food down.
And I said,
hey,
try this Brownie.
You know,
and pretty soon they're going to the
dispensary regularly,
you know,
especially if you lived your life
without it and you thought this is all
it's available now all of a sudden you
have this new cabi your own.
You can't move around much.
Hey,
you know,
there's something I can do here.
Reduces inflammation to a lot of people
that have serious problems with walking
around.
They take some pot and it just makes you
all loosey Goosey as a lot of folks that
have experienced that pain relief from.
Especially if it's high in CBDS.
Right.
I,
I use it for pain relief.
And actually,
I,
uh,
when I'm in pain,
I can't tell it I'm high when I smoke
it,
but the pain doesn't,
I don't think it goes away except you
just don't pay attention to it.
I don't know what the mechanism is about
Ufo shows.
Have you ever had any experience that,
uh,
when you were,
um,
on any sort of a psychedelic that you
felt was like some sort of a paranormal
experience,
like a Ufo experience or like being in
contact with something or seeing
something that you,
uh,
you experienced where it felt like it
was a real thing?
Yeah,
yeah,
several times.
Uh,
mainly on Iowasca.
But,
uh,
there was,
there was one time that you still is
just crystal clear to me where there was
this.
We're sitting in darkness,
you know,
and it appeared like there was a black
curtain in front of me was just a really
bright light coming out from the bottom
and from back behind me,
this,
this female kind of entity,
I,
it was just very dark and shadowy.
I said,
what is that?
And this,
you know,
this could be going on in my head.
I,
I admit that,
but to me it was real and this entity,
she said,
well,
that's what you are really made of.
That's your core,
do you want to see it?
And she reaches down and start to pull
this up.
And it started getting so bright.
I said,
no,
I got scared.
I don't know why.
And uh,
some of my friends said,
I can't believe you didn't let her pick
it up,
you know,
but it was,
it was like a message,
like you are this bright,
shining spirit behind this thing.
To me that was a real entity and counter
of some kind.
So you think that that was like an inter
dimensional thing that you were
communicating with or could have been or
could have been a figment of my
imagination.
You know,
I,
I've not tried to distinguish between it
because the emotional impact of what
went on and what I was thinking and
saying and frayed to look at my own core
was kind of fascinating,
you know?
Well,
it's also what is the source of the
imagination and why is the imagination
so obviously affected by different
chemicals.
And where's the imagination come from?
Exactly what the imagination is clearly
affected by cannabis,
clearly also affected by caffeine,
clearly also affected by alcohol,
definitely affected by Psilocybin,
definitely affected by many,
many,
many other things.
Airplane Glue will do it.
You have ideas that are different than
the ideas that you have if you're in a
baseline sober consciousness,
and the real question then becomes what
exactly is imagination?
Is Imagination just a series of
chemicals interacting with neurons,
interacting with thoughts and ideas and
learned experiences.
Because out of the imagination comes
everything that everyone ever used on
earth.
The thing that wasn't here already,
anything we made,
whether it's a phone or a television set
or a curtain that all came out of the
imagination.
So the imagination isn't just something
where you think things up and they.
Well,
you know,
maybe I just imagined it.
Nothing happens without imagination.
Exactly.
The imagination is the source of every
single creation.
It's a weird thing when you look at it
that way.
Well you don't look at it as something
like,
Oh,
you're just imagining things that aren't
really there.
Right?
Well,
you're also imagining the wheel.
You're also imagining Internet
connections.
You're also imagining airplanes.
Yeah.
Somebody had to imagine all of those,
all of that.
Without that,
there's nothing.
Without the human imagination,
the world would look radically
different.
It would be 100 percent natural and we'd
be animals.
The imagination is the one step that
takes us from animal into animal that
changes its environment radically and
starts to transcend itself,
starts to symbiotically attach itself to
its own creations,
which coincidentally came out of the
imagination.
The imagination created technology that
like the glasses you're wearing or the
watch I'm wearing or any,
any of the things we're talking through
these microphones.
All of that is technology created
through the imagination,
right?
Shoes or tech,
you know,
so when you see something and you say,
well,
maybe it was my imagination.
I'm not exactly sure what that means.
See,
I don't really care whether it's my
imagination or some other
multidimensional entity.
What I focus on,
what am I learning?
What am I feeling?
First of all,
what's my emotional state and then what
am I going to take away from this?
What am I going to learn?
And,
uh,
recently,
podcast,
I put out Mckenna says something to the
effect of what makes us think that,
that the entire cosmos can be understood
using the neural network of a primate.
He says,
we're here to observe and appreciate.
And I like that,
you know,
rather than try to figure out black or a
dark matter and all that,
that's great.
I'm glad people are working on it,
but I'm not gonna worry about it too
much.
I'm,
I'm going gonna appreciate.
And,
and,
uh,
you know,
look at the wonder of the world.
Just look at nature.
It's just amazing.
Mengele known just looked at all the
different varieties of insects.
They're just freaky,
weird,
alien creatures that we just take for
granted because they've always been
here.
Well,
spiders,
we couldn't live without spiders,
you know,
or bees or bees.
And that's getting to be a problem.
It certainly is.
And there's a lot of theories about
that.
But one of the more fascinating ones to
me is that they are absolutely convinced
that whether or not they can survive it
or not,
cell phone signals are damaging.
B's got to be.
It's,
it's fucking with the way they end
people powered lines and cell phone
towers.
You don't want to live near any of
those.
Yeah.
Well I think that a high power lines has
there been a direct correlation ever
established between them and sicknesses
between some high powered lines,
not the real super high frequency power
lines you had.
There had been in effect,
uh,
I know somebody who died of cancer quite
young who lived under those for a long
time.
And now that was anecdotal,
but I think there has been,
there have been some studies now showing
because people in certain neighborhoods
have sued and things like that.
I've been around him before where you
feel them.
Yeah.
And can feel that weird fee here.
You're sanding necks and you kind of
feel a buzz around you.
We just realized like,
this is enough energy to kill everyone
you've ever met ever instantly.
And it's just shooting through these
wire lines.
Well,
we don't know what we're doing to
ourselves with all these electronic
signals.
You know,
you can't get away from it when there's
Wifi everywhere now.
There's no cell phones.
There's TV,
there's radio.
Think of the information that's just in
this room that we can't see.
But with the right equipment we can tune
into.
Well,
that's where it's going to be really
weird when that equipment is actually
inside your brain itself.
Yeah.
That's going to be very,
very,
very strange.
It's getting there to us.
So close.
You know,
they gave the person that first ticket
for wearing google glass.
I saw,
I saw that,
you know,
and I think that was a valid issue of a
ticket to.
I don't want people driving and looking
at Google at the same time or I don't
like people talking on their cell phone
unless they have hands free.
My question is how can they prove that
it's active?
Because if you just have that thing on
your eyes,
you can't.
I,
I think the beat that ticket.
But
uh,
I think it sends a message.
Yeah.
The cops don't like technology.
Well,
they liked the technology they have.
It's also the other messages.
They like writing tickets.
Oh yeah.
They want to write as many as they can
and they have to fill quotas.
Feeling quote as one of the most
disgusting things anybody ever got away
with the idea that there has to be a
certain amount of crimes that are
committed in a month.
Like what if everybody agreed to only go
the speed limit for like a year.
What would happen with the police
officers just explode?
I mean,
what would they do if we all agreed that
that would be an interesting project and
some small town.
If you could get everybody to do it,
then nobody has any money that's coming
in from.
From speeding tickets.
What do they do?
Because they rely on it,
you know,
they rely on it for a source of income.
It's those couple of little towns on the
way to burning man.
That's,
that's most of their income is insane.
I mean,
look,
it's one thing if you want to tickets
someone because you want to give them an
incentive to slow down,
to make people safer.
That's one thing,
but as soon as you start developing like
you have a standard amount of money you
have to make every month from you just
saying that people never improve,
you're just saying that people will
never get better at following the law,
never get better at being safer and just
the fact that you bank on that you have
a quota that's disgusting,
but they were known speed traps and in
Texas you know that you wouldn't go
through this town because it was 15
miles an hour and 16 and get you a
ticket.
Connecticut's horrible.
As Connecticut.
Between Connecticut and Boston,
there's a lot of stretches where it's 55
fucking miles an hour and 56 and there
is nothing there.
It's just straight line and you just
want a gun it,
you want to get the New York between New
York and Boston's like three and a half
hours at 55 miles an hour.
We're just going cheese a scrape right
everywhere you looked.
Some asshole disguises a tree pointing a
radar Acha so stupid.
And now Jamie put up a picture just a
moment ago,
but now in,
uh,
in Colorado,
they're developing this new technology
to tell if someone's smoking pot and not
look at these things,
tell if someone's smoking pot enough
inside of a building for it,
the smell to leak outside.
So they've developed this instrument
that measures the amount of cannabis
smell in the air on the street and
they're going to start to give people
tickets for these things,
you know,
that'll help vaporizer sales.
Well this is in Colorado pot legal,
this is so fucking stupid.
Those are the 40 percent that didn't
vote for it.
It may be that or it may just be the
fact that people are just floating out
of control and just weeds blowing
everywhere.
Like,
you know,
like tumbleweed.
I like the smell of weed just wafting
through entire communities and people
are catching contact ties and they've
had enough.
But you're not used to be.
You'd put your pot in coffee and the
dogs couldn't smell it for now they've
trained the dogs to look for the coffee
as well.
I don't know if this is true,
but a friend of mine told me that,
oh,
what he's been doing is buying a bear
pis and wolf pis and sprinkling it
around his tire tires and in his trunk
because he says when the drug dog smells
it and they go crazy,
they forget about drugs.
Totally.
And they want to go attack,
tackle bear,
you know,
I don't know if the cops do.
I don't.
I don't know at this.
Probably is made up,
but it's a great story.
You wouldn't think it would be made up.
I mean,
dogs instinctively freak out and they
smell wolves.
Yeah.
And so a pete's coffee.
That seems to make sense.
That's.
Hmm.
I wonder if they can get in trouble for
like pasting wolf piss on your tires.
How do they prove that they have a wolf
piss knows.
Then they put it on and bring in the
wolf dog.
They have a wolf piss detecting device
just like they have a cannabis smell
detecting device,
but there's some,
some sense that a dog can't resist that.
You know the one cent that supposedly
universally applies to all animals that
brings in here brings an lps and Moose
beavers piss.
Really?
Yeah.
Beaver smell or beaver,
beaver,
estrogen,
whatever it is.
Beaver sent.
I know a lot of young men to go after.
Exactly.
Which is interesting that term be
because they don't look like,
look,
if you're a woman's vagina,
looks like a beaver.
Take her to a doctor.
Something wrong.
It's not supposed to look like that.
So if you call into the beaver,
why are you calling it a beaver?
Because somebody else did before because
it's.
Well then the other idea is that it was
created back when they were really
hairy,
mean we don't know about the Internet
for porn before an Internet porn.
Yeah.
Porn in the Internet.
I think porn got women to trim it down a
little bit and the imminent,
the Internet came along and it was just,
it was just fire through bushes,
just the cube.
But apparently the scent from the glands
of Beavers is,
uh,
the best sexual attractant for other
animals.
Never go figure.
Yeah.
I don't know what that's about.
I mean,
who thought that the beavers were the
studs of the animal world?
There's certainly a weird fucking
animal,
meaning if you see one in real life.
Oh yeah.
You know,
and you see their crazy houses that they
built next to the lakes were these
giants in little lake in a canoe and
paddle out there and there was a big
beaver dam there.
You could watch them.
Then they were busy as beavers.
Busy as beavers.
Otters around there.
And people eat them,
delete them.
Apparently they own tastes bad.
I don't know.
I guess when people are starving to
death,
you know,
I watch a lot of those,
uh,
Alaska shows where people live in Alaska
and eat whatever they can get ahold of
them.
A lot of people eat beaver up there.
They eat beaver tails that cook the
beavertail.
That sounds like it'd be pretty tough.
Cld eat a lot of seal.
Marinade it.
Yeah.
Seal and beaver and you know,
gotta what you got to eat,
whatever the hell you can get ahold of
up there.
Probably.
If you didn't know what it was,
you'd say,
Hey,
this is kind of interesting.
It can't be picky,
they just need a source of calories and
protein.
Protein.
Yeah,
that's right there.
Take it.
You know,
and apparently seal oil is very
important for them because it's very
high in calories and the cold you deal
with apparently that's one of the best.
The worst losses of caloric or of
calories is your body burning off
calories to keep itself warm.
It's like one of the best they say to
lose weight is to actually to walk
around with like less jacket or less
coats.
Then you would feel comfortable with
because your body in order to keep warm
is actually burning off and on.
That's interesting.
So are you going to go hunting in
Alaska?
No,
I'm going in Wisconsin.
I'm going,
I said this weekend.
Oh Wow.
Yeah.
I would go in Alaska too though.
What are you going to after dear?
Huh?
Yeah.
There's a guy who's got a farm.
It's overrun with deer and he brings in
people to hunt them,
to manage them every year because the,
you know,
the reality is,
as you said,
especially in Wisconsin,
a lot of them are going to die by
predators.
A lot of them are going to get hit by
cars.
A lot of them are going to freeze to
death and you,
in order to keep the herd healthy
managed,
you gotta you gotta finish and you've
got to be the wolf and I want to.
I want to try to live this entire year.
I want to.
I want to pick a time like after the
first of the year and tried to live the
entire year on game meat.
I think it's possible.
I think if you're going to be a meat
eater,
you know,
to know the exact source of your meat.
I think it's probably the best,
most ethical and sort of sane way to do
it.
The disconnect between us and our food,
whether they're like,
I love growing food in a garden and then
cooking and eating the vegetables that
you grow.
I mean,
I think it's a beautiful thing.
It's,
it's an interesting connection that you
have between where your food actually
comes from.
I have chickens now and I get,
I get fresh eggs from the chickens and
I'm trying to get closer and closer to
my food,
if that makes any sense.
Well,
we mainly organic or almost all organic,
but mainly vegetables.
We eat chicken maybe twice a month and
we have a friend that slaughters his,
uh,
his pig once a year and we know how it's
grown and raised and everything.
But uh,
mainly vegetarians,
but it,
all our food,
most of it comes within a 25 to 40 miles
of our house,
you know,
that's.
We belong to a CSA community supported
agriculture and,
and I do most of the cooking and so it's
really fun.
You get this box each week and then you
got to figure out what you're going to
do with stuff and that's really cool.
That's a lot of fun.
I would love that.
I think I've talked to my friends about
that with everyone.
So God damn busy,
we'd never get anything done.
But the idea of getting together,
everybody buying in on a plot of land
and then hiring someone to run that plot
of land and produce food for this group
of people,
like say get 20 people together and say,
well this is our grocery bill for the
year.
If we can manage a plot of land and buy
a plot of land together,
everybody pay for one slash 20th of it
or whatever,
and then hire someone to take care of
everything and hire a few people.
I'd be some CSA is up here.
There must be,
you know,
there's several of them in San Diego
County and we belonged to to this one
for quite a few years now and they
supply most of the local organic stores
and so what we're getting are the
tomatoes that are other heirloom,
they're not perfect.
They're in.
We're getting food from a farm.
Like it'd become a.
not everything's the same size and shape
and all like that.
It's real.
It's real food is picked that day or
maybe the afternoon before and it's real
good fresh food,
but that way we don't have to get our
group together.
Now we're,
we've gotten a bunch of people involved
in this and some people don't like
pomegranates,
persimmons or whatever comes sometimes
in the basket and so we swapped around
with each other and stuff and uh,
so we usually eat everything,
so I get all the throwaways idea,
had a bit of doomsday to it.
My idea was like if the shit hits the
fan,
you're in the survival stuff and you
know,
you read all that too.
And when I was younger I was into that
too.
But now that I,
you know,
my dad,
my brother and my mentor all died at 63,
so I'm eight years past my expiration
dates.
So I feel like it's all free time.
I exercise,
I eat well,
but you know,
it's,
I'm not stressed about that.
I see the Google kids are working on
longevity,
uh,
things now.
And,
and I just commented a friend yesterday,
I said,
you ever noticed that all of this at
longevity work is done by people in
their thirties and forties,
but,
but I'm here seventies or eighties.
You say,
oh no,
I don't really need that.
I've had a lot of fun.
I want to have a little bit more fun,
but you know,
if you gave me,
you said here's a pill,
give you another 100 years.
I'd have to think long and hard about
that.
Really?
Yeah.
Oh yeah.
Because you would worry about
deterioration or no,
you're not having fun.
Well,
because,
uh,
there's a lot of pain and watching your
friends go through what they're going to
have to go through.
Everybody's going to go through love
affairs that are broken and tragedies
and stuff like that.
I just don't want to watch anymore that,
you know,
I,
I love affairs.
That's the big push over the edge.
No,
it's,
I'm thinking of my grandkids now.
Oh,
they're getting their hearts broken and
everything.
We were talking about the radio lab
thing earlier about the guy who went
through this horrible circumcision
process of becoming a runner.
Wouldn't want a son to go through it.
Yeah.
You don't want your kids to grow through
heartbreak.
My children who've already gone through
heartbreak now it's my grandkids and I
pour it and I told one of my
grandchildren.
I said,
you know,
if I'm not around when some young man
breaks your heart,
I will come back and haunt him.
She remembers that the guys,
why is it his fault?
He doesn't want to be around her
anymore.
Well,
see,
I'm,
I,
I have four,
five grandchildren,
four girls.
If it wasn't for that,
I'd have a little problem with women,
but I have a new sensitivity to women.
Well,
I have a very good sensitivity to women
too and I have three daughters,
but my point is that a lot of heartbreak
comes from the fact that people just
decide they don't want to be with you
anymore and it doesn't work out right.
And people think that when someone
leaves them,
that they're taking something away from
them,
they feel this deep sense of loss and
they're connected to the idea.
Part of growing as a person is realizing
you're going to be okay and here's where
mtma would be really cool if it was
legal.
Because when you and your partner gets
points say,
you know,
if it's bad for one person,
it's going to be bad for both of them.
Even if you're not talking about it,
so if you sat down,
got together one evening,
just the two of you did Mtma and talked
it out.
Now I know from personal experience
that,
you know,
my marriage with my previous marriage
was really getting rocky when I found
the MTMA and we stayed together another
six,
seven years.
That good?
Yeah.
It really worked out good.
Because,
because it died after that.
Well,
the kids were grown with.
A lot of things happened after that,
but.
But it did extend our marriage and
extended it and a really good way.
Oh,
that's great.
And we were married 21 years and we're,
we're good friends now who was a rocky
period for awhile,
but we've worked ourselves through that
to where,
you know,
we both respect each other and we
realized that it was not a one way
street.
But uh,
you know,
I think that Mbma would be great for
couples therapy of people,
uh,
when they hit that seven year mark or
whatever it is,
you know?
Yeah.
Well,
I think there's a lot of things that
people hold in depressing relationships
and don't communicate about,
and then sometimes the psychedelic
journey together can open those ideas up
and you start talking about things and
you find out that there's been a
misunderstanding all along or that it
could a bit of lack of communication
that you could have worked things out
much better,
much easier a long time ago or that
you're both feeling the same way.
They both want to move on,
you just don't know how to do it.
And you know,
I've had one experience where I went on
for months,
something was building up and finally
got it out and she said,
oh,
that's no big deal and it's something
that had been a big deal to me for a
long time.
And it turned out if I had just been
talking about it,
I would've had a month of bliss instead
of hell.
You know?
So communication is the key and there
are some things that help you
communicate.
Pot helps you communicate.
Yeah.
Don't you think that those things and
those heartaches and those,
that's part of what makes you a person.
It's information you have to get that
information.
It's feedback
now.
I wouldn't want to not have any of my
heartbreaks and stuff.
I just don't want.
I don't want to see it happen to
somebody.
I understand and I agree to a certain
extent,
but I think it's very important that
everybody goes through a certain amount
of it just to understand what it's
about,
but you don't have a choice.
You're going to look.
I've had friends that have gone through
it where I know they.
They became better people because of it.
Yeah.
A friend who went through a devastating
breakup and now he laughs about the idea
of being stuck with that woman.
You know?
Back then he thought there was no way
you could live without her,
and I was like,
yeah,
it doesn't.
Yeah.
No matter what happens to you,
how big the tragedy is that after some
time passes,
eventually that becomes one of your
funniest stories.
Oh,
I doubt it.
no.
Right.
Some of these things that were did was
eaten by a wolf on talk,
now that I'm thinking about,
fucking saw your family die in a plane
crash.
I'm thinking of things happened to me.
Fucking crazy.
If you think about some things that
happened,
seemed to be a tragedy at the time and
usually between people carve brands just
talking about like breakups.
I'm talking about like getting fired.
I'm talking about things that are not
really devastated.
Getting fired is a good thing.
I've had that happen sometimes that that
can turn into a good thing.
It can be a changing experience and
change I think oftentimes opens up the
door for good.
Yeah.
You know,
change opened up the door for good
because it gives you a new found focus.
You know,
if you survive it,
you're going to be stronger.
Yeah.
Every time I've like had something
happened to me where I had to rethink
things,
that's always been a good thing.
Oh yeah,
and when you get fired,
you all right,
what are we doing here?
And you all of a sudden you get this new
motor.
I realized subjectively this would be a
good thing for grandkids
when it happens to him.
I just don't want to go through.
That's part of being a GRANDPA.
I mean,
isn't that what they always say that the
strictest parents were always like the
most lenient grandparents?
I wasn't a strict parenthood.
Even more so than even more lenient,
but yeah,
the idea,
especially when you're an older person
and you've experienced so much pain and
hardship and you see the innocence of
children whose how beautiful it is,
they don't know any racism yet.
They don't know any homophobia yet.
They don't know any blind objective
hate.
They don't know they.
They don't know the disillusion of
government.
They don't know all this.
Right?
They don't know any of this yet.
They don't know like they don't read
the,
the rebellion against taxing and it's
like all the different aspects of
society that,
you know,
bring people to this hysterical freakout
point where you're like,
this fucking thing is I'm mad as hell.
I'm not going to take it anymore.
I'm like,
I love that.
Yeah.
They don't have that.
They have,
you know,
you stepped on my toe,
they have,
that's my toy,
you know,
relatively speaking,
these are big problems for them to all
the little kid problems that we just
have to learn how to work our way
through.
And my three year old has a way bigger
problem with my five year old taking one
of her toys than I have with anything in
life.
My five-year-old takes her toy and she,
she screams tiers are flying out of her
face.
That never happens to me.
So for her,
that's a devastating apocalypse.
A huge groups of toys.
Yeah,
it really is.
It's relative,
relatively speaking,
and you have to address it that way.
You have to sort of respect the fact
that they actually are freaking out and
although it doesn't seem normal to you,
you are grown adults.
Right?
But for a three year old this you've to
that this is a real serious thing for
them,
you know?
And so you got to treat them like
adults.
My parents didn't shut up,
you know,
that's how I grew up.
Shut up.
Shut your mouth.
I'll break both your legs.
That's the type of shit I heard.
I was.
I was really lucky.
I grew up liking an ozzie and Harriet
family.
It was,
it was my problem.
Yeah.
But I couldn't have asked for better
parents and we were looking at it.
Turned out ecstasy dealer.
Dallas drug dealer sends him to college.
He deals well hosting a drug podcast.
Guys.
Crazy.
What is this book that you wrote?
The spirit of the Internet.
Uh,
that's,
uh,
I wrote that in 2000 actually.
It's one of the first books that
compares the Internet to a psychedelic
drug speculations on the evolution of
growth.
Global consciousness.
Yeah.
Wow.
Look at you.
You fresh faced little.
Yeah.
That's a long time ago.
That's 2000 when you wrote this in 2000,
13 years ago.
I.
That was the last nonfiction I wrote.
I've got a fiction book up now.
That's a first of a quartet I'm writing.
But uh,
uh,
I went to fiction because it's so much
more fun.
Do you remember sort of Graham Hancock?
Did you,
do you remember when people thought that
the world was gonna end in 2000?
Oh yeah.
Y Two k,
well that was a big deal,
man.
See I got involved in y two K in about
1995 because we,
we've
set aside millions of dollars to fix all
those problems and most of the software
industry did.
I mean there was a huge thing and the
press only picked up on in the last nine
months or something and we'd already
spent millions of dollars and years and
years of work.
There's specialized companies working on
it and so I really didn't think anything
bad was gonna happen.
I wouldn't want to be somewhere on an
airplane right then because there were a
few glitches.
Well,
I didn't know.
I didn't think the airplane would crash.
I thought I could get stranded somewhere
and they couldn't get my reservations.
Oh right.
I wouldn't worry about the plane itself.
That was a fear though.
Like air traffic controllers that their,
their computer systems,
we're going to go down.
There was a potential for that,
but it was nothing like the press made.
What the fuck did they do for air
traffic controllers before there were
computers,
eyeball,
I guess radio and I will look in the 19
sixties.
What?
How did they describe by cow?
I guess it was like a coming in at
30,000
feet.
Twenty five degrees north.
I got to talk them down.
I don't know.
I'm a commercial pilot.
Vital I've got.
Are you really?
But it's restricted to hot air balloons,
commercial commercial pilot and it says
restricted to lighter than air aircraft.
Lighter than air.
And I,
I don't have a balloon anymore,
but I used to fly balloons.
Yeah.
Whoa,
that's got to be spooky.
Oh,
they're great fun.
Like you in a basket near space.
It's just awesome because now it gets
loud when you burn,
but then when you're not burning you're
just floating.
It's quiet and you could hear the sound,
you know,
there's no obstruction.
So you can hear people talking on the
ground.
And in Dallas there's this one track
that we had taken Sunday morning because
there was a woman who would lay out in
her backyard but naked.
Yeah.
So we would come in,
we'd burn.
And then we'd,
we'd come up high so that we coast down
in low and come over the lake and just.
And then we'd say good morning,
she jumped in.
How rude.
Yeah,
it was a,
you could hear everything in Texas cars
you'd fly or and Sunday morning and see
pickup trucks with people passed out in
the back of them and stuff.
Wow.
With yell at them.
How dangerous is it though?
It seems like it's pretty dangerous.
The reason I quit is because I wasn't
paying close enough attention.
I almost hit a power line and it scared
me so much.
I was flying people for money and stuff,
you know,
at the time.
Oh my God.
I got wrapped up in the conversation
these guys are having,
that's my problem in paying attention to
them more than the flying.
And they didn't know.
We had a close call.
I knew we had close calls.
How close?
Not that close.
Close enough.
I,
I was coming down and I didn't burn soon
enough.
And so it takes a while to get your
momentum backup and uh,
you know,
I cleared it by 50 feet.
But you know,
I should have cleared it by 500 feet or
something.
Like,
no,
I was coming in for a landing,
I guess.
Anyhow,
it scared the hell out of me.
And I said,
you know,
that's it.
How many people had died hitting power
lines?
So that's mainly,
it was just happened to people in
balloons.
Not,
not,
not all that many compared to the number
of people flying,
you know,
it's safer than regular aircraft or you
harnessed in when you're up there.
Oh No.
Oh Jesus.
I used to sit on the edge of the basket,
you know,
and burn.
Really?
Oh yeah.
Fucking a man.
What if a crazy rebel wind came along
and knocked you off?
Well,
you wouldn't have launched.
If it's over 10 miles an hour,
you wouldn't launch.
We have a lot of trouble for her.
Look so spooky.
We'd curling my toes.
Just sitting there looking at that
video.
We'd go to these airshows where they
bring in biplanes and stuff like that.
And for the balloons,
they would put up a pole in the middle
of the airfield with the keys to a
cadillac or something on it and you had
to go five miles away,
anywhere in the radius of five miles
away and launch and whoever could grab
the keys,
got the balloon.
Wow.
What if they collide into each other?
You kind of bounce off.
But if you're at the same altitude at
least,
but you the rules the road so you're not
supposed to do that.
But nobody in things I ever flew in ever
got the keys.
But you have a beanbag too,
so you throw that in.
Whoever got closest would win money or
something like that.
But wow,
it's great fun.
You know that my,
my ex wife took me on a balloon ride for
my 40th birthday.
And on the way back I said,
well,
how much do these things cost?
How did he get started in the next
morning?
I was taking lessons.
I had a lot of money.
Then.
How much does it cost to get a balloon?
A balloon is about $35,000.
It wasn't back when I bought it.
Yeah.
And how do you fold that bitch up once
you've done flying or they pack into a
basket that's a.
Oh maybe a third of the size of this
table.
Wow.
And,
but then you have your basket too.
So you have a trailer behind your.
Do you have a parachute up?
There ain't shit hits the fan will know
nothing.
No dude,
I had balls.
I had one guy wanted to pay me to take
them up in a parachute,
but he wanted to jump out,
but I didn't want to do it because once
a,
once a guy jumps out,
you get so much lighter and if you're
not careful,
you shoot up too fast.
You collapse the envelope.
That doesn't happen very often,
but they're really safe.
Really safe.
There are a lot of fun and wow,
that sounds scary.
That you lower yourself.
Do you have to lower it?
Naturally the.
There's a hole in the top and you have a
line that goes through it and a rope.
Pull it and bleed air out of the top and
let it go.
And then when you're,
when you're actually landing,
the top is held in by Velcro and so
except for the little flap that's open
and when you're just very land,
you rip that called pull the top out,
you pull the top out and then it will
deflate and land down.
Sometimes your landings are a little
rough.
You know,
I've had landings are dragged for 50
years.
One hundred yards were bounced up and
down.
You know that the conditions sometimes
make it tough.
And in,
in North Texas at the time you had to be
really,
you know,
you can,
you're allowed to land anywhere when
you're landing,
you know,
the Faa let you because you,
if you,
if you out of fuel.
And there was this one farm up in north
Texas up by Cisco I think it was.
And,
and whenever the balloons would come and
landing,
you can see dust coming on these gravel
roads from two directions.
One would be this farmer with his pickup
and his shotgun and the other,
it'd be the sheriff to come to protect
you because the farmer,
hey,
did you landing on their lawn when
ballooning started?
In France,
they would carry a bottle of champagne
to give to the farmer when they landed
as,
hey,
thank you for letting us land here.
Here's the champagne.
When ballooning started in the United
States,
the balloon has never gave it to the
landowners.
They drank it themselves,
you know,
champagne and propane.
Breakfast.
The balloon is how rude.
That's why they ruined the whole thing.
Look at this.
That looks like Albuquerque.
Yeah.
There's one in Colorado too,
and Colorado Springs.
We went to.
The woman that taught me the balloon,
moved to Colorado Springs to.
Yeah,
we went there to see it,
but there was bad weather so they'd
never launched it.
So you got to do it,
you know,
at sunrise and sunset the a couple of
hours until after sunrise and a couple
hours for sunset.
That's the only time that the air is
stable enough.
Have you ever met anybody that was up in
a balloon and saw a Ufo?
No.
I mean it's too early in the day or plus
you're looking at other things.
How convenient.
But what most people like to do on their
first balloon ride is picked leaves from
the top of a tree.
Wow.
For some reason that's a big thrill,
you know.
So we'd go and skim the trees and they
can pick leaves.
Wow.
That's Weird Grief Fund.
It's weird that we figured out how to
float float around in the sky.
Yeah.
You know,
it's just a matter of time before we
figured out how to do it with suits.
Some jet packs are coming around pretty
good and well they've got guys that have
those wings suits that jump off cliffs.
Psychopaths some nuts.
Oh,
I can hardly watched those videos for me
to watch.
And there's one word,
guy crashes.
It's really hard to watch that one I
haven't seen,
but it's just a matter of time before
they figure out something with like a
wing wings on that technology is going
to grow.
I think everything's going to grow,
you know?
I mean if they have a jet pack now and
they.
Do,
you know,
I watched one when I was in Denver.
There was my friend willy has a Klg.
What is it?
Kale,
PJ Klp,
j,
the radio station had a guy come in
that's a,
a,
a that had a jet pack guy come in and he
launched a jet pack in the parking lot
and flew through the air for like 10
seconds.
You can only do it for like 10 seconds
and it was like within x amount of years
are going to be able to do five minutes
and then,
you know,
x amount of years after that they think
they're going to figure out some sort of
power source that's going to be able to
make it a viable mode of transportation.
But it was very complicated as far as
like the controlling the yard and what
is it called?
There's like to pitch,
pitch and Yaw.
Yeah.
Apparently it's like it's not a simple
thing to figure out how to do.
We didn't have to learn that to get a
license for balloons because you know,
just up and down and he had literally
have to learn whether cloud's a.
You had learned about procedures with
the FAA because you have to call the FAA
in the morning,
get a weather report and all.
And you tell them where you're going to
launch and so they'd know some balloons
are going to be in the area.
How much different is that than a blimp?
Can you,
can you target a blimp?
I've never been in a blimp.
But pilot one with your license.
Oh No,
no.
It's lighter than air.
Well maybe.
I don't know anybody crazy enough to let
me do it.
But I guess I guess that would be legal.
It's lighter than aircraft.
Yeah.
Do you have to renew that license or is
that once you get it,
you got it.
That's the crazy thing.
You,
you don't ever have to renew it,
but you have to have a check flight
every year I think with somebody else
who's a commercial pilot.
So all you have to do is get a friend,
go out and take a ride with you in your
current.
Again,
I'm not current.
What was that?
When you just put up Jamie got an
address that flies and lady Gaga the
actual lady Gaga,
like remote controlled.
And uh oh.
So is it lady Gaga or is it a toy?
That's lady Gaga.
Lady Gaga is in a jet pack.
Okay,
here she is.
She's got a helmet on.
Let me see this.
Well,
this is.
We just want us after it's over.
So she climbs into this fucking thing
and flies around.
I didn't think jetpacks could be
annoying.
Book is Lady Gaga and Jetpack Yeomans.
We ruin everything.
This is so stupid.
She's connected by wires.
Shut this off.
This is a fucking charade.
Sunday really?
A jetpack.
She's all wired up and everything like
that.
It's more like a little helicopter.
Yeah,
that's horse shit.
That's what that is.
It's wired.
But you know there have been guys go
into the stadium football stadiums and
those jet packs.
Yeah.
Well there's that one guy that landed,
he was in the middle of a boxing match.
Evander Holyfield was fighting Riddick
bowe and the guy landed.
He had like a parachute connected to
fans and he called himself like the fan.
I remember that.
And they landed in delayed the fight for
like a half an hour while they had to
arrest this guy bringing police and they
beat the guy up and everything like
that.
And then it sort of changed the,
uh,
the atmosphere of the fight because
there was a big break and blow the
fight.
Anybody cool off and then had to go at
it again.
But that was,
I saw on,
I used to walk on the bluffs down by del
Mar,
which are maybe 30 feet or something.
And one day a guy came by and one of
those,
he's a parachute,
had a big fan on the back and,
and he was at eye level with me and he
said,
hello,
hello.
And he's moving very slowly.
Yeah.
This is the video riddick bowe and
evander holyfield fight and look,
they stop and they're like,
what the hell?
And they're looking at is boom.
The guy lands ringside in the crowd.
They should've turned hola holyfield
onto them.
Let them while they were in the middle
of,
he has other more important things to
do.
They just beat the shit out of this guy
though.
I can see why you think that guys
probably still in jail or I'm surprised
they didn't just reschedule the fight.
That's not really fair to do that as
well.
I think people wanted to conclusion
yeah,
it was all going on and all the money
there in all the money on paper view as
well.
Poor fighters.
So yeah.
You know what,
they should have just started it up
immediately.
Shouldn't have waited a half an hour to
give it a little five minute break,
cut the cords,
just,
let's do this.
But as I think it was a quite a,
quite a break while they arrested this
dummy,
she needed pitch.
That's it.
That's an example of a needy bitch.
So they should have those fights
indoors.
Yeah,
I think they probably mostly do.
I very rarely hear about fights out.
Do I know they do a few occasionally
outside and Vegas is a big one,
uh,
way back in Africa or something.
I can't remember.
The two Moitai ones they do do more
time.
Ones in Vegas outside.
Well didn't get quite
as loud I think.
Yeah.
But it's also your,
you're,
the environment is different.
You're dealing with outside rain and
weird.
You know,
I went to a,
um,
a king of the cage.
Used to have these fights outside.
I went to a couple of them,
they used to have them in an Indian
casino in California back when mixed
martial arts was illegal in California,
so they would hold them in this outside
casino and one time they uh,
it started raining,
it was pouring rain out and instead they
decided to let the fights continue in
the pouring rain.
So these people are fighting,
they're slipping,
they try to throw kicks that fallen on
their ass and people are climbing on top
of that.
They're soaking wet.
It was the craziest and they released it
as a DVD,
I think it's called King of the cage,
wet and wild,
but it's a really insane series of
fights where people were trying to fight
in a torrential
rainstorm.
People just,
just so nutty.
Did you ever hear of an old long time
ago wrestler name Gorgeous George?
Yes,
sure.
I saw a gorgeous George Wrestle.
My Dad took me to see them in the Elgin
Highschool Gymnasium and the big deal,
he had long hair.
Well,
it was maybe almost down to his
shoulders,
but not quite,
but at that time I was huge in his.
When he come out in the ring,
in the beginning,
he,
his hair would be up and he'd take bobby
pins out of his hair and throw them out
to the audience.
I was so disappointed.
I didn't catch you on.
That's so funny.
Gorgeous.
George's George,
what's another thing that people would
come if they came here from another
planet?
The biggest.
What the fuck is going on?
Those guys are really hitting each other
like,
why are you watching?
That was fun.
We had to find out who's gonna win,
who's the champion of the world
this week.
Yeah.
We were strange for strange floating
around and balloons pretending to hit
each other.
Not Erase.
Listen,
man.
It's been a lot of fun.
It's been great.
Fun is enough.
Really glad to get to meet you.
I don't think you realize what you're
doing,
but you are.
You're filling in a role here for a lot
of young people that you know.
You don't know how smart you are.
Maybe you do,
but you're.
You're extremely well read.
You know so much your time at Graham
Hancock about stuff.
I read the headlines and you know,
all these terms about the skull and
stuff like that,
but what you're doing is you're taking a
really,
uh,
a high level intellectual product to the
masses into especially young people that
maybe hadn't had the advantage.
You go to college or something and they
find out,
hey,
they're as smart as anybody that went to
college and you're really doing a really
good service with these products.
Well thank you.
But I'm not trying and I'm working.
That's why it's working.
I'm extremely uneducated.
You're very well read.
Well,
I read a lot of things but you know,
I mean what is education?
They are not reading but as far as like
formal education and it is also as far
as like,
I don't know,
I just liked what I like.
I'm interested in certain things and I
find that there's a lot of things out
there that are fascinating that people
just aren't paying attention to.
And I think what would I see in what we
talk about on the podcast is really
reflected by what I see on and when I
see on the Internet,
when I see,
when I go to the various websites that I
visit for information,
I see just a massive new upsurge and
curiosity.
I think the people were way more curious
than they ever have been before,
just by virtue of the fact they're
getting more information than they've
ever done.
They can get it,
you know,
they're not being held back.
So I think what this podcast is,
we came along in the right place at the
right time and it was the right type of
person in me that kind of can bridge a
few different worlds.
Exactly that,
that's what you're bridging quite a few
different worlds.
And that's really important in the
potheads exactly.
When the bridge between the meat heads
and the beds were not all that
different,
you know,
we might look different,
but there's,
there's prejudice against people who
engage in martial arts and exercise just
like this prejudice against people smoke
pot.
And some of it's justified.
And some of it's not.
Yeah,
there's assholes in every.
Absolutely.
It's so easy to define people because of
that,
you know,
and I think that,
uh,
in conversations like this and podcasts
and it kind of gives everybody a better
sense.
We're getting into people's heads
because you're writing their ears,
you know,
they got the earphones on,
they're listening is theater of the
mind,
you know,
and uh,
it's,
uh,
the old voice in the back of the mind
that you hear that,
you know,
I've heard so many of your podcasts
that,
you know,
I feel like I've known you all my life.
I feel I've known you a long time to.
I've listened to you on many road trips,
give the introductions to all these
different various psychedelic talks.
How many episodes do you have?
Uh,
I just last night did three 78.
Wow.
You are on episode four.
Nineteen.
You almost ran for 20.
We were going to do a special for 20
episode,
but now I'm like,
what?
That's so stupid.
I'm so tired of that hole.
For 20 thing.
It's just like,
what?
This is a number,
the podcasts or the pot,
I mean we,
and I'm kind of hypocritical because we
always like make a big deal of it each
100 that we hit,
but for 20 to seem stupid it seems like
a tired thing for Tony.
Like come on,
I'm thinking about for 400 what I've
been working on it.
It's not too far along yet,
but I've,
I've cut out little sound of Mckenna,
you know,
30 to 62nd soundbites and I have about
100 of them from a 100 different talks
he gave and I'm going to try to spring
string them together and cut up and try
to make it a single cohesive type thing.
Hasn't been working too well yet,
but uh,
it's worth a try and he has one of the
cool things that you do do that's kind
of scary and dangerous and sacrilegious.
You Edit Mckenna speeches.
Get a lot of grief.
A fucking freak.
And why'd you cut out the stuff about
the stoned ape theory?
Well,
because it's the 80th time.
You heard it.
You know,
I'm not a historian.
My job is to get the carnival barker and
all of the masters copies are going to
Arrow,
would have all the masters and then the
real master tapes and all are going to
go back to offend Mckenna.
Beautiful.
So that's awesome.
Yeah,
they're out there now.
They're out there.
You can get a hold of them.
Now.
I've got about another hundred Mckenna
talks.
Nobody's heard yet.
Including me.
Hundred.
Yeah.
Oh my God.
Wow.
So I'm.
I'm good for another year or so.
And plus we were doing the plank and rj
talks at burning man that gets.
We had another 30 or 40 every year.
Wow.
You change your name because of burning
man.
Yeah.
Well that's when you know you get too
high when you change it.
My friend rob did that.
He used to be.
Chris became.
I've been working up to it and,
and my,
my sister in law who died had called me
Lorenzo all the time.
So it was a family name and,
and at burning man,
this damn parrot crime's up on my arm.
And I said,
what's that Paris name?
He says,
Lorenzo.
And I said,
oh,
that's my name too.
And that was the day I changed it.
Wow,
that's hilarious.
That's really hard for my wife and
family.
But they finally got there.
Oh,
so the twitter is psychedelic Lozo l o z
o.
So a follow on twitter and the podcast
is the psychedelic salon is available
for free.
It's on itunes.
And can people donate if they want to?
Yeah,
that's how it's kept alive.
I can't afford it.
They just,
you know,
I've got a a donate button on the
psychedelic salon that us has a donate
button.
I'm putting us.us.us
yet calm net org or us and it all goes
to the same place and then I'm going to
put a bitcoin thing up there too.
Beautiful.
And they can go to Lorenzo haggerty.com
and it has links to a little 15 minute
video of my life.
And then the,
the MDM story in Dallas era and all the.
All the links are Lorenzo haggerty.com
outstanding.
And the book,
the spirit of the Internet is back when
he was Lawrence Lawrence.
I'm looking for,
Lorenzo is the spirit of the Internet by
Lawrence Haggerty.
Genesis generation is my novel.
It's just out.
Beautiful all on on kindle.
Thank you sir.
I appreciate it.
It's been an honor to be an artist for
me as well.
It's really cool and I think both of our
audiences to cross a lot and so I'm glad
they both got to hear it.
Absolutely,
and I,
like I said,
I think that's how I heard about you in
the first place.
I'm pretty sure.
So I've got a lot of people in my
audience say the first time they heard
about me was from you,
so it goes around,
comes around,
and indeed it does.
Thank you sir.
You're welcome.