Don't right.
Yeah,
and we're alive.
You got to put dive,
put that thing down.
I want you to focus.
I want you to fuck cause I gotta get
into your head band.
I got to find out what you're about.
Your instagrams just at Joe Rogan,
right?
Yes.
Okay.
Did you post it
posted?
Go,
go.
Okay.
Turn that oversee.
Can't look at it as the key sign that I
wouldn't think that a guy like you'll be
easily distracted.
You can't be.
I'm like,
I'm just like on different things.
If I get on something I'm on it and then
it's like something else and my brain is
doing so many different things that at
one time,
how did you get to be the guy that makes
people shit their pants when they watch
your videos?
Because if you haven't seen any of his
videos,
stop,
pause podcasts for perspective.
Go look up James Kingston.
What is your youtube?
I just put James Kingston,
James Kingston will pop up and all forms
of social media,
right?
You got Instagram,
all that jazz,
and there's just ridiculous photos and
videos of you doing shit that people
watch with their friends and everybody
goes,
John Chase of Christ and they cringe.
And your asshole puckers out like this
one.
Where are you out here?
Uh,
climbing in the Ukraine with Mustang
wanted.
Is that the guy's name yet?
So as you,
you hooked up with the Russians,
you out rushing to Russians?
Yeah,
I didn't,
I wouldn't say out rushing to them,
but,
but that's what they do,
right?
That's the whole thing.
And he said,
I think only Russians can out Russian
Russians.
So he's climbing.
First of all,
how hard is it to get to this tower?
We're looking at this video and I am
fucking freaking out.
How high are you up here?
This one,
I think it was like just over 200
meters.
This is my staying.
Oh my God.
He's hanging by one hand.
This one is the second tallest building
in new crane.
Right?
Oh my God.
How do you go in the bottom and it's
like a shopping center.
And then they took me like through all
these little doors and then we took a
lift down into like the basement and
then we walked through the basement and
fight another lift.
And Oh my God,
he's standing on the edge here.
Who standing yet?
You must thing again.
Oh my keys out of his fucking mind.
Holy Fuck.
This video is hard to watch,
man.
So in these mosques and what your hair,
what,
what led you to this and how long have
you been doing this?
So I've done Porco for nine years.
You know what Parkour is?
Sure.
Jumping around,
all that fun stuff.
That classes for little kids now they
do.
Kids have pretty cool.
Yeah.
Break their arms at about four years
ago,
I got to a point where I was like
satisfied with what I was able to do.
Right.
But I was still like super scared of
heights,
so I was like,
okay,
I know that if I want to get over this
fear of fights,
I need to do it face my fear.
So is this your stuff?
Yeah.
So this is you running on trees and
stuff and the whole idea behind
[inaudible] is to use the world around
you.
Steps and fences and all kinds of crazy
shit and uh,
you know,
you're essentially performing acrobatics
with all this stuff.
Yeah,
just jumping around.
Yeah.
I think the now how do you do this and
not get hurt?
He's just practice a lot.
Like the whole idea isn't to go out and
just do crazy stuff and,
and risk your life.
You start slow,
you start with small jumps and then you
progress steadily and sensibly.
And then eventually you'll get to a
point where you can do things that make
most people feel a bit sick.
Well,
what did you start doing?
Did you take gymnastics and snowed or
something?
I was like a little fat kid when I was
younger.
Not Super Fat,
but unhealthy.
Just played computer games.
That was it.
How were you able to jump so far too?
That's another thing that freaks me out.
There's growing legs.
You know what?
I'm six foot three.
I can jump.
I know,
but there's a lot of people that are six
foot three.
They can't jump from one building to a
next.
Like I've seen some of the ridiculous
ones where you jump from the top of a
building to another building,
like on a very small ledge that you
landing on.
Yeah.
This practice,
you start with like the fuck do you
practice that?
You stopped with the jumping.
That's like four foot wide.
Right.
And then as you get,
but you do that hundreds and hundreds of
times until that becomes like nothing.
Right.
And then you'll realize that you can now
jump five feet and then blah blah blah
blah blah.
And I,
my peaks like 1111 and a half foot
standing jump and a half foot.
Yeah.
Wow.
Duty should be in the Olympics.
They are on another level.
How far can like a long jumper jump?
Eight feet,
20 feet,
something like that.
I think the record's probably 2122 with
the whole shit,
but still 11 feet in between buildings.
Now when you're jumping in one buildings
taller,
another building smaller,
it gives you more time to,
to travel,
right?
Yeah.
So like,
like when you're jumping,
I saw this one video of you were on,
you were on the ledge and you leapt
across from one building to another and
I'm like,
this has gotta be Photoshop.
This can't even be real.
The one that you post are,
yeah.
Yeah.
That one's in Cambridge.
That one's actually a small jump because
it's quite big height difference.
Massive impact because of the height.
Yeah.
And you've got alleged that's maybe like
a foot deep to land on and then there's
a scaffolding pole right in front of it,
dude,
that you kind of slam into.
You can see it in the video.
I slam into that pole,
Jesus.
But that,
that's all part of taking the impact to
you use your arms as well.
Yeah.
But that's,
it doesn't seem like something could
practice a lot.
Right.
Slamming into something that hard.
Those ones you can't practice a lot,
but no.
Yeah,
you figure it out.
You figure out how to take impact and
yeah.
So you started doing this about four
years ago,
right?
You started doing the height stuff,
started doing the climbing kind of scary
stuff.
And when did you start releasing videos
right away?
Um,
no I don't really,
I mean I'd,
I'd released one though.
This one.
Oh this one makes me shit my pants.
This is it.
That seems so far.
How far it's not that fun.
Like you could jump to the lower bit
there quite easily.
That's what other people have done
right.
Into a pole arc.
Yeah.
That is bananas,
Dude.
Yeah.
So how many,
how,
how much is the distance between those
two buildings?
Between those?
Probably like 10 foot,
12 foot maybe.
It does not seem like it,
but didn't do it.
Cause it's because there's a big drop as
well.
It's more about judging it correctly and
not jumping too far and not jumping too
little.
Right?
Yeah,
I see it like 12 foot,
I think.
Run that one more time Jeremy.
I just want to see this one more time
cause this freaks me out every time I
see it.
Every time I see it I'm like,
he's gonna die for sure.
There's no way you can make it.
So you kind of like lean forward and
then swing your arms and then push off
of it.
So you're,
you're like a standard.
Yeah.
Jump cause you're already committing to
the jump as you like.
Yeah.
You could see it in your momentum like
your head,
cause you have a Gopro on his above.
It's past the center line of like that,
that beam that you're standing on and
you're going out there,
what's it called?
And that's it.
Oh that's the idea.
Like you train,
you train enough so that when you're
stood on the edge looking at something
like you have no doubt,
you can't afford to have any doubt.
If I doubted myself there and I commit
to it and Eileen and then I back out,
I'm dead.
I had him go crazy dream last night man.
That I'm just remembering.
Yeah.
I had a crazy dream that I was climbing
with Alex honnold.
Yeah,
no Alex.
Alex has been on the podcast before and
uh,
every now and then I'll think about how
crazy he is about how crazy what he does
is,
but how like mellow and she is about it,
you know,
like,
you know when he's describing climbing,
he's like,
it's really actually kind of mellow.
It's like if anything is like,
if you're really scared,
so he's gone horribly wrong and it's
really,
really bad.
It's exactly the same.
Yeah.
People think I'm like,
hello and Adrenalin jumping.
Yeah.
It says he fell,
but unless you just fine.
She pulls it out right there then.
There it is,
dude.
Fuck all that.
Is this Alex?
That's not hidden.
Don't think so.
No.
It looks like,
Oh my God.
I'm not into that.
Crazy.
That's too much trust in the backpack.
Everything I do is like interesting
that,
yeah,
not into that.
My friend Andy,
Andy Stump,
he does that wingsuit shit.
He's got with a world record and
wingsuit flying.
Yeah.
He's out of his fucking mind.
He just loves to do that.
He gets to the top cliffs of the world
and just throws his fucking body Hoff.
And it has like a squirrel suit,
like the close proximity stuff where
like we watched one the other day where
a guy slammed into a bridge.
Yeah.
He missed in it.
I've seen that.
Yeah.
The sound as Rod.
I don't know why.
Rough and expect it to be so loud.
Yeah.
The meat and those people on the bridge.
Oh yeah.
And his family were there.
That's not good.
Yeah.
Um,
do you worry about that when you're
doing these crazy jumps?
I don't know.
So I mean it's,
it's in my mind like if I make a
mistake,
that's it,
but I don't make mistakes.
That's,
that's what you got to be confident and
you've got to have confidence in what
you're doing.
Otherwise.
Like if you're,
if you're up there and you're scared,
right.
The chances of failing are so much
higher,
I think.
Yeah.
I think with anything,
I mean,
you have to be in the moment,
right.
Well prepared in the moment.
Yeah.
Um,
how much of what you're doing or is it
really you taking a chance and how much
of it is just you having a better
understanding of what your body is
capable of and the average person than
most people I should say,
not taking chances.
Maybe like 10%.
Wow.
That's interesting.
And that's,
that's only on me taking shots and
trusting structures.
Like maybe jumping to something that I,
I'm not able to check first.
Right.
But it doesn't happen often.
Every time I do it I'm like probably
shouldn't have done that.
It's really interesting.
Also the,
that you picking this up four years ago
is sort of like we are social media.
It's around the time where social media
really started to take off.
Yeah.
Maybe a couple of years before that it
did,
but like youtube videos of people doing
crazy shit really between like six and
seven years ago.
That's when it really,
is that right?
Am I saying that right?
Yeah.
Like 2000 tennis is a really started to
take off.
Yeah.
So you kind of caught,
you caught that wave and I didn't,
you know,
I didn't really get anywhere any kind of
good,
decent like following on youtube until
three,
four years ago.
That was it.
I released my first like crane climb
video that that blew up and went super
viral and that was,
that kicked everything off.
And then because of that video and now
the a TV show in the,
in the UK on channel full and then that
was everything just took off then.
Wow.
Now these Russian cats that you were
hanging out with in the Ukraine and we
climbed up on that tower,
there's a lot of those guys.
Like you seen a lot of videos?
Yeah.
Like what is it about Russians and
climbing on the,
what is it about these crazy kids and
why they're so nutty?
I don't know.
That's something I've been trying to
figure out.
Like I've,
I've only been to Ukraine,
I haven't been to Russia,
but there's not much,
like there's not much going on there,
you know,
there's not much to live for in Russia
or Ukraine.
I don't want to sound mean,
but I know what you're saying.
Yeah.
And that's so much cut.
Uh,
they're just familiar with death and
violence and stuff like that.
Like Mustang,
he goes out,
I don't know,
every week.
And it goes like organized fights,
just like street fights and just beats
the hell out of brandon people.
But that to me is like,
so he does those English boy,
those organized treat fights where they
like five guys take on five guys,
big groups.
I've seen those.
Yeah,
he's,
he does that.
And I was like,
what?
So he just does everything crazy.
Yeah.
Wow.
Whoa.
And he just,
does it offer the thrill?
Yeah,
I think so.
Damn.
What a weird way to live.
I know it's weird way to have your brain
wired.
It was such an interesting kind of
insight when I was there to people like
that.
So how do you make contact with these
guys?
Do you speak or Ukraine or whatever?
The speaker.
They're Russian.
What are they both usually,
what does it,
both Ukrainian.
Russian?
Yeah.
So it was organized for me to go meet
him for the TV show I did in the UK.
And that was a part of that show was me
going to Ukraine to meet somebody else
that did similar things.
And that was where I met him.
So they somehow or another got in
contact with him through his youtube
videos or something along those lines.
Wow.
In a strange world we live in now,
you know?
Yeah.
You can go to that place and risk your
life with a bunch of other crazy people.
Yes.
No,
that's cool,
I guess.
Yeah.
Now what has it been like for you to
become famous for being like this crazy
risk taker?
Um,
I wouldn't say I'm like super famous.
Already famous.
I know who you are.
I told my friends,
they're like,
oh,
that too.
It's crazy.
How many millions of hits to your videos
have fucking millions.
Bunch of million.
That's famous man.
That's what's called famous.
Right.
Unless it's one dude is watching it over
and over again.
That's just my mum,
my boy,
he's alive.
Oh,
that's cool.
I Dunno.
That's a bit weird.
Yeah.
You'll famous.
Yeah,
I guess it's the same as that,
but on a much smaller scale.
Yeah,
but you're famous for doing like risk
take.
I'm just framing payments for talking
shit.
Yeah.
It's easy to talk shit.
You just have to say funny things or be
ridiculous.
But you're famous for like literally
doing something that makes people shit
their pants when they look at a video of
it.
I look at videos of the stuff you do,
and I started Jamie,
I'll tell ya,
I started squeezing.
I'm like,
fuck.
And I go,
oh,
what the fuck is he doing?
I don't,
you know,
I don't have any desire to do what
you're doing.
That's why my dream about Alex,
about climbing with Alex,
like here's one.
Yeah,
this is the first one.
So this was the first big one I ever
released.
This video literally changed my life.
This is what we announced two,
2016 it's three years climbing over some
water.
It was this the first time you had done
something like this?
No.
So I'd done a couple other ones,
but this was the biggest and this was
like the first big one that I'd hung
off.
God Damn Dude.
No,
you,
you're in it.
It's funny cause I live like just next
to that,
which is really cool.
Oh Wow.
Dude,
if you fell that would not be good.
Not even into water.
It's just the water.
He'd survived.
Oops.
Oh you fuck,
you're out of your fucking mind man.
Well you dealing dude.
What were you thinking right now when
you're hanging above that water?
First of all your hand sweaty.
Not Hands.
My hands.
Never already.
My hands sweat when I'm not doing
anything,
but what?
I'm doing this stuff quite,
it's like who's stopping you right now?
Send my friend Simon is up there with me
and another friend Doug was there too.
What do you think Simon and Doug would
do if you fell?
Well,
they just hurry up real down and oh
Jesus,
you go in one handed
mother fucker dude.
Like what are you thinking?
Why you're doing this?
You know what?
Just like Alec Arnold said,
there's not much going on.
It's just me in that moment.
But there is,
you get a first time to eat breakfast,
right?
Yeah.
But thinking about what you're going to
eat for breakfast,
you know,
most of the time when you get to a
situation where you're about to do
something that you've never done before
and you kind of naturally,
your brain kind of hyped it up and makes
it seem a lot worse than what it
actually is.
And then you do it and you're like,
why the fuck was I scared of that?
That was exactly the same.
So it's like just scared of that because
if you fell you're fucking dead.
Yeah.
I mean that's not rocket science.
That's a thick pole you're hanging on
to.
I sound like a small poles,
like super easy.
Can you do a one arm chin up?
No,
I'm not.
I'm not like particular stone fatigue at
all.
Please work on that.
You should be able to do it when I'm
channel.
But if your like what?
Active limbs,
man,
it's not,
it's not easy to do one.
I'm Chins when you have this big,
but there's gotta be some crossfit guys
that can do it.
Yeah.
I feel like strength isn't in my jeans.
No.
Started out of it.
And that
you were hanging from your fucking,
how long did you hang for a,
I saw him three times.
Probably like 30 seconds each time.
It's hard to hang 30 seconds.
30 seconds is tough.
It's not when you like,
when you do that all the time we'll
stuff is swinging around and all that
stuff.
It's quite easy.
But most people overestimate the amount
of time that they can hang.
Yeah.
I uh,
we had this thing on fear factor where
people had to hold onto a bar that
hangover like a river and a girls beat
the guys.
Really?
Yeah.
Interesting.
Because girls don't weigh as much thing.
Yeah.
So the girls would be like 110 pounds
and they'd be able to hang on for a
couple of minutes.
Where's the guys at?
About a minute and a half.
There were all tromping off.
Yeah.
I weighed 200 pounds.
That's a lot of weight to carry around
in your hands.
Flat at the moment so that I don't know
how you could possibly allow yourself to
get fat when you're not jumping across
every,
I think every ounce is important.
Yeah.
Like backpackers lose weight so they
don't,
they don't have as much body weight
around.
I need to lose it.
I need to sort my life out and start
your life.
You're doing crazy shit.
So you,
um,
this is like what you do professionally
now,
right?
How does that work?
I'm like,
what is a normal,
a normal day.
Yeah.
Did you go out,
jump up and say,
you know,
the normal day I do a lot of work behind
the scenes.
Just like editing and emails and just
like boring stuff that people don't see
this trait of duties.
Exactly.
Yeah.
It has to be done,
but it just works the same as any other
online influence.
They're like,
you got a big following,
opportunities come your way.
And if you do something like that,
that's a bit different and a bit,
I guess crazy to most people.
Even cooler opportunities come in when
it that's,
that's it,
right?
You got Youtube money,
you've got like merchandise on my
website.
You've got sponsored videos and
sponsors.
That's it.
Really.
So you work directly with sponsors.
You have like an agent or a manager.
That's hilarious.
It's kid.
You're going places.
Yeah,
I smoking a big cigar.
Listen,
we're gonna have to take it to next
level.
Can you walk into your hands?
Can you walk in your hands on top of the
Russians?
The Russians are walking on their hands.
I can't beat the Russians,
man.
You can't go too crazy.
How many of them die a lot?
I think there's,
there's a few videos floating around of
people falling off cranes and shit,
but it's super like,
oh,
that's not nice to look at it.
Yeah.
Have you seen those videos?
I haven't seen any of these.
I want to see him.
Well,
the wingsuit guy flying to the bridge
the other day,
I thought I didn't want to see it,
but then I watched it six times in a row
and blacks out before he hits,
right?
Oh No.
Have you found that?
Oh yes.
Oh,
you see him bounce off the bridge and it
sounds like a car accident.
It's a bang sound like
the bang.
But it sounds like a car accident.
Yeah,
it's fucked up.
It's the screams afterwards that get me.
Yeah,
it's all bad.
Yeah.
All of it's bad that people going,
oh,
bone line.
But that is half of the reason why these
people were watching is the possibility
that that could happen.
Even though they don't want it to
happen.
That accentuates thrill.
It's a strange thing,
isn't it?
Because I hate watching and stuff like
that,
but there's something in me that's like,
I can't not click it.
How could you say you hate watching
stuff like that?
Because you do dare devil videos.
I mean,
I hate watching people die.
Yes.
Oh,
I understand that.
But do you like watching people live?
Do you like watching people take risks
and live or do you go,
oh Jesus,
I don't,
I don't really watch that much stuff.
So you just do it.
I just do stuff.
Yeah.
Interesting.
So do you look at like the competitors?
Like is there like a,
a bunch of you that are like pushing the
boundaries and you're like,
Huh,
Nah,
I literally have no interest in beating
other people or making something better
or more dangerous than other people.
I have no interest in that.
I'm doing it because I love it and I
love making videos and you just see
those guys that were walking on their
hands and they were doing flips and then
they were doing hoverboards on the edge
of this building.
Yeah.
That when I have a real problem as rough
because I've been on hover boards before
and sometimes you fall off,
sometimes they fuck up,
sometimes they stop working,
sometimes she goes wrong,
like you're trusting and some cheaply
made Chinese hunk of Shit.
Jesus.
Oh you fucks,
I can't.
Oh he's spinning around in circles.
Spinning bothers me so much.
And he's like literally like getting to
the edge and spinning around.
I mean inches from fucking certain death
and moving quite quickly by the way.
I mean,
I don't think it's that bad.
Like shut the fuck up.
Of course it's,
I've been in one of those and it's quite
easy.
Shut it off,
Jamie.
He's got his hands,
his hands,
dude,
he's standing on his hands on a fucking
hoverboard on a building on the top of
the world.
Fuck you.
He's crazy.
These people are crazy.
Look,
my hands are Russian.
Russian.
Yeah,
they're different folk,
right?
Yeah.
They're their own species.
There are definitely wild folk.
It's just the ability to do that,
and then,
and this new thing that we have now,
we can take videos of it and just upload
it instantly.
You don't have to have any sort of a
network or anything that approves it.
You put up your own thing and then boom,
all of a sudden you're like,
yeah,
you're a one man show.
That's like the most amazing thing about
youtube is it's like everybody has a job
on youtube.
Anybody can go on Youtube,
upload stuff,
get paid for it.
Right.
That's just,
it's just so cool.
And then if you make good stuff that's
inspiring people or people enjoy
[inaudible].
Yeah,
it's crazy.
So cool.
It's very strange,
right?
It's a completely new world that I don't
think that anybody anticipated that they
were going to have individual content
providers.
We're essentially going to be like their
own network.
Yeah.
Now how,
what kind of an obligation do you have
to the people that are,
that are watching your show?
Like how often do you post stuff?
Um,
I have no like set schedule.
I probably should,
I feel like I grow a lot more if I had
set that.
Like the more I upload,
the more I grow and that's just how it
works.
But like how often can you do that?
Common ground climb stuff every day,
you know,
it's not that.
Right.
So how,
how many days a week a good month in
terms of like video uploads would be
like three,
three or four videos.
One I was like good for me.
That's interesting.
Yeah,
because some people try to up hit,
I'm trying to do better but,
but it's hard though,
right?
It's just given the nature of what you
do.
And I live in the UK most of the time.
And the,
the weather there is just like,
yeah,
you can't be hanging when it's raining
out and it's always,
oh fuck that.
Oh,
you get up there and just do,
but your friends are there with the
camera.
You're like,
let's,
what was,
tell what off,
tell it off.
I've had a few Jewy situations.
Oh fuck.
Climate.
It's normal.
And then when you get to the top,
that's what it was like,
fuck.
Where did this witness come from?
Oh my God.
Why don't you put that sticky shit on
your hands?
Like football players use football,
American football.
Sticky Shit.
Like chalk or,
no,
it was like for cars like glue,
they spray glue in their hand,
stick them,
stick on his own.
What's called,
yeah,
yeah.
Spray some shit in your hands.
Make some sticky.
I'm like,
hmm.
Thinking to taking it to the next level
with the sticky.
Imagine if you're like hanging in,
you just kind of get off.
Stripper's use it to allegedly,
um,
some stuff that you could buy that uh,
you would,
uh,
put on.
I think they spray on their legs so they
could cling onto bars better and their
hololens.
Yeah.
Yeah,
it makes sense.
They also helps not getting like
calluses and stuff.
Ah,
that makes sense.
No,
that doesn't make sense.
Because you think like it would you want
it to be lubricated then?
I mean like,
um,
when they start to like get sore
blister,
if I use chalk,
I don't get that because they either rip
shock.
Oh yeah.
I use chalk.
I use truck for weightlifting and stuff
like that.
I sweat a lot though.
I'm really sweaty hands for whatever
reason.
I'm just a sweaty fuck.
So when I watch your videos,
I start sweating,
man.
I started freaking out to change your
clothes.
Yeah.
Like when I used to play pool,
I've always found it really hard to use
a pool cue that doesn't have a wrap on
it,
you know what I mean?
And like if it's just a,
um,
a piece of wood that had like a Polish
or a,
um,
a finish on it.
So what I would do is I would get that
stripper stuff and I'd put it on my
hands.
And then that way it allows you to like
gently hold onto the pool cue.
That sounds so dorky.
But uh,
this stuff unfortunately though gets on
your hands and then you could transfer
it to the balls and it makes the ball
stick to each other.
It's not good.
Not Good.
So that's my knowledge of a stripper.
Gooky stuff that you can have it on with
whatever it is,
but it's not stick them though.
It's probably something similar,
but there's also a product that I've
used called dry hands that it's like any
per sprint for your hands.
Yeah.
I found out about this cause I tried to
choke.
You seen that stuff?
No,
it's that,
it's just like,
it comes out like a Suntan lotion.
Ah.
And then it just rubs in and kind of
dries out and make some pretty sticky.
Ooh,
I haven't heard of that.
Liquid Chalk.
I bet.
At the same thing.
Yeah.
It's,
uh,
essentially somehow or another they've
figured out a way to stop you from
sweating if they spray some stuff on
you.
Like,
well,
that's what antiperspirant is.
That's a big thing that people like.
Right.
And they like to not sweat and their
underarms.
Disgusting.
Yeah.
Fuck man,
this,
I,
I really have a hard time just watching
these videos.
I can't imagine if this is like the
world that you've,
you know,
I mean this is the path you've chosen.
Your on your,
you know,
you're in one of the top guys in this
madness,
I guess.
Yeah.
You are not for me to say no,
but I'm,
I don't mean in terms of ranking,
I'm just saying that it's,
it's a crazy path to take with your
life.
What digital.
Yeah.
It's unusual.
Um,
but I've never been kind of,
I've never fit into like just the normal
world.
I hated school.
I ended up quitting school,
like fairly early.
No qualifications,
nothing.
And how old were you when you quit
school?
Uh,
I can't remember the ages,
but it was like,
what's,
what do you have hit you up high school
and then you have college.
College?
Yeah.
Um,
so high school I quit like two years
before the end.
I think I was like 13,
14.
Wow.
You'll like done.
So done.
Really.
Did your parents get mad?
Yeah.
He's like,
don't worry mom.
I I climbed trees and shit.
Yeah.
I put my mom through a lot of shit when
I was a kid.
I will do you now 26.
So you started off this stuff really
early.
So at 22 you're out there filming these
fucking crazy adventures.
Yeah.
What'd your parents think then?
Well,
when I started like I started a little
bit of filming,
just the park or stuff.
Maybe in like 2001,
it won't be in now what I was 17,
18 was what I think I first I first made
a video and it was me just jumping
between railings and,
and like small stuff,
you know,
safe stuff.
Moms like,
Oh that's nice.
And now I remember what I felt shut out,
that she was just like not the fuck.
I think she hit me by the back of the
head.
How old were you when you showed her the
video of you hanging from the crane?
What?
I released it three is it goes right
away.
Like when you look,
check this out mom.
I never show her.
She doesn't really know about things
until I,
until the,
the video is done and it's uploaded.
That's a good,
yeah.
So what did she say to you when she saw
that besides hitting,
you did have to sit down was he never
hits me.
It's usually just like,
I think she was just freaked out and
blown away.
Yeah.
But I don't know.
I can't remember.
It wasn't like encouraging words.
It was like,
what are you doing right while you're
doing this and do you remember what you
said?
Not really.
I,
I usually just say the same thing.
I enjoy it.
Just enjoy it.
That's it.
Now was there any legal repercussions to
doing something like that?
Have any,
has anybody ever gotten mad at you?
Uh,
yeah.
In the UK,
there's not really,
because it's trespass.
Right?
And there's no like criminal damage or
anything.
And Trespass in the UK isn't a criminal
offense.
It's a civil offense.
So I can only get in trouble for it if
the owner of the property for some
reason wants to take me to court,
I sweating like a pig over here thinking
of you hanging from that bar over that
water.
I'm fucking sweating.
My hands are sweating,
my feet are sweating.
I'm sorry I interrupted you.
But so it's just a civil offense.
Yeah.
And Uk,
it's just a civil offense.
And if they catch you,
what does that mean?
Like you have to pay a fine or
something.
Uh,
the people that catch me,
it's usually just the police.
Somebody sees me,
calls the police,
the police come and they say,
what you doing?
Try to kind of tell me off and then sent
me on my way.
Cause there's,
there's nothing they can do,
which is,
which is good for me.
What is this?
Jamie makes climbing a tower guard.
There's a guy up there,
right?
Yeah.
So this,
this is the tallest thing I've ever
climbed,
right.
We're in the middle of get up there and
there's a dude up there.
Yeah.
So I went up and then about 10 minutes
after I got to the top,
the crane starts powering up like,
like spinning and shit.
And I'm like,
what the Hell is going on?
Like somebody like got a remote for this
crane.
So I climbed back down from the,
it's like it's one of these,
right?
So there's a little kind of thing here.
And then that's the main arm.
Okay.
So I climbed down from the backside and
then he's in his little room doing this
crazy stuff.
And so you're still climbing even though
you know this thing's gonna move all.
I spoke to him and he said,
hey brother,
I had a little conversation and I was
like,
can I climb this crane?
And then I was like,
can you,
can you just like leave the crane still
lock it off for like 10 minutes while I
do it,
cause I've come all this way.
And what'd he say?
And he was like,
yes.
Okay.
Wow.
What a nice guy.
Yeah,
I know.
And this has been moved down.
The bottom does in Dubai.
This is in Dubai.
At the Marina.
Yeah.
It was really cool.
I love what happened.
Now when you're doing this and you're
climbing,
when you're worried about being
arrested,
cause if you get arrested in Dubai,
that's no joke.
Yeah.
So they say I don't,
I don't know.
Dubai.
Dubai's a funny one.
I felt like they've got,
I feel like they've got bigger fish to
fry and they're kind of dealing with
actual serious stuff.
This what,
what,
what happened when I got down,
I had to like sit with all the site
managers and everything for a few hours.
And the main guy,
like the site manager,
the main site manager said if they
phoned the police,
they'll all lose their jobs.
Okay.
So that's kind of how it works.
Oh,
okay.
So usually they beat the fuck out of you
and tell you don't come back.
They don't know and never,
no,
but I mean,
I'm joking,
but they can't be happy that you're
doing this right.
And it wasn't,
but they also work because it just blew
their minds.
Oh,
I see.
Every time it's the same.
They're like,
you shouldn't be doing this.
They tried to tell me off and then when,
when,
uh,
when it comes to me leaving they're
like,
can we take a picture with you every
time you're so high up here man.
How,
how high are up?
Your right,
it is 450 meters.
What in the fuck is,
yeah,
I'm just thinking of 450 feets
ridiculous.
450 meters.
That's,
that's insanity one over the water was
only 300 feet.
So this is like full times,
full time.
It would take you a long time to hit the
ground.
Yeah it would.
So while you're climbing up here,
what is going through your mind?
You're just being careful and watching
your stuff.
This one was like really greasy cause
I've been for that for two years.
I think the driver's head and it was
just coated in like grease and dust the
air and fuck.
It was like climbing,
climbing yet like somebody had just
smothered it in moderation.
Oh my God.
Just while I'm gone slow and I'm getting
my feet in the right place.
And so the feet part of slippery too.
Everything is like butter.
Yeah.
Christ,
James,
James.
So you get up to the top.
Please tell me,
don't hang from the top of this too,
but it was just too slippery.
Yeah.
Oh fuck you made a judgment call while
you're there.
Yeah.
This is such a mind.
Fuck.
Good Lord.
You're up by the way.
How awesome is Dubai credits?
I love it.
What a crazy.
A city that didn't exist just a few
decades ago.
So cool man.
It's one of my favorite places mainly
because you can do stuff like this.
Where do you do when you get up to the
top?
Do you just like put,
throw your hands up like I'm the king of
the world or do you have a jerk off up
there?
That'd be a feat.
It's a light up there in case a fucking
plane hits it.
It's how high you are.
The Oh,
trump.
It's hard to watch.
So,
um,
how many hours did it take you to do to
get up there or how long did it take
you?
Two hours.
But it was like,
so the beginning was I got there at like
three 30 in the morning and in Dubai
they start work at like three 30 or four
o'clock because it's cooler and that's
just like hundreds and hundreds of these
dudes stood outside the,
like the entrance to the site.
So I'm like,
how the hell am I going to get into this
place dark when this is all going on?
It was pitch black.
Yeah.
And I managed to find like a little
corner that I could sneak in and then
sneak over the fence and there's people
everywhere and I don't know how I
managed to get in without them seeing
me.
And then as soon as I dropped down,
I just dropped to the floor and they
crawled across the floor between like
these scaffolding bars and stuff like
that.
And then Tom Cruise mission impossible.
I've had some cool situations,
man,
some really fun stuff.
And then I get to the bottom of the
crane.
So the idea is I get to the crane,
I climb up like a bit of the crane and
then I get into the building.
That's the easiest way.
And usually because to climb the crane
for 450 meters is just like insane.
Especially in that heat is a killer.
And I had like just one of these one
bottle of wineries.
So you are your,
um,
so it takes you a couple of hours and
you're going through the building first.
So it took me a while to get up the
crane and then in,
cause I've got backpack and it's hot and
it's like dry and it's hard to breathe
and wow.
Yeah,
it was the wrong time of the year to do
it really.
And then I get in and then it's just
stares and stares and stares.
That's crazy.
You get here at three 30 and everybody's
just showing up for work too.
So they work three 30 until like early
morning and then they quit.
They seem to work nonstop.
Those guys,
I don't know how they do it.
It's not good.
And that probably paid like two bucks a
day or something.
Yeah.
There was a whole a vice special on it
about,
uh,
some of the more unscrupulous builders
out there.
But they do is they go to third world
countries.
They promise these people a certain
amount of money and then they bring them
over to the life.
Yeah.
Then they going to be able to send money
home and change their family's lives.
So they go there and take these jobs and
they take their passports away.
Yeah.
We give them a fraction of what they
were offered and then they live in
squalor through,
I think I've seen it.
They live like out in the middle of
nowhere and they will have these shared
showers and toilets and toilet.
It's like a hole in the ground.
It was awful.
Yeah.
Yeah,
yeah.
I mean that's a,
that's how you get up city built that
quick,
cheap.
Yeah.
It's scary is so,
uh,
but as uh,
as a completed entity as a thing,
it's pretty impressive.
Yeah.
Cause his truck,
you know,
as a city,
it's amazing.
Yeah.
This is one of the coolest cities I've
ever been.
They're just pushing it,
just pushing,
you know,
they just living it up all the time.
Have you seen the new big,
um,
what's it called?
Big,
but like the London eye,
that building a London eye in Dubai,
in the marina,
and it's like so much bigger.
What does the London eye,
you know that,
have you been to London?
Yes.
Big.
Oh,
the ferris wheel.
That's what it's called.
The London eye.
Yeah.
But the building a bigger one,
that voting not times,
like five or something ridiculous.
Yeah.
I've been on,
I've looked at it by that.
I haven't been on it.
Yeah.
The one in Seattle,
I want to go there.
I want to go that around Christmas when
it's cooler and see if I can get 690
foot high Dubai.
I will be the low world's largest ferris
wheel upon completion in 2015 it says
it's not finished,
those motherfuckers union.
So last time I saw it was just the do
need to get more and to kidnap more
people.
Yeah.
Get them to work.
That's,
uh,
that's when you get on a ferris wheel
now.
Like do you go to Disneyland and be
like,
what kind of bullshit is though?
Something like the last time I went to
Disney land was here and I went I two
years ago and yeah,
I was like,
you be like,
Ooh,
space mountain tower of terror on space
mountain was the best one.
It's pretty bad ass.
Yeah.
It's even better now cause there's,
it's like star wars themed.
Is it?
Yeah.
I don't know if it's permanently star
wars themed and be guardians of the
galaxy.
Oh,
they just closed it or about to Oh yeah,
they can net.
Yeah,
the ad graphics and stuff like that.
Yeah.
Spice it up a bit.
I liked dlt cups.
Yeah,
those are fun.
That fun.
Yeah.
But for a guy like you who experienced
is real life and death fears like that.
Disneyland.
Shit's gotta be boring as hell,
man.
Yeah.
It was pretty boring.
Pretty Boring.
But it's like something you've got to do
once in your life,
right?
I bawled like a little Mickey Mickey
Mouse and there's an adult version out
here.
You've got to go to six flags.
Six flags.
Yeah.
What's the one that's opposite?
California is something that's right
next to Disneyland.
Oh,
California adventure.
Yeah,
that's true.
Yeah.
That's really good.
I felt like the rides were better.
Well,
it's more,
they're more adult oriented,
but they have a bunch of kids rides
there too.
Yeah.
But um,
six flags.
Six flags is way more like the sum of
their roller coasters.
Just fucking ridiculous on their way.
Crazier.
Yeah.
Way crazier.
But it's a different thing.
You know,
it's not,
it's more like older people.
It's more like,
like high school age and up versus
Disneyland's is really fun for little
kids.
Yeah.
Six flags.
I got like a lot of shit.
It's not even designed for little kids.
Yeah.
I think that some of those ones where
you go upside down some of the roller
coaster once and same one,
what is it,
an x factor or something like that?
X something out there.
I should go while I'm here.
I should check it out if it's a good
one.
Yeah.
It's exciting,
but it's just,
we're just thinking like,
do a guy like you,
like that kind of excitement is probably
really bland.
Yeah.
But like I said before,
because it's not in my control,
it's still kind of gets me a bit.
Oh,
right.
Of course.
It's good.
Yeah,
it's good.
Scares me a bit.
Do you think long term
okay.
Little bit.
Yeah,
a little bit.
But like,
I mean,
do you think long term is as far as like
how long you can do this stuff?
Not really.
No.
That's,
that seems to be the thing that people
tell me the most.
They're like,
well,
if this is your job now,
surely you've got like a,
a limited kind of time to it.
And like I'm 26 I would say I've still
got another 10 years of good strength,
good health in me.
Yeah.
I don't know.
I think in that time I can build
something else up so I don't need to
worry about what happens after.
So do you want to stay in some form of
entertainment?
Like,
you know,
I'd like to have a good entertainer.
Right?
Consider yourself,
I'm sorry.
I hit you with all those career goals.
I'm just a dude,
but what people call me.
Right.
You're a professional dude.
There's a little data.
Yeah.
It's a new disk distinction nation.
I'd like.
So after I did the TV thing,
I really enjoyed it and I've shot like a
couple of pilots since then for things
and I think I'd just like to,
to have my own TV show.
Hmm.
Well doing what?
Like what would you do?
Do Crazy Shit.
Wow.
The idea in the moment that I shot the
pilot for is I travel the world and
meeting other extreme athletes and I try
out what they do and that's,
yeah,
good luck getting insurance for that
show.
That's going to be a problem.
You might have to shoot it on your own
and sell it somebody.
Yeah.
Device.
So like if,
yeah.
So if you do something like that and
somebody falls,
yeah.
Then when you do the show it
like if I was there and I filmed it,
yeah.
I wouldn't know.
No.
What if you show them falling and at the
end you just put a smiley face.
I put an Emoji,
rest in peace,
lol,
lol.
I couldn't do it.
You don't see the actual impact.
You just see a smiley face.
Maybe a bouncing smiley pace where they
were going,
going,
and then year dip,
dip.
That's all folks cut to commercial.
By the time you come back,
people are thinking about other things
are ready,
their phone's buzzing and people are
texting them.
They're trying to get laid.
Yeah.
Pizza got delivered or over it.
I wonder,
man,
what,
what would they tell you?
Like if you were doing something for a
production company,
do you think they would want to include
all that stuff?
Like,
yeah.
I surely they're not allowed,
right?
I don't know.
I mean,
what are they allowed to do and not to
do if people died in reality shows
before,
I got to think they must've done that.
Reality shows have been around for quite
a long time,
but it's the kind of thing that would
happen and then they'd
cut it out.
It's not live though,
was it?
So you can cut it.
Yeah,
you would cut it out,
but everybody would find out.
Hmm.
There was a show footage always leaks as
well.
Yeah,
there's always something.
But there was a show in the early two
thousands where these people were doing
some sort of a wilderness adventure type
show,
like a race through the wilderness.
They were on rafts or kayaks or
something along those lines on rapids
and a woman got trapped.
Um,
we've got wedge and a rock,
her boat,
capsize weights,
and I think she died.
And that was the first one that I had
heard of and I was like in the early two
thousands but there's gotta be a bunch
of them
because there's so many shitty reality
shows now too.
There's so many production companies
that are just,
yeah,
people are going to die.
Yeah.
People up must be dying already.
But that's,
is that something that you think about
when you're doing this show?
Like if you're hanging out with these
crazy Russian cats and they're,
they're doing these things,
it is a possibility.
If you do it a thousand times,
there is a possibility that one of those
times,
so I'm just going to fall.
Yeah,
I dunno.
I've,
I've been in situations,
it was one building in Ukraine where I'm
sad.
It's like,
I think you shared this clip where I'm
walking across the white beams and it's
like nothing underneath it.
Um,
and we both walk out to the edge and
then Mustang climbs down and hangs off
it and I'm looking down at him and I'm
thinking like I can,
I can create the image in my head of him
slipping and just disappearing.
Yeah.
I've,
I've had a few moments like that where
I've just kind of tried to imagine what
it would look like,
but it's not a nice thought.
No,
it's definitely not a nice thought.
But that's the whole reason why it's
interesting is because it's possible.
But if I was doing a video in here of me
hanging from a chin up bar,
that's the only a foot off the ground,
nobody would give a shit if I'm there
looking everybody one arm.
Yeah.
I'm just like James Kingston and do
well,
fuck,
I'm crazy.
No,
there's a floor below me.
Even if I perform the exact same
movements that you do,
if I'm not,
my life isn't in danger.
It's not even interesting at all.
The only reason why it's interesting
it's because your life is in danger.
Yeah,
but that's,
that's like one of the funny things
about it because it is a simple as
handing off a bar.
Yeah.
But people are just like,
what?
Yeah.
Like if there's a small ledge.
Oh Jesus.
There you go.
Barefoot.
Huh?
How come you decided to go barefoot?
You get bad grip barefoot.
Jesus son.
This is that moment.
Yeah.
So you're standing up there looking at
him.
I'm just looking down on him and he's
hanging and then he'd like,
does this stuff always go on one handed?
Oh Jesus Christ.
The only goes one handed for a little
bit and then he goes back to one handed.
Oh you fucker,
Yo,
fuck.
Are you freaking mound?
You're freaking me out.
And he's just hanging there too,
by the way.
He's hanging in there.
He's still hanging in there.
He's one arming it the entire time while
this security like patrolling around the
button.
No idea that were there.
Yeah,
the clang of his body weight hits that
ground,
that fuck.
And he's laughing and smiling.
What is he saying?
His hands are slippery.
It was,
it was a strange color.
Like you'd end up with like chalky
hands,
but it was like a purple.
He kind of color from the paint.
Yeah.
Wow Dude.
You guys ready?
And he's wearing sneakers.
That's the security down there.
Let,
oh Jesus dog as well.
Jump on that dog right from there dude.
Um,
do you have this,
a desire to like keep upping the ante?
Is that an issue?
Um,
not really.
No.
I just like,
ultimately I just like creating stuff
and I liked making videos and I liked
exploring places.
I like heights,
I like jumping between stuff.
Like the natural progression for me is
to,
is to get higher and things get bigger.
That's just how it is.
So it just happens.
But bright but not thinking about it.
I'm not thinking like,
okay,
I've just released this so now I need to
do something bigger.
Like it's just there.
It's just not true.
So how do you go about making a video?
If you decide I'm going to make a new
video,
like what?
Do you have a thought in your head like,
I need to get on the Eiffel Tower?
Like what?
Do you know what?
The Eiffel Tower was?
Never,
never a plan.
I never thought,
let's go to Paris and do the Eiffel
Tower.
Did you do the Eiffel Tower?
So how'd you do it?
If it's not a plan,
how'd you do it?
So I was in Denmark just traveling
around with a bunch of friends and
instead of getting in the minivan and
driving all the way back to London,
I was like,
no,
I don't want to sit in a van for 15
hours.
Let's just fly somewhere and continue
this adventure.
So me and my friend flew to Paris and
then the next day we ended up climbing.
Now for tower.
Do you think this kind of stuff was
being done before people were
videotaping it?
Like was this must've been,
it must have been.
I feel like for certain people it's just
a,
it's just in them to kind of explore
places you shouldn't really explore.
And I think he's,
yeah.
Well,
for you it seems like something that was
fostered though,
right?
Because you started off just doing the
par course tough.
And this became of it.
But you know what?
When I was a kid,
I was like,
I was annoying little kid.
I was always do things that I shouldn't
know.
Yeah.
And I mean now I'm just a big,
just a big version of what I was then.
Wow,
okay.
Ooh,
there's some pretty cool videos.
If you look up on youtube of like urban
exploration and people were finding
weird pathways and like,
oh shit.
Looked on 60 feet underground,
we made it and there's this shit that's
been buried under here.
Wonder why it's buried and look old
electronics fifties and stuff like that.
Like under like uncovering the hatch and
lost.
So it was sort of like that.
Yeah.
Well that's,
that's very interesting to me.
But what I'm,
what I'm really most fascinated by is
this willingness to put your life in
mortal danger.
Okay.
And that,
how exciting this is for people to
watch.
Like what's the most viewed video that
you have?
How many hits does it have?
A,
I think just over 4 million
people.
Yeah,
this one's got a few million I think.
Oh,
this is you.
You get,
so we climbed it.
We went,
we just pushed it too far.
Like we went up to the very top
platform.
If you've been to Paris,
no,
it didn't say off the tower.
So you can take the lift up,
right?
You can,
you can walk.
Can you take the stairs to the second
platform?
That's the highest you can take the
stairs too.
There is stairs to the top,
but they don't allow it because they're
like weird and narrow.
And so you take the lift to the top and
then there's like a door that's always
manned by a security guard that is the
door to that staircase.
And that's what we came up from the
backside.
So we,
we went up,
I'm,
for some reason we just had the urge to
just go inside even though it's lit up,
even though there's cameras everywhere.
Uh,
we opened that door,
I step in to the top platform and then I
just hear this,
this walkie talkie just go like,
ah,
like you go crazy and French.
And I was like,
Shit,
we've definitely been seen.
Let's disappear.
So then we ran down,
we climbed out of the staircase and then
on each,
on opposite corners of the tower in the
main beams,
there's like kind of like a little
pocket inside the beam that you can jump
into.
It must be like two by two.
Like size.
I barely for intimate,
right?
Cause I'm huge.
My friend is small.
So you just like Brooke disappeared into
this hole and then we sat on opposite
ends of the tower and hid and the lifts,
you start hitting lifts coming up,
you start hitting people running up and
down.
The stairs you see taught is
everything's kicking off and we're
hitting these little holes
and they're searching for us.
And I'm just like hiding in this hole.
And I'm like,
I've got one shoe off because it
wouldn't fit in.
I've got my knee wrestling on my shoe,
I've lost all feeling in my leg because
the blood circulation has gone.
My head's sticking out the top and I've
got like my tee shirt of my head,
like a little Ninja and this people with
torches going up and down looking for
us.
So do you have video on that little
pocket that you were in?
Uh,
it's not in this,
no.
I do have,
it's only on two sides of the tower,
which is strange,
but it's kind of similar to this gap
here.
Oh,
I see.
It's there.
It's in the right in that corner there.
So yeah.
And it's like a foot and a half by a
foot and a half.
I think I barely fit in.
So how long did they wait?
So we're in the room in,
this was coming up right now.
Yeah.
This is what it was starting to open up.
This was like as we,
so this is like right where as here,
just before we go.
Cool.
Yeah.
So He'd tucked in.
It was just before he got caught.
So how'd you get caught?
Because the lifts started coming up
because of that.
The staff start coming up to work or to
clean or something and they just saw us.
We're just like running around these
beams and there's lifts everywhere.
So what happens then?
So it like,
so we're still in this hole and we sit
in this whole for like two hours,
at least two hours where they're going
up and down.
It goes quiet.
So I jumped out of the hole.
I have a look around,
I go and see stevie.
Stevie's like half asleep,
just chilling in the hole and then
come back to the whole.
I'm like,
yeah,
that seems like pretty clear now.
I think they must have thought that we
jumped off with parachutes and we would
go because they couldn't find us.
And then I was like,
yeah,
this seems pretty clear.
And then every single light on the tower
goes,
the whole thing lights up.
And this isn't like the twinkly lights
that they have on every hour at night.
This is like internal lights that are
like this big,
like the whole fucking tower up.
So I jumped straight back in the hole.
I'm like,
what's going on?
And then lifts again,
people up and down the stairs again
looking for us.
So when we sat in these holes again for
ages
and then,
and then it finally goes quiet,
the lights are still on for a little
while and then the whole thing just
shuts down.
And I think that was it.
So I jumped out,
I had a look around to went and got
stevie and then it was ours again.
And then we were up there until like
9:00 AM I think it was.
How long was that?
How many hours?
A 1:00 AM til 9:00 AM.
Wow.
So you were climbing around I think for
eight fucking hours.
That's nuts.
Yeah.
Running some.
That French chocolate barb.
She was really good.
Oh,
that's all you eat.
It's all we had.
Yeah.
So he came down because you were hungry
and we came down because we got caught
now.
And so you would have stayed there for
the rest of the day.
Um,
the idea was to like wait till it opened
and then get into a,
a place where you could hide like near
the second platform and then just drop
into the second platform and just merge
in was like the tourists.
But we didn't get that far.
That would have been car.
So the plan was to wait for it to open
and sneak out with the crowd.
Just jumped out of the beam into the
crowd.
Disappearance or lift done.
So when you get caught then what
happens?
So we've got seen by like a big group of
people in,
in one of the lifts and we just like
waving and they're like,
ah,
like angry looking people but like angry
people and happy people.
They're like,
what the heck's going on?
And then,
uh,
we were like above slightly above and
maintenance platform where they have
like lifts that take workers up.
And then,
so we had to climb down and we met
people on the maintenance platform
getting the left.
There's like five of us,
like to me and Stevie and they're like
few other people.
Security,
just like private security for the
tower.
And then we come down to like the
basement lifts open.
There's just like a room full of
policemen and we're like go scene in the
movie.
And when they do that bit,
I had to hide every single way,
sd card and everything that I had on me.
How'd you do that?
Three counters?
No,
no.
It was an option.
That is the only option.
Yeah.
I haven't had to do that yet.
But he had a condom.
You tied in a knot?
Yeah.
Put them in the condom.
Put your finger up,
move on.
Yeah,
that's right.
All right.
So how do you um,
hide the SD cards?
I mean they must have went through your
stuff for the flight.
I thought they would,
but they didn't.
I don't know.
Paris,
they don't give a fuck.
The attorney delayed drink wine
chocolate had like a big five d like a
big DSLR.
And then I had I think two gopros and so
to mike arrestees and one like cf card
from the,
from the big one.
And I had like this bag that I had,
like little tiny pen pockets,
like really thin pockets.
Right.
And I just stuffed the Mike cresty cars
down there and it had like a,
a little rip in the back padding of the
bag.
So I just threw the CF card in the back
of the bag and it just fell down and I
just hoped.
And then when like we got to the police
station,
they were like,
you have so many cameras on you,
clearly you've been filming.
And I was like,
no,
I forgot the SD cards.
Cameras died.
And they,
they believed that I had to surrender
everything on my phone.
I um,
you had to surrender everything on your
phone.
Yeah.
So,
so I had three cameras,
right.
So it was like I had three cameras and
my phone.
So I was like,
I'm going to have to give something up
to try and save the most valuable,
the most valuable footage.
So I was like,
they were like,
did you feel most,
I only filmed in my phone because my
camera's died and I forgot my SD cards.
And then they went through like the
footage on the phone just made me delete
it or,
oh,
that's cool.
So the,
the footage and the phone was like a
ruse.
The footage on the phone was like me in
the,
in the little hole filming,
talking to the camera and like filming
the people looking cause was like this
and I put my phone down.
Great.
That you had something to give them.
Yeah.
So now then what happens?
How long did they detain you?
Uh,
we were there for like eight hours.
So that another eight hours.
So when you're eight hours up there
climbing around,
how do you pee?
You pee off the edge of the town.
Oh my God.
That's probably where he got arrested.
The person on these French people as if
life wasn't clicked on them enough.
Yeah.
I think by the time it gets to the
ground,
it's kind of all spread out and we're
not,
or it's a fucking raging river of pis,
right.
On some little Old Lady's head.
Yeah.
It seems like if you were,
why don't you just pee on the tower that
way it dribbles down slowly.
It doesn't hit anybody in the head.
I mean if you were sitting on the Eiffel
Tower and you needed to pay,
there was no one below you because it's
like 4:00 AM okay.
You'd pay off the edge.
Maybe that's even ruder.
I'm sorry enough person.
If I did pay on them,
maybe it was a romantic couple going for
a walk,
maybe it would have really worked out.
All of a sudden the girl goes to lighter
cigarette and you piss running her head
and she gets mad and the fucking evening
and poorly and they could have,
it could have been a perfect
relationship,
but you ruined it.
I killed it.
Yeah.
So you come down and then another eight
hours of detention.
Yeah.
And what do they do to you?
Handcuffed us to a chair.
We just sat in the middle of the,
of this police station.
There's like sales behind us with people
going crazy and like people bleeding
from the eyeballs and we just sat there
like people bleeding from the rivals,
from other crimes,
nighttime fights and stuff like that and
just drunk people.
And we just sat there for ages and then
we finally got taken into separate rooms
where we were questioned by some high
up,
I had a woman,
he had a dude and we were both
questioned for a couple hours and then
we were back out handcuffed to the
chairs again.
And then they took all of our stuff and
they searched it and I was like,
well,
if they find it,
they're going to be like,
okay,
you just told us that you feel nothing.
And we've just found hours and hours of
footage,
like what's the deal?
So I was like,
oh please.
Cods.
Yeah.
And then,
um,
they finally brought the,
brought the bags back.
Like it must've been an hour.
They had them full and I thought they
were going to go through everything,
but they brought it back.
I checked it and I was like,
[inaudible] the gods are still here.
Then we just like,
we just lost it.
We were so happy.
But the,
the policemen,
I had no idea what we were doing.
So did they kick you out of the country?
No.
Record.
And I said nothing at all.
So I had to go back to that room.
I had to sign an agreement that said,
I promise I will not climb the Eiffel
Tower for three years.
For three years.
That's it.
That was it.
Yeah.
Wait a bad them.
Right.
How come they only give you,
how can we,
I'll take forever.
They must like it.
Yeah.
You know what?
Interviewing me,
he loved it.
She did.
She was like,
you really shouldn't be doing this,
but how did you do this?
It's incredible.
Like she loved it.
Why Oak?
He loved it.
Yeah.
Well,
I think once they realize that you're
polite,
you're a gentlemen,
you're a very nice guy.
You're just a thrill seeker.
They're like,
okay,
this is not a threat to society.
Yeah.
Sky's in a terrorist.
So the second question she asked me was,
did you leave a bomb up there?
Oh God.
And I just laughed.
I was like,
what?
Come on.
Oh Wow.
Well,
that's something they have to take any
consideration.
They have to actually trust you.
Right?
If they let you go and turns out you did
leave a bottom up down [inaudible] then
they have to like,
they would have to comb over the
building with a fine tooth comb and you
just say he's going to be like,
yeah,
you know what I did?
I left the bulb up there.
No,
no one would write.
So they really have to trust you.
Yeah.
Fucking Europeans.
Ridiculous,
ridiculous people.
Three years.
Fuck you.
You throw me in jail forever.
His America,
they put you right in Guantanamo Bay.
They throw dogs in there with you.
Cool.
It just seems like um,
they're a little bit looser over there.
A little more relaxed about things.
Yeah.
I was under,
I was driving from La to San Fran a
couple of weeks ago up the one is it the
one amazing drive and I find like a
couple of cranes.
I went and saw like some elephants,
the elephant seals and then shortly
after that I just found like a building
site on the site,
like near the beach,
like a hundred meters back from the
beach.
I was like,
of course I need to stop.
And just do this because it's dead.
It was,
um,
what we can,
was it a holiday weekend?
Right.
So I did it and I stopped and I climbed
it and then I'm at the top and I looked
down.
So I had like a rental Mustang and I
popped the Mustang in the site,
like on the top of this peak,
it looked really cool,
but you could see it from the road.
So a cop,
cops driving past,
he sees the Mustang.
He was like,
what's going on?
So he pulls in and he's walking around
looking,
and then you looked up and he sees me at
the top of this crane and he's like,
you get your ass down here right now.
And I was like,
fuck,
this is the first time I got caught in
the U S I was like,
shit,
what's going to happen?
Well,
you in California,
it's better than getting caught in like
Arizona.
Yeah.
This is Texas.
The shoot.
You just shoot me.
Yeah.
Okay.
I'll bear that in mind.
That's what I'm scared of.
That's what I'm scared of him when the
UK,
what?
We know that the cops over here to be
like this,
they just shoot people.
That's like what we're told,
you know,
that's what they feed us.
You're white.
You gonna be okay.
Um,
so the guy gets you down the woods.
She was telling me,
get out of there.
He shouts at me.
Yeah,
I've got this all on video as well.
He shouts at me,
I come down and then he just lays into
me.
Yeah.
Asking me from England,
you don't know any better.
Exactly.
Yeah.
It was like,
oh,
in England it's nicely.
Well,
you're not an,
you're in the United States of America,
boy,
and you need to do what you should do.
So yeah.
So he doesn't want to fill out the
paperwork.
It took my driver's license.
He checked all my stuff and then he,
he was like,
okay.
He came back after like 10 minutes.
He was like,
okay.
So I made a decision and I'm going to
leave this in the hands of the site
manager.
So he goes and he tries to find a site
manager,
but it's a holiday weekend.
Nobody's there.
So he goes to the office,
he phones up some number on the,
on the door and he speaks to the site
manager and the site managers just got
back to La from,
from where he's working.
And he was like,
you know what?
I've just got back home.
I cannot be bothered to deal with this.
So just,
just let him go and then we just go.
And that was it.
What is the worst you've ever gotten in
trouble?
Uh,
there's nothing,
you know,
nothing.
There's nothing like bad.
Are you worried now though there with
your Internet fame that now you're
getting millions of hits in these videos
that people are gonna,
they're gonna recognize you and maybe
even like a target you yeah.
Set an example.
Yeah.
I don't know.
I've thought about it,
but it doesn't seem to happen.
Happen.
It seems to be getting easier because
that all shit Yo,
this guy like can I take a picture of
that?
That's just how it works.
Do you worry that you're encouraging
people that are not as competent or
thoughtful as you?
Um,
I'm worried that somebody that is a bit
silly,
you might see it and think,
oh,
I need to do this to,
to be cool or to look cool in front of
my mates.
Like young kids.
Right?
The allegory about that.
Yeah,
but there's not much I can do.
Like there's,
there's so many more things out there
that are so easily available on the
Internet that kids could watch and be
inspired by.
And like I'd just,
I always make it clear that what I'm
doing is just,
well,
I want people to get from this is like
I'm just going out exploring the world,
live in my life in a way that I enjoy
doing things that make me happy,
pushing myself,
developing myself,
becoming a better person,
a stronger person.
And that's it.
And climbing and jumping around.
It's just my way of doing it.
Like we all have our own little
passions,
right?
That's just mine.
Yours might be badminton or like
something Ping Pong.
That's another thing that's interesting
that's happening now with the larger
number of content providers,
like so many people like yourself that
are doing things like this.
The idea that one person is responsible
for their influence becomes less and
less plausible.
It just comes more like,
well,
what is he representing?
Well,
he's representing a 26 year old guy who
absolutely knows how to do that.
You know?
It's not,
you don't have to do what he's doing,
but he can do what he's doing.
So are you supposed to stop doing what
you're doing?
Which you obviously very case actually,
because you're not a good example with,
they're the perfect example of someone
doing it correctly.
Yeah,
exactly.
But that people just don't just don't
get that well.
The idea that you're influencing people
is always,
it's always very tricky because we'll
please supposed to do,
he's supposed to live your life in a
cushion room so no one gets injured
because that's the only way to influence
people positively.
You know?
In terms of like if you're going to do
risky things,
you could always be an example or be an
inspiration to someone who's not as
competent as you.
Yeah.
I'm naked.
Risk,
death or injury.
Yeah.
I don't think,
honestly I don't think anybody is stupid
enough to see it go out and try it.
Like most people on Earth.
Right.
Can put them up a crane and they'll shit
themselves.
Yeah.
I didn't think any 12 year old,
14 year old kid is going to say it and
be like,
oh dude to the,
to the climate.
Right.
And off it.
I just don't see that happening.
Oh,
they're definitely gonna do it.
I disagree.
There's going to be a bunch of them.
Yeah.
There's a lot of crazy fucks out there.
Just like you pal.
Yeah.
It's be on me.
Like I can't,
Russians have been doing it longer than
I have flat.
Did they start this stuff?
Yeah.
As far as I know.
He went up there with big ass heavy
cameras and stuff.
I saw was Russians big ass fucking boom
box cameras.
Yeah.
I wonder who the first guy was to climb
up on top of some beam.
Cause I saw one where there was a a
steel girder that it was extended out
into the forest by rusty,
right?
Yeah.
And it's trees everywhere.
Asked for the first one I saw it was,
it might've been the first one.
Yeah.
That one's doing push ups and all that.
Yes.
That fuck yeah.
Russia.
That's right.
I want to go.
Then I really want to go there because
it's still there.
Oh No,
don't do it.
And he's not that picture where he's
like,
this is epic.
Yeah,
here it is.
Do you these hanging upside down and
he's extending his lens.
This guy's out of his fucking mind.
He's doing like flips and he's doing
chin ups and he's letting go of his
hands.
He's doing chin ups and he gets to the
top.
He lets go of his hands and he's doing
several of them.
He's doing one leg with one leg crossed
over the other one kind of winded.
Oh my God.
They're balancing on their hands over
these beans.
That's the one fucking Jesus Christ.
This is driving me nuts.
But you see like there's a bunch of
videos of dudes in this place.
I know.
Well how many people have died from this
place?
It must be a few.
Oh my God.
Look at this guy gripping.
Ooh,
this is so scary.
Good Lord.
This is so sad,
Gary.
As a watch.
This video isn't that old.
Do you think this may be started once
the,
sorry,
once cameras became the portable enough
to get up there,
like the small little flip cams and
blogging cam.
Yeah.
Maybe it wasn't,
you weren't capable of taking a big ass
vcr camera like you got a drone in one
of yours.
I saw them and drones are being able to
do live video now.
Look at my hands.
He could,
I could.
I could like ring the out in a glass
right now.
I'm watching this video and I'm freaking
out and these guys are doing it and
they're laughing.
You know,
they're so high up.
Look at that forest below them.
Yeah,
I think,
I think you're right that people have
always probably done this.
Yeah.
Amazing feats of athleticism too.
If you look at this guy bouncing in his
hands,
his feet up boxes,
full plank hanging off.
Look at this guy.
I mean that is,
that's some serious fucking strength.
Yeah.
I mean it's just,
it's such a crazy endeavor.
Where are you doing some of this before
you could film it like before you even
had a camera.
So it's not just about showing people.
Okay.
Do you know anybody who's fallen and
died?
Um,
no.
None personally.
You know,
there was a,
it was a park old guy that fell off a
rooftop.
He was doing a back.
Some are still on the edge of a rooftop
from you,
like a wool like this,
which is like an easy thing to do,
but something must've got to him and he
fell off and he died.
Yeah.
16 stories,
I think.
Woo.
This is recent.
Couple of years ago,
I think.
Where do you fall?
What place?
Uh,
I think it was Russia.
That's pretty sure it was rush.
You Google it,
you'll find it.
So it's surprisingly few deaths.
Yeah.
That we know about the,
a publicized,
I don't see that many.
Yeah.
Which is good.
I guess.
Yeah,
for sure.
So you're planning a lot of leads me to
believe that people aren't stupid enough
to go out and mess up.
Well,
it's such a scary thing to do that it
just takes a very small percentage of
people.
Yeah.
And,
and it grabs a hold of them and says,
you got to do this too.
Yeah.
There's a video that's actually on
youtube that probably shouldn't be on
youtube.
Have somebody fill me from the ground up
at a crane and a guy like walks across
the top beam of the crane and falls and
you'd just see his body just,
Oh God.
Yeah.
It's disappears behind some of the
building.
Well,
I think as long as it doesn't hit the
bottom,
they'll that you show it.
Yeah.
And then we have rules like that.
Like you'd know the guy had died.
Yeah.
Which you can't see it.
Strange.
So 10 more years of this.
I Dunno.
You're not thinking about the future.
You're just a wild man.
I was just the wild man.
Yeah.
Living on the edge.
Just see what it's all like.
Yeah.
Wow.
It's like pointing to thinking that far
ahead.
You know,
I could die tomorrow,
we could all die tomorrow.
It could all get hit by a bus or we
could live and then you go,
fuck,
why didn't I think about tomorrow?
Yeah.
It's not a bad idea.
A plan,
assuming you will live.
Police released horrell video of school
by falling a hundred feet to his death
as warning to daredevils.
Police in Russia.
I've released the horrifying video at
Russia.
Yeah,
we don't need to see this Jamie.
This kid is going to fall and I'm going
to freak out even farther.
Like I've seen this.
Yeah.
What other interests do you have to
train side's doing this kind of crazy
shit I do or not?
No other sports really.
I just love filmmaking.
I just love making videos.
I love filming stuff.
I love taking pictures.
I love creating these little films and
it's like both of my passions just work
hand in hand.
I've got the Parker and the climbing
stuff and I've got the filmmaking.
Do you ever film stuff that's not scary
and Dario and stuff and do people need
to do more of that?
Do People respond to that?
Yeah,
I um,
so I put out a video a couple of months
ago of my new car,
like at my new car video.
So it's basically like a car review.
Right.
And people love it.
Oh,
I think I might've seen that.
Do you have an m three and four for a
new one?
Yeah.
I think I did see that.
People like it.
It's like 200 normal guys.
Yeah.
It's a great car.
It's an amazing Chi.
And you got that car from money that you
made from risking your life?
Yeah.
Wow.
From like Youtube ads and stuff.
Is that what it is?
Cheated money.
Sponsorships,
everything.
There's a beautiful car.
They're so well engineered.
Yeah.
Look at it,
man.
It's a piece of law.
It is.
I had an m three.
The last one.
Yeah.
I had the old one.
The Old v eight.
Yeah.
This is interesting that the v six
turbo,
right?
You like it
like it's a completely different sound.
But I like it.
I used to have like a turbo charged car
before the va m three and I missed all
the,
the little hisses and the wobbles and I
missed it,
so now I've got it back.
That's stuff much faster.
A lot of people like the roar of the v
eight yeah,
it's the big complaint about the m three
m four rather.
He doesn't have that roar and it
doesn't,
it's completely different,
but I wouldn't,
I wouldn't compare them.
I wouldn't say all the m three is
better.
It's just a different,
it's a different breed,
you know?
It's like,
well we're getting used to cars that you
make.
Those electric cars are becoming more
and more prevalent.
I saw that the Tesla numbers the other
day,
Jamie,
it's 2.5 seconds,
so let,
it's so less than three it's 2.5 they
like the model x,
like the big one as well as the other.
Really.
I think the big ones a little silly.
It's sub three I'm just say this week
too.
I wonder if they updated the speed,
like the software update,
like a foam or update at speed to your
car.
Yeah,
it's nuts.
It's crazy.
Elon Musk,
man,
he's,
he's killing it.
He's on the spectrum for sure.
Right.
Gotta be super wizard.
Yeah.
He's an alien.
He's probably,
yeah.
This,
uh,
those people,
those like people that pushed things
like that.
What does this zero to 60 in 2.5 seconds
has 315 miles of range.
Not if you'd go that fast.
It's 289 miles.
What does that stop lying?
What does it say?
Is it a different one
and model two?
They make that sweet one,
that little tiny one.
Do they still,
there's Tesla's still make that little
sports car one.
Nah,
they don't,
they,
they released them in limited numbers.
The little tiny one.
The little little lotus look at him.
Yeah.
That Lotus looking one was beautiful
that first wasn't it?
Yeah.
But it is on skinny tires and apparently
the weights all fucked up.
It's like Porsche nine 11,
but way to the extreme cause all the
weights in the back.
Yeah.
Just like a Porsche,
but way more weight.
Yeah.
So it's like if you go around a corner
and the asset and kicks out on you,
you just won't know.
Or if you're going around a corner and
you're hitting the gas and you let off
the gas,
you know,
you get that,
that tail end Sorta pendulums out on
you.
But the beauty cause man to you cause it
fun.
Yeah,
me too.
I'm a big fan.
Big Fan of engineering drive.
Um,
my favorite car,
I have a Porsche nine 11 gt three r s
dude.
Yeah.
I have an older one,
a 2007 when there were still manually.
Yeah.
They don't make manuals anymore.
Now they're all up those paddle shifts,
which is a,
they're really fun but it's just not as
fun.
Yeah,
it's different.
Yeah.
I'm a big fan of a clutch.
Not just one thing I like about the m
four.
It's one of the few high end sports cars
where you could still get it,
that clutch all the American cars do it.
Like corvettes.
Yeah.
You still get with a clutch,
but like a Porsche Porsche's,
the Gt three and the gt three Rs.
Now you gotta get automatic Ferrari only
automatic.
Yeah,
that's my car.
That was before I took the painting off
the,
the wheels are off the side,
the gt three Rs logo.
I'm like,
that's a little school boy racer.
Now it's just white.
But those are uh,
what I like about those cars is not even
really growing that fast as the
connection.
Like when you're going around corners,
it literally is like a ride.
It feels like a Disneyland ride cause
it's so hard.
Yeah.
And it's also the engineering,
like you can appreciate the amount of
thought and trial and error in
calculation that's involved and creating
something that's so capable.
You know,
when you drive a regular car,
you know,
it's just a car.
You drive and around and you drive one
of those things around and you're on a
ride,
you know?
Yeah.
So Siphon,
yeah,
me too.
I'm a big fan.
So do you,
this is like all your life.
You just enjoy making videos,
taking photos and doing these crazy
stunts and filming them and he just
living day by day and keep on keeping on
living the dream.
Yeah,
you are.
And a lot of ways,
man.
I mean there's a lot of kids that are
going,
wait a minute,
you could just do chin ups on a crane.
You can get a fucking BMW.
Yeah.
You'd be surprised how many people are
like,
you don't deserve this.
Oh fuck those people.
Because you're risking your goddamn.
What you do is what you do is climb
ladders and listen.
People watch the videos.
Jealousy.
Does this tell us you're always going to
have that?
Yeah.
Here's going to have haters.
Do they motivate you?
Nah,
that just let me laugh.
Haters do.
Yeah.
Do you have a place that you want to go?
Hong Kong.
Oh Chinese don't fuck around dog,
but she looked at some videos from Hong
Kong.
Man,
it's the place to be,
but if you get caught over there they
might throw you in a hole.
I don't know.
I think a few people who have been
banned from Hong Kong for like some
years or forever.
I've not,
I've not heard anything bad.
I think I would imagined that anytime
you get arrested in a foreign country,
he was this Hong Kong.
Oh High Rise Hong Kong.
It's guys walking around with a selfie
stick sponsors.
Oh my God.
He's shown his sponsors.
Who the fuck would have been at backup.
Backup is sponsors.
Yeah.
Backup.
Click pause.
What is this?
Jet Flight search engine.
Jet Radar flight search engine.
Hotel.
Look.
Hotel search engine.
So what's that was her sponsors.
What's happened here is he's been like,
okay,
I need to get to Hong Kong but I have
money.
I need to get a hotel in Hong Kong by
die of money.
I'm going to contact a flight company
and a hotel company and see if I can get
them to give me both for video.
But how insane are those companies that
they like?
What are you going to do some illegal
shit in China?
Yeah,
man.
Yeah man.
Put My name up there.
I want to,
I want people to know 1 million,
100,359 views.
That's why I like fuck it.
Have a lot of those people are going to
use our service.
A couple of those buildings I guess if
the guy lived,
it's not negative,
right?
Yeah.
If you made it through.
Yeah,
exactly.
It's like,
yeah,
that's the deal.
If you uh Oh my God,
this is so bananas gloves.
Oh He's got clubs on you.
You think he's a pussy for wearing
gloves.
I mean,
but that's like,
that's like a pole background,
but the idea is to not have to rely on
anything.
Like you build your hands up so that you
can do shit like this and not have to
worry about cutting your finger.
Now when you were doing park horse
stuff,
we do in like back flips off buildings
and stuff.
Have you ever seen that video where this
kid in the ghetto,
he's on a second floor roof and he does
a back flip and lands on the ground?
Yeah,
probably.
It's,
I've seen some seriously high.
One fucking crazy.
Like,
how does a guy live from that far away?
You did.
You just learn how to land.
How does he learn how to land land in
landing away,
right?
Your legs take as much of the impact as
they physically can.
And then you smash your bum until the
ground and then you just do it
backwards.
Roll.
That's it.
Watch this guy.
And if you bumped back,
flip off the 40 foot roof.
I think this smashes his head.
Yeah,
for sure.
But what's crazy is he actually did
this.
He did a back flip.
Like somebody gave him something like a
dollar or something crazy,
right?
Wasn't it like 20 bucks or something
ridiculous with this dude?
Like he's standing there.
Okay.
And this is no one had to
please don't hurt yourself.
Please look at this.
I'm going gonna say a prayer.
You hear that?
I'm ready.
I don't even want to look at that.
What?
You're not going to turn away either
though,
are you?
You want to be there.
So this guy is standing there with his
back.
He's building height right now.
Here it goes.
Smash.
And he made it.
I'm good bro.
I'm good.
Holy Shit.
He's got strong bones would be snapped.
Yeah,
that is.
And that was a hard surface he fell
onto.
Yeah.
You would just think that if someone
just jumped,
like,
is the flip helping at all?
Does how's that?
Just because of the momentum is it's
going this way instead of just going to
slam straight down.
I think it makes sense some of that into
that,
which is like,
you know,
when you see people jumping massive roof
gaps and they laugh and they roll,
that's converting all this downwards
momentum into a forward and to Ford.
And that,
that means you can jump a lot further
than you think.
Oh,
that's interesting.
So,
but how do you,
if you have to drop straight,
what do you do?
A,
you lied and you just slam your hands
until the ground as well.
Spread out.
The impact is as best you can.
Yeah.
It rolls are any good,
really a feel going forward.
Quite a lot.
So running.
So if you had to jump off of that 40
foot high wall,
that guy was on,
how would you jump?
Uh,
I'd probably hang off the edge and just
straight drop.
Um,
yeah.
It's not one that,
that's not that high at the fuck.
Are you saying you don't think you'd
have a problem making that jump?
No.
Really?
Yeah,
I've done big drops.
It helps.
I'm big as well.
So does it,
but makes it your heavy too,
right?
Yeah,
but I,
my legs a lot.
I've got good legs,
man.
My legs like my strongest thing.
Do you exercise or do you just do a lot
of that?
Just the exercise comes from doing it
and that's it.
And how often do you do it now?
Not so much.
I used to do a lot,
like I used to go out every day and
train all day and just repeat jumps and
everything.
Now it's kind of like bill in me,
but it doesn't have,
it's not a problem.
Like as the more famous you get,
the more obligations you get,
the less time you have to practice and
the more people expect of you do crazier
shit.
It's a problem.
Yeah.
But fuck,
yeah,
don't die dude.
You seem like a nice guy.
No it die.
Please don't.
That'd be,
it'd be a wonderful story if you made it
through this thing.
Yeah,
no problems at all.
And you know,
people be like,
look,
you just,
the only thing you have to fear is fear
itself.
Yeah.
That's true.
Anything else to add to the people
before we get the fuck out of here?
No,
not really.
Thanks for watching.
Thanks for having me on please.
My boss room.
We made it happen.
I'm glad we did and I'm glad.
I'm glad I got to meet you.
They're normal guys.
It's you.
I looked in your eyes.
He looked totally normal looking in your
eyes.
There's nothing crazy going on in there.
Right?
You would just assume,
I mean,
you look at some of these Russians and
you look in their eyes and you just see
death and learning different for an
yeah.
Yeah.
Whoa.
So they're the kings of this shit that I
guess.
Yeah man,
it's a weird thing to do.
It's a weird thing to do.
What do you have planned a that people
can look forward to?
Um,
I've got quite a lot going on at city.
I've got some,
a couple of huge videos to release from
Dubai.
I'm doing something here next week.
Involving your helicopter in America.
America?
Yeah.
What part of America should we say at a
Oh,
downtown La Hollywood sign.
The people know about it.
Sure.
Yeah.
People just saying helicopter,
just saying working on it.
You're doing it from a helicopter.
Yeah,
dude,
don't fall.
Yup.
If you fall,
the people are going to get mad at me
for sure.
Yeah.
You encouraged them,
you told them to go farther.
You just dude,
craziest shit.
So I've got a few big videos.
I've got a book coming out,
which is cool.
Oh,
this is matt.
What's your book?
Photography and stuff now.
It's like a live story.
Oh yeah.
It's like my beginning how I discover
park or how I started climbing and then
not like a few select big climbs that
I've done.
And did you write it or do you talk to
this guy's written so it's like,
it's uh,
based off interviews.
I'm not a writer.
I can't write a book,
but a couple of big interviews and then
he converted into a book and then a
bunch of pictures as well.
Just cool.
Wow.
Yeah.
Well listen,
you've scared the shit out of me
numerous occasions,
so in a way you've absolutely entertain
me,
so I appreciate it man.
And uh,
it's very nice to meet you and continued
health and success to you.
Please.
Like very much.
You were a nice guy.
I don't want anything bad to happen to
you,
man.
Be careful out there.
It's fun.
James Kingston,
ladies and gentlemen,
what is your instagram and your,
your instagrams.
Jane.
Jane,
do you have a twitter and twice the same
James Kingston?
He's put james gets in any way.
Are you okay?
Thank brother.
Very nice to meet you man too.
Thank you.
Good night.
You fucks.
See Ya.
Okay.