Oh false swag five,
four,
three,
two.
Yes,
yes.
Ladies and gentlemen.
Yes,
we're here.
We,
I'm sorry we didn't go live earlier.
Folks tweeted it 20 minutes ago.
We just said a bunch of shit.
We could never talked to you about
gossip.
A lot of it had to do with Dick's as
usual course.
When shops on.
It's about Dick's.
Go do what you gotta do.
Dixon gossip.
Speaking dicks.
That fucking thing.
You're driving around.
You're driving around a kid's toy that
the La.
It's so crazy,
Mr.
fuck boy,
toy dude.
I was because I came straight from the
airport.
Tell him what it is.
That's a slingshot.
So it's uh,
there's,
you know,
it's a three wheeler,
so big two wheels in the front one the
back.
It looks like Bruce Wayne's like,
yeah,
like batmobile,
like weird toy.
It looks like you shouldn't be able to
drive in the street.
You're like,
wait a minute,
how do you.
You could just drive that around.
Quitting.
Know how does that work?
That's A.
is that a car?
Like what is that?
I don't know what it is,
but technically it's considered a
motorcycle.
And you know,
I,
I have the helmet,
I wear the helmet sometimes kids,
if you're listening,
definitely wear a helmet when you have
it.
But I was,
I parked at the airport because I don't
want to park my,
a porsche parked at the airport and then
I uh,
I thought I have time to go home because
I land this morning from San Francisco,
don't have time to go home and change
the cards out and then come here and you
know,
take a shower,
whatever.
But I didn't.
So I was like,
ah,
fuck.
I just struggle all the way down there.
Go on the four or five over the hill.
It's lovely though.
The wind in my face.
I got fucking eighties rock on this
fucking.
I was feeling myself,
man.
I thought did.
I mean people are like me.
Like that's either the coolest guy I've
ever seen.
The biggest tool.
It's like it hit me with your best shot.
I'm just fucking flying man.
That's hilarious.
You listening to Pat Benatar just wowed
and Oh my God,
I love it man.
Because again,
I would never get on a motorcycle,
but because this thing is so big,
so it's a little safer,
a little little sick.
It's because people can see it,
like most likely get fucked up.
Can't see it.
That's a big part.
But this thing,
I mean when to my face I can see like
everything meant like a car.
You're sewing clothes.
This I love it.
And the stick shift.
Like I feel like I'm one with the road.
Oh really?
Oh yeah.
Oh yeah,
that's better.
It isn't,
it isn't driving,
uh,
you feel.
I feel more like I said with the road,
I feel like,
uh,
like Paul Newman or some shit,
like a race car driver.
Especially with that thing that seems
like the sweet spot between a motorcycle
and a car.
Exactly.
That's why it makes sense.
And the gas mileage on it is super
beast.
It's awesome.
I'll probably weighs nothing right now.
Thing little engine in its fast.
But if your ways.
Can
you pick it up?
I don't know.
We should try after this.
Should I pick it up?
You and I can definitely pick it up if
it weighs somewhere around like,
like a really light light car is
supposed to be the most fun to drive,
let's say like a 19,
73 porsche because they're not,
they're not that powerful,
but they don't really need to be 1973.
Porsche has like 200 horsepower.
It's like,
wow,
there's a fast little car because they
way you can get them down to like 1900
pounds.
That's insane.
It might.
My Gt three is 3000 pounds,
so think of nuts.
So severity light.
That's why.
That's why when you're buying a porsche,
if you get the Targa,
there's so much heavier glass.
They're heavy,
heaviest,
fuck.
All that bullshit.
Look sick though.
They do look cool,
but I don't think they are.
Especially the old ones.
I don't think they're the most rigid.
I don't think they had that debt.
Like I used to have an NSX that had a
target top.
What do you got to your 1700 years at?
You were saying Porsche.
Wow,
that's light.
That's lighter than probably one of the
lightest cars you could get.
Here's the stickler,
no airbags,
so if someone were to hit me,
that's no Bueno.
I live life on the edge though,
fellas.
Look at that thing.
She can do it that way.
Like having no airbags.
How does that work?
I'm not sure.
It's basically a motorcycle.
It's considered a motorcycle on the
street,
but they say cops.
If they see you that a helmet,
they will pull you over and pound the
car.
I just.
These things are so new.
They think I'm like some low budget
alley cat,
Bruce Wayne or something like that.
They thumbs up past seven of them.
I mean if you don't have a helmet on.
Yeah,
and I go in Carpool.
I go in Carpool like an asshole just
blaring eighties rockaway.
A carpool because it's a motorcycle.
I'm like,
well classically it's a motorcycle.
Wow,
you could.
You could go into the Hov in that.
I'm not sure,
Joe.
There's really no rules.
I'm kind of no man's land right now,
so you can.
You're allowed to go in.
How funny is that?
You're allowed to go in the Carpool lane
and a fucking motorcycle.
That's the opposite of carpooling in it
when it's so stupid,
like if you're carpooling on a
motorcycle,
you putting somebody at risk corral.
If you get somebody on the back with you
soon.
Every time I see a guy on a motorcycle,
I see one person I see like,
well it's dangerous,
but it's gotten worse.
I see two people on a motorcycle.
I'll go,
well this is.
This is like exponentially more
dangerous and usually it's his girl in
the back with like she is daisy dukes on
or something.
Right,
and how much,
how good are you at adjusting with that
extra 125 pounds in the back.
Yeah,
that's what I'm saying.
That extra hundred 25 pounds or whatever
she weighed one.
Let's go one for.
Let's make a real woman.
Let's say she's a hundred 50 pounds,
so if you get to 150 pounds behind you,
how good are you at correcting for that?
If you really practice that,
are you good in the moment when the shit
hits the fan?
Do you make good decisions?
Do you even know if you do?
I think it's one of those things where
it doesn't matter if you're both on a
motorcycle and you have daisy dukes on
craft gives off fucked meat goes
everywhere.
Super Meaty.
Oh,
just chunks of meat.
Hit the gravel
and rip apart and tear would go barefoot
and shorts,
no shirt riding a motorcycle and you can
do that in Colorado.
You didn't have to have a helmet.
I think Nevada has no helmet too.
It's a bunch of places like that.
Arizona,
no helmets.
I saw these dudes riding around and
Harley Davidson's no helmet and I was
like,
what kind of fear though?
Like for you to ride a motorcycle,
how are you going to tell them where to
a helmet if they.
If,
if they don't want to wear one,
who gives a fuck?
Because that's the only thing that could
save their life.
I know,
but if they're on a motorcycle,
you know what I'm saying?
Like,
yeah,
whatever,
man,
this is how I like to live.
Well,
there's A.
There's an argument there,
man.
For sure.
I don't.
I don't think he should be able to tell
people what to do,
but I think guidelines for young people
are very,
very important because they make good
point,
impulsive decisions and if you you could
protect more of them.
If you made a mandatory helmet law,
maybe you should say up to age 30 and
over age 30.
You do it over the fucking why they do
it because you can't have all those
loopholes.
Kenya.
Yeah,
probably makes sense.
I think the reason why they do it,
it's for insurance.
I think insurance policies don't.
They don't want to pay out for injuries
and death and all that shit.
That's why they make seatbelt laws.
That's why they make helmet laws.
I don't really think it's to protect
people.
I think protecting people as a
consequence of protecting their money.
It makes sense.
Yeah.
Gross is that.
I'm pretty sure that's true though.
That's live.
So they realized how people,
how many people get injured and how much
they have to pay.
So they factored in and they say,
well,
just lobby for more protection in the
car is more airbags,
airbags,
mandatory seatbelts,
all that different stuff.
Like a lot of that is really under the
guise of protecting us.
It's really the protective insurance
company's money.
It's nasty.
They say,
uh,
your,
your odds of getting a motorcycle
accident your first year of owning a
motorcycle or 99 percent.
Oh my God.
Ninety nine percent of people get in
some sort of.
They wreck it.
They do something their first year of
driving a motorcycle.
Wow.
That's why you don't buy a super fancy
motorcycle your first year.
Do you ever see Dean Dale reading when
he wiped?
No,
he wiped back when he's fat.
Dean Dean,
um,
got off sugar completely.
Really impressive.
Actually.
He was always,
it was never fat,
but he was a guy who was not taking care
of himself.
Sorry,
not going to the gym.
And he got real thick and he was on a
motorcycle and some crazy meth head
caught them off.
Some lady,
I might've been a stolen car.
It was something like super sketchy,
but she,
she crashed into him.
He wiped,
she never stopped and he just got tow up
all of his side,
his legs,
his arm.
He just got severely jacked.
Yeah,
there is.
God Damn.
Yeah.
Dean del Rey living life.
There's a,
um,
there's a picture of the actual wound if
you could find it.
He put up the actual wound on his,
uh,
especially on his back inside.
It's really bad.
I mean he fucking.
I mean,
if I'm going to crash,
I want to be because of my error,
not some random lady not seeing me on
meth.
Yeah,
it ain't.
No,
it's not in there.
It's a,
there's a picture of it.
Oh well the worst.
But anyway,
all that white shit all over his side.
Those bandages.
I mean,
that's how big the,
the fucking giant tear is.
It goes.
His skin is fucked up for a good solid
foot and a half.
How funny is this?
And so in the NFL,
NBA,
Nhl motorcycles are illegal.
Once you sign that contract,
you cannot drive a motorcycle.
I'm sure there's guys that have them,
but legally it will void your contract
with the UFC.
You can win a motorcycle.
They give you motorcycles.
That's because of the deal with Harley.
I get it.
And Weird.
Yeah.
Well they're also like,
I don't know.
I mean you got to think of who was
running the UFC.
Right?
It was owned by two guys,
the fertittas that were independently
map,
very,
very wealthy already and very wise
business and they were fans,
so they just decided,
fuck this,
let's just try it.
Let's try and make this work.
Try to make it real.
They hired Dana fucking white to be the
president who was crazy and it all
worked.
It was going to give away.
It was like said.
It's great.
Like his craziness is part of the reason
why it's so appealing.
Like when Oscar de la Hoya was talking
shit about the mayweather,
Mcgregor fight and he and he goes,
well,
he was like,
lol.
Is this guy sniffing coke again?
I love that.
Such a,
such a role.
He didn't need to even go into the cross
dressing.
No.
Yeah,
you're right.
Jack could coulda gotten nasty came with
that,
the sniffing coke.
A lot of people don't come,
but don't tell him,
don't make us make the UFC with the
whatever.
10 million followers,
blast a picture in high heels and went
out without him having to do it because
if it's an obvious second thing and you
say the first thing and be real mild,
everybody else would pick up the slack,
I assume.
Did you see a dose?
Dos?
Yeah.
At dose.
Back to see it.
The graphic he made of triple g Canelo
and Osceola was in the middle as a cross
dresser.
He didn't want to me with a fanny pack
on.
It's Jesus Christ.
Jesus Christ.
That's funny.
Oh my God.
Oscar.
Oscar,
Shut the fuck up.
Please.
Oscar was smart though because with the
all the hyper mayweather,
Mcgregor,
he would go on and shit on it.
Write Shit on the fight.
Just to hype up his fight though.
Go to that nate and nick.
Picture.
That's everyone's on steroids.
Go Scroll up.
Scroll up to the top whole.
Everybody is on steroids.
What a great picture.
They might be right.
Yeah,
they might be right.
You know what I started watching last
night,
I don't know if you'd say an ICARUS or a
car wreck on Netflix.
Yes.
It's all about doping and this,
uh,
this guy is helping the Russian
team.
There was one estimate that it was
somewhere in the high nineties of
Russian athletes are on performance
enhancing drugs.
That make sense that,
that.
That's my thing with this whole Jon
Jones stuff,
like I go back and forth.
I'm going to quote our friend Eddie
Bravo.
When you look into it,
when you look into it,
that Toronto,
like so many guys article came out
today,
I think I'm Fox Fox sports are came out
today of this guy who was a minor league
baseball player and he's a pro now and
he's tested twice for it,
positive and a third time and he's
waiting to see if he gets banned for
life because three strikes.
You're out in baseball fan for life and
they're saying the how many guys in
baseball get tests hot for this Toronto
Ball?
And they say in GNC,
they have 47 products at GNC that this
can show up us.
Wow.
I know.
So I saw that.
I'm like,
Oh fuck yeah,
but wait a minute.
He's not supposed to be taking anything.
You're talking about a guy who's already
lost his ability to make a living from
Mexican Dick Pills.
Like why would he ever just take
something off the shelf at Gnc?
Well,
we're,
we're not giving the Guy Kudos because
he's the smartest tool in the shed.
Sharp,
what I say,
smartest tool in the shed.
Tools.
A smart to smoke a little weed.
You know what I'm saying?
Like he might've been like,
oh,
I need energy.
Give me this.
What is that?
She Pi on the bolts out of his neck and
he takes that dude.
The truth is,
I would never do steroids.
I put that on my children.
I put that on my heavenly father.
He did not bring heavenly father.
I love how we capitalize heavenly father
because for sure in fact,
read.
You don't want to go to hell spec
aspect.
I'm Jones thirties facing up,
man.
Imagine if he comes back at 34 and still
fucks everybody,
but he's 260 pounds at heavyweight.
Fuck all this cut and wait.
Just just go on a power lift and rampage
for the next four years.
Keep your body in shape.
Still Fuck everybody up at heavyweight.
But if you look at that Tran of ball man
and see how much per how many guys test
hot for it and they're like,
what the fuck?
It's not in there.
I can see Jones argument a little bit.
I know I go back and forth and I'm off
the stream,
but when I see that and I see how big of
an issue it is in baseball and Minor
League Baseball,
Usada and the commission might be like,
fuck,
look at all these guys,
man,
we got real issue here.
Maybe did fuck up.
So then I think there's no way to give
them for years,
but I realize now I haven't heard of
anybody else tested positive for the
stuff in the UFC.
Have you?
Is it the same stuff?
Frank Mir test positive for you?
This is the other thing.
Usually if a guy tests hot for something
out of one of those major camps,
other guys can test hot for the same
stuff unless he's getting it straight
from the power lifter guys.
Yeah.
Whereas NFL brothers didn't.
Frank Mir eat kangaroo.
Those like tainted kangaroo meat,
Bro was at the worst argument for
people.
I mean,
you're the smartest tool in the shed.
Some people eat kangaroo,
but it's not common table fair in
Australia.
No,
fuck no.
I was just in Australia doing the
kangaroo burger.
The venison beef eating.
Yeah,
but he didn't say what he was flagged
for.
My favorite part,
however,
he was still given a maximum punishment
by.
You saw the,
I think as he claimed,
he listed numerous potential sources for
the positive test including eating
kangaroo meat while in Australia.
You saw it as like,
what out of here.
That's the best you got.
We've heard a bunch of shit,
but that's all you got.
Boy.
You know what's interesting?
It's like how much does it help?
How much like what you think about like
what these guys are doing.
I mean definitely steroids help right to
steroids make you a better athlete.
They allow you to recover,
let's say 10 percent better.
Yeah.
It's hard to tell though,
because could John beat Daniel cormay
without that small dosage of Toronto?
Yes,
he could do.
That's what DC was saying.
He was like,
the guy doesn't need to do it.
He's super talented.
Doesn't need to do it.
I know.
That's why when you look at the
evidence,
you're like,
why this small amount of Trento ball and
you see all the other guys tested
positive for it.
How much would this really help him?
And he risked all this to take something
piss hot and it's really not helping
that much.
And then where do we stop?
So right now we want to enlist.
And I had been the fucking poster boy of
making fun of John on this stuff.
But in all seriousness,
we're do.
We'd say,
all right,
most guys are doing it because there's
this heard Luke Thomas talking about it.
Uh,
they uh,
a water right.
Sat in water.
Yeah.
What is the Big One?
I think in 2007 they did this survey of
athletes including fires that were going
overseas and competing and they,
they ask them at,
at,
at a kind of under the radar how many
guys are doing performance enhancing
drugs.
It was an alarming number,
like 78 percent.
And that's people,
you know.
I bet it would be a little higher than
that.
Yeah.
So like,
you know what I'm saying?
So we're,
we're,
we're gonna Tarnish John's name and he's
not the greatest of all time,
but it's like,
okay,
but then you'll pay to watch over him
fight.
You pay to watch vitor Belfort fight,
you know,
like we don't know exactly who's doing
what.
Right?
But if overeem becomes a champ,
I guarantee you,
if he pisses hot as a champ,
people turned on him to know I get it.
But he,
he's,
he's tested for way worse things than
John has,
but he hasn't.
He,
we tested for testosterone,
right?
Didn't he?
It was just testosterone.
Oh my God.
I had elevated testosterone levels.
Bane.
I mean the same shit when he was Uber
Room.
That's more than testosterone.
But he,
but he tested positive for that,
didn't he?
And he said a doctor gave him a shot.
Wasn't that like the whole deal at some
doctor's shoulder at for?
I know they don't.
I don't,
but let's just think about what they are
like.
So he tested positive for testosterone,
I believe.
Well if you just pause for that.
And if you had a exemption that means
his levels were on that feed doorbell
for Nate Marquardt Shit where they test.
You're like,
holy fuck man,
how are you now?
It's one of the other guys.
He's one of the first guys pop by Usada
I believe he was also the one who
remember he ran away.
Oh that's right.
Got to go.
Literally sprinted to his car that he
got.
Daniel got a big man run.
Yeah.
And then we had to come back.
He ran to his car.
He asked them after like a post or a
preflight pr thing.
He's like,
Oh shit.
And then ran like,
you know how he runs in the octagon?
He was like doing that and so got away
and he got in his car and drove off.
Yeah.
What happens?
You get in serious trouble,
right?
Fuck yeah.
Someone convinced them to come back.
Probably Dana was like,
what the fuck happened with vandelay and
vandelay for life?
The social life.
I don't think that was use out of
though.
I feel like that was Nevada.
The Nevada commission.
They're the same ones.
You want a band nate for letter.
Nick for life and fucking told Connor.
He owes him $2,000,000
and then he has shoot commercial
$150,000
and and shoot a commercial and what?
Fuck you.
I'm not finding any commercial.
Yeah.
Do you know that?
What was the commercial and
anti-bullying commercial pace?
Hundred $50,000.
Shoot this commercial for free.
Why would I.
Why would I do an anti bullying
commercial?
When you're bullying me,
you're bullying me into doing an anti
bullying commercial or conscious.
We're like,
all right,
well cool.
I'll do the commercial,
but I'm gonna give you.
My rate is about 2 million commercial
right now.
I need about 100.
One point 7 million.
That's why I need you guys all meet
that,
so I'll pay the fine,
but you don't mean one point seven to
the commercial.
There's a lady in Nevada state athletic
commission is very mean.
Know that one lady.
Think of that your job,
but I've been to,
I forget who was a.
was it John John?
Was it Nick Diaz?
It might've been Nick Diaz,
but just the scolding that she was given
one of the fighters while this was all
going down when they were going over
some sort of a positive like you know,
because they're government officials,
you know,
so they feel like they have this power
and they,
it becomes like a tyranny.
They're not nice.
Like you don't have a personal
relationship with this guy.
You shouldn't have personal issues like
just stern faced anger in your voice.
You're in like some sort of a
competition to convict someone and to
punish them go thing.
Absolutely.
Yes.
It's not like,
look,
they're there can absolutely be like
what?
Say what you want about the Golden
Snitch,
right?
Novitsky.
I like it.
So when I spray snitch,
that's a positive.
It's a fun thing to say,
but someone gave me a golden snitch.
Toilets,
you know,
from a Harry Potter.
No others.
Golden snitch to Harry Potter.
Carry on.
The Novitsky is never angry about it.
Never emotional about it.
Very factual.
Like when he describes what a thing,
what's not casting judgment,
he's not being mean.
He's just saying this is what we have,
this is how we know he's doing his job.
The Guy Catch John with this trend of
bull shit.
God,
I hope that happens.
He's not doing any of that.
Also your realized when they brought on
Novitsky is day.
We're trying to paint the picture to
sell it for the most money possible to
be taken serious.
So you signed this huge reebok
endorsement deal,
you know,
you start doing pump and dump,
is that what you're saying?
It's got to pump it and then the,
the and then frank and Lorenzo just sold
the remaining shares too.
Like we're really out.
Someone was just telling me about how
they do that with businesses.
Like some businesses are not operating
just to try to make a profit.
They're operating to sell.
Yes.
And I went why it's.
And then this one guy was telling me
that his friend had a business that was
operating that way,
but then it didn't sell,
the sell fell apart and then they have
to change the business plan and then
start making it a business to make
money.
Like what the fuck are you talking about
with the fertittas?
I mean you're talking straight maverick
when it comes to business.
So with all all they have going on,
they don't need the UFC do well if that
doesn't help his mind thing,
I mean shit.
And right now they look at it and as a
business.
So let's take these steps with the
strict test and get fucked guys down the
road.
Don't care reebok this don't care.
That's not our deal.
This is what's going to make it look
best for buyers.
That's what we're doing for billy.
And Go fuck yourselves.
How fun fell is just genius strategy.
Really,
really teach it at Harvard with Dana.
Then the fertittas.
Did the project teach at Harvard?
Yeah.
Really think about it that way in terms
of I could just a giant sum of money to
be earned.
You only look at as they earned it too
because you think about like where the
business was before they came along and
how they were 40 plus million dollars in
debt.
When they filmed the ultimate fighter,
they were losing so much fucking money.
Just hand over fist,
losing money and there and at one point
Lorenzo would call Dana and said,
let's sell it.
Try to find some buyers in the morning.
Then he woke up in the morning,
change his mind.
It's like,
fuck that to him.
We're going to keep it.
I mean that's how much money they were
losing it.
Not a lot of people would have done
that.
Depends how much money I have in the
bank.
Yeah,
but even if with a lot of money in the
bank,
you can't just keep chewing through
money.
You will,
you know,
you're $40,000,000.
That means a couple years,
year $100,000,000
in like you're going to get that hundred
million dollars back.
Not very likely.
How bout their cousin bought the Houston
Rockets for two point $2,000,000,000.
That family is fucking falling.
Hashtag ball it Hashtag ball and I
stopped talking to deb needs a loan for
two years.
Yeah,
Johnny does need alone.
He to someone.
Nice.
It tell Johnny doesn't need 14 houses.
Johnny settled down in a night.
I mean,
what kind of speed are you want?
Will you sign the mortgage for that
14,000?
You're like fuck,
just killing it.
But that 14 towns like holy shit,
what do you do with you don't do
anything with them.
That's the problem.
So he go thing.
Look at that.
Johnny Depp's,
Kentucky Horse Farm fails to sell at
auction.
I wish
that bitch go for two point nine.
He just did it.
Just happen no matter what.
Like lookup,
scroll up and look at that picture of
him.
Does it just happen no matter what?
That after awhile you almost become like
a caricature.
You become one of the characters.
Yeah,
I mean you,
you paint yourself as the odd fellow
who's she know on the outside for the
longest time and then all of a sudden
you become this blockbuster guy because
johnny didn't for the longest time you
should talk about because he's a very
respected actor.
Hell yeah.
And he used to talk about how he doesn't
want to be Mr blockbuster guy and then
he gets on pirates of the Caribbean.
They probably just thinks it's a cool
part,
but it's still disney,
you know,
Disney.
But it seems like a cool part.
I mean,
so it was alice in wonderland that
didn't fuck his life up.
Alice in wonderland,
which is great.
Good movie.
He was a great movie and he was awesome
and amazing as the mad hatter.
I was the mad hatter for Halloween.
I dressed up,
but he's,
you know,
he's a legit,
brilliant actor and then all of a sudden
he's in this blockbuster that's a Disney
thing.
So all of a sudden he becomes this like
huge international,
just top of the food chain superstar got
a Jack Sparrow tat to you.
Here's the jacks.
You hit the spiro on his forearm.
He.
How would you feel like if I had a fear
factor tattoo on my leg,
a big MTV center right here.
I wasn't on MTV.
That's right.
And See,
but if it was on my thigh and it just
said failure is not a factor for me on
your ribs.
Fear not.
Oh,
and you pull up in that slingshot real
dick move.
I would have to gold plate it.
Yeah.
I felt like that slingshots missing some
bling.
I needed to be Shinier.
Yeah.
Sometimes.
I don't know man with Johnny Depp.
He just got too into it.
Well,
I just think you know,
when you're on something that you don't
enjoy,
it's one thing that does happen.
I happened to a lot of people on bad
sitcoms that are making a ton of money.
They just start going crazy and buying
all these things because they need these
things to make them feel good because
their work doesn't.
At least.
Yeah.
At least I'm working,
but I'm going to get that new Ferrari
Ferrari for whatever the fuck it is.
Four 59.
Is that the newest one?
I'm whatever it is on the top of the
food and shit,
dope ass Ferrari.
I mean maybe you just like Ferrari's,
but then you know,
maybe you just buy a yacht maybe by this
and maybe you buy that and then you sign
a deal to do the show that you don't
even want to do anymore,
but you have to sign that deal now
because you've got a $12,000,000
mansion in Malibu overlooking the.
I think.
I think done Johnny Depp.
Anyone his life go now after four house
he goes,
God,
I might chill out on the fifth one,
man.
Not really even staying the other ones.
This is just a theory.
No one was like 10 bro.
I think we should take a break.
This is 14.
This is just a theory,
but I think that one of the things about
a guy like Johnny Depp is
if you want,
and I don't know this amber heard lady
who was living with.
She seems nice enough to me.
Very beautiful.
Matter of fact,
I read somewhere that she was like some
computer program said that she was the
most beautiful person alive.
He didn't even make sense to me.
Right.
Like symmetrical.
I guess.
Her eyes or something.
I don't know.
Yeah.
Well my computer's different.
My thought is when she's beautiful
school,
but my thought is when you're a dude
like him and you got a girl like that in
like,
you know,
you're,
you're having a great time.
Like one of the great things to do is
probably just buy a ton of shit and just
impress this girl and just take her on
this journey.
The goal,
what kind of once 14,
how crazy he's doing.
Well,
he didn't.
He didn't buy 14 houses with her.
I'm sure you only bought a few eight,
but he's going crazy.
He's buying all kinds of shit.
Like she loves that,
but this is what I think.
I think things just escalate.
Think things just escalate,
spiral out of control and they just get
you get away from yourself.
Next thing you know,
you're standing on the fucking red
carpet with eyeliner on and silver
chains and your insured is opening the
chest.
I need.
You're acting like you're on some crazy
indie rock band and you're 53.
You become a caricature Jack Sparrow,
you start dressing like the what you
think people want to see like the
instead of you and you kind of forget
who you are.
Maybe.
I mean,
I'm not just saying just him.
I'm not.
Jim Carey's latest interview.
Yes,
I was going to bring that up.
He's playing,
he's playing.
He's,
but he's getting ready for a character
who acts like that.
He's an character that moment.
That's not Jim Carrey.
He's doing.
He's also my favorite human being,
one of them,
but he's playing a character in that so
he has a new role
who he's playing,
but the guys,
he just signed it.
They announced yesterday signed for a
new show on showtime where he's playing
a comedian that's freaking out later in
life or something like that
and that's what he's doing now.
He was a part of the whole,
I'm dying up here thing.
He's a producer,
so he's playing a character of a
comedian who's freaking out who freaks
out like that.
Like that's a typical to that role.
So that's kind of what he's doing there.
He was supposed to play,
or at least there's a rumor that he was
supposed to play Terence Mckenna in some
sort of biography.
The fame
psychedelic adventure,
tourists turns Mckenna be great on this.
Amazing on it.
She is Andy do frame.
I'm sorry.
Andy Kaufman painting too,
like,
Hey,
he's got some really cool painting that
he's been doing recently.
It's a real cool little piece that
doesn't look recent.
It looks a lot younger there.
I think this has been been prior two or
three year time period that Scott made
over this six minute video.
Do you ever see his dog?
Cool stuff,
man.
I know he's a sick painter.
That thing with the neon and black.
Go back to that for a second.
Jamie.
The thing with the neon and black that
he was just super talented.
That's really cool looking dude.
Did you see his daughter when she was on
American
idol and the poor girls getting ready to
sing?
You know,
the biggest night of her life,
like let's go ahead and wire it.
Ended her famous father,
Jim Carrey,
gyms all.
Hey,
he's like on skype.
He's like,
hey baby,
good luck that I take it away.
Little carry.
I'm like,
Oh God,
what a shitty moment man.
For her,
like let her have her moment,
man,
to bring it to your dad's Jim Carrey.
Television man,
that's how they do it.
They go 100 percent cheese on.
Don't go at all this.
They want to appeal to Joe Slack,
jaw sitting on his easy chair at home
just like this.
I feel like even Joe Slack jaw doesn't
like that bullshit.
There's enough people that do and enough
people that will tolerate it.
See Ratings Beg to differ.
Well,
they don't really.
They do still have good ratings.
It's just a tired show.
Well,
it depends what it is.
Like if you think about most shows like
ratings are down in general,
but look at things that are more organic
and real,
right?
Like your show,
like look,
other podcasts,
like other shows on youtube,
stuff like that where it's not so
bullshit producer Tony,
how to feel what opinions you should
have,
but they're stuck in that model because
they have commercials.
They're stuck in that model because they
have to those commercials that they have
to interrupt their show with like
everything has to kind of wrap up every
few minutes.
How many minutes did they go without
commercials on a regular intelligence
bubble?
Guppies let you play the full thing,
but it's like bubble guppies.
My kids love it.
Oh my kid's obsessed.
They loved it when they were little.
Let's find that out.
I get on at 22 minutes,
seven minutes or so,
every seven minutes.
Roughly every seven minutes for a
sitcom.
And do you think they do the same for an
hour show?
The brakes are different depending on
the show,
but it's like 12 minutes,
20 minutes.
They're always going to be.
You can never get real deep.
What if they frontloaded it like
podcasts and does no one's gonna.
Watch that part.
No one's watching them anyways.
Sometimes they do that.
Like this show is brought to you
commercial free.
By then you don't get it,
but they still announced that every
phone.
That's probably the way to do it.
That's probably the way to do it or
product placement is a way to do it.
Just don't be gross product placement
stuff.
Yeah,
you just can't be gross about it.
It's like the team and someone is
drinking a coke show a coke.
It's nothing wrong with that.
As long as it makes sense for the scene.
You know what I mean?
Like the.
The idea that you're going to put stuff
in there that doesn't belong for product
placement.
Well that's gross,
but if you could figure out some way
where it's organic,
I think that model is terrible.
It's so hilarious like that.
Yeah.
He's tough,
powerful rob lowe,
but dimey very handsome,
but I,
I think they're going to start
gravitating towards more that realness.
They have to smell bullshit now.
Yeah,
but Joe Slack jaw sit in his arm chair
in rural Illinois.
Sorry to pick on you,
Illinois.
Just to pick the state could say
Massachusetts Montana,
but he's just sitting there and he's got
his mouth open and maybe that appeals to
him and maybe you'll tolerate it and
then there's that whole spectrum in
between.
True of people that like this.
My favorite show,
I love it when people kept saying,
I fucking love it.
I love it when they get up there and
they try to sing and that voice cracks
and you know,
they're embarrassed.
Oh,
I made me feel so good.
People do lot.
I used to love it when I'd watch
American idol,
my favorite part was the people that saw
me to those.
That's my.
When they get all serious,
that's like,
hey,
I gotta go,
alright,
you're good.
I'm out.
Whatever happened to that lady who was
like,
she looked like she was like inner
fifties teeth.
Ralph's,
Susan Boyle.
That's America.
Got Talent factor in England.
It was,
it expectation.
What happened is that Simon cowel guys
on everything,
he's ridiculous.
And I heard,
I heard she got bond,
crazy bond.
Those black girls.
Um,
I heard,
not that that matters,
but it,
um,
right.
Um,
I heard Susan Boyle,
I got paid bank and it was like,
fuck this fame thing.
Well,
really it's almost like you,
some of them laying on her teeth.
Britain's got talent.
So great.
She was two.
I remember when they,
they just didn't expect it and she came
out and just smashed it.
Mastered.
I remember was when I was like,
Whoa,
that is crazy that she can sing that
good today.
Well she,
hold on,
she just turned 50.
She's my age.
Yeah.
How's that possible?
Well,
that's crazy.
That scares the fucking shit out of me.
You're aging like cheese.
She's aging like fruit.
Wow.
She got a use it or lose it baby.
She's using her voice man.
Yeah,
but voice around.
I'm sure she's still probably singing
here and there just isn't like tour.
I know she kind of bounced out of the
spotlight though.
Well if she lives simple,
you know,
or she made a ton of money.
It's a weight loss photos.
Oh,
she's 56 son Kenny Bro.
She can't,
she won.
She was 50.
We'll see what our program looks like in
six years.
Talks about that shit.
I look like her.
Yeah.
All those talent shows are fucking weird
man.
You know America's got talent and what's
the one with Jennifer Lopez is on one of
them now.
Oh,
she has a dance show.
Right?
And then that country music guys on with
that other girl with Katy Perry hosted
our painter like $25,
million bucks to content,
some crazy amount of money to host.
And he was like,
hell no.
He would be onto Donald Trump.
Hates black people.
How about Donald Trump going at espn?
Yeah,
but he's wrong.
He's sober.
Leaving.
No,
there were ratings are up.
Like,
that's so crazy.
Returns aren't up.
Are they down?
Yeah,
it does.
Because of him.
People leaving cable and somebody said
that the ratings are up though.
The recent ratings.
Maybe.
Maybe I just read things and I just go
with the NFL is back.
I mean they're just up because the
summer's over.
But in general they're down.
Just in Esp.
They had all those cuts,
had killed a bunch of people.
Budget cuts.
He cut so much talent.
But that was it.
Oh,
what's her name?
Jamal came out was like,
on her.
Granted she's an employee of Espn,
but on her personal social media on
twitter,
she was saying he's a racist,
stuff like that.
He's a white supremacist.
And uh,
she said he's the worst president of her
lifetime and a lot of people said that
it's just the fact that she is a public
media figures.
Everybody wanted her fired.
And this is like,
it's weird outrage culture we live in,
right?
She's entitled to Her fucking opinion.
Now the thing is,
does espn want people on their network
being all political and talking about
shit like that on their social media?
And do they have rules about that?
Because some companies do have rules
about that,
whether you agree with those rules or
not.
Some companies do have rules on what you
can and can't say on social media.
But here's the thing that I found
fascinating.
Donald trump didn't talk about her,
talked about espn.
I thought that was a chicken shit thing
to do.
Like there was a woman who works for
espn.
Oh yes,
that's true.
That's what I'm saying.
There's a woman that works for Espn,
a very specific person,
not espn,
you know,
telling lies should apologize or
whatever the fuck he wrote.
He didn't call her out.
I think he's,
he's knows you can't do it,
especially not now and everybody thinks
you're a white supremacist.
Can't pick on the black lady he picked
on Rosie O'donnell all day long.
Right?
He'll go after everybody else.
Call him a loser girl.
Miss America and her little speech
slammed him too.
She said a whole bunch of shit about him
and you see this gentleman is that Kirk
Cameron looks like Kirk Cameron.
That's homeboy from survivor.
Who is it from survivor from survive.
Some bachelor Bachelorette.
You ever seen him getting roasted and
when he was accused of cheating on his
girl classic.
Anyways,
yeah,
that Miss America,
she said Shit about trump and no one's
going after her necessarily.
She's quote unquote gaining millions of
fans right now.
Right.
But what's interesting is I watched a.
someone posted something about Anthony
Bordain.
Anthony Bourdain was caught by TMZ or
the airport.
Okay.
Very quick.
Sort of silly interview.
They asked them a question,
if you had to cook for Kim Jong Un and
Donald Trump,
what would you serve?
And he goes,
hemlock.
And he walks away.
It's a joke.
It's a fucking one line is also funny.
He's a funny guy.
He says a one liner and all these people
are saying,
should he be fired from CNN for saying
that he would poison trump if he had,
you know,
good luck to secret service is going to
contact you,
and so I look at his fucking twitter
page man,
and it's crazy.
All these fucking psychos are telling
the secret service.
They should investigate it.
CNN,
are you going to fire him like you
fired?
Raise the Azelex people.
Men Outright Co out,
excuse me.
Outrage culture.
People are getting excited
about things being outrageous instead of
just going,
this weed is got me coughing instead of
just looking at it and going,
well,
I don't agree with that.
Fuck that guy.
Or going well,
that was obviously a joke,
which was like the normal person would
do it like affects you.
Like not at all.
Do you really think that Anthony Bordain
wants to fucking poison Donald Trump and
they should lose our jobs?
She's amazing by the way.
She's a beast on its culture.
Outrage culture.
People just decide they can try to
affect something.
And then things start getting ramped up,
the momentum kicks in,
all these other people jump on board and
they get excited about being a part of a
group that wants to get Anthony Bourdain
kicked off the day,
what they want,
some sort of weird direction.
They think they're important enough
where they can get these people fired
and they think if they get together
enough,
they're going to have the power to
affect that person life even believed
there.
Right.
Bunch of pitches.
And I kept saying,
you know,
threatening the life of Potus.
I kept saying,
you got,
what are you talking about?
The king,
you guys are out of your mind.
This is a person with a terrible job
saying that game of thrones Donald Trump
is a person with a job that no one
wants.
Okay.
That's what he is doing a good job at
it.
No,
but is anybody doing a good job at it?
No.
I think Obama was like the best
president we ever had.
And you look at it.
I know people can get mad at me for this
and there's a lot,
a lot of things that I think that he did
that I don't agree with,
like the way went after the press with
the way he promised to protect
whistleblowers,
but he never did like free speech and
people having to give up their sources
was damaged heavily during Obama's
administration.
The use of drones,
unprecedented use of drones,
unprecedented amount of civilian deaths
during his administration.
The question is,
how much of that was his fault?
How much can one man even control?
I mean,
this,
I think it's an impossible fucking job,
but the way he carries himself,
like a person I'd love more than it is
about here,
the way he can enunciate clearly.
He,
he's,
uh,
to me it was like a good representative
of what I would like to see as a calm,
peaceful,
educated American who's smart and he is
just,
he's affable,
he seems friendly and Nice.
He seems like one of us,
he's the first president that kind of
seems like one of us where you could
chill with them and you could have.
I could actually relate to them.
Yes.
They don't Bill Clinton White House and
I don't believe.
I think if I was alone with Clinton,
I probably wouldn't be able to jive with
them.
I just don't think.
Especially if you're alone,
there's a chicken.
The room.
I think it looked right past you.
You'd be like a distraction.
You have to cock block with that room.
Yeah,
I think almost not like a rooster.
I think Clinton's a straight up rooster.
Yeah,
he's in that room.
It was like he just can't help himself.
He's just got that.
She's flinging Dick.
I got time to talk to some fucking old
comedian.
I'm hurting the sligo.
Oh,
you were fat,
but you voted for my grades.
Get the fuck out.
That was a long time ago.
Fuck.
Face to get my deck.
I'd love to talk to you,
but I ain't got that much time.
If you looked at me lately,
motherfucker.
I'm dying.
Okay.
I'm here for you.
Fucking this up,
man.
Hilarious.
That's exactly like,
hey,
have you ever been on Air Force One?
You know,
I still get to use it.
I wonder if they still get to use it.
They get secret service through the rest
of their lives.
How they fly around.
They fly around commercial.
Although,
uh,
President Carter was on a train like
high five and they're not train a flight
high and everyone,
President Carter was a beautiful person.
That's why you only lasted one term.
You know,
they've negotiated with the hostages in
Iran to make sure that the hostages
weren't released until after Ronald
Reagan was elected president.
Now that is some shady shirt,
dirty shit politics.
You kept Americans imprisoned extra so
that you would look good and they would
be released when this fucking actor with
slick black,
black hair gotta crack a few eggs,
make an omelet man.
It's so.
None of that stuff spreads me when it
comes to politics or none of it.
So it's all business.
Reagan was also the first guy who used
the religious groups of our country to
get elected.
He got them on board with him to let you
got to do well.
He brought in religion to politics and a
lot of ways or made it,
made it popular and obvious that that
was a good choice to align yourself as
being the PR.
Like no president today could be an
atheist.
I don't think I disagree.
Yeah,
because what do they live in for?
They're out there in the White House
when to launch a nuclear bomb.
They think that the end doesn't mean
anything.
Okay.
I'm here for God's heavenly glory.
Well,
what's my heavenly father?
I'm looking over my heavenly father
right now.
What's the percentage of atheists in
the,
in the United States now?
It's higher than ever,
but it's still low.
I don't think so,
man.
Fuck Sakes.
But I think it's less than 30 percent
get,
but you need those if you want to run
for president because people are more
concerned about the Lord than they are
about anything else.
Okay.
Twenty two percent of the US population
is religiously unaffiliated.
Atheist makeup.
Three point one percent ignacious makeup
for percent of the US population.
Two percent.
So it says at 22 percent,
but it says they're not religious.
The religiously unaffiliated.
Those are votes for the theist
president,
but I don't know if that means
religiously unaffiliated like they could
believe in God,
but they just don't belong to a certain
church we get in those votes.
Okay.
Two,
14 general.
Yeah.
Those.
Those votes I think would go towards a
religious person.
If the person go back,
please,
if the person believes in God said to 14
General Social Survey reported that 21
percent of Americans had no religion
with three percent being atheist and
five percent agnostic.
That's not even as much as I thought.
It's not that many people,
Ma'am are.
You cannot.
I just don't
think I shouldn't say this.
I shouldn't say this in a blanket term
because maybe it can happen,
but I just think it's not a good
strategy if you're just trying to get
into office because trump was never
religious and now he talks about God all
the time.
Now it's all,
you know,
God this and God that it's a strategy.
I mean,
it's like you almost.
It's like words that you have to say
like,
Ma'am and Sir that don't know.
It totally makes sense to you.
Well,
did you,
I heard the,
uh,
I think the governor,
or maybe it's the mayor,
Florida,
when the hurricane was about to hit,
I'm watching just balls deep in it on
the hurricane,
stuff that he's,
he goes,
you know,
your money's great but big C and you
just pray for us.
Just keep praying for us.
That's all we need.
We need to pray before this thing hits.
I'm like,
dude,
you better figure shit out like that.
It sounds good.
And he was everything.
Just keep praying for us.
Just pray.
That's all I asked.
Everyone here,
pray for us.
I'm like,
man,
you need more than that brother.
I made it work,
Bro.
Did you see this going around yesterday
afternoon,
facebook and got in trouble after some
people were digging into the advertising
thing that was going around also
yesterday with the algorithms that
people are looking into the Russian.
I think someone uncovered that $100,000
had been paid to either some Russian ad
agency or something.
I didn't follow the exact story,
but digging into that,
they found this story that Jew haters
and an algorithm created,
uh,
this tag two people and labeled them as
Jew haters,
and so someone could buy a targeted ad
to them and what they were,
I guess they were assuming is that trump
people did it or they were.
Hold on,
hold on.
You're not saying this right.
Sorry.
Explain this more clearly.
So someone could put an ad on your page.
No,
no,
no.
A lot of hypothetical.
Yeah.
I could put out an ad if I was a buying
for Hillary,
for instance,
in this situation or for trump and
targeted towards people that were
labeled as Jew haters.
We're labeled as within facebook.
Okay.
So there's four.
So facebook has a category of Jew
haters.
They're saying it was done by a computer
algorithm,
not by,
excuse me,
by a person.
It just sort of happened.
What?
Yeah.
And that's what this is.
It's still being uncovered right now.
This just hit yesterday,
Jew haters was trending on twitter.
Now
what is going on?
Facebook advertising the best that there
is like for anyone because of the
algorithms,
because you can pick out a certain
demographic.
If you have a show in San Francisco or
in La,
you can literally pick everyone in a 10
mile radius and they will see that that,
but that is such a crazy eight or figure
it out.
Yeah,
but what a crazy thing.
The idea that you could reach a group of
Jews.
How about don't allow those people to be
their reaching them with it.
On this same answer,
in the same vein,
I was going to ask you a second ago when
you said you were looking at Anthony
Bourdain's twitter account.
You saw a bunch of hate.
Yeah.
Do you think that that could be bots Bot
let me correct that.
It wasn't Anthony Bourdain's twitter
account.
It was a under the tweet by TMZ for show
the video.
Then there was all even that even,
but I'm sure they probably went this.
It even easier to do.
Then you could specifically by by that
hate for cheap,
25 bucks,
10 bucks,
but they also hire people that might be
multiple twins that mean by the,
by that,
hey,
you could send the messages that you
want and you could set up a couple of
keywords and 500 accounts.
We'll just start sending those messages,
fake accounts,
so accounts.
How many people are going to go look
through to find out how many of those
accounts are fake,
right?
Do you have to write out the tweet for
those fig fig?
It'll fill in the word
holy shit.
So how do you know if someone is doing
that?
Great question.
They're fighting that on youtube or
facebook,
twitter,
the finding it everywhere and they're in
it,
right?
How do they know?
Well,
they,
they can tell by the algorithms in the
computer.
Programmers can figure it out,
can make fake accounts for sure,
and that's why I went twitter,
instagram,
they can do a flush of all those Bot
accounts and so you'll see a lot of
people's followers like Kim Kardashians.
She lost like 3 million because there
were a bunch of Bot accounts.
Fake accounts.
Well,
there's so many fake shit.
I thought she lost three minute when
people saw her real ass.
Good Lord.
Really?
Did you see that?
No,
I've seen the port now.
Did you see that Mexican disaster?
No,
she was on the beach in Mexico and she
didn't have her own photographer.
Here's the thing,
do whatever you want.
Don't want to body shame.
But yes I do,
but let me just explain my position on
this.
When she shows,
when she shows all these pictures of her
giant perfect ass,
she's showing an extremely unrealistic
representation of a human being.
So what she does is she hires a
photographer to follow her everywhere
and take pictures,
and then they photoshop the shit out of
him.
They cleaned away all the lumps and then
she looks amazing.
Right?
So while she was on the beach,
they were.
They were taking pictures of her and she
didn't know they were there.
That is a dumper that's gross.
That is a thing that's not real.
That is all fat that someone stuffed
into your ass like a giant diaper and
when they smoothed it out and put it on
instagram with all the retouches and
everything like that,
this forces women to like think that
this is possible,
but this is normal.
My Girl's ass beats by the way,
but it's reel to reel and she's got a
body that it makes sense and she makes
her look like Mr.
Burns as like if you have a giant head
and then a tiny little nose like one of
them plastic surgery knows people are
going to go,
hey,
this isn't right.
Like you did something weird.
She's what she's doing is not only not
hot.
You could promise she becomes famous and
then it becomes a thing that people do
down here.
Hold on.
Remember when we're talking about wigs,
we weren't you here when we're talking
about powdered wigs.
Was that you?
As you made a big think about that?
These fucking guys with syphilis that
were losing their hair and started
wearing wigs.
Everybody started shaving their head and
wearing those goddamn countered with
because they looked like those guys.
They wanted to be cool.
You cannot hang on Kim.
Credentialing to make an ass as cool.
My man.
No,
that's not a real class.
She didn't make gas cool.
J Lo made assets way before Kim
Kardashians.
I saw legit,
super legit.
Legit.
That's a real class.
This is a disaster.
This is my problem with Kim Kardashian.
Well not my problem.
Kim Kardashian.
And granted she's influenced a lot of
people and I would not,
I would not kick her out of bed.
I look at those because those pictures,
those pictures are being sent to a
cartoonist,
you know,
whatever.
But um,
they're not real.
The problem is,
is her sister who little sister.
So like my nanny's daughters always
around our house.
She's 12,
she's in seventh grade.
Every most girls,
especially in middle school,
high school.
Everyone looks at Kylie Jenner.
She's a fucking let you sprints Diana.
Like they think she's the shit.
Have you seen what that bitch has gone
through?
Its in saying the plastic surgery said
you're talking complete reconstruction
of her face,
body ass,
titties,
ribs,
completely different person.
Go reconstruct.
It's not Smith shaved her chin down,
yes and cheekbones and make her look
like Kim and hurt us and they cut into
the bone in her jaw when she was 16.
What the fuck are we doing?
But now all these little girls look up
to her like she's this huge role model
and I asked him like why do you,
why?
Why do you like her?
And like just the life.
And then you know,
she,
she comes out with all this stuff.
She has lube aton.
She's driving guy because all of a
sudden they think like that.
Oh that's what I.
that's what I get to big wigs,
big ways.
The same thing.
So same goddamn thing.
And so those dudes wearing wigs that
everybody sees and they think they're
the shit and so they want to copy them.
That's why it's dangerous.
It's dangerous.
Different though it is,
but it's not same fishes but it's,
it's the same theory.
It's the same thing that happens to
people,
but what she's doing is bonkers.
It's,
but it doesn't matter.
It becomes a trend and then people get
sucked into that trend and she becomes
important.
Here's why I'm mad at myself.
I'm not mad at her.
Stop it all though.
I don't want to look at these pictures.
You stop at Jamie.
Jamie,
Jamie.
I'm the one explaining all of it.
He'll come in and Jamie will come into
here.
What happened with beyonce and Jay z?
I'll go,
no,
I'm Jay.
I'm with you,
man.
Did you hear the tweet?
Kanye and Jay z are back together.
Get them as fucking Ritalin,
but with her.
What's.
What's I get why people are going to go.
She's beautiful.
I'm mad at myself being like,
God damn.
She's fine.
She's feeling she's hot.
She's not an ugly woman.
No,
no.
She's sexy now.
You need a young daughter.
Both.
Are you talking about Kim?
Oh,
Kim.
Kim's great.
I'm talking about Kylie who I think
she's 21,
but before you know basic white girl,
average flat ass white girl.
Then now she's this video vixen and I'm
not mad at her and she thinks that ass.
It'd be like a water balloon.
Have you ever felt?
No.
What's it like?
Pretty Glorious.
Really?
A fake one?
No,
no,
no.
Not.
Not if they have implants,
but they can take fat from their stomach
or their size and they inject the fat
and ugly ass no different.
Right.
But when they
walked over to the bathroom and then you
see their ask going back and forth like
a water bed.
Doesn't that freak you out?
It was a.
There was a video of what does that
young age as lately Zalea,
whatever her name is.
There was a video of her shaking her ass
and someone sent it to me.
They go,
dude,
what the fuck is this?
Was it cool?
No.
She's wearing these skin tight pants and
as she's shaking her ass,
it's like you ever try to fuck on a
waterbed?
Yeah,
it's a nightmare.
Yeah.
I had one when I was 21.
It was a disaster and as a kid and then
I swapped it out for one with Baffles,
which is actually pretty bad ass.
A water bed that has.
Yeah.
Baffles are it.
It's not one giant bag.
It's a bunch of tubes.
That makes sense.
When you get in there,
it's pretty firm,
but you feel the cool,
the warm plots.
It's pretty dope but you get and you
could fuck with one of those,
but with the other one it's like trying
to fuck on a whale the fucking night.
It's like trying to fuck while your
paddleboarding is trying to fuck on one
of those.
Fuck the one of those vibrating machine.
It's just a night.
Yeah,
so that's what her ass looks like.
She's shaking her ass and it's going
back and forth and back and forth like
some crazy ass camel thing.
Like you're storing water in Medicaid
thing,
scalable,
showing fruit back,
dooring water in it.
It's like there's something going on.
It doesn't make any sense.
Who is this?
I mean that's fine right there.
That's not the video.
There was a video of her dancing
onstage.
I wish I didn't like that stuff.
Pink Pants.
Yeah,
but this is like,
this is a little amusement as will be
looking at different colors.
It's negative,
you know,
but that,
that that's the culture we live in.
That's what we like or not.
We sir no big titties and disaster and I
don't like it.
I didn't ask that.
I like big cities like crossfit checks.
I like chicks.
The two squats and shit.
I like chicks that looked good.
It looks strong and healthy.
That's what looks good.
Strong,
healthy type of chicks.
Kaolin well he's not here.
Let's leave him out of this.
Callan loves like the big bulky,
like shredded girl who if she had a dick
like,
oh,
that makes sense.
Yeah.
No,
I mean the girls that look like girls,
girls will lift.
Yeah.
When you see their ass,
you know that isn't earned ass.
That's not some fat experiment.
Dr Frankenstein's lab.
I don't have to picture you with a tube
running down your mouth.
Keep you alive,
but you gotTa fucking your noses taped
up and you're lying there with your eyes
rolled back in your head while they
fucking ass.
Like a caulking gun is to both at the
same finish line though.
It's just,
it's not healthy.
They're not as vibrant.
I see a woman that's in shape.
She had some counselors were like,
I'm sure like a man who's in shape.
It's the same thing to people like
people like things that are healthy.
It seems like you're talking about sex,
right?
Well,
sex,
you don't want to have sex with somebody
who's sick.
Right?
You don't want to have sex.
Someone who doesn't feel good,
you don't want to have sex with someone
who's barely making it.
Like if you get a staph infection
because someone's been pumping fat into
your asshole and then all of a sudden
you're feeling feeling sad,
but you still have this big ass.
Is that sexy?
No,
that's not fun.
It's not exciting.
Like you're looking at an unhealthy
persons body.
Like you look at her body like that's
not a working out body.
She hasn't worked out for.
She does because that's a lazy person's
body results and I'm not saying lazy
person like mom,
that is a full time job.
Listen,
if you can't work out,
I'm not blaming you.
If you don't want to work out,
I'm not blaming you,
but if your fucking job is only to be
professional,
hot chick and that's your body,
you better work out.
Yeah,
you got to get on that horse.
At least eat or good.
That's what I'm talking about.
I liked that.
I also love that.
I'd like to talk a Gal who does some
dead lifts.
I like how she's using those path to
cover shins.
Something gross about girls scarred up
shins.
Unless they fight,
unless they do Moitai then it's kind of
even then.
Then it's hot again.
Leave and then gangster ass chick lit.
That's a good picture jamie,
but I feel like bodies should be earned
in the gym.
I mean I just feel like pumping some
stuff into your ass,
but it's a trick.
What about titties?
That's where I vacillate.
Exactly,
but here's the thing,
you can't earn titties.
That's why I let it go,
because you can't earn them.
You can earn an ass.
He kind of subject a little bit.
Little bit.
Almost genetics.
Yeah,
but I mean,
come on,
let's be just be honest,
but we're talking about most.
You can do some squats and deadlifts and
lunges,
build that SMP thing.
How much you could probably affect it.
You put.
You might be able to not be able to get
to Jayla levels,
but I bet you get to pretty perky levels
sometimes.
I don't know.
I don't know what he was doing.
What?
I don't know how they're working out.
I don't know if they got a good trainer.
I don't know if they lift heavy,
they'll have to see the program.
Yeah.
You'd have to see their program.
You have to find out what their diet is
because people make a lot of goddamn
excuses.
Genetics or genetic,
like Jamie's not going to get as big as
fucking Yoel Romero.
It's just not in the cards.
One hundred percent.
True.
Right.
Genetics do come into factor,
but when you just blame genetics for
everything,
it's like,
okay,
but did you work?
How hard did you work?
Did you try?
Did you advance at all,
like where was your starting point?
Where are you at now and how much effort
did you put in along the way?
You're cool with titties because that's
a real woman's ass.
She is so real.
Forty held sheedy 85 years old.
Fifty one.
The good thing about that,
you can shoot loads in there all day
long and nothing's happening all day
long.
No one's home game over.
They're about to have a kid or to.
Everybody's trying to.
You're all practicing.
I would try.
I saw that the,
uh,
the vine,
I was like,
I would in pregnant her right now and
figuring out was probably still viable
for another four or five years.
Her genetics.
She is a straight smoke show.
Yeah.
That's superior genetics.
She Never Latina superior genetics.
Correct.
But also hard work.
She works out hard,
man.
You ever see her dance routines and all
this stuff that she does?
She's carving out hard hundred percent.
Yeah.
I mean that's,
she's a professional hot chick was also
a singer who's also an actress.
She has talent.
These other groups come out,
do not write,
but she also works hard.
See,
that's what I think.
That's sexy.
Yeah,
and that's what I think.
Like if you want to spy,
like if you want to be a man,
right?
You wouldn't be built like the rock.
Right.
I see the rock on the fucking instagram
in the gym.
Every God damn day we're here.
We're getting it done.
You know,
nobody works harder.
Alright.
Have a good day.
Everybody.
He's like all inspiring and shit.
He's shocked to the fucking gills.
He looks huge,
right?
That isn't clearly,
but that's an earned physique.
Does not stuffing fucking silicon plates
in his muscles to puff them up.
He's not injecting synthol in there to
look like one of them crazy
possibilities and other stuff though.
It's a four,
but he's working out.
He's working out hard.
I don't know what his test levels are.
The probably elevated,
but the point is even with drugs that's
accessible.
See,
it's still hard work,
but yes,
it's still a real muscle.
Yes.
Where I draw the line look of girls
could take a steroid that made them grow
an ass through.
Wouldn't be a flat ass on the planet
Earth Gangland.
There would be no girls.
The difference between girls and men is
that because there's a lot of guys don't
want to take steroids.
They're like,
fuck that.
I'm not going to hold.
Some don't.
If steroids existed for women's assets,
who would be as common as botox?
They would all be jamming it.
It'd be like here die.
Every girl would have a fat ass.
If you could afford it.
If they could figure out a way to break.
Like I said,
I was driving on the street the other
day.
I saw a sign that said Botox.
$12.
God,
Doug,
that's a deal for sure.
Don't go there.
You Bell's Palsy.
He had a stroke.
Apparently.
Like a very tricky process.
You've got to know when you're shooting
that stuff.
Fuck yeah.
I saw a deal for a lazy guy surgery by
one kid,
one in Venice by no,
you cannot do that.
You cannot skimp on your eyeballs.
Please go to a reputable laser eye
surgeon.
I only get one next week.
You don't want to deal on a deal on ice
surgery or surgery.
Implants or tattoos,
you hear about that one person that got
arrested,
they were given.
People ask jobs and they pretended to be
a doctor and they weren't a doctor and
they were shooting all kinds of stuff
into people's assets.
There wasn't cement cement into the ass
of these people.
Oh my God,
God did wrong with.
People are crazy.
They're suiting rental form.
Kardashians.
I blamed kindergarten.
She
because that lady is working at
walgreens like,
fuck,
I look like Kim Kardashian grab her ass
and you literally feel a rock of some
and they're like,
what do you have a given tumor?
This cancer is this fucking kidney stone
that didn't pass lodged up and your ass
cheeks nuts,
man.
In many ways through your hip just
lodged itself.
But here's the thing with tidies,
I'm all about them.
I'm all about implants.
We go back to the thing.
You cannot earn big breasts.
You can't earn them.
So what about guys with calf implants
that you celebrate that?
No.
John was Needham.
Jon Jones needs.
I mean he doesn't need them.
How about that?
Well,
Jon Jones has the calf have an ankle and
he doesn't,
he doesn't care,
not like a Samoan ankle.
Here's the capital of like a white girl.
And by the way,
there's a glorious picture of Mark Hunt
with a fanny pack that I put on
instagram today.
And a whole cogan stash you.
How about that fanny pack though?
Pretty gangster.
So please by support.
Mark Hunt's new book is out now.
Um,
yeah,
look at that.
It's a fucking camel.
Fanny pack.
Extra points.
He sells gangster.
He's the most gangster guy ever.
I do love that.
Stash.
You know,
I saw was a scary gentlemen an article
though,
an interview they did with him.
That was a very,
uh,
sad and disappointed.
You know,
like he was telling us.
No,
no,
no.
That was terrible task.
So rough scale overcame that.
It wasn't about that.
It was about his brain damage.
Oh really?
What was he saying?
Saying these are already starting to
slur his words and forget things.
That mustache and fanny pack shows me
that I looked for signs that when I saw
the mustache in that fanny pack was
Lorius.
You can't be every day when I run dia,
I don't wear it to the Goddamn
supermarket like a psycho.
I do.
They make sense though when you think
about them.
They're awesome.
I just don't,
I just don't do shit.
But.
So he was saying it.
I'd be done.
Okay.
I'll give you one of my thanks.
But uh,
he was saying that he has brain trauma.
No Shit Sir.
Yeah,
no shit.
For sure.
We know,
but he was talking about it,
that he's slurring his words and just
having trouble remembering things.
But then you also said he was born to do
this.
What are we supposed to do?
And if he dies doing this,
he'd be fine with that.
He put a,
there's a caveat to that.
He said if I die in the ring,
like I want to die in the ring,
go out on my shield,
but it better not be from someone who's
on pds.
Yeah.
And that's a really good point for
people over the last five people he
fought and he tested positive for PDS or
tested?
No,
I think it was all pd because it was
brought all of them.
It was allister's test,
positive in the past,
these for doom and I'm jake bigfoot and
jds right now is um,
you know,
that's just a diuretic,
but I'm just saying as far as failing
tests,
if you would just go by failed tests
almost every.
If you look at Mark Hunt's career and he
went through and went guys test
positive.
You're like,
oh my,
no wonder he's infuriated at apple and
he has brain trauma.
Superior genetics like Mark Hunt's
genetics are insane.
Like his ability to take a punch for
years was ungodly.
You would see him get hit and you'd be
like,
this doesn't even make sense.
Is that he took cro,
cop head kicks,
Bro.
What are you working at?
What you show me?
Ah,
let's just go through them.
Cro.
Cop.
Our Silva is tested positive.
Did Verdugo test positive for somebody?
Yes,
for doom.
When did he test positive?
Um,
awhile ago.
Okay.
So a positive,
steep pays 100 percent legit as clean as
they come.
There's big Silva again.
How dare you.
He had a drop on them the first time you
saw crushed him the second time because
the second time you side was involved in
bigfoot.
Silva wasn't on the juice and he got the
first time.
The first time bigfoot Silva was on the
Jews.
He tested positive.
Not only that,
he tested negative before the fight and
positive after the fight,
which means he juiced himself up before
the fight and they had that incredible
epic five round war.
Remember that fight and it was amazing.
It was so epic that Dana White had a
bunch of Mark Hunt roots of fights too.
They made like for two before to ever
happened.
They printed up the jackets for two and
he sent me one and I was like,
dude,
I'm all in.
That was one of the craziest fights of
all time and then a week later came big
foot test positive and he's like,
this dumb motherfucker like this could
have been like this.
Incredible.
Yeah.
I mean it was just the Joshua Klitschko
style.
Incredible.
Incredible matchup.
Right?
So He tests positive and then you saw it
as on his ass.
Then they come back for the second fight
and mark hunches smokes them in the
first round.
I mean just ran through them,
but you just look at him.
So he got big foot jds is under,
you know,
he's had his issues.
He got Ben Rothwell busted.
What I was going to say though is if
anybody legitimately has a reason for
using steroids,
it's bigfoot because bigfoot has real
gigantism and he had a tumor removed
from his pituitary gland.
Like his body doesn't produce
testosterone,
right?
Or any hormones,
Body's a wreck.
This is a.
This is a gray area because it's not
great because it's brain surgery.
He had a tumor on his pituitary aware of
that.
Look at him.
So even even if you get,
if you give them trt,
you'd have to regulate so much where he
doesn't have such an advantage.
I'm not saying you should cause him
without.
It is awful.
You can't compete.
I'm saying more than that.
Maybe you shouldn't be able to compete.
That's what I'm saying.
This isn't the business for you.
If you have to have testosterone to
compete,
unless you want to go to Russia or
Japan,
it's skin birthed out there.
Oh,
well,
he's probably done it.
I mean he's had so many,
so many crazy crazy fights,
but he was the first guy to Tko Faye
door.
Yeah,
he was at that shit when he mounted
them,
like ankle lock in his.
Just giant finger going like this and
then just did fader was done because
fader in all seriousness should've been
a two.
Oh,
five pounder.
He's just a tank who's just unbelievably
talented and ridiculously skillful
in his.
His execution and just figured out a way
to win was lightening fast.
Fucked a lot of people out.
But God damn.
Could you imagine if he got himself and
ferocious shape at two?
Oh,
five nuts,
man.
Two 40 2:30,
2:30,
2:30
2:28.
Good.
Solid.
Twenty pounds of fat.
One hundred percent.
Yeah.
So he's really like to 18,
which ain't shit to cut to two.
Oh,
five.
Okay.
Well Anthony Johnson goes,
what if he changed his diet?
Who knows?
He might literally be like two,
oh seven.
You know,
if he lost all that weight,
explosive a real belly,
and I'm like,
Gosh.
And Dad got.
Yeah,
I mean that might be 25 pounds.
You know what I mean?
He literally might be like to 10.
Here's back to marketing and this is
bombing.
I gotta get this out.
So he says,
Hey,
I see signs of brain trauma,
right?
Like I'm slurring my words speech than
isn't he a main event next month?
Yeah.
Like at what point does,
when you hear that,
does the UFC and the commissioning of.
Oh,
let's stop.
Let's stop.
Let's stop you.
You're slurring your words and who's
fighting that?
Russian cat.
Oh,
like 11.
Right.
A big fight for fucking market.
Which Russian guys get to Bora.
I forget that there's so many goddamn
Russians now from Russia.
Russians are taking over the world,
um,
that Russian got it stopped.
Stephan struve.
That's pretty God damn impressive.
Any other Molena tattooed hosting round
is bad because we're identical.
Mulana tattoo that the grandma had a big
fan.
Yeah,
I guess you're welcome movie.
Um,
yeah,
that guy's a bad ass.
He's have a sweet left high.
Kick it doesn't do much orthodox.
Yeah.
Just uh,
you know what I'm saying?
If you're marketing,
you're like,
all right,
I'll do it.
At least I'm the main event on
Australia.
But at what point do we have someone
where we have a guy like the golden
snitch in the UFC who is watching out
for that stuff is going,
man.
So Mark Hunt doing every word.
He has some real issues.
Man.
You know,
where someone to look out to take care
of these guys because mark come.
What's going on and shield I don't want.
I don't want to watch marketing 10 years
shitting his pants and drooling and
doesn't remember his fight career.
Right?
I don't give a fuck if he repeats that
Russian guy in Australia.
He has nothing.
He has nothing to prove.
Yeah.
What's it do for him?
Well,
at a certain point you really,
you have to have some sort of a
regulation that stops people from
hurting themselves when they're,
they've taken too much damage and they
can't make good decisions anymore.
Right?
But then it becomes a personal freedom
issue.
Free will,
right?
Because because there's a certain amount
of damage you're going to take,
like there's fights that probably
shouldn't get made like Francis and
gone.
Oh,
versus almost anybody.
Almost anybody says agreeing to getting
your fucking head scrambled.
Yeah.
I want to see what happens with
allister.
I want to see if allister can survive
for allister.
Yeah.
Because in Ghana clip some once and
allister could be in deep,
deep trouble.
Also,
Francis has never fought a strike or a
high level striker,
let alone the best of all time.
The division,
but you don't have the same chin so it
doesn't.
It's interesting.
Match up fast.
Too many scary.
Allister's Francis Francis.
Well alster is clearly fast too,
but.
But Francis always do is touch that
chin.
Once true Francis puts people to sleep.
I got to see him do at a high level,
really high level.
Jump on the train when you have the
capabilities,
but when you watched it with a Lawsky,
Arloski is already down down the slope.
You know,
he's already slide and way down and he's
been knocked out.
Who knows how many times been down the
slope.
Yeah,
he's been down the slope,
so that was impressive.
It was a good test because Arlovski
still knocked out.
Travis Brown just a couple of years ago.
He still cannot.
Yeah,
I still can fuck you up,
you know,
if you make.
If you fuck up.
True.
I'm just saying that the fucked up big
foot too.
Yeah,
that's true.
That was a while ago though,
Joe.
It was.
He went on that tier.
Yeah.
Now it's over,
but yeah.
Well Steve Big Steve ended that.
But a guy like I think jds to be a good
test for him.
Alistair overeem be pretty good.
Yeah,
no,
for sure.
Look,
it's a great denim on board because
right now to be honest,
we need them.
We need a young killer,
like a guide to bring some life into the
heavyweight division.
He just has everything going as far as
like his ability knock it dead,
his look.
I mean he just jacked that the market
believes can be tough until his English
is better.
I don't think so.
Really check was coming out of the
corner.
If he starts American people at heavy
Wayne and you can get a highlight reel,
the heavyweight champion based work,
working people,
he's from Cleveland and he's not a draw.
He knows.
I don't understand it.
Is it a marketing thing?
One hundred percent.
I haven't done it right or I'm not
blaming the US public has to jump on the
public.
It's not the UFC.
I mean still doing his thing.
He's doing their thing with them,
but sometimes the stars don't align
where you become this crossover pop
culture icon ass public.
They're like a white guy standard.
What?
He's a firefighter though.
Standard.
But he's knocked out everyone's standard
va.
How is that standard?
It just people want it and.
But He's real humble and you know,
well spoken and she's not cocky so they
don't.
They were drawn to negativity,
withdrawn to the John Jones and the
economy,
you know,
they want that kind of that it wasn't
really negative.
He's not talking about.
But she talks a lot of shit.
He's going to be hot.
Takes deep take.
He's working his ass off.
Training hard to win the fight.
Isn't that crazy?
That.
Well wIth connor,
the thing that sort of sensational about
him is he has both of those things.
He has fighting ability and he also has
this crazy personality that's magnetic
cord where steve page just has the
fighting ability and just.
I don't know,
I just love his work ethic.
I love the fact that he still has a
firearm gig.
I love it,
man.
Not that people dead.
Just your heavyweight champion of the
world is not a draw,
which is insane.
Yeah.
I know.
And even a francis knocks out.
Allister knocked out steve Bay.
There's no way to draw.
Yeah,
it.
There's just these and I don't have the
formula.
Trust me.
The ucb hit me up if I did.
There's this weird superstar soup and
you have a few ingredients in your myth.
We don't know what the others are,
but guys hit it.
Yeah,
you hit it almost sunk by chance.
Yeah.
They just come around once a every now
and then.
Conner wasn't like that early in his
career.
Just good.
Not at all.
He was just a great fighter,
you know,
he's just like looking promising and
then all of a sudden it gets to the ufc.
He feels the crowd,
all the irish people behind him and he
starts talking shit and going off and
then people love it and he talks more.
Shit goes off more than he starts
predicting what round is going to merck
people in and then he starts pulling it
off and then he's like,
who the fuck is that guy?
And everybody goes crazy.
And the thing about john john didn't get
really mainstream espn coverage.
Good morning America till you went bad.
Then people are like,
oh,
I want to see that bad ass fight.
He's been amazing for how long he had a
press conference that he.
He said,
what I've always said,
he said,
at the end of the day,
he goes,
uh,
about him.
I've always said about him.
He goes,
at the end of the day,
I'm a bad motherfucker.
I'm a wild motherfucker.
I want.
And that's what I do.
perfect.
At the end of the day,
that's what said at the end of the day,
I'm a wild motherfucker.
I'm like,
that's what I would say.
That's it,
brother.
Run with that.
I told them that too when I talked to
him about it.
You know when he wanted to have a
conversation before he did the podcast
and you know,
we wanted to come clean.
I go,
dude,
you're going to make mistakes.
You're a wild motherfucker.
It's okay.
That's.
You don't get to be as good as you are
without being a wild motherfucker.
You don't have to apologize for it to
john.
If he came out and went,
listen,
me and haley,
I'm going to make some steaks and I
probably make a lot more.
I'm a wild motherfucker.
I'm the baddest dude on the planet.
This is what you get.
Love it or hate it,
but he dropped them.
I just can't do things that hurt people
like the driving fucked up,
smashing into that lady's car.
You Take away the things that hurt
people and you just have party and
having a good time and occasionally do
blow.
Nobody's going to care and that's give
up.
That's a great guy.
That's a fun guy.
It's like you just gotta make sure you
avoid hurting other people and then
this,
this thyroid thing is the goddamn that's
the knife in the heart like this.
I said,
you gotta,
you gotta.
Look into this drought ball stuff with
the,
with the baseball.
All these guys who have all these
problems that gnc.
It's in all these supplements.
I saw that and again I've been roasting
john bad because I'm upset.
I'm mad at him because he's my favorite
fighter,
one of them,
so it is possible that he could have
taken something that's trace elements of
this.
I've also seen that other things are
recognized as that stuff in the task,
but I have a hard time believing that
you wouldn't know that.
I know so I have a hard time.
Once they come clean with us,
they'd come out with this.
I don't think it's ever been proven once
that they said that a person had tested
positive for something and that that
person had never actually taken that
thing.
I don't.
I have not seen that one.
No,
you saw a so thorough it.
Listen man,
if you have the golden snitch on your
trail,
you're fucked.
He's like sherlock holmes of pds.
You are so fucked.
And again,
Just fucking dead calm about it.
Not judgmental.
Just the facts going over the details.
This is what bothered me the little bit
and why I'm going back and forth on
John.
If my career was in jeopardy,
I would be out there be like,
listen,
this is what fucking happened and hear
me out.
I'm not going radio silent.
Sending these weird cryptic tweets doing
this.
Even if my manager like,
dude,
let's wait.
I'm doing a press comes like listened to
me right now,
man.
This maybe I took this supplement.
I've never done steroids in my fucking
life.
That is bullshit.
Yeah,
but you can't say too much if it's going
to go to some sort of a arbitration or a
trial or I don't know what the process
can.
You can if you didn't take it,
but here's the thing.
He's got to find out how.
If there is a way that something
happened,
a loophole safe you,
maybe it's you,
okay.
Say you take something from gmc and
maybe you take a bunch of shit and you
thought everything was good and then you
get tested positive before you say
anything.
I never took steroids.
Like you have to find out what the fuck
it is was in those stuff,
those things.
So you have to report those things and
then they have to check and then they
have to independently by those things
from a shelf,
from somewhere else to confirmation.
And that's a process.
And this is one of the thing that jeff
novitsky said.
You got to let the process play out
before you start accusing john.
So there'll be a process.
I'm just saying,
man,
that's not good a sample and be sample.
It's not good.
I just think it could go a long ways
with his fans and everything going on.
If he came out and was just like,
let me tell you guys,
you're going to hear this because the
public right now we see test a,
test b both positive.
Oh fuck steroids.
He's dead to me.
Um,
but if you look at a tweet where he said
that he never took steroids,
his kids,
his heavenly father,
remember he capitalize.
Heavenly father.
So skeptical.
So fuck off.
Fuck off.
That actually made me go.
Hmm.
He was on steroids,
huh?
Yeah,
it'd be too.
I was like,
god damn it.
Let me put all right.
You clearly understood what he went.
Heavenly father,
I was like,
oh,
you're a bad guy sean.
He's a bad guy.
How about,
how about john does this?
And we're all like,
oh,
fucking the worst.
Greatest of all time my ass.
Then brian cushing football,
brian cushion captain of the houston
texans.
He's been caught I think two or three
times before.
Straight up test,
positive for p,
d,
like straight up steroids.
And he's a monster linebacker.
Have used test again,
I think your band or he's gonna miss
like 10 games.
They docked $4,000,000
of his paycheck.
the media doesn't make it nothing about
it.
This guy's a superstar Ball.
Of course they're on steroids.
Everybody who's 360 pounds of solid
muscle is on steroids.
But how crazy.
We just give them a ride off,
like they shouldn't be testing those
guys.
It's ridiculous,
but he's up.
He's playing a position to where he hits
guys.
He's taken years off their life.
He's given them bring trauma and he's
rocking them.
Jack to the gills.
That's what people want to see.
If you want to see football,
okay,
you want to see big giant guys colliding
with each other.
You don't see natural athletes are out
there like trying to fucking pound whey
protein in the middle of the night.
WHere do you want to see natural grass
on the ufc?
Hate to tell ya.
I hear ya.
Those guys aren't right.
I hear you.
But there's weight classes in the ufc
and that's where it gets different
because you're talking about god's
trying to get as big and as fast,
as powerful as they can and we've all
known forever.
You ask the average person to football
players take pe.
Of course They do.
Of course they do.
You'll look into these mountains.
Well,
most people assume you'll see posts on
pds,
like I've had some talks and what did we
say?
Lie though,
I mean there's a giant percentage but,
but there's a different standard way
less are now,
but I think for the longest time,
42 supplements including some that are
available at gnc contribute or positive
test for toronto ball sports article.
YeaH.
Yeah.
The official said the cubs,
again,
we're reminded this week that players
should only.
She used only supplement certified by
nsf international and independent
organization,
the tests and approved products,
blah blah blah blah blah blah blah.
So there's a lot of shit.
Look,
the union havers concerned about the run
of suspension of tyrannical and
continues to seek evidence that might
shed light on why some players are
testing positive because so many guys
are testing positive for it.
Well,
isn't this a short acting drug though
that's out of your system fairly
quickly?
I think that was the thing about this
stuff,
but then there's even debate on that
though,
jill.
Yeah.
Why did I see?
Why don'T I see something that said it
had a 60 day window.
I've seen,
I've seen months.
I've seen weeks,
I've seen days,
I've seen ours again.
We don't fucking know dude.
It's been explained to me the stuff that
gets out of your system the quickest is
those little edible testosterone things
like the gummies and stuff around them,
but those are just a few hours in a few
hours or out of your system.
The other thing we're going to,
just like we're doing now with baseball,
like barry bonds,
mark mcgwire,
sammy sosa at the time were like,
oh my god.
Pds whole month.
That doesn't count.
The years go by,
we're like,
those guys are still pretty fucking
good.
If even the pitchers were sauced up,
I think that could happen with john to
like five,
10 years that he knows he's the greatest
of all time still.
Yeah,
but no,
because danIel cormier wasn't sauced up.
Daniel cormier was totally on the notch.
You don't believe that?
I don't know.
I assume he is.
You have to know.
I have no idea.
I have no reason not to.
I don't know anything in this world
anymore.
When it comes.
Well,
you know,
you gotta think man,
you're held on the line.
Your futures on the line.
Your career's on the line.
You've been out of the game for
essentially two and a half years plus
one fight in between there,
the osp fight,
but he's been at a cage for a long time.
You got to fight the best in the world,
the best in the world.
Skeptical tomato.
You got all this pressure on you and you
just go just a little bit,
get a little bit.
I don't know if you need that help if
you're.
John might not.
Might not to go the club.
Do a couple of cans of coke.
That's maybe it's one of those things
where he's always used it,
got away with it.
Now he didn't.
Maybe he took a supplement that had an
in it.
I mean we really don't know.
It's one of the things that stress that
I really believe you got to kinda before
casting 100 percent judgment on them.
You gotta let it play out,
but this is the thing we say.
Let it play out.
Again.
I know I'm playing both sides of the
field here,
but when you say let it play out,
we.
We know he has a history of fucking up.
Yeah,
he's going to hang him before it's
actually come out because we go,
no,
he's consistently good at beating people
up and fucking up and here's another
fuck up.
Yeah,
that's a good way of looking at it.
that's why.
That's why everyone's like,
nope,
he's done to me.
Well,
it's depressing to us,
right?
As fans because he's so fucking good and
to know that he's going to be out
possibly for four years now.
That shit's just devastating to me when
we meet him.
I know people don't know.
We don't know.
We fucking medium.
He was like steep pay for the
heavyweight title.
You fucked.
He didn't even know about that.
Well now you know,
tough fight for steep bit and then he
was gonna fight.
Brock lesnar we gusts in dc again.
There's so much out there to versus
steep a for the heavyweight title would
be wise.
We'll talk about fucking dragons and jon
snow.
It's because neither one of them is
happening.
It's interesting,
right?
It's like what your theory about the
fertittas pumping up with reebok and
with usada and then just to sell that
science do theory,
but it's a very good theory that I
haven't heard before.
A word I'd never heard it.
Is your theory entirely your idea to.
I mean,
it's evidence,
it's just.
But the evidence was always there.
Always,
always put two and two together.
What they're doing.
It's genius mean if they really played
at that,
that three d chess,
that's fucking genius.
One hundred percent.
That's what they're doing.
But it really is a smart man.
If you just bought it and you were a
wme,
he probably um,
fertitta is this jewish sot of thing?
Are we doing with this?
Yeah.
You're going,
hold on.
Is your how.
How long has it been?
I don't know what their deal is with you
because you saw it as a,
an employee of the ufc.
It's fine.
Now.
Realize that.
Right?
Find out what,
how long the deal is with the ufc and
usada let's say.
Yes.
Let's say here's these 10 years.
You can't do 10 years,
10 years,
going to be buying 14 houses if it's
tangible.
What happens if they abandoned it and
all of a sudden everybody just comes
like Eric Silva comes back.
Jack writing skill.
Everybody are jacked.
Allister goes back to being ubering.
I'll ask to do is pass the one at the
weigh ins set.
We're going sizzler.
They better pray to god.
That golden snitch contract runs out in
the next two years.
You bringing that russian cat from a
charisse,
it whatever it is.
Are you bringing everybody in?
Anybody?
All The russians,
they're the best at it.
All of them.
Bring them in.
This guy had this dude on a protocol.
I fell asleep.
I Was watching.
I want only watch the first 15 minutes.
Then I to bed.
I'm going to watch the rest of it.
I've heard about him,
but he was banging like five different
things in his ass.
These like amber liquids.
It looked like Jack Daniels.
You know,
he's a cyclist.
he was a very slim guy,
but he just started doing this.
He just started doing this while I was
listening to sky and I guess the idea is
that they're going to test him and he's
given ped forever and he's going to test
the siCk.
Yeah.
I need to see the whole thing.
Or like I said,
like 15,
20 minutes into it.
I wme you're looking at that going,
um,
when's that contract up?
Went to the reebok.
You're literally going,
you're going to tear it down and go,
let,
let us do it.
Like you guys got to this point.
Like this isn't working for us now.
Yeah.
those are two ideas that look good to
sell to another company and make it
legit.
But the thing is like,
if you can get a better deal,
like right,
you have a deal with reebok goes for so
long and then if it's profitable for
reebok and adidas comes in and goes,
hey,
we like what you're doing here.
Uh,
let's,
uh,
switch it up,
let's go adidas.
And then you have a bidding war between
adidas and reebok.
And then maybe nike thinks about it too.
And you know,
if you can prove that you're cleaning
the sport up,
right,
with usada,
that's a very smart move to get a big
company to invest in a sport that's when
you do it.
But the big company as to see some sort
of a payback,
that's why people were pissed off
because they were like,
well the sponsorship doesn't match what
we were getting before.
And you know,
I know you had a real issue with that.
It was a big like $100 plus thousand
dollars a fight.
Yeah.
That,
that was the biggest issue is I liked
the uniform system and make it look like
professional sport.
But if you're gonna bring in a major
sponsor like that,
then cut down,
guys pays,
then you're fucking the product.
You're fucking the fighters.
And wHat you don't realize is you
actually fucking reebok the ufc as the
middleman.
You're screwing reebok because no one
had any issues with reebok.
They,
they're owning the crossfit world.
They're doing things actually like I
have no issues with your back.
I talked to represent from reebok the
other day.
You want to send me a fight?
Kip?
I'm so,
for who?
Who does it say new boxing shoes and
some shorts you want to send me?
I'm like,
all right,
cool man.
I would like you honest fight kit so I
could spell her name.
I want mine.
How much if I gave you $10,000,000,
do you think you could spell you on and
you jet checks last?
Nope.
Not even close.
I bet she came.
spell it,
get her together.
She's like,
who is this?
What is this z?
Or ask something.
Jamie.
I just see that as it was.
It's just the program they started
together so they can cancel it anytime.
Maybe would imagine.
They probably one a contract.
It doesn't say that they have a longterm
usada or only thing I forgot is that the
ufc has committed millions of dollars to
in an out of competition for sure to
bring in for the ufc to bring in a big
sponsor like reebok,
like that's a good way to ensure that
you've got to clean sport,
that you represent you to represent a
clean sport.
You know?
That's why that fighter.
The other night when gavin tucker
fought,
I'm god damn it wasn't John Tucker
because he's,
you know,
he's the guy who took the beat down,
right?
Yes.
Would that riff right?
That ref
that stopped the fight?
Scared to admit social.
The m no.
He looked great though.
Rick.
Rick the gladiator.
Yes.
Rick to first take mustache glen to
freshman.
Glen beat the shit out of him.
Beat the brakes off way too much.
It was like that fight should have been
stopped like minutes before.
Horrible.
It's not good.
Like when you see that,
like if I was reebok and be like,
hey,
this guy can't do.
We can't sponsor a fight with this guy's
a ref ever again.
The sport that will do that.
Whatever.
You got to know it now.
You know.
You know what I'd do if I was the ufc,
if I'm wme,
I get rid of the snitch.
I don't say anything,
but I don't say anything.
I let people assume I let people.
Everyone assume.
I'm sure there's a nondisclosure all
that.
Don't think the golden snitch is going
to go on the ariel helwani show.
The moment.
Maybe pay him a fat summit by katie.
Go away,
but let's not say anything.
We're not doing a strict.
It was brock lesnar's urine looked like
gatorade.
Like gravy.
Yeah,
I don't.
I.
That's what I would do.
I would just take him out of it,
the equation,
not say anything to the public and then
all of a sudden you have all the
monsters back.
People get to know how are they going to
know.
We all assume they're gonna know they're
gonna.
Find out people are fans.
If I know the general public will find
out,
everybody's going to find out.
You don't think so?
No.
That's so stupid.
I don't think so.
You think it wouldn't get out if you saw
to left of the ufc?
Like what about the testing?
No,
no,
we were still.
We still doing this thing that they do
before it was still being there.
We're still testing state athletic
commission tests,
which would test after the weigh in and
then maybe after the fight,
depending if you saw it as just a
surprise testing whenever and the 365
days a year and they also way more
thorough tests are very,
very few do blood.
What?
Um,
the other one only does urine victor
content.
The guy who got busted the balco scandal
when it comes on the blocks.
When he said to me,
he was like,
if you fail one of those posts weighing
tests,
that's an intelligence test.
You just,
you're just a dummy.
He's like,
anybody knows that they're doing can
pass those tests.
Yeah.
If you have a guy like him,
you're dealing with these high level
guys.
Like that's an easy test.
You saw her though.
There's no.
They're keeping your,
your,
your piss in your blood for like seven
years.
Freezing that shit.
Keeping it for seven years,
man.
Too much.
They're going to test it to strip people
the title.
No,
the olympics is already done that.
Yeah.
No,
they busted russians retroactively.
They busted two gold medalists.
I want to say like 2008,
two gold medalists from 2008.
They're like,
yeah.
You imagine getting that call.
Who the fuck was that?
The olympic committee from fucking just
stripped our gold metals.
Well,
you know,
they came real close to banning Russia
from combined now in rio.
Did they banned the some of their
athletes or is that China?
Did they ban like china's a gymnastic
team?
Do you have to give that back?
The metal is going to go to siberia.
taken heightened mass pike with a knife.
They took like reggie bush.
Remember that they took his heisman.
You can't find anymore.
And they took their trophies.
He took his heisman.
For what?
For what reason?
Because that year he received benefits
like you took money from boosters.
Good lord.
They're like,
can I see that trophy bitch from my.
They gave him money.
He gave his parents like a house or
something like that.
So they investigate it,
took all the shit and they voided all
us' wins that year.
All us seeS wins.
Holy shit.
Because he violated that agreement.
Him and the coach and they had a bunch
of fuck uPs and ncaa.
That is so bizarre.
I now just have to act like it never
happened.
That's so crazy.
How is that possible?
How can you.
They're saying they've wins everything.
None of it counts in the record books,
so I could still the record.
It's out of the record books.
The money money was transpired.
The people watched it on tv.
You know what I mean?
Like the university of.
Well,
it's like jon jones,
daniel cormier.
You could call that a no contest.
All you want.
We saw jon jones beat daniel asleep.
We saw it.
We saw the ufc.
He made the money off the.
Yeah,
but they're not thinking that way.
What they're thinking is this is not.
It's a violation of the rules in terms
of like someone competing on a
performance enhancing drug.
they set up the rules.
The guy violated.
So this trip,
just title as they're supposed to and
they reinstated into dc.
I'll do one better.
How about ufc?
200 were brock lesnar.
Think about that and then you,
because you get all the bikes for brock
lesnar didn't realize test hot
afterwards.
He's like,
fuck them wet.
Of course.
I was just like,
god damn pro a little,
you know,
brock lesnar independently tested
himself a shit ton of times leading up
to that trial.
Well listen,
let me listen to me.
Listen to me.
Don't get crazy.
When you independently test yourself,
it's because you want to make sure that
you're showing up clean.
It's not because you think you're clean.
You want to show the world is because
you want to make sure like,
hey,
is this showing up?
For sure what was going on?
We okay here,
let's chest out like,
is this really working multiple
independent test that he did,
which you wouldn't have to do if you
weren't taking anything.
He's trying to get whatever it is out of
his system trying to get his body up to
baseline for sure.
I mean,
when you watched him in the wwe and he's
300 plus pounds,
he likes to say he's,
he's a giant guy,
you know,
and he's 39 or something like that.
That,
that was a dirty one.
That was the most dirtiest one.
That's another Mark Hunt beating.
No slurred speech.
Yeah.
Alistair overeem.
That was the worst one that needed.
Took to the face of flatland,
straight up,
flat line right in front of us.
Man.
He was doing a toe curl.
You know when they get killed and get
that toe curl show.
Do you like the shocker with their feet?
Is that toe curls hard to watch because
you know that,
that that's the whole body going.
It's weird.
People enjoy seeing that.
They don't enjoy seeing that.
They enjoy seeing the kick lending
because it's so difficult and you know,
the consequences are so great because I
like the way we're made up you.
You almost want to flInch when you see
that someone's brain shuts off like
that.
You should be genetically.
You go,
oh my god.
You know,
you know,
I just don't think the people that
suffer the most start,
they don't come out about it.
It just kind of go away.
What do you mean?
Like guys like don fry,
you don't see don fry all the tIme being
interviewed on tv.
You don't think about like his fight
with takiyama when they both stood in
front of each other and blast each other
in the face over and over and over.
The older generation,
not in their nature to do that and
they're not,
they're not very good on camera and
stuff like that.
I think as you go on.
So what I mean,
you're going to see guys coming out
though maybe I hope,
but it just because people don't see
them,
they fade away.
So you're saying I do not in the
spotlight.
Yeah,
they're not as poly.
So people don't think about that.
When you think of fighting,
you think of,
you know,
watching tyron woodley right now in his
prime.
Now you know he's doing damage,
you know that,
you know,
he's had some good fights but he's okay.
He's fine.
Yep.
You think of it as one knockout last gen
two,
um,
nate marquardt in strikeforce.
That's like the only,
like real bad loss that he has the other
losses,
you know,
it's just,
doesn't,
doesn't seem like he's in a bad place,
but then,
you know,
you don't see guys that were in the ufc
15,
20 years ago,
you know,
that took crazy debt.
Like gary goodrich,
big daddy goodrich who went over to k
one and he's got crazy cte now.
Horrible.
He talks about it,
right?
He's trying to,
he talks about it really openly and
it's,
he's got a great twitter to follow them
on here.
No,
with you for sure.
Yeah.
Talk about that.
I mean,
I'm sure he'd want to talk about that.
You'd want people to know.
You know,
I just,
obviously if you're gonna fight brain
traumas,
one of the commission,
that's what we do obviously.
So If he were to come on and my brain
ct,
I don't feel like most people are like,
god,
it's terrible.
I'm not watching it.
But you feel bad.
Like,
you know,
you see someone slurring their words.
You'd ever see Joe Frazier before he
died?
Yeah.
He was on the opiod.
Anthony show once and I remember
listening.
I was like,
wow,
this is hard to listen to man.
It's just like there's some guys like
that in the afc.
Yeah.
Yes.
I won't mention names of some guys who I
have conversations with them.
Like,
oh my god,
man.
You see it?
Yeah.
It's like nobody rides for free.
You get hit enough.
Just it's the weird thing is the number
is different for everybody.
like the number for one guy like Mark
Hunt.
It took years and years and years and
years and years and years for his chin
started failing.
And you think about the fights.
He had the strike
for the,
all the,
the um,
uh,
k one pride,
pride fights.
He had,
you know,
I think he fought and dream as well.
When dId melvin manhoef knock them out?
Was that in dream?
Uh,
no.
No.
It was a pride.
It just the all the k one bounce man.
I mean he was a k one grumpy caitlyn.
Yeah,
mean he fought some fucking warrant.
Was it a k one?
Mma fights,
yeah,
I mean just there's only so many of
those fights you could have.
it is weird how certain guys get,
you know,
their capabilities to take punches so
much longer than the other guys.
We doN't know what it is.
I think it's a structured thing.
The way they're built.
I think the way you're built,
like Mark Hunt is built like a tank.
He's five,
10 to 65.
He's just a tank.
The other problem is the size of his
head.
His body's denseness.
When you see his shins,
like when mark is standing in front,
his knees are giant,
his knees are like this big.
His shins are huge.
He's like a thick bone guy.
Well,
the other issue is is you have,
especially as a shame mixed martial arts
called mixed martial arts,
ufc,
but mixed martial arts is so new in the
grand scheme of things compared to other
sports.
We don't know the best way to train,
to stay healthy,
to not get in trouble.
We have not been people trying to figure
out there's doctors.
It Just hasn't been around long enough
like in football and the cfl just passed
this.
They're not allowed to put pads on and
practicing where they hitting practice
and one that is a rule smart and now the
nfl is going,
we're going to look into that.
Now.
The nfl only has I think 14 days of pad
work,
whether they're in pads during the
season,
but they want to eliminate that.
Well,
it's been around for a grip.
The best saving grace for the sport
would be,
or the best hope for the sport would be
medical science.
Medical science comes along with some
sort of stem cell regeneration thing.
Brain come back to 100 percent,
which god totally possible.
They just have to crack the code.
You just think about what they can do
with other parts of your body to where
they can repair things.
The brain is far more complicated than
anything we have to deal with,
but if you could somehow or another rig
night,
the body's ability to heal itself and in
fact they have a new chip that they're
going to,
uh,
that they're working on now where they
install it in a person's body and it
reprograms your genes and they think it
can repair brain trauma injuries,
tissue damage,
and even the effects of aging.
oh my god.
Oh my god.
Yeah.
It's a chip you put into your body and
it reprograms your genes.
And I think it's probably at some very
embryonic stage of development,
a trillion dollars.
I know.
Who knows,
but they're true.
They're probably trying to juice up,
you know,
excitement for it by making it this.
I can't imagine.
I can tell.
Look dude,
you know,
I've,
the store with my shoulder,
my shoulder was fucked.
I was ready to get shoulder surgery was
hurting all the time.
It doesn't hurt at all.
Brains for an animal.
It is.
You're right.
It is like you talk the way more can you
do.
Yeah.
You listen to the scientists go,
we can.
You need
a new heart.
We can make that you had lungs,
muscle bones,
we can make all that can help your brain
right now.
Now stop and think about where we were
50 years ago,
50 years ago.
None of those things are possible.
So all these ideas that are commonplace
today,
we're just science fiction.
Fifty years ago,
50 years from now,
they might be able to use this ship.
Have you found that thing that chip?
The one I found isn't even new.
it's from three years ago,
but made by.
no,
no.
That's not what it is.
It's a new chip installed under skin
that reprograms dna and can heal
injuries.
Look,
look,
forget about brain injurY.
Just look at that because new chip,
I think it can replicate and restore.
The Idea behind it is it can program the
genes to replicate and restore any sort
of injury to resolve.
For some,
I think it was live science.com.
It's one of those,
uh,
websites,
science websites I go to the regular
hitch about that is by the time that's
out you.
And I'd probably be dead.
No,
that's not true.
It might be out real soon.
Breakthrough device heels.
Oregon's with a single touch device
instantly delivers new dna or rna into
living skin cells to change their
Function.
This is it.
They've developed a device that will
switch cell function to rescue failing
body functions with a single touch.
The technology known as tissue nano.
Transfection injects genetic code into
the skin cells,
turning those skin cells into other
types of sales required for treating
disease conditions.
Welcome to the future motherfucker.
Cte out the window.
FootbAll,
no helmets don't be a pussy stitching.
They have a bunch of boxes of these
ships sitting by and you're down.
Your head smashed in like that fucking
guy.
The mountain from a game of thrones
crushed.
And they just stick that shit on your
eyeballs.
Pop right back in place.
Like,
whoa.
That was.
You know what happens then?
Sword fights.
Yeah.
once they could just grab a hold of you
and bring you back to light,
it'S going to be a bitch.
If he had stabbed,
her sword fights would be like,
you're not allowed to cut their head
off.
Can't fix,
I can't fix that.
It's like elbows to the back of the
head.
When you got the back mountain,
two effective.
Within one week,
active Blood vessels appeared in the
injured leg and by the second week the
leg was saved.
Holy shiT.
We researchers studied mice and pigs and
these experiments in the study,
researchers were able to reprogram skin
cells to become vascular cells in badly
injured legs.
That lacked blood flow so amazing
probably for people that diabetes,
amazing for people that are suffering
from all sorts of circulatory
conditions,
bro.
It takes less than a second and the
noninvasive.
Come on,
son.
Welcome to the new world.
It's like that nas song.
The chip doesn't even stay in your body,
I think says they can fixing shit.
why isn't this bigger news?
Why isn't this on cnn?
all that shit.
That's a good question.
They're too busy talking about trump or
flat.
They're talking about whether or not
trump is a racist and whether or not
that girl should get fired instead of
excitement.
woo hoo.
I'm a how's that?
Not exciting as shit.
It's exciting.
It's shit.
I'm going to go bash mY brains in.
We're in the new world,
man,
and this is just one step,
right?
What is this going to be like?
$20.
We didn'T see this comment.
What's it going to be like 20 years from
now?
We don't know who's in Austria right now
and some fucking laboratory with white
gloves on.
Huge brands putting their hand into some
crazy machine.
There's a petri dish and they got all
these lasers are zap and this thing and
they're poodles.
What the fuck they're doing right now?
What's a bummer?
This is the first I've heard about.
Do you fucking brought it up?
I'm on the balls on popham stag sent me
that.
Shout out to matt stacks.
I like that guy.
He's awesome.
He's a great guy.
This,
this whole.
What we're experiencing now is this,
you know this I'm escalating sort of
technological race,
like one invention,
like this is going to allow for the idea
of several other different inventions
and maybe they'll come up with
something.
They add this to crispr.
Crispr is this new genetic
reprogramming.
I don't know if the best way to describe
it,
but it's a tool for altering genetics.
Now they get a hold of that and they use
it with this.
So you use crispr and this.
You got the hulk,
you got John Jones and brock lesnar,
baby.
You got the hulk.
Fuck jon jones and brock lesnar for the
hulk shows up,
right?
Not if they had a baby crashing through
the wall.
He leaps through the marine albert
nonstop,
literally from the dressIng room,
beliefs through the air and boom,
as the center of the octagon it goes and
brock lesnar just goes,
shit.
That was the best.
When the hulk grabs that fucking thor's
brother and these like,
I'm a god,
he just grabs one because I'm on the
ground for the bus up.
The contents.
I fucking love the idea that some
peaceful mark refollow low character
who's this brilliant scientist who
select concerned with helping people.
If you piss this motherfucker off,
he becomes a bulletproof giant is pretty
dope.
NoT only it happened so quick that he
tried to shoot himself in the mouth and
by the time the bullet hit the skin,
he's the hulk.
Spit up a bullet.
Come on son.
ITs greatest fucking super hero
character of all time.
The whole that yoU think everybody else
Can suck my dick.
Every single one of you know why?
Because they all call in the hulk.
If the shit goes wrong,
if everything goes wrong.
Like what?
Just sending the hulk.
What's that asshole with a bow and arrow
doing there?
Get the fuck out of there.
What are you going to do?
A triangle people with your stilettos
on.
Shut the fuck up everybody calling the
green guy and let's just get this over
with punching spaceships
into oblivion and what are you going to
shoot arrows at the spaceship.
Archer the fuck outta here.
I love you.
He's the best.
He's doing one to call.
If I was captain America,
I'd be like,
listen,
I'm getting the fuck out of my face.
He wanted to get some shoes.
She's the only one that can calm them
down.
Calm down hulk.
What?
That looks so fake there.
That looks like my kid drew it.
Literally.
It looks like it looks like shrek.
There was two hulks though.
Yeah,
it was zero punch and then the mark
rubin.
A bunch of them.
Yeah.
At norton was one.
ErIc bana was the worst.
I want to see that eric banner movie.
Not that he's a bad actor.
He's an amazing actor.
He was great.
And chopper chopper is ridiculous.
Fucking fanTastic.
But there was something about that hulk
movie with him and I was like,
this is whack.
It's not his fault.
I went,
I went to see it's super duper high and
when I went to see it super duper high,
I was like,
oh my god,
the acting in this movie.
So bad marijuana is the number one
detector of shitty acting like you
didn't sense it.
There is go big screen on that one too.
So that's eric bana one.
That's early days.
That's the first whole san francisco
hulk.
Yeah.
So you see the difference between the ed
norton hawk on the right and actually
the one on the left looks terrible.
No one on the left obliques.
Bloated ban a whole clique,
so faked ed norton one is so much
better.
Which one's this?
That's the bag that looks like shit.
Now go to the most recent.
The mark.
Ruffalo hulk.
Let's see what that one looks like.
Yeah.
The mark refollow hooks of best hoke.
Yeah,
that's it right there.
Come with more realistic.
A little more,
but I mean it's obviously.
It's still a hulk.
Woo.
Go fullscreen.
Jesus christ.
Yeah.
That's dope.
If that thing hops into the octagon,
brock lesnar,
good luck.
If you're whole thing is that you're big
and strong and that's a big part of what
brock lesnar's thing is.
He's big and strong.
It says only thing.
Yeah.
I mean he's like the hulk of ufc
fighters.
What are you going to mighty mouse.
I'm going to move around them real well.
That was the ed norton one.
The opening scene when he fucking.
Whoa.
Ooh,
that does look good.
It looks dope.
Teeth are fucked.
If we could figure if they can figure
out a way to do that to people.
The world's gonna be a totally different
place.
It's not that far away.
Look,
let's think of what they could do with
steroids.
Like did you ever see that guy who just
died?
A rich piana.
His name is.
He's a famous internet,
a bodybuilder.
Colts,
a bunch of time.
Nicest guy.
Ever.
Seemed like a very nice guy.
His arms are as big as my entire torso.
Look at the size of this fucker.
He just died and I think they suspect
painkillers did a man.
I mean,
I can't imagine stores didn't have some
sort of play in the death of this man.
Could have very Well have.
But um,
there were suspecting painkillers
apparently.
All the big cycles that he did wear like
a long time ago and he does it really do
those big cycles anymore.
But he is josh preposterous.
Look at that photo right there.
That is so preposterous.
Look at the size of his arm.
It's like he's got a person that's head
is attached to his shoulder,
his and the person's like holding their
body like this is,
are these bicep as a person's body with
their arms crossed?
It's like the three of ours put together
in here.
He's enormous or was I should say right
now,
but yeah,
you go into a coma or something.
I don't know.
Look at that picture there and famine.
This giant dude.
What?
What does that natural bodybuilder what?
What are you saying?
Natural bodybuilder.
Mike o'hearn dates.
Michael opens up steroid whatever is
bodybuilding.com.
People get super into that shit.
Muscle roast roast that.
If that guy is real,
if that's a real natural bodybuilder or
not,
we need to find out what he's eating and
let's see if it passes the golden snitch
test.
He's naturally on steroids.
he's just cleaned the day of the
competition.
Probably all those fucking guys do it.
WhY would you not?
You're not hurting anybody.
he shreds city though.
Natural bodybuilder,
but it's got to be possible to get a
certain size.
Just like the biggest freaks I know are
genetically like my friend clop bose
fucking shredded naturally be the those
guys are,
but that will get that picture of them
with the six pack of him.
Go back a little picture of him.
Look at that.
Come on son.
that dude's jack suited.
If that is natural,
100 percent natural,
that's insane.
Genetics,
they'd be the most insane genetics I've
ever seen and I'd be willing to bet my
life on it.
He has something run through the system,
but is it possible to be built like that
with nothing else?
Then genetics and hard work.
What do you think,
joe?
I say no,
no,
not.
Well,
I want to say no,
but I think that tyron woodley could
probably look like that.
Like I six four sir.
I don't mean like the height.
I mean if tyron,
you'd be looking at like tyrons body
checked,
like naturally jack,
like dave's superior genetics.
Look is jack's on the left though.
That's him.
Yes.
So he wasn't born like that.
You know whaT I'm saying to.
he's made that partying back then.
But look at any picture of woodley.
Average jack jack it everyday and be in
Ghana.
There's another one.
Some people have such weird mentioning
all black guys.
Yeah.
Fluff people have crazy narratives and
positive blah blah blah blah blah blah.
But there's got to be natural
bodybuilders that are jacked.
I had a friend,
um,
I know one day Brian Frazier,
a friend of mine from boston who was a
stand up comedian who was,
it was huge,
thick and tall ass.
No,
he wasn't that tall.
He was like maybe,
I think he's five,
10 or 5:11,
but like soup at the time,
super jacked like giant muscles.
And I know for a fact he never did
anything that he didn't.
No,
he didn't.
I'm telling you,
I know the guy very well.
He didn't do shit,
but like I know in natural bodybuilding,
he's obese.
He trains for doom.
He trains a lot of these guys named some
mix of phi trains out of a anderson
silva's jim are used to it.
I think he's straighten out training out
of a header,
gracie's gym and he's a natural
bodybuilder.
He competes and he is fucking shredded
these big.
No,
he's just,
he's like thin,
like strong.
Yeah.
There it is.
That's shredded now.
That's totally possible to do.
Naturally he's on.
I know for a fact it can totally be
done.
His whole family,
his brothers,
his sister,
like they're all built that same way.
Totally can be done.
The question is can you do what the
other guy looks like?
No,
that's different.
I shouldn't say no because my clock,
my buddy clop,
he's 66 to 70.
If he and he eats like shit and he's
jacked and shredded.
If he got on like a regular diet,
like a strict,
like quito,
I'm sure you'd leni out even more and if
you've got obsessed with lifting,
like he was lifting every day.
She is several times a day.
Yeah,
like it was his job.
Yeah.
Like these guys,
maybe this possible can just.
You'd have to have be a freak of all
freaks.
It's like girls with giant natural tits.
Like,
whoa.
Where'd that Come from?
Like there they do exist.
God bless them.
Yeah.
Guys were huge hogs.
They exist.
Do they ever do people big noses?
Am I right?
Yeah.
Those love a guy with a big nose.
Sleep and eat either pussy from behind.
Some chicks love a big nose.
That's why it's very strange.
I want to back the knows they want knows
in the ass mouth on the pussy.
That's what they want it.
That's why they love a big doc.
Used to have a bit about it.
It's called doing the pigeon.
I think that's what it is.
I don't know for sure,
but as a girl,
as a girl,
you can't have a huge nose.
No,
that doesn't help.
It doesn't help.
No.
Like cyrano de bergerac.
It would help if she was lying on her
back with her head,
like leaning over backwards.
That knows could be like a taint rub.
Right?
That bird.
That bird is horrible to see that video
that I put on my instagram,
but this bird fucking up.
This chick a woodpecker finds these
chicks in this bird nest and Just
starts,
jack and horrifying.
Is that a.
Is that a woodpecker woodpecker crime or
is that like a pitch and he's fucking.
It's just aNother bird.
Some other kinds of birds.
He ate his brain.
See if he could figure it out and that
fucking chick can't do anything.
It's just getting literally stabbed in
the head repeatedly by a woodpecker.
OH my god.
Fuck woodpeckers on people.
we have a weird idea what nature is and
you need to see things like that,
like there's a great website,
instagram page.
Nature is metal.
Is that the one that I was at?
What I retweeted.
Nature is melted as nature's metal.
One of my favorite.
I go to that everyday.
Nature of metal is crazy.
It's all clips of shit getting jacked.
Everything is crocodiles,
jackin,
gazelles and hippos.
Jack and crocodiles and crocodiles,
jack and other crops are going ham on a
cruck.
That's an alligator,
but yeah,
otters.
Ruthless bro.
If an audit things that a look at that
thing that's a fucking hawk tearing
apart.
Another other bird.
Holy fuck.
Nature is metal.
Let me see.
I'm not sold yet.
There's one of a lion.
Oh,
that had.
Oh yeah.
Look at that crocodile.
Oh jesus christ.
Look at that one.
Crocodile with another crocodile in its
mouth doing a crocodile role.
Winging it through the air by its head
and ripping his face off.
Just date.
They are fucking ruthless.
Go take noted friends.
Friends,
disagree.
As I say,
nobody.
Look at that.
Fucking look at the teeth on that thing.
Do you see that?
A reporter,
he was surfing with his friends in sir
lanka last night,
got eaten alive by a crocodile.
Oh great.
He went to go wash his hair and I was
like,
oh,
cool story reporter.
Got them.
Blow the reporter.
You know the guy who his job was a
reporter.
He was out in certain lonca,
just vacationing.
Surf boarding,
saltwater croc dot his ass.
God damn saltwater crocs was terrifying.
Look at that one up top.
We've got the one up top with the deer.
Got jacked by a tree.
Look at that.
Palm tree dropped on his head.
The tree just fell on his head.
What are the odds are not good.
It's a terrible way to go.
Terrible way to go.
Just landed right on his head.
How the fuck does that only have 159
likes?
Because now we will talk about it and
get more likes despite the blow up
properly.
So we got 17,000.
Are you just going to blow?
It should nature is metal and then
underscore.
But go,
uh,
go further down.
There's some fucking crazy ones on that
page.
I go to this shit everyday.
I'm going to follow it now.
Yeah,
there's a lot of my that about the fuck
up.
That snake there.
Look at that one.
Yeah,
go,
go back.
Please look at this one with this
crocodile right here.
The mouth open with a zebra head in his
mouth.
look at that.
Oh,
you know what people send zebra head.
He sent me these all times because when
I was leaving hots,
I sent them a zebra and I'll let you
ever seen anyone a fucking ride.
a zebra.
You can't.
I'm a zebra.
People are like,
really?
Then they send me these all the time.
Look at the mouth on that thing.
That is a fucking dinosaur.
That's a dinosaur.
That zebra is fucking.
I'm not mad at his set of his teeth
either in that,
but um,
he's obviously older,
right?
Like,
that's an old fuck their teeth up pretty
quick.
They probably don't live that long.
I mean,
I woUld assume that zebras much like any
other animal that lives in the wild,
you know,
they,
iF you,
you know,
if you Can get to 10,
congratulations,
you did something amazing.
You're killing tHe game,
but those zebras,
if you're like looking at their,
um,
look at that.
How about the jack?
That mouse?
that's a metaphor for life.
Look,
picture the zebra stripes.
Those are designed so that align has a
hard time picking out one individual
animal.
Is that why they do it?
They're always together and to hurt.
You can't tell if you look at him.
I always wondered that because to me
they would stick out being black and
white and the goddamn desert,
no africa,
this is one of the things they did.
They put a collar on a zebra to track
them and every tIme they would do it,
that was zero get killed because they
could see it because they could see it.
It would stand out.
I can see that color.
Like that's the one.
See that there's a pattern that they use
for cammo that I'm like,
there's a company called firstlight.
They make like the,
if not the best,
one of the best,
uh,
hunting gears in the world.
It's like they make this really fine
merino wool clothes that they put
camomile patterns on and they.
When you sweat and merino wool,
it's like really good because you never
get cold.
It keeps your body says it's a natural
fiber,
but anyway they have this a one,
a pattern they use called asap,
a s,
a t all season,
all terrain and in a way it kind of
mimics what you see in a zebra.
So like what a zebra is like.
You can't make out the outline now
because there's the blacks and the
whites.
The contrast.
It's like you have a hard time for an
animal in this camp was black and white.
This campbell's got a few different
shades in it,
but the idea behind the invention of
this camp I was working one of the first
cameras like most camel's back in the
day used to be either like army shit
like vagina or they would be like
leaves,
like actual leaves.
A lot of companies started making like
where it looks like photo realistic
trees and patterns and stuff,
which kind of works kind of the whole
idea.
That's asap.
So see,
see how that is like it breaks up,
looks like you go up right up there to
the jacket.
Jamie.
The jacket right there.
Yeah,
that's a kind of a ghillie suit.
What has all this extra phrase to it
that you would use that if you were
hunting turkeys?
Because turkeys can see real good.
But when you're wearing that,
the idea is that all those stripes break
up your outline that say the exact same
reason why a zebra has that shit.
I did not know that.
I always wanted that.
I always wanted it to that.
So have you seen the new uh,
uh,
body suits doing the water for sharks?
So they have the suits?
Yeah.
Have you seen those?
The,
you're saying so there's sharks can't
see your electrical signal.
So we know it's for sharks that.
So they don't think you're a seal.
Oh,
what does it do as a different color?
Some of her black and white.
If you look at him,
there's this thing called hex hecs and
they're these suits that people were in
particular when they go to it.
And jamie,
what is this?
Carbon full sleeve wetsuit.
No,
that's just pretty.
If you go to like a fish,
I'd fuck you up if you're like,
yeah,
you look like a sweet,
delicious tuna.
Oda heck suit h e,
c s.
So I don't know if this is real.
So this is one of the things that I want
to,
uh,
just right.
Heck,
suit,
hecs suit.
Um,
I would love people.
Yeah.
Hex suit.
I would love people to tell me whether
or not this really works because
apparently your body is supposed to
admit some sort of electric electrical
signal.
And if you run your body over thiS
thing,
it doesn't,
it registers your body's electrical
signal.
But if you put this heck suit on and run
your body over this thing,
it doesn't register.
So that prove that it's really working
with you guys.
Chilling.
Turkeys.
I don't know that guys in shape.
I mean,
but it works apparently like noticeably
works in the water.
Like this guys,
what he's doing here,
he's just fucking day run.
No,
no,
no.
You can't.
They try to get the fuck away from you
with this heck suit on.
They've shown the difference between
wearing it and not wearing it and it
seems to see this I'm not impressed with
because he's about to shoot this animal
and that animal can't see them.
Anybody can do that.
I could do that with like clothes on if
the animal can't see it.
Doesn't matter.
Yeah,
but the animal doesn't see you.
It doesn't matter.
But if the animal sees you,
the idea is that this heck suit is
supposed to somehow or another to
protect you.
They shouldn't have shown that one
because that video didn't mean anything.
It's like you couldn't see that the
animal was looking his way.
So it's interesting though.
See the shows like see,
go back a little bit.
So watch it shows when they walk in.
No,
you just had it.
Just leave it alone.
Go back there.
Kinda watch.
See he's passing in front of it and
without hex you see how it registers now
with the heck suit on.
It registers very little and this is
somehow or another supposed to be red,
red.
Recognizing the electrical signal that
your body has to so bad because you get,
you get your piss on,
so I'm pissed off.
See,
this doesn't impress me.
There's a fucking armadillo.
Husqvarna romberg's test.
Anyone.
Do you know anyone that has one?
John dudley.
He believes in it.
That's why I'm curious about it because
I don't know how much there's John
Dudley right now.
Heck's testimonial.
I just don't know how much science is
behind it.
I mean a lot of times you want to
believe that things work and I think you
kind of.
It works with coyotes too.
That's the weird one.
Comedies like walk right up to people
that are wearing it.
The idea is that animals might have
certain sensors and the ability to
detect signals that you give off that we
just don't possess.
So because we don't possess those,
those abilities to recognize those
signals,
we don't recognize that these animals do
because we don't think of it as an
option and what they're saying is it's
entirely possible,
especially with predators,
apparently entirely possible that
animals emit some sort of an electrical
signal that animals are attracted to.
And then when they see this person
wearing this heck suit,
those signals don't come through and
they don't know what the fuck you are,
which is really fascinating.
See electromagnetic signal,
right?
Is that what it's saying?
Yeah.
I don't know how much of it is real
though.
Like I've never,
I've never seen a study on it.
They have studies on this.
I do that.
When you go up there,
when it says proof,
do they have a proof thing?
If you go to the top.
I like how it works.
Yeah.
How does it work?
That's where I'm looking at it.
There's no like,
oh yeah.
See I feel like hex blocks you
electrical signal.
Okay.
Seems to block that.
They think the real question to me is do
the animal see it?
They've done an extensive,
extensive studies on what animals do and
don't see as far as camouflage.
And I think one of the ways they've done
that and what kind of light they see.
One of the ways they've done that is
through like they have like deer farms
where they have undulates in captivity
and they feed them and they only feed
them if they can see certain things so
they show them certain things and that's
how they measure whether or not they're
actually able to recognize patterns
because some patterns are really good,
like some patterns just completely break
up the outline of a person to an animal
and the animal just see some weird shit
that looks like a bush size of the mesh
is crucial to effectively blogging,
humility,
faraday cages,
what it's explaining,
which is the part I was just kind of
look looking at this as the science
invented in 1836,
so just before a dude invented
chiropractor by an english scientist,
michael faraday.
A faraday cage is an enclosure made out
of a conductive mesh material that
blocks electrical fields by channeling
the electricity through the mesh to use
to protect electronic equipment from
lighting,
lightening strikes or in screen rooms,
which allows for environments to be free
of electromagnetic interference.
That makes sense.
What I don't know is whether or not an
animal can see that.
I'd like to know.
Yeah,
couldn't look.
Why don't you google?
CAn animals detect electrical?
I'm pretty sure that energy,
that's why it shows those flocks of
birds floating around.
From what I've read science things.
That's how they're communicating through
electric schools of fish or magnetism.
Magnets,
magnetic waves.
Electromagnetic waves is what?
Yeah,
I mean it only makes sense if you watch
those giant flocks of birds all flowing
together,
that they have some sort of way of
interacting with each other that we
don't understand.
Like what is it?
I don't know,
but there's something going on.
I mean there's no way you could ever get
people to fly through the air like that.
I mean,
I've heard people that said they've
taken like the god dose mushrooms can
see it when they're like all fucked up
on the beach.
They can see magnetic waves coming in
off waves and I've never been there.
Hi.
I apologize.
I took.
No worries.
That was brutal.
That was not a piss,
bro.
Listen,
this.
I was trying to be cool.
I don't know if.
Could tell thAt this shit sweats.
no,
listen to this.
What happened?
I haven't eaten anything all day.
And then went to starbucks.
I went,
you know what,
give me one of those nitrile I need a
venti.
And she goes,
we don't do vanities.
It's dangerous.
Only grind down that bitch bro.
It's like a crazy kind of like a pink a
guinness coffee that comes out of like
attack.
Oh.
It's like,
it's Just like caveman nitrile came in.
Nitrile is super strong,
but give me a venti no,
I get some shit to display.
nitrogenated coffee.
Yeah.
Super strong.
She goes,
I can't give it to you on the ground.
And went I find Just put two shots in
it.
She goes,
we don't recommend that I could put two
shots in it.
So that's what I got.
Two shots in it.
You see that slingshot bitch would do
shots in it.
She did that and halfway through talking
about camouflage,
I went,
oh shit.
Ms dot starbucks was right.
Yeah.
That horn the bozos.
Shit my pants.
I swerved out the closest I've ever come
to shit my pants on.
Fucking on a podcast,
on anything.
I shit my pants hands ever.
No,
no one.
Brian lyons says shit.
His pants because he was later mr.
Shell.
Yeah.
Hilarious.
Don't men don't shit their pants.
Spare pair of pants.
Trunk and just changed them.
What'd you do?
Oh,
you did.
How'd you clean up?
I just went to a gas station.
Oh sure he did.
He's still tony's guy.
Ever makes total sense.
Do.
I was trying to be cool and it's
probably a good idea to keep a pair of
pants.
Underwear,
socks,
shoes.
Why don't piquet tape one small change
of clothes and your trunk?
Always a smart move.
I never do it right,
but it seems like if you have a trunk,
what the fuck you karen.
What's in your truck?
You have rome.
I mean it's not like it's going to cost
you gas mileage.
Just a little baG.
It makes sense.
That makes sense for that.
Did you bring a whole upstairs?
Yeah,
bring a whole outfit and extra outfit.
So if soMething terrible happens.
Well,
I'll tell you right now,
something terrible will hAppen when I'm
on the four.
Oh,
five night goddamn slingshot with no ac.
Seeing my stomach is on the fritz.
like why did you get that thing?
like what was what was going on and gave
it to me for free?
yes.
That's ridiculous.
I'm not,
I'm not that stupid.
I'm going to have this.
They went,
yeah,
have it.
Yeah.
So you just have to tell people how
ridiculous it is.
They.
They didn't even say that.
I said,
if you want to post by whatever you want
to do,
man,
we want you to take this spin around for
me.
Cool.
RighT.
Might as well.
It's amazing.
I love the fact that it's got a stick
shift.
You need it for a spin off.
A weird one.
I drive that corvette.
The corvette convertible.
Yeah.
No,
no roof will flake a raw when I'm behind
a truck and got a foot rock spits up
when you go behind the truck and I,
I'd always get out of the way.
Yeah,
you got to be clever about how you
approach like large groups of cars when
you have a convertible for a motorcycle.
I guess that's why I liked it because
I'm more in tuned with what's going on.
Like fuck it,
I'm on it where it went off on my car
and so comfortable the pdk I can have a
case shit and jacking off whatever.
Yeah,
It's interesting.
Like does your car have the car play
thing where you can talk to it and tell
what jakks people amazing.
Is that ridiculous?
It reads the text
for you and it tells you a like,
would you like to reply?
And you're like,
yes,
I would.
bitch takes them back.
Whatever you want,
whatever.
You don't need to get texts anymore.
Texts him.
John,
I wonder if you could program siri where
you say bitch after everything.
Of course bitch.
Yes I do.
Bitch.
And if you don't say bitcH,
siri doesn't recognize.
I'm sorry,
what did you say?
bitch?
You hurt me.
You that new life phone drops next
month.
I'm stoked.
Sort.
Have you seen it?
There's a lifelong.
Finally,
there's two new ones.
I only tried a google phone for like a
month.
I feel like you're on that google trip
for a second though.
I did.
Well,
I tried to get off the apple tit and I
went with a mac lab,
windows laptop and I went with an
android phone,
kept abandoned boulder and the
announcement for it,
they said something when they were
showing the face id.
That kinda was alarming to me that I
didn't know.
Oh yeah,
the touch id one in 50,000
chance that someone just unlocks your
phone without your fingerprint.
Doesn't seem like that secure one in
50,000.
It's pretty goddamn security.
Jamie.
Pretty secure,
but I'll take my chances.
How many dick pics you can.
They can easily get on my.
I have a apple pay put on my phone so
like you can get.
You can start using my card right away.
Start paying for shit if you did my
phone.
The new ones.
It's face recognition and that's the
next one.
It says it's one of the problem with
that is well one of them.
I want my worried about that.
I'm worried about you being next to your
girl and you grill sticks your phone
right on your face.
That starts it up and then.
Oh look at this motherfucker.
Jamie vernon with a bunch of dick pics.
Oh,
once and then that one.
It's the same.
Fall asleep when she puts her thumb on
there and unlocks.
That's true.
She tries to get my face to touch me
when I'm asleep.
I will wake up immediately and choke
you.
Just for this one.
You said you were looking at it.
You have to like,
you have to have your eyes open so then
she drugs.
You need your fingers.
Pose your eyelids back.
She can do it.
Figure it out.
I'll just do is paint fake eyeballs on
your eyelids shut.
You're asleep.
But she's got white paint.
It just be crazy.
And then she puts like a little black
sharpie mark,
but it's like the most expensive phone
ever.
No,
I don't know.
It's like 1200 bucks.
I think if you're buying it outright,
that's spiderman.
Look at my phone.
My son broke the fuck.
I refused to get a new one.
Why?
I'm waiting for the coming out,
but it's interesting that they're coming
out with the iphone eight,
eight plus and the 10 all together at
the same time.
It's like,
look,
you can go packs.
You can go po it.
Skip the nine.
It's just the 10 year anniversary.
What jamie?
It says iphone 10,
how to pronounce the new iphone.
Then you have tim cook saying we call it
iphone 10.
Boom.
Correct me if you're wrong.
I didn't know that.
So there's a nine and a nine.
They skipped it.
Hold on.
So here's the thing,
you get these bullshit ass like dead
spots where you don't have a screen on
it,
so you could fear all poor next to that
person that has the 10 that has no
wireless charging.
Let's start with eight as where I was
charging two and it's waterproof now
like you can go in the ocean with it.
Can you know wHere the phone?
Yeah,
now its water resistance.
That one's just what little bit
waterproof.
The new one,
but the new new shit.
Water resistant swim.
Swimming underwater picks.
The new one is three,
right?
Iphone three.
watched the watches,
the cellular added to It.
I like it so you don't even have to
bring your phone.
You can go running and then you girls
back at home.
She's like,
I use your face to find your phone and
now I'm carrying from your own phone to
say,
fuck you.
I'm in your house on fire
dick pics,
saddened,
son of a bitch.
dude,
I don't get down with iphone watches.
Not my cup of tea,
but the phone call,
like three seconds later you're
receiving dead pigs to you taking it to
andy.
Jake wants to suck your dick and you
didn't block his number.
You said to your.
That's what I would say.
If I wanted a second guys,
dick,
I'd say hello.
Come on over and suck my dick.
Honest.
You just cut it out.
You're being so silly.
That's what they say.
If they know they're gonna,
sock it,
lol.
Yeah.
If you say and then they call you up and
go,
hey,
don't ever fucking texted me.
Something like that again.
I'm sorry.
Just joking.
That was like normal,
but if they go,
lol,
lol.
I was like,
she's like getting wet,
just freaking out,
lol.
You're silly.
If people say,
lol,
you silly goose,
you silly gobble driving over your
house,
taking the.
What is it about these new phones like
what do you really.
How much do you need that new phone?
How much do you need that new screen?
It's like it's a trap like and that's
going to be a piece of shit in a year
from now,
a year from now,
it's going to be some new thing.
That's everything though.
It puts pressure on you to get the new
phone because that's what's cool.
That's what's hip,
but they.
They're adding new stuff to it.
It's like the new car.
Where's the fingerprint reader?
There isn't one.
It's just your face where you can go
fuck yourself.
That's stupid.
What if I face kids beat up and us.
It knows it's learning with you and it
shouldn't because you would have been
looking at it earlier that day,
man.
That's kinda scared as we're learning
with you.
Yes.
Yeah.
What does it fucks up and that data is
all stored somewhere and it's supposedly
encrypted.
Jesus.
The apple has my face,
I just thought about what are they going
to do three or four or five years down
the line when they have five years of
your aging of daily 12,
15,
20,
30,
40 times a day.
Do you thInk it looks at kylie jenner
and goes,
who the fuck is that guy?
Yeah,
it's good to recognize girls.
Fucking give that kylie jenner surgery.
Is it kylie or clo?
which one's the
one as the most highly?
What?
What is it?
Where's the rest of your jaw?
What's going on here?
Get a new iphone every few months.
Just it.
I don't like that.
No fingerprint.
I don't.
I don't think I enjoy that.
I think that seems stupid.
You might love it though,
because we're going to take your face.
Hold it up and they'll pull you over.
They pull you over.
They're just going to take your phone,
put it up to your face.
All you have to do is give me your
phone.
I want to know wHat you're doing.
You can't look at my phone.
Oh yeah,
and they do that and then they can just
do it like people have.
Cops have tried to look in people's
phones before.
They've told people to see if they're
texting.
They're allowed to put your finger on
it.
They're not.
Yes,
they are.
they're not allowed to enter your
password then.
Not allowed for you to ask what the
password is.
That's why they'd say for people you
should not use the fingerprint part
because cops can actually actively use
it because it's not specifically stated
like you're not allowed.
Yes.
Lupo not allowed to tell someone you
want their password because that's an
invasion of privacy.
You are allowed to take their finger and
put it on their phone and open their
phone up.
What the fuck?
Exactly.
Yeah.
It's like technology moving too fast and
we don't have the words in the language
and the,
you know the preparatIons,
they're deal with it yet new system
built into the ios 11 which comes out a
couple of days.
That allows you to bypass that sort of
quick tap five times.
You can turn off touch id basically is
what they're calling it as a cop to
count one,
two.
What was it?
One shit?
Yeah.
I just don't think that's the way to go.
The facial recognition thing just seems
corny.
I gotta do this every time I want to buy
something.
No,
you can't just put my fucking dumb on
it.
You know what it is.
Here's the problem.
These cons can't fIgure out a way to get
your fingerprint right off your phone
yet right off the main screen.
That's what they've been working on
forever.
Trying to get on the big screen.
Yeah,
so you just touch anywhere on the screen
and it picks up your fingerprint.
That's what they've been working on
forever.
They do not have that yet.
So they went with facial recognition,
which they've already had for snapchat
and for instagram filters and all those
things.
Really see your face and then turn you
into abraham lincoln or some shit way
better than those,
but it's an acceleration of that.
Would they have been able to do is get
your whole screen to be a fingerprint
sensor and still be able to show images
and all that stuff.
Got something like six film selfie
cameras,
ones like thoughts like the camera was
doing.
It's like a little xbox.
Connect with the self is the camera
industry just doesn't just tell you
they're useless.
Last time you saw like a straight up
camera.
Well you'd have to be like a guy was a
photographer like jamie.
Then you carry those goofy brIcks
because you want to impress chicks.
You whAt he's doing is just take a
picture of the sheriff's autologist
earlier the lighting.
Let me just fix your hair.
Richard harris.
But even at that they like to pose.
Did they go?
Did you see them all the time that they
just go on like little photo shoot dates
with girls too and two,
three,
four,
five,
10 times and there's taking pictures of
each other.
They don't need to hire the photographer
anymore.
I've
seen that man.
I was at a restaurant and these two
bitches just kept doing that back and
forth wIth each other.
I was like,
ladies,
enjoy your meal cry.
And they were like,
no,
like this,
like this.
Hold on Phones.
Yeah.
This is the.
I'm about to take a selfie face.
ready.
There's a thing that girls do with their
neck that they only do when they're
about to take selfie.
This is it.
Ready?
Just that weird neck boom.
It's like,
shit,
this is weird.
Self like you don't ever do thAt.
And the other time,
except for when you're looking at your
phone,
you're just trying to sell,
right?
Nothing is.
Nothing is more awkward.
Seeing someone tried to take a selfie.
You ever seen that mom at the playground
with their kids trying to take selfies.
She takes 40 slumping selfies.
You just do like dispatch smile as what
you look like.
Okay.
You just roll with it doesn't always
look great.
You don't have tricking people but
filters.
That's how they do it,
man.
this is weird.
Chicken,
chicken,
chicken heads.
that's where it comes from.
Chickens be crazy.
It's not where it comes from,
but it belongs in it.
True.
It's in the same night.
Yeah.
Umbrella.
But that's a real chicken head.
Yeah,
I mean this is really,
this is,
trust me,
I've chickens fucking chicken.
This is.
That's what they do,
man.
There's nothing more awkward seeing
someone's trying to take fucking
selfies.
It's so embarrassing is definitely more
awkward.
Shit.
It's more awkward if your friend is
taking and you're a guy,
you're standIng there like,
hold on bro.
Hold on bro.
Oh my god,
hold on bro.
Hold on bro.
Like this.
It's so weird.
Why would he say your guy and you're
poking your ass out.
Like how many guys take pictures like
this?
Hippo.
I'm going to look,
look,
mysterious.
Thinking about this book.
I'm writing so awkward,
man.
I saw a story about a dude who died
because he was getting a dick operation.
What?
Yeah,
he's getting fat pumped into his dick,
like kim kardashian's ass,
but he just had a fucking heart attack.
Fat went through his bloodstream somehow
and his body locked up and that's a wrap
and he was like 32 or some shit.
How old is he?
Thirty,
30,
30 year old.
Relatively healthy person wanted a
penile elongation and girth enhancement.
Surgery hollow,
but girth,
which includes transferring from one
area of the body and replaced he see,
he doesn't understand.
When we talk about having a fat dick.
No,
that doesn't count,
does it?
It's like you take that literally you
can like George Foreman fists like,
man,
I wish I had a fish like george farms,
so pump fat in my mickey mouse gloves.
Sky fucked up,
man.
He fucked up.
Well,
he defInitely fucked up.
Now he's dead.
Hit a pulmonary fat embolism.
When fat traveled the bloodstream to his
lungs and ruptured blood vessels.
Christ first case of a seemingly simple
and safe procedure,
a penis enlargement by autologous fat
transfer cause of sudden death of a
healthy young man.
According to the report,
doctors believed this is the first case.
First of all,
doctors.
Fuck you.
Because that sounds like an ad for dick
surgery,
which you shouldn't get.
Okay?
Because you don't know what you're
doing.
You're just making weird fucked up.
Dick's.
You're not make a bigger delta.
It's,
it's completely useless procedure.
Well,
how about If never works in disfigures?
Man,
what have you.
Dick got fatter,
but the head was the same size,
big giant guy with a tiny head.
It is a steroid dude.
There's pictures of him on the internet
and his head is the size of a softball
and his body is as wide as this table
and is the weird.
It's like beetlejuice.
He looks like the henchmen from myra
brothers.
The movie,
if you remember that.
It might be faked out.
It might be like one of them social.
I love that guy.
Had not beetle.
Just willy was fucked.
Outstanding.
What a class is fucking phenomenal.
Move one of those remakes things that
are happening.
So he's going to be beetlejuice though.
I'm pretty sure it's like a sequel or
something.
Oh,
it'll probably be telling or she's
creepier looking better.
Do you see it?
I heard it's really good.
I need to say it.
I love shit like that.
It's exciting to last night people like
have you seen them?
Like,
you know,
like best movie eveR.
I
can't wait man.
I'm in me too.
I'm all in.
If figured out.
I think we need more monster movies.
Didn't you say that?
John landis,
his sons remaking american werewolf in
london,
they're redoing some like,
uh,
so in the same vein that the avengers
exists now,
they're doing the monster world where
the money is coming from the
frankenstein and the mummy.
You're goIng to hang out together and
we're going to get together.
like they're going to be a fucking
fighting team.
I love origin stories first and I'm sure
there's going to be a monster mash
fighters
now.
They drop,
drop the best.
Not what I asked though.
I'm pretty sure.
John landis,
his son,
john landis,
the original director of an american
werewolf in london.
My favorite movie of all time to watch
to this day.
Wow.
Which,
which one?
First one?
The real one.
The only one.
NIneteen.
10.
I don't know.
It was.
I
think I might have been like right out
of high school because they didn't like
85 or we're often.
So he's made comments against the remake
that his son is making is what?
Oh,
john landis is made comments against his
sons now work dick six hours ago.
The clarification of these comments,
how about you keep your mouth shut?
Pops just let your sunshine.
It won't do a damn thing is.
Yeah,
but what if your son was like eddie van
halen son,
and he just takes over van halen.
Oh,
that'd be a buddy.
Hey,
fuck face.
It'd be a superhero.
He starts singing.
He's like,
I'm van halen to.
No,
no,
no.
we'll check my last name.
I can't use the van halen name.
How about I'm mike van halen mike the
mike van halen band.
That's my.
Can I use that?
I'm gonna sink.
Panama.
Is that okay?
That hot for teacher kind of just had
the script process right now.
He's writing the script and it might get
made.
So it's not even.
Oh,
because his dad tweaking.
Someone probably asked him and there's a
ways to go blog about it and I spread.
Um,
what year was american werewolf in
london?
Made?
Let's guess.
I want to say 90.
I'll say 90.
No,
87.
We'll say 92 77 one way off.
But then that's great.
Another one,
like a more current one,
right?
Oh yeah.
American world from paris was terrible.
I'm thinking about.
I had that hot french girl oddly hops.
When you said that your favorite movie,
I completely judge you because I was
based on that because that's terrible.
That's so bad.
But that girl was in an amazing movie
that nobody's ever heard of called
killing zoe.
Let me see.
Email right around the time that see
pulp fiction was made by quentin
tarantino and Roger Avery.
A lot of people forgot about Roger
Avery.
Roger avery,
who was a brilliant,
brilliant screenwriter.
Really interesting guy.
And he went to jail for like a drunk
driving accident on the pch in malibu,
like serious stuff.
And he was actually tweeting from jail
for awhile.
Yeah,
it was way,
way,
way back in the day.
Yeah.
Julie delpy.
But Roger Avery was tweeting from jail
like really interesting shit.
And one of the things that came out of
that was that quintin tarantino,
you used to have this ramp that he did
about a top gun being like really gay.
And he did some movie but apparently
stolen straight up from Roger Avery did
his bit.
Roger avery had mapped it all out.
Oh fuck.
And you know,
just ganged.
Hook it.
Yeah.
And did it in a movie.
Did it in a movie?
Damn.
Yeah.
That's the word.
But the roger,
every movie killing zoe is with that
girl julie delpy and it's excellent.
It's really good.
It's a crazy like drama drama,
a crime drama movie.
Do you have to quinten tino?
can't miss.
I'll fucking kills it.
Kills it.
Yeah.
It's a bummer.
Then when you hear that he stole roger
avery's topcon thing.
And what I would like to hear his story
like maybe Roger Avery says he stole up
be him and clinton and Roger Avery came
up with it together.
Maybe they're drunk.
LIke going back and forth.
Yeah.
And then maybe quintin just wrapped.
But I know people have done that before.
Doug stanhope is,
had a problem with that.
Has guys opening with him and he'll be
on the road.
They'll go to a diner and he dug a be
riffing about something and they will do
it on stage the next day because they
don't think it's a bit.
It's like they're getting in under the
wire terantin here and screenwriter
Roger Avery with tumi pen pall fish.
And that's what I said.
It says this was originally written.
Yeah,
this,
but let's see if he says that for a
separate feature while it's compelling.
The theory,
uh,
Arizona one.
Oh,
is this the thing about him stealing it?
This is just about the theory itself.
And then this mentioned is him them
together writing it.
While it's compelling,
the theory airs on one key aspect of duo
argue that top gun is subversion on a
mass level,
but tony scott did not set out to make
starship troopers.
Much of it's homo eroticism was
happenstance.
OkaY.
I'm just showing you today and said that
they wrote it together here in this.
Find out of that.
Now that find out if that's true.
Like find out if a Roger Avery says
quintin tarantino stole that idea from
them.
So stay on hold.
we'll be at a restaurant just hanging
out.
Whatever.
Riffing has a couple of cocktails in.
I'm riffing with his opening acts.
This is a long time ago,
but he had a real issue with it.
And those guys would wind up doing his
riffs on stage,
like he was thorough and I don't think
you've wanted to say anything to him
because he was all pissed off.
I was like,
fuck man,
I can't even ran around you guys.
Damn.
Because that's like unspoken shit.
Not even unspoken.
It's like you can't do that.
That's stealing.
That's still ideas.
Yeah.
And a guy like stan hope rather.
Um,
that's how he formulates ideas.
He bounces them off friends if he can't
bounce them off you because you're just
dealing with shit.
And its concepts does happen though,
you know,
sometimes even this day and age though
because you found out so fast.
Yup.
Just like John Jones,
people still do it.
People still cheap.
They try,
he caught them comment with comedy
hanging out in the back and you say
something funny and then a week goes by
and some guy goes up and does the same
thing that you said.
Comedy comedy Is way easier to do that
with and say cheating with steroids.
One hundred percent because what
steroids.
The thing with steroids is you could
test it,
but the thing with comedy is you could
say,
I thought of it too,
and you're like,
okay,
well top gun does seem gay.
Think about it.
You know,
I mean val kilmer's faces all sweaty and
shaven.
He's goT this like gay fuck boy haircut
and him and tom cruise looking at each
other.
Tom cruise gets mad rides off when it's
motorbike because he's dangerous.
Dangerous people.
Buttfuck.
OkaY.
Yeah they do,
but fuck crazy care.
It was kind of slippery,
shiny,
smooth face.
It comes out of the shower with a towel
on,
looking at each other's eyes.
Play volleyball and yeah,
I mean it's not out of the possibilities
that you could come up with that too if
you just watch it.
You like,
yo dude,
is it me or is this a gay movie?
You can totally see you saying that.
That seems like a total credit shaoguan.
It'd be like it is book the woman.
What the fuck of woods?
A woman's name.
I forget the woman who plays is a girl
kelly something.
Press plays places a female love
interest.
She was probably like,
what is going on?
Fuck me,
goddamn sexy.
Who wrote it?
It's like,
oh,
the gay boy in the corner of the.
Literally like,
that's what it is.
Like he's struggling with his true
nature.
I mean that's something that anybody
could come up with.
But the question is,
did roger ever come up with it and did
quintin tenant terentino's steal it
because you don't.
Quintin tarantino has been accused
before of using the plotlines from a
bunch of real classic japanese movies
for his films.
Oh yeah.
Yeah.
Like,
um,
the hateful eight and sheet.
I don't know about that one,
but I think that was the thing with a
reservoir dogs.
I think reservoir dogs was essentially
almost like a tribute of a classic
japanese gangster moving.
Oh,
I didn't know that.
Yeah.
See if that's true when you would like
to other people googling concepts for
that.
He takes a lot of whatever influences
he'll call it,
but it's like direct steam scene,
stealing or whatever.
Which is why someone would probably
accuse him of doing this with the roger
everything online.
Do you ever see rodrick go to see?
If you could find Roger Avery tweets
from prison.
It was fascinating because he was in
jail and somehow or another he was able
to tweet.
I don't know how he's pulling it off,
but theY found out about it after
awhile.
And they,
candice,
shit will.
Twitter's been around how long?
Not that long.
Seven years.
Six years.
Eleven years.
Shit.
And this was at the beginning days of
twitter when hardly anybody was using 20
pulp fiction writer tweets on life in
prison.
Look at his face there.
January.
Was that say 2008 for drunk driving?
Yeah.
So he was quite a few years after it
started.
Um,
sickness spreads throughout the
facility,
like bush fires.
It was great stuff,
man.
I remember reading it is really
interesting stuff.
So you can find it that you wouldn't
even think about that,
like,
right,
like a sickness spreading through the
place.
Like a bushfire man.
Amazing poet with his word.
Well,
he's a brilliant writer and that's why
that movie killings zoe,
which is his movie,
did he.
What else did he make or underrated
starship troopers and said,
no,
I don't think that was him.
I think that was someone else.
They were just talking about the
homeowner versus quentin tarantino's of
attraction,
I think was the one big one he made to
do.
remember that?
Yeah.
A bunch of fucked up shit happening in
that movie.
He's got a weird mind for sure.
Going to have to be beowulf.
Beowulf.
That was a crazy movie,
man.
It was like a.
You're watching a live video game.
Oh yeah.
Bailiff is weird.
Oh,
silent hill.
Alright.
Yeah.
Beowulf is like they did at cgi,
but not realistic.
You remember that?
Well,
it started off as a video game,
right?
No,
this is a fable.
It's a.
It's an old,
old,
old story and they used a back when
angelina Jolie,
when she hypnotized brad pitt,
got him to stop drinking.
AdoptIng random it.
She cracked that dude.
She cracks them all.
That's a black widow right there.
Boy,
billy bob thornton,
maxim.
Maxim had billy bob thornton lower blood
around her.
They both were in each other's blood.
Crazy.
Yeah.
She was reading them back then.
It was just too powerful and attraction.
Those lips too.
Yeah.
That world out of the world.
That movie.
It was weird.
I didn't know that she was the tiger and
panda.
No,
killing the game.
Yeah.
But it's um,
the beowulf movie was fun because it was
like animated,
but like they used people's faces so it
was like kind of close.
But you knew it wasn't real.
It's real weird.
I don't know if you could pull that off
today.
You could.
It was,
yeah.
It was a fun movie.
It was good.
Like that movie.
Oh yes.
Avatars a little bit of that now because
avatar,
the people look like people.
And this will be.
Nobody looks like a person.
Yeah.
But the avatars look,
they do look like aliens,
but they still have the same kind of cci
quality.
Yeah.
Like you can tell it's the actor.
Yeah,
that's true.
But it looks a lot better than this shit
way.
That's also because it's not a person.
See,
that's the sneaky trick about cgi is
that cgi works best on something that's
not real because we have nothing to base
it off.
Exactly.
That's why cgi so bad witH animals,
like when you see like those wolves in
the game of thrones,
I'm like,
that's not really.
Although jungle book said what up?
It's not bad.
Pretty good.
Pretty fast.
Getting way better for sure.
I better.
It's like it's at the edge of what they
called the uncanny valley.
The uncanny valley is so like the gap
between something that looks hyper
realistic and something that looks
totally fake.
Yeah.
It's like you get to this point where
like,
wow,
almost.
It's real close,
but then he can't tell.
Wish I could stop clearIng my throat.
Try not to focus.
Fucked up.
You getting mad?
No,
it's the weed smoked weed.
Before this podcast,
I'll take over shitting my pants.
I'm worried for that slingshot.
We'll just let that bathroom up one more
time.
You don't want to get on that pch.
Start spraying people behind you.
When that ocean wind hits you.
Okay.
You're driving in your car and just shit
splatters on your windshield.
You should call you shit on my fucking
porsche.
We haven't problems.
If you are,
we're in that slingshot and use diarrhea
just flying out of your ass and you
maybe have beaver fever.
Fever is when people drink water.
They get out of the ground like a creek.
Water.
You get giardia.
It's from beavers shitting in the water.
like literally you're getting bacteria.
Giardia literally comes from animal shit
got be receiving from this,
but when you get it,
you're like hurting.
You got to put on my happy face.
LIke you have plenty of energy.
Yeah,
dot.
All right.
I'm going to get to any given blankets.
Shit,
man.
I just can't believe you haven't shared
your parents before ever.
I've even when I was a kid,
man,
one time made coming here just now.
I was coming home from fear factor once
filled my pants up like,
like uh,
one of them glad.
Hefty bag.
Like a construction worker.
Would you throw some benton there or
something?
I just couldn't hold it in.
I was like,
jesus.
Jesus.
Oh no.
It was just pick up a car.
Were you in a.
I don't remember.
Did you shit your supra?
No,
no,
no.
That was passed that in 95 or something
and he says let these logs.
I didn't want to.
I don't remember the exact specifics,
but I do absolutely remember failing my
underwear was shit in my car going,
fuck.
I just couldn't.
I maybe I'll stuck at traffic.
I don't remember the specifics,
but I for sure shit my pants.
It must be so bad for you to go,
fuck it.
He tried.
It was.
No,
I didn't have a bar.
There was no argument on my part.
I really didn't have the willpower.
There was nothing there that could stop
this date in place.
It was just going to take place.
This levels to everything,
bro.
This levels to diarrhea.
Grievance is certain levels of diarrhea.
Well listen,
I don't care how much fainter workouts
you've been doing,
things coming do you think?
I would imagine like,
but it's probably like,
you know,
girls do like cagle exercises,
exercises to me it's like,
man,
who's got that?
Is that muscle even devoutly you're at a
long road ahead of you.
Tiny man,
that bad bitch russian chicks and carry
weights.
There's a woman from Russia that has.
She has the world record,
it's like 70 kilos with her pussy.
She clamps down,
they put like a golf ball at the end of
a rope attached to a kettlebell,
or there's some boys that golf ball or
posting ads,
clamps it down,
carries that weight around.
I don't want that,
but your butt wiLl be way easier to
clamp down,
but I don't care who you are.
If you had the diary I had that day,
it's coming out.
I'm telling you right now because if you
get a metro brew with extra shots,
you go and sizzler in your pants.
How to do,
but key goals.
Here we go.
Here you go to this.
Uh,
what is the way,
what's the website we're dealing with
here?
Luxury spa.
Is it a grow website?
But kiehl's candles.
So what they are and how to do them get
larger.
Please.
Let me read this.
What?
No,
no.
Larger.
Yeah,
there we go.
Why do,
but key goals,
key goals are designed to tighten the.
Wow.
Look at this word.
P u b o c o c c cocky j.
G,
e u s who's foe?
Cock?
Gs.
Muscles,
your asshole.
The pec muscles are used for two things.
Clenching your anus and controlling the
flow of urine.
Anytime you stop yourself midstream at
the urinal,
these are the pec muscles at work.
Hmm.
Well,
my shifts working overtime right now.
My,
my,
my anus clench,
and I'm like cain velasquez.
I've stamina.
Women was strong.
Pec muscles tend to have tighter,
stronger vaginas,
which often means stronger contractions
during orgasms.
If you know anything about orgasms,
you know that stronger is always better
says in all caps.
If you know anything about orgasms,
that's not a very technical way to
write.
Men on the other hand,
use the pc muscles to stop their urine,
mid flow,
but also to stop urine from coming out
in the first place when you feel the
need to use the bathroom,
but have to hold it thanks to a long
line.
Those are the pec muscles doIng the
work,
so you're crunching your pec muscles so
you can stop your flow of pis or you're
tightening up your asshole.
Oh,
you will be able to clench,
to stop gas from passing through your
anus to hold your waste until you reach
the toilet and even to eliminate waste
more efficiently,
be supposed to be better at getting
buttfuck.
Is that too tied down?
Why did he leave that out of there must
have.
But key goals is an exercise that they
use for tightening your vagina to
enhance intercourse.
So you're calling it key goals and
you're saying,
I'm doing it.
Stop shitting myself.
How often is this taking place?
Maybe you should reconsider your diet
for you.
Sit around like an asshole.
just clench your butt all day.
Well,
I wish I did those exercises last night.
Oh,
well no.
Then he would be fatigued.
You want to do them?
Like two weeks ago,
friend started out.
Expect this though to build up.
I did my run today and uh,
uh,
went harder and stronger than I've ever
done it before.
I still suck at it.
But instance,
it's all hills.
You know,
I'm doing this doing two miles and these
very steep hills,
but I'm can do it longer.
Just I know I suck at it still,
but when you know that you make it just
like a little bit of progress,
just a little bit of progress,
you know?
That's
the same thing with buck eagles.
You can't just.
I've been doing this,
are running for a long time.
Right.
I've been in london for a long time.
Still running shoes.
Not today.
Today I didn't because I've been.
I've been hunting with these things.
He's solomon's don't have laces on them.
No.
Like for kids,
they pulled tight with like a cord and
then slides down.
The court tucks into the mouth.
Your shoe.
very easy to tighten up when you're in
the field out there in the field.
Enough time to issue,
but I liked the vibram five fingers
better,
but I've wanted to get a real hard
running today and I have to be more
careful where I step when I wear those
five fingers shows I can just go
reckless,
hard,
full out with these things on.
I'll step anywhere.
It doesn't matter so he can get a better
workout.
Yeah,
because with the vibrams,
if I hit a sharp rock,
I'm kind of fucked with this.
I'm not even feeling that shit with
these things.
I can run over pretty much anything,
but I think for,
for controlling what's up,
so close to it,
but it's almost 2:00
I want to fuck with my speedster muscles
or whatever it is.
Keep it together.
It's your face,
your face ready as you like jesus,
you know he liked,
you know what your face looks like.
A teacup ride at disney when you do the
thing is spinning and kind of going too
fast.
Like oh me,
I don't be the first to get his shit,
his pants,
me and campaigns and our kids got in one
of them tea cup things and with me and
him going full clip.
I mean full clip.
I don't know how.
I don't.
There's a limitation on how fast those
things go,
but it ain't getting anY faster.
We got it.
It was so ridiculous.
We were spinning so fast.
Sick.
Oh totally sick.
My youngest,
my seven year old is fucking nuts.
She loves to go on those things fast.
Like there's a carousel at the mall.
It's actually way faster than one at
disneyland.
Really?
Yeah.
They have a tea cup thing on there and
you write down the street that the panga
mall,
you grabbed that fucking steering
wheels.
Just whipping around.
It goes so fast.
Your head is like you're holding your.
You have to use all your muscles to keep
your head from just bending over.
That's what you look like right here.
You like to say?
Yeah,
I'm a.
It's the same thing as like you're on a
teacup.
Like,
ooh,
I really do.
Just stick your ass hole up with the air
when you get on the highway.
When you come over the crest of the
four.
Oh five.
And you get that big long hill.
just pull your pants down,
lift your ass in the air.
I'll take you to paint your canvas.
No one sees me.
Shit that slingshot out.
Cowan has a great story about being
another girl once,
like many,
many moons ago,
and he was going on a hike with her and
he had a shit and so he came up with
something.
Hold on,
I hear something and he like made a out
of it that he ran and shit and she
thought it was really funny,
you know,
and she's like,
what are you doing?
Nothing.
I heard something.
I thought no big deal.
It's just making sure that we're safe.
And then there were kept hiking and
things like,
oh my god,
I have to shit again.
And they ran away again and she's like,
what are you doing that she realized he
was shitting.
oh no,
no,
sorry.
This is out there in the woods.
Shitting himself is just nothing you can
do is life.
It is a weird thing,
man.
Like inefficiency of the body,
like breaking everything down but not
this stuff.
Get it out of here.
Your body's like this.
not good man.
Get it out here.
I wonder if like hot lava.
That's a good.
Is that a good design like fishing
animal?
Is there any animal or plant is a plant.
do that.
Like the plant takes things in,
but the plant doesn't shit anything out.
Right.
Putting it through the waist does it.
It gets rid of,
gets rid of oxygeN.
It processes carbon carbon dioxide and
turns it into oxygen,
but it's not waste.
That's like us.
We breathe out carbon dioxide.
I wouldn't necessarily say it's waste,
it's just we're transferring.
We're quite a few.
If that carbon dioxide was in your body,
you die.
Right.
So we're getting rid of it.
No,
no,
it doesn't kill you.
You obviously you're making it.
You're pushing it out.
You just don't want to have too much.
But do you know that the,
the air is not really mostly oxygen.
do you know what most of the areas?
Nitrogen,
nitrogen,
like a massive percentage of it.
I think it's in the high eighties,
right?
Want to say 68 percent.
Something like that.
Let's find out what the plants.
Just to turns it into carbon dioxide.
That's there.
That's it.
That's all they do.
That's amazing.
They can do it.
So what they're getting out of the water
and out of the soil.
They figured out a way to use.
But what percentage of the air is
nitrogen?
I really want to say it's in the
eighties,
but I don't know.
I'm just making it up.
You know,
they pull nitrogen out of the air and
use it for fertilizer 78.
Goddamn,
that's high.
It's a lot.
It's mostly nitrogen.
Twenty one percent oxygen.
That's crazy.
You would think of the air is mostly
oxygen and carbon dioxide.
That's what I've been taught in school.
But all the other animals,
living organisms may besides plants
released the ways we do every other
mammal fish.
They all do it.
You know what's crazy is that um,
the,
there's nitrogen around us all the time
and the dude figured out how to extract
that nitrogen out of the air and use it
for fertilizer.
And that's why there's so many people on
the earth today because a guy named
fritz harbor and he made something
called the harbor method of extracting
nitrogen.
Did iT like in world war one to genius
also created [inaudible] a,
which is the shit that they used.
They changed,
you know,
the stuff that they,
they gassed the jews with fucking he
didn't mean camps.
No.
He made his icon a which had a scent to
it.
And then they re because.
So you could tell what is there to get
away from it and they removed the sent
and created zyklon b and that's what
they use,
the gas,
the jews and the gas chambers.
Man.
Crazy.
And he was jewish,
he said more fucked up.
So he was there during world war one.
And then when world war was happening,
that's when he had to leave Germany and
one of dying of a heart attack.
Yeah,
It was crazy shit,
man.
He was a,
he was also,
this was the nuttiest thing about harbor
at the time.
He was receiving the nobel prize for
creating the harbor method of extracting
nitrogen out of the atmosphere.
Rightfully so.
He also was wanted for crimes against
humanity because he was gassing the uh,
the british and canadian,
I think it was troops,
like when they first started,
he was waiting for the first guy that
initiated a gas attack.
Jesus christ.
Crazy.
So this guy that's responsible,
the nitrogen from the harbor method is
responsible for some insane percentage
of the nitrogen that's in people's
bodies that comes from food.
Like the thing,
it's something around like half,
like half of the nitrogen that you have
in your body from food.
It was a direct result of them
extracting it out of the air with the
hopper method,
which is like what?
And this is the same guy that was
gassing allied forces and this is the
same guy that created this icon,
a which eventually became zyklon b used
to gas.
The jews.
Really brilliant dude,
but nuts.
His wife apparently shot herself in
front of him because she liked.
She disagreed with who knows what The
whole thing was,
but what he was doing and he was off to
war and all those things.
So in front of him he shot himself.
He left his dying wife with his 13 year
old son,
said,
see I got to go to war is a terrible
person.
Who knows.
I mean,
who knows what the actual circumstances
where,
you know,
like I guess you'd have to get like all
the variables are what,
why he left the sun.
Might have had other people to watch out
for him.
He couldn't.
He had no option other than to leave.
Have they killed the drop them off at a
friend's house for god's sakes.
I don't know if the kid was with
somebody or not is my point,
but that's the story behind it is this
one brilliant guy figured out a way to
extract nitrogen,
became this a fucking monster.
A monster.
Yeah,
but also the reason why.
I mean maybe somebody would've figured
it out eventually,
but he's the reason why they were able
to do that during world war.
I think someone eventually came along
and figure it out.
Yeah.
Does she post that stuck with most
things with most things.
I think that was the case with the
invention of the light bulb.
I think there was a bunch of people that
are working on at the same time and the
invention of a.
I think the telephone was the same
thing.
Radio is the same thing.
There's always like almost inventions.
Like we were talking about that chip
that sort of rewires your dna.
There's always these inventions that
opened up the possibility of other
inventions and the technology that
allows for an invention like that gets
analyzed by a bunch of different people.
So there's,
you know,
it's always one of those things
where anytime something happens today
there's a network,
it's very rare that one person figures
one thing out that nobody ever saw
before.
It's like there's a network of
inventions and innovations at all.
Yeah.
Because you need machines and computers
and all these different things that
other people have created that allow you
to do the calculations to invent
something new.
So all it feeds off of all of it.
Then isn't it the best kind of.
Sometimes the best marketer,
best talker,
they get the notoriety for it.
So sometimes yeah,
sometimes just like fighting right?
Full circle.
So before we end this canelo or gennady
golovkin oh my god,
what a fucking fight.
What you lady is mexican.
So you've got to root for canelo.
Otherwise from the central,
downtown guadalajara,
they'll kick you the fuck out.
I'm rooting for a canelo.
I'm rooting for a good performance
brennan shop because that's what I do.
That's what you do.
I do.
I have to know about this case.
Yup.
Why?
Because I want to see what happens.
I want to see what happens.
I don't have like a guy I want to win.
Like if Virginia triple g wins,
I'm not going to be bummed out.
No.
I want to get fight.
exactly.
I want to see what happens when I'm that
guy.
I don't see either guy lose.
Like I like both of them.
I got to lose.
I don't want anyone to have that l today
too.
Oh yeah.
With that little kid punched that guy in
the deck.
That's his son punched that guy in the
dick.
BIlly Joe Saunders.
He's a great following.
This little kid on the fucking like he
gets on the scale.
He gets on the scale and the guy's like,
no,
don't do that.
Dude said,
look at this.
He's flexing kids on a scale and he just
like,
what's up man?
And he punched him and he kicked him.
That's so fucked up.
That's such a bad look.
Well,
it's so stupid that they let that little
kid be there.
What if he punched that kid right in the
face?
Shut the fuck up.
Please slap him.
If he kicked him,
be good to go.
Thai boxing,
right?
I'm about to throw up really going on.
Yeah.
the lady aT starbucks says shots.
She's fucking right.
Yeah.
You can't add extra shots to a caveman.
Nitric lasers.
Tate tate.
Fletcher can consume.
He can throw that caveman nitrile down
like it's water.
Let's just wrap this up before you shut
yourself in.
Shit myself.
What do you think's going on here?
Not good at this.
My prediction.
I think if triple g doesn't stop him,
canelo wins in a decision.
The public's piss because you got To
look at the politics of it.
Golden boy.
Canelo is the woodland.
Wait a minute.
You.
You're saying if triple g hold the music
place.
He's saying if triple g outboxes and we
won't get the decision.
Nope.
Box him for you.
I think you would because I think it
sets up the rematch.
I think you'd get a rematch no matter
what.
Even if it goes decision,
as long as no one gets stopped.
So you really think that if triple g he
puts on a show and outbox for like 10
rounds,
which I don't think you will.
I think it's even close.
Like let's say it's like seven to six,
something like some crazy,
you know?
Yeah.
My concern with caneLo is that he might
not have the endurance for a prolonged
firefight and you think triple g does
because he done against jacobs a pretty
tight against jacobs now.
That was a goddamn firefight as well.
And come on that fight because it was
close.
Oh,
I thought he won the fight.
I'll give it to.
It was a very fucking clothes.
Jacob's completely different fighting in
the canal.
Jacob has watched that the other day.
Great fight.
I forgot how good it was.
Jacob's is a motherfucker clear some
space on my dvr.
So I was deleting some boxing matches
like us goes to a certain thing like why
do I have 100 ted nugent spirit of the
wild safe to ship.
So I got to that fight and I said,
well let me wash this again because it's
triple g fights coming up this weekend.
That was jacob's can fight his ass off.
That was a great fight.
Toughest fight for triple g go.
He's over the hill,
you know,
jacob's just legit and completely
different.
Funneling canelo,
his footwork,
it makes me wish terence crawford,
but just a little bigger.
I know because he's about 45 now who go
up to 47.
He was the flight pack.
Yo.
Yeah.
I wish she was like one 62 thin fella,
you know,
but I just tell them all.
I think pArt of his style is like he's
built perfect for the way he fights.
Yeah,
no perfect endurance.
If you put more weight on him,
he'd probably be weighed down a little
bit of slowing down like that.
He's definitely in a zone 40,
47.
That's the right way.
Class.
A killer year man,
because now they have anthony joshua,
he's fighting and then you have legit
goliath heavyweight champion.
Built like a statue.
It looks like a greek god.
Like really well spoken.
Super polite.
Under around british guy.
Yeah.
And then you got a wild or deontay
wilder fighting a fucking.
What's the name?
Uh,
the fucking cuban killer.
Oh yeah.
King kong.
Yes.
It's fighting him.
Yeah.
I think it's a rough flight for.
Yes.
I think it's a bad idea.
The winners of each of those will fight.
It's good time for boxing,
but tomorrow's the big one.
Tomorrow is the big one.
Tomorrow.
Can't wait.
Shows who the superstar of boxing is.
[inaudible] loma chanko I think is like
one of the most skillful guys ever.
But he's not being challenged.
there's not a lot of drawl.
Well,
there's also not a guy in his division
that stands out as being the guy who has
to fight.
He's like mighty mouse.
Yeah.
Whereas like canelo and triple g is the
fight that everybody's wanting to see
for awhile.
I think you'll get a trilogy anello up.
Who knows?
Who knows how it plays out.
I can't wait though.
Yeah.
I wonder.
I'm really wondering what's going to
happen.
I'm super fascinated.
Me too.
And then you also have,
what do you think about David Branch
versus luke rockhold tomorrow?
He's somebody.
I haven't seen it myself.
People are like,
hey,
have you seen rockhold at wayne's
doesn't look the same to what wins they
had.
Wayne's I yesterday.
Oh,
yesterday at williams.
So I thouGht wheN you're saying at
wagons,
I was thinking like other ways.
Like what?
Wayne's a here.
I forgot that it's today.
Yeah,
today was the fights tomorrow they'll
wayne's.
We're today.
Yeah.
Yeah,
and people were Complaining about it.
Let's to get a pIcture of luke rockhold
from today's.
When looks at it,
you could argue is the best middleweight
in the world.
He,
you know,
he had that rough.
Can you argue with that?
Michael bisping knocked him out.
We hear me out and then you could say
he's not because michael cubism is the
real champ,
but he got caught by busy.
Right?
But before that,
luke rockhold is a motherfucker.
Hector lombard's back.
Did you hear that?
A tiago alvarez had a back out they guy.
Was that what it is because of a
hurricane.
There's nothing wrong with rockhold.
He looks fine.
The fitness I've ever seen him talking
shit to each other.
Rockhold should want to hear what he was
saying,
man.
Oh listen,
David Branch.
No joke,
dude.
Don't get confused.
If rockhold fucks up and gets clipped by
branch,
what is it?
What are they saying to each other?
They volume branch.
Been talking shit for a while and yeah,
see if you can hear it.
Former ufc middleweight champion.
Luke rockhold versus the ninth ranked
david anik,
we hear this
break,
break you up.
ShIt talking.
What does that mean?
I'm going to break you off,
son.
That'd be funny.
If you get all up in that area.
what does that mean?
What does that mean?
What exactly does that mean?
You're going to want to fight,
right?
You know the swIng.
Do you break me out?
You're going to pray.
I mean,
does that mean luke's been gone for
awhile?
Branch is a tough customer and he's a
former world champion at world series of
fighting at light heavyweight
middleweight,
but if you're not in the ufc,
I don't give a fuck.
You're not fighting the same guys.
Luke rockhold thought,
well,
he fought rumble.
Anyone went to a decision and a decision
to rumble in world series?
I light heavyweight.
Yeah.
That's rumbling world series.
He was a world beater.
It wasn't that long ago because it
wasn't the rumble in the ufc.
Also dave branch.
How does running the ufc before world
series?
Not good thing.
It was a world series of fighting does
work well.
Gerald harris kao at him with a slam and
his first fight was a great thing to
see.
Yeah.
And then he lost to somebody he'd say
like it depends.
Like how focused,
motivated,
very skillful,
very skillful is ground gives very good.
Talking about branch branch I think on
the ground.
Right.
It may see he can't say underrated
because he's under because he was
fighting,
playing grab ass and world series of
fighting.
It's not even close to.
I mean you're talking about wmb compared
to mba.
I Just think he's very talented and
have.
Rocco doesn't take them seriously the
same way.
It didn't take Bisping's seriously.
He get fucked up 100 percent,
bro.
There's a lot of pressure on rockhold
because he's been gone for awhIle.
You know,
he needs that.
He needs this when my.
The only way I think rockhold gets
fucked up is again,
yeah,
if you don't take him serious and if you
know if his heart's not in it,
but if a game rockhold shows up a game
day,
brand shows up,
rockhold destroys them.
You know what rocklIn could see
recording even submitting them
underrated with his top position,
because the top game is like having a
fucking tree on you.
[inaudible].
Ridiculous,
ridiculous.
You look at the.
The leo machida fight beat the shit out
of them from the top position.
He looked like when he fought weidman
down.
When he got weidman down,
you could see like why moves like
shocked.
He submitted bisbing with one arm after
a head kick,
but still I think.
I think if rock called stand up is gonna
be the difference maker and he's got a
long reach man.
It's huge.
It's got to make sure that he doesn't
fuck up and get clipped again.
But I want to see what happens because
when a guy like rockhold who has a lot
to lose but not a lot to gain fights,
a guy like branch who has the golden
opportunity in front of them.
I mean if branch can beat rockhold,
just gigantic elevator.
I mean huge and I've been watching this
training footage.
he sees training fucking hard.
Just the question is,
is it hard enough?
Has he been.
Is he in that kind of shape?
Is he at world class level?
He's really never fought anybody like
rockhold other than rumble in the world
series.
But also with branch it's like,
are you gonna?
Take the fucking governor off and go
after it because it's his last night.
Maybe it's just a dance partner.
Even the world citi is findings out
murking guys.
So it's like in the ufc,
he's never been that guy.
Everyone was afraid of luke rockhold
take the governor off and kick in the
fucking face.
It's a very interesting fight because
it's supposed to be.
If you looked at it on paper,
it would be more of a showcase fight for
rockhold.
Rockhold was the former champion.
I don't think David Branch is ranked in
the top five.
I think he's nine.
Yeah.
Yeah,
that makes sense.
So it's a big opportunity for branch.
You know,
how old is branch?
I want to say he's like 30 seconds till
the black death.
How dare you,
you suffer good thing.
Sure.
Thirty five.
Yeah.
So it's not too old.
It's going to be interesting.
And then brock hold is like what?
Thirty?
Rocco was still pretty young.
I think that the thing about rockhold,
he needs this fight because out of
sight,
out of mind fund a grip.
So everyone's like,
all right,
let's see it now that everybody
remembers.
Bisping clipping them,
knocking them out and then talking mad
shit to him inside the cage after he
knocked him out.
Is this fight tonight or saturday night?
Tomorrow night.
Is it for sure tomorrow night?
Or do you want fight campaign?
Yen.
But you're not going to be here.
You guys do a fight campaign instead of
a wash.
Atlanta,
triple g.
I can't miss it.
I gotta see I gotta go watch a little
bit of lag.
Little bullshit fucking screens here.
Yeah.
Oh,
we'll watch both.
Do you want to put one of them on
youtube as well?
Bravo playlist.
The background.
You see tower seven collapsing.
We'll put a k one on one of the.
Can't miss it man.
Yeah.
This car is not that bad.
You know?
It would have been a lot better with
thiago alves and Mike Perry.
that would be a crazy fucking fight.
A monster to both american top team too.
That's right.
Yeah.
Perry's a monster,
but tiago is just very skillful.
There's a big difference.
Okay.
It's fine.
Alex rayez stepped up.
Alex rodriguez is no joke,
man.
13 to who's Alex Ray as short notice
I've seen him fight.
Yeah.
Right.
Like what kind of shape is he in?
Kenny?
Make the wait.
Was thIs say no record there?
It's not.
While they have to update it.
Fight history.
All right,
let's wrap this fucker up.
Good night.
Every body fighter and the kid t fat
k.com.
Long beach.
Next friday.
Laugh factory packed factor k.com.
Live.
Um,
tickets for the first show.
Just went on sale today for new years
eve.
Tickets for the second show.
The 10:00
show or I think they're sold out at the
wiltern in los angeles.
And the great and powerful ian edwards
who is,
in my opinion,
one of the funniest fucking comedians
working in the world today.
So a first show is going to be at 7:37.
Second show is at 10.
Seven 30 tickets went on sale a couple
of hours ago.
Alright,
you fuckers we'll see you soon.
Bye bye.
Big kids.