Hello Freak bitches,
but then over the course
of the maybe three,
four or five years or so,
they started having real issues
and they don't necessarily tie that to
the Diet because they remember feeling so
much better when they
first switched to it,
so they don't think
that what they're going,
what's happening three
or four years later,
it could be the cause of their problems.
I see this all the time with
vegetarian and Vegan diets.
That's exactly what I want to
talk to you about in terms of that
because most people who switched to a
vegetarian or Vegan Diet,
you're going to see some instant benefits
because of the fact that you have much
more nutrient dense foods.
You're eating a lot of vegetables,
you're you're,
you're changing your die in a lot of ways
to the positive or towards a positive
away from what you were talking about,
those primary foods and Americans
tend to eat all the processed sugar,
all the,
that just nonsense and chicken tenders
and all that crap that people eat,
which is just so goddamn common,
right?
So automatically over that you're
going to see some longterm benefits.
But one of the things that I've been
reading is about people that have found
that over the longterm,
the lack,
this is contrary to what
a lot of people think.
Yeah.
Lack of saturated fat and cholesterol,
dietary cholesterol and saturated
fat leads to hormonal imbalances,
leads to your body having a harder time
producing sex hormones and all these
different issues with your health or
your body almost starts robbing itself to
make up for the nutritional
deficiencies of your diet.
Yeah,
yeah.
I mean,
uh,
we talked about this before,
but humans are animals and we're,
we're,
while we're omnivores and wait a minute,
I saw a video on youtube.
There's a guy that says there's
no way that we are herbivores.
And then if we were so fucking wacky,
dude was saying,
if we,
if you're really a,
an,
uh,
an Omnivore,
you should be able to eat a squirrel.
Just grab it and eat it raw and like,
yeah,
no,
it's just the most bizarre.
There's some strange arguments out there.
It's like we shouldn't
drink milk because you know,
there were the only,
uh,
you know,
we're the only animal in nature and in
nature that drinks the milk of another
animal.
Yeah.
Well we're the only animal
nature that uses iPhones too.
I have a whole bit about this.
It's hilarious you said that.
Yeah.
What else?
Appointing people do fly planes,
movies,
call each other on the phone and
tell each other how awesome milk is.
It's a ridiculous argument.
But,
um,
so yeah,
getting back to,
to their ideological arguments
more than scientific.
Absolutely.
Yeah.
So it doesn't stand up to scrutiny,
but with,
with,
with a vegetarian or Vegan Diet.
So there's lots of different
ways to look at this.
This starting with an
evolutionary perspective,
which I was getting at.
Um,
omnivores are opportunistic.
They will eat whatever is available
and they'll eat the most nutrient dense
foods that are available
if they have a choice.
And that's just,
again,
that's survival.
You know,
an animal that is able to utilize the
nutrients that are available in its
environment to maximum advantage is
going to survive compared to one that
doesn't.
That's basic evolutionary theory.
So,
um,
if you study traditional peoples,
as far as I know,
still there's never been a traditional PE,
you know,
group that that has ever been identified
that voluntarily followed a Vegan or
even vegetarian diet that I know of.
So that should tell you
something right there.
And ironically,
the fact that you and I are
even having this conversation,
this wouldn't even be happening if
humans had not learned it's eaten meat
basically where there are
a lot of anthropologists
who now believe that eating
meat was essentially what made us human.
You know,
we came down out of the trees and we
developed the development of tools that
could crack bones to give
us access to the Merrill,
which is super nutrient
dance or to sliced meat,
which allowed us to be able to
digest the meat more quickly.
Um,
number one.
And then to the development of fire,
which allowed us to cook meat and
cooking makes the nutrients in meat more
bioavailable,
allowed us to spend less
time foraging for food.
So most large prime,
it's like gorillas or chimpanzees span
over 80% of their day foraging for food
because most of the foods they
eat are really not nutrient dense.
So they have to eat a boatload of stuff
and just sit there and chew on the
plants all day to get enough nutrients.
And,
and so this evolutionary theory is that
we learn to extract and harvest much
more nutrient dense foods from animals,
fats and and other nutrients
and the meats and organ meats.
And we had,
we could then spend a lot less of
our time going around getting food,
which allowed us and then develop
bigger brains and you know,
become human and have this conversation
where we're talking about a vegetarian
and Vegan diets.
Yeah,
it is kind of an interesting,
and it's also important to differentiate
the difference between what you're
saying is essentially this science behind
the development of the human animal,
right?
Versus the moral and ethical debates
that lead and environmental debates,
which is also moral.
So we can,
we can,
we can talk about that too,
which is what influences people
to become vegetarians and vegans,
which I totally respect.
I understand what they're saying.
The real problem is when they distort
the reality of the scientific findings,
the human animal and diet.
And that's an issue with a lot of people
that are vegetarians and vegans that go
on about how healthy they feel
and how about how awesome,
but they're not doing
blood lipid profiles.
And when they do,
like Sam Harris,
who is kind of the forum
for ethical perspective,
for ethical reasons,
is tried a Vegan diet and
his health is suffering.
He's getting real issues
with his blood lipids.
Yeah.
What can someone do if they
want to file that diet?
Like what,
what is imperative as far as
healthy fats as far as getting,
making sure that your body doesn't have,
you're not taking in too many
simple carbohydrates like,
hey,
what,
what steps need to be taking place?
And this is obviously not saying
that you shouldn't fall Vegan Diet.
It shouldn't follow a vegetarian diet.
You should do whatever you want to do.
But there's gotta be some ways to
mitigate some of the health consequences,
right?
Yeah,
there are.
And I believe that I agree with you that
people should be free to make their own
choices.
I've never pushed a particular diet.
You know,
people sometimes ask me,
how do you convince someone to go Paleo?
I said,
I don't,
I don't spend my time doing that.
If someone wants my advice and ask me,
I'll give it to them,
but I'm not going around proselytizing
for a particular way of eating.
Um,
so yeah,
let's break this down.
And we talked about the evolutionary
argument for eating animal products and
there's a scientific argument,
which now is what we're
talking about the issue with.
And we should,
we should even kind of distinguish
between vegetarian and Vegan diets cause
they're,
they're actually quite different.
And I think it is possible for some people
to be healthy with a vegetarian diet.
I think it's a lot less
likely with the Vegan Diet.
And I guess I would say it this way.
Um,
if you have,
if you're Vegan and you're
eating a Vegan Diet,
you need to have a perfect vegan diet
to be healthy and you need to know what
you're doing in terms of supplementation
and how to meet the nutrient needs that
aren't being met through diet.
And at least in my experience,
there are very few that
actually do it right.
Um,
when it's done right,
I think it's possible
for some people to be,
to,
to be healthy and thrive.
And that's obvious because
there are people like rich
roll who's like out there.
He's a Vegan triathlete who's out
there doing centuries and killing it,
ultra marathon.
He is just an amazing
athlete and he's Vegan.
And so,
you know,
you can't say that it's not working for
it and you can try to say that you're
going help.
So it looks like he's
30 years older than me.
Yeah,
he's a,
he's a great guy.
I've met him a couple of times.
Um,
and uh,
so it certainly,
it works for some people,
but there are a lot of factors that
determine whether it's going to work.
So one is how well you
do it too is you know,
whether you know what you're dealing with,
supplementation in terms of
getting the necessary nutrients.
Three is genetics.
So let me,
there are genetic differences that
determine how well we convert precursor
nutrients into the nutrients
that we actually need.
And let me give three examples
to make this more real.
So one is EPA and Dha.
These are these long chain of mega three
fats that we've heard so much about
that are crucial for brain function,
cardiovascular function,
et cetera.
And we primarily,
you get them by eating fish.
There are no sources of those in a
plant based diet except for algae.
Um,
but an algae is not the bioavailable.
And how many people do
know that eat algae?
I don't know.
I mean we can,
you can cause that famous
green supplementation stuff is,
you can use it as a supplement
but very few people are eating it.
So,
um,
but you,
but there is something
called Alpha linolenic acid,
which is in walnuts and flax seed.
That's an a mega three plant fat and,
and humans in theory can convert some of
that plant based Omega Three into this
long chain EPA and Dha that we need.
But the thing,
here's the thing,
only about five to 10% of that gets
converted into EPA and even less to Dha,
like two to 5%.
So you have to be chugging tablespoons
of flax oil in order to get as much EPA
or Dha Epa that you would get from
eating just a little bit of fish.
And that's if everything is going well,
because if you have deficiency of any
nutrients that are involved in the
enzymatic conversion of those plant
based fats into the long chain fats,
then you won't make those
conversions at that optimal rate.
It'll be even less.
And ironically,
many of those nutrients are nutrients
that are not well represented in a Vegan
or vegetarian diet.
So that's one example.
Another would be vitamin K two,
which is uh,
uh,
a different form of vitamin K
that's recently been discovered.
And it's really important for
cardiovascular and bone health.
It basically puts,
make sure that calcium gets in our bones
and our teeth and our heart tissues
where it belongs and keeps it out of
the soft tissues like our arteries where
calcium would make our arteries hard and
increased the risk of a heart attack.
So,
um,
k two is only really in animal foods with
the exception of some fermented foods
like Natto,
which is a Japanese fermented soybean
product that most people cannot stand.
Um,
it's,
it's a strong taste.
Not very many people are eating it here.
Uh,
Kufier and,
and Sauerkraut and Kimchi have,
have k,
k two in it.
Kaffir I've been saying
Kiefer my whole life,
that's how I've never heard it.
So that's how they say it,
where [inaudible] is from.
Every other person I've
ever met says Kiefer,
so don't worry about it.
Okay.
And could fear from Nolan fear
you'll be in the select few,
but no,
honestly I feel good about it already.
So yes,
you can feel superior.
Now,
can I stop you real quick
just because we're going to,
I want to get a little bit,
um,
uh,
onto this track of what
you were describing.
Boats,
fish oil and conversion and the
difference between flax seed oil.
What,
what can vegans take in order to sort of
recommend that vegans take micro algae
because it has preformed Dha in it.
So you bypass that whole conversion
issue and if they do take micro algae,
is that sufficient or how much
different is that than eating fish?
Well,
it's quite different because fish have
a lot of other nutrients aside from EPA
and Dha.
They routine,
they have selenium,
they have a lot of other
bioavailable nutrients.
But,
but,
and the other disadvantage is
you have to take a boat load of,
of LG boatload.
Give me a,
uh,
I think so.
There are different products
have different amounts,
but um,
you know,
I think you'd have to take six to nine
cups a capsules a day of the average
algae supplement in
order to meet your Dha.
No.
Done.
It could,
it's absolutely possible,
but that would be a good way to
be healthy with the Vegan Diet.
That would be one way to address the
shortcoming of know of lack of Dha on the
Vegan Diet.
There are other shortcomings,
other nutrients like B 12 which that's
a big issue and vegans need to be
supplementing with that.
There's a myth out there that there are
some plant sources of B 12 like seaweed
and in spirit like spirulina
and nutritional yeast,
but those actually contain,
uh,
kind of phony forms of B 12 that that
can block the absorption of true 12,
which is only found in animal
products or supplements.
So a B 12 supplement
would be really important.
That's why it's the source
of a B 12 supplement.
Um,
they,
it's synthetic,
it's synthetic I think,
but they just,
there's three forms.
It'd be 12.
There's,
there's hydroxy Kabbalah,
man and Methylcobalamin or f or four
forms that you can supplement with
Cyanocobalamin and Adenosylcobalamin and
Cyanocobalamin is the synthetic form.
And then the other ones are natural
forms of B 12 that you would encounter in
food.
So people can supplement
with any of those.
The,
the natural forms are better to supplement
with cause they're more bioavailable.
But definitely if a Vegan,
I would recommend supplementing with B
12 because there aren't any sources of it
in the Diet.
And studies have shown that 68% of
vegetarians are deficient in B 1280 3% of
vegans are versus just 5% of omnivores.
Wow.
So it's a big difference.
We're not,
you know,
and that's a factor in,
in many different issues,
right?
It's a factor in the production of muscle.
Uh,
all production of all red blood cells
depends on B12 and full eight and so on.
I mean that's pretty fundamental,
right?
And then the Myelin Sheath requires be
12 and this is why B 12 deficiency can
mimic the,
the signs of Parkinson's or Alzheimer's
to these and people who are aging.
B 12 deficiency happens in elderly people,
not because they're on a
vegan diet because they have
low stomach acid and they
don't absorb the B 12 as well
as we do when we're younger.
And so a lot of people who are elderly
who have no symptoms of Parkinson's or
Alzheimer's,
they can sometimes be misdiagnosed with
these conditions when they're actually
just be 12 deficient.
So it's a series.
It's a real,
really important nutrient.
How can vegans be assured that the B12
that they're buying does not have a
animal products?
Uh,
we do.
Do they have B12 when you bind a
supplement that typically it's usually a,
I'm not the best person to
ask about that because I'm,
I'm not a Vegan myself.
I was a macrobiotic at one point.
What does that mean?
What's the difference?
That's deep,
deep
macrame macrobiotics is that is a whole
nother system of way of looking at
foods,
a job and you know,
uh,
Japanese,
approach and um,
you know,
the whole reason I came
to do what I'm doing now.
So I got really,
really sick and my twenties I almost died
and I spent about 10 years just trying
to get back to health.
What did you pick from?
I was in Indonesia.
I mentioned earlier,
I'd traveled around the world and I was
surfing and I got the classic tropical
illness.
It's like immediate dysentery,
Giardia and blastocystis hominis so to
parasites and an Amoeba and was just,
you know,
coming out of both ends,
delirious,
didn't remember really
anything for three days.
Um,
luckily there was one other Australian
guy in the village that I was in who had
some antibiotics in his medical kit that
kind of brought me back from the brink,
but,
um,
between the parasites and
then the multiple rounds of
antibiotics I had to take
to get rid of the parasites after that,
it just wreaked havoc on my gut and it
took me basically 10 years to recover my
Ho yeah,
10 years.
It was like the last decade when I was
at 10 years because you approached it in
correctly and you could do it better now
or was it just such a devastating round
of disease that I think a little of both.
I mean,
so I was,
I'm 42 now and I was 25 when this first
happened and we didn't know anything
about the gut and the microbiome
compared to what we know now.
There was very little
awareness on this topic,
that point.
Yeah.
Just in 15 years,
it's just,
or 20 years.
It's,
it's crazy.
So,
you know,
I took way more antibiotics than I would
have done in retrospect because that's
what the doctors were
prescribing and saying,
look,
you've got these parasites,
we've got to get rid of them.
This is how you do it.
And you know,
and I think the antibiotics,
if it could have been like the treatment
was probably worse than the disease for
me,
you know,
after the number of courses
of antibiotics that I took.
Wow.
So along that path I tried to out every
special diet you can possibly imagine
including becoming a vegetarian
and a Vegan and then a macrobiotic,
Vegan and raw food vegan.
I've been there,
done that.
And um,
so I'm completely sympathetic like to all,
and I'm also a longtime
meditater and Buddhist.
So I understand the
ethical argument very well.
Many of my friends don't eat meat.
I'm sympathetic and I care
about the environment.
I'm sympathetic to that argument.
I'm certainly not,
you know,
I'm coming to this from a place of
I think a pretty balanced viewpoint.
Um,
and uh,
the,
the issues for me,
the reason why I eventually brought
animal products back into my diet with the
Aye,
Aye.
It became clear that I needed to do
that for my own health and I was able to
reach a level of
understanding and,
uh,
about the moral,
ethical and environmental
choices that I was making.
Um,
that,
that I felt good about.
I want to go back to something
you were saying about the,
you know,
vegans and vegetarians and how to kind
of optimize if you're doing that diet.
So,
um,
two things that wanted to address.
One was you asked about mollusks.
I've actually argued that a vegetarian
diet with shellfish and organ meats would
be better than a Paleo Diet with
no shellfish and organ meats.
Interesting.
And that's because of what
we talked about earlier.
Muscle meats,
organ meats and shellfish are the two
most nutrient dance classes of foods.
Like I,
I've just been finishing the curriculum
from my clinician training program where
I'm,
um,
you know,
going through systematically
every nutrient and I'm looking at,
uh,
in nutrition data what the most,
the highest food sources
of those nutrients are.
And again,
I wish I had the thing to
just lay it out and show you.
But you know,
in almost every case it's an organ meat
or a shellfish that's the highest source
of that,
whether you're talking about be 12 or
iron or copper or zinc or full eight.
It's always beef,
liver,
chicken,
clams,
oysters,
et cetera.
And so if someone was a veggie vegetarian
who's willing to fudge a little bit
and eat just organ meats and shellfish,
they,
I think that would be a healthier approach
than someone who's just eating lean
muscle meat.
Um,
organs get tossed out a lot.
It's a,
it's really,
it's a real problem in
the hunting world where,
um,
when people got an animal,
they leave the gut pile.
And there's even a gutless method
that a lot of people use when the,
uh,
they take on a big game animal,
like an elk or something like that.
They just,
they leave it behind.
They leave the heart,
they leave the liver.
But I saw this documentary on wolves and
was really fascinating was one of the
ways that they distinguish
who the alpha is.
And then wolf pack is the Alpha
Wolf is the one who eats the liver,
the liver and the fascinating.
There are other animals that that's true.
And I think that was true in a
hunter gather societies as well.
And someone was trying to say to me,
well,
we'll livers process toxins.
Don't you think they'd
be filled with toxins?
That's a common
misconception.
The liver processes then,
but this,
the fat stores them.
So if you're concerned
about toxins in food,
you should make sure that you're eating
pasture raised organic fats like butter
and cream and things.
If you eat dairy products,
animal fats,
grass fed,
grass fed butter,
uh,
if you eat lard or tallow
or anything like that,
it should come from pasture raised animals
because the fat is where toxins are
stored,
the liver processes then um,
so when you're,
I'm sorry to interrupt you boat.
So when you're eating anything that comes
from an animal that's been fed grain,
you're dealing with an animal that has
the same sort of inflammation issues a
person has
from processing things that it's not
naturally supposed to process like pat
processed wheat and the bleached flour
and things besides antibiotic residue.
Right?
Yeah.
So when you're taking in those animal
products that we traditionally do,
whether it's butter or milk or dairy
or cheese or things along those lines,
when you're taking those from
an animal that's eating grain,
you are actually getting the fats.
So your,
your,
it's less healthy than actually
eating the liver of that animal.
Yeah,
I would,
it may be.
I mean the liver is more
nutrient dense anyways,
but um,
pasture is animal fats,
uh,
have a lot more nutrients
than conventionally raised
fats because the animals
are eating grass and grasses way more
nutrient dense than the grains that you
know,
conventional animals are fed.
Also the Omega threes
and sixes are different.
The ratio,
the May mega six is the same but Omega
three is three or four times higher in
pasture raised animals.
Why does that make it six to sign?
It's a good question.
It used to be,
you know,
the,
the kind of a consensus was that Omega
sixes would be higher in Omega threes it
would be lower,
but actually it looks like and make a six
is constant and Omega three is higher.
The Omega three is higher because of the
grass probably has more alpha linolenic
acid,
which is the plant based form that day.
Then animal does a conversion.
I mean that's the thing that's really
interesting to consider here too is humans
are really inefficient and making
these conversions of these less active
nutrients to the more active ones.
We started talking about
it with EPA and Dha,
k k vitamin K one is
what's converted into k.
Two cows are experts at doing that.
They're really good at it.
Humans not so much.
So when we eat the animal and the animal
is basically done the work for us and
we get the preformed final nutrient that
we need rather than having to do those
steps ourselves.
And this is starting to rub,
it's just,
it's just a function of the adaptation
of people developing while eating these
animals.
I think so,
yeah.
Beta carotenes and other example that's
a precursor to active vitamin A or
retinol and Beta carotenes have
some benefits in our bodies,
but retinols is the real thing.
You know what?
We need more than anything.
And uh,
that conversion is as low as
three to 5% and some people,
and in fact there,
there are some who don't
make the conversion at all.
And those are the people who turn
orange after a carrot juice fast.
Ever seen anyone with
like the orange palms?
It happens.
My friend Andy used to drink so much
carrot juice that the inside of his hands
and his skin would turn orange.
Yeah.
So he probably wasn't good at converting
Beta carotene into retinol because we
should be able to do that,
but some people can't.
But it isn't just the mass quantity.
So yeah,
I mean it could be that too.
But um,
uh,
the retinol is only really present in
organ meats and pasture raised fats.
It's not even really in muscle meats
like lean ground beef or chicken breast,
boneless chicken breasts or,
um,
so in order to get retina,
we need to consume these pasture raise
fats or we need to consume Oregon means.
And as you pointed out,
the organ meats have really
fallen out of favor in the US.
And this is only recent,
like I bet you our grandparents ate a
lot more organ meats then we eat still in
some,
you know,
many parts of the world.
They still eat organ meats.
More try.
We do.
Yeah.
Liver and onions is a very famous dish.
Beef heart.
And so you'll see within the Paleo
primal kind of world that organ meats are
making a comeback because we understand
now what the nutrient density of these
foods is and there's less now,
even in the mainstream world,
there's less of a solid argument that can
be made about these having cholesterol
or you know,
high levels of saturated fat.
They would prevent us from meeting them.
Now,
what would be the difference in terms
of the nutritional density of molluscs
versus Oregon meat?
So like if you were trying to,
if you had a vegetarian or a Vegan
is on the fence and you know,
you made these arguments that are
very rational and logical and he said,
look,
mollusks are essentially a very,
very primitive form of life
that doesn't feel pain.
And you could argue that there's more
evidence that some plants feel pain and
plants also have some very
intense level of communication.
Where there,
there,
there's a really interesting,
uh,
addition of radio lab recently
where they went into this,
where they sort of are trying to
understand the difference between,
uh,
the,
not the difference rather,
but the,
the,
the complicated relationship between these
different plants and the mycelium and
the soil and all of the different fungus
in the soil that also acts as sort of a
transportation method for
various nutrients and minerals.
And they're actually pulling
these minerals out of the
rock and they're getting
sugars from the plants and they're
exchanging them for minerals.
And that there's this really complex
interaction that we have sort of just
looked at and said,
oh,
there's dirt and there's plants.
But there's a lot going on between
these various life forms and one of them
being fungus,
which again is closer to an animal that
it is still plant but is imperative for
the life of these plants.
And then somehow or another,
there were actually even sharing
resources where if they find,
or they're allotting resources to
certain plants that are more deficient or
they're trying to channel
resources to them.
So there's some form of communication.
And exchange here.
Yeah,
that's,
that's intelligence right there.
I mean,
Paul Stamets has done amazing work on,
um,
my youngest,
youngest in general.
Um,
yeah,
I would say that that's
a really good option.
I mean,
um,
when you look at nutrients like specific
nutrients that it goes back and forth
between liver and,
you know,
Oregon meats and shellfish and some,
some nutrients,
uh,
organ meats are higher,
like vitamin A or iron
and other nutrients.
Shellfish are generally higher
like with zinc or copper.
Um,
but certainly even,
even,
uh,
shellfish are higher in almost all
of the key nutrients that we need.
Then a lot of the plant based food
alternatives that they would be choosing
from.
And so if this a Vegan was willing to
eat molluscs I would say that that would
be a great idea.
And,
and uh,
the,
the benefit there is you don't need to
eat a lot like three ounces a single
serving,
uh,
can meet your copper
requirement for the entire week.
Oh Wow.
Just one time.
All the time.
Oysters.
And same with iron.
I think if I'm going
off the top of my head,
I'll iron and zinc,
it can nearly meet your
entire weekly requirement.
So it's not like you have to
eat a ton of these things.
You,
you know,
you have a serving of clams once a week
and you have a serving of oysters once a
week,
uh,
you know,
on top of,
uh,
getting as much nutrient
density as you can,
um,
that should do,
that's be 12.
That's iron,
that sink,
that's copper,
EPA and Dha.
The launching and Omega
three fats are in these,
uh,
in these malls cause as well.
Uh,
and it,
they're typically low on the toxicity,
uh,
scale too.
They're not,
they don't tend to have a lot of mercury.
They don't bio accumulate a lot
of toxins compared to some other,
you know,
Predator species of fish that are higher
in the food chain that accumulated a
lot of toxins.
Is there any benefit to eating them
cooked versus raw one way or the other?
Well,
you know,
there's all,
there is the chance of
disease and you know,
eating raw wasters.
Um,
I think it's pretty minimal
compared to some other risks,
but it's,
it is there.
And cooking,
yeah.
Mitigates that.
Definitely.
I think in general,
cooking makes the nutrients in meat and
animal products more bioavailable rather
than last.
Uh,
and that's,
and,
and vegetables,
it's,
it depends on the vegetable and the,
um,
and the method of cooking.
But,
uh,
it,
it's a mix.
It's more of a mixed bag,
but with [inaudible] me to genuinely
improve the bioavailability.
So it really is in a lot of
ways an ideological issue
where it's sort of framed
that,
you know,
you don't want to contribute to suffering,
but these things really
don't suffer there.
Yeah.
But even there,
you know,
as we talked about,
you're going to contribute to contribute
to suffering and potentially more if
you're looking on the
scale of individual lives.
And it might sound like this is nit picky,
but it's not.
We're talking about actual lives,
you know,
and,
and then you have to
start evaluating like,
is a cow more ascension are worth,
you know,
the life of a cow worth more than the
life of a rabbit or a vole or the kinds of
animals that are being killed.
And in the end,
you know,
in the production of these plant foods is,
it's a real question.