The joe rogan experience.
The reason why feminism exists,
the only reason why it exists is because
there's an imbalance.
If there wasn't an imbalanced,
there wouldn't be this need to be
extreme towards that side.
If it was like,
no,
if men were like really kind to women
and there was no dispute,
then there would be,
there would be,
it would be ridiculous to have feminism.
Nobody would believe in it.
The only reason why it can exist,
like whether you believe in a lot of the
things that they generalize or not,
and I don't,
I don't believe in the generalizations.
I believe there's a lot of good people
out there and I think as soon as you
start lumping men and a general
categories,
it's just like lumping women or anyone
in the general categories were too broad
in a spectrum is always an exception.
Everything,
but there's too many different variables
when it comes to humans interacting with
each other,
especially sexually.
But the only reason why feminism exists
at all is because there's something
wrong.
If there was nothing wrong,
if there was no women that were getting
shit on,
if there was no sexual harassment in the
workplace,
if there was no discrimination when it
comes to employment,
if they're the don't know,
none of those things existed.
You couldn't make the argument.
It just,
it's that simple that nobody would buy
it.
The women wouldn't buy,
nobody would join.
They'd be like,
what are you talking about?
Like every men,
men treat women like they're themselves
living in life,
you know?
But that's not the case.
So when you have,
whether it's the men's rights guys or
the feminist,
the reason why these groups exist is
because something's wrong.
There's not a balance,
you know?
And there's always going to be someone
that's out there on the far end of the
seesaw trying to tip it one way or the
other,
but that they exist because something's
going on.
The men's rights guys exists because
there's something going on.
Because a lot of guys do get fucked over
in divorce.
Man,
I've seen it.
I've seen some brutal shit happened to
men in marriages.
I've seen some men that were targeted by
women who are just,
there were financial assassins and they
went after men for their money and got
pregnant with these men for their money
and stole money from these man.
I've seen it.
I know it happens.
I've seen it without this.
The baby part I've seen,
I've seen people get fucked over.
I've seen it happen many times.
It doesn't mean that the men's rights
guys are right.
When they say stupid shit,
like men get raped more than women,
you know?
Yeah.
You fucking get raped by each other.
He'd dumped.
Fuck.
That's such a dumb thing to say.
It's just,
it's so,
it's like,
it's such a disingenuous argument.
Are you really worried about being raped
dude,
cause I don't worry about it ever.
How about that took her to prison?
Yeah.
I don't worry about getting raped,
man.
That's never comes up.
No,
and I'm around UFC fighters all the
time.
I'm around people who actually could
rape me and it doesn't really come up.
I just went,
a guy says that if a guy was talking
about divorce laws and the idea that you
know,
someone can actually target someone and
someone can extract money from them by,
you know,
by basically a conspiracy,
you're conspiring to rip guys.
Often.
That's what a gold digger is.
It's a whole profession.
There's songs about it.
I mean,
it's not like a kind of a myth,
like a unicorn or something like that.
It's not what Coupa cobre it's a real
fucking thing.
It's a category and society,
gold diggers and you know,
that's not good either.
But then there's the guys who fall for
those traps.
Where's that?
That's natural selection.
You stupid.
Fuck.
How do you,
how do you not look at her and look at
you and not know she's after your money.
You're disgusting,
right?
What do you think?
It's your personality.
You know,
you're walking around with a fucking
$10,000 watch on driving a Ferrari and
you wonder why women want you to pay for
their rent.
Okay,
that's what you do.
Stupid.
Which I'm on both sides.
Both sides of the fence.
That's how rocket.
But you know,
I'm trying to,
I'm trying to bridge gaps here.
I'm trying to bring people together.
I'm trying to let feminists and men's
rights advocates and everybody know that
we're all just humans.
When I see,
like I was watching this thing about
atheism plus,
I don't know if you know what a few of
them is in pluses.
She's the people that wanted attach
atheism with core values,
like against sexual harassment,
racial discrimination.
Mike,
and they had this really long verbose
speeches.
But my problem with that,
when I was watching that,
I was like,
Duh.
Right?
That's what it essentially,
that's what it is.
Anyways,
it gay marriage,
Duh.
What racial discrimination,
You know,
w w sexual discrimination,
Duh.
All of its De,
yeah.
It shouldn't be there.
It should,
everyone should just,
we should all know that.
It's like when you start railing on
about it,
you make me want a sexually harass
somebody because you're so fucking
annoying and it's so obvious what you're
saying.
It's so stupid to keep harping on shit
that I say we shouldn't stab babies.
Yes,
yes.
Stabbing profound.
Yeah.
Nobody.
If you don't want gay people to get
married,
you're a fucking asshole.
If you don't think that black people
should have the same rate of pay as a
white person,
you're an asshole.
If you don't think black people should
live in your neighborhood,
you're an asshole.
If you don't.
It's all nonsense.
It's,
it's so clear by this day and age that
it's Duh.
So when I see something like atheism
plus in these long drawn out speeches
where they're mentioning all these other
things that we should all already agree
on,
like where are we starting from?
And we started from barbarism.
Are We fucking pirates?
Are we,
are we educating fucking horrible
criminal people?
Our fee is like,
yeah.
It was like,
stop harping on this shit enough
already.
We should literally make two countries.
We should saw the fucking country in
half and put up a giant fence.
And anybody who doesn't want gay
marriage,
anybody who doesn't want black people,
anybody who you know hates Asians,
get over there,
stop.
Right?
You need to figure it out on your own.
I tell many people have already figured
it out.
That's to,
I would say like a small island.
I looked like an island.
This let it go and do that.
It might even be half the people,
but it's going to be the,
my point is if you're joining atheism
plus Jesus fucking Christ,
aren't you already there?
I mean you really have to repeat that or
I mean how much preaching to the choir
has to be done.
They have to Chirp on that same shit
that we all rational people already
agreeing.
Saw this pitch.
Rajender Monitor.
We'll take the left.
You take the right go right,
and we can all live in each of the spots
we want to,
but let's put,
let's recognize what we have over here.
We have a bunch of black bunch of Jew
haters,
but you gay bashers all in one country.
We could give them Louisiana.
Not Louisiana is pretty cool.
We should we give them North Dakota,
give him South Dakota.
Nobody even goes there.
Wasn't even Rhode Island moved to South
Dakota people to like Connecticut.
They'd be so happy so much.
That was the way this is Spotsy give him
some upper Alaska areas.
Will they have camps?
That's what we should do.
Take racist rally.
I can live with polar bears.
You want to know how much you're going
to love black people after nine months
of living with polar bears,
I got an idea.
Let's take everybody and put them in a
kid
that's never been done before.
This will glue the idea.
Well,
clearly we have too many people that
suck.
Okay.