Great. Great. Hmm. That's probably, it
is great. We can you, yeah, great. Great.
Nailed it. That's where I
got it. Ron White. We live.
Oh we are. Oh, sorry. We're what a
fancy beginning. That's how I do it.
I like it to be professional. Cheers my
brother. Cheers. Cheers. Good to be here.
Good to be here.
Delicious. Good to see you
after that. Mentally intensive.
Uh,
carbohydrates versus fat.
I'm done. Genuinely came out of
there looking at ex exhausted.
It was a rough debate.
They were going back and forth.
They didn't like each other.
They were mocking each other a little bit,
but hopefully people got some
information out of it. Two good guys.
They just a different positions.
They don't see eye to eye Joe. Nope.
What are you gonna do? What are you
going to hear them out? Exactly?
What am I going to do? Ron
White. So, uh, apparently Ron,
why you have a mugshot that
we can add to our collection?
You have one over here. I'll
have it framed and descending
on up. Oh, I'll meet.
We'll make sure it's a small enough to
put on that wall out there, you know,
so it'd be a pretty big one. I'd like to
have a pretty dominant spot over at the,
uh,
tell me what you need experience.
I'll give you a fucking six foot tall one
brother. Alright. Alright. That's all.
That's it.
Six foot tall size.
Yeah. Get it free. Fuck it.
Yeah, it was a bad picture.
They were really bad. So this, we're,
we're talking about this, this is a,
you got busted for weed.
Somebody ratted you out that
there was weed on your plane.
No, that they didn't say there
was a weed on that plane.
They said it was a drug smuggling plane.
And uh,
so there's a hotline that you can call
and they just pilots that I'd fired.
And uh,
and so I'm just sitting on the plane
looking out the window and there's drug
dogs and people invest and machine guns.
And I'm like, what's going on out there?
Well, but you know, as soon as they
determined that that's not what it was,
that I just had some personal weeds that
obviously somebody called in and allied
instead of going in and
arrested and that guy,
they took me to jail then it makes
no sense at all. And then the,
in the newspaper, the sheriff goes, well
he might not have had much pot with him,
but who knows how much he did have.
And who knows, I didn't kill somebody.
How about we just put me up for murder
right now if we need no evidence at all.
You know, is he didn't steal
larceny. How about that?
It's something they went
and they drove by in a pit.
They drove by three meth labs in a
dead hooker just to get to my plane.
And the really,
the funny part of it was the next day we
were going to go somewhere else and I'm
in Louisiana and uh, but then now
I've got a, you know, just we,
we can get rid of, that's
all we can do. Cause they,
they might do it again next
night, next place, more dry.
So now we've got an apple
were smoking out of there.
They have to have them on horseback and
Alex feeds that one of the horses as
he's walking back, you can take
this little apple. They tried,
you'd check your plan again.
They did check it again. But we,
we just had come up with this
little plan that uh, you know,
we would just would end,
he also had to eat a little bag of
weed and he was really stoned on stage.
That's really strong. But we, you know, we
didn't go to jail that night. If you eat,
just eat, just eat weed will get you
high. Yeah, absolutely. Will it take,
it takes a while, but it was a big old
chow of it. I mean, it will be old.
The lip full cheek full. I'm surprised
people don't chew. We'd like,
there's no one out there chewing.
It tastes like ass dude,
which is why nobody eats. We'd
even the cookies, you know,
they gotta they gotta watch
it to keeping patients.
There is a growing number of people
who juice the leaves and drink it.
Yeah. You know, like wheat grass juice.
They do it with the
leaves of cannabis plant.
I've seen people squeeze it to make
the Gig like the concentrate out,
but did not think they're a, they're
sticking in one of those master caters.
Is that what they called?
Those things that make a,
you know like wheat grass like he had,
they can get juice out of fucking grass.
It makes sense.
If you could get it out of, I mean
of you could get it out of the plant.
Right? It doesn't, you don't
get, you don't get high though.
It's like getting a CBD out there.
What's the point for Health Ron?
Oh yeah. You know, it's
like, oh duals pot.
Oh to tell you what's not bad. You've
heard the Heineken Shit that we got.
We have Heineken zero, zero, whatever
the fuck it is. It does not taste bad.
It's okay. Go to no alcohol in it, but it,
but it tastes so you don't get
that annoying buzz. I know.
No you don't get none of that.
Cause you guys had that soccer,
a sober October and it looked like you
were having a blast. I have to admit,
sitting from the sideline, they call it,
boy, this sober thing looks like a blast.
I did have a November to remember.
Yeah, we had no remember November. Um,
yeah, sober October is interesting.
It's good to do every year. I like
to do it. You think you'd ever do it?
I don't think I could not. How many
days do you think you'd take it off?
Uh, you know, really not one.
It'd be very happy about it.
Everything that I've got a little touch
of a alcoholism that someday I'll either
deal with or I won't. But, you know, it's,
it's a maintenance thing with me. So,
uh, maintenance as far as
keeping your mindset correct?
Just feeling good.
Like what is it?
Yeah. You know, it's just a
give a fuck juice. I don't know,
it's just something that I seem
to require, you know, it's,
I can't wait for that first drink
of the day and then I usually drink,
you know,
pretty much to access
every single night of my life. So, I mean,
I'm not saying this is a good thing and
I'm certainly not bragging because I see
people that are sober and I get
jealous of him. I'm like, wow,
what would that be like to
wake up feeling good every day?
And I'm so to it. I don't
understand that. I mean,
I don't understand why I won't just
let it go. Uh, but it's, you know,
I know it's such a big part of, you know
who, who, who people perceive me to be,
but it's also just a big part
of how I perceive me to be.
Well people who perceives you to be,
they perceive you.
Like if anyone has ever asked me, what's
Ron white like or what do you think?
He's like, oh great guy likes to
drink a lot. Always funny. Yeah,
that's him. That's what you, you,
you have the benefit of,
you don't have a,
an act like you're not putting on an act,
but you are a character like that.
But as who you are,
it's so much better.
Like if people found out you
were some tee total and got like,
have you ever seen somebody drinks fake
shots on stage? Yeah. That's rough.
That's a rough place to be pretending to
be. Boozing it up with the Oud. C'Mon.
We'll foster Brooks,
who was the best
Vosburg who's so good at being
a drunk with a teetotaler
Dean Martin as well. Not as he told me,
but he didn't pretend. I don't think so.
And I hear that, but I've, I've seen
him, when I did the Foxworthy roast,
I went back and watched
all those rows and uh,
that guy was drunk and if
you go watch movies, he was
in, he was not a good actor.
So he was acting in Him and frost
foster Brooks were in the same one.
And Brooks was just so
good and so edgy and uh,
but you could tell which one
was really drunk. And, uh,
I think a lot of times in Vegas he
might've had fake drinks and you know,
or maybe people just wanted to say that
because it's a little story, right? Yeah.
But he looked like a, you
know, he was fucked up to me.
Have you seen that show on a, I don't
know if you watch any of Amazon prime.
You ever seen that show? The Marvelous
Mrs Maizel. It's about a standup comic
now. I see. I hear about it all the time
and people are always saying, it's really,
really good. It's fucking
great. That's fucking,
I just finished a something today.
So, uh, I'm looking for the next,
the watch that man, especially
season one, season one just to see.
Season two was great too.
I enjoyed it,
but people didn't give season two as
much reward as much props as they did.
I liked both seasons, but there's a
woman in that was my point who has an,
she's putting on an act like she's this
really high Falutin lady who pretends to
be this chick from queens and
she puts on a fat suit and,
and does this act and a,
it drives Mrs May's.
We'll fucking crazy. She hates it. And
she talked shit about her and it starts,
spoiler alert, I won't
say anymore, but it just,
that trap of being a character,
right.
Pretending to be something that
you're not, you know, I think that,
and this might be
a little bit of a stretch, Joe, I
don't know. But you know, it is.
I think that's why Steve Martin and quit
because it was a parody of a comedian
and which was brilliant
and, and so funny. Uh,
let's get small was one of my favorite
albums ever and I took it with me
everywhere.
I went in and played it for people and
then took credit for how good it was,
even though I really had very little to
do with it except for spending the money.
I remember when I was a kid, I listened
to that long before I ever did stand up.
He was fucking great. Right?
But damn, he was great. But he,
and he was doing 45,000 people a
night when he can, when he quit.
Yeah. I think that was the problem.
I think he just got over a, he,
I think he's like a lot of comedians.
They feel a lot, you know,
they're not numb people.
They feel a lot. I think for him like
this, that's why I'm drinking it. Right.
Maybe I don't want to get in
touch with those feelings. Well,
everybody that's damaged feels a lot and
everybody has the common cause damaged,
you know? And I think with
that, I think with Steve Martin,
he was just so big, man, I don't think,
I think he's bigger than you are.
I combined like he just would go on
stage and they would go fucking crazy.
It didn't even make sense to
people. Right. So difficult
for him to perform. Yeah.
He didn't know what was funny
anymore. And uh, yeah. So I think,
I mean it was a ballsy thing to
do. Fucking crazy. And um, but,
and then he walked straight
into film and, you know, it's,
everything he's done has been
crazy, crazy successful. No, he's,
he's excellent. And I'd love to go
see the band. Uh, Cathy Nelson and my,
okay. I think runs the touring thing. Uh,
she would see the band and went back
and talked to him and said it was great.
Wow. I like to meet him. He lived at,
we lived in the same town for a while
and I'd like to meet her, but, uh, uh,
I never ran into him. Ran Into Jonathan
Winters there a couple of times.
What was he like? He was holding
court at the post office and, uh,
it like 20 people around.
He's doing characters,
he's killing it at the post office.
And I saw,
and that was the second time I saw him.
The first time I saw him was he was
having lunch by himself and, uh,
and I was with another comic and he goes,
do you think he'd mind if we
went over there and said hi?
And hour later we were like,
well, we gotta go. We gotta split.
It was Robin's big influence.
Right, right. Yeah. That's a,
yeah, that's true. He was so,
he was so who the fuck was like him?
Think of that.
Yeah. It had to start with
something. Right. That's what I got.
I got this theory that uh, there's, uh,
two kinds of comics bridge builders and
people that walk across those bridges.
I'm a big walker. Yeah. I didn't
invent any of this stuff. I think,
uh, well you got to go back to
like Richard Pryor and Lenny Bruce.
Those are the big ones.
And then Kennison is a big one.
Kennison because Kennison taught us that
somebody can genuinely not like you
and you can still make them on. Yeah.
Well he also taught me that you
can punch down as low as you want,
as long as it's funny.
Right. As long as it's funny.
As long as you're good enough fucking bit
that he had about starving children to
this day.
I had an argument with a
guy on the podcast about it
when he was telling me that
you comedy only punches up I go,
that's crazy.
Kennison had two of the best bits of
all time. They're both punching down.
One was about starving kids.
The other was about necrophiliac money,
banked corpses. But that's his down
as he can get me a fucking dead body.
And both those bits where fucking genius.
And it's the same with the,
it's the same with nine 11.
You know,
if you're good enough of a rider,
you can do material about that. But
if, but if, but you better be good.
You better have somewhere to go. That is,
yeah, you better have somewhere to go.
And I heard a couple of good pieces, I
don't remember who did them, but you know,
uh, but like the week
afterwards, the guy that, uh,
it was some guy that was the opening act
was trying to riff on it and I got him
over to the side and I said, hey dude,
not a, this is my stage right here.
And normally I don't tell it
the comics what to do. Uh,
but until you have something to say
about it, that's uh, that's really,
really funny. I don't want
you to bring it up. Yeah,
that's a tough one because you could
kill the whole show some middle that goes
on and you lost friends in the towers. And
that was a week ago. All right. I mean,
not,
there's like levels of tragedy.
That's a real tough one to find humor in.
I'm not saying that someone can't do it.
There's people,
people find comedy in everywhere
and it's legit. They do. Right.
They have a perspective.
It's just the I, you know,
how good are you going
to avoid those things?
That's how good I am. I get it. I
get it. I'm not good enough to do it.
Patrice O'neil had a really
great point about that.
He's like all things when
someone's trying to be funny,
they all come from the same place.
Just some of them miss.
Some of them just aren't funny.
You can't get mad at those. Right,
because it came from the same place like,
yeah,
I bet someone would admit that they
told a joke that wasn't funny. Whoops.
Tried. They tried but they didn't. They're
not trying to be mean like the, the,
the response. Sometimes it just
didn't work. Yeah, it just sucked.
But you know when someone's Ad Lib
and some things are going to suck,
but the response sometimes to
one that's like ow off, you know,
it will maybe a little bit too
harsh or maybe a little too soon.
Like people get so fucking mad.
Well, you sent me a tweet about
that Cosby bit that I did and uh,
and it was really funny. And uh, but it,
it just stirred the pot so much like
you, you think rape is good? No,
that's not what I said it all. That's
not what I said at all. I made a joke.
That's it. Uh, and, and
you do that too. I mean,
you stir up the pot big time. It's
great. And you'll just go watch this and
a
of point though.
And if you have a point and you,
you really are trying real hard to be
a good person. You just have a point.
I just have a point on things. I'm
going to say it. No, you might,
you might get mad, but I'm, I'm
not saying it to be a bad guy.
I'm saying it because this
is what I do for a living.
So I do thought we find things.
You know,
bear was telling me that he did a
Carolines in New York City. He's like,
it was almost like a college gig.
He's like,
people are so sensitive now in New York.
Oh, you know, he and I just did a,
the VFW hall and Hollywood, and, uh,
then, uh, the it,
and I was calling him about
another comic that I wanted.
I was just talking to the bar and
thought he was really funny. Uh,
and I now can't remember his name.
Uh,
Joe Derosa the road.
And I called him and he goes, yeah, no,
he's really good. And, uh, and, and,
uh, he goes, how about I come over and do
it? And I'm like, well, of course, Bill,
whatever you want to do, time
on it. Come on over. Well,
he was doing a bunch of Trump
stuff and, and uh, you know,
and I guarantee, and my fans are
pretty split down the middle,
but it did not go over well.
And he didn't give a feelers fun about it.
And, uh, so he just made them mad and
stirred them up for about 20 minutes.
And then we both did my sat and we
smoked a cigar. And, uh, he, you know,
he's not drinking either for like a year.
Yeah. He looks great. He looks really
good. He looks thin and healthy. Yeah.
Yeah. That, that's Trump jokes
or interesting because, uh,
I don't remember anybody getting
mad at you for Bush jokes.
Right. It's different. Just
jokes, right? Yeah. Yeah.
Even if you were like a Bush supporter,
you could crack a joke about the way he
spells potato or something like that and
nobody gave a fuck. They didn't
care. It was a different thing.
Even if people were supporting Bush, by
the way that spelled potato wrong. Oh,
that's where I was quail. Well
that's right. That's right.
That's how these rumors get started,
man. Is I don't think it's data.
You conspiracy dude blowing off this.
Who spelled potato wrong shit.
Oh, that's right. It was him. Um, Bush to
fuck some things up too though, didn't he?
Well, didn't you fucking stuff
up? There's the whole album,
like the wit and wisdom of George W.
Bush and he says like, fool me once.
Shame on you. Shame on
me again. I don't know.
You know what's interesting about Bush
is when he was running for governor of
Texas, he had a completely
different way of communicating.
He talked like a really smart guy. He's
very articulate. I mean he was smooth,
smooth talk like arguments.
W W is a video of him,
but from back in the day when he was
running for governor and he's great,
you listen to him like glue, this
energetic, intelligent guys articulate.
He seems like one of us.
And then there's,
they had a side by side video
comparing to like Bush after seven
years in office and he's barely hanging
on right. Cause I pay attention to shit.
He's given the reins to heaven
and Hell to Dick Cheney,
Dick Cheney's in a bunker, seven miles
underground making the Ferris decisions.
You know, I mean it was
weird. It was a weird time.
But you can make fun of Bush all day long.
Nobody give a fuck.
You make fun of Trump today.
Kill you. Yeah. I almost got in a
scuffle the other day at the gas station.
This guy just starts spouting out stuff.
He was putting gas in this car ride
over there and [inaudible] and just,
and by the first word that consent is
that came out of his mouth from nowhere,
hadn't said a word of the guy.
Didn't say hi to him. Nothing.
Nancy Polosi is a dumbest person that
ever lived on this planet. And, and,
and I get baited so easy.
I just said probably not.
Probably not that you're probably wrong.
She's probably not.
Obama was an idiot.
He graduated number one from Harvard law.
So yeah, views politically
aside, we can start with,
he's probably not stupid.
And what a good speaker.
He was the best. Oh yeah, it was smooth.
Most presidential,
he was a,
he was a guy that you were happy to have
represent you whether he'd believe with,
you know,
believe in him and support his ideas are
not as a representative of our culture
of our civilization. That guy was
smooth and measured and articulate and,
and off the book,
you know, most of the time,
but you know, he was just,
he was saying what he thought and he
wasn't reading off a scripted, well,
you have a story about
Clinton w I know, I know. So,
oh well,
being off the book,
Clinton was such a good orator
that the teleprompter went off.
It broke like five minutes into his
fucking speech and he did all that shit by
memory. Just did the whole
God damn thing by memory.
And I played nine holes of golf with
him. What was it like and uh, it was,
well, there's still security
secret service all around him.
And so it was a private golf course.
Uh,
Larry Ellison a that
owns oracle. Oh Wow. Uh,
owns this private golf course.
It has 14, he's a big tennis guy,
so he puts on the tennis stuff out in
palm springs and nobody plays his course
and he doesn't play golf. And, uh, Eh,
it's just his private as a
deal [inaudible] course. Yeah.
He's got his own courses.
He played through our group and
shadow creek and Beverly Hill,
I mean in, in Vegas. It really exclusive,
of course, impossible to get on. And,
and he was playing by himself and
he was gone the tee box. And I said,
as lonely at the top.
And Larry, he goes, yeah.
And he was balling and went
off by himself. And uh, but
he wasn't even there, but,
but Clinton was,
and he told me a story goes,
his friend of his a record
producer rap records big.
I didn't tell him who it was and
didn't tell me who the artist was,
but the artist
was all dugged out and he was in a Ferrari
store and, and uh, and uh, the salesman,
it goes, are you thinking about
buying this car? And the guy goes, no,
I'm going to buy the car.
I'm thinking about pussy.
So the Glen told me a story that had the
word buzzy in it and a Clinton Clinton
told me that that's a great fucking story.
That is a great story.
That poor bastard.
It's almost like a comic.
Like he could just be free.
He got divorced and just started
going on the honest direct Clinton.
I did. I didn't want to either.
Again, I was going to do,
what would you do? Would you do, you're in
my position. Would you do, you're smart.
You know,
you don't got the 40 years left to live.
How to shove my packer right in her mouth.
That's what the whole idea of being the
fucking number one guy you gotta be so
Goddamn Pussy hungry to want
to be the number one guy.
100% you've got to have big appetites,
that's for sure. For everything. Yeah.
For everything. For everything. And
that'd be a super conqueror. Yeah.
And all those guys aren't seeing,
not all of those guys,
I don't want to generalize,
but, but it's really,
really common for men that are in power
positions to just be horny as fuck.
Yeah. All the time. Of course. I mean,
we've got to go back the way
we want these people to behave.
It's so contrary to the way any
king ever behaved ever in history.
Like the stories of kings throughout
history. It was always decadence.
It was always,
you know,
all these women and why is food and more
food and the feeding them valves open
sores and cutting off the
fucking ex wives heads and shit.
That's what you think of ordering armies,
people protecting them. He's like,
those people were just gluttons
the super gluttons of the world.
Right. And we don't like that. Like it.
So then we tried to turn someone into some
fucking Norman Rockwell person. Right.
And that doesn't work either
because you don't have enough,
uh, you, you don't, you,
you don't have enough charisma
to lead. Maybe, you know,
Trump is showing us that like you
could talk shit about him 24, seven,
365 days a year. He's not adjusting
anything. In fact, he digs his heels in.
He says, same fucking guy. No
matter what happens. Well, you know,
I really don't like to get into
manifestation on throb because it,
and the reason is I just don't feel like
it's my job and I feel like it's your
job. My job is different. My job is
to go up there and just, you know,
meg, I'm laughing, but I don't want
to be divisive. Yeah. Here, you know,
I just don't want to do it because it's,
my fan base is split and you know,
I've had, uh, and, and you know,
nothing ever really happens,
but I had a guy one time we here that
said something to meet and greet who is
paid to take a picture me and then
refused to take a picture of me because of
what I said. And I'm like,
I don't give a fuck to,
we don't take a picture leave that.
I don't give a shit. People. Yeah,
but you know that's also one of the,
it's like they're exerting power over you.
Take a picture. I'm going to unfollow
you on Instagram too. Ron White, right?
God Damn Communists. What am I going
to do? That's the one girl. She said,
I'm now I'm going to unfollow. You
used to be funny, but now you're just,
I'm going to unfollow you and I
know it doesn't matter. And I said,
you can't leave.
All the plants will die
whenever you're in a bind.
Quote Bill Murray.
Yeah. People are just so mean. It's one to
hurt you, Ron white for no reason. Yeah,
but nobody,
I've already been as mad as I can
be and I'll never be mad at her.
And it happened when I was 16 years old,
so it's hard to make me mad.
And I'll tell you what made me mad.
I just got my driver's license.
My mother asked me to go to
the store to get something.
It's in the summer in Houston.
I don't have any shoes on. Oh,
my door step into a shitty pampers.
There's somebody just thrown in the
parking lot and I didn't just put a toe in
and go, oh, that's baby
shit. That's wrong. I just
showed my whole foot into it.
Green baby shit coming through my toes.
Smears all over the diaper.
Right. So I'm stuck.
I don't know what to do.
I'm not going to get back in my
mother's car with these shitty food.
I can't go into the store with
baby shit all over my foot.
And I thought about just cutting my
foot off and just leave it in the diaper
with a note that said, you should use to
be a perfectly good fucking foot dude.
And nobody's ever made me that mad sense.
I was so fucking furious and I just
wanted to hate and kill over a shitty
pamper. That's crazy that that was
all it took. That's all it took.
That's all it took. But it was so
w you know it just put me in a,
I've been stuck before. Let me tell
you about the other time I was stuck.
This will get us off of politics.
Um,
I'm in my tour bus and,
uh,
I'm partying with my buddy
Steve and my best friend,
my road manager who passed away and,
and he never gets laid,
but it looked like he had
an angle on this girl.
So I picked up my beer and went back
to my bedroom, which I never do.
I sit up there and drink with the guys
and I go back there to just to go to
sleep. But I didn't ever take
booze back there or anything in it.
But I'd gone back there and laid down
and I put that Doseck he's bottle on the
counter and then we took off during the
night while I was real drunk and Steve
was real drunk and the bottle falls
off and breaks and I don't hear it.
So in the middle of the night and my bed
sits high cause you want to try to get
those beds towards them center, uh,
cause it's on those axles anyway.
But the closer it is to the center of
the better it feels when you're in it.
So you kind of slide off
of it about an inch. And I,
my foot went into the bottom, the beer
bottle at a shard hanging off of it,
about an inch and a half long. And
uh, and I just, and I landed on it.
Well now I know exactly
what it was and uh,
and somebody had hit the master
lights so I can't turn the lights on.
You have to go back and turn them on,
on the master switch.
But I know that around me is broken
glass everywhere cause I understand what
happened. I understand that bottle
fell broke and I got it in my foot.
So I pull them up foot up and I didn't
know how big the Shard was and I just
pull it out of there and blood just
starts gushing out with Steve's passed out
in a bunk and he can't hear me. I
can't get to a phone. I can't see.
So what do I do? I just crawl back
in bed and went to sleep and bled.
And Steve said the next morning it looked
like somebody killed a hog and learn
and uh,
he's lifted up the sheets.
Even the bus driver saw my foot
and they were like, alright,
this the price.
Did you worry about bleeding out?
What else to do?
Cause then the only option was to take
another step and cut the other foot.
And uh, do you have your phone
with you? I wasn't within reach.
I was just stuck and I was also drunk.
Stuck in drunk it bleeding. Damn.
That's a good combination. Yeah. Yeah.
I was stumped. I didn't know what to do.
I didn't know how to fucking combative,
so I would just crawl back in bed
and I'm like, no, is your foot oh,
13 stitches. Uh, as soon as
I woke up and looked at him,
let's call the hospital guys.
And uh, things sewed it back up,
13 on the bottom of my foot, right
in the arch. And uh, it was uh,
it was mess. It was a fucking mess.
Every time if you fuck your foot up,
you realize how much you need them.
Like,
you could fuck your
shoulder up and that sucks,
but you can still walk somewhere and get
something or other foot up. You're like,
oh, okay, this is, this is a real problem
operation or something. Put every, I
played golf every day, so, oh yeah.
So it's a real problem. The
real problem with me, every day,
every day, I can, not every day,
but every day I can golf is one of those
games mad God guys just get fucking
into cough. Eh, it's, you know,
it's, you know, look at it,
look at what you're into.
You know,
it's something that you do and
you've always done and you just,
you just keep doing it. You know, back
then it, I've watched it on television,
like as a soap opera,
I just watched 80 hours of the players.
It also gives me a reason not to exercise,
you know,
cause I got this golf to watch.
Golf does give you some exercise though.
That's a fact. You are walking
better than being sedentary. Yeah.
You're walking around and you think in,
you know, and you're planning shit out.
Looking at the curves of the thinking,
Ras and measuring that we're trying
to work out solve problems and so,
um, I get it. I'm just
terrified. Terrified. I'll be
one of you guys out there every
day. Yeah. Right. No, I know.
I have friends that go out every day.
You can do one of them,
but I know other guys I do too.
Every time they get a chance.
The guys I play with Google every
day. Yeah. If you can pull it off,
it's like a gentleman's leisure
way of life. Yeah. You know,
it's always back when I was a club comic,
that's how I killed the day.
Got started playing when I was like 13
and so I would just go to a golf course
and you know, schmooze out a deal where
I could play golf to her every day.
And you ain't Jack Shit to do during the
day and clubs for 15 years. You know,
I'm doing 48 weeks and make it 500 a
week or whatever it was when I started.
And it was a middle act out there.
You had to work them all cause
you deeded it to $500 real bad.
Do you ever look back on those days?
Like you reminisce? I, you know what, I,
it's,
it's a good thing for me that this
was the path of least resistance,
right? Cause uh, it was
really one for stand up.
I'd be a regional marijuana distributor
in the state of Texas and, uh, in a,
in an industry that has some
questions coming up. So, uh, you know,
I did it because I loved it,
but it was also fun, fun,
fun, you know. Uh, and uh,
and it was easy for me.
I didn't mind the travel because
I like drinking free and bars and,
and uh, and, and, you know,
practicing this art form and,
you know, and I, but I never ever
thought it would go where it went.
You know, if, you know, people ask
me, well, how do I do that? I'm like,
I don't know how I did it.
And that was right there when it happened.
I have no idea.
I barely remember it.
But did you live in
Mexico for a little bit?
In fact is a really,
really,
really good PGA player from
the same town I lived in, uh,
played golf every day where I played golf.
I didn't know him.
He was young. He would have
been, let's figure it out.
It would've, he would've been, he's
like 21 or two now. And, uh, he was,
he was on the, in the heat for
this tournament. Uh, Abraham,
my answer is his name and,
uh,
born and right now some Mexico waves was
actually born across the border because
there's no wall. Right. They can just
come over there and have a baby so that,
but his parents must've been fairly
well off for that part of the world,
you know, to, to do that. But he's
great. He's great and not dig it because,
uh, I, you know, and I see where
he came from exactly. You know,
it's where my son made a hole in
one when he was eight years old,
was on the capacitor and
golf course in Reynosa,
Mexico holds and one does
a guy getting his career.
Uh,
I've had one of my sons had one.
And you know it like the
big guys, maybe 16, 17, 18,
a whole lot in a whole lifetime
does no equivalent in other sports.
Yeah. Went all in one. There's no
equivalent in any other game right there.
There was a double eagle.
The uh, what's that mean?
That's where you make a two on a par five.
So that means you sunk a whole
from to 60 to 262 yards out.
You made it on the second shot.
Oh Wow. There's rare. Very rare.
Very rare.
But legal slightly less rare
than Hohenwarter way less rare.
Way less rare because the whole,
because at part three could be
as much as 125 yards, you know?
And then most of Martin made on the
longer one 85. But you know, you're not,
the guys like me aren't hitting
the par three from two 35.
And if you think about it,
I guess there's nothing like that in
any other game or sport in one where it
just works out perfect.
Maybe your walk off Grand Slam or yeah,
maybe it does happen way more often
than that. Way More. Well, yeah,
way more often than Holland. One for
how many people try it every, you know,
you don't get many chances
at that Grand Slam,
but try and have anything
make pitch at you.
You're definitely gonna hit the ball.
It's right there.
Like that golf ball is just right there.
I mean, you might not have a good lay,
but you're definitely going to hit it. And
I say it on the right shit. Well, yeah.
Well if you hit a foul ball, you got
to play it. You got to go find it.
And it's just,
it seems like the odds of you getting
a hole in one must be off the charts.
It must be like a thousand
to one or a hundred thousand.
A one or something crazy like
that. Yeah, maybe. I mean,
but most people may maybe never,
you know,
what do you think the numbers
numbers would be? What are the odds?
Oh fuck to own one.
I didn't graduate.
Let's throw the math to those carb
guys. So signs do, they were killing me.
Yes.
Sign made one the 11th day ever played
golf in front of me and his coach and his
best friend.
And it was a 95 yard par three from the
regular women's teas where the u s kids
club, a driver that I
still have. Wow. And uh,
and it just straight at the hall.
He had a great golf swing. The kids,
if you treat him or he's,
his golf coach was good even though
they spoke a different language, they,
they understood golf and
how to teach him that swing.
And so he was good at it and he
didn't really play much anymore.
He decided staying but uh,
planted 10 yards in front of the Pan,
bounced twice roller right in
the middle of the cup. And I,
at this point I'd been playing golf for
30 years and I'd never done it. And uh,
so it was a big deal.
And he got his name and a couple of
newspapers and they mentioned him on the
golf channel.
He was the youngest kid that had
made a hole in one that year that was
registered.
And then like two weeks later,
his six year old did it unless
I was like, uh, you know,
they took all the joy out of it for
him. That was one kid. He was lucky. He,
his window on off a mailbox here, you're
just winning off a perfect golf shot,
golf shot. That's a hard thing to
learn, right. That swing, Eh, you know,
it is a really difficult thing
to do and it's, it's just a,
it's a thing that you learn how to aim
it. It's like a bow and Arrow, you know,
uh, even though that's a little
easier to teach somebody how to do,
but to do it exceptionally
well, you know, it's, it, it's,
it's not easy to do and a and,
or a sling shot,
how to get the power at the right spot or,
or even flat casting is
not power everywhere. It,
its power in the right spot that does
it. And the risks. Yeah. And, uh,
so it's, it's, it's hard to do,
but it's fun to do once you,
once you,
once you learn how to hit a good solid
golf shot and the ball comes off the way
it's supposed to, it's, you know, it's
bliss. I'll tell you something. Here's,
here's the story about golf.
My best friend who passed
away died of brain cancer.
So they had done a surgery on him that
he had just down scars down his neck,
down his back where they were trying
to harbor. They were, you know,
they were shooting it, you know,
he was already, you know, he had,
he should have had a death sentence.
We just weren't saying it out loud.
And we were, uh, at my
place in Montecito and, uh,
we had thrown everything at this cancer,
but the kitchen sink and we were looking
for the fucking saying know, and uh,
and it, Steve Goes, let's go
golf course, man. Uh, he goes,
I'll help you read some putts.
He was always good at reading putz.
We'd been playing golf
since we were a little kid.
We'd known each other since
we were six. And, uh, and, uh,
so when I got my clubs out,
his clubs were in there too.
So he reaches into his pill bag and
takes another pill of pain pill and said,
I'll throw mine on there, you
know, I might take a swing. So,
and he did off the first tee box and
it hurt and it wasn't very good. And,
uh, and, and he just went and, uh,
but every once in a while he'd
put a ball down and he'd hit it.
And we get to the 17th holes,
part 367 yards as long. Oh.
And he hits his drive with his,
with his driver and, and, and uh,
and it fades off a little bit to the
right, but he caught it. And, uh,
so it was up kind of by the world,
by the green,
but the pen was kind of on the other side.
And I was like, great. You know, that.
And, uh, and so he hits a chip
shot, which is easier to do.
And he's always really been good at that.
And he hits it to about seven feet.
And I'm like, oh my God, he's
got a seven foot putt for par.
And He makes it and this dying man gets
the biggest grant I've ever seen in my
alive. And it was crooked
because his muscles had been cut,
but it just brought him pure fucking joy.
And then I got to see the last
part he ever made. So, and uh,
I got to witness that, you know,
joy. So that's pretty cool. Awesome.
That's pretty cool. That's
golf, you know, it, you know,
with it means that much to you.
You know,
he can make you feel better if you
do it right. One that I get it.
I think it's like in any
difficult game like that,
I guess it'd be like
that with a lot of games.
But there's something about golf too that
it's very physical and you're doing it
outside. It's one of the only things you
have to do outside, you know, other than,
I guess you could do tennis
inside, like really, right.
But golf is a fucking giant ass course.
You're going to be walking,
you got to go outside. I'd do it in
a golf cart, but you know, I walk,
I walk from the golf cart to the ball. So
that's happening. Something's going on.
Something's going on, but
you to stay loose. You know,
that's why it has the only
reason that I do yoga, it is a,
is to keep my lower back and my,
you know,
keep everything moving around back.
Right. Yeah. Well it's just got,
it's all got to turn, you know,
around your spine and that, you know,
I'm 62 years old and uh,
and so that's just harder to do
it unless you keep, you know,
you got to keep those muscles stretched
out, uh, to be able to do it at all.
Yeah.
I think it's like that with the anything
where you're moving your body as a unit
martial arts stuff or anything, you
better as you get older and particularly,
you better be really aware
of all the moving parts. When you're a
kid, you could just fucking hit the gas.
When you hit 50, you better be, you know,
you're swinging a tennis racket
or something like that. You,
it'd be aware of your shoulders.
And your knees.
Where have all these moving parts?
How old are you?
51 51 well wait, wait, wait
for 62. I'm not waiting.
What's up? Here's tiger and tiger's back
injury. He's had four back surgeries.
Oh No. He had another one. I, this
isn't like yesterday or anything,
but this is from a oh good.
Why has announced that he had undergone
anterior Lumbar interbody fusion?
Oh, that's fusing his Dick's. Many
thoughts. Many thought is disc. Excuse me.
Hello.
Hey Roy and Joe and many thought that
is competitive golf career was over and
his fourth surgery since March of 2014
which involved removing the l five s one
intervertebral disc
fusion material to connect
the l five and s one vertebra.
At what?
Oh my God.
Although he's apparently recovered
quite well from the operation.
This surgery is quite rare
amongst professional golfers.
One of the PGA player at
Dudley Heart had also, uh,
had had a fusion in the same location
as woods. Fucking fusions. Rough man.
That means there's no disk left.
Right. And he won the, uh, uh, uh,
the, whatever they call the Fedex Cup
there, the last tournament of the year,
last year, tiger wanted. And so he
came back from that. That's incredible.
Oh it is amazing. And I was there, uh,
is it East Lake and Atlanta
and, uh, and I do all their,
all their charity stuff. Yeah. That's the
footage of him going up to 18th green.
He's about to win this
thing. And it's, this is the,
the top 30 golfers on the PGA tour,
which is the toughest tour.
There is these people, Jazz.
And now you're in sport that everybody
gets some run on the field and follow him.
Right. Walk right next to
them. There's no crowd control.
Amnon was right up there that was
right up there above this green.
Uh, cause I, I walked with it cause I
get to go inside the ropes. So, and uh,
and I followed it. A couple of
choked. Nah, it didn't matter.
This is the one he needs right
here. The short one. Yup.
And they get a two shot lead
going into that and that's it.
And they won and he won the whole thing.
And that was the comeback. You know,
that was the comeback that people said
would never happen that he would never,
not especially at this level.
That's a hard tournament to win.
I mean that's a tough,
tough stuff.
Tiger's back the back. I love it.
The require a lot from people.
You know,
if,
if they get some strange along the way
he got it rough after his whole divorce
and the sex scandal.
He had it rough for a long time.
People were coming after him.
But the thing is about those
back surgeries is a wonder
why they did the fusion
cause I think they do articulate and
discs now that seemed to be very effective
at I, you know, I think he tried that.
We have to, he had boy he had four. So
cause people are, I know a few
people that are doing those. Um,
they've got those discs down.
They put like a titanium movable disk.
Basically it takes the place of the disk.
It's in your back.
Eddie Bravo had that done. I
don't know. Was this, that,
you know, I play all these,
um,
okay.
Pro Ams increasing offers performance via
an anterior approach is that it spares
the large muscles of the back
that are critical to golf swing,
which potentially makes the recovery
for athletes athletes a bit easier. Huh.
I would imagine whoever was looking at
Tiger's back was about the best person in
the world to be looking at it.
So I'm sure they would have,
he had a pretty big budget for
it. Yeah. I mean you would want,
I mean they must've like really calculated
it. That was the best move was maybe,
um, if they put an artificial disc you
would, you'd would move funny. I'm good.
I don't know man.
That whole the back things rough one,
you ever had any back problems?
I don't have a lot of any kind of problems
except that little alcohol thing that
I got going that little squeaker and uh,
but I played golf with guys in these pro
am's and most of them were, you know,
football,
basketball players and most of them are
around my age and most of them are in
pain. You know, they, it what?
It turns out smoking pot watching
cartoons good for your knees are fine.
And uh, I just didn't get
hurt. You know, I didn't,
I played golf when I was on
the golf team. Yeah, it sucked.
But I was on the golf team and junior
high and high school and football too. But
life of relative leisure is good for the
joints. Right. It's good for the joints.
Right? You don't take a pounding. Not
from where I'm laying. Yeah, the fucking,
the knees and the ankles.
So we were talking to a Camaro mine
yesterday who's UFC welterweight champion.
He's had five knee surgeries.
Both of his knees are basically
bone on bone can't run anymore.
I had all kinds of crazy out.
We'll still fight.
Thing destroys people with no to just
fight. He destroys people. He's the best.
He just beat Tyron Woodley
who was the best before him.
It's fucking crazy. I mean
when I laughed so hard when a guy goes,
my balls got high and you go,
there was the best company. The best
thing you could have possibly said was,
I understand that was love that guy.
Oh Man.
Lewis is, he's a, he's a genius.
He figured out a way to be himself.
He forgot his Instagram page. No, no.
If there's anything fucking
crazy going on in the world.
Derek Lewis has it on Instagram.
Page is Instagram page is the best.
People found out about it.
I gave him a shout out to his Instagram
page on one of the UFC broadcasts and
now it's got like, what does he have?
How many followers do you have now?
1.6 million. 1.6 million.
It's that good though.
It's fucking chaos.
He always gets videos deleted and removed,
but apparently they leave him up there.
I mean,
they're not threatened him to take them
down, I don't think. I hope not every,
it's where I go to look at it.
Any fucking dummy that's trying to like,
like light a bomb under a
tire and fly through the air.
It's smashed the roof of a fucking garage
with his face. He's got all that shit.
Motorcycle accidents or people
trying to do wheelies and they fall,
it lands on him. Anything fucked up on
the Internet. Tariffs on us. It's funny,
he's got it all. Anything crazy?
Fucking, he's a hilarious guy.
But the fact that he could say
something like that, you know,
like right after this fight,
my calls was hot.
He starts selling tee shirts
afterwards. My balls, Assad tee shirt.
So they don't, uh, I got one.
I don't think real people listened to
anything that's being said about, uh,
Derek,
please,
I need one of those shirts.
A need.
One of those shirts please Derek.
Oh my God. He knew best. He said,
you character fight his ass off too.
So do what, what? Uh, I know
what your show, but uh, what,
how many fives do you do now?
And does anybody care about
a fight you don't announce?
Yeah, for sure. Care. Yeah. I do a 10
a year, 10 a year, 10 events a year.
I'm doing like a big pay per views. Like
there's a lot of them that are overseas,
but they want you to be the
voice, right. Well ahead of time.
I just don't have the time.
I don't have the time with all,
with the podcast and with
doing stand up and you know,
making Netflix specials and shit,
that's just don't time. Fuck no,
I know there's not like it better
when I do it once a month, like once,
like 10 times a year is basically
once a month or I liked,
I liked that better because
it seems like that's um,
and it's the higher profile
stuff. I don't mind the, Oh,
there's a lot of fights that are not that
high profile that I lost their Crosby
stills and Nash and you're young,
you just pop in and do the big shows.
And that's funny, you know. Yeah.
I care as much. I love doing it, man.
I love doing it. I still do. But um,
it's amazing to me how many people that
I meet because I had talked about you
and I'm proud.
I love our friendship,
but I really am hurt you a lot and
I admire you for a lot of reasons.
But one of them is that you're famous
for a lot of things and some people don't
know you is all of those things.
I don't know if anybody does well,
probably because they listen to the
podcast and there's millions of them.
But still it's, uh, I
don't think we, I, no,
I don't think it's as common for people
to know how good a comedian you are. Uh,
you know, of course they don't
unless they've seen you, you know,
live because they might think of you
as the guy from the fear factor or the,
uh, or the man show or, or, or UFC.
And you're famous for all of those
things and standup comedy. Uh, that's a,
that's, that's crazy. But I, but I, but I,
I find myself defending you sometimes
going listen to his fucking standup,
go watch, turn on Netflix and wants
that last special watch. All of their,
it's really,
really good stuff.
He's one of the only people that really
makes me laugh. And, uh, and, and,
and I feel like I'm out here. It's
spreading the word. You got to podcast.
It reaches the entire universe.
And I'm explaining Joe Rogan to people.
So listen,
I love you and I appreciate you.
So you saying that to me
means a lot to me. Thank you.
Well that's a anyway,
baby shit all over my fucking foot I'm
saying is it was and I'm not over it.
I'm just not over it.
It's a good thing to be angry if you're
going to have one bad moment in your
life, that's a fucking,
that's a management cause you
can hose it off your foot.
Right? There's no hose. That's what
I'm trying to say. There was no house.
I get it. It wasn't no
fucking hoes. I get it.
So why wouldn't have been stuck if there
would have been a hose that was in the
parking lot of a grocery store,
Jamie will be telling me the Conor
McGregor was mad at me for something.
We'll be saying I could pull up the
video. I guess. What was he doing?
Is that a legal, are we allowed to see
him? What did he say? Something like, uh,
I script,
I talk off script,
talk on script or call fights on a script
or dad is not really true because no
one ever gives me a script.
That's a fact. I mean,
I don't know what exactly he said,
but maybe just didn't like my commentary.
I bet he likes it when he wins.
Right. You know, when you had this
picture in your, uh, right here in the,
what do you call this place
in the studio?
The actual is I'd like him
to call a fight how he sees it correctly
instead of reading off a script though.
Uh, well that's, that's uh, you
know, that's his perception.
I understand what he's saying. We got,
sometimes people think that, but you know,
it's very difficult when
someone's calling your fight.
If he's talking about me calling someone's
fight, that's not his friend, then a,
that makes much more sense. It's fucking
hard, man. It's hard for me. It's a,
I have a really hard time calling friends
fights. It's fucking hard. I don't know.
I'm friends with them. Yeah. Why not
know him that well, but I like him a lot.
I respected fun to watch him fight.
That's for sure.
Do you want to play the click?
Yeah, sure. Go ahead. Play it.
Great phrasing. Insight. Great
fight.
Heaven sees it correct.
Now the script
guys slept from Mcgregor
the same way as to
maybe I too.
So he's talking about
do must ask him if you do the
podcast. Yeah, I kept his position.
You know that Dee has fight was good
fucking fight, man. It's a hard fight.
I wasn't calling it like the last fight,
but I had to call it with the
knowledge of the last fight.
I had to know what happened in
the last fight. The last fight,
Diaz survived the storm,
tagged him,
hadn't Brockton then
finished them on the ground.
It doesn't mean that he didn't win the
second fight. It was close fucking fight.
The second fight was a very close fight,
but you have to acknowledge that
that other, the fight took place.
So he also said it like with a smile.
I think that guy is,
I mean one of the most dynamic
individuals to ever compete in sport.
He's a special person. Very
special person. Very unusual guy.
Even if he doesn't beat
Khabib ever again or you know,
he loses to this guy loses to
the Floyd Mayweather w who cares?
He's still one of a fucking
billion human being.
He's an unusual guy.
The amount of electricity,
it's fucking good man.
He starched Josie Aldo.
It was one of the greatest featherweights,
if not the greatest,
next to Max Holloway of all time.
Starts from with one punch when Aldo was,
although, although was the fucking
man, I mean he was the man.
He was smashing everybody for years and
Connor talks so much shit to him and
climb so deep inside his
head and infuriated him to
the point where you're so
emotional and he came charging at Connor
and Connor just slipped back and bank
drop like the best one punch
knockout in the history of the sport.
Oh no shit. Oh, 100% because
it was so significant.
There was so much hype behind
it. It was a guy. We were like,
how good is this guy's this guy really
the next big thing or is he going to fall
apart when he meets a real champion like
Aldo and then he knocks him out with
fucking punch. It was crazy.
And then hammer fists.
And why is that when he's on the
ground, I mean it was definitive, right?
Like 14 and the first set seconds,
the first round he throws a hopping
sidekick. He's gaging the distance.
He's got like this karate stance
and then he sees Josie load up here.
You can watch it right here.
He sees Josie load up and when
he sees Josie load up, he,
he had this fight one,
can I play it?
He had this fight one even before, I
mean he knew how it was going to go down.
He knew what all those going to do.
He was real emotional and angry.
So he knew he going to come forward.
So he's gauging is distance pains.
He that Bam.
Oh,
the Friday one.
I mean,
that was like one of the most spectacular
chaos in the history of the sport
because it had so much meaning to it.
It was so important.
It was for the featherweight
championship of the world.
Conard already won the interim title,
Him and Aldo facing each other,
this big hype thing. It took her a year
to put together crazy stuff. He's awesome.
Did you call that? Oh yeah. Yeah. I think
he's the only time I've ever yelled out.
He slept him when someone got
cracked because it's just,
I don't even know why I said it. And
she's like, that's what came to my head.
It just, I just yelled it out. He
said that's cause that's what he did.
He slapped him.
I saw that
special about that guy who now has for
a world wrestling or a professional
wrestling. The guy would, Jake the
snake? Yeah, it would be announcing it.
Oh, I'm sorry. Um, which
guy? Jim Ross. Okay.
Uh, you know, he's got real
bad PTSD and he's got a car,
but he's a great rat. A rat. He's
a star. And that sounds like it.
It's a book.
A documentary that I saw and I,
and I can't remember the
guy's name and the weight,
and in 20 minutes I was still
not well remember the guy's name,
but it was, it was great. He,
and he's really good. I mean,
you saw it after for big events. He does
all their big events or that he did,
and then he'd like fall off into this
crazy depression thing and then they'd
come back and you know, it was, it was a
great story. I wish I could think of it.
I would think you would know who that was.
Mara. Mara Nala. Oh, was
it moral? Yeah. Yeah. Yeah.
Moral does a showtime boxing too.
What's that?
Is that your phone? Ron Does it.
He folded things back in black.
Yeah.
I think, uh, the specialist
called bipolar rock and roller,
and Mara has been on the podcast for,
he's a buddy. He's a great announcer,
a really, really nice guy too. But yeah,
he suffers from mental illness and he
does a really good job of talking about it
and making sure that other people know
that this is not something that you
should be ashamed of.
You know,
let's go into this just from my side.
Okay. Love you dad. Aw, how cute.
He does that in the middle of nowhere for
no reason at all.
That's awesome man.
Ron White getting some love,
but yeah, more. Um, Mauro
is uh, he is to do pride.
Um, he's deprived commentary.
He's done a lot of boxing.
He did showtime boxing.
He does WWE.
He's done a bunch of MMA shit too. You
know, bunch of different organizations.
I think he even did glory for awhile.
He does Bellah tore too. That's right.
He does. Beltour he's a
really good guy. But yeah,
mental illness is a weird word,
man.
Uh, from Washington documentary
a fan, you know, go a,
even if you don't know anything about it.
I loved wrestling when I was a kid and,
uh,
I was a big Wahoo McDaniels fan
who was Wahoo McDaniels. Oh, come
on. I don't know man. I don't know.
Danielle came up during
the Bob Backlund day.
Yeah, this is gay. He was a Dallas Cowboy
at one time and he was from Midland,
Texas. And he was Cherokee
Indian sides of him.
Oh yeah. Look at him. And he
looked like a comedian to write.
He was like shaky green or somebody,
right? Like, yeah. Who Does he look like?
He would, he would come out.
Now I, I, this is the first,
my first encounter with the peanut,
my first encounter with
the police Buddy Hackett.
That is what his Buddy Hackett that my,
my cousin who's a few years
older than me. Well, I'm,
I'm visiting my relatives up in this
little town north of Amarillo. Uh,
and so we go down,
down,
down and Merrill six 60 miles down to
Amarillo and he's going to take us to the
sport, a tutorial to watch, uh,
the super inferno who I hated.
I mean,
this was on local television,
all over the taxes. Then they,
and they, one of the stops
was there and, uh, and,
and so we win. And I, and I
don't think I'd been to one yet.
And it was my first one and a,
and I love Wahoo McDaniels cause
he gets out of there and just be,
and he comes back from anything.
Right. You'll think he's out of it.
It ain't out of it.
He just say he is amazing and fun
and you know, I just loved him,
loved him.
Look and a,
and I hated the super inferno cause
he was like rushing or something,
hit something that they would,
there was easy to hey cause we're all
the propaganda we were getting about
Russia. It was like their women are ugly.
I'm like, no, they're not. You know,
it took me a while. It was like, it
was almost like Phil, uh, Pittsburgh,
because we talk so bad about my relatives
about Pittsburgh because they hated
the Steelers. And I just had this
image of Pittsburgh, of this dark,
cloudy people been over gray in the face.
And first time I drove
into Pittsburgh I was like,
I just place his gorgeous look
at this place. It's a blast.
It's a hoot. Great place to
perform. Oh yeah. It's, it's always,
you know, it's always been a big,
uh, a big stop for me. I mean,
once I got out of the club,
yeah. Pittsburgh's gray.
Cleveland's another one that's very
underrated. Cleveland's fucking ground.
I had a blast playing.
They didn't Improv down in the flats
man titty bar right there in the parking
lot. It was like, man,
this is one stop shopping for Ron White.
How many dates he do in a
year, these days. Hundred and
Chins. Shit, he's last year.
Oof. And then, uh, and then I, you know,
and then I tried to do sets when
I'm in town and, and uh, the, uh,
and I should do more, you know, I kind
of Nice. Is it to have a store though?
You know, it's great. Uh, I went
to the memorial and, uh, Brody's.
Yeah. And uh, you know,
I'd like to just tell your listeners
that you never know when it's going to be
the last time you see somebody.
So don't ever,
ever hesitate to say I'm
going to need that money.
Right.
You can't do it later.
You can't get it from their mother.
You know, you can't do that.
So very good point. So don't forget that
every time I saw a Brodeo game, a hug,
that's one thing. The protean I
always had and always, always.
Every single time I saw Brodie,
God gave him a big hug.
Like he was a big hugger. Yeah. You know,
I, I only knew him as a brother. You know,
I, you know, I, I feel important.
I feel like it's important to me to be a
part of the comedy community, you know,
participate in it.
If you're out there and you're a
comedian and you want to be a comedian,
you can be a comedian,
but you got to go be a comedian and you
got to do it every day. You know, every,
you know, for the, for the most part,
and I know you're the same way. I mean,
I know the, that you'd never pass up an
opportunity to get behind the microphone,
whether it's eight or 10 million
people to listen to this are,
there are 65 people in a whatever. It
doesn't matter. Doesn't matter to me.
You got to do it all, all the
time. To do it right all the time.
You lose the touch with the reality of it.
And also it's pace,
rhythm could be in and how
comfortable you are in any situation.
You know, this situation, it's just
me and you talking or 26 people.
I play the laughing skull and
Atlanta to 65 people sold out.
It's one of the hottest rooms I've ever
had. My hands. I love that joint. Oh,
in that cool place. Yeah, I did that
place a couple of years ago. Yeah.
That was my hand when I lived out there.
And what a great place to practice. Oh,
it was, it was great.
It's a great staff too.
It's like a there look comedy fans,
people.
The vortex was a really cool
bar. Next Great Burgers, right?
They sell a lot of number one tequila.
Nice. Yeah. That's a great little spot.
If you could have, that's
what every city needs, right?
They need a great little comedy community.
You know,
where you got up in commerce
that are really working on it.
People that really appreciate it.
Well, there was a really good, uh, uh,
comedy scene in Atlanta and
I like a couple of guys that
won last comic standing,
uh, came out of Atlanta. And that's
great. I'm so bad with names. Like, yeah,
it's only like if you stopped and think
how many real comedy communities are
there in the country. I don't even
think there's 10. You think there's 10?
Well,
you know,
Saint Louis has always had
one in Chicago's always had
Denver's always had one.
And of course, La, New York, Houston, uh,
kicks in Greenley and pineapple,
pineapple.
Once,
he didn't want to use to do,
he would drive all the way
across Houston to ignore me.
That's what he did it,
he did it all the time too.
And he had no reason to be there.
And I,
and I know that some of those guys
didn't like me because I don't,
I don't know why. I don't know why,
but they were really, really clickish.
And I went in there and one night
and had a horrible set and a,
and I was following Hicks
or, and uh, you know,
and I had really green show, but in
the right circumstance, you know,
in a comedy club with nothing
great happening before you,
it kind of worked a little bit
that night and didn't work at all.
And uh, Eh, eh, but,
and I was probably getting a little more
work than those guys were, some of them.
And they were like, oh, he sucks. Well,
the fact of the matter is I did suck
because of my act went up. You know,
you don't want to follow it.
I say that to make the story better.
I wasn't following Hicks,
but he was, you know,
or Kennison, but they were both
there. Oh, okay. No, I had done set,
but everybody was good. I mean, the
green to be good. All these guys,
we're seasoned pros. So that
was a hotline up and, uh,
but, but I never felt, you know, like the,
any of them liked me except for Higgs.
And I came to see him, you
know, do, do shows and, uh, uh,
I asked him to do the story about,
uh,
just the John Davidson and
the mask and the, and he goes,
here's what he says. He goes, don't
stand next to the exit. It's just a tip.
Cause people just walk out of
the show. When he had watched
him do that, he, he, uh,
he did that at the Nick's comedy stop in
Boston and he cleared the fucking room
man.
And it was,
it was crazy because at the end of the
show there was me and Greg Fitzsimmons
and maybe three or four of the comics
of five or six people in the crowd.
There was like maybe 20 people left, all
told, laughing our fucking asses. Right.
Everybody else is getting up angry.
I saw it go both ways. You know,
I've seen him beat crowds to death.
I saw,
I sat one night at the last stop and
Austin and nobody in the room could
breathe. And he was in the mood to do
it. And, uh, you know, and you know,
and, and I think sometimes he wasn't,
sometimes he, yeah. Or whatever,
but he was in the mood and decided to
just fucking stab us all in the face and
the, and it was, and it
was just, it was beautiful.
He was exceptional.
Now,
whether or not people think he
was one of the greats like that,
that's entirely subjection,
right? It's subjective.
Rather you'd say it's completely up
to your own interpretation. But to me,
he changed comedy and a lot of ways
because he made people talk about things
that were important because everybody
else was talking about nonsense.
You're talking about airline food and
how come I can't lean my seat back?
Standard normal shit. I'm
following that up. Exactly right.
And he was coming along talking about
a positive drug stories. You know,
a man on acid realize it all matters.
Energy condensed to a slow
rhythmic vibration. Like
that whole fucking bit was,
it was Tom with the weather app.
That feels amazing.
Yeah, no, no, it was anyways,
influential. I mean the, I know it,
I think I can say this about Bill Hicks
and I am an expert at standup comedy.
I would have a triple doctorate in,
uh,
if you gave those kinds of
things for the work. I've,
the amount of time I've
put into it and uh, and it,
and you as a peer would
have the exact same thing.
So for me to listen to someone's
opinion about standup comedy,
they have to have a lot of credit to me
before I really give a shit what they
think. Okay. So here's
what you should think.
The only thing that every comic from my
generation agrees on is he was better
than us. And that's the only thing
that they agree on. And, and,
and they,
and I can't find anybody that has
a big argument that he wasn't,
and that was the best that ever lived.
No.
But did he influenced me
more than anybody else.
And you probably more than anybody else
because you're certainly that way also,
you know. Right. Some of them, somebody
built that bridge. Yes. And you,
and now you feel free to talk
about anything. You know,
none of yours act as ever hack. You
know, there were a lot of hacks,
but I think it's freed people
not to be a hack, you know?
Yeah. He uh, he cared people that
he made it shameful, you know,
are talking about hat. But there was also
you're cured above stealing material.
So I don't know if I did I, well,
I think it's still going on.
I guarantee you it's [inaudible]
there's a chain reaction to it.
Just like craft getting caught,
getting a blowjob that shut down business
all know you've gotten to know United
States.
Nobody walked into a spa without wondering
whether or not existing of Arabian
and your name was going
to be blown out on them.
Isn't that crazy?
But here's the thing they miss.
They get this guys that there's a
video of this guy doing a massage.
So they've got video of it, right? And
at the end, the girl jerks them off.
What if she didn't jerk them off?
What if she just gave him a massage?
What kind of a fucked
up invasion of his privacy have you
just went in there to get a massage?
Right? Or was everybody just
getting jacked off? I would imagine,
but he sent him a plea
deal to drop the charges.
So I don't know what happened really.
He ratted everybody out.
I need to stay at, yeah, he's
not going to brown kids. Well, it
Jackie, you know, I was a so lonesome, you
know, I took some comfort there. You know,
in my lifetime has a Paul
Simon once wrote and,
and um, okay. I'm not, I'm, you know what,
I'm not going to say it because it's
just not worth it. You're worth it.
It's not it.
But everybody seems to be perfectly aware
that they could be washing your feet.
Yeah.
Yeah. And you know, and that's fine. Yeah.
Why is it that a guy like that
would go to a place like that?
Like he's so rich, I, you know what?
He has a guy, if you don't have a guy,
should get a guy no further,
a cleaner look,
look no further than a in the,
and this is ever,
everybody's going to realize that you
reached out fading. My memory is now, but,
uh, uh, uh, the English actor
that got caught with the, uh,
yes. Elizabeth Hurley's husband
Hugh Grant, right? Yeah.
Look at Hugh Grant. Married to the hottest
woman on the planet at the time. Right.
Ruthlessly hot.
Raw. Yeah. Amazingly hot. He wasn't
married to her either. Right.
They're boyfriend, girlfriend. And uh,
and even I couldn't understand that.
Right. I mean, cause I, I, you know, I've,
I've been with a couple of hot chicks
before in my life, but this was,
he wanted a freaky. Yeah. He
and I, you know, ag, I get that.
And it comes back to that appetite
thing that guys have. You know,
I've gotten a hand job from somebody
and I admit this and it was the best sex
I've ever had in my life because it
was somebody that was a number one,
it was a great massage. And then
this tantric thing going on and uh,
and, and, you know, and, and it,
but it was fantastic and,
and pricey and, uh, and,
and it's free most anywhere.
And that's in Vegas is legal as it can be.
You know,
they have milking tables and have a
whole, your Dick Hangs through and, uh,
they do table. Look it up, look
it up. They got it for the guy.
If he lives in his stomach. Well, you
don't have, you got somebody to crack.
You got somewhere to put the hard on.
He's laid on your back. No,
but it makes more sense.
Hygienically to have like a
hole in the bottom of the table.
Okay.
It'll be on the screen, I'm sure
soon that is. Listen, listen,
I,
all I'm saying is that in like in Canada,
they,
you know, are the, most of
the rest of the world. It's,
uh,
getting a tug is really not a
crime of any kind whatsoever,
and is harmless. And who
gives a shit and, well,
why is it okay to massage your feet?
But it's not okay to my, I know what,
I would rather massage my dick
then my own feet. I would,
and I prove it on a regular basis,
regular basis.
I think the problem really is sex
trafficking. That's the problem.
And that horrible error.
That's the worst thing. Exactly.
I can imagine, but, but it,
but again,
I'm not gonna,
I'm not gonna go there because it's the
most horrific thing you could imagine.
The most horrific thing
you can imagine taking.
Just finish watching that series
about taking Madeline, uh, and,
um, and so I'm like, I
just can't even that, that,
that I would, you know, I would support
any, anything, any way, shape or form,
uh, to have it stomped out,
spend billions of dollars,
put boots on the ground,
will stop it if you can,
in any way you can. Women who are
trying to be legitimate sex workers,
whether or not you think that's
the thing, they, you know,
it doesn't matter what I think, it
isn't, it isn't, you know, go down to go.
I just went to Amsterdam before I took
my mother to Barcelona because I wanted a
little three day stopover,
uh,
before I spent eight days a
mom and Barcelona and, uh,
and their signs don't take pictures
of our sex workers, our sex workers,
not sex with our sex work. And, uh, mean
they, they, they totally own it and go,
hey, this is not a bad deal.
You know, uh, you know,
your,
you know what you're qualified to do,
make French fries or it turns
out you're super hot and,
and you in our country, you can have
this job or in la or in this country,
you can have that job,
just not everywhere,
but it was only a couple of spots in
this country. Right. But in Nevada,
in Nevada for, I think that, I didn't
even know. I think it just Nevada.
I think that's it, but it's, to
me, here's what's really important.
Okay.
I play Vegas a lot,
right?
I'm 10 weekends a year at
the Mirage and marijuana is,
uh,
is legal recreationally now.
And they have the biggest dispensary
in the world was just like a, like,
it's like a universal made it or
something. You know, I went in there,
it was fantastic.
And a prostitution is legal.
You can get a little drink of liquor
24 hours a day, seven days a week.
And I realized that I'm
a law abiding citizen.
I hear when I'm standing on this
part of the United States ground,
I don't break any laws at all.
I can be free.
That's why I feel so good when I
go to Vegas. That's why people go,
do you like Vegas? Do you get tired
of it? And I'm no, no. You know why?
Cause I can breathe deep motherfucker.
That's why I could be who I am.
I can it openly.
Yeah,
I can, uh, you know it and, and,
and so can everybody else
saying that? And that's why, uh,
Oh yeah, I've, I've sold
out 250 shows and same with
the, you know, the, uh, you,
you realize it's the law
that causes the paranoia.
You know,
because when you're in Amsterdam and one
of those coffee shops smoking a joint
and drinking a bad ass cup of coffee,
it's fun and free,
you know,
freeing and it's the way it
should be. You know, the, the,
the fact of the matter is,
the same thing happens to me at Florida
with just a little bit. I'm handcuffed,
taken to jail and,
and moved from city jail,
the county jail and processed and
fingerprinted and photographed.
They printed my address
on the Internet so people,
anybody in the world could just
walk straight over to the house.
I don't think anybody did because
nobody gives a shit except for people.
A few people did. Right?
Ron White has a jet
[inaudible]
that's the part I don't believe.
But anyway,
yeah man, it's laws. The real problem
when you make alcohol illegal, you,
you made organized crime big.
That's what happened.
That's what they did learn
that from prohibition.
They should be learning that from all,
all the drug problems
we have in this country.
Alana,
we'll be selling for the price of corn
in 20 years because it takes the same
amount of effort to grow it, right? Yeah.
No, it's easier. This is probably easier.
You probably need less pesticides. Right?
You know, there's, um,
there's a gigantic problem south of our
border folks with drugs and it's because
of us. It's 100% because of us. We've,
I mean, not us, like you and me,
I don't do any drugs.
They sell the pot that I get,
I get from people that
grow it in California,
but there's a lot of people that buy
coke and if you buy coke or Meth,
you probably buying it from
someone down there. And you know,
there's a God damn thriving industry that
would go away if we made things legal.
If you gave people like you Ron,
why you're telling me you
shouldn't be able to go buy coke?
Who the fuck they to tell you?
You can't buy coke? First of all,
you sell Tequila.
Kill yourself.
Yeah. Feel the way more fucked
up on my Dick Ila. Yeah. Or No.
Quick as fucked up as far as fucked up
as heroin as fucked up is anything else.
I know. Probably easier
to close it off. You know,
I all on my own amazingly great Tequila.
Uh,
I have found myself puke and because I'm
an idiot and got just too carried away,
you know, it's probably easy
to kill yourself with, to
kill them. It is. With coke,
you probably have to do a
lot of coke to die. Right.
It's probably hard to do that.
Coke at the end when you're
fucking nose is bleeding.
Your heart's pounding out of your chest
to go take another bump to push yourself
over the edge.
It's probably hard and a scar face.
Oh yeah. Oh yeah. Right. He lived
cocaine. They shot him up 55 times.
Yeah, they didn't. No. Joey
Diaz is alive and well.
He tried ideas is alive and well.
Right?
You got to do a lot of coke to kill
you, especially. Well, Joey Diaz,
that motherfucker can eat.
He can eat rat poison and go do a show.
He'd be mocket death.
Fuck you. Cock sucker.
I went to see him in Austin.
He was playing at us that we had
watched him just blister a crowd.
I mean, you just go listed him. He's my
go. It was a, it was so much fun to watch.
He was a,
that seemed do short sets all the time,
but I got to watch him do you know you
have 50 I think if he did probably around
50 minutes or something like that.
And it was great. We had a blast.
Try replicating that and this
fucking sanitized world. Right?
There's pure al everywhere you turned.
The thing is if you're a true and they
are something that I believe that if it
is a comic or whatever,
if you're true to your nature,
then enough people will be attracted
to that and that you don't,
the only mistake you can make is to
not be true to your nature. Right.
And if you look at all the great
or really successful comics and a,
in the history of comedy, they,
they were true to who they were.
I mean Cosby but,
but you know,
he tricked everybody.
Yeah. He pulled one over on us.
Can you imagine if he was honest?
What I like to do a drug
where man and fuck them.
I really did that bit of state. I never
really did that bit on stage very much.
Can I do it on your shoulder?
Oh fuck yeah, they uh, let
me think about it cause I
got bill Cosby and Bill
Co is bills defense, uh,
explained to us years ago how much he
hates cursing and no one curses more than
a wide awake woman who's being raped.
So
it's terrible.
It just Joe.
But it made me cry laughing cause
it's so fucked up. I mean you look,
it's both true and fucked
up, right? Oh yeah, it is.
Yeah. It's not an endorsing rape.
That's why it never really found a spot.
The opening line up.
That's an hour and 20 minutes long.
So open with that mother fucker,
sir. I know I do. I, you know what,
it was always just a mixed review. It
made people think it may. Yes. You know,
it was like baby duck pussy lip tacos.
You know,
you either liked it or you didn't like
it, but you listen to the next bit. Wow.
You made sense though? It does make
sense. I mean, it really does show,
it's just a funny thing to say.
Well, I think we should all
should have known like with his
trying to control other people.
He was always trying to control young
black comics and stop them from swearing.
Right.
Eddie Murphy to prior or was it yeah.
And people any called prior.
Yeah.
Shut the fuck up. Did you get paid? Eh,
tell bill to have a coke and a smile
and shut the fuck up. Yeah, that's it.
That was, there's a guy that I'd like to
get back into comedy. Eddie Murphy, Eddie,
if you're out there,
kept packing the comedy so hard at a raw,
you know Ross Oh, good. Delirious.
Delirious of the best comedy
specials of all time. Of all time.
And he did his thing, but he said
also himself. Yes. Bill Cosby himself.
He himself was very good that,
you know, a lot of comics.
Learned a lot about standup comedy
watching bill Cosby himself. Oh yeah.
He knew how to hold a moment. Oh yeah. Oh,
it was a beautiful, we works. So you know,
that thing was framed like this.
The whole show was just his face and no
cutaway to fucking people laughing in
the audience are cheesy shots from up
here where you can't see who it is.
It was just framed in red, right?
Just on his face and, and, and it was,
it was gorgeous work. Just gorgeous
work. I've thought about this many times.
Do you think that those
people from back in that era,
from back in like the sixties and the
50s that they used to drug each other and
they didn't think it was as big a
deal like that men would do that,
which would we would consider
today to be horrific. You know,
the idea that you would take someone's
daughter and drug her and it's horrific.
Oh yeah, we want violent repercussions.
Yeah, that's fine, that violent,
I want to smash. But do you think that
maybe back then they were ignorant,
they didn't know any better.
Like you always hear about people slipping
people in Mickey did they think it
was cute where they actually do it? Like
how many men were doing that back then?
Do you know what?
I'm [inaudible] I find myself to
be a so conservatively that I,
I really can't think outside in that box.
Get all,
I just watched that documentary
about him taking that girl.
They don't know what happened to her.
Took her when she was three years old,
but they were,
but it talked a lot about recovery and
all that and just how sick of fucking
world is out there. And I can't
even think about it. I mean, I,
this one detective had to look through
these dark websites and I'm like,
and look at these images and you can't,
and look at those images. You know,
it's just a sickening thing. No, Ron,
they're having a hard time with that,
with the people that work for social
media sites when they have to take down
videos like on Facebook and things
like that. I like a lot of them,
like they're taking down these
horrific videos, like horrible,
all shit all day long.
These people were just finding the
things that are like horrible accident.
It's horrible. Assassinations, isis
videos and they're just taking them down.
Right. You know, I was on
Jim Norton show one time.
He showed me a video of a gaff
fucking a snake. And I'm like, dude,
I don't want to see any of this
shit was in the fucking gym.
Know when Jim Jam and that. And
he's very, very funny and I love to,
whatever I do with Jim is fun.
But he looks at anything on the people
covering the heads off and all that stuff.
But he just said, well look at
it. And I'm like, the guys that
snake pussy,
he found a snake plus he and stuck.
Well, you ever see a snake egg,
you know, regular size cock.
So you know it's a fucking
hole. Yeah, it's fine to hold.
The dude's haven't fucked. I'll
find you whole. It can't be fucked.
Five the fetish. I love Jim Norton
for the same reason why I love you.
He's just himself like he's not
pretending to be anybody. He's an himself.
They won't watch your man fucking
snake. He's, he watched men fuck men.
He loves everything he likes.
He likes transgender women.
He gets off on it, it gets it. He gets,
and he's open about it talks about all
the time to the point where when he was
on Opie and Anthony and the
one they were in their prime,
it was like one of the major
themes was that a Norton,
is it into a transgender women?
What's that called?
I don't know. It's called being Jim
Norton. Right. He's happy. I mean,
there's gotta be a name, right?
There's probably some names.
So this is probably like
a slang term for it.
Then there's probably some
sort of, uh, you know,
I was actually thinking of anybody knew
what that was. It would be you. Yeah.
I've never heard Jamie.
You think there's a word for dudes
are only in two transgender women?
I bet there is. If there isn't, we could
probably make, now you're talking about,
sure.
There's got to be,
oh,
a man is now a woman.
Right, right, right. Not a
woman that's now a man. Well,
this should be two. Right?
There's piggers, which is a man who's
now one of them is still has a Dick,
and she can peg you. Yeah. Right?
She's your girlfriend and
she can fuck your ass. I had,
I had sex with a woman that was a,
she played for the WWE Mba. Well, she said
three, but I know she was a full head
taller than me and she was so tall.
She could stick a finger in my ass.
She,
her arms are so long that she could
reach around while I was whoa and stick a
finger in my ass. And I'm like, let's
just go to the church, you know,
and get married.
Silver
with some gladiator children.
Big Funny Dude. Come on,
search here. I haven't found that term,
but I've even heard a lesbian man,
a lesbian man. What does that mean? Okay,
I'll take a stab at it and
say help me. It's uh, it's,
it's a,
it's a man who turned themselves into
a woman, but he still likes women.
Yeah. But he can keep his penis, I think.
I think that's what's going on. Yeah.
He goes by,
he just likes to be pegged by women.
Oh, not in, he's not in the guys.
I've never heard that term. I just,
I'm looking for a lesbian man,
so he only likes gay,
bisexual.
That just opens the field up all the way
that shuts it down. That you're right.
And who's going to, that's like a
Iq, that pond to fish from question.
Not very big.
Not that big
a lesbian man. Imagine if like that's
all you'll put the bat signal out.
I'm a lesbian man.
I'm just looking for Gals to peg me.
I bet there's a lot of them that would
want to fuck you just for revenge.
How much of that is a women that,
why is it that the pretty women don't
seem to have any problem with men?
Like a lot of them were like
pretty easy going about men,
but if you have bad genetics,
like if you got dealt a
wrong end of the stick,
that's that is if there's like people
talk about income inequality in this
country and that's definitely a real
thing. But if there's a real thing,
it's like who do people want to
fuck inequality in this country?
And that's off the Goddamn charts,
right?
I mean there's just as men and as women,
we just have to,
we have to understand that some people,
they have a unearned
tyranny on sexual affection.
It's unearned.
They didn't have to do anything like
these Russian women at that people are
lying to you about, right? Yeah.
You meet them and you go, Jesus,
it's just rushing gladiator genetics
and perfect like model form and you're
like, Holy Shit, let me get the
fuck out of this room quick.
I was on a cruise one time
that was married and um,
and I had rented the, like the back
quarter I've ever in the same spot.
Oprah stays in and it
cost a fortune and I'm at,
we're out on the deck and there's two
big suites in the middle and another one
just like mine at the end.
But the one that was in this one,
which was also a real expensive room, was
this Russian dude. And he was short guy,
chunky and bald.
But the girl who was with him was
just a 12 and I knew his second.
I saw her.
I was fucked because there's no way
my wife was not going to catch me.
Just at least take it away.
One little glimpse
and then she was going out.
Yeah, that's what you want. You'd rather
fuck her and then me. And I'm like, no.
Absolutely not. Absolutely
not. Why would I? Why would I?
That's outrageous.
What did outrageous assertion?
What an accusation.
Yeah.
If they only knew how vulnerable
we are to a woman like that,
it's like that woman can,
there's a lot of people that that
woman can like run their life and they,
they'll meet a guy who's an accountant
who's never fucked a 12 and they'll start
talking to him and basically end up
doing the thing they want to do as long
as they're willing to actually touch him.
Right. As long as you're willing to
stick their fucking beautiful guys mouth,
he's helpless to suck on his lips
with Brian, that pussy against deck,
he's grab his ass.
She put your finger on the
base of his taint and rub it.
Why you stick your tongue down his throat.
His Dick is hard as a rock.
Well, these things have
never happened to this man.
There goes the neighborhood time
was back the car up to the house.
Throw the keys in the fucking yard. Tell
the kids, yeah, that's an ice tea. Sorry.
I'll do it. Turned out this way. A hood,
ice tea and body count.
Fuck yeah.
There's certain women that
they could just run you. Oh,
well I know. I know. I know. I get it.
I get it. I'm married. One of them
got to be careful. Just get you,
uh, if you, if you're not, if
you're not, here's the thing.
Yup.
How much of that,
Blake, for dudes who you, there's
certain cases where you know,
it's not gonna work. Like
God dammit, this dude,
he's like a small sheep and he married a
wolf or it's just a matter of time for,
she fleeces him and gets the fuck out
of dodge and hopefully he'll still be
alive, but this is not going to work
out well. We've all seen that before.
Oh, I wish I could tell you this
story. I wish you could too.
Let's shut this fucking podcast off and
resume at 10 minutes. Okay. All right.
Let me,
let me tell you this story because I
just don't want to say it's intertwined
with something, right, right, right.
But it's very, very pertinent.
You know everything with that.
She was on the legal ramifications.
Can anybody go to jail? No.
Can Anybody get sued? No.
No. I don't think so and
it's the truth. Okay,
so I'll just create a fictional scenario.
Let's call the gentlemen.
What do you want to call it?
Let's let let,
let's call him Todd Blaker tie.
Bleeker.
Okay. Now I can't even do it
this way, but I'll get chastised.
I think people would find out slow down
and also I'm drunk and I know you get me
drunk on your show and Oh, it's my
fault. Give me fucking people on reddit.
They had their fingers above the
keys. They were hovering, right?
He starts searching,
right?
There is no such thing as a guide and
I will not tell you the story on this.
Anyway, what was amazing was, I
saw it happening in front of me
is his wife was there and they'd been
married for a long time and he didn't look
like much and, and uh, at all.
And uh,
and,
and there was a kind
of an assistant and uh,
that was ridiculously
gorgeous. And so I just looked
at that and I was like, uh,
and it went exactly. I've seen where
I thought it was going in and a,
and there was nothing he can do.
Mean there was absolutely,
he was completely power
this person, nothing he could do. He
wouldn't give everything. Oh yeah.
Gary Oldman and Dracula. I remember that
time we were like, what? No, no, Ryan,
it was just hypnotized by put,
putting a shirt in the middle of the night
and Gary old would be slithering into
the fucking windows as missed
or body heat with, it's like,
oh yeah, with Kathleen Turner towards
the fucking chair through the window,
throw your right in the fucking bat.
He didn't even want to abuse
the door to fuck her. And, uh,
it was great. I was counseling and
turn it back in the desert. Ooh.
How it gets.
I mean she developed some health
problems as she got older,
but when she was young, holy moly. Yeah.
It was amazing. Yeah.
There was a lot of things
or feel like rubbing went off thinking
about me. Oh, you're your few.
So go ahead and do it.
Nice. Nice reciprocation. Yeah.
It's hard when you watching the guy get
preyed upon when you're watching like a
man's struggle with the fucking spiders
web and you're like, well hey man,
you know, that'd be fun when she
does fuck you right there. Right.
So as long as you can stay
active and get close to her,
I don't want to get too much money.
It was careful.
Yeah. It, uh, I, I know
because, uh, you know the,
the, the one I had been around for a long
time and it was a contract, so, right.
Yeah.
So there goes that part of it,
but I think the paperwork was fairly solid
in towards the end of like a limit or
whatever. Okay. Now
No, keep moving. All right.
I knew a guy who was about to marry gown
shouldn't know and he was trying to uh,
do uh,
no prenuptial and my friends
were screaming at him like,
what the fuck are you talking about? And
he's like, look man, I don't if it was,
if it doesn't work out, I'd like her to
have half and then went. But the fun,
it's almost like,
you know,
like you wish you had garlic to put
around you right now you're telling Noah
about the flood
show really to animals and they both ugly.
She's not okay.
Understand this world is not fair.
The reality of not fair is you made enough
money to attract her, but she's got a,
she's got a web and you might get hooked
and you might get injected or you might
be able to figure out a way to keep
her nervous. Right. How do you,
do you gotta act mysterious bro?
I'm serious and I have like a a book.
Is that how you did a, a special books
that you read? You got to be Moody,
got to go on early morning
runs or they're still asleep.
Get to get show powers that they
don't have to do any of these things.
You got to show powers haven't
done one of these things. Yeah.
You have to be different. You have to
be able to quote Shakespeare. Yeah.
You gotta be,
you gotta be willing to give up a lot of
money if you're not going to do and you
got a hot wife,
you've got a certain amount of time
before she gets bored with you fucker
trainer.
Right.
Her trainer here at what I think is
going to happen is within the next week.
That exact same thing. Oh, I've
seen that happen. Yeah. I've, uh,
I've been friends with a lot of
people where that's happened. Um,
what I think is going to happen within
the next 50 years is there going to be
able to eliminate the idea of unattractive
people legitimately through through
DNA. Right. I think they're
gonna be able to do that. We're,
they're not going to know the world that
we knew when we were kids. No Internet,
no fake tits.
Sometimes people were just unattractive.
No one knew anything about diet.
Nobody worked out. Nobody worked out.
When I was in high school,
it'd be fucking work.
Dudes would like bench press and shit.
You know,
like how many women lifted weights when
we were in high school and that the
cheerleaders were in good shape.
Yeah, for a little while. Yeah,
for a little while and I got nobody.
Nobody kept going.
Did Rocky really start like the
big movement started my movement.
I've read about it, but I don't know how
true it is. I was two way too young dude.
When rocky came out,
I think I was seven and a,
I drank raw eggs and ran around the block
and I told her vessels to load. That
100% did. I was like, Holy
Shit. I want to be a fighter.
I started drinking eggs and running.
I never ran. Oh, seven years old, man.
Fuck my doing running. Maybe I was eight
head no such effect. Dot. Donta Donta Dah,
Dah, Dah, Dah. I was like, well, rod
was amazing. He goes eight. I
don't even know how old I was,
but I remember it when it came out.
I've never been more inspired
for something in my life.
I'm moving change the world. People
don't even understand how good it was.
He lives on my street.
Really? Yeah, he does.
He's on one time driving
his range rover with a,
with a big cockatiel on his shoulder.
Like, well that's Kinda cool. There he is.
There he is running around fucking
weights in his hand and shit.
Why don't we converse all stars? One of
the reasons why we're after this day,
they might not be all stars.
There might be kids.
It might be like some cheap
Walmart version. Who knows?
But this is some fucking epic shit.
In the 1970s,
what year was this movie?
Let's take a guess.
What year do you think it was?
I want to say it was like 79 yeah,
76 76 the spirit of 76 was the rematch.
No, there was 76 because
that was when Apollo creed,
I want 76 at a middle as exactly
in one debtors across uh,
uh, I believe it was Alabama. We and uh,
he drove a 1970.
He drove the bicentennial Vega.
Right.
So it was a Vega,
the 76 Vega W had said 76,
you know, some things
that would, you know,
celebrate the sesquicentennial
or whatever it was. Um,
no, it was probably 200 years, I guess.
I don't know. I don't know. A long time.
I was nine years old when this movie
came out and so that's exactly how old I
was. I got to tell you, is it technique?
Like God needs to tighten up and
swing like the way thrown punches.
So that would been neat to coach.
He needed a coach.
Well he got one in Carl
weathers. This was, uh,
in rocky two rocky to Carl
weathers became as put it,
was it rocky three three, right, because
that was when he fought Mitchell. Yeah,
that's right. Right.
Yeah. He woman since Amen.
Ain't got no hot beat. Just stay up
every night wishing he had a real man.
Bring your pretty little cell phone my
apartment tonight and I'll show you a
real man.
You probably wouldn't say,
I couldn't believe he was
saying that to rocky. Right,
right. It was like if he was saying it to
a Wahoo McDaniels, you know? Yeah man. Oh,
I didn't even finish that story.
Oh yeah. So here's what happened.
My first encounter with the police,
I found out that that the bad
guys were coming out of one side,
one dressing room, and the good guys
were coming out of the other side.
So I went up to the standards and waited
for the super inferno to come out.
And when he came out, I spit on him.
I just spit on. It was just a big old,
I hate it all. I really, I did. I, I've
never hated anybody who before eight
just spit on him. And uh, then the
cop saw me do it and they came,
got me and they took me to
my cousin and they were like,
he spit on a super inferno and he,
you know,
he was like, oh, that's horrible. And
if he does anything, you just keep,
and so, but afterwards, my cousin thought
it was hilarious. Of course you did.
That's a story. I was trying to put him
out the super inferno. Oh, I get it. Yeah.
It's funny.
Yeah.
I don't think I've ever been to see a
live professional wrestling match other
than Eleanor Kerrigan from the
comedy store. Well, you know Tony and
uh, uh, those guys, they go to the,
Oh yeah. They were like, you got to go
with this. And I'm like, Nah. You know?
All right.
Tony was responsible for 10 minutes of
my last special me shitting on him for
load probe. Right, right, right.
It was, I remember, I remember.
He loves it. Yeah, he
does that show the four,
what does it call for storm? And
I believe you're storming. It's a,
they do a wrestling podcast from the
comedy store with a bunch of other comics.
Who were the other guys? Find out their
names. You'll find it out in a line.
But uh, yeah, he loves that Shit.
Loves it. He's always like, dude,
you got to watch it with me.
You'll love it.
I loved it when I was a kid.
It's the store horsemen.
Horsemen. Oh, perfect sound.
Right. Who are the gentleman that are
involved in this venture with them?
Fun Show. I did it once. Tony
Hinchcliffe Johnny's Scortis.
Matt Edgar and Josh Martin. There you
go. There you go. Yeah. Chris Burns.
There you go. There you go. Yeah,
they do it from the basement.
And you've been in that studio
downstairs in the basement.
I did a podcast out of their
fucking great down there man.
I love the fact that the comedy
store's embraced podcast.
You know what the comedy store
embraces what's important always.
Yeah. Over any other place. So you know
what they embrace comedians and uh,
you know, customers really come
second to the comics there.
So cause there's one parking lot
and people probably not know this,
but there's one parking lot holds about
30 cars or something like that or 20
cars or whatever.
And guess who gets to park there?
The comedians that are playing that night,
they get to pull right up and park by
the door. And that is so cool to me.
And not only that,
there's a bar that if your name
is not written on that building,
you can't go in it without somebody
who's name is written on that building.
And those are the,
and it's so cool to have your name written
on that building and go to that bar
that's just for you. And, uh,
and I, I, you know, they, they,
they have the, my number
one Tequila and, and uh,
I can smoke cigars and not
everybody could spoken there,
but I get that one little extra deal.
They don't give a fuck.
Don't you do whatever you want in there.
Uh, yeah, yeah. And there's a place
to smoke pot. They built that.
They built a glass piano for prior to
snort cocaine of office because they
understood, here's what
they understood, Joe,
here's what they understood.
They understood the comics are insane.
So come be insane here. You know,
if, if you're crazy, we get it.
We don't care. Come be crazy
here. You know, and, and,
and then at the Improv
you had bud Freeman,
goat going language language.
Watch your language.
He's fucking him. Say
that. I heard him say it.
And the first time I ever
came to the comedy store,
which was probably in 90 or 89,
I made a soldier and out here,
you know, to see what happens.
So I don't know anything. I don't know
anything. I don't have any friends.
I don't know. I don't
know anybody. I got it.
I was in the cheapest hotel room on
sunset boulevard, which were $50,
which was outrageous back then. And, uh,
and the first day I got into it,
a hotel into an elevator with his huge
black transvestites that there was all
dressed up going to a show,
going to, uh, to, uh, you know,
one of those big drag queen
shows. And, uh, I was like,
oh, okay. All right. And,
uh, but I went to the,
to the comedy store first and they,
they,
it was a Monday night and they fucking
put me on. I told her I've been doing,
you know, standup and Texas for, you know,
a couple of years and they fucking put me
on they, it, and I didn't do very well.
And, uh, not necessarily, you know,
early in the sat, same piano player,
you know, there's nothing changes.
And uh, but I would go to the, to the
Improv and buddy come over to me, he goes,
and he knew me because he'd seen me
do open mic at the Improv and uh,
or be the opening act and they improv in,
in Dallas and he come up to me and Ron,
could you do me a favor? I'm like, yeah,
but what?
Cause you stand over there because you're
blocking the way through here. Okay.
A little further. Okay. Okay. So they
just wouldn't they, you know, they,
I was a new guy, you know, and
all I needed was, you know, uh,
a break whether I deserved it or not,
they gave it to me. It's a, it's a store.
The store has a heart that
way, you know, they, the,
well, they, the, the store
is, the art form is primary.
That's everything. It's everything. It's,
everything is built around that art form.
He didn't use to let the
agents and the managers in
the pot, you got to buy a ticket
if you like. We're a CIA agent.
You want to come see this guy or that
Guy Ron White, he had a buy a ticket.
That's the only place in town cause so
the agents couldn't just come in and and
run the place like they
did in a lot of places.
They would come and they would be
in the back of the room talking.
I remember I went to a showcase once,
it was a backward William Morris, uh,
put on this showcase of the comedians they
represented and they did it in a club,
like a nightclub on sunset.
And Nick Depaula was onstage and
they asked me to perform like,
you're out of your fucking mind.
I'm like,
there's no way I'm going to perform at
this. I know what this is. I'm like, I'm,
I'm not looking to get hired for
anybody. Merde represented. I go,
I'm going to watch,
like this is going to be a disaster.
So I go with my manager and I'm in
the top level and everyone's talking.
All these fucking agents
and agents assistance,
they're not even watching, no
reason. Not even watching Ron.
And so I'm watching these guys struggle
on stage where no one John Henson goes
up and then Nick Depalo goes up and
nick was the only one who said anything
about it and about everybody
fucking talking at the top. Like,
these are my fucking agents.
This is unbelievable. He
was, he was making fun of it,
but it was,
the comedy store would never allow that.
They would kick everybody out of that
room. Get the fuck out of here. Right.
I get Outta here.
And they still to this day,
don't tolerate that kind of shit at a,
they don't breed that
kind of thing in college.
Let me go on record as
saying this, Joe. Hey, uh,
I'm not saying I don't like the other
rooms and I'm not saying I'm not glad
they're there. And I'm not saying I don't
need them as bad as I need the store.
Uh, uh, they're,
they're good solid comedy rooms and
I think they're trying to make the
adjustments and they're starting,
because somebody asked me the other
day at one of the other clubs,
one of the comics hanging out at
the comedy store. I'm like, Oh yeah,
let me tell you. So on
number one, Eh, you know,
so my Tequila and they do and uh,
and but also they,
they, when I come to your
place, I got either I got to,
I got to Valet Park and pay for it.
You pay me $25 to do a set,
they pay me $35.
Now both of these numbers are low,
but to some comics they'd rather have that
of the, and they noticed the 10 bucks,
you know,
she need the money and a lot of cases
that you have to choose between those two
clubs. You, is it still that
way? I mean, I know it was, no,
the store and the Improv in
particular get along really well.
We get along really well now.
And Paige,
who does all the booking for the Improv
is always at the store and she's good
friends with Adam. Okay.
That's good. Yeah. That's,
I offered you a spot on the show that
I'm doing tonight at the Improv if you
wanted to do it because I'm
there when I have time. Yeah.
You're doing a show tonight. Yeah, I'm
doing a show at eight o'clock tonight.
The improv was, you had another
one Thursday night at the Improv.
Anytime other than one tonight. Uh, full
of like Yam, Ron White. Beautiful. I mean,
I drunk at my now and the perfect
time, it's five o'clock. Alright.
By the time eight o'clock rolls around,
you'll be simmered.
You'll be like braised beef with
her having to need Adderall.
It'd be falling off the bone.
That's what I want you putting it into
your schedule. It's three hours from now.
Go Oh Jay McGraw or your your boy.
I love him.
I had his daddy on the show.
I know he's calling me now.
It was dropping science and his Daddy,
his dad's a fucking genius.
Doctor Phil. Yep. He's a great
guy. Like people who don't know,
Dr Phil,
he's a fucking great guy.
You know it, it's uh, he,
he sent me a text the other day
and he goes, I've got this idea.
You're going to think it's
crazy. And, uh, so we,
we made it the Beverly Hills Hotel and,
uh,
and I play a lot of golf
with doc and I know him well,
and I have for 10 years or
whatever, who's dot Dr Phil. Oh
yeah. Who Do you remember who
we're talking about? We said Doc,
I never called the Dotcom fell.
Oh, I thought I call him doc.
Jay's daddy can shake them out
and play it. That's what I said.
He goes, all right,
here's what we should do.
We should do a two man
show. And uh, and uh,
and I know he's out of production and
I know he's bored and he's also hurts.
So he's had that motorcycle
wreck and you know,
it's getting new shoulder surgery. Right.
So he's like, he really can't play golf.
I don't know. He's just bored. And
so it, so it really is and, and,
and I would do anything doctor
Phil wanted to do, you know,
cause I love spending
the time with him and uh,
and the add or anything he does is a
big success anyway, so I would do it.
But he really, he, he here
was his idea. It's a, it's a,
it's a two man show on Broadway.
Right.
And he goes, and then, you know,
I'm not sure how it starts and I'm like,
okay,
it would probably start with the curtain
opens and you and I are standing there
because it's a two man show on Broadway.
That's probably how it starts.
And he goes in there, we could
do a Q and a and I'm like, no,
we'd have to do something
before the Q and a doc. Right.
Because when we've done that
before and it's Hilarious, right.
Are just as close as we are.
I mean the,
where we're born and our
circumstances in life and,
uh, and, and,
and he's completely under missionally
fun fucking beyond me as far as any kind
of success that anybody's ever had.
But it wa but we both came from
nothing in the same part of the world.
And so we have this connection that
people have a hard time understanding,
you know, they can't believe you
and doctor Phil or they literally,
we tell people we love each other.
And that's, I mean, and, and, and,
and to give you a good example that he
took me dive and we flew in his golf
stream to the Cayman Islands. And I didn't
even have a certificate or anything,
but I'd had one.
It was just expired.
And so we went on this dive and he
watched me like I was four years old the
whole time we were underwater and a,
if I got close to something
I shouldn't touch, you know,
so, so I know he loves me, right.
I know he loves me and, and uh,
and so, but there, we
really didn't have an idea,
but I just knew that I knew that he was,
that he was bored and any want to have
lunch and talk about something, I'm like,
let's talk about it. I,
cause I would do anything.
I would love to figure out
something to do with him.
That makes sense because we would, because
we come off really fun together in uh,
in, in, in a,
in a juxtaposition
situation. Right. And, uh,
our views, even though we come
from a similar background,
how different the views are in some
ways now several, they are in some ways.
So it's fun stuff. We should do
your podcast together. Love it.
Yeah. He just did it. He just did it
like a two weeks. Yeah, I knew that.
I knew that that was, that he told
me. Hmm. Now he's exceptional.
Love that guy. He's fucking easy going
guy too. I'm really happy to be around.
Right. You know, like comfortable
in his own skin. See, you know,
was a reason why so successful. Right.
It's not like anybody could do that. Like,
look at that Doctor Oz guy. I talked to
Roz guy, I'm watching him and I was like,
ah, I don't know. I don't
know. I don't know doc. Well,
you know,
he,
he does three unscripted
hours a day all day,
a podcast now.
And I did his podcast because
also during that lunch he said,
also, I have a podcast and I'm
going to start it up and, uh, want,
I'm going to do a few people before I do.
You just get used to it and
then have you come on. I'm like,
well for sure I'll do that.
How funny is that?
He thinks he's needs to get
used to it. Alright. Yeah.
He just unscripted television along with
a camera in his face all day long. Well,
it turns out he didn't
need to get used to it.
He was great at it from
the very beginning.
That's the same exact skill. He talks to
people. He knows how to talk to people.
He knows how to listen. That's the, yeah,
that's what is missing in a lot of people
when it comes to the area where I've
played golf when the one time when I
was going through a divorce and, uh,
people ask me does he give
unsolicited advice? And I'm like,
he doesn't give solicited advice,
even if you asked.
So I'm playing golf with him and I'm like,
doc,
there's uh, there's divorce is
killing me. It's just killing me.
And he goes, keep your head still when
you put much what he said. And I'm like,
what? He goes, keep your
head still when you put you,
you're in a better mood
when you putt well,
but you're moving your
head all over the place.
So why don't we start with keep
your hands still when you Putt,
which now is a metaphor for a lot of
things to me is keep your head still when
you Putt, you know, do
what you do well. You know,
it's what makes you feel bad or whatever,
you know.
But in that particular case that there,
those were really simple words and I know
they were right off the cuff and I've
thought about them all the time since
you keep your head still when you Putt,
that's solid advice. Yeah. So it's,
so it's a little bee bee be more
centered me and you know it in the zone.
I'm not if you were playing pool to keep
your head down when you shoot. Right.
He had done when you shoot on the shot.
Right.
And that was a fall through but,
but you wouldn't exactly call
it advice but it, but it was,
it was something I listen to and continue
to think about to this fucking day.
It is advice because if you're
really good at golf in that respect,
if you know how to not move your head
like that's a discipline where you can,
you can apply that to the rest of your
life right here. You know, you're,
if you're loose and you're not drinking
and you're fucked up and you're not
using good technique, your head's
going to be all over the place. Right.
Same thing of pool stay down in your
right now. Archery. Yup. Oh yeah.
Camera is still fall through.
Correct. Follow through.
It's very important.
Some more.
Do you try to control it and
be all herky jerky and shit.
Archery archery's a incredible,
one of the most zen things I've
ever done in my life, surprisingly,
surprisingly zen,
you
know, Foxworthy. When he built
his big house in Georgia,
he had a deer set up dear target set up
that he could walk out on the balcony of
his office.
Yeah,
I have them in my yard.
I'm all over the place,
the deer problem in our neighborhood.
And they said,
you know what you had to do just shut
the gate and turn Foxworthy loose in here
with a Phyllo and he would
kill everything in here.
He's a natural born killer is going to
be real careful with people shooting
arrows and neighborhoods. They do
that in certain places. They have,
he's a residential deer hunting permits
where there a allow bow hunters to come
in and shoot deer in,
you know,
suburban communities.
Cause they just have such
an overpopulation of too
many people are hitting them
with their cars. And Yeah.
So like this place is like,
I think there was one place in Texas,
Jane, feed them Doritos out of your hand.
They'll just spread around you and
go, yeah, here's a bag of Doritos.
Especially those high fence places, right,
where they have feeders set up a forum.
Um, there's, there's a place in tech
in Pennsylvania look up. This is true.
There's a neighborhood where you can
hunt deer there through my meditation.
A piggy or a pig story, Tommy? No, no,
no, no. Go ahead. No, I'm done. All right.
Jamie,
will Google the Pennsylvania place
where you can hunt deer 365 days a year.
All right,
so let me,
well, we figured out a way
to tell the story. Okay.
Jay or buddy Jay McGuire
op is a TV producer, right?
So they,
they produce the doctors and the
doctor feels show and the bull on CBS,
but they also have another 10 or
12 shows on any level of cable.
And if they could sell it, they'll
make it as a TV production company.
So the guy that made the movie,
and I always grew up his name,
so I'm going to have you look it up.
Did the movie about the the kid and
we took 16 years to make link as well.
Why am I saying it right? I'm from
Texas. I don't know that movie.
What was that movie? They followed him
from the time he was a kid. It the APP,
but the movie took 16 years to make. Oh
yeah. It was called about a boy, boy.
Boy, boy. Yeah. Yeah.
So, and the director was
James got a lot of tabs
open, I think. Lean clatter.
Yup. Yup. And so
he, he, um, he, he bought two.
Uh, I just want to get
the story right. Got It.
He bought two miniature potbelly pigs
that turned out to be not manager potbelly
pig Whitney Cummings has, that's not
real at all those miniature pigs.
It just starved a little pigs.
Let me, okay, let me finish.
Let me finish. All right. So he
needs to find something
to do with these pigs.
And it turns out in Bastrop,
Texas where he lives now.
This is a very famous artistic,
probably one of the best directors
alive. And he's from Texas. He did,
he did the first movie with
Matthew mcconaughey. Hey,
uh, about living in Austin.
And I, I, and I, I, you know, you
just give me so wasted on this show.
I can't ever remember anything.
But anyway, Connie with
AIDS, right? No, no, no, no,
no,
no.
So this was the first thing Matthew
mcconahey really discovered mcconaughey in
when he was going to University
of Texas and did a movie Wat.
Wow. We've got to start bringing
a friend with me. Um, what is it?
I Dunno when you just talked
about yeah, no, no, no, no.
The Matthew mcconaughey and that director,
first movie Matthew Mcconaughey ever
did I think, was it tasting confused,
confused. [inaudible] old school.
Alright. Alright. Alright. Alright.
So, oh, okay. Was it do deer
thing? True. Yes. I found a
neighborhood where it's true,
but I'll wait. Okay. So here and I'm
going to insert a story. All right,
so this is my Matthew mcconaughey story.
When I was moving to Austin,
I have friends there that
are, you know, I like Austin.
I got friends, but I
always thought, you know,
I'll end up being friends with Matthew
mcconaughey and, uh, because we,
we know a lot of the same people, you
know, and, uh, and we both spoke power.
We're both from Texas, we're boat
and this will happen. And, uh,
and I love him and I really like
working with Wade and I was like, oh,
that's what we friends, it'll
be great. That'd be great.
Part of my thing. Awesome.
So Amit,
Matthew mcconaughey had a charity event,
but in,
in this scenario I have
imagined him saying,
your Ryan White,
you're my favorite comedian ever.
I got a hot tub going off in my backyard
with a couple of girls and I got these
great fucking joints and we'll
go over there and smoke pot,
drink Tequila and sec.
But what happened was he went,
Oh nice to me.
And then he went on to me,
the next person and it was a long
pause there where I should have said,
I love your work,
but I didn't because I already had it
planned out that he was supposed to say
how much he loved me.
And so I just left a long pause there.
And then when it was all over with, I
said, I shouldn't tell him I loved him.
I told him,
I told him I loved him but I didn't
planning. So anyway,
back to the big store. So
this guy finds the pig rescue and,
uh,
decides he wants to do a documentary
about it. Well, he calls, uh,
Jay McGraw's, right hand girl and
the right hand girl, right woman,
brilliant girl that runs
things for Jay.
And I can't remember her name because
I'm an idiot and I've met her two times,
but, uh, and uh,
and says I'd like to do a
documentary on is this thing.
So she tells Jay and he
goes, Linklater, all right.
Yeah.
So he calls cvs.
I don't even know. I should be telling a
story. And they, and they say, fuck yeah,
we'll do anything he wants to do is he's
got his name on it, right? He's, uh,
he's got a movie coming out with Cate
Blanchett as opposed to when everything
there is, and he's an
amazing guy. Just an artist,
doesn't care at thing about anything,
but art doesn't matter if it takes 16
years to make. This guy's amazing. I,
so Jay has this idea of us do, and, um,
uh,
Judge Roy Bean with me as judge,
where we've been been
doing a comedy and a,
or we were not even zeroed in on what,
but we liked me doing that character
of preacher Hang Lynn Barr Tinder,
right? So, uh, and I would
like to play the role,
and I wouldn't mind finding a TV show
to settle into at my age, you know,
for awhile, you know, if I could do it,
but it's gotta be the right thing with the
right people, or I won't do it. And, uh,
so CBS says, yeah, we'll do
it. You know, the fuck out.
We'll do it. And, uh, so
they're, they're gonna make,
they're going to have a meeting. And
so Jay calls me and he goes, well,
why don't we talk to them about this
George judge, where being thing.
So I live in Austin, right? So I'm
writing 27 miles from bass drop.
And then,
so I can go out there for the meeting
and it's in this little restaurant on a
river. And, and, uh,
and they talk about that for a little
while and then we talk a little bit about
Judge Roy Bean and then it's time
to go to the pig rescue. Well,
I don't have to go to the pig
rescue, but now I'm a big, you know,
I really want him to track this
film because I know if he does,
it'll be made a film, you know, it'll
be, it'll be a big thing if he does it.
So I go 250 pigs,
well kept and well fed,
fenced in in pins.
They actually,
there's a feral pig problem in that part
of Texas and they have these cameras
that are Predator cameras and they have
footage of these huge feral pigs walking
up to this fence looking at these pigs
going, how'd y'all get in here? Really?
Whether you laying in the mud and they
bring you food when we don't even know,
wait an hour. We got in here
where it is in here. And uh,
and they're anywhere from,
they had some rescues that were
little bitty to 750 pound pigs.
All of them sold the same premise
that these are miniature pigs and a,
it'd be 150 pounds.
750 pounds science.
Your pigs. Yeah. Alex
Raimundo about three up.
You think I'm given,
he bought three up and turn them loose
in the wild and they turned into pig.
What are you going to do? Well, he
lived up in, uh, up in the whatever,
the high mountains. He's part of the
problem. Right? Part of the problem.
Not Problem. Okay, here
you go. So I'm walking,
it's all, it's all it's, it's well done.
And this guy seems really
reasonable. Right. And uh,
uh, and he's also an executive
for a construction company,
a big construction company. And
this is his passion. And then,
and then it was all right. This
is the part I can't tell. So
we, yeah. Oh fuck. Yeah. I say
this part of it, I understand.
And a pig, so, and I ended up
liking the pigs. You know, they're,
they're, they're nice. If you scratch him,
hey, they have arthritis of the big ones.
I can get around and, but
it's basically, it's a
WHO's going to save his pig
kind of an operation. And I'm like, well,
do you know the Carnita
Gat, the wood, you know,
probably pitch and you know, if
want wanting to retire, you know,
cause I asked the guy,
I said, what's the, um,
where do they go from
here? And it goes, so, um,
so he, there's someone adopts them or
they get turned to bacon. They, uh,
no, they, that's it. They, they
lived there until they die. Wow.
Is the way I understand weird
because they're almost, oh. Dot here.
I left this part out.
Oh.
So we're in the house talking
about the ship and uh,
and haven't had enough of it.
And I've got a joint in my pocket and I
really want to smoke some pot and hang
with the pigs because it seems like that
would be really fucking fine. You know,
just a scratch on the pigs.
All stolen new shit.
And that's how mature I am.
Uh,
and so there's, this big comes out
of the back squealing and they go,
that's Whitney Cummings pig.
Ah,
so she rescued a pig
during the Malibu fires.
She documented it very heavily on
her Instagram. Yeah. Show it to you.
Okay.
I've seen her pig, uh, know
I saw it in person person.
That's Whitney Cummings pigs.
So they're like a couple of nights
later I'm up at the store and Whitney
Cummings is there and I go,
oh, where do you see this?
She drove that fucking pigs all the way
across and be like two days of driving.
She's insane.
Trove a pig in a car for
two days to a pig sanctuary.
That is ridiculous.
It's Hilarious, dude. It's Whitney
Cummings pig. That's hilarious.
That's crazy. I want to hear more of
the story, but I got to Piss so bad.
I'm gonna pee my pants. Two podcasts
in a row. Talk to this guy. Hey,
I'll be right back. We can't just
cut the thing off for awhile.
We could just cut it off.
Totally. No, I don't, I don't,
I don't want to end it because it's
five 30. Yeah, yeah. We'll wait.
I got another to do. I got no where
to be so bad. Sorry. I saw it.
How was that you ran
until Tony last night?
You're telling me I had a good
time there. Yeah, yeah, yeah. Uh,
it was, uh, it was just a
gas. I had a friend, uh,
uh, I had dinner with
friends that night and, uh,
in Malibu and then came out and
did that side. And, uh, and it was,
it's just a great idea for a show,
the kill Tony Show,
if you have a chance to download a that
podcast. Uh, it's a, it's a hoot. It's,
it,
it's so much fun to do it.
So that a live audience down
to the comedy store and a,
it's a great premise and I won't
bore you with all the detailed,
but she can just tune in and
if you check the video, it
probably is up on Youtube. Oh yeah.
It's a big, it's not a, it's not Joe show,
but it's a big thing that does to the
band just shop as they look like how many
guys? Oh, they were, oh, it was so funny.
Jeremiah doing Foxworthy was,
uh,
was it really would Jeremiah
just makes me laugh so hard.
Everything he does just kills
me. And uh, he'll be, you know,
hopefully in my old age you'll be given
me mercy work because I'd tell him how
good he is.
He has his own podcast too.
I thought Jeremiah wonders where he does,
he does some voices and whatnot.
And so does he ever got it?
Cause it doesn't have guests. You should
probably just talk to him about it.
I don't know that.
I didn't know that you weren't on it.
I didn't want to say it that way,
but
you know, I haven't
been on it. Uh, the uh,
I always wonder why Bill Byrd didn't
have me on his show and the fact that he
didn't have anybody to share
by himself.
Some people,
a lot of Comedians crystally it
doesn't all by himself too. Oh really?
He said like one guest on, I think it
was just his brother for a special,
but he's done 130 or so all by himself.
It's a lot.
You could do one prior all by herself too.
You know what, I prefer
not to. I've got to,
I've got to save up thoughts for
eight months to do the Rogan show.
And
so I, so I'm loyal to the,
I'm loyal to this show.
Huh? Do you know what that is?
No. Mitzi shore. Oh, wow. Yeah.
Uh, our friend Taylor Taylor boss,
he painted that for me. Wow. How bad.
I says that,
that's an old
picture. Mitzi when she
or he is cute. Cute.
Very hot. She was, uh,
one of the most important figures
in the history of the comedy,
one of the most important figures in my
life for sure. That lady mentored me.
All of us.
I mean, all of us, because that's
the only reason the store exists.
The inmates run the asylum.
Right.
She's the only person that let the inmate
understood it in the mental hospital.
That's the actual original pressure over.
Great. Is that, ah, it's fucking amazing.
She's like Betty White.
You ever see those titty pictures of
Betty White when she was like 21 year
though?
Yeah.
He was so crazy and wild.
It's all right that she's got her nipples
in that picture. Right. She's, uh,
our friend rose, who's a tailor, his
girlfriend, uh, put a post on her. Uh,
when she died,
I couldn't repost it like for any other
woman I met might be able to repost it.
But she said like,
I forget what she called or something
about something she called her like the
greatest boss Bitch and history.
Like I can't,
I can't say that I like it, but
I can't repost that. You know,
it just didn't you just
say it? Yeah. But I mean,
I can't say I can't put it
on my Instagram, you know,
I'm just repeating what she said,
but it was just,
to me it was a hilarious and accurate.
A woman can say shit like that,
but, uh, uh, a lady like current doesn't
look pat. A man calls her a boss bitch.
Like, hey, how some respect. It's
fucking Mitzi shore. But yeah.
So Taylor painted for me and hangs
over the studio watches over us,
you know,
I genuinely don't think I ever met her.
No, no. Yeah, I had some
great conversations with her.
Yeah. When I came in that
first time, you know,
I was just standing out and I had no
idea what was going on. And, and then,
uh,
I really didn't come back to,
cause I did a show in new port beach.
It's a laugh stop out there and just
got this horrifically horrible review.
Did I tell this story last time?
It was so bad how bad
it was. Joe, there was a picture of me,
I'd only been saved with standup up
for my three and a half years and then,
and so then the guy that booked that room,
watch me do it like an eight minute
set in Austin and I had a killer eight
minutes, but he hires me
to do 45 minutes. And uh,
and so I go out there and I'm nervous
anyway, right? Because it's an,
that's a big club.
And,
and the two guys before me were
a Seinfeld and slate and so,
right. So, and then Ron wives,
three and a half year old
booger eating moron thing and,
and uh, so, and, and at this point,
I don't realize how bad I am because
they haven't read it yet. And, uh,
so before I'm nervous and they got to
go with it. That's Dunkin Strauss and,
uh,
and he writes a,
the comedy reviews for the Orange
County addition to the La Times,
which is about 6 million
people. And, uh, I like,
Oh,
well I wish you'd given me a day
or two to settle in. And so, so
I do this, that, and it's
not great and it's a,
but it's not bad. You know,
I think I pulled it off, you
know, they laughed at it,
you know, they laughed at what I had
put together and whatever it was,
and I expected him to be there to
congratulate me on how good the uh,
set was and shake my hand and do a
little interview to build this great
interview. So, but he wasn't there
and I'm like, oh, okay, well then,
then next night there's like an a little
open mic night before me. So there's a,
in one of the guys, I know Steve Apps
from a, uh, Texas is on that. And,
and then that night I fucking kill
and I'm really drunk and you know,
and I'm giving advice to other
Comedians, you know, how,
cause I made my ego's
just flare and I'm like,
I'm probably going to leave my wife and
go find that girl and lived to Cottey
beer posters and uh, they, you know,
it's amazing and the people are
patting me on the bag on here, man,
you are really, really
good. It is amazing.
So I was staying at the Marriott
suites hotel on the bay,
which is Nice Hotel I've ever stayed in.
And uh,
you had to pay for part of it yourself.
And, but that was all I had. I was making,
I didn't matter,
never made that much money before.
He was like 14 or $1,500
and uh, for a week. And,
and uh, so it's, it's a,
it's unbelievably beautiful with a
gorgeous view phone, bathroom, you know,
two bathroom, big marble,
everything, big nice stuff.
And, uh, I go back after that. Well, the,
now the review comes out the next
morning and I've got this massive hanger.
I'm just so sick draw,
waking up, going out,
he's a trust. And I says, I
blink my eyes and start going,
oh the review,
the glorious review was out there,
the review that's going to be touting
my praises to the masses all over the,
this area of southern California.
Probably the beginning
to my hugeness and uh,
probably is what's going to happen.
So it turned out I had bought a bag of
popcorn when I was drunk and I followed
that bag,
that popcorn trail from my bed out the
door, down the hall into the
elevator. The elevator I got on,
had popcorn on it. So it was the same
one I came up and I was just drunk,
staggering around with a popcorn bag.
And I followed that.
Now this place is just right down
the block from the, from the club.
And when I go to, when I'm playing at
a club, I hang out at the club a lot.
You know, cause that's, I just that
those are the people I know. Anyway,
those have been my friends forever and
they're still my friends, you know,
I love some of these are
the people that work here.
So I walk in the door and uh,
one of the girls that worked there and
looked at me and she goes, don't read it.
And I'm like, what? He goes, don't read
it wrong. It's not true. It isn't true.
And a hatchet job. And
I'm like, it's a plot,
a hatchet job. So I'm like, no,
give it to me. I, I can, I can read
it. Got, you know, how bad could it be?
So
there's a big picture of me,
this big 6 million people this big.
It was,
the article was this big,
it was a quarter of a page and
it said in big black print,
even when whites not blue,
he's not funny.
And I dropped the newspaper on the floor.
I couldn't hold up a one ounce
newspaper because the life is in Biz,
sucked out of me.
And I also agreed with them and felt
like I had just been found out as a phony
and I was a phony and I
didn't belong here at all.
And uh,
and I picked it up and read it and uh,
and it said watch and
whites 41 minute show.
So they were nice enough to point
out. I didn't know, I just had to,
I had to scrape it, crawl to get to
41 much less. The 45 I had agreed to,
they pointed that out with
was like watching a polar
bear lumber around on stage
and something comical or interesting
happening only occasionally.
Now here's why I'm,
I can quote that
all these 29 years later,
I went across the street to the liquor
store and bought a bottle of Tequila and
a packer razorblades true story.
I go back up to my Marriott.
So we told him the bay and a set,
they're this big desk and I'm
just drinking this Tequila,
reading it over and
over and over and over.
And I got a big bag of weed and I'm
smoking pot and I've convinced myself that
they're going to cancel the show
because who would come to a show,
right. With a review like that. And,
uh, and then I'm thinking, well,
they probably have to pay me for
the shows I did even, you know,
even though I wasn't able to
finish the week, right. So I just,
I just assume I'm fired a genuinely
believed that in my heart that I'm fired.
And,
uh,
so I wake up from the stupor and I got a
drool stain on this fucking article and
a half a joint and a it,
I mean,
it's dismal shit, right?
It's dark, dark time.
And I walked down there, fuck the
show sold out. Both of them are,
it's comedy in fucking
1990 [inaudible] 89 or 90,
whatever it was. And you know,
all the clubs were sold out.
Nobody gave a fuck about that
fucking review. And uh, they,
they give a shit. And I, then I went
on stage because I was still a Raco.
I'm drunk, I just woke up.
I'm not very good. Anyway,
I have no confidence whatsoever.
I totally agree that I suck and
I'm not worth a God damn thing.
And I go up there and have the worst set
I've ever had a sold out house and it
was just sucked. It just sucked.
It was a horrible and uh,
and then the guy that booked
me calls the club and
they go, he goes, yeah,
cause he read the fucking article and
he goes, that's kind of be a gut punch.
I mean it was a long, there was other shit
in it too. And then it was good. And uh,
so then that they get me on the
phone with him and then they get,
cause they asked them, they said
we just want to see if he's okay.
And they're like, oh no, he's not
okay. He's not okay at all. I'm like,
I'm really now I'm now,
I'm calling my wife going,
I just wanted to talk to you
cause I love you so much.
I'm thinking about the Ducati beer
poster anymore. I'm just calling her.
I just love you.
I want to be together forever.
And she's like kind of standoffish.
And I'm like, he's like,
she could tell I had a bad review.
So that,
uh, that kind of scared me
away from La for awhile.
And I realized then that they were riding,
I should've been slapped in the face
and I wasn't good enough to be on that
stage.
I was not.
And that guy actually apologize to me
one time cause I was showing him later in
lab and I'm like, no dude, you were
totally right. You are completely right.
I should have been slapped in
the fucking fat three years in.
You're just getting, you know,
he had no business there. And uh,
and so, you know, and it all
worked out the, you know,
the best way it possibly
could have and that,
but that also included a couple slaps in
the fucking face going, you're, you know,
you're not,
those are important. And I
really do. I think in the,
in the moment those feel bad,
but every big leap I've made as a comic,
cause after I bombed every big
leap for real, like the, you know,
someone telling me they had a bad time,
my show,
I just felt like you were off like,
fuck.
That feeling makes me so hungry
to figure out how to do it right.
That's where it, where it comes
from. It makes you, you know,
you realize there's an urgency to
this thing. And then over the years,
part of the fear of bombing is what
makes me work so hard on new shit.
Front of the fears would
makes me do so many sets.
I'll do two podcasts at night and then
I'll do four shows. I'll go to the store,
I'll do two at the show, a store,
I'll do one or two at the Improv.
I might even go to the ice house
or the, Haha, I'll fuck around.
These are all the reasons I'm not as good
as Joe Rogan right here. I get scared.
Ron White. I get scared. You know,
I do too. And I, you know, I, I,
well I can't, I can't tell you
it at 62. I do all those sets,
but I can do it. I do
it, go out and do sites,
a lot of sets and a lot of guys
that are kind of in my, you know,
in my age group really don't come out
and do sets that much and I come out and
do SAS and I hang out.
You're ageless.
I think of you, you know, you said
that one time, uh, in the back room.
You like come older than you guys. And
we were like, we don't give a fuck.
That doesn't mean anything. This,
this, this, this thing is about comedy.
It doesn't matter if you're a lesbian,
if you're trans,
if you're from Philadelphia
or the Philippines,
no one gives a fuck. Are
you funny? If you're funny,
that's all we care about. We
don't care if you're 90, 19.
I mean,
I'm fucking Kowski is,
what is she 22 or some shit? She might
be 22. She's one of my best friends.
I love that girl. She's
got damn hilarious. She's
kid. We talk all the time.
We talked about comedy. I have her, she
hosted my sets, the Improv all the time.
Nobody cares. Nobody cares about
your age. They care about comedy. He,
Dom Irrera is the same, same
way. You know, nobody thinks
of Donald Herrera is o.
Dot. Merera is older than us. No,
it's Dom Herrera is a God damn comic.
He's a monster.
This is a very,
very unusual group of humans. You really
think about the people that we know.
You know, if you looked at the
entire population of the planet,
there's 8 billion people or seven
and a half. Is that what it is?
Seven and a half something.
Some crazy shit.
How many of those are comics Zit?
Is it a thousand couple thousand? The
real ones, how many of them are headlines?
How many of them can do a solid hour?
How many of them were filmed a special?
How many of you have two, three
specials? Jesus Christ, Ron White.
You and I are and we
weird waters really of us.
Maybe 20 years, maybe
20 of us. Yeah, if that,
yeah. We don't give a fuck how old you
are, dude. You better stick around.
I'm fine dude.
I'm fine.
Hi. I'm drunk in the middle
of the afternoon when I got
work to do thanks to you.
I had a, a friend of
mine, uh, when I was, uh,
my daughter had that event in Vegas and
I went down to see you. They're like,
you're going to see a comic. I
go, don't go and see Ron White.
Of course I'm going to go watch
him. I go, I have the chance.
What am I doing with my wife and watch
fucking to catch a Predator or some shit.
I said, no, this is whatever.
They're different watching
television or something like that.
I'm gonna go downstairs, watch Ron
wine. I'm at the Mirage. You know,
I still love it. Still love
watching it. Still love it today.
And it's, you know, it's
really, uh, it's such a
hotbed. I get into it with the guys
at the seller in New York and uh,
cause they're all like,
this is the most significant comedy
club and the in America. And I'm like,
it's the most significant hundred seater.
Yeah. The idea that that place is more
significant than the store is hilarious.
That's so silly and it's still fun
and I love, but it's all get silly,
right? No. Yeah, that'd be ridiculous.
No second place by a fucking large margin.
Right.
Come on son. Dave Chappelle's up
at the fucking store all the time.
Chris rock comes by. Louis C K.
I'm sure he'll be back. All right.
It's a fucking crazy place,
but you're there.
Delete is there Bryan County there?
Joey d is there.
It's chilly out one night.
And they were,
I think it was eight people in the show
that make at least 50,000 every time
they opened their mouth and a seat or
in one fucking show for $14,000 come to
the fucking store crazy and watch a show.
You know it's not,
and if you come like on a a weekend,
it's not as quite as strong because
a lot of the guys are out again,
girls or got dope doing set
somewhere. But, but Tuesday,
Wednesday, Thursday, the
best time it's the, you know,
there's nothing like it because we all
have to do what we're doing and we're
lucky to be able to do it where we do it
do one night, the lineup
was Tom Segura, Bill Burr,
Bert Kreischer, Allie won me, Joey Diaz.
Crystally uh,
Tom Papa Ian had,
it was fucking crazy.
It's crazy all the time.
By the time you got to the end of the
line up, you're like the home alone kid.
Like, what the fuck? Look at
this lineup. This lineups insane.
It is. It is. And it's also what makes
it so fucking fun for me and watch,
you know, it, you know, I, I got,
I got to live in Beverly Hills and
I live two miles away and, and uh,
and it, and that's what gets
me off the couch to go, uh,
to go live my life and blow the horn
battery that plays a battery. We're
doing a lot of shows. The improv though,
I'm doing two this week. I did two
last week. I'm doing them all the time.
What I did. I talked to
them about, I'm like,
how about I just bring some of my friends
over because like we could all do shit
like,
like Santina we'll do a set at the Improv
and then we'll shoot over to the store
and do his set.
I'll do an eight o'clock show store
doesn't open till later on weeknights CZ.
So we've been doing a lot of shows down
there to the Improv is a great club man.
It just, the lineups were weird.
The way it was set up was weird.
There was a lot of weird shit going on,
but if you could just get the top
notch people and I was talking to them,
I'm like click, we're right over there
with fucking, we could walk here.
It's a mile away. But you
know, I mean it's a mile.
Nice. I love the Improv. But you know, if
you want to smoke a joint at the Improv,
you have to actually stand on Melrose
and traffic and smoke your weed and that
ain't cool.
And they're trying to change that.
I believe they're going to change that.
I believe they're looking at that.
Trying to make that they're building that
area on top where there's going to be
a little balcony out on the roof of
the part of it and, and it helped.
They do.
And if they do it will make a difference.
It will make a big difference. Yeah.
Will the hangs not that good there.
It's hard and when you wait and you
go on stage, you're essentially in.
That's why.
That's why Bud Freeman was going wrong.
Could you just stand over there?
Mitzi shore was literally like you guys
saw them out. Everybody sorted out.
Sorry it out. She didn't give a fuck
man. She understood. Keep everybody safe.
Let the lunatics running the
asylum. Yeah, and they did.
I'll never forget the day she
passed me ever in my life.
You're really finding all right,
you're going to pay regular now.
I was like Holy Shit. Now explain
to people what a paid regular is.
Cause I don't know. Well it's like you
made that you got the stamp of approval.
You might actually have a career. Like
I wasn't if I was going to have a career
in comedy. What's hilarious is
I was on a sitcom at the time.
I was out here and do a television
show for Fox. I had done,
I had been on showtime.
I already done,
I'd headlined a lot of clubs all over
the country, probably prematurely.
I'd really only been doing
standup for six years,
but uh, you know, I had maybe
a good 10, 15 minutes I could,
I could actually do a real
solid half hour if I had to,
but 15 minutes that I could
really kill with and uh,
did to be able to do a set in front of
her. And she goes, you're a paid regular.
I was like, I'm a fucking
comedian. I'm a holy
shit. You've, you've been given the
nod. I thought it was a fair trade man.
I thought it was a fraud. Even when I
was saying that, even when she said,
I was like, damn, I
tricked her. I tricked,
tells people in the audience I
tricked her. That's how I felt.
I felt like a tractor.
Fuck a trick to everybody.
But everybody treats
everybody in the beginning.
The beginning is the beginning of one guy.
But it's good that you didn't trick
them hard hits there important important
stuff.
Eating Shit on stage is critical.
If you can't accept the
fact that it's a process,
you can't want to everything
to happen right away.
And the only way for you to be really
sure that it's not happening yet is to
bomb, right? Yeah.
There's no other nothing,
nothing tells you so succinctly
that you're doing it wrong.
Like eating shit on stage.
Right. And you kind of learned a lot
from it. I mean, as you go, you know,
and that, you know, you don't really mess
around that much with comedies, venue.
You don't want to play a football
stadium or whatever. Right.
What's the biggest place you've
ever performed at a well,
blue collar comedy tour? We
held the uh, the record, uh,
where the predators play hockey
and a in Nashville and a 20,000.
That's a lot of sampling. And Elton
John held the record before we broke it.
And the reason we broke it as we were
in a center stage in the middle and
there's only four of us doing standup,
so it was,
nobody will ever have a smaller stage.
Wow. For that show there. Right.
How could they, and that was right
before we film blue collar. One two done.
Josh Wolfe showed me a picture when
you opened up for Larry, the cable guy,
you will opened up and
some football arena.
He's on stage and he takes it like a
selfie out. Looking at the audience.
It's the craziest thing you've ever
seen your life. See if he could find it.
Josh Wolfe, uh, opening up for
Larry, the cable guy. Selfie.
It's fun. I don't even know if he put it
online. He showed it to me on his phone.
It's fucking bananas. There's
50,000 people there, you know,
50,000.
Oh yeah. He was doing, he's doing crazy,
crazy, crazy numbers and number. Yep.
Like, and didn't even
talk about it. You know,
there was a lot of people that are hating
on him. He couldn't be a nicer guy.
He's also a great pace, rhythm
and timing. One land or guys,
you know it. And uh, as good as it
gets, I've seen him just crowds to
death. Funny Dude and uh, and gifted
and also has done it. You know,
he's totally paid his dues.
You know,
how many percent did I met him in 92.
I see you've done him longer.
Nine. Holy Shit. Look at
that fucking right. Yeah.
I haven't played this place.
Look at that fucking,
that's gotta be, that's gotta be
in Nebraska, right? So, right.
Everybody's be Lincoln, Nebraska.
That is one of the most insane
crowds I've ever seen in my life.
But it makes sense. He's got great
fucking timing, man. And I met him,
like I said, in 92 I think at the, um,
comedy works in Montreal when
Jimbo used to run the joint and a,
he was a great guy, man back
then. Even back then he was a,
I think he was a radio personality
in Florida at the time. You know,
he's just [inaudible] the cable guy was
a character he did in that and that he
would bring it into a show for one
joke and then it kind of just took over
fucking crazy. And people don't
know, like he's Dan Whitney.
It's like a regular person, regular
comics. He's trapped. Right?
He is Larry the cable traffic, the
place you'd like to be trapped. Right.
The place where you're
making $30 million a year.
But it's like this marvelous
Mrs Maizel thing. Except he's,
that's who he actually is.
I mean,
he doesn't have to wear a
fat suit or anything crazy,
but, well there's, you know,
his dad was a preacher and a
pig farmer from Nebraska. Wow.
And uh,
and so he does this a great auctioneer
voice where the lawyer has sold a little
Danny Whitney from across the street.
Wow.
A preacher in a pig farmer.
Holy Shit. Speaking of pigs,
the pigs just keep coming back.
Yeah.
The
thing is you can't save the pigs.
You got to kill some of them.
You know what the ultimate conundrum
because like it would be nice if we could
have like some sort of a
harmony with nature with pigs,
but that's not possible.
If they're wild,
they're fucking up a storm to have in two,
three litters a year with six to eight
little piglets and they're just running
rampant and there they come. Viable.
I think, correct me if I'm wrong,
I think female pigs become viable and
you get pregnant after four months.
You're exactly right. That's why
they make these little bitty pig.
And they have these little bitty pigs too.
And they're the cutest things I've ever
seen in my life. Oh, they're adorable.
And I said, can I pick one up? And they're
like, they squeal like a pig, you know?
And literally I picked one up
and they like, they made a noise,
like I was stabbing a screwdriver into
their ear. And I'm like, oh, okay.
All right. Well they're
smart. They get scared.
They're smart. It's so it's a crazy
thing because like you want to love them,
but then if they're taking
over your neighborhood,
you want to fucking shoot him and kill
him and they're delicious and they're
delicious. That's their problem.
Right? That's the whole problem.
They're delicious.
You know how they got into California?
No. William Randolph Hearst. Oh yeah.
That crazy asshole.
He's to bring him and he would populate
his forest outside of his home with wild
pigs have been wild boars.
Boys go out and fucking shoot them like
so if you go to like tach a pea or any
of these areas that have wild pigs,
so you'd go to certain areas like
towards the middle of near Bakersfield.
There's wild pigs out there. That's
all. William Randolph Hearst. Wild pigs.
Thanks bill. Yeah, that crazy ass
hall. He let pigs loose in California.
They were everywhere.
Big Sur like hunter s Thompson used to
hunt wild boar in big Sur with a fucking
machine gun.
Those were William Randolph Hearst wild
pigs that had populated all the way up
the coast all the way up to San Jose.
There was a fucking news story from
San Jose where they were knocking over
people's trash cans and he's like a huge
tech community's a hundred pound pigs
knowing people most enter me wild ones
aren't that big. The wild ones too,
like a big wild once,
like 300 pounds, the big,
really big honor one daughter,
Madison, Georgia. They're there.
You know what happens there though?
They're domesticated and then people let
them go. See, don't want to look at this.
I bought the computer. Don't fuck up
my fucking story. Truth. No, no, no.
I know about this.
One thing I do know about is feral pigs.
I've studied them pretty,
pretty closely. Why?
Because I'm friends with a lot of people
that are professional hunters and uh,
I wanted to know how the fuck they
got so big. Like there's a video of a,
there's a photo rather one they called
Hogzilla. That was from Georgia.
It's a fucking enormous pig.
But it looks,
look at that motherfucker.
King Kong hog from Russia makes
Hogzilla looked like a baby. See,
I'm not buying that.
What does that guy look at the guy's head?
See that guy's head. That guy's a
mile away. Where the fuck is that guy?
That guy could be on top of that thing
and that look looks like a German chap.
How much this away? We have no idea.
This is a photograph. Oh, hold on.
Let me see that Tusk. CN. Let me
see the tusks. Eh, it's a big pig,
but it doesn't have to be that big
that that could be a 300 400 pound big.
It doesn't even say, did they
weigh it? 1,175 pounds to bigger.
Whoa.
These guys with the scales,
what website is this? We've got scales.
Website is, it's wide open spaces.
Hmm. That's a pretty reputable
that not all shoulder.
Yeah. Five and a half feet
at the shoulder. Christ.
Honestly, picture he brought 200 of
these. Not specifically that one,
but it was a Russian boar he brought
in from Russia and they've ended up
breeding with local feral pigs
and they got big. Yeah. Well,
here's the thing about bores
and pigs and all that jazz.
It all comes from the same genus. It's
all from something called sue [inaudible].
Sue scruff is all pigs.
What's crazy about that is like when
you see a domestic pig and they look all
cute and cuddly and pink and chant.
When they get loose and they
go wandering through the woods,
they turned and their
face changes. Their face gets longer.
The Grote tusks, their hair gets thicker.
This one,
it says the shoulder height.
Is that how high the shoulders are off
the ground? Right at five and a half feet.
Trice that's so big. That's all. I'm
three inches shorter or taller than that.
The five and a half feet. That's
insane. That's this tall on me.
So me standing out. Okay, I'm five, eight.
Look at this. Watch this. Here's the pigs.
Here's the pig shoulder, right?
Right. That's all honoree.
Where's three inches? Like right
here? That's fucking insane.
That's a pig that high. That's
insane. That's an elk. Hogs,
hogs. Hogzilla was a shoulder height
of three feet, so that's almost double
five and a half feet tall.
That's so big.
But if it was a thousand pounds,
that makes sense. Cause, uh,
a good elk is like 800 pounds.
A longhorn steers are so far behind it.
[inaudible]
hunter's trick, right? So Hunter's trait,
that's what's drawn. It's back here.
I don't see his hands. You see his hands?
I don't see you say, trust me, look at it.
Listen that guys in the next [inaudible]
next area code. That guy's hiding.
He's way behind that thing.
You're supposed to be right next to it.
If that is a deceptive photo.
When you take a photo like that,
that is you doing that on purpose,
what you're supposed to do,
he's supposed to put your
gun or your rifle or you're,
or you're a bow and arrow.
You lead on the animal.
You stand next to it so that people that
know how difficult it is and people say,
Oh, you're trophy a hundred
now you trying to kill a smart,
mature animal because that's the one
that's healthiest for the population.
That's the one you want to
take out of the breeding cycle.
This is one that's already spread.
It's jeans and hunter's respect when
someone shoots a mature older animal.
That's a for sure. It looks
good, right? I'm hungry.
Those are not that good to eat unless you
really know what the fuck you're doing.
Like you gotta be to slow
cook that motherfucker.
That one you want to do low.
You want to probably Brian,
that bitch,
get them in a big old Vada saltwater
with brown sugar and garlic and let them
soak for awhile. This article is sort
of saying it could be bullshit bullshit.
I'm telling you, that guy's too far
away. You've got to listen to me.
For us to see a guy that's that far away.
What are you saying to her Russians,
Bro. It's that guys near the
bumper. That's a hockey car.
Look where his shoulders are.
They line up almost with the bumper
that you guys know Alex tiny.
He's way behind that pig in
relation to the size of the car.
Exactly. It was like a third grader.
Exactly. It doesn't make sense.
This guy is hiding.
He's hiding behind that pig.
If you wanted people to
know the actual perspective,
you'd say that if he had a rifle leaning
up against that pig and the rifle look
tiny, you'd be like, Holy
Shit, that's a giant pig. Yeah,
but there's nothing in that photo
that represents an actual perspective.
You'd have to be standing right, like
he's hiding. He's he. He was so old.
We can't and see bitch. You could see
that in a five and a half foot tall pig.
Well that pig six one laying down in
this picture. Yeah, in the picture.
These are some, his niece is the
only evidence they have dead one.
That means that the wearable,
if we have in the lobby,
could be real to the world was a thousand
pounds. It's even bigger than this pig.
Yeah, that's stupid. That's what people
do, man. People take pictures of animals.
They hide in the hunting world
is called the grip and grin.
Take a photo like a hold a deer
and you'll look, push them way out.
People do that with fish too.
Like you caught a big bass
and you take that big bass.
You put it way in front of
you, it looks gigantic, right?
If you take that big basket like,
Hey, look at my big bass, right?
That's a confident person.
Confident person got that basket
behind them or that motherfucker.
Do you know how big it is? Wrong,
bigger, wrong. Keep guessing.
Doesn't matter if this guy's a liar.
The guy in withholding it out in
front of him, he's showboating.
I'm not buying it. That
fucking pigs. 300 pounds.
That's a baby pig or against
it. Whitney Cummings, pigs,
brothers and sisters got loose.
They shot it.
So I saw her right after that.
I thought I told you, it's like,
you're not going to believe this shit,
Whitney. I have pictures of your pig.
You know, show it to her on the phone
and she just flipped the fuck out.
Ah, yeah, she's a, that
lady loves animals for real.
She's who?
God bless her fiance.
He's in for a a long
run of animal husbandry.
My friend's wife,
she sees
an animal this dead and
it's a winter subarea.
She'll put it in her freezer.
Oh God.
Wafer-Thin and Berea and wait for
the ground to thaw and then dig all
embarrassed. Jesus. That's
deep. Whitney wouldn't do that.
Sticks to the next level. This lady. Yeah,
that's taken it to the next level. You've
got to accept this is a cycle of life.
You don't have to like just leave it
outside for something to eat. Yeah.
That's what you're supposed to do. What I
do. Well, it's, there's a reason for that.
Those animals, they need to stay alive
to the animals that eat dead animals.
They need to stay alive too. Right?
This is the whole cycle. Well,
not just vultures. Rats, you
know, there's a lot of, uh,
and a lot of lower Chavez's cabin.
Interesting is this show
gets Drucker and Drucker.
I grow Meyer Lemons at my place and so
I look at the lemons and something is
eating the rind off the lemon and
left the lemon hanging on the tree.
PERF in perfect condition. And
A, I'm like, well that's odd.
And then I see a one little group of
perfectly peeled lemons on the ground and
then there's two more
lemon pods on the tree.
Perfectly Lemons. No rat. And I'm like,
what the fuck is this? This is yesterday.
This is how this aspect yesterday,
this hidden memories from the
past, which I have almost none. No,
but yesterday and uh,
so we looked it up and
it's called a roof rat.
And they love it.
They love specifically Meyer Lemons,
which is what these were.
And they love the, the ride,
but they don't like the sourness
of the, uh, of the fruit.
So they just eat the,
uh,
they just eat the rind and leave the
fruit hanging on the tree. And it's,
it was just baffling
really when I first saw it,
but that they do the exact opposite with
oranges. And we also have blood oranges.
And so they'll put a little hole in a,
meet all the fruit out of and leave the
husk hanging on the tree was not on the
inside. I'm like, Jesus
Christ fucking dicks.
So now when I eat an orange or
a lamb or whatever, I'm like,
throw the rides out there,
saved the fucking fruit. You
know, I really don't lie.
I don't like to kill anything. I
have a peach tree. I may be eight,
three peaches the whole time I've
been living in this fucking house.
I been living in that house. It's 2003.
These God damn squirrels eat my peaches.
Right? They eat every fucking peach
I've ever grown. Look at that.
Look at these rats. Look at,
well that's what's left there.
They dug a hole in that shit.
I literally never get
to eat peaches all day.
All have all these things
going on in my house right now.
They're called roof rat.
I got serious coyote problems.
I have no more chickens kind of out
of all my chickens in one fell swoop.
You ready for this?
They killed the last nine chickens.
I had to transfer to them them because
my chicken coop burnt to the ground.
So we had to get a smaller coop. And
you're blaming that on the Chi? No,
we, the chickens escaped and we saved the
chickens and we got them to this other
coop, um, after the fire. And uh,
it wasn't as reinforced as the
original coupe, the original coupe.
I had hired a guy who's a
carpenter to build me a nice coupe.
He did a great job and the coyotes were
on the roof one night chew and at it.
And I had a fucking,
I had a death perch set up on my porch.
I had my whole weight out there. I
had arrows, range finder. I even had,
I even laid bait out in my yard waiting
for these [inaudible]. I was ready,
I was going to Rambo,
but I lost my patients and I'm a busy man.
I got a lot that's due. So I
abandoned the project. Fire,
burnt my fucking chicken
coop down to the ground.
We put these chickens and another coop
and these coyotes tour that coop apart
and they did it when we weren't home.
And uh, we came home is just feathers.
There were all gone. All nine of them
there, you know, part of me admires them,
you know,
part of me is like these little wolves
are surviving in the suburbs is trying to
figure this shit out.
Man.
They will break into this thing or die.
My wife was getting uncomfortable because
you're basically making your house at
target. You know they're on the
roof right next to the house.
These little small predators
or chewing the roof of that,
the chicken coop before the
fire happened and it was like a,
that was the one I decided to go to war.
I didn't fully committed to
war cause I didn't get a,
I was going to get a sub sonic 22.
That's the way to go. Cause it,
you were here a subsonic 22,
it sounds like says pack.
It doesn't sound like
anything but it's lethal.
I had a coyote but I don't think
it's legal inside city limits.
Like I don't even think
I should be saying that.
I wanted to share it with them
with a rifle. It's probably like,
like a criminal intent idea.
But I never really considered it
and I definitely never bought one.
But I was ready to fuck one up with a
bow and arrow. But uh, now it's over.
They got, they won, they figured it out,
the fire opened up the door and they um,
after the fire was they were real sketchy,
real loud and cause they were trying
to figure out what the fuck is going on
because like all the,
the brush was gone so probably the rabbits
were missing and the rats or mice of
course there were, yeah, we're
going to say Jamie. Yeah, it was a,
it's weird. It came, you know, came home
and see just feathers everywhere man.
Just feathers.
Like just like someone just sliced a
few pillows and just shook them all over
the yard. Like fuck, you know,
we should look back and try to figure
out what we should have closed with.
That's a good way to close cause with
murder chickens, we've got a show tonight.
Ron White will be with me. All shows
are sold out. I'll go in. Well show us.
Show sold out this weekend.
I met Austin Cap City comedy club that
sold the fuck out too with George Perez,
who's Goddamn hilarious.
And Andrew CNT no there Friday
and Saturday. [inaudible] town.
Dammit. My place is under construction.
Emory doing my house. Why?
Intercontinental Man of mystery.
He travels all over the globe homes
and many mysterious locations.
Don't you have a place in Atlanta too?
Uh, so that and bought the place and uh,
and awesome. I like it.
I like to move though.
I like where you like to go to
my favorite spots in Austin too.
You can easily, whenever the five
response I could live in either or.
I need to get connected to the music
vibe in Austin and figure out real quick
who you really love to see and sure, sure.
But I don't like it. I like Atlanta too,
and I love both of them. All right.
Ron White, you're a bad motherfucker.
It's an honor to call your trafficker.
I appreciate you dearly.
As you're back at your Holla. That's
it. Fuckers. We'll see you soon. Uh,
more show tomorrow night.
Hmm. Yeah, yeah.