There we go. Oh, and we're live.
Hello. Okay. And that was that.
That's looking that easy. That easy. Yeah.
We didn't say very much
interesting before it started. No,
we were starting and then you just said
shut the fuck said, hold that thought.
Plus this, uh, this concept
of things getting better.
And we were talking about war more being
too cause as a world war II helmet that
um, Shane against the machine
is the gentleman's name.
He's made me another sculpture and he
started making sculptures out of a,
these world war two helmets with a lamp
underneath it and an actual real world
war II ban out as well.
And you were saying was a terrible idea
that it's going away, you think? Really?
Yeah. Real really fast. And you,
you mentioned Pinker and that's everything
I will say is redundant to Pinker.
I mean that I'm a better
angels of our nature is one of,
I think the most subversive books
of our time. You know, people are,
there's such a, um,
it's a fetish to suffer.
It's a fetish to say how bad things
are. People getting really off on it.
And when you start saying, you know,
after you say one death by violence
is too many and we got to clean up the
environment and duh duh duh duh, duh,
say all that stuff and it's all true.
But you can also take a breath and
say things are getting better. Yeah,
I think we need to recognize
that. And the problem is there is,
there is violence, there
is horrible things,
there are horrible things in the world.
They still exist and now they're magnified
because of the fact that we have this
ability to look at it on your phone
anytime you want to look at it on your
computer. When you say one
thing, it's the same thing.
I think calories in information
are identical, you know,
for millions, billion years.
Um, the biggest problem,
every living thing had was too
few calories. And then for a,
what may be 75 years,
a very small percentage of the animals
in the world had this problem of too many
calories and there's nothing
that prepares anybody for that.
We now have more information in
one issue of the New York times.
Then I'm a 17th century peasant
would had in their entire life.
So we have this glut of information that
we're dealing with about as well as we
dealt with calories. I talked
about this quite often,
but the way I describe it as diet and
that most people have a poor diet and then
most people's diet is not nutritious.
And if you have a poor diet that's not
nutritious, your body becomes unhealthy.
Well, if you have a poor mental diet,
and I've discovered how many people do
we talk about this with like three or
four people we've been talking about
this, like taking in information.
You should almost think of it as a
mental diet because if you've taken bad
information all the time and negative
information, I will speak for myself,
but I don't think I'm in any way alone.
I often forget where I read stuff,
so I have to be really careful to not
read too much garbage or it just pops up
in my head is, Oh, that's
real. Right. You know?
So I try to go with the new sources
that are, I think are pretty reliable.
Even if I disagree with them.
Like I try to read the times cause I
know there's a level to how much they're
going to lie. We know, we know where
the parameters are. They're lying there,
you know,
we know where they do the spin and if
you just just pop around the web at
random, you can't tell what kind
of information you're getting.
But I also want to add
to this, you know, it's,
it's exactly the way I
feel about drugs, you know,
as much as I want to say,
this is not right for me.
Information has to be out there and all
information. Absolutely no gatekeepers,
you know. No, I, I completely agree.
And I think that we're coming very close
to a time where technology allows us to
understand what's true and what's
not true. We're not there yet,
but I think we're,
we're really close to being able to have
some sort of an ability to read minds
to, to decipher information
like really clearly.
But the problem with reading minds, um,
if we could do it to ascertain truth
is a truth is very different from what
someone believes. You know, if
you had a perfect lie detector,
it would not help you with
criminality at all. Cause you know,
people that think they're innocent may
very well think they're innocent even if
they are not. Oh sure, sure. Yeah,
that's a really good point. And you know,
another really good point, his memory
is very fallible. Oh yeah. C I a,
you know, I got a lot of,
I've got a lot of shit for this and
I talked about it a little bit on,
on my podcast, but um, you know, I
was in the room with Trump a lot.
You know I did two tours.
I did two tours of duty.
Tell me about that. What does that like?
Cause I was supposed to do that show
and I passed on it. Yeah. I was like,
I don't want to live in New York for
three months or whatever. It was.
Just seemed like it's
wise. Either way. It was a,
it was a primetime television show.
So it's sold tickets and that is our
job. Right. And that's what we do.
And I went on with one idea in
my head, you know, Annie Duke,
you know the poker player she had been
on the year before. And I said, um,
why am I going on? I mean, I know I'm
normally going to sell tickets and that's,
that's just a done deal, but where
am I going on? What's my real goal?
And she said, go on and show
that atheist can be kind.
That'll be your only goal
for the whole show. Oh,
because they're going to jump
on you for being an atheist.
They'll jump all over you for that and
just show that you're the one that gets
mad the least.
So the one that you're the nicest guy on
there and you're the hardcore atheist.
And I went, okay, that's a good goal.
But then you sit in the room and
I don't know how well, you know,
the president of United States, I don't
want to know him at all. Yeah. Um,
but you spend, um, uh,
bout two or three hours every other day
sitting in a room across the table like
this with a table. You
can't put your hands on,
why can't you put your hands on
it? Because it might Mar it in.
That's hilarious. Put a hand print on it.
They literally tell you don't put your
hands on the table and you have to sit up
straight. And the camera, if you're
like the team captain, which by the way,
they hate it if you
call them team captain,
they like to have it, you know, sub
sort of business jargon and you're in a,
you're in a set. And that's the thing
that everybody else on the show would say.
We're going into the board
room now. And I'd say, no,
we're going onto the board room set.
So it wasn't a real board room? No,
of course not. None of it was really
a sound stage. Ah, it was, you know,
it was in the Trump towers,
but they'd taken over Florida,
NBC guts it and puts up this shit.
And then you've got your camera
that your hero camera that's um,
over your shoulder that shooting Trump.
So you can't lean into the camera.
Right.
And they want a little piece of you so
you can't lean out of the camera so that
you've gotten about two hours where you
sit up straight and you can't move side
to side and you can't put your hands
on the table and you listen to someone
speak for two hours that they're good at.
Try to edit out to get three
minutes where he sounds okay.
Okay. What does he have to say for two
hours? He will talk. He would talk,
I mean, things obviously have
changed, but he would talk about, uh,
I was reading this blog on the internet
that said I didn't sell my property for
enough and I bought it for $3
million and I sold it for 4 million.
Isn't that a profit? Isn't that
a profit? What do you think?
Isn't that a profit? Yeah, that
would be $1 million profit. Well,
they said I sold it for two
less than two little, okay.
Who was this? There was somebody on
the internet. Okay. So, you know,
he'd be arguing in front of us with
perhaps a 18 year old guy on the internet
who thought that Donald Trump should've
made more from a real estate deal.
And this is something he really
concentrates on. He seems to,
I'm still to this day, yeah. Obsessed
with what anybody says about him. Anytime.
It's so odd. And I thought, and I
want to say this very clearly, um,
I thought he was wonderful
at his job. You know,
if you had someone who was actually
a business person, I'm on that show,
it would be the worst show in the world
because bill Gates would make proper
decisions. Right? And
there'd be no surprises.
You want someone capricious and crazy,
but no filter. That's what you want.
Right? And that's what we got. So he
makes arbitrary decisions that you try,
you know, the human brain tries
desperately to make those make sense.
And that ends up being some kind of
entertainment. And, um, so I actually,
uh, actually a Donald Trump jr said to me,
and of all the people
we've had on this show,
you seem like the only person
who's ever liked my father.
He said, you actually seem to
like them. And I said, you know,
I have a fascination and
to respect and a, um,
affection for people who are
able to get out of their filters.
And I said, some people do that
with pure genius, like Bob Dylan.
Some people do it with
bravery, like Lenny Bruce.
Some people do it with drugs.
You know, Neil young, perhaps,
uh, Jimmy Hendrix perhaps, and most
people do it with a mixture of stuff.
But I said, um,
Thelonious monk said the genius is
the one who is most like himself.
And I said with some sort of, um,
mental problems coupled with, um,
greed and a lack of compassion.
Your father has somehow found
a way to throw off the filters.
And I will listen to tiny Tim talk on
tape for hours because I liked that little
bit of Asperger's and all
that other stuff. But, um, I,
I'm not assuming I'm not qualified
to do, but I'm saying this is auntie,
I can hear him talk forever.
I can listen to Lenny Bruce.
You know how we will never has those
hundreds hours of him just ranting on his
tape. I think. I don't like people
on drugs that much, but boy I do.
And I listened to a Lenny
Bruce talk forever and uh,
Donald Trump had the dark
side of that. You know,
it was almost like when I was hitchhiking
around the country and you know,
homeless and shit and you'd end
up at a biker place and you know,
some clubhouse and some guys
just holding court ranting.
I've always been interested in the people
who were out on the margins, you know,
and what,
what Donald jr um,
took as affection I guess
was a bit of affection.
But it's also that if you have thrown off
some filters, I'll listen to you talk.
And um, so that was that. It was
very, very strange. And then, um,
I really did spend a lot of time kind
of sticking up for Donald Trump saying,
yeah, there's interesting
stuff there. And yeah, he's,
he's crazy and he's venal
and, um, he's empty. Uh,
you know, really weird stuff
that you've never seen before.
You have never seen someone who is
never laughed sincerely and never made a
joke. Never laughed sincerely. No, he
will, he will laugh in a bully way.
He look kinda fat Joe. Yeah, he'll do
that. But he won't laugh at himself.
Oh no. And also, but never a even a joke.
Even it says phrase on Twitter.
Did you see the thing he did on Twitter
the other day where you put a picture of
Trump tower in Greenland and he said,
I promised not to do this. Yeah. Yeah.
I mean, I laughed. That was funny.
Giant Trump tower in the middle of
Greenland. I never saw it. I mean,
I saw that, but we never saw him in
person. I never saw him in person.
I also never saw him showing the
enjoyment or understanding of music.
And those two things are two things
that I connect with people very much on.
I do too. But one of my best friends,
Doug Stanhope does not like music.
Oh yeah. Yeah. I know that
guys fucking hate music.
And tell his father, really tell her
his father didn't like music. I mean,
I don't know mean and
aggressively did like abuse. Yeah.
I don't know what that is, but
I do know that I don't, I don't believe
that we see things the same way.
Like I don't think we
taste things the same way,
which is why some people enjoy certain
kinds of foods and some people hate those
exact same foods that some people, the
music sounds different, if you will,
in terms of like what,
what their emotional and psychological
makeup is and what it does to them.
Some people don't want to have
none of it and that's staying up.
When I lost all that weight, you lost
over a hundred pounds. Congratulations.
And I read a lot and also more
importantly for years and kept it up. But,
um, uh, when I was reading about taste,
I read this book and I know it's awful
that I can't bring up the name, but, um,
woman wrote this wonderful book about, uh,
preferences in food and she was
trying to set up a dichotomy.
Let's talk to those people who think
there's a natural taste and desire in food
and those that think it's all environment
and what you in memory and so on,
and you just can't find
scientists on the other side.
All of our food preferences are
habit and there's nothing else habit.
It's just habit. Is that
proven? How can they prove?
Seems to be a lots of studies,
uh, with young children, um,
lots of studies with people who they
control their body. But how do you make,
how does it make sense when you have
two kids that have radically different
tastes that grew up in the same
household and they have essentially very,
very similar food experiences? Yeah. Well,
I don't know how they tease out that,
but they, I have one daughter,
one daughter who loves
spicy food and she's young.
She's nine and I love spicy
food. Yeah. And, I mean,
this fucking kid can eat jalapenos cause
he eats habanero sauce. She'll like,
I'll say this one might be a little too
hot for you. She's like, let me try it.
And she'll like dip her finger
in and she's like, put it on.
She'll eat chicken with habanero
sauce and she's a little Savage.
My other one doesn't want to have
nothing to do with it. She did.
She thinks everything's too hot. Like
a little bit of pepper. She's like, Oh,
it's too hot. But you know, I,
I found when my, uh, when I,
when I changed my diet so radically that
my comfort foods changed and my habits
changed and what I liked Chino, a lot
of that is because of gut bacteria. Oh,
I know that. I know. Yeah. Micro-biome.
Fascinating. Really fascinating stuff.
And seeding back to your brain, you
know, uh, that was the thing that was so,
so strange because seeing your emotions.
Yes, very much so. But when I, uh,
I became plant based vegan, um,
for health reasons and I wrote in my book,
I wrote a lot of stuff about
I am an unethical vegan.
I'm not doing this or any sort
of animal, any sort of animal,
lack of animal cruelty,
nothing. Strictly health.
That's why I'm doing the
plants and the story.
And this has happened to a lot of
friends of mine who changed that after
whatever it takes. And people
are guessing like three months,
four months of 'em have
no animal products. Uh,
those little critters eating shit and
you're in your guts dye that liked the
meat stuff and they're not
giving that feedback loop.
And I just found a real emotional
change where all of a sudden I went,
I don't want to be part of that.
I'm of the suffering. Yeah.
It was really strange how that
changed and it really felt to me, uh,
I was so want to, uh, I, you know,
hardcore atheist as you know, and um,
I don't believe in a mind
body separation at all.
And yet I seem to believe
that when I was 350 pounds,
that, um, none of that
affected my emotion.
And then I lost all this weight and found
there were so many changes in me that
seem to be intellectual and emotional.
And actually I had a lot
of evidence where physical,
well put me up on the mind, body
separation should fuck you up
because a lot of people make these
assumptions that you know you are not your
body and a lot of very intelligent people,
they issue working out and they don't
want to exercise and they find it like
it's a vanity thing. It seems
egotistical. They don't,
they don't like it.
And so they put it in this category of
kind of knucklehead dumb things to do.
But your body and your mind are
all in the same house. Yeah.
If your house is filled
with shit, it doesn't help.
And it was so amazing how,
I mean I completely believe that
and yet I wasn't living there.
I was like thinking that I
was living this, you know,
2000 year old idea of little homonculus
who's kind of living inside me,
who's this pure pen and
then the body is just,
the vehicle is driving around
it. That's just not true.
BW with that. I think knowing
you as long as I've known you,
you're an intense thinker and you,
your mind is something you mean,
you cherish your thoughts and
you, you embrace them and your,
you're a very intelligent guy and I
think you just probably rejected the idea
that there was anything outside of
the mind that had any influence.
Yeah. We also talked about
this. I was also, you know,
I was the biggest guy to ever go
through my school. So, uh, my,
my small high school in
Western Massachusetts, you
know, so I was, I was six,
seven and they wanted me as
center of the basketball team.
They wanted all this stuff and those
kinds of people and that kind of culture,
you know, I wanted to listen to music,
I wanted to read and I set up
this, you guys who are physical,
I don't like you, I'm on a
different team. Yeah. You know,
and my dislike of competitions and
teams became a team thing. Yes.
Yeah. That's the thing. You
always get stuck in the, the,
the dislike of teams becomes your team.
And I'm trying so hard now
to think I have two choices,
one or 7 billion, and there's
no teams between that.
I can either be myself or I
can be one of all humanity,
or I won't even say 7 billion,
let's say 108 billion.
The number of people who have
lived in history, you know,
those are the people I can be.
It's why I'm trying to not,
and this is impossible to do by the way.
I'm talking about how I'm explaining to
you how I'm driving myself crazy, right?
I'm not going to get real information. Um,
I'm trying to not think
ever of us in them,
but I'm trying to say those
of us who voted for Trump,
those of us who believe this.
So it's always us because man,
I'm so fucking sick of teams and
I even look back and go, you know,
I love the velvet underground.
I hated the fucking Eagles.
And that was a fucking team. And that
was bidding [inaudible] at forced upon,
you know what I mean? I wanted to be the
kind of guy that went from, you know,
Zappa, the velvet
underground to Bob Dylan.
That was all okay. And the
Eagles and the Doobie brothers,
they were not what I listened to.
I'm just trying to let that go. Yeah.
You want it to be one of the
cool kids. Yeah, exactly. Yeah.
And whenever you want that, you've
got to say, well, you don't,
one of the cool kids that's the hundred
8 billion who've lived on this planet.
Yeah. That's a great way to
look at things. And I think,
I wish people taught that in school.
The dangers of being involved in teams
because we get involved in teams in terms
of like, you know, you're playing
basketball or whatever, but,
but teams in terms of like the what
I believe versus what you believe.
And I think we're experiencing that
politically right now with the most
polarizing time and in my
lifetime that I've ever,
ever met worldwide. Yes.
Worldwide. I mean, it's, it is not,
it is not an American
thing. Right. And, uh,
it's just insane. And I also know,
that's why I said, you know, I,
I try to go with the velvet underground
and the Eagles because that's where I
can really see where I'm
wrong. You know that I'm wrong.
How do you deny victim of love?
That's a great song, man. Okay.
Once jokes in the mix, the
Eagle's changed. You know,
people have to recognize,
I was in the middle of the
China's see with Joel Walsh, ah,
through a series of odd coincidences.
Why don't I add, well, just a,
just last year we got this gig, uh,
Paul Allen, who is one of the sure.
Microsoft guys. Sure, sure. Great guy.
Right. And he had great things about him.
Books us to be on a cruise, uh,
to do a show for his friends.
He had like 200 friends and he's
bought this fucking cruise ship.
He's rented this fucking cruise ship
thrown off all the chefs and everything.
Bring on his own people and
they're going to go from,
I'm from Kobe to Shanghai and he wants
the entertainment to be Jay Leno,
Penn and teller and
Ringo Starr. Whoa, okay.
That's what it's going
to be on the China sea,
on a cruise boat for like
200 people. And he books it.
And as I said to my friend,
Piff the magic dragon, I said,
do you know how much it costs to shutdown
Penn and teller in Vegas and fly us
all to fucking
Japan to beat on a cruise ship to do a
fucking Penn and teller show and then
come back. Do you have any idea how
much that costs? And Piff said no.
And I said, me, me either.
But it must be a lot.
You gotta talk to my managers or something
cause that must've been a shit ton of
money. So he books this whole thing
and then Paul Allen dies, right?
Dies. So you know Glenn,
who you met out there,
the long suffering Glen who our manager,
he calls up and after few days and says,
really sorry for your loss and we'll
trade in the tickets and get you the money
back and we can probably rebook those
those weeks or it's not going to cost
anything. It's so sorry but them, no,
no, we're still doing it. And then goes,
well, you're w w w the person
that booked us, his dad,
we're still doing this gig. And
they go, Hey, yeah, we went, okay.
And I said to Glen, do you know now
that we could work for dead people,
our careers going to take off, you know,
cause that opens up the market. Right,
right. Um, so turns out
that his friends, you know,
Paul Allen's friends are people like Joel
Walsh and Billy Gibbons and all these
food scientists and
all these great people.
So there I am in the middle
of the China's sea with, um,
with a Joe Walsh onstage,
just in three in the morning playing
piano for like 15 people and you know,
singing Desperado and those kinds of
things and talking to Joe Walsh and stuff
and going, now, why exactly was I
on a different team from Joe Walsh?
Why exactly was I on the Lou Reed
team instead of the Joe Walsh team?
They knows the big Lebowski influenced
you. Maybe, maybe, maybe it was there,
but it's, it's just, um,
it's just trying to be more and more
inclusive is just a really difficult thing
to do. Whether it's the, and the
music guys are all that stuff,
just everybody be everybody.
You can become a prisoner
of those thoughts and those,
those things as you espouse. Like
when you start saying fuck the Eagles,
like you're stuck, you're
stuck with fuck the Eagles.
And then when you start
to realize that, you know,
when the clash was hitting in the U S
there were people sitting around a board
room going, how do we get 20 year
old assholes to buy this shit? Right?
It was all being done and
laid out and that's fine.
That's their job and that's
great and God bless him,
but I got to be aware that
they're doing that. Yeah, I know.
When you think about someone's selling
sex pistols merchandise, just like,
well there's sex pistol slump, sorry,
there's sex pistol slot machine.
When I was first in the hard rock,
you know, and there's a big side,
the only notes that really count
are the ones that come in wads,
and that's over the door of a
casino that you're walking in.
And then there's a Sid
vicious slot machine and you
go, okay, okay, so this is,
you know, sat tires, debt. We can no
longer do satire. That's over. Well,
it's hard to do attire to this
dot. Oh, never liked it. I
never worked really hard because there's
so many people that are serious that
are more ridiculous than satire. There's
a guy who, I don't know his real name,
but his, his Twitter
name is Tatyana McGrath,
and he plays like the most
woke person in all of Twitter.
And I retweet his stuff or her stuff, the,
the pseudonym all the time. And people
get furious. They're like, Oh my God,
is this fucking person serious?
Like this is bullshit. And I'm like,
it's parody. And they're like, Oh.
And they go, okay, I get it. I'm like,
it's that close. It's that close to
being a real person, but not close.
We've already crossed over. Oh yeah,
absolutely. There's no way to tell. No,
there's no way to, well, with woke
people with the, with the woke young,
they're still wouldn't tell with you,
with anybody far writings. Well, yeah.
Anything, yeah. There's no way to tell
with any of us or so. But I never, ever,
ever liked satire. I
never, ever liked parody,
even when I was reading national Lampoon
on the onion. How about that? Is that
a turnaround fast enough for you?
The onion is too good. When the onion
did the headline, when Steve jobs died,
which said a nation, uh,
mourns the loss of the last person
to do what the fuck you was doing,
I went, ah, that's perfect. But
you know, I, I, I saw that post. Do
you have up? Yeah. About
here in your, uh, which one?
The Lenny Bruce without tears.
Oh yeah. Yeah. And you know,
the idea of walking, I
mean, and I looked, I was,
I was whatever. I was, uh,
10 or 11 when Lenny Bruce
died. And, um, but you know,
I, I didn't ever hear him until after
he was dead. And you're younger than me,
so even more so for you. But I, um,
I did not go to college, but I, uh,
I would hitchhike up to the college that
was nearby when I was in high school,
which was UMass and all
that. And yeah. And, uh,
cause I'm from little dead factory
town North of there. And, uh,
I remember seeing, uh, Lenny Bruce
without tears. They showed that as a film.
Oh wow. I'm a college campus. Wow. Uh,
I think I'm remembering this right.
Like we know our memories are wrong,
but I saw the film very
early and it was, uh,
completely life changing
for me. You know, um,
the idea that stand up comedy was going
to go from [inaudible] to me was the
Smothers brothers, uh, to, um,
to somebody actually talking
from their heart in a way that,
uh, made people laugh, but
who cared. And of course,
then Andy Kaufman turns
that entirely inside out.
But the idea that that form
was created, you know, um,
created here in the U S when
you went from being a, you know,
a park, a carcass, you
know, Albert Brooks,
his father doing the Greek dialect and
even throw in Amos and Andy and all
of those people that did joke,
joke, jokes and character stuff.
And then all of a sudden the guy coming
out as himself and talking about his
real life was just mind blowing to me.
And so the idea that
instead of doing parody,
being able to get your laughs,
stating what you believe,
and maybe that means people are
laughing at you and maybe that's okay.
It's definitely okay. Um,
but I don't think there's anything
wrong with any way to do it.
I think there's nothing wrong with Abbott
and Costello. You know what I mean?
It's, I was having a talk
with Gilbert, you know,
Gilbert Gottfried and we were talking,
he said, you know, and in the, um,
in Laurel and Hardy stand, Laurel was
the brains. And then the three Stooges,
Moe was the brains. And in the Marx
brothers, Groucho was the braids.
And dabbin. Costello had no brains.
You know that total you want to talk
about the Stooges began archi? Yeah,
the Abbott and Costello or just
completely off the map. Yeah,
just really for the time though,
it was groundbreaking. We,
it's hard for us to wrap our head around
as was Cheech and Chong, you know,
Cheech and Chong for the
time was groundbreaking.
I know that has to do with
drugs and that for me, for me,
I was on a different team at that time,
but I've gone back and that
stuff is good and of course,
but I'm also a liar because I was crazy
for Firesign theater and memorizing
everything and feel Proctor's still up.
A good friend of mine and
that was very much drug base.
I think that comedy is like music in
that there's a whole bunch of different
ways to do it. You know,
and if you were a big fan of Bruce
Springsteen and you went to see Bruce
Springsteen, but run DMC showed up
instead, you'd be furious if you're like,
what the fuck is this? But
obviously people love run DMC.
It's a different way to do a thing. It's
a different way to express just and,
and, and, and a way to learn.
Yeah. No way to learn when you get,
when you get pushed out of there.
But it's, it's just, uh, uh,
that, that whole idea that
you've got to, um, this, I mean,
my life is so heavily affected by drugs,
even though I had this
whole, you know, I, uh,
I'm not gonna do any drugs. Why did
you have that decision? You know,
I don't know. I don't know. That's always,
and I've talked about this on my
podcast forever, you know, I tell him,
how old are you now? I'm 64 years old.
And you have no experience with drugs
other than gun medication, surgery? Sure.
I mean, yes. And I have,
I've had a deep enough injuries
that I have experienced.
Keep getting surgery cause you love
drugs. Excuse. Well, you know, uh,
Trey Parker, um,
said that my big flaw was never
having been high so we can fix that.
So I know. So he did fix that.
I went in for dental surgery,
serious dental surgery, and
they fucked up. And the, uh,
the dentist told the nurse what he had
given me in terms of painkillers and she
took that as what she
was supposed to give me,
so instantly doubled the dose and I
was so fucking high and out of my mind.
People can die that way. Yeah.
And I told my wife through my Hayes
of not knowing who I was called,
Trey Parker drag came to Vegas and said,
I want to sit with Penn high. So he
flew in while you were fucked up.
Oh my God. How long did it take
him to get to you? We, we, he was,
he was planning on being there like, he
came like a day early. Oh. So he got,
he got there like I was still high and
Trey said I didn't remember anything and
traced out the next day. I was
right. You should be high. Well,
there's different kinds of high, like
there's different kinds of music.
And you know, I was very, I was very, uh,
I was very close to Lou Reed and I was a
very good friend of mine. And Lou said,
speaking on behalf of the people of earth,
which I often do. We don't want to see
ya. I'm a motherfucker, don't do it.
So Lou says no, Trey says
she has, what does Joe say?
Well Joe is interesting cause I wanted
to talk to you about this cause we had a
conversation a long time ago
about this and you said that I,
and I'll remember this very clearly,
I may paraphrase this, but you said,
I think we've learned all there is to
know and I don't need to do it. Oh yes,
I said that and I was wrong. Yeah. Yeah.
Well I think you should
experience psychedelics cause
I don't think psychedelics
are a totally different thing. They
don't take, you know, Sam Harris. Sure.
And Sam Harris is the one who
got me meditating. Awesome.
Which took him a years of arguing with me.
And now it's been three or four years
that I have not missed a day, not Mr. Day.
You, uh, you have a problem.
Here's one of your problems.
You're very intelligent. You're also
very large and you're very articulate.
And people like to hear you talk. So
you just can talk and you can take over,
you could overrun things, and you can
make an argument that people just go,
all right, okay. And they stepped back.
And that's good if you're
trying to win an argument,
but sometimes it's bad to take an ideas.
And I remember when I had that
conference exactly right. Thank you.
When I had that conversation
with you, I remember saying,
I'm going to revisit this someday and
one day I want to get pen fucked up on
mushrooms. That's what I remember thinking
like it might be a good thing for,
well, the best thing for you would be
something that doesn't take very long,
just so you can expect like DMT is the
best one because it takes like 15 minutes
and it's over, and then your body brings
it back to baseline almost immediately.
So you literally traveled to another
dimension and then you're back and you
don't have to worry about any overdosing
because it's an indogenous chemical.
Your body knows exactly
what to do with it.
So one of the quickest chemicals that
your body can break down and bring back to
baseline in, in my defense, uh,
from the very beginning
of my not doing drugs, um,
which is an odd, odd kind of
a kind of baseline there. Um,
I always left the door open for, um,
for psychedelics and what I,
what I disliked the most was
wine with dinner. Really.
I disliked the most social kind
of lubrication, wine with dinner.
Amazing. Doing this in past tense, you
know, that's, that's right. That's right.
That's where I always was and I always
left open the possibility of some of the
more intense stuff. Wine with
dinner is a delicious drug.
It's one of the rare delicious
trucks. Like, I like whiskey,
but let's be honest, it tastes like shit.
It's weird. You're drinking is tough.
Like, whew. Like it's got kind of a
good flavor, but it's like, it's harsh.
She can't drink it. Like,
it can't fuck with Koolaid.
Kool-Aid tastes way better than
whiskey, right? Koolaid. It's cheap.
He doesn't mix it up. It tastes
delicious. It's way better tasting.
But you know, wine has a delicious
tastes that you can enjoy.
Here's my problem. One of
my many problems, we'll
detail more than one. Okay?
But I have no skill at moderation.
I'm 64 years old and I've never been
able to do anything with moderation.
So I think if you told me we're gonna
do acid for the rest of our lives every
single day, you could make that
argument. The idea for me, that's hard.
Like I said, but I said I was
meditated. I haven't missed a day.
Maybe you should microdose
yeah, maybe. Yeah,
we could give you a little right
now. Just a little spray. You do.
Microdosing just raise
how I gonna do it now.
Now I want to think about
it a little bit before,
although it would be pretty boss,
tell me why and I'll open the
box. You get the box right there.
I got a box right here. Yep. So, um, how
often do you see, Oh, I was going to,
I was going to answer that question.
I have a zillion answers to why I've
never done drugs and none of them are of
course true cause we don't have access
to that stuff that we really do.
But my parents and my whole family and
back generations teetotallers so there
was never alcohol in the house ever.
I never saw my parents take
a drink when it was on TV.
It was a totally different thing. It
just didn't happen. I didn't have any,
they never preached about it.
They never said don't drink.
They never said don't do drugs.
It just never was in the house.
And that statistically has
a huge effect on people.
And then the first people
I fell madly in love with,
you know, uh, Lenny
Bruce, Jimmy Hendrix, um,
had been in my mind killed
by drugs and I kind of said,
Oh people would that have this kind of
personality when they get into drugs,
they sometimes have trouble.
And I think that maybe being 19 years
old and trying to get into show business
that may be being the sober one allowed
the dumber guy to do a little better,
you know, is everybody else kinda get
out of my way? They were fucked up
some of the time.
I could get other stuff done and then
that starts reinforcing that may no longer
be valid. Well there are drugs.
I mean I've never done Coke and one
of the reasons why I never did Coke,
and I've talked about this many
times, my friend growing up,
his cousin used to sell it and
I watched his life fall apart.
They were just doing Coke all the time
and lost a lot of weight and looks like a
vampire. It was very strange to
just hung out in their attic.
Apartment is really weird. And I
remember thinking, fuck Coke. It's like,
like a guy I know got bit
by a monster, you know,
and was infected with something. The
people, the people that I've been on Coke,
not pleasant, not good. It's not. I
don't, and I think that's also, you know,
one of the accusations against Trump that
he's on some sort of speed, you know,
which is why he's so
inexhaustible, you know?
And also why he has this inability to be
affected by criticism in terms of like
he doesn't, there's no self reflection,
no shame, no shame, no self reflection.
And that's something that is a symptom
of people that are on speed. You know,
and this is the Adderall generation
that we're living in. God damn,
there's so many fucking people that
are on Adderall. I mean it's so,
it's so goddamn common. You know,
I was having this conversation the other
day and someone was telling me about
this guy that they know
who's really brilliant,
but he won't stop til he's
got ADHD and you know,
he just can't stop and he won't stop
talking and this and that. I'm waiting.
I'm just waiting while this person's
talking to me. I'll go, he's on Adderall.
And they go, yeah, he is. It's a
medication. I go into their [inaudible],
it's fucking speed. That
guy's on speed. Okay.
And you can call it a medication
because you can buy it at the pharmacy.
But that fucking guy's on
speed all day long, every day.
And there is a giant number of people
in this country that are medicated and
that are on speed all the time.
It's a great Andy Warhol quote,
which was in the 60s we thought
we're getting to know people,
but we were getting to know
drugs. Uh, you know there's there,
there is definitely,
there is definitely a personality type
that we think is an individual that
actually does seem to have a tie in
with its fucking Adderall mindset.
There's a speed mindset and it's a go,
go, go get everything done more, bigger,
faster, accumulate shit.
I'm the fucking man.
I'm the fucking man like
that. That's a speed mindset.
It's a dangerous mindset.
It's a real weird one.
And it's not one that laughs at itself.
It's not one that's self deprecates.
It's all me, me, me, me, me. I'm the shit.
And that's what you get out of Trump.
I mean, this is, I mean,
there's a guy who was in a journalist
who wrote a story about how he knows the
very Dwayne Reed pharmacy in Manhattan
where Trump was getting diet pills way
back in the day. We were supposed
to take it for like six weeks.
He took it for years and
this guy is saying like,
this is what you're dealing with.
Like many people have called him the
Adderall president, like this is it.
It absolutely could be that he's on
something that all the we're talking about
this whole time is just
speed. Yeah. Yeah. I mean,
and it gives them the energy to look.
Remember when he was running
for president? I'm like,
how the fuck is this guy not tired? I
get tired if I tour and do stand up.
When I do stand up, it's an hour,
20 minutes of my own routine
that I've wrote myself.
I'm hanging out with friends. I do
two shows a night and I'm like, whew.
This motherfucker's touring, flying
around in jets all over the country,
just in exhausted. Just no fucking script.
Just goes on stage in front of everybody.
Just ranted and raved about China
and the economy and build wall. Well,
all right,
we're going to go to Ohio and then off
to the jet eating Kentucky fried chicken
and fucking flies in Ohio.
And he does it again. I mean,
who the fuck at 70 has that
kind of energy people on speed?
I don't know if it's true. I
might be wrong, I might be wrong,
but it seems like it,
it seems like all the pieces are in
place and there was a psychologist is,
did an analysis of all the
various psychological, um,
traits that people who
are on in fed amines have.
And they compared it to Trump and like
all of them megalomania all over the
various psychological characteristics,
inability to accept criticism. You know,
this thinking that everyone's
against them. This, the, the, this,
this delusions of grandeur,
all these different,
thanks. What was, there was a
guy on, uh, on, uh, there was,
there was on apprentice who talked
about him, uh, him doing these,
these kinds of drugs. There was
a news story. It was like a,
it was like an intern that
we weren't going to, uh,
w w just kinda faded away after
that. But I, it's a, a, it's a,
it's a nutty a, it's a nutty thing.
Tom Arnold claims Donald Trump's snorted
Adderall and the apprentice set. Okay,
well I know Tom, he's crazy. I
love you Tom. But I don't know.
Yeah, maybe he did, but mate,
Tom Arnold would say that he snorted
Trump or snorted a Coke just to piss Trump
off. He would say that just
cause I'm fucking with him.
I'm getting under his skin. Maybe
did snort Adderall. I don't know.
I don't know. It doesn't seem like he,
that it's the kind of
thing he would snore it.
It seemed like he would pretend that
it was medicinal. Yeah. He take a pill.
Yeah. I mean it's kind of
medicinal. Here's the thing,
it will allow you to get
more things done. You know,
we had a guy in here wrote a
book on Hunter Thompson and
uh,
one of the things that he's talking about
was that he needs Adderall to right.
And I was going into it with him because
one of the things that dirty little
secret about journalism is a tremendous
amount of journalists are on Adderall.
Tremendous amount. Like an enormous
amount. Like one of my friends who's a,
a pretty rigid,
do we know how much Adderall
is going into the USA?
That's a good question.
How many Adderall prescriptions
were made in 2018?
Let's just find that out. Um,
but my friend who was a legit journalist
for legit publication said you would be
stunned. And he goes, he goes, it's
an enormous percentage. The majority,
they just started banging it out
too. I mean, like they did with, um,
with the fentanyl, the vets to children.
They just bang out Adderall under
and a what's the other one? Prozac.
No, the other one they do
for, I guess for it, for, um,
attention to fish deficit
disorder is another one. Other
than Adderall was, I'll just Adderall
maybe. Prozac. Adderall. I know Prozac.
Prozac was, they put my neighbor's
kid on Prozac was fucking horrific.
Seems low. 16 million adults
are prescriptions refilled.
16 million adults had prescriptions
filled. That's low thousand abuse it,
which seems low also. So 16 million.
Yeah. What does that like 3% yeah.
Yeah. That seems low. Less than
four 4% something like that.
I don't know. It seems very low. That
was last year. Did 2012 is the last, Oh,
2012 I couldn't find any, but that's
a million years ago showing up.
Maybe that was true for 2012 I think it
probably was true for 2012 I think we
live in a whole new world now and I
don't think it's anywhere near 4% or 5%
whatever the fuck the real number is.
I bet it's about 10 I bet it's 10% of
people in this country on Adderall.
If I had to guess, I bet it's around 30
million. I bet it's around there. Yeah,
I'm not, yeah, I wouldn't be shocked.
I know a bunch of people that
are on it a bunch and you know,
some people tell me they have to take
it. That's when my favorite one is.
I have to take it. I won't tell you
what happens is you die, you disappear.
What happens? You don't take it.
It's fucking speed, man. You know,
like a lot of the people that take
it, they're not healthy otherwise.
Like they're not exercising,
they're not drinking a lot of water.
They're not meditating, they're not
eating healthy foods. Like what do you,
why do you need that? Like what happens
if you get rid of all that other stuff?
Like cut out the shitty food, cut out
all the sugar, start drinking water,
no booze. Let's get you
exercise in three times a week.
Let me see if you really need
that. Adderall shit. Yeah.
How many vitamins do you take? Do you
take vitamins? Do you eat healthy?
Are you drinking fruit
juice and vegetable juice?
Are you what kind of nutrients
you taking into your system, man?
And you're wondering why you
don't have any fucking energy.
So you're just pouring
jet fuel into your tank.
Lighten the whole fucking thing on
fire. But, and the other hand is like,
things get done when you take speed.
You know what we were talking about
Hitler the other day that, um,
why wouldn't she be, why wouldn't we
be, we were talking about who was,
who were we talking about? Was it a
with Faheem? I don't remember. Um,
but we were talking about how Hitler, um,
w there was a time where Hitler had come
back from something and he was supposed
to meet Mussolini and he was
like physically exhausted.
So his doctor injected him
with a combination of steroids
and liquid cocaine and
he just just fucking fill with energy.
He's like, give me another one.
And the guy's like, no,
I can't give you another.
It's like fucking give me another one.
And he gave him another one and then
he went to Mussolini and ranted at
Mussolini.
Just fucking talked at them for five
hours and Mussolini just never got a word
in edgewise. And apparently mousseline
his plan was to talk to Hitler and go,
Hey man, Italy wants to
get the fuck out of this.
We're not really interested in
that. And he was like, what?
Then just fucking going crazy for
five hours, sweating like a pig.
Cause he was on fucking Coke,
he was on Coke and steroids.
They just pumped him up with it. Maybe
it's best to stay away from some drugs.
Yes. Okay. Yes. But
I mean it's,
it's amazing how much productivity
gets done because of caffeine.
Right now. What is caffeine? Caffeine
is a very mild stimulant in terms of,
you know, compared to Adderall
or things along those lines.
But it is a fucking truck and it's a drug.
There's a God damn drug store on
every corner. Everyone's buying it.
It's in every gas station. Everyone's
fueling up. Y'all have few up caffeine.
You know, I, I don't, I brought,
no, I drink decaffeinated coffee,
which means I drink 5% of
what? Right. You know, I drink,
I can drink eight cups of coffee and
it makes a, you just like the taste.
I don't like the taste, but
I liked the social stuff.
I like having a hot, bitter thing
in front of me. Let's just have tea.
I have tea too. Yeah.
My eyeball. I nervously,
I nervously drink. Yeah. But like,
you know, like some people smoke. Oh,
I to sell sir. Like they have uh, uh,
decaf coffee or decaf tea or something
like that. I like sells her too.
It makes me feel like I'm doing something
rather than drinking water. You know,
like, I like sparkling water.
It's water with entertainment.
I like sparkling water
with a little lime. Oh,
I've got a drink here and I
still drink. Or you know what,
you take decaffeinated espresso and then
you pour a carbonated water on top of
that and then you've got bitter bubbly.
You're drinking a potion, you want that.
You want a potion,
a potion makes you feel like an adult
if they feel like it grow Koolaid.
This is an adult boy.
Exactly. And when you're,
when you're a non drinker of alcohol,
you have to work very hard to look like
you're drinking like an adult. Yeah.
So you've never fucked with alcohol at
all? No walls, no nothing. No nothing.
I mean, try it. Okay. I know I'm
talking to somebody who pays attention.
So you can say that there
is alcohol and vanilla,
there's alcohol and things like
that. So you can't say none,
but none that I ever acted.
I never, I never went to,
I never went to a searched out. It feels
good, so I never even accidentally,
no one ever even, you know, fuck with me
on that real well. That's good. That's,
that's surprising. Yeah.
That is surprising. Given
the circles you travel in.
I would imagine eventually someone
would be like, enough is enough.
Get this guy fucked up. It's to be
funny. Yeah. This would be really funny.
Yeah.
It seems like someone would have that
would've fit in someone's sense of humor.
Some great word knows. This may be the
day. No, I wouldn't do that. If you,
if you really want to say the word, we'll
open up the box of doom. You box it.
How often do you do a psych and drugs
drill? Yes, I can do not that often.
A couple times a year I'll go get like,
I mean we did mushrooms on a
podcast a couple months ago,
but that was a small dose,
but a, the tank is my friend
[inaudible] century two. I have one
right here. I have one your size.
[inaudible].
I went to one of these places where you
pay them X amount of money and you go,
man, because my buddy Tim Jenison,
we did a movie called Tim's Vermeer where
you painted a different mirror in his
garage and uh, Tim was really into
that. I'll do anything Tim does. I just,
I just loved him. And uh, so I
went and you know, whenever you pay
a few bucks in you, you'd go in and
float in the tank. And I was so ready.
I have S this happens so much in my life.
I get so ready for a
major change in my life.
The first time I wanted to become
a vegan, I went out with a friend.
This was like in 1990 and there was a guy
who was making fun of brutally ripping
them the fuck apart for a stupid
eating, you know. Then I said, listen,
I want to go out with you to a restaurant,
just eat vegetables and I'm
not going to interrupt you.
I'm not going to make funny.
You talk to me for three hours
about all your Peter singer's stuff,
all your ethical vegetarian
stuff and you convert me,
that's all I want you to do. Ah.
That was the reason I went out.
That was the reason I went out with them
and I finished up the whole evening and
I went, you know, I really respected
your point of view until I understood it.
Then motherfucker talked me out of doing
what I wanted to do and so I got ready
man with the, with, with the uh,
isolation tack. I said, this'll be good.
He's told him about this. I'm just
going to go there. Sensory deprivation.
I'll just let my mind wander. And I
went in there and it was just salting.
I was bumping against walls.
Yeah, yeah, yeah. It's, you need to get
used to it. It's like the meditation.
Try meditating once you're like,
I couldn't concentrate and meditate me
once is useless. Yes. Yeah. It's um,
you often, you do the tech all the time.
I used to have one of my handles
sitting now, no all times,
but often I should say. Um,
I used to have one in my house
and now I just have it here.
But it's a very valuable tool.
And you meditate as well? Yeah,
I meditate. I like to meditate for shows.
I've been doing a lot more lately. Um,
uh, but the tank is a great place to
meditate as well because it's meditation
squared.
It's meditation without any external
stimulation so I can climb in there and
[inaudible].
And do you follow,
do you follow breathing rules
and stuff you would do on normal?
What kind of meditation do
you do when you meditate?
I'll do what I've been doing.
What I've been doing lately is all
I do is concentrate on my breath.
Other things get in there, but I just
say, breathe in, breathe out, breathe in,
breathe out, breathe in, breathe
out. And I just concentrate on long,
slow, rhythmic breaths and I get
myself into this weird state.
And you know, this'll come in. Ah,
you gotta fucking low front tire.
You gotta you gotta get that
filled. Uh, this is, you need this,
the your inspection sticker and
all and the bullshit comes in.
But I just breathe in, breathe
out, force it out before,
sit out and after five
or 10 minutes of this,
I can get to a nice state where I can
just keep doing it, keep doing it.
But in the tank, it's very
accentuated because in the tank,
I don't have to think about my butt
in the seat, my hands on the table.
I don't have to think about anything
else, just I'm just lying there.
What you're experiencing when you're
talking about bumping into the walls,
that's just a technique thing. When
you, when you lie in it, right?
You get into the tank. First of all,
you need a big tank. You're a giant guy.
Um, there's a lot of
those little pods, those,
those are barely big enough from me.
You know, it's for a guy like you,
you need a large one and you lie down on
the tank and then you put your hand on
one wall and your hand on the other
wall and you let the water still,
because it's going to be a lot of little
ripples when you're floating because
you're so buoyant.
There's a thousand pounds of Epsom salts
in there and you're floating and it's
easy to just kind of
bounce back and forth.
So you put your hands
there until they steady.
And then once the ripples kind of stop,
then you slowly bring your hands down.
And then when you slowly
bring your hands down,
you do it really slow so you're not
making any ripples and then lay there.
And then you could be in the exact
same position for hours. And that's,
that's how it's a technique.
It's just you have to center you.
So how long you do?
Two hours is what I like to do and I'll
do an hour if I'm in a rush and I have,
um, a, a work shape or throw it
is. Yeah. I mean, it's not a rush.
It's just an hour. But if I can't
spend any more time than an hour,
but I have a tape recorder that's voice
activated and it's Velcro and so I can
stick it up inside the thing. So if
I have an idea, which I do sometimes,
sometimes I have this temptation,
fuck, I gotta get outta here.
I gotta write this down.
I can just say it and the,
the tape recorder will pick it up and
there have been brilliant stuff you said
no nothing and never
used it once it's there.
You haven't gotten out of the
tech and had satisfaction? No,
there's no that Keith Richards thing,
right that nobody went to sleep. Really.
He had this sound activated recorder
that he got by the side of the bed and,
and his guitar and he
went to sleep one night,
woke up the next morning there
on the tape recorder. Oh,
there was some voice activation in the
night. He played it. It was satisfaction.
My friend. We haven't gotten that
yet. No, I haven't had that yet.
My friend works at a school in
Connecticut where his kids go,
or Keith Rich's kids go and Keith Richards
will ride on a bike to school with a
fucking bandana on. And like my friends,
like, Holy shit, that's Keith Richards.
Like he's just kinda hanging around
with normal people and he said,
it freaks you out when you
see him. You're like, what?
That's fucking Keith Richards. He
just hangs out. Just like, you know,
he's a giant superstar,
but he drifts into the real world and
it just freaks people out. Yeah, it's,
it's, it's, it's, I mean,
I only met Keith Richards in groups
of people that were what's really like
bicycling into your yeah, but still
it's so, it's so amazing. Surreal,
so surreal. Epic human. Yes.
The voice recorder thing is new.
That's why I haven't had any new,
it's a new idea that I have
because there's times that I did
to this team thing and the, uh,
and the separation of America
and getting more polarized.
That's going to be solved by
Joe in the tank at some point.
We can count on that. No, now
that you got the recorder,
we're going to solve it ourselves.
I think we're going to solve
it ourselves through just time.
I think as we're getting back to Pinker
were talking about Pinker earlier that
he gets so much shit for saying
that things are better than ever.
It doesn't dismiss horrific acts.
It take place or terrible things.
And it doesn't say that
the battle is over. No,
I mean this is one of the things that
I would push in my little microcosm,
push for so hard in Penn
and teller, you know, uh,
tell her and I would have real
trouble just crossing a finish line.
I would just say to him,
you know, tell her we, we,
we've done five seasons of
bullshit and it went well,
let's go out the two of us have coffee
and donuts and let's just say, wow,
we did that and then push ahead for
the next thing. And I would just, uh,
I just think that Pinker is like that
with me. Pinker's like saying, you know,
human beings, we're doing
okay. We're doing okay,
we'd done some really good things.
Now let's get back to work.
We're most certainly doing
better than ever before.
And I think that's an accumulative
thing. It's like it's time.
Don't blow everything that pink came come,
which if we don't destroy the
environment, if those two things,
the two enormous ifs, we're
in very good shape. They are.
The thing that blew my
mind about Pinker in that,
in that book better
angels blew my mind is,
uh, there's this line that's that,
that, that has been obsessing me, uh,
with a Cracker in teenage angst. I
don't know what the world may need,
but I sure as hell know it starts
with me. And that's a wisdom.
I've laughed at all this shit that I've
laughed at that turns out to be true for
me now. It just makes me smile
and fills me with joy. You know,
uh, early part of the 20th century,
all these authors and artists and all
these guys were saying Hemingway's step,
we're gonna stop war by writing about
war and writing about how bad it was.
And we're going to give empathy for other
people and we'll understand this and
we're going to really, with our art,
make an effort to make humanity better.
What I Jack off bullshit
thing to do. I think there's,
could you imagine something more that's
just twiddling your Dick than say a
neck. Oh, I'm going to do art.
I'm going to write and it's
going to change the wine poetry.
And then Pinker's book says, why is
all this stuff get better so fast?
We think it may be art had a baby empathy.
And it turns out that, uh, all this
stuff people were saying about, you know,
we can change,
we can change how people see warfare
and how people see one another.
And that's what scares
me so much about, um,
how some people speak of. And I think
it's because I don't understand it.
Usually when I'm against something,
it means I don't understand it.
But when they talk about
cultural appropriation,
cultural appropriation seems to me to be
the greatest thing you can possibly do
to see the world through the eyes of
someone who grew up differently than you.
To even try to do that for. Even for,
to pretend right now to be a a, you know,
white nationalist
even trying to do that seems like it's a
really good thing for us trying 10 just
to get into their head just to try
to fantasize what it's like to be,
for instance, a uh, uh,
African American transgender
man. If we try to do that,
we're writing a piece of art and we
try to see ourselves from that point of
view. I'm not, not that I'm not herself
see the world from that point of view.
That seems like nothing but healthy.
It seems like that takes you
out of your identification.
Well, I think there's a lot of what we're
calling cultural appropriation that is
really people trying to tell
other people what to do.
Cause people enjoy telling people they
can't do that anymore and getting angry
at those people. They enjoy it.
They enjoy pushing buttons. People,
you give them a rock and a window,
they want to throw that
rock through the window.
It's a natural part of being a person.
And if you see a girl with hoop earrings,
like bitch, take those earrings off.
Those are for Latino's or there's a for
this. So those are for that. I mean,
and the argument is so often
not even based historically,
like the earring thing. Like fuck Ben,
what are you from Sumir like that's the
oldest known hoop earrings like you,
that's all you're from Babylon.
It's also what a, I don't know if this
is, this is not Pinker, this is Noah. Um,
Rari um, who uh, who talks about when
you're talking about cultural stuff,
how far back you going? Right? I
mean, there are no tomatoes in Italy,
but you know, sure. Yeah.
Tomatoes are not indigenous.
Italy pasta came from China and
potatoes aren't from Ireland. They,
they don't start there. You know,
so you have to keep going back.
There was a great, you know, uh, Paul
Simon got so much shit for Graceland,
uh, you know, and uh, and,
and David Byrne get so much shit for
stuff and there's this wonderful thing and
David Burns, uh, book how music
works, which is a fabulous book,
but he doesn't ever address this
picking things from other cultures ever.
But he talks very strongly about the
African kinds of music and the influences
they have from other places.
You know, cause there is not,
there is not a culture
other than the whole world,
especially not now. You might be able
to have made the argument 200 years ago.
There were
Pat, the thing is though,
that people enjoy cultures.
So if that is the case and everything
does assimilate and becomes one big gray
mass, we're worried that we're
gonna lose Indian food. Right.
We're worried that we're going to lose.
I have no worry of that at all. No,
I have no worry because I think that me
loving sun RA,
even though I'm not African
American and me loving Lenny Bruce,
even though I'm not urban
and identify as Jewish,
I think that loving these
kinds of cultures should
not be based on an accident
of birth. The
loving thing is one thing though.
I think the real fear of cultural
appropriations is that will take on those
things as their own. Like
there's a gentleman, I'm
trying to remember his name.
Uh, he is a famous Mexican
chef, but he's not Mexican,
but he cooks Mexican food. He
cooks it in Chicago. Walt Bayless,
is that his name? Um, something.
Bayliss. Rick Bayless. Rick Bayless. He,
this guy has an undeniable
passion for Mexican cuisine.
I mean, he fucking loves it.
He has a couple different restaurants
where he cooks Mexican food and he was
getting protested and people
were furious at him. Um,
because they had just decided at one
point if this guys had like, you know,
a 30 fucking year career of being in love
with Mexican cuisine and being like a
real historian of Mexican cuisine
work where it comes from. The regions,
the ingredients, like
where's the best ingredients,
where's the best places to cook
these things, how they do it,
why they did it this way and I mean
speaks with incredible passion about this.
They were deciding that he's
a white guy and he shouldn't,
shouldn't be able to do this,
shouldn't be able to sell. This,
shouldn't be able to like
do you fucking assholes?
Like this is the guy he's helping
everyone recognize the beauty of this much
maligned food. When you, when
people think about Mexican cuisine,
he is one of the rare people in Western
culture that talks about it like it's
five-star cuisine. So
many people talk about,
Oh I love street tacos and fucking I'm
going to be a big fan of case a D no,
this guy is talking about the very best
Mexican cuisine in the world and trying
to interpret that and sell it to people
and trying to turn people on to how good
this food is.
And yet he was taking so much shit when
a person that wasn't born in that act,
the accident of birth to be in there
falls in love with another culture.
I don't see why that isn't more beautiful.
Yes. Yeah. That's, that's, that's,
that's what I'm looking for. That
Steven Seagal. Yeah. He moved to Japan,
became a master before
he became kind of silly.
He was one of the very first guys to
ever teach a kiddo in a dojo in Japan.
That wasn't Japanese. I think
he actually was the first,
I think it was the first American
to ever run a dojo in Japan. So no.
Okay.
Giving me on psychedelics is very easy
compared to getting me to really dig
Stevenson guy. I mean, I'm not sure I do,
although I do appreciate his
first movie above the law.
I appreciate what he look.
He likes his prepositions.
He's a silly fail silly fella
for sure. Many of us are. Sure.
But what he, he did do is
he learned I KIDO at a very,
very high level, like undeniably.
And he was teaching and in
Japan he spoke perfect Japanese.
And it was a very rare guy,
you know, and now, you know,
became a Hollywood guy in movies
and who knows what the fuck else.
And it became an enormous, you know,
physically you got fat and you know,
he's kind of silly now,
but at one point in time that
guy was as legit as it gets.
Isn't that always true? It's
always starts. You don't want it.
I'm going to completely change the
subject is like if I met, you know,
I to talk about
when you came on my radio show with Phil
plait about the talking about the moon
landing. Yeah. But what I, what I
think is fascinating about this,
about clubs and stuff, you know,
is, uh, I, uh, you know, and I,
I know I've, I've read here
and there that you, you've, uh,
you've gone back on a lot of that and
your conspiracy stuff. And so, yeah,
but that, that's not what
I can explain that to.
I don't know what I'm talking about.
You know, this, this is the thing,
I have zero astrophysics education. Zero.
I don't know anything about whether or
not it's possible to put people on the
moon. I do know fuckery and
I, I do know teams and I do,
I do understand when people
are bullshitting people.
And I think there's a lot of that
with, with a lot of the NASA stuff,
a lot of the older stuff,
and particularly there was a lot of
manipulation of images and putting things
online that may not have actually really
happened because it was press releases
and there's an image of Michael Collins
from like a Gemini 15, that's a, a,
a very clear, um, image of him, uh,
doing a simulation like in a
studio with straps and harnesses.
And then someone from NASA or
someone put that exact same image,
blacked out the background and used
it as a photo of, um, of a space.
Meaning it's not real, you
know, but they sold it as real.
There was some overzealous
shirt like that,
that if you're conspiratorially
minded, you might say, ah, once,
once you start lying. Yes.
[inaudible] you're 51 and stuff. We
know they lied like motherfuckers. Yeah.
And that's the problem.
But what I just want to compliment you
and I just also think this is really
interesting, you know, so Joe
Rogan believes this crazy shit.
We didn't go to the bone. I
know Joe Rogan, we're on it.
We're on a radio show together,
but dah, dah, dah. He's a good guy.
But that fear factor, but, and
he believes this shit. Let's,
let's have him talk to someone
who's real. So I call Phil play do.
I don't know that well, right?
But he's the bad astronomer and
he knows this shit. And I say,
I really want you to come on my radio
show and just talk to Joe Rogan about, uh,
about, um, the moon landing landing.
And uh, Phil says, OK, no problem.
We'll just go on there. We'll,
we'll set them straight. And I go,
I just want to warn you, uh, have your
ducks in a row. Cause Joe's really good.
And he goes, well, Joe's Joe's
a comic, right? I go, yeah,
and that's your problem because
Joe's better at talking than you.
Joe knows when the commercials are coming.
Joe knows how to make a joke and Joe
knows also how to set you up and take you
down here. Oh no, no, no.
It'll be no problem. I said,
you understand that he's smart.
He's a comic, right? Yeah.
Not an Astro physicist, but you
understand that he's smart and he's also,
you are going into his form.
We're going to be on radio.
This guy has done a lot of radio.
This guy's talked to a lot of people,
so just have all your facts in
line and then we're sitting there,
cause you know, you were,
you were on the phone and
uh, Gudo it was on my podcast with me too,
sitting across from me and we're
listening and you come in and you come in
humble and charming and sexy and
with perfect timing on everything.
And Phil placed as well.
I'm like, go, Oh man,
Joe is wrong and Joe is
going to fucking win.
And I said, how you set
this up so that, um,
so that uh, it will be
a fee. It'd be fair.
My whole thing of doing this,
the way I bill boarded it was I'm just
going to have two guys talk from two
points of view. I'm not supposed to
commit it. I don't know if you remember,
but the whole show EDS and I go, Oh,
by the way, we did lay it on the moon.
They just tried to do this final authority
thing and Phil us afterwards. Well,
he, he had, I said, yes. Yeah.
And it's just that idea
that you can't, you know,
his idea was there's the
science team. That's right.
And then there's just goofy comic and
trying to get Phil plait understand that a
goofy comic was not a goofy comic.
And I believe that the only thing that
the SATs truly test is how good you will
be. That can be as a
comedian, that kind of verbal,
it was a wonderful thing to listen to.
It was wonderful to listen to someone
who I believe absolutely was 100% wrong
who was just so skilled and so moral
and so thoughtful and so humble.
You had everything going
for you that I respect,
except it didn't happen to be right.
Well, we don't know what happened.
We assume that what we
see is what happened.
We assume that what the scientist
tell us was hat was what happened.
We assumed that what NASA told us
was what happened. When you say,
I know this happened. Right.
You are not always correct.
Exactly. Oftentimes. Correct. I know
Kennedy got assassinated in Dallas.
I've seen the video. I know
he got assassinated. Dallas.
I don't know of Lee Harvey
Oswald did it? I don't know.
I assume he was involved.
It seems like he was. Yeah.
Was there other people involved
to, I assume there were,
and one of the reasons why I assumed
there were the magic bullet. The fucking,
the guy who got hit with the ricochet
under the overpass know that I made the
shot with Amandla Huracan. Oh yeah. It
can be made. Yeah. Oh, that's horse shit.
Listen, I've talked about that
in, in length towards that.
Yeah. Well, there's a lot of things
is a lot of things. Um, there's,
there's a lot of things we could
go over the Kennedy assassination.
There's a lot of things.
I'm not [inaudible]
are we good?
Are we going to solve the polarization
in America or are we gonna sell them the
Kennedy assassination? Or are
we going to solve the bullying?
Or you would do all of them. Okay. I
just want to know what our goals were.
The Moonlight branding
is a conspiracy theories
dream of conspiracy theorists
dream because it's got
everything in place. It's got this
incredible technological achievement.
It's got these three guys
that look incredibly nervous
at the post landing press
conference and they'll
look all sketched out.
It's got these guys that don't
do interviews afterwards.
It's got no one ever lands on the moon
again after 1973 or whatever it was.
It's got all these
technological achievements,
but we never get outside of
Earth's atmosphere again.
We're always inside of Earth's orbit.
There's so many beautiful things that
conspiracy theories can grasp a hold of
them. Go see it's bullshit.
But it doesn't mean it,
but it doesn't mean it didn't happen.
There's the van Allen radiation belts.
There's that.
We never even send a chicken in deep
space and had to come back alive.
There's all these things, but it
doesn't mean it didn't have. Right.
And my problem was, and this is, you
know, when people said, Oh, you know,
you've sold out. You're a shill
now. And like, no, no, no.
I'm just being honest now.
Whereas before I wasn't being honest with
myself and I wasn't being honest about
the subject. I do not know whether
or not people went to the moon.
I was pretending that.
I knew that people didn't go to the
moon and I was arguing it that way.
I was on a team, I was
on team. It's bullshit.
We didn't go to the moon and you,
you really can't do that
accurately. It can't be done.
You can say, this is what's interesting.
This is what I find curious.
This is what's weird. In fact,
there's not a single technological
achievement from 1969 that's not cheaper,
easier and faster to reproduce today
except going to the moon like he's one of
the rare things in life that still
doesn't mean it didn't happen. Right?
Like outcomes.
Razor's a slippery thing because there's
weird shit that happens and you gotta
take that into account.
Like there's no absolutes.
There's not one thing that you can say,
well there is a rule and this rule
must be followed. And here's that rule.
It doesn't work that way.
The world is made of weird.
And I'm also the, the, the idea, there's,
there's a thing that's changed.
There was an article in the times
about this and you might've even been
mentioned in it. Um, there's a, uh,
a playful space of conspiracy theories
that it's taken me a long time to
understand.
My daughter is 14 and she talks about,
you know, her,
her father did a show called bullshit
and she talks about how she loves
conspiracy theories and this is from
Paul McCartney's dead till we didn't land
on the moon, all those
things. But she sees it,
which I so hard for me to understand.
She sees it as not impacting reality,
but as a playful inter
intellectual exercise.
I don't know what's going on.
But there was this wonderful article in
the times and you were mentioned there
too, but there's also another
guy who does it who will do this.
Uh, to use a cliche, I can't
think of a better one going,
going down the rabbit
hole of conspiracy stuff,
playing around with the logic that feels
like a mathematical thing or a pure
philosophical thing or a or a angels
dancing on the head of a pin thing and a,
there's a quality that you have learned,
um,
that my daughter has learned
indirectly I think from you,
um,
through other people doing this of there
is a playful space or rediscuss how we,
uh,
how we share our reality that is happening
in the conspiracy theory art form and
the conspiracy theory art form is now
seeming to me to be more like rap or rock
and roll or it's just a form of thing
where you play around with this kind of
thing. And I am so I'm literal minded.
So verbal minded, you know, Bob Dylan's
easy for me. The stones are hard,
you know, Zappa's easy, 20th
century classical's easy,
but just funk is hard for me and
it's the same kind of thing here.
It's really easy for me to
say we are doing, um, uh,
the old fashioned scientific inquiry
and this is the way falsifiable,
but there is something happening in
our thinking that's really interesting.
Then I had to have my daughter explained
to me and the New York times after I
already [inaudible]
I knew you and watched
you do it. Well, you've,
you've always been a champion
of science and reason, right?
And conspiracy theories for the most part,
flying the face of science and reason.
And if you don't want to be a buffoon,
nobody wants hopeful poetic theory
happening. But it's tricky and you don't,
people don't want to be a fool.
Well, I'm a professional fool.
I don't mind being a fool and you know,
being self-deprecating and being a moron
as part of being a comic, it's fun.
The,
the conspiracy theory world went South
for me when I did a television show.
I did that. Joe Rogan questions.
Everything shown. I spent six,
seven months doing this show and at the
end of it I was like, okay, I get it.
This is a bunch of unfuckable white
guys. That's what it really is.
That's what I decided. I said, you
know, I had a bit about it. I said,
do you want him?
The one thing you don't find when you're
looking for big foot black people,
you're more likely to find Bigfoot than
you want black guys looking for big foot
is a bunch of unfuckable white
dudes out camping and listening to,
what did you hear that? What is that?
You know? It's like it's nonsense.
Like you're,
you're wrapped up in this idea that
there's a mystery and there's a something.
There's a thing, a quality, but human
beings where we want to uncover secrets,
we want to be the person that finds out
the truth because then you're miserable.
So shitty fucking life now doesn't matter.
The fucking aliens are real
man. They're here and aha.
Aha. One of the best
things we can get probably better
than coming, is that feeling of, aha,
I understand. I've gotten a,
and we see this all the time, detective
shows, you know, Sherlock Holmes,
you know, nothing to do with police work,
but there is a feeling that wouldn't it
be nice if in this hour I were able to
figure something out? Because if
you want understand string theory,
you're not going to do it an hour.
You're not going to do it
ever. Those guys understand it.
Even if they T precisely, let's take an
easier one. Let's take a candle flame.
You're never gonna know
STEM at, right. Uh, studying
that forever. And there's,
there's an area where conspiracy theories
are exercising the muscles of logic,
exercising the muscles of skepticism,
playing around with the,
with the haiku of if then,
if then playing around with, um,
what we feel about the government
and other people and stuff like that.
And you're playing around with all of
that in kind of a semi safe zone and even
watching you just do it
here, where you will, you,
will you bang out that stuff
and say, this is the stuff.
I questioned what's coming out of
that poetically. Uh, and I thought,
let's not even talk about whether
we went to the moon or not.
What's coming out of your style
of inquiry on that kind of thing.
Your style of skepticism is
just fascinating and beautiful.
And I see the conspiracy thing
as not so much a breaking down,
which I used to see it as a
breaking down of science and reason,
but I see it as rather a, a
creation of a new form of poetry.
That's weird. I don't know if my daughter
just said, my daughter just says,
you know, I really like conspiracy
theories and I say to her,
you know, Paul McCartney's still
alive. Right? But you know,
she's 14 and your pen Gillette let,
so she's rebelling. You understand
that, right? You're a parent,
you know, it's like your baby just
told me something really important.
Yeah, there's two dirt down the
real life. Here's the thing,
it's like Neil Gaiman's
daughter coming in, uh,
all golfed out and you'll say to her,
I invented this. You can't do this.
This is not the way you can rebel.
You can't rebel against me like this.
You can't do it with black hair
and eye shadow, you can't do it.
But yeah. Yeah. Well kids, you know,
they, they find their own way and they,
they want to express themselves, you know,
they want to exert power over their world.
But did you see that article that
you were mentioning? No, I did not.
I try not to read anything
that I mentioned that,
I mean I briefly do
oftentimes. And I'm like, huh,
I tried to never read anything with my
name in it because it's not written for
us. Right.
And I'll tell you the exact moment that
happened to me that was so great. Uh,
it was in the 80s were on Broadway
and, uh, I, the cone brothers were
just starting to do movies, you know,
and I was really interested in
them, you know, and uh, I had,
I had like an hour fray,
which when I was doing stern and
Letterman and Saturday night live and on
Broadway, I never had an hour free.
And I was a magazine, like vanity fair,
something, who cares? Fuck what it was.
And has said what the cone
brothers are really like,
what it's like to work with the
cone brothers. Okay. And I said, ah,
I'd never read magazine,
but a by this I'll learn a little bit
about the Cohen brothers on up to our
office. You know, it's like the
Brill building, you know, uh,
Lauren Michaels sit in
my office, open it up,
put the cone brothers like
turn to that page. I said,
if you want to know what
the Cohen brothers are like,
it's like hanging out with
Penn and teller. And I went,
Whoa, Whoa, Whoa.
How does that even real close
the bag of seed? Put it aside.
And they were going on comparing it and
I went, I have no information on this.
None. There's no way I can access
it. Then that moment I went, Oh,
wait a minute.
When it says Penn Jillette
in an article or in a book,
there's no way I can understand
that. Maybe others can, you know.
So when it says in the
article, um, you know,
when Joe Rogan does conspiracy stuff,
duh, duh, duh, duh duh duh duh,
you can't understand that. It's
like Mike Desmond said to me,
the major problem with talking to
Jimmy Hendrix was he never heard Jimmy
Hendrix. He never saw Jimmy Hendrix
on stage. He couldn't. And you know,
so you are the one person that using
Joe Rogan is an example, you know?
Well you know, kind of a Brola Terry kind
of a kind of a does this bro culture.
This is Joe. You can't understand that.
You have no idea what that means
cause you're an individual.
Well it's also people are trying to
encapsulate you by those brief moments and
might've seen a video or heard you talk
about what it means something to other
people. It means something. And it also,
you can easily categorize someone and
put them in this box and now I've defined
that, Oh, I know what that is.
Let's see what else before hanging
out with Penn Jillette. Yeah.
It's also part of your
job, part of your job.
One of the things you've created is you've
created something in the culture that
means the New York times can say Joe Rogan
and are people reading that know what
that means. But there's no way Joe Rogan
can know what that you can pretend,
right? Well, you could be like
Trump and get mad about it.
You know where the rubber really hits
the road with conspiracy theories right
now, Jeffrey Epstein. Oh yeah. That's
the where the rubber hits the road.
That's where people that are not
conspiratorial minded are like, wait,
what the fuck is going on? What
all the cameras were bad? Oh,
that guy was on suicide watch. He tried
to commit suicide and then they're like,
well, don't do that
again. And then he did it.
Like if you talk to people that have
been locked up, they'd take away, man,
you've been on suicide watch.
They fucking take away
everything and you find this guy,
he's got a broken neck and
he hung himself. Like how?
How did he hang himself?
Can we see the video footage? Oh, sorry.
The cameras are broken and yourself
is wicked hard. It's not easy.
It's not easy. It's not easy when
you're in a jail. And they told me, Oh,
have you been to jail? No,
no, no. Never been in jail.
I was only in jail over night. But I mean
they, if you're on suicide watch, man,
they make it hard for you to kill
yourself. They watch you and if your,
is that what? Suicide watch beans. Yes.
They watch you so you can't
kill yourself again. That's the,
they watch you every 30 minutes or so.
What the fuck was this psychologist
thinking that took this guy off suicide
watch? Literally a couple of weeks
after he tried to commit suicide.
If someone tries to
commit suicide, you know,
not speaking as a guy who's had
friends commit suicide, why?
They're fucking thinking about
it for years, man. Some of them,
they go back and forth day to day. Some
of them, some of them just do. Yes,
some of them just do that. But
when someone does actively try it,
they're not gonna just be fine while
they're in fucking prison awaiting trial
for having sex with kids.
It seems like Jeffrey Epstein's life was
going to get really worse from what it
was few months before.
Could be or other people's lives are
going to get really worse because Jeffrey
Epstein's now in jail and they're digging
deep into his past and well when we
flew with them 26 times, 26 times,
and ain't a lot of
times to fly with a guy.
I don't understand what the
big deal is. We flew in a Chet,
we rode a bus together. He was on
the back of my bike. Do you know,
do you know people that know Jeffrey
Epstein? Yes. Yeah, yeah. I do think too.
And a lot of them, uh, it really
was that, yeah. Talk to him,
well hung out a little bit. There's many
people that feel like he was an agent,
uh,
and that he was trying to compromise
people and that's one of the things about
this whole Lolita Island thing is
that they would compromise people.
They would compromise people by having a
bunch of young girls who are very sexy,
who were hired to go and flirt and
maybe even have sex with people and that
these people were young. These girls were
like 17 under age, perhaps under age,
some places perhaps not
under age, other places,
but in incredibly
embarrassing and you know for,
for the people and agent
compromise for home. Who knows?
I mean there's a lot of thoughts,
but that's one of the things about
when he got arrested, the the,
was it the prosecutor or
whoever was it cut him.
The deal literally was quoted as saying,
I was told he's above my pay grade
and that he was intelligence.
That's the quote. Really the intelligence
thing. Try to find that quote. Yeah.
Try to find that quote. Yes.
The guy said this was when he gave
him a lenient sentence many years ago,
Shelly 12 or something. No one seems
to know how he got his money. Well,
the fucking $70 million penthouse that
he had in Manhattan was given to him.
Right. Given to him, who the fuck gives
someone a $70 million house? Well,
I was kind of hoping you would
to me. I don't have one. Okay.
If I have a bunch of them, I'd
give you one. I got it wrong.
You gotta go now I'm just joking. I was
here to give a $70 million house. Oh,
you were told wrong. Yeah.
Yeah. I mean I think the guy,
I think they are, look,
I've talked to people many times that
work for intelligence agencies and there's
a lot of weird shit that they do and
one of the things that they do to
compromise people as they get them
involved in weird stuff that could be very
bad for them if it comes out and then
they have influence over this person.
And if you got a guy with a
voracious sexual appetite,
I mean there's a few of those fellows
out there and you know, Hey man,
proud of that. Archie, I'm out off
now. I'm going fucking hanging out,
having a good time with Jeffrey and we're
just flat around. I mean, come on man,
it's, it's, it's highly likely.
One of the guys that I know that knew him
was also a freak, like a sexual freak.
And I'm like, okay, I think, I think
I see a pattern here. This the,
it's very likely that
that's what was going on.
This guy was compromising people and
probably absolutely a sex addict himself.
And I believe all the women that say all
the horrible things that he did to them
and hired them for things and had
underage girls do sexual things with him.
It's probably true. It's probably true.
He's probably a fucked up twisted dude.
But many people that are involved,
even in good things get compromised.
Like there's many people that work
for the CIA that were legitimate CIA
operatives who wound up selling drugs.
This, there's a lot of this happens.
People go sideways, people get in
involved in shady activity that are cops.
There's cops that wind up doing illegal
things. They signed on to be a cop,
to be a,
a person who's going to serve and
protect and be involved in the community.
And slowly but surely they get compromised
and they get involved in illegal
activity. And the next thing you
know, they're corrupt. That happens.
It happens. And then sometimes
people's fucking suicide themselves,
the people that, uh, that
I know that knew him,
it was a,
they weren't even aware
of the CD stuff going on.
So of course that's going to
be true too. Well, he was a,
it'd be 100% he was also a champion of
science. I mean a champion. Yes, he,
but that's the thing about people.
They can be really good. Sure.
In some ways and horrible in other ways.
This idea that people are buying or
you're one or a zero is nonsense.
There's really good people
that do terrible things.
There's really terrible people that also
do good things. You know, like look,
fucking Trump just passed something
and no one wants to give him credit for
this. He stuff was the
kidney stones. He did.
He did wonderful stuff for
kidney transplant stuff.
I'm sure he pushed through,
well that was going to say
that he absorbed all the
student loans for disabled
veterans. [inaudible]
fantastic. I love it.
You don't hear a word about
it and where to praise. Look,
we should absolve student loans for
fucking everyone. We're crippling kids.
We're crippling the 17,
18 year old kids who sign up for these
fucking loans and they get compromised to
the point where we have people to this
day right now that are getting their
social security,
their social security money's getting
docked because they owe student loans.
They're at the end of the fucking road.
But what do you do? What do you do? Uh,
and this is a real question.
This is not rhetorical.
What do you do about
the feeling of fairness?
The people that work their way
through college waiting tables?
That's a good question. Working
really hard. And then they, uh,
we just say their feelings,
which I think is valid,
which is, yeah, yeah, you got fucked on
this, but let's help someone else out.
What did we hear? Compassion.
Here's the cause. You know, um, uh,
there are people that worked really hard
to not have student loans and there are
people that took them. Um,
there has to be somebody who took them
prevalently 100%. I think quite a few.
And I think it's also,
we also should pay attention to the human
mind and the development of the human
mind in the frontal cortex.
And the frontal lobe does not develop
properly until you're 25 years old. Right.
So some somewhere in that
roster minus four years,
definitely out 17 it's
definitely not 18 months.
So you're taking on these
fucking loans. You, you,
you can't be trusted with money or your
future or thinking about what the fuck
you're doing in terms of like taking
on a debt of hundreds of thousands.
We have to, and this also
ties in, um, uh, with,
with bisexual stuff as well.
Don't we have to decide when someone's
adult and then give them that respect?
Yes. We have to say you're 18 years old.
We can't control what decisions
you make. Yes. Does that,
you're going to be, cause I think 25 is
too old. I think 25 is too old as well.
Yeah. But I think
we're saying is, I mean look,
there's a lot of 18 year old people that
make very good moral decisions. Yes.
And we should, we should praise that.
Here's the problem with the student
loan thing, in terms of the fee,
that's the only loans that
you never get exonerated from.
You can get bankruptcy, right? And
you can get exonerated. You can,
you could escape the
loans of credit cards,
the debt of mortgages.
You could escape a bad business collapsing
and owing millions and whatever you
get. You could escape
that through bankruptcy.
You cannot do that with student
loans. It's a corrupt system.
You take a child who's trying to learn
a trade or trying to learn a profession
and you acquire insane debt that's going
to track you and cripple you for the
rest of your life. And no
matter what happens to you,
you owe that money.
But also you're taking your
colleges out of the free market too,
by giving those, by giving
those loans easily. Yes.
And by having government help. Yes.
So you're also taking away the
free market because you know,
we found out that when you put the
free market in, like play six surgery,
when insurance doesn't cover it,
it gets wicked cheap. You know?
And if colleges had to be paid as people
went without easy loans to get and
colleges did not
get government money, they
might be wicked cheaper.
I think that will be
really, really expensive.
I think [inaudible] crazy expensive.
I think the real solution is in treating
education like a thing that's going to
make our society better.
And think of it as the same way we
think about the fire department.
Same way you think
about police department,
that, I mean when you read the paper,
there's always one whole thing about
colleges getting too expensive and people
can't go do they need to.
And then you turn 20 pages later in the
paper and there's an article about how
online learning is going to happen is
happening and all of this stuff is going
to happen.
Do you think that that idea of college
is going to hold up for another 10 years?
I think there's an experience that
people, I mean, did you go to college?
Well, I did, but I went to college in
my town. I went to UMass Boston and uh,
I really only went because
I didn't want to be a loser.
It was really all it was. I was, uh,
doing martial arts and
fighting and traveling all
over the world or all over the
country rather. And, and thinking about
doing standup at the time as well.
And then transitioning to doing stand up
while I was also still taking classes.
I was learning nothing. It
was a complete waste of time.
I was only doing it so I could say
yeah, taking classes at UMass Boston,
I was barely paying attention,
barely showing up. And um,
it was just a thing that I didn't want
to tell people that I wasn't going to
college. Like that was the number one
reason why I did it, but I, but that was,
I had a unique life from the
time I was, uh, you know,
graduating from high school to
the time I started doing standup.
I was obsessed with martial
arts and competing and
that's all I wanted to do was
make the Olympic team for TaeKwonDo.
That's what, that was my goal.
And that's what I was trying to
do. So I wasn't a normal person.
I wasn't like I wasn't going to go to
Ohio and fucking travel over there and
take a full course load and not
be able to pursue what I wanted,
what I wanted to do.
And also you've got a window
[inaudible] yeah. Politically that's it.
It's fairly,
and there's no, there was no scholarships
for TaeKwonDo goes and doesn't,
it didn't exist. And the only other
option was the army. There was a dude,
I think his name was clay barbers,
this really talented guy who
was a fighter who was, uh,
on the U S team at one
point in time, I think.
And he was a competing
through the army. Like they,
they had subsidized his
training somehow or another.
And I was thinking maybe I should
join the army like those, the other,
the only other thing that I was thinking
about doing. But um, for people,
I think there's a thing about
getting away from your parents,
getting away from them, getting
away from their influence,
being wild and crazy and be with a
bunch of other kids and trying to find
yourself. And I think that comes from
traveling to a place and going to college.
And I think there's, there's
some benefit in that.
And I have friends that have had great
benefit in that sort of a transformative
experience of being on a campus,
a physical campus in a place that's
outside of their hometown where it gives
them this new experience where
they get to try to reinvent.
There's no doubt about
that. Yeah. People do that.
Being able to be someone else. But
I wonder, I wonder if all of that,
why are we giving that a four
year period? Why isn't that our whole
lives? It can, it could be and should be.
And isn't that the way
that's going to change?
Cause people aren't having jobs for
the whole life anymore. And by the way,
the liberal arts education was never
supposed to teach people a trade. Right.
It was always supposed to make it so that
young men could talk in it at parties.
Yeah. That was the idea. We can
have the same cultural thing.
We can tell about Shakespeare, we can
talk about this, we can talk about that.
But none of this was meant to give
people jobs. Well, it's so rigid, right?
You get out of high school,
high school was this torturous affair
where you're being a square peg,
they're trying to shove into a round hole.
Then you get out and then they fly off
to wherever the fuck you're going to go
to school and you go there and you're
forced with this overbearing workload of
school and then social things.
You're trying to figure out what's okay
and what's not okay now where's the safe
space and what am I, what am I?
Am I allowed to say this and
am I allowed to say that?
And what are the new rules now for this
new generation and where are we really
gonna change the world.
And then all the sudden you're out in
the world and you realize that fucking
money that you spent or that loan that
you got is not getting you a job and
you're fucked and you can't get a job
and you're also massively in debt and
severely depressed and trying to
figure out your future. I mean,
Missy go on Adderall and you're like,
we're setting people up. We're setting
people up for a horrible failure.
I am with Bernie Sanders in that I think
education should be free and I don't
think that's a bad thing.
I think as you burn it,
I think you should have to earn it.
How bout if education is really cheap?
Like everything else is getting cheaper,
ma? Well, I mean TVs are really cheap.
[inaudible] more expensive.
I think we could pay for it with taxes
or maybe wrong or the individuals could
pay for maybe the individuals
because cheap and if it made sense,
if it made sense.
I mean if you want to learn
something now we know this very well.
If you want to learn anything now
you can get it for free on the web.
You definitely can do many things.
I mean other than physical things,
there's a lot of physical things that
you need to be taught by a coach,
but I think there's a lot of things you
can learn online and even the physical
things, you can get a big chunk of it
from online tutorials. I mean let's,
let's talk about all that matters. Okay.
Let's talk about juggling. You know,
I grew up as a juggler when
you were doing the TaeKwonDo,
I was juggling all the time.
That's all I did and that was
my whole life was juggling.
And what happened was with the internet
juggling gut tremendously better because
people could watch videos of things they
knew were possible and get better if
juggling get better.
Physics certainly can.
It seems like you can take a course at
any college online and if you sincerely
want to learn, you know, I don't know
if we need to have this, what is,
what does the term called when the,
when the Amish take their one year of
Rumpelstiltskin assessment from spring
program spring.
I don't think we need a nationally tax
subsidized Rumspringa for every person
in the country. I don't see what it
is. Right? Yeah. You go to college,
well you just described we do
the dah, dah, dah, dah, dah.
It seems like live your fucking life.
There isn't this four year magic period
or there's two year magic period and go
out and learn the stuff you want
to learn. I mean, um, you know,
we both have children and they'll be
talking about going to college and of
course my, my, well not of course,
but my wife will push very hard for
college and my thinking is anything they
want to learn they can, they can
just learn it. Yeah. You know,
by the way,
this was also true with just
the libraries in local towns.
It's just more true now. It's
even easier now. You know,
I can't imagine growing up where my,
my son can type in Lenny Bruce and
it all just pops up. Right? I mean,
that was amazing. Store
order it, order it.
They didn't grip into Griffin's
music store in Greenfield,
Massachusetts did not have the Carnegie
hall concert right there in the stacks I
had to order. All right. Frank Zappa
on the back of one of his records.
Menches Lenny Bruce and
he's on Sergeant pepper.
I guess I should learn about him.
Um, uh, let me write that down.
That's how I learned
about Terrence McKenna.
I learned about Terence McKenna from
listening to a bill Hicks record. Yeah,
yeah. I was like, who is this McKenna
and what's a heroic dose? And at,
at Frank Zappa, one of his
records, I forget which it is,
I think it's freak out, but it might
be absolutely free. Says on the back.
Do not listen to this song until you've
read Franz Kafka and the penal comedy.
Ah, I got the record, opened it up.
It said that I listened to one side,
got to that song, got on my bike, rode
down to the Greenfield public library.
Kafka. I've got this written down.
Kafka in the penal colony, sat there,
Reddit went back, listened to the record.
My entire education starts with Mike
Nesmith of the monkeys who said,
listen to Zappa,
listen to Hendrix from Zappa to Lenny
Bruce from Lindy Bruce to the whole world.
And I believe that, uh,
that is available to everybody all
the time. I mean, I don't know,
as I would say tax players should
pay for college. I think I would say,
did we need college?
Isn't that fade in a way?
I think there's a real benefit to
being in a classroom with a brilliant
professor. Yeah. Yeah. I think there is,
but we're also seeing with Ted talks,
which I know are jive, but there
is a, there's all these, you know,
their job, you, there can
be a lot of jive Ted talks.
There's some jive Ted talks. Yeah. Yeah.
But what I'm saying is I went to
one of the first Ted conferences and
[inaudible] and got to
hear, um, you know, um,
all these credible people speaking.
It was mind blowing and I wasn't
college age. I was, you know,
I was whatever I was 45 or
something 40. And it was,
it was an amazing spirit.
Jonas Salk, you know, I sat
and listened to Jonas salt talk.
I know I've been in a room with brilliant
people speaking and it's really,
really great, but I think we can,
we can deliver that cheaper.
And that's the side that Bernie
Sanders I want to talk about. It's not,
can we give endless amounts of money
to these fucking people on college
campuses?
Can we pay them all the money in the
world to take our children and give them
something to do in between smoking
dope? Could we rather just say,
can't we make this experience cheap enough
so that anybody can go and experience
it? Why don't you, why?
Why isn't it possible for you for a
few bucks to go and be in a room with a
brilliant person?
I think that would be a thing that would
be beneficial to almost anybody at any
point in time instead of the rigid
structure of like, you know, this is,
you know, you have to get all this
work done by X amount of time.
That's the other thing that
happens to kids too. They're,
they're taught about having no sleep
and about beating your body up and about
cramming and about getting all this
work done in a short period of time.
They're really,
we're really preparing them for a horrible
job and all this shit that doesn't
work, you know, all that weird,
that weird kind of hazing shit that
we do for medical professionals.
You're going to work for, for a fucking,
never weren't saying it's terrible for
the patient if we're bad for everybody,
you know? So my thing,
you just made the argument about the
frontal cortex and you're not really ready
to your 25 [inaudible].
What are the huge advantages I had in
my life was a shitty, shitty education,
horrible education. You
know, I went to a bad, bad,
bad public school that had an influx
of hippies from UMass that came in and
experiment that on us. So we
had no education whatsoever.
I graduated from high school
on a plea bargain. Uh,
I had very good, um,
S a T so I had scholarships
to wherever I wanted to go,
but I chose not to because
I misunderstood Bob Dylan.
I didn't know he was lying.
So I went and hopped trains and
hitchhiked around and lived homeless for a
couple of years and I never read
Bowlby Dick till I was 45. Thank you.
If I'd read Moby Dick when I was
supposed to would call the JJ,
I wouldn't have gotten it.
But I was able to get it at the right
age and now it's my favorite book cause I
was ready for it. You know,
there's so many things that are on the
curriculum that are very, very important.
Maybe not that day.
I think there's also an issue with people
not thinking of education in terms of
like that it's a lifetime for sure.
It's not something that you graduated
from college and then you're done.
We really should be educating ourselves
throughout life shorts and not just
accidentally or
incidentally by experiences.
We should do it because there's things
that we pursue that are interesting now
is one of the greatest times ever to do
that because of audio books that you can
do it while you're in the car. You
could do it while you're on the train,
you can get educated and you can also,
they're doing this weird connecting
thing where I've not
experimented with this,
but I'd love to where people take courses
online and then find people who are
also taking courses online in their
communities and then immediate like a
fucking Starbucks to discuss what
happened before, uh, in the class,
which is mind blowing that that can
happen. So you can take, you know, uh,
one of my huge, I mean,
one of the things I wanted to do is I
wanted to learn to play jazz and let it
play upright bass.
I took that up at 45 and I learned to
play upright bebop bass passably a huge
accomplishment. And now I really
want to learn a language, you know,
so I was looking at a little bit,
cause I figured maybe there's a
government watch list I'm not on,
so I should learn Arabic.
No, that was my thing. Cause
don't you think that that,
that ticks all the boxes that's
going to give me everything. Yeah.
If I just learned Arabic.
So I started looking
to how I can learn how I
can learn Arabic and uh,
it's amazing the kind of network that's
developing all over the world to be able
to learn anything. So my argument
with you, uh, on, uh, on the, uh,
on the Bernie thing of paying for
everybody's college is I think we can get
college so fucking cheap. You can
go to college your whole life. Well,
I don't think that's a bad idea, you know,
if it's possible to get called that cheap.
But I don't want professors
to be poor. I mean,
I think one of the real problems we have
with public education is that people
don't want to be a teacher because Patriot
teachers don't get paid much. Sure.
But there's, there's a way, there's,
I would say that's government
intervention that's doing that.
I would say if you, government
intervention is keeping the salary.
I think so. Really?
I really think so because I think that
we're not having enough of the, of the,
of the, of the competition is
stuff there. I mean, um, you know,
you, you would pay good money to be in
a room with the Steven Pinker, you know,
and I think that locally, this was always
a problem that I'd never figured out.
You know, when I was in Greenfield,
Massachusetts, a town of 20,000,
I would say to all the other, uh, by
other high school students, I would say,
you know,
if we didn't give our money to the rolling
stones and the Beatles and Dylan and
all these other bands,
we could pull our buddy together
and have a really good local band.
We could have a great band
right here in town, you know?
And I think that if you
thought of education that way,
can't we get in our little area really
great teachers, you can teach this stuff.
It might be pretty
[inaudible]. Well, it'd be okay
using if we could spread education
right through any, any method,
whatever we can do, if we can
encourage people to be more educated.
But I think that one of the best
ways to do it really is just, look,
there's a lot of podcasts
that are educating people.
There's a lot of information
that you can get and it's minor,
but it's what getting is, where
there's more information
available now than ever before.
I think it's very different than
what colleges traditionally colleges.
A thing where you go and it's
a Rite of passage. It's like,
and we don't have those in this world,
and I think we could do with them.
I think we could do with these rights,
particularly for young men. I don't mind,
and maybe it's the case for young
women, obviously I never was one,
but when you're a young man,
there's this transitionary period where
you're a boy and then all of a sudden,
am I a man yet? Like when am I a man?
Certainly a lot of, a lot of cultures,
religions have done that.
Getting thrown into getting that
certificate and getting your diploma.
Holy shit, I graduated from
fucking university. I'm a man now.
I'm a grown up. I have a degree.
I'm a woman now. I have a degree.
I am an adult. And you're obviously,
you know, uh, I'm, I'm seeing this,
you know, it's okay to speak
with an accent. It's not
okay to hear with one. Uh,
I'm hearing that from someone who spent
an awful lot of time explaining to
myself and others why I didn't
go to college. You know,
you wanted to show you weren't
a loser. I didn't have that.
I didn't say I went to Ringling brothers
Barnum Bailey greatest show on earth
clown college. You know what I
mean? If you want a big shore,
you don't get respect. That's where
you go. Well, I'd say I talk about it.
It's just cause I want people to
really know where my head was at.
I don't want to like glorify
was when I was in college,
I went without any right of
passage at all. Right. You know,
and the closest I had to a right of
passage was earning my living. Well,
the trust. Huge. You were also,
you were on a different pursuit.
Like your pursuit was the Carney
pursuit and you enjoyed that.
I mean there was like a, you have
how to lust for it, you know,
and it obviously worked
out well. Did okay,
listen, you really have to bale it too
because it has to occur around now. Yeah.
Okay. Alright. What are you doing?
You just hanging out. I'm no,
I'm going to go. Why do you watch this
show up? Perpetual grace limited. No,
never heard of it. Okay. What is it?
Um, uh, uh, did you watch show Patriots?
Nope. Okay. Um, best shows I have seen.
Are they fiction television? Yes. Okay.
Yes. Not the Patriot. Not Mel Gibson.
Put a show called, what's
it on? A Patriot is on, uh,
Amazon prime member. They used to be
like 20 shows and you knew all of them.
Now there's millions. It's
impossible. Uh, so I am going to uh,
meet and talk to the guy who created
all, all of those things. Oh,
there it is. That show grace. Yeah.
Perpetual grace. They're in Israel. Oh,
okay. And I know that dude, what's
that dude's name? It's Ben King's lads.
Right.
And then that's Jimmy Simpson and that
guy to the left is Jimmy Simpson there
guys. Great. I never knew who that guy
is. He's just always awesome. Yeah.
What was he in recently? He was in
something really good. That's right.
Westworld. Steve Conrad is
the guy who writes, directs,
produces, creates these
shows. And uh, I uh,
he happens to be in town and I'm
going to talk to him for my podcast,
which is Penn Sunday school.
I'm going to go to another studio and
talk to him and I'd already set up the
time. So nice at the camp B,
a change that Amazon's doing
all these different shows.
They're getting into the standup comedy
world now too. Yeah. It's crazy. Yeah.
Huge. Huge amounts of beautiful.
There's so many places with this.
So much stuff. But there's so many
places to put that stuff. Yes. Beautiful.
And wow, what a great time.
We got to do this more often.
We got to do this more often. This
is the first time we've done it.
How is that possible? This podcast
is almost 10 years old. Yeah.
Is the first time you've been crazy
and also cause people yell at me.
That's a Twitter thing. Go
talk to Joe Rogan. You asshole.
This is how fast time's going.
When I did your radio show,
I didn't have a podcast that
was more than 10 years ago.
That fucking crazy and crazy flying.
Let's promise to do this once a year.
Can we do that? At least let's do it.
Okay. Thank you, sir. Thanks a lot, man.
Thank you. Bye everybody.
[inaudible]
[inaudible].