Um,
uh,
Christine,
we're live.
Hey,
how you doing?
We talked a lot before this podcast.
We even said we weren't going to talk.
We're like glitch.
I don't want to talk to you too much.
A lot of stuff's talk about,
but Dan,
we got into everything.
Christie Brinkley,
fibonacci sequence,
any robbins.
Tony Robbins.
We covered a lot of ground crime.
Um,
boyfriend's as dogs,
as protective dogs.
Yes.
Protective.
Um,
how did you get to become a life coach?
Oh Gosh.
It wasn't the worst.
No,
no,
no.
It's just a long,
it's not,
I never planned on it and I don't really
even like that
got cooked at home.
What's a good name?
I haven't come up with a better name for
it and let's come up with right.
Maybe by the end of the show we'll come
up with something better so that,
that's,
that's your job,
Joe.
I've got my new title by the end of the
show.
So I started out in Hollywood actually.
I moved out after college to La because
mainly because growing up I was teased a
lot.
I was massively insecure.
And if you've got something to prove,
Hollywood's a great place to come to
came out here to like,
oh,
fucking show you.
I'll show you.
Yeah.
I,
since I didn't fit in,
I didn't have a lot of friends and boys
didn't really ever like me unless they
wanted to cheat off my paper.
I became addicted to achieving and
that's like,
what can I be?
I want to be somebody.
Like if only I was somebody.
Oh yeah.
How old was I?
Yeah.
Oh Gosh.
When it started,
ten eight something like that.
That's when you started like wanting to
prove yourself.
Well,
that's one,
not
teasing started happening and that's
when I started to feel like I didn't
really fit in and I needed to find a way
to feel worth something.
So overachieving kind of became my way
to do that.
And then at 10 I was diagnosed with
depression and put on Prozac at 10 I
know that's what we'll bookmark that
combined.
And so from a very early age,
I really thought something was wrong
with me.
I didn't fit in.
And so I had to come up with these
compensatory strategies to feel worthy,
to feel validated,
to feel like I mattered.
And so I just became like straight a
student addicted to achieving,
went out to college route,
grew up in Texas,
went to northwestern,
graduated early and was just committed
to moving to Hollywood and working my
way up as an actor.
I mean,
as a kid I was an actor.
I tried that for a little bit and then I
was like,
Whoa,
this is way too much rejection.
I can't deal with this.
I want to go on the other side of the
camera and pursue this career in
Hollywood.
And I didn't know what exactly I was
gonna do.
I thought I was going to be a producer
or something like that.
But I came out,
I was 20 years old and I applied to the
William Morris Agency to,
you know,
being assistant.
They're like,
you have to go through the training
program,
which is like pushing mail carts around.
And I did not want to do that.
So somehow I got a desk like really
early and started working for the head
of TV packaging and quickly learned I
did not want to be an agent.
Like it just didn't like it.
It was crazy long hours.
I was treated poorly.
It was just a hellish job and it was a
lot of selling.
I didn't really,
I don't like that either.
So I left and actually went and worked
on the man show I did.
I was thought maybe I'll like
production.
So first season as demand show I was
there,
which was kind of a blast.
And also just crazy.
It's a crazy show to work on.
I mean Jimmy and Adam were always like
super awesome to me,
but I was,
you know,
a young girl,
pa running around there,
the dancers were everywhere.
Like I just,
I was like,
what am I doing here?
So I quickly got out of production and
then started in comedy development at
paramount and started scouting comedians
and going to comedy clubs and finding
people that I could represent and bring
in,
maybe get deals for them.
And that quickly transitioned to moving
to another company where I was doing
comedy development and then I quickly
fell back into being an agent.
So that was like my first career was
like going to comedy clubs late at
night.
Um,
Eddie F two I think you know was your
first client.
Yeah,
he was my very first client.
We still keep in touch.
He says hi.
And that was like my life.
So here I am now 24 25 working at a big
agency representing clients.
I was the youngest female agent like in
the department,
maybe even in the city at that time.
I don't,
it was really young,
got promoted really,
really super young and I was dating the
head of a movie studio and I was living
this amazing Hollywood life,
like making a lot of money,
going to the Oscars and Golden Globes,
private jets,
hanging out with celebrities.
Like I totally had it all,
but I still wasn't happy.
It was like I had achieved one thing and
then there had to be the next thing and
then I just leave this and then it had
to be,
next thing you know,
I'd get the guy,
I still wouldn't be happy.
I get the promotion still.
I was on that constant chase and nothing
ever was like doing it.
So about two years I did this job,
I'm still on antidepressants.
I'm also taking antianxiety pills at the
time and just like trying to like manage
my life.
And I was one of those people that I
could really look good from the outside,
I could seem like I had it all together
and the inside was a totally different
story.
It's Kinda like a duck on water,
you know,
it looks smooth,
but underneath it's like that's,
that was what I was like.
And you know,
a lot of people ask me about how to
achieve all this and still like suffer
from depression.
And I was a very functional,
depressed person.
Like a lot of people think if you're
depressed,
you just lay in bed all day and watch,
you know,
soap operas or something.
But that's not the,
that doesn't,
you know,
summarize all depression.
Like there's different ways it shows up.
And so I was able to live my life,
but I always felt like something was
missing.
I always felt like I wasn't enough and I
just had this heavy,
heavy energy and an and nothing I could
achieve whatever,
filling that gap.
So let me keep going.
So,
uh,
one day I was riding up in the elevator
to work and I had basically a mini panic
attack.
I just,
I couldn't breathe.
I got off the elevator and I just
couldn't catch my breath and was looking
at,
there was a lot of weird folk painting
and art in our office and I was looking
at the weird photos and the one outside
of my desk was this woman in a negligee
who is nine months pregnant in this huge
yard sale with a Ufo light shining down
on her about to take her up
and I'm moving again at this painting.
I feel like that's me.
How did I get you
here?
And I just,
I wa I went back down the elevator,
walked around Beverly Hills and then
came back upstairs and I just wanted to
quit.
All I wanted to do was quit.
I thought that was the answer.
It was just I could quit my job and
reinvent myself and start over,
but I needed someone to give me
permission.
And so I called my dad because my dad
is,
has always been there for me and like,
Dad,
I really want to quit this job,
can I?
And He did a really good dad thing,
really pissed me off at the time,
but it was a good dad move.
You want to guess what he did?
Told you get your shit together.
Hello?
Said I love you but I can't make this
decision for you.
That is a good dad thing.
Yeah.
Get Dad thing.
And he hung up and I quit the next day
and that was the first really big risk I
ever took.
Why did you feel you are the pregnant
woman with a Ufo about to take you off
in a flying saucer that
Pelican fused and lost and like,
I didn't fit in and like chaos and it's
all wrong.
And how did I get here and what has
happened?
Isn't it crazy that Hollywood has so
many stories?
I mean,
not obviously,
not exactly like yours,
but so many stories of people who were
rejected and who have decided they're
going to come here to prove something or
to get the love that they need.
And what do they run into?
They're in the business of rejection for
every,
most people don't really think about it
because most people don't act.
But if you try to act,
you have to audition.
And if you audition,
you're going to audition with hundreds
of other people.
They're all trying to get the same job
and they treat you like hundreds of
other people were trying to get the same
job.
It's the weirdest thing and people leave
and they're just devastated.
They're so confused.
They get nervous before the thing and
then they leave the thing and they feel
so helpless.
Yeah,
it's the,
it's a strange,
strange business.
Yep.
Really is and it's,
it's so often not based on talent.
No,
it's so often not based on who's the
best person for the job and that's what
frustrated me as an agent.
And also one of the reasons I left the,
had a deal that I put together,
he was actually involved in it and my
boss made me attach a show runner who
like nobody wanted and,
but he needed the police,
that client and it killed the show and
it killed these guys.
The opportunity
all the time,
all the time in the US.
When I took over the man show,
there was a showrunner that there's
this,
this weird incestuous sort of fucking
business in Hollywood of connecting
people.
It's almost more about being social than
it is about anything else.
It's about making these relationships
almost like politics.
You become beholden to these people and
you get them jobs and they get you jobs
and you all just feed off of each and
y'all suck.
It really happens a lot.
It happens a lot with comedy writers.
Yup.
There's a lot of comedy writers that are
just,
you know,
they're,
they might've even been on Seinfeld or
something,
like a great show and there's a few
brilliant writers and there's a few that
are like,
what in the fuck is this guy doing here?
Well,
his agent is this guy's agent and that
guy's agent force this guy in.
If you get that guy,
you get this guy too.
And they make these deals.
Exactly.
And that's what was so frustrating for
me is I'd have these really talented
people and I couldn't,
I couldn't get them jobs.
Why did they put you on Prozac at 10
did?
Were you an only child?
No,
no,
no.
I was the oldest.
You're the oldest.
How many kids?
Just to,
and I think,
you know,
my,
my parents loved me a lot and they just
were doing the best they could and they
were listening to doctors.
You know,
it was a time when,
if a doctor tells you something,
you listen,
what was bombing you out?
Like do you,
like what did,
what was it the point where they were
willing to put you on medication?
Well,
I think I went from,
when I was little,
I was really outgoing and talkative and
happy.
And then when the teasing and bullying
started to happen,
I completely just shut down.
Like I shut off a particular group of
people that did it to one girl and then
it like kind of bitch.
Well she's the one I wanted to mention
when I won my Oscar that was,
oh,
you wanted to get up there and say this
is right.
You know?
Eventually I got over that.
Uh,
but I just,
I really just shut down and withdrew.
And
so it was just like,
did you move to a different school or
was it just one particular kid?
They wanted me,
my parents were like,
go to a different school,
honey.
Like,
yeah.
And I just wouldn't,
I was,
I was stubborn and I wanted to stay and
I think I was just scared,
you know,
that's the thing,
like,
oftentimes what we know that's,
that's bad is safer,
feel safer than what we don't know that
might be better.
I had a comfort zone and where I was
like,
even though I wasn't really happy,
like I knew that school,
I knew,
I was afraid that if I went to new
school,
I would just have to deal with the same
thing.
So I was just like,
I'll just stay where I am.
Isn't it crazy that you could run into
the wrong person when you're 10 years
old and it can fuck you up for a decade
or two?
Yeah.
But I think we,
I mean,
I don't know any human who hasn't had
something in childhood or adulthood or
whatever that is.
We can call bad jamie.
We'll get them perfect.
Nothing's ever went wrong.
Nothing's ever gone wrong with you.
Just wait.
It's coming in too
smooth and calm young.
Jamie's collected.
Yeah.
No,
everybody's had difficulties.
Yeah,
it's unavoidable.
But the w the,
the bullying thing is very,
it's,
it's very strange how prevalent it is
and how it seems to be a part of human
nature that people have some strange
desire to find someone who's weak or
who's insecure or who is,
and then literally go after them and put
yourself in front of them and fuck with
them and,
and ruin their life.
Their,
she,
let's go get her.
Like that kind of shit is,
it's a weird natural pattern that human
beings follow.
And I've always wondered like,
we need to talk to Gad sad about this.
Like what is the evolutionary basis for
that?
Like what is it about people that makes
them want to do that?
Especially young people.
I don't,
you know,
and I think it's different with the way
girls do it in the way boys do it.
How do girls do it?
Girls?
It's a little more sneaky and I think a
lot of times it's based more on jealousy
and that might have like,
I don't know,
that might have some unattractive,
no,
I think that,
um,
I was,
I was smart.
School came easy for me.
The teachers really like me.
Parents liked me.
And so I think that that might have had
something to do with it.
And again,
I don't know,
you know,
it's 10 like I have no idea why they did
what they did,
but it was more sneaky like passing
around notes saying I joined the,
I hate Christine club and like having
everyone sign it and,
and just kind of quietly doing it behind
my back and,
and pulling all my friends away where I
think boys are just more aggressive.
Like they'll,
they'll beat you up,
they'll put you in lockers,
they'll do that,
that kind of thing.
But I think it's just a,
a power thing and you know,
within every bully as a scared little
boy or little girl.
So it's just,
I think how we're always,
not always,
but so much of the time we're trying to
compensate for something,
you know,
where we feel less than where we feel
insecure.
We think if we can just have power over
something or somebody else that's gonna
make us feel better.
There's also a thing that happens when
like the,
I hate Christine Club thing where the
other girls were probably like,
I don't want to be on the end of that,
so I'm going to join in.
Yup.
You get,
you get scared that they're going to go
after you next and you want to be on the
mean team.
I think that's what's going on with
Donald Trump.
I really do.
I think that's a lot of the reason why
people are with him and,
and,
and for him,
he's,
he's so vindictive and mean and he,
the way he goes after people,
I think you see a lot of people support
him and sort of like,
like cower to him.
Yeah.
Like even that Megan Kelly chick who's a
super brassy Badass ice princess,
she did that interview with him after
they had their little thing when she sat
down with them and she was,
she was so like submissive.
Who was weird.
It was,
I mean,
maybe we should try to keep her job.
Maybe Fox News,
right?
Or the riot act,
I don't know.
But it was really bizarre to watch her
tone down.
Do you ever see it,
see the followup interviews this year?
She didn't call him out on anything.
Thanks.
You just not really,
no.
She was really submissive.
Hmm.
It was,
it was not what I expected it was.
It was very orchestrated.
I mean,
I think it was kind of obvious at that
point.
I don't know if he had,
he was the nominee or he was on his way.
It looks like all the other nominees
were falling apart.
Yeah.
And um,
she did this interview with her and him
sat in some office room,
like sat across from a table and it was
like,
they're like,
people are scared.
Yeah.
People scared of,
of,
you know,
the,
the strong man or the strong woman,
you know,
the,
the person who's going to go after you
or the unpredictable,
like I think Donald is so unpredictable.
You never know what he's going to throw
at you.
And He,
yeah.
He will go to whatever length he needs
to go to,
to humiliate,
to make you feel less than to,
to throw you off your game.
Yeah.
You know,
so probably was just like,
I better just,
well,
he just,
he sues so many people and so many
people sue him.
He's,
that's his world,
you know,
and that's,
that's like a normal thing for him.
If he doesn't have a bunch of lawsuits
floating around the world,
he probably feels like nothing is even
happening today.
You know,
they're going to got to get something
going.
I got to sue somebody.
That's crazy.
But I think that,
that,
that is one of the reasons why people
like are attracted to him because they
don't want to be on his bad side.
I think people are terrified of him,
you know,
super billionaire,
very famous,
big,
powerful guy.
I think,
um,
there's a bunch of people that,
uh,
like with this,
I hate Christine Club.
If there was this one mean bitch.
Yeah.
That just wanted to go after you.
There's probably a bunch of people that
would want to side with her just because
they're scared that she's going to turn
on them and start going after them next.
I think that's probably right.
Yeah,
for sure.
Right.
It's total,
it's,
it's a tribal thing.
It's good.
Becomes this weird like that.
So that's our leader now.
You got to,
you know,
yeah.
A lot of leaders are the most vicious,
mean,
nasty,
terrifying people.
You know,
look at the dictators in Russia or Putin
or Kim Jong.
Ooh.
Or what are they known for?
The dictators and a lot of these Middle
Eastern countries,
they're fucking ruthless,
ruthless people yet.
And everyone's scared of him.
So they all go behind them,
you know?
Yep.
Better to be behind them.
Then you go up against them to feel the
wrath.
Yep.
Yeah.
I think fear is a big motivator,
unfortunately.
Yes.
And it I think impacts our ability to
really think clearly about something
because we're just so scared and so
threatened that we,
we stopped questioning,
wait a second,
like what is he really saying?
What does he really leading me to?
Yeah,
yeah.
Cause that's the thing with Donald and I
talked to people who support him.
I'm like,
but do you,
do you,
do you understand?
Like he would have more money if he
would have just like taken the money.
His father left him,
invested it versus all the bankrupting.
He's done.
I mean,
the keys,
there's just so much that doesn't make
sense about him yet.
I'm just like,
okay,
well
there's never been a man alive that
needs mushrooms more than Donald Trump
is.
There is.
I haven't heard of them.
I mean,
I'm sure.
I'm sure there probably has been,
but he needs him.
I think he needs to go straight to the
Amazon.
Yeah,
you might need to go right there,
but he needs something.
Yeah.
It's just he's,
he's almost like the super impulsive
hubris character.
Yeah.
You know,
everything is like a,
when Hillary Clinton says,
you know,
he doesn't pay taxes because she goes,
I'm smart.
Like he can't help.
Like you're on the deer out of fucking
debate on TV.
Yeah.
You said you're smart because you don't
pay taxes.
Right.
Me Reflect,
reflected me.
It's not just him,
like,
it really reflects like where we are as
a society,
that enough people support him to get
him to the place that he is.
I think we're so polarized right now and
like,
look,
I don't really love either candidate,
to be honest.
I just don't.
But I think that,
I hope that maybe this is just wishful
thinking that we'll have four years of
whoever it is.
I think it will be Hillary,
and then in the next election we'll have
people that we're actually excited about
supporting and voting for.
That may be,
but I don't see those people anywhere.
Yeah.
Do we want for the job?
Exactly.
What one wants the job.
That's the problem.
It's a crazy job and it's a job where
the just try to destroy you if you run
for it,
you know,
and you're seeing that with,
with trump and you're seeing that with
hillary and they're pulling out all the
stops and by the time it's over,
the opinion of the commander in chief,
it's going to be terrible no matter who
wins.
Right.
I mean there,
I mean that crooked hillary thing is
going to stick forever.
Hashtag Crooked Hillary,
it's going to stick forever.
And People's opinion of him is horrible.
You know?
It's no matter who wins and she's going
to win,
most likely.
But it's not good.
It's not good for any of us.
Nope.
It doesn't represent what we think of
the United States says we think of the
United States is being this unbelievable
place of creativity and innovation and
the greatest super power of the world's
ever known.
And this,
you know,
it's really progressive force for good
in the world.
And you know,
I don't know,
maybe we need to go through this time
though to shake it up a little bit.
Maybe things need to get bad to get
better.
I mean,
and I see that in human psychology so
much do you need,
you need to hit rock bottom.
You need to go through these hard times
to have something better emerge that
maybe that's just wishful thinking.
No,
I think you're probably right.
I think we also needed to understand
because the wiki leaks,
um,
revelations,
like how exactly politics is run even
with the people we think that are the
good folks.
Like it's all fucking gross and dirty
and all the stuff with the Clinton
Foundation and all the stuff they did to
Bernie sanders and they conspired to
keep that guy out.
And there's,
I mean,
he's a Democrat too.
There are whole,
the whole thing was supposed to be about
who is the person that best represents
the people with the people choose.
But now the Democratic National
Committee was fucking working to make
sure that Bernie Sanders wasn't the guy.
Yeah,
and they were all conspiring with
Hillary and they're all pulling favors.
This is like we were talking about
before with producers and networks.
It's the same shit.
It's just using your power and your
influence and all the friends that
you've made in all the years and all the
favors and pulling it together.
But now we're being exposed to it in a
way that we haven't really,
since Watergate.
Watergate gave us like a little window,
a tiny little window,
but the access to information was so
minuscule back then.
Like we clung to those 15 minutes of
whatever,
Watergate tapes,
whatever it was.
And we were like,
look at this.
Oh,
I'm not a crook.
You know,
like he,
he was doing what they were all doing.
He just got caught and we got a,
we got a sense of it now.
But now when you read these emails about
how they really feel about each other
and all the fucking gross nist that goes
on and
oh no,
I try to not engage too much in the
gross ness cause it's just like what's
the point?
Guess the point is to understand what
the world really is about.
What the structure of government that
looms over us is really all about.
Why are certain things legal,
why a certain things illegal,
why are certain loopholes in place,
how did they get in place?
Who benefits from them?
What is a charity?
And if it is a charity,
how come you get paid so much?
Yeah.
Like how come you get paid $250,000 to
speak and then all this money goes to
your charity.
But that $250,000 goes to you.
But you just talked for an hour.
Like this is a scam.
But that's the thing.
Like you're asking,
you're being curious,
you're asking questions.
And I think that's helpful.
I think what so many people are doing
are just getting mad and just trash
talking America and the the candidates
and,
and that doesn't do any good for
anybody.
If you want to like ask questions and
get involved and start to get curious
and quest,
that's,
that's awesome.
That's how we change things.
But I think too much of this has just
been so emotionally driven that people
are just getting upset and not really
going,
Huh,
what can I do?
What can I learn?
How can I shift this in some way?
Yeah.
It's also people are like super psyched
to get behind their candidate,
their team.
I got to tell you like there's a lot of
gross this on both sides for sure.
There's a lot of gross on the trump
side.
There's a lot of mean assholes that have
finally found another mean asshole
that's run for president and they're
pumped like he's one of them.
But then there's a lot of men who are
using Hashtag I'm with her and they're
the grossest little fucking white
nights.
Oh my God.
I've run across a few of them on
twitter,
like the White Knight.
You don't know what a white knight is,
how dare you.
You really don't know like a knight in
shining armor.
Yes.
A man comes along,
it comes along and positions himself as
the superior morally superior to call
Michael Shermer calls.
Virtue signaling.
If someone who would would say,
you know,
Hashtag I'm with her Hashtag male
feminist,
you know,
Hashtag [inaudible] that's real.
There's a lot of those out there.
Yeah,
they,
they're trying hard.
They couldn't get laid in the other way,
and this is,
this is the strategy there was the
strategy is to position themselves as
the super progressive.
Yeah.
It's like people who don't want you to
think that they're racist,
so they go out of their way to
discriminate against white people,
other white people when they're white.
I read this thing with this woman was
saying,
if you are a white person and you were
up for a job and you are up against a
person of color,
do period not period,
take that job.
You don't deserve it.
Examine white privilege.
I was like,
oh my God,
what Liberal Arts College do you belong
to?
What fucking crazy shit is in your head.
Like what?
I don't get it at all.
Do period.
Not Period.
Take that job.
Hi.
Yeah.
Well you don't have to get it.
We went on a tangent and went off.
We were trying to find out how you
become a life coach and all of a sudden
you're talking politics.
Yeah.
White Knights.
I love it.
I lockers.
Jets.
Yeah.
And now,
now I know a whole new understanding of
white nights.
Well,
I always understood it as you know that
the man who's going to come in and
rescue,
that's that.
But they're positioning themselves as
that.
But that,
yeah,
I think we're a couple decades away from
all this going away because I think
technology is going government going
away,
all bullshit,
all bullshit and lies.
This is where ups,
so I really believe this.
I think technology is going to enable
just like no one anticipated.
You know,
as you can go back to the f,
the first days of cameras,
if you went to act in the 18 hundreds
and they first had a camera,
yeah.
No one would have ever thought did in
the lifespan of just,
I mean what was the first camera,
Jamie?
Like 1860 something like that.
Like civil war era was like the first
cameras.
No one would've ever thought that in two
lifespans,
which is essentially what it is.
From then to now,
you would be able to send video to
Australia instantaneously from something
that slips into your pocket.
I think it's like stop
to think about how much we've seen in
our lifetime.
Yeah,
I think we're just so used to it.
Yeah.
We're so used to google and the
Internet.
When Hillary Clinton was a telling like
Donald Trump said something and she's
like,
Google it.
Google what?
He said,
it's not true,
and I was like,
how hilarious is that Hillary Clinton is
telling people to Google Donald Trump?
Like,
like that's,
that's how beautiful access to
information is today.
Yeah.
I think we are a couple of decades,
maybe a little bit more away from a
completely new paradigm,
a completely new way of accessing
information.
I think we're going to submit to
something,
whether it's a neural implant or some
sort of a augmented reality,
and we're going to be able to read
intention and thoughts.
It's going to be,
there's not going to be any lying and on
a hundred years.
I really believe that.
Totally think you're right.
And I think that's why we're seeing so
many of these systems breakdown,
like the presidential election,
which,
which used to be this coveted amazing
thing.
Now we're kind of looking at it as like,
it's,
it's a reality TV show.
That's what it seems like now.
It's all pussy grabbing,
craziness,
craziness.
That's the,
I mean,
I just believe that
first,
like 20 minutes in the second debate,
oh,
I had been out of the country for a
month,
which was so refreshing and to come back
and I watched it and the first 20
minutes was just character slams.
It was nothing about nothing about the
issues or anything.
And I was just like,
what?
What's,
what's happening?
That doesn't make me happy.
Like,
it doesn't make me feel like if he shits
on her or she shits on him and she tears
him down,
it doesn't make me feel like she's
better.
I liked her in one of the debates
because I didn't tune into it until the
last like hour and he was saying a bunch
of crazy shit and she would start
laughing.
I was like,
that's how she should handle him.
Yeah.
She should handle him like he's a child.
Like if she did that,
but she's fucking crazy too.
So change depending president.
Another tangent.
Lots of life coaching.
Get that.
How do,
how do you go from,
all right,
so when you're were mad at both of us,
by the way,
I'm sorry.
Shoot about poetics.
Yeah.
How about you just shut the fuck up.
I will totally own that.
I,
that's not my area of expertise.
So guess what?
Nobody knows shit about politics.
Even the people doing it.
That's why Donald Trump's running for
fucking president.
Nobody saw that common.
You know what?
Nobody understands this stupid system.
Yeah.
But You understand life coaching or
we're going to come up with a better
name.
So life coaching.
Yes,
but so the way it happened
is,
um,
all right.
So I quit my job,
which threw me into an even worse
depression because that was my whole
identity.
Like it was my success in being an
agent.
And so then in a period of,
I don't know,
like six to eight months,
a bunch of things happened,
I went into lots of debt because I tried
to keep up with this lifestyle.
I,
um,
was a strange for my family for a bit,
cause I made a choice that they didn't
really like.
And I got diagnosed with another
autoimmune disorder on top of everything
else.
And then I was engaged and thought,
oh,
I'm going to be a wife.
Like that's my next role.
I'll be fine.
And then six months before my wedding,
he dumped me culturally.
So I it not,
you know,
I know people listening have been
through worse,
but in that like span at 26 years old,
losing my career and money and family
and health and love,
it was kind of like this sucks like
this.
I really didn't know what to do.
And I had honestly a moment on my
bathroom floor,
which I don't know why it was on my
it was disgusting,
but she was laying there.
It's a good spot to cry.
The tiles are nice and cold,
you know,
it feels very dramatic.
And I had this like kind of insight,
I guess you could say of how much I was
relating to everything as a total victim
as like everything was happening to me.
And then it dawned on me,
I'm the common denominator in like all
of these situations.
So either I have just really bad luck or
I have some influence over this.
And again,
like it was just a teeny bit of an
insight,
but it was enough of a new perspective
on my life that kind of got me off the
bathroom floor and started to give me
some kind of hope and started to make me
realize I needed help.
And like I,
the way I was doing my life wasn't going
to work anymore.
And so I found,
I thought I was having a quarter life
crisis and I found a book by that name
and I read it and it was fine,
but it wasn't going deep enough for me.
So I decided to write a book about my
experience and everything I was learning
and um,
how I like was getting myself off my
bathroom floor,
I guess.
And I was interviewing people for the
book and they kept saying things to me
like,
can I set up a session with you?
And I'd say,
why?
I got all the information.
And they said,
why aren't you a coach or a counselor or
something?
And I'd say no.
And they said,
you should be,
should be.
And I kept hearing this over and over
and over again.
So I went to my coach and kind of my
first teacher who I met when I was 22
and I was still seeing,
and she has had a major impact in my
life.
And I said,
Mona,
you know,
everybody's telling me I should do this
and I've been looking for my career for
you know,
years and maybe this is what I'm
supposed to do.
She's like,
Yup,
that's what you're supposed to do.
And I go out,
I've been coming for five years,
like,
why didn't you tell me this?
And she said,
you know,
you had to figure it out,
you had to find it.
And so that's how it just started.
Like people kept reflecting back to me,
hey,
you're good at this,
he should do this.
And I didn't really know how or what.
And so then I just became,
I started studying it,
I prentice with her,
I got training,
I got a master's degree,
I wrote more books.
And it just sort of happened out of my
own life and out of just creating things
that I thought would help people and
people going,
actually this is really helping me and
can I talk to you more?
And that was,
you know,
a good 10,
11 years ago.
Have you pushed some mic forward a
little bit more and make the sounds
sorry.
It sounds good in your ear.
Just the recording.
It will be.
We got it.
Isn't that an interesting thing that um,
it's oftentimes small choices that
people make that dictate what happens to
them in their life.
But if you just decide that things are
happening to you,
you don't take any responsibility for
any of the choices.
That's to me the biggest difference are
people who are able to change their life
and people who don't is ownership is
realizing that yes,
things happen but we're not victims and
anything can happen.
But you,
the same exact thing happened to you and
I,
and we can make different choices about
what we make it mean and how we respond
to it and we're going to create
different results based on that.
So it's not what happens to people.
It's not just luck.
It's truly what are you going to choose
to believe about it.
And that's to me the key differentiator
between staying where you are and kind
of regressing as you get older and just
repeating your familiar patterns and,
and repeat life and more stubborn and
all those things.
And you know,
just looking for those short term bursts
of happiness and like a trip or a bottle
of wine or whatever versus like really
getting clear about how you can change
your life,
what your purpose is,
what brings you joy and like who you
really are.
There's a thing about life coaching to
or any,
but I mean just to forget that word,
but the idea that your dispensing advice
or giving out inspiration or you know,
writing things down that have affected
and helped enhanced you.
People want to dismiss that stuff.
Like,
oh,
I don't need that.
Oh that's nothing but right.
I feel like one of the best things about
being a part of a community or being a
part of a culture is that you get to
look at all of the things that people
have done,
that it benefited them,
and all of the,
the,
the positive choices that someone has
made.
And you can learn and experience those
without having to go through all their
bullshit.
Yeah.
You know,
and there,
there's a lot of things that I've
learned from people,
whether I've read things that they've
said or listen to speeches that they've
given about mistakes that they've made,
where I've come across a similar moment
in my life,
I'm like,
ah,
I've,
I know what this is.
I know what that is.
It's,
I think it's one of the best tools that
we have when,
when,
when it comes to improving and enhancing
your own life,
your own individual experience is
looking at all the different shit that
other people have done.
And it's,
it's a weird one because people dismiss
it so easily.
They don't,
first of all,
they dismiss it at a,
there's a certain amount of Hubris and a
certain amount of ego attached to it
where they don't want to admit they have
an issue or they don't want to admit
they need help or they don't want to
admit that they need to be inspired or
they need,
you know,
some sort of motivation.
I think it's,
yeah,
I think it's fear.
Yeah.
Back to that whole,
this life that I know is comfortable.
I may not like it,
but I'm so scared of uncertainty that I
don't want to make the changes.
People are terrified of the unknown.
There's also a lot of fuckery of foot
when it comes to life coaches and
motivational speakers.
And there's a lot of hosers like we were
talking about before the podcast,
about a couple hosers.
We know there's hosers out there and
those people,
but it's like everything else,
like,
you know,
there's bad car mechanics,
they'll put a used part in your car and
fuck you over this.
There's bad doctors,
there's bad everything.
Everything in this world as someone
who's half asking it.
Yup.
And the problem with that whole,
the idea of being a life coach or being
a motivational speaker is that there's
not really,
like,
you don't have to get a phd to do it.
You don't have to,
you know,
you don't have to like prove yourself.
Like Mike has opened up 15 different
businesses,
so he's going to show you how to do a
business like this.
The guy's a successful businessman.
That makes sense.
But there's a lot of people out there
that are doing life coaching that are
fucking failures.
Yeah.
And maybe,
maybe that's not the worst thing in the
world to be a failure because you've
learned from those failures and maybe
your achievement or your contribution is
expressing those failures and your
revelations from those failures and that
could help somebody else not make those
same mistakes.
Yeah.
I mean,
I think I've had a lot of so called
failures and mistakes.
Um,
did you ever have one of those like
bathroom floor moments?
So it's like life pivot.
I'll a man,
first of all.
All right,
so check on the floor,
right?
Yeah.
I mean,
um,
no,
all bullshit aside.
Yeah.
There's always,
um,
for,
for a comic,
the big one is bombing.
Bombing on stage is devastating and you
start thinking like,
I can't,
I can't do this.
Like you can only take so many of those
bombings in your life.
Yeah.
It was like getting beaten up.
You can only get beaten up so many times
before,
like your brain stops working.
Right.
And there's that relationship breakups
for sure.
Um,
devastations I think are always the best
for a rebirth.
Yup.
And at the time they don't feel like it.
No.
And devastations went to anything
devastating the habs do in your life
while it's happening.
You feel like,
I don't know if I can take this,
but then you get through it and you have
this sort of enhanced perspective and
then you also,
we live in an amazing time where you can
see,
you know,
not that you should revel in other
people's failures,
but you could like,
look what most of your failure is.
Nothing in comparison to what's going on
in a million like Syria or million
different parts of the world that are
just filled with fucking chaos.
Yeah.
Most people can't see that because you
see your life and your wife is all,
you know when your life is falling
apart.
Right.
Well and I think too,
you know,
we get so kind of narcissistic and our
problems that we forget the bigger
perspective and we don't,
a lot of people talk about being happy
all the time you should be.
And I just don't think that that's real.
I think that you,
I,
I've grown and I through contrast
through,
you know,
I,
I think I really understand happiness
and joy because I've really understood
depression and sadness.
Like that polarity I think is such a big
part of what we're here for.
Yeah.
I mean you can look at,
you read a book about different parts of
the world and what's going on.
You,
if you're still happy,
have to read that book to something
wrong with you.
You know,
like probably shouldn't be happy all the
time.
There was actually,
I think it was scientific America or
something like that that had an article
recently saying,
you're not going to be happy all the
time and you shouldn't be.
And there's a,
there's a reason for it.
There's peaks and valleys in everything
in life.
Yup.
And that I,
you know,
for people listening that might be in
one of those valleys,
it's like,
don't try to just get through it,
really ask,
you know,
why,
what can I learn from this?
That was my biggest thing is I stopped
asking why is this happening to me?
And started asking what can I learn?
Yeah.
So instead of painting yourself as a
victim,
you paint yourself as someone who
present in the moment and just,
okay,
I don't want to do this anymore.
Right?
Let's figure out what's going on.
Exactly.
And we don't,
a lot of times we don't have the tools
and that's where things like life
coaching and personal development come
in handy is Chris,
we can go and get those tools instead of
using our old coping mechanisms by like
being strong or overing,
overworking,
overdrinking over,
do,
you know,
jumping into a relationship,
like whatever it may be.
We,
we don't really learn how to deal with
disappointment,
failure,
anger,
or shame,
any of those things.
And so we're kind of left to these quick
fix devices that I think that's a big
reason addiction is such a problem is
because we don't really learn how to
manage emotion and how to manage
disappointment.
And so we go for that thing that makes
us feel better in the moment.
But the problem is we have to keep
upping the ante.
You know,
at first that one glass of wine does the
trick,
but then you need to,
then you need three,
they need vodka,
whatever it may be.
And so,
I mean,
why I'm so passionate about what I do is
first of all,
I never,
I never thought I could be happy.
Like I really didn't.
I thought that this,
you know,
I,
I was going to be depressed and I just
was gonna constantly be looking for
something to fix me.
I never really truly thought this life
that I'm living now,
what is possible.
Again,
externally things look fine.
But internally I'm talking about a
totally different kind of experience and
it's only because of those like really
awful moments.
I call them expectation hangovers,
that I was kind of desperate enough to
let go of my normal coping mechanisms
and my trying to control everything.
It was like the ultimate and surrender
truly of going okay.
Like I don't,
I don't know.
I need to find a different way to deal
with this.
And that's really what has led me down
the path that,
that I am today.
So,
you know,
I,
I think that life coaching and the
personal transformation industry and all
that,
like you said,
there's a lot of,
what'd you call him?
Hoke hokies.
Yeah.
Hosers oh,
sorry,
sorry.
It's Bob and Doug Mckenzie.
I don't even know who that is.
Fucking 1980s siren live character.
Oh,
coach posers.
They're from Canada.
Oh my God.
He hoser remember those guys.
I don't know why.
Why hosers learning all these words.
This is great.
Why hoser I don't know why that,
I hardly ever use that.
I don't know why it popped up.
I love it.
I want to go back to the the PROZAC.
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
Cause I'm super picky.
Your parents put you on that stuff when
you're 10 years old.
I think it was more the doctors.
Okay.
Your doctors,
your doctors put you on that stuff when
you were 10 this old block tests and ink
blot test.
Yeah.
You know,
what do you see a demon?
Yeah,
exactly.
What do you see?
Death.
Yeah.
What do you see?
A skull?
I probably said things like a butterfly.
I know that bitch.
I hate from school.
We'll fucking axe in her head.
So the doctor puts you on Prozac and
what kind of an effect does that have on
you?
I mean,
I actually helped.
It really helped.
I think it helped me.
Um,
I,
gosh,
it's so hard to remember too.
I mean,
I was 10,
but when I talked to my parents about
it,
they're like,
you know,
it did help because I really do think
that because of everything that
happened,
you know,
my brain chemistry did shift.
You know,
I do think that we can shift our brain
chemistry with repetitive thoughts and
you know,
I had enough thoughts about,
I'm not likable.
I had just intense inner critic in my
head.
And I do think that shifted my brain
chemistry.
And I do think that the medicine helped
me at least get to a point where,
you know,
I was like kind of awake again.
How long does on tank?
I don't remember,
but I know that,
you know,
especially in my twenties,
like I'm still on it.
Oh Gosh.
I was on it until 30.
Yeah.
I was on every,
from every,
I was on Prozac.
Welbutrin yeah.
Um,
years 20 from the time you were 10 so
all through high school you run that
stuff?
Yep.
Wow.
I,
I believed that I needed it just like a
diabetic would take insulin.
So how long ago did you get off of it?
A seven and a half years ago.
Wow.
And,
and like,
totally,
I,
I never have any regression or dips,
but I did,
I was super intentional about getting
off of it.
I didn't just stop like,
especially after 20 years,
it took me a while.
It took a lot of the emotional work that
I was doing with my coach Mona,
because he know so much of depression is
suppression,
so,
you know,
and all that stuff was happening.
I,
I think I was pretty angry about it,
but I had no outlet for that.
Especially as a girl.
Like boys again can go out and get stuff
out.
But a lot of times,
and this is why I think so many women
get irritable and bitchy and all those
kinds of things is because women,
we don't have like that outlet for
anger.
And so we internalize a lot of that.
Like we can do sadness but anger a lot
of times get suppressed.
And so a lot of like me getting off my
medicine and not feeling depressed was
not being suppressed by exercise.
The exercise is okay,
but until you like go back and actually
process the emotion,
I mean exercise is good in terms of
moving the energy,
but a lot of times you have to attach
like the feeling with the movement,
right?
So like a lot of my retreats that I do
where I just bring women,
I facilitate like an anger barn for them
where anger burn,
what does that,
it's like a safe place for women to get
their anger out.
Like,
and it's not just catharsis.
Like there's a whole kind of process
they put them through so they like,
you know,
kind of reconnect maybe earlier life
experiences where they didn't feel
protected or they felt unsafe or they
felt,
you know,
abused or whatever that is.
Because again,
like this is just,
this is all comes from my own life
experience in working with,
Gosh,
thousands of people at this point.
Like I,
I see over and over again.
People that are depressed,
shut down,
have a lot of anxiety,
not happy with their life,
have some like unprocessed thing from
their past that just needs to move.
And when I create this space for people
to start to move that energy,
it's like underneath there is creativity
and passion and peace and freedom from
anxiety and all that kind of stuff.
So when you're looking at me like
he's looking at me like,
who is this girl?
Um,
so when people have that space to
unleash that and to let the energy move
through them,
because I think there's a difference
between emotion and feeling.
So feelings to me,
our physiological responses to thoughts.
Okay.
So if I sit here and think about the
future of that I'm scared about,
I'm going to feel anxiety.
If I have like,
oh my gosh,
what if like someone breaks in my house
tonight,
I'm going to feel fear.
You know,
if I,
I can,
I can feel regret because of a thought
or guilt.
But,
but emotion,
energy in motion.
If someone hurts one of your kids,
you're going to experience anger.
You know,
like it's a natural response.
Someone close to us dies or we have a
heartbreak.
It's natural to feel the emotion of
sadness.
And I think that there's a lot of kind
of misleading information about like,
oh,
we create all our feelings with our
thoughts and we can just like affirm our
way out of things and think our way out
of things.
And to some degree that's true.
Changing our thinking does a lot,
but with some core emotions like anger,
shame,
sadness,
I think we've got to feel them.
And I think that that's what people are
really scared of is actually kind of
opening that box,
opening that can of worms and going back
and actually feeling those feelings.
But the thing is they're in there and so
if you don't get them up and out in a
healthy way,
then I think that's what creates a lot
of depression,
a lot of depression,
perhaps,
maybe even disease,
things like that because they just get
stored in our body somewhere.
It makes sense.
So what do you do to these gals?
What do I do to these gals?
Um,
I,
it's just creating a space that just
scream,
well,
no,
it's not a pillow fight.
No,
it's not that I give them,
I definitely give them something to hit
with like him,
those foam noodles,
you know,
that you do.
I do.
And Oh gosh,
the comments to this,
I'm going to be crazy.
I can't believe this,
but here we go.
So I,
um,
and I put on some pretty intense music.
And again,
I don't even know,
not slayer,
slayer after slayer,
it's more like,
it's more like metallica.
Metallica is on my playlist.
I'll,
I can pull up my place later.
They really want to see it.
Um,
you have a beat the shit out of a foam
roller.
Oh,
for sure.
Yeah.
Cool.
Or burn or burn playlist.
Yeah.
Well,
I'm telling you actually.
So one time I was doing this,
I rented a house actually out in the
near here,
a Gore and people were doing this
process and again,
like I prepped them like the,
you know,
I,
they,
they bring to mind things that they've
maybe,
like I said,
like we're angry about things from their
childhood,
you know,
it's not just like a throw them in a
room with loud music and say go after
it.
Right.
They're very,
there's a lot of processes I put them
through to get them to this point.
But anyway,
so we're doing this one time in this
house and there's like 20 women,
loud music,
yelling and um,
the cops show up
and
the guy's like,
um,
what do you like?
What's going on here?
And I step out,
I stepped out and I explained,
I said,
you know,
a lot of times I,
this is a women's workshop and a lot of
times,
you know,
we,
we hold back our emotions and you know,
we end up getting irritable and this
just as healthy way for,
you know,
people to,
to heal and work on their emotions.
And the cop looks at me and he's like,
um,
can I have your card?
I want to send my wife.
No kidding.
That's what the cop said to me.
So there's,
I've gotten lots of calls from husbands
and boyfriends and even kids and like
thank you because there's something
about,
it's like pulling off our armor
honestly.
And there's something about doing like
the deeper work and kind of going to
those scary places that takes a layer
off of us,
I think.
I mean it's,
it's similar to plant medicine and a lot
of ways of like going to those places
where they're kind of like,
hmm,
where are you?
Come out the other side and you have a
deeper understanding of,
of yourself.
Um,
so by doing something completely
ridiculous and crazy and just letting
loose and all the madness involved with
it,
it's almost like a reset
for,
yeah,
yeah.
Yeah.
And it's not,
again,
like it's facilitated,
it's not this,
this crazy,
you know,
people going into fight screaming.
It's not fight club.
It's not because there's a difference
between Catharsis and like actual right
processing stuff.
But it's just,
and again,
I think we,
we don't really understand emotion to a
certain level and we think that big
emotion is crazy and it's not
necessarily,
I think what is crazy,
what makes people crazy is suppressing
it their whole life and trying to manage
it through their mind or through doing
things or through whatever else versus
actually like being willing to look at
those parts of ourselves because we're,
you know,
we're humans.
We have a mine,
we have emotions,
we have actions,
we have,
you know,
our spiritual self,
whatever you want to call that,
like something that's connected to
something bigger than us.
And I think we need a holistic approach
to really gage.
Now,
from the time that you decided to get
off of the antidepressants,
did you follow a protocol?
Did you go to a doctor to discuss it
with them?
Did you read anything about how to do
that and what advice would you give to
anybody out there that might be
listening that also is going through
that same sort of situation?
Um,
doctors told me I couldn't do it,
so
I have good doctors ever stay on and I'm
getting paid.
Exactly.
Um,
so I had,
you know,
my coach at the time,
he was really helpful who was more than,
again,
like coaches such like a,
I don't even know what to call her.
She was,
how did you find her?
I was dating a guy who was an addict and
complaining about him to girlfriend at
lunch for like the 80th time.
And she said,
um,
pill,
no drugs,
like coke,
alcohol,
maybe pills and the pills to fun times.
Good Times.
Hollywood.
Yeah.
Was Super Great.
I was popping xanax while he was doing
all that.
So anyway,
I,
um,
and I've totally lost my train of
thought.
Oh,
how'd you find your coach?
Oh yeah,
yeah.
I had a find a coach.
So we're sitting at lunch,
I'm talking about this for like the 80th
time.
And she goes,
I can't,
I can't listen to this anymore.
I went and saw this kind of Kooky woman,
go see her.
So,
and I had been like to shrinks my whole
life and I had never been to like a
coach.
I had always been to therapists and
psychiatrists and so nothing against
therapists and psychiatrists,
they do good work.
Um,
but I had kind of like reached my limit
with it.
And so I go to this woman's house and
she's like,
it's totally stuck in 1985,
like her decor,
her fashion,
everything.
And I sit down and I sit across from her
and she didn't even see me in a normal
office.
I think she knew she needed to be like
totally get me out of my comfort zone.
So she put me in her son's bedroom with
like these race car,
bunk beds and I'm sitting there on this
race car,
bunk bed,
the going,
where am I?
How did I get here?
And she walks in,
she sits in front of me and it was the
first time in my life and I felt loved
by my parents,
but this was the first time in my life I
felt really seen.
Like it was almost uncomfortable.
Like this woman could almost see through
me.
She could see me,
she could really see me and I felt zero
judgment from her,
like zero.
And although it was scary and a little
bit because it was like kind of,
I felt very vulnerable.
It,
there was something so reassuring about
it because she was the first like
practitioner I had seen that didn't see
me as broken.
She really just saw me and she was the
one that in so many ways helped me over
the years get off the medication by
teaching me how to release my emotions.
Um,
by helping me understand that,
you know,
bad feelings aren't necessarily bad.
I also got very clear about my diet.
Like I got off gluten because a lot of
times gluten can impact brain chemistry.
Um,
I stopped drinking and it wasn't ever a
big drinker,
but I stopped drinking for about two
years because alcohol's a depressant.
I'd always been into exercise and
fitness and eating healthy and
everything like that.
Um,
and then I also started meditating and
like finding some kind of connection to
a higher power.
I didn't really have a name for it at
the time,
but something where I didn't feel like I
was so alone because that was kind of
one of the scary things about
depression.
You feel you feel alone a lot at the
time.
And so it was a combination of all of
those things that over time and the
belief that I could,
and I really had to change my belief
that I could get off of them.
Um,
so for people that are considering it,
um,
don't just stop.
Like,
it's dangerous just to stop because that
can really mess with your brain
chemistry.
Find somebody who knows something about
this and can put you on a plan,
can help you.
You know,
I'm,
I'm not a doctor.
I'm not here to get met,
get give medical advice.
So,
you know,
consulted doctor.
Um,
but for me it was number one,
the belief that I could and number two,
finding the people that could really
support me.
And number three,
making the lifestyle changes that I
needed to make to support it and being
willing to go to that dark,
scary place that I was afraid to go to.
What do you mean by when you say that
she was the first person that didn't see
you as broken?
Well,
how do you,
what do you mean by they all,
they all saw you as broken?
Well,
I think
when,
you know,
for me,
when I would go to one of these doctors
or therapists,
I mean they'd see that I was on
medication since I was 10 and um,
they kind of relate to me in that way
as a depressed person.
No,
just more like,
like I had a label like this is it,
you're depressed.
And so that's why they weren't willing
to consider,
are you getting off of the medication?
I felt like the is a part of who you
are.
You got to accept it.
It's a daily thing.
It's like brushing your teeth,
you're not going to stop.
Yeah,
maybe.
I mean,
I don't even know what they were
thinking was just know how it felt and I
just did it.
Maybe it was because like at the time I
didn't believe it yet either.
Maybe I need to someone who believed in
more than,
I do think that also the people that
deal with people every day,
whether you're a psychologist or a
psychiatrist or whatever,
that you're so inundated with people and
their fucking problems that after a
while you just become overwhelmed and
it's very difficult to see people like
can have a fresh reset every time you
see something like this is a new person.
Her name's Christine.
Hey Christine,
what's going on with you?
Yeah,
I think you're right.
I think it's therapists,
psychiatrists,
they have hard jobs.
Like imagine your whole day is person
after person talking about what's wrong
with their life.
You know that that can be very draining.
You know,
even when I first started as a life
coach and I saw person after person
after person,
I really had to learn not to take that
on.
And not to let it drain me.
Um,
so again,
like I have a lot of respect for their,
at my mom's a therapist,
so I have a lot of respect for
therapists and psychiatrists are very
helpful to me.
I just think for me in my life journey
and what I wanted,
I,
I just,
I didn't want to spend the rest of my
life medicated.
I just really did it.
Yeah.
So what is the difference between life
on medication and life off medication
and how long has the process of weaning
yourself?
I mean,
I think it took me,
it took me a good two years to feel like
it was finally kind of out of my system.
Two years.
How long was it before you were actually
stopping taking it?
Um,
well I,
I,
Gosh,
I can't remember exactly,
but I think I,
I probably weaned for a good six months
and then it was like a year and a half
till I felt like it was like cleared out
of my system.
Wow.
So for six months you slowly wean
yourself off of it and then at the end
of six months you're not taking the
medication anymore,
but you still feel foggy.
Like what do you feel?
Okay.
Yeah,
I was,
it was,
it was like my system was recalibrating,
you know,
all my brain chemistry was recalibrating
and you know,
cause that stuff affects your brain
chemistry.
It affected my hormones.
Like it,
it just,
you know,
it effected a lot.
Yeah.
So did you take like one pill and then
cut it down to three quarters of a pill
and then
I did consult a psychiatrist and um,
they gave me like a winning plan.
So yeah,
whatever at different people,
like it's not a standard thing,
like different psychiatrists will tell
you different things.
So it depends on what dosage you're on,
how long you've been on it,
which medication you're on,
what the side effects for for it are,
those kinds of things.
What does it feel like when you're first
day no pills?
Do you remember that day?
I remember the first day I woke up and I
felt clear,
like I felt like
I don't want to get kicked out of here.
No.
Um,
like,
like it was like out of me and I was
oh my gosh.
Like I just felt like a fog and a
heaviness had lifted.
It just fell.
And I also felt like
I had deeper access to my creativity,
my intuition and all those things were
present,
but it was just,
there was just sort of like some white
noise there.
And I also like for me,
depression manifested as being
incredibly self critical,
like super self critical,
like this very,
very,
very loud inner critic.
And so that started to lift too.
But again,
I was doing all kinds of other work at
the same time.
You know,
I was studying with my life coach,
I was getting a master's degree in
spiritual psychology.
I was a spiritual psychology.
Yes,
good question.
So,
um,
it's a place called the University of
Santa Monica and I didn't know anything
about this place,
but I had been a life coach and I
thought,
okay,
if I'm helping people with their life,
I've got to know how to help them deal
with their past.
Like I can't just work on present and
future without like having some skills
for dealing with your past.
And so I was researching schools.
I thought if I could get a master's
degree in psychology that would help me
and that would be good for my career and
all those things to have like some
credentials.
So I researched and I find this school
and I didn't really know anything about
it and I'm like,
this is great.
And the spiritual part didn't have
anything to do with any religion or
anything like that.
It was more of the premise of you know,
that that traditional psychology is,
is kind of a little bit more about like
labels and spiritual psychology is more
people have the inner resources they
need to to heal.
And I didn't,
again didn't know much about it.
Show up at this school with my laptop
thinking I'm going to like take notes
and there's going to be lectures but it,
there are no desks.
It was a highly experiential school.
It's like I said a two year program and
in that I really learned how to um,
change my belief systems.
He'll stuff from my past connect to a
part of me cause we all have like our
basic self,
like our conscious part.
But I believe we also have something
deeper like art,
we can call it our intuition,
we can call it our gut feeling,
we can call it our authentic self,
but there's some kind of inner wisdom
that I think all of us have access to.
And this program really helped me get
more access to that,
that part of me so that I could start
listening to that more than my old
conditioning.
My old belief system is my old fears
because you know,
when we're born we're kind of this blank
slate and then stuff happens.
And we formed these stories about our
lives and who we are and how we get love
and how we get validation and how we get
acceptance and how life works and who we
are and our identity.
And it's kind of a just a story.
And we have,
we can change that story,
but it takes work going back and
deconstructing that story and letting go
of some old beliefs that maybe we've
hung on to,
to create a different one.
So that's,
that's what so much of my journey has
been about is kind of looking at what's
the story I've created about my life and
how can I change it?
Because the story that I had was I'm
depressed,
I'm,
you know,
have to be achieving all the time,
being hard on myself as how I motivate
myself.
So on and so forth.
I'm constantly rejected,
blah,
blah.
And by believing that story,
it was creating results in my life that
align,
that aligned with that.
And so to create different results,
I had to have a different story to tell.
And so there's this shift that that has
to take place.
And it's,
it's like turning a battleship,
right?
It's not,
it's not a quick thing.
It takes a long time.
No,
it's,
it's not.
And I think that's another,
um,
kind of let downs people have when they
go to a seminar or read one book,
they expect to change overnight.
And it's a,
it's a process.
Do you remember the secret?
I do.
There was a girl,
I've told this story before,
but she was so nice.
She's friends with my friend Kelly,
Kelly Carson,
you know,
Kelly corrosion comedian.
Funny girl.
Anyway,
uh,
she was at the comedy store one night
and,
uh,
she was,
she was talking to Kelly and,
uh,
I was talking to her and she started
going on about her future,
all the things that she was going to do.
She was going to be married within a
year.
She was going to have the career that
she wants.
She was going to this and that and that
and this.
And,
uh,
I was so confused and she was like,
um,
I found the secret I'm doing,
you know,
do you know about the secret?
I go,
oh,
uh,
the power of positive thinking,
I that kind of thing.
She's like,
it's,
it's not just that,
it's not just positive thinking.
It's like you do create your own future.
You create your own identity.
You create,
you know,
you,
you create reality.
I was like,
okay,
like you sure?
And she's like,
yeah,
I'm sure you know I'm,
I'm positive.
Okay,
good luck.
I'm like,
boy,
the problem with all that stuff,
of course,
if you've never heard of it,
is what do they,
what?
What is the,
the,
the term for it.
They're trying to achieve law of
attraction.
Yeah.
What,
what they're trying to achieve is
they're trying to like,
you take the a photo of your dream
house,
you pin it on your wall,
you take a photo of a Ferrari,
you pin that on the wall.
You're going to get those things.
The problem is when you watch those
videos,
when they say,
you know,
I had this photo of my home on the mall.
I had the Ferrari that I wanted.
I had my dream life.
Now I have those things.
I made those things happen with
intention and with thought.
Do you know how many fucking people have
a photo of a beautiful house on their
wall and a Ferrari?
And they got no fucking house and they
got no Ferrari and they never will like
you.
It's,
you're taking it from a biased pool of
successful people who will tell you that
this happened to them.
But there are literally millions of
people who think positive and nothing
ever happens to them.
So this girl who,
um,
was a very nice person,
uh,
she came to one of my shows like a year
later and a were hanging out outside and
I go,
how's everything when you're doing?
She's like,
well,
it's really a drag,
you know,
because I was convinced that by this
time I would have all these things.
Yeah.
But you know,
my dad,
he's still,
you know,
fuck up and this and that and I've got
this problem,
that problem and I just don't understand
it.
I don't understand it.
I believe that I was so sure.
And we had this like,
really,
it was really interesting because she
was like two different people.
Like I'd met her twice.
Right.
So I meet her this one time and she's
just a glow with this delusion that now
she's got it and she's getting,
she was,
she thought also that talking about it
all the time was part of how you affirm
it.
So she was saying,
you know,
I'm going to be married in a year.
I'm going to do this.
I'm following the secrets.
She kept saying it and it was whoa.
And then a year later she was just,
I don't get it.
It didn't work.
And so we had this sort of heart to
heart about it.
Haven't talked to her again.
And I don't know what the hell happened
to her,
but I'll never forget it because the two
different people,
the,
the girl who was like,
it was like kind of crazy,
like all why I didn't believe in.
And then a year later,
year and a half I think just wasn't
happening and life was still kind of
shitty.
And she was,
she couldn't understand why the career
didn't happen and alive didn't happen.
And it's is all,
it's a slow shift.
It's a slow shift and I think the law of
attraction can be misleading because
it's more,
you know,
change takes more than I put a picture
up and I do some positive affirmations.
If like down deep,
you don't feel like you're worthy,
um,
or you're,
you're not going to be able to attract
those things.
You've got to like kind of go back and
deal with core issues and core beliefs,
systems in order to shift things in your
life.
I mean,
if it was as easy as putting pictures up
on our wall,
everybody would have,
you know,
Lamborghini's and hot and wives and
husbands.
So,
but it takes,
it takes more than that.
It takes being willing to like do some
work and take some responsibility rather
than just thinking the universe is Santa
Claus and just was going to pop
something into your life.
I acquainted
to people that are morbidly obese that
want a six pack.
Like it can be done,
can be done,
but God damn.
Yup.
You got a long road.
You know,
if you want to climb Mount Everest and
you're starting in Santa Monica,
you gotta fucking get to Mount Everest.
Absolutely
right.
Absolutely.
And then that's when people ask me how
you get off antidepressants?
I'm not like,
oh,
I just did this and then I did this and
then I did this.
It was,
it was years of like,
you know,
deciding I was going to and having the
right people around.
It wasn't,
it wasn't an easy thing.
It's probably the hardest thing I've
done.
No.
Now what is the difference between
antidepressants and like Xanax?
Like when you're taking,
you said you were taking both.
Yeah.
Why do you need the Xanax if you're
already pilled up on the
antidepressants?
I mean,
again,
not an MD,
so not my territory,
but for me like I,
the antidepressants just kind of kept me
steady.
But then with my boyfriend at the time
and my crazy Hollywood life,
like I just had so much anxiety and you
know,
you go to a doctor and you're like,
I have so much anxiety though.
Like,
do you want to say or how do you define
anxiety?
I'm like worried or not worried a lot
like kind of high,
strong.
I'm not able to calm down.
Um,
yeah,
just that just normal like anxiety,
but I didn't have tools then my tools,
then we're medicine.
Mm now had better tools.
So now do,
do you take anything?
Nope.
And then supplements,
supplements,
vitamins and stuff.
Vitamins.
Yeah.
I'm super like I love human hacking and
human optimization.
I'm,
I love exercising.
I love meditation.
Meditation.
I take Alpha brain,
like all that stuff.
Okay.
And you,
do you ever miss it?
Like is there ever a time when we're
like,
God damage my pop,
Xanax and fucking drinking glasses?
No,
no.
I will say this though.
One,
I had my eyes Lasik,
Lasik,
the Lasik and they gave me valium and I
was like,
oh this,
I see why people get addicted to this.
This is incredible.
But I'm glad they did because I was
super freaked out about them cutting my
eyeball open and valium just relaxes you
rise.
I wouldn't done it felt great.
And then the only time I ever did it,
but no,
I don't miss that because what I have
now is,
um,
like I feel clear and alive and you
don't feel happy all the time.
I definitely have my days,
but I don't relate to it as I'm
depressed right now.
It's just like,
oh,
I'm having a normal,
like,
you know,
human experience and not having the
best.
I think stories like this is a very
inspiring to people and I think it's
very important in it.
We don't want,
it's,
it's like,
it's hard for people to look at people
who aren't doing well and talk to them
and just go,
oh,
I don't know what to tell Ya.
And,
uh,
good luck.
Let me get the fuck away from this
bitch.
You know,
like that's how people think.
Like I don't want to deal with her
problems are his problems are I wanna I
wanna I want to separate my and
concentrate on myself.
So I think when someone like you can
sort of express how you were in this
really bad state and yours is a very
bizarre situation because you're talking
about being on these pills from the time
you're 10 right.
That's,
that's really unique.
But then having almost a decade off of
them,
seven years off of them.
Yeah.
I'm a state.
And it's,
I,
I honestly think
it helps me help people.
Like it really does.
I've had lots of training as a life
coach,
but my own life experiences have been
the thing that's really given me the
most critics,
I guess you could say.
Well,
you credentials or that you're actually
happy.
Yeah,
I'm actually happy.
I,
you know,
I hate,
I've been able to create a life and a
career in friendships and connection
that,
you know,
I thought I no longer live that story of
that.
I Hate Christine Club.
I have great friends,
great women friends,
like all of that,
you know,
and,
and that's,
I,
I'm no like different or more special
than anybody.
It's just again,
choices and I made choices that led me
to this point.
And everybody has that.
Everybody has that freedom.
What's the book man's search for
meaning?
Have you ever read that book by Viktor
Frankl?
He was,
yeah.
um,
in concentration camps and he was
actually a psychiatrist,
I think.
But he talked about,
you know,
he kept himself saying,
and he kept himself free through his
mind.
And he says in between stimulus and
response,
basically what happens and how we
respond is a choice.
And in that choice lies our ultimate
freedom.
And I think that that's true.
That's,
that's what we all have.
That freedom,
no matter what your circumstances.
No.
When someone comes to you and they're
like,
Christine,
I'm all fucked up.
I need to get my shit together.
Like,
how do you,
uh,
how do you start with somebody?
But it's different.
You know,
everybody's different.
But is there anything that people are
universally could benefit from?
Is there,
yeah.
Yeah.
The,
the number one thing that,
where I start with people is having them
really look at their relationship with
themselves.
Because when they come,
they're like,
oh,
I'm fucked up.
Or I need help.
They're relating to themselves as if
something's,
you know,
something's wrong with them and they're
being really hard on themselves and
they've kind of lost hope and lost
belief in themselves.
So the first thing is just like
acceptance,
accepting where you are.
Because you know,
I had,
I haven't liked everything that's
happened to me,
but one of the main raise I've been able
to move through it is because I stopped
fighting.
It isn't that like in martial arts,
if a punch comes at you,
you're not supposed to resist it.
You're supposed to kind of move with it.
Yeah.
Move away from it or roll with it,
roll with it.
Right.
Like your teeth are your teeth and take
it on a job.
Exactly.
And in life we kind of do that.
We're like,
oh,
I don't want this break up.
I don't want this layoff.
We resist it,
we fight it.
And so it's like,
can we just get to acceptance of like,
okay,
where are you are who you are and what's
happening right now?
Perspective and perspective.
Yeah.
And when you can get to that neutral
place,
that's when you can start doing the
work.
And that's when you can start doing
different things.
And then the second thing is I ask
people like,
do you believe you can shift?
Do you believe that you have like the
power to make different choices and
change?
And you don't have to know how that's,
that's my job.
I'll help you with the how,
but you've got to believe you can
because if we don't believe it's
possible for us and it's really hard to
make any kind of change in our life.
Hmm,
yeah,
that is,
that is giant.
But how does someone believe,
like how do you get someone to believe
that they can make change?
Like do they have to see evidence in
themselves?
Do you,
is there like,
do you recommend like attempting things
or tasks or hobbies or,
right.
Well a lot of times it's going back to a
time in your life where you did take a
chance or you did do something that was
a stretch in some way.
Like everybody has times in their life
where they've done something they
weren't completely sure they could do.
Even if it's just a little thing and
everybody has that reference point they
can go back to.
But a lot of this joe,
like honestly a lot of it is taking a
leap of faith and I,
I've taken a lot of those and I've
wanted to know the answer and I've
wanted to know like 100% that this would
be guaranteed.
Like if I take this leap of faith,
everything will work out.
And I,
they haven't always been 100%
guarantees,
but it was in taking that leap and
taking that chance and having a little
faith that things started showing up and
things started shifting and that's what
started to create the evidence.
And it's a tricky thing cause I think
people want evidence before they make
change.
But you have to start making these
little changes,
beef to start having the evidence show
up.
I don't know if I answered your
question.
No,
that doesn't make sense.
Um,
I,
I've often said that very difficult
tasks.
Like a anything that's difficult that
you do?
Yeah.
It gives you the confidence that you can
overcome adversity and you can,
you can,
whether it's I'm a martial art thing or
something along those lines or marathon
running or anything.
When you do something like that,
these incremental changes happen where
you push yourself through things,
especially if you can achieve a goal.
If you could set out to do something,
you achieve that goal.
Like I'm going to run a marathon by the
end of this year.
I don't know why I keep saying marathon,
but you know what I'm saying.
Yeah.
It doing things along those lines,
they can be motivating.
Factors are,
they can help push you.
They can be the engine that starts to
push things in a positive direction
and you start to believe in yourself and
you start to believe,
oh wow,
like I can do this.
I can take this step.
You know?
I often tell people that show up or come
to a workshop.
I'm like,
just that fact that you're here is proof
that you believe you can change because
like you wouldn't have shown up if some
part of you was an,
you know,
kind of certain that you could,
have you ever had someone come to you?
You're like,
I can't even help this dude.
The girl.
No,
not yet.
No.
Do you get mostly dudes or girls?
Well,
I only coach a few people now.
Um,
my retreats are mostly women.
My private clients both.
And then my courses and stuff.
How can we have retreats that are all
women?
Not,
well,
I know,
I know.
I'm going to get,
I'm going to do on that.
Um,
will be both men and women soon and was
like a recipe for danger,
too.
Depressed people hopping in the woods or
wherever we're going first.
The one that everybody's depressed.
Some people come just to grow and like
the range means they're out in the
woods.
That's amazing.
No,
I like to do it in places like Bali and
Costa Rica.
This might be able to,
some people.
So I,
whenever I go to anywhere tropical,
I get eaten alive.
Alive.
No matter what other people have three
bites,
I'll have 400.
I finally figured out B one,
vitamin B,
one,
two.
It's totally stopped it.
You have to find it.
Like you can't take a b complex.
It's vitamin B one.
Huh?
And it's for some reason stops in
mosquitoes and bug bites.
I have no idea.
I just know worked for me.
It does something to change your smell.
I don't know.
It just worked.
It was my salvation.
I was so happy.
They don't bite you at all a little bit.
But again,
it went from being eaten alive to just
getting a few.
Did you ever try thermacell?
No.
What's that term?
A cell is a device that a lot of people
take when they go camping.
Things along those lines.
You,
um,
it's like,
uh,
it looks like almost like a radio and it
has these little pads and you slide
these pads into this heating element and
this very fine mist comes out of this
heating element.
You could put it on the ground near you
and the bugs won't come with an 18 foot
circle.
Yeah,
yeah.
Use it when you're hunting.
And you're in the woods because if
you're,
if you're in the woods,
like,
especially in Alaska or Alberta,
I don't know if you ever been to Alaska
in the summer,
the mosquitoes are insane because they
own their only alive for a month.
Oh,
so today's good at town like rabbit,
barbarian,
mosquitoes like me and my friend Ari
went fishing in Alaska and it was so
crazy that you would get out of the car.
We pulled up to this,
uh,
the stream.
You get out of the car,
you open the door and then won't,
you're hit with a cloud of mosquitoes.
We jumped back in the car and shut the
door and we were in the car with like 50
mosquitoes.
We were like,
what in the fuck is going on?
So then we're spraying ourselves well as
spray all these toxic chemicals that
found out about thermo cells,
dermal cells just,
it cleans it out totally.
There's an easy to travel with them.
Yeah,
they don't even,
they're really light.
It doesn't even smell.
I mean you barely smells,
but bugs don't want to have anything to
do with it.
Mosquitoes don't want to have anything
to do with it without thermacell was
like hanging out in the woods,
like sitting in a spot.
It's almost unbearable unless you have
mosquito netting and you don't want to
wear like all that mosquito bug spray
stuff and your,
your skin is an Oregon,
you know all that stuff that you're
putting on your skin.
It is just not good.
I was using my first couple
of days on my last trip and I started
getting sick and I'm like,
I can't.
This is like,
what am I doing?
And you're processing it with your
liver,
terrible skin.
It gets in your bloodstream.
Terrible.
Yeah.
I mean I'm sure there's probably some
nontoxic alternatives,
but they probably don't work then so be
it worked for me.
Hey,
b one you hear it folks five.
I've heard that before.
A friend of mine was telling me that
about Africa.
They went to Africa and they took a
bunch of b vitamins that did it,
but b,
one in particular did it for me.
Find anything on that.
Jamie,
I found something that said that studies
are inconclusive but it may make
mosquitoes.
Thank you.
Stink.
Good.
Perfect.
It's fine for me.
Dig it up.
I wonder if it's like a vitamin that
makes people think you smelt good.
People are mosquitoes.
People don't.
Yeah,
because if bananas don't eat bananas for
mosquito season,
don't eat bananas.
That makes sense it.
But I would think that like,
well it does probably like weird smells
that you're not even sure you did
attacked you.
Now some people just give off a weird
odor to people.
Yes.
I mean,
not even like a,
maybe not an odor odor,
but like they just feel weird.
You know,
they said that,
um,
Chris Ryan,
my friend of WHO's,
um,
he,
he's a author.
He wrote a sex at dawn.
Yeah.
He's great.
Yeah,
Super Smart Guy.
He was telling me that there's certain
odors that human beings have and those
odors enabled people to understand
whether or not they're genetically
compatible with each other.
And you know,
like they used to be when we were kids.
I used to always hear about couples
taking blood tests to make sure that
they could have babies together.
Yeah.
That was a thing.
That was a thing they would,
they would make sure that they were
compatible.
And I don't even know if there's real
science behind it,
but they would take blood tests to find
out they were compatible.
That was like,
I remember it being like really common
to discuss.
I mean it was,
this is,
uh,
the eighties or the nineties or whatever
the fuck it was.
The dark ages of science.
It was that easy,
right?
Yeah.
But not compatible obviously personality
wise and all the other things that come
into play.
But they were,
he,
Chris Ryan was saying that women can
smell a man's clothes.
Like you could smell,
literally smelled their clothes and they
would know whether or not they would be
attracted to that person based on the
smell that a person's getting.
Not,
not like,
oh my God,
this guy stinks.
But like literally like you,
your body knows what's repulsive and
what's not repulsive in terms of like
genetics based on someone's odor that
they give off on their clothes.
But what it didn't work is when they put
women on the pill.
Ha.
So when they put women on the pill,
they were no longer able to
differentiate whether or not someone was
genetically compatible by smelling them
that it gave you,
it fogged up your,
your natural senses.
Because I think when you're on pill you
don't actually articulate.
Right,
right.
So you're not in the natural rhythm of
biology.
Yeah.
I think there's a natural feeling that
women have when they're around a guy
that they would breed with or a guy they
wouldn't breed with.
Kay got to go,
you know,
like that and that is probably a good
thing.
And that people that are on the pill
might be making like really shitty
genetic choices,
like literally genetic choices.
Ah,
you can blame your last bad ex boyfriend
on being on the pill.
You could give us now I'm accurately,
I really think you can.
I mean it totally makes sense.
I probably,
Chris is probably listening right now.
Go and you fucked it up.
I probably did.
But I think there's probably something
to instinctual reactions to people.
Yeah.
Like,
I mean,
have you ever met someone and like for
whatever reason,
I just don't want to be around,
that's for sure.
And then you find out years later that
that person's fucking crazy or this or
that.
There's,
I think people give off in detectable in
terms of like what we classify as
smells,
but maybe these pheromones have some
sort of a weird reaction to your birth
control pills affects women's taste in
men.
Bam.
Wow.
How synthetic hormones changed desires
and women and their choice of a mate
intimate.
Yeah,
totally.
Makes Sense.
Interesting.
Yeah.
Well it just makes sense.
I mean it just can't be,
nor your body must be so confused.
Like this pitch is pregnant all the
time.
I know.
That's what it thinks.
Your body thinks you're pregnant all the
time.
I know.
That's,
yeah,
the pill scares me too.
Just synthetic hormones pumping through
your system.
Yeah.
Tim can't be all that good to never get
off.
But a lot of women never get off it
right there on it forever.
Yup.
Yeah.
I don't like it.
It makes my hair oily when I'm off it.
Yup.
Here's stuff like that.
There's other ways to balance your
hormones.
You know,
I'm not a hormone specialist,
but why does hormones make a girl's hair
oily?
I don't know.
I have no idea.
How do we get on the subject?
Smells.
Retreats.
You don't take dudes,
dudes on retreats.
Yeah,
I would think that like getting a bunch
of people that try and get their life
together and then having them all
together.
A male and female.
Do you run into these weird issues were,
you know,
they're really just trying to hook up?
Yeah,
exactly.
You can get really distracted and you
can get,
like if there's some kind of attraction,
you can forget what you're there for and
get obsessed with someone and,
and it can kind of throw off the thing
and there's something too about,
okay,
you know,
women coming together with women and men
coming together with men.
That I think is important.
And I think kind of back to that tribal
conversation we need,
I got a lot of women,
including myself,
have like beef with other women,
you know,
and they don't like being around just a
bunch of other women.
Like there's competition that comes up
and you thought,
oh,
well I used to because I was scared of
other women because I had all that stuff
happen.
I didn't really trust it.
Um,
and so when you get a group of women
together,
a lot of times there is that like
comparison and judgment and I can't
trust and did it.
And so it's important for women,
I think to gather together and kind of
do work separately from when there's men
there because there's something that is
very healing just in that.
And then you know,
it just,
there's a level of vulnerability that's
possible when there aren't men.
They're not to say that you can't be
vulnerable with men there,
but it's just a different dynamic.
And I think the same goes for Matt and
like,
I know man who do men's groups and men's
work and there's great value in that.
And that's important.
And I think one of the problems I see a
lot in intimate relationships is that in
a heterosexual relationship is that you
expect this one person to be your
everything and you're not,
you don't have a tribe and you don't
have a community.
You don't have friends of the opposite
sex in the same sex that are fulfilling
kind of these needs it that we all have.
We just project like this.
My one person has to be my everything,
my soulmate.
And so,
you know,
having your community,
whatever it may be,
and having different friends I think is
super,
super important to having a healthy
relationship.
Yeah.
Having friends period is super
important.
There's something that I tweeted today
that I was reading about.
Um,
they were talking about the role that
genetics and family have in creating a
personality and how much of an impact
your peers have and they think that your
peers and the friends you choose have a
bigger impact than anything in your
life.
Yeah.
And it was really fascinating.
I,
I tweeted this morning for on it,
but it's,
it's one of those articles where you
read it and you go,
oh,
that completely makes sense.
Researcher argues that peers are much
more important than parents.
That psychologist underestimate the
power of genetics and that we have a lot
to learn from Asian classrooms.
Interesting.
Yeah.
What about it?
What about Asian classrooms?
You have to go down,
scroll,
forgot what that was about.
I don't know.
Probably too long of an article to
really get into it,
but um,
we'd have to read it.
But peers in general,
I think I'm choosing likeminded folks
and choosing people that are on a good
path.
They,
it,
it helps support you and it supports
them and you feed off of each other.
And when the tribe does well,
you do well.
Exactly.
This is very,
it's very critical.
And people,
they,
everybody wants to be the person that's
accomplishing things.
Everybody wants to be the one,
it's out there.
Go get nit and fuck the world's all
about me.
But if you do that,
you like,
you're gonna,
you're gonna mess up the whole happiness
thing.
Like the happiness thing comes with all
the people that you're around having a
good time.
Absolutely.
Yeah.
And,
and then it's just like,
it's endless.
You have to keep upping the ante.
Yeah.
And I think what we want more than
anything is connection.
Yeah.
We want connection.
We want love what you want to feel like
we belong to.
So I think belonging is a huge,
huge,
huge thing.
And I think as adults we think we belong
by,
you know,
achieving things.
But really it's finding those people
that you can just be yourself
with and to have that tribe and,
and also let go of the people that are
bringing you down.
Like I've outgrown some people in my
life and some friends,
not that I'm better than,
but I'm just on like a different,
different path in a different route.
And it's important I think to kind of
know like who's the sort of dead weight
and your life and what are some
friendships that might have reached
their expiration date that,
you know,
like,
I love you,
that's been great.
But you know,
and a lot of those friendships,
like you're not helping them either know
you.
And matter of fact sometimes when
someone cuts you loose,
you go,
wow,
what the fuck is wrong with me?
Maybe I need to look at myself.
Right?
I mean sometimes when you enable a
friend,
you're not only,
you're not doing yourself any good,
right?
Not doing them any good either.
Exactly.
That was a big Aha for me when,
um,
my fiance broke up with me because I
very much like want it to be like the
victim in that.
But I had to look at,
Gosh,
what did I like?
What did I do?
Because everybody's like,
oh,
he's such a jerk,
Dah,
Dah.
But I really had to look at how was I
showing up in that relationship that was
impacting his decision because he wasn't
a bad guy.
Like he wasn't just a jerk who decided,
you know,
I'm going to break up with this girl.
Like there were ways I was showing up
that were,
that like made him make the decision
that he makes.
So I think in any of this situations,
friendship or relationship,
you know,
you don't,
you don't want to go too far the other
extreme and be like,
oh my gosh,
I'm a loser and think it's all your
fault.
But it's important to look at,
Jeez,
what's my part in this?
You know,
what's my responsibility because I
played a role in this whole thing.
Yeah.
They,
I mean there's no one way street when it
comes to relationship.
And if you're in a relationship with a
bad person,
like why,
why exactly,
why did you get in that in the first
place?
And they trick you.
You know,
if they did trick you ha,
you know,
what did you do when you realize it was
a trek?
Did you stick around and try to fix it?
Yeah,
I think that's a really good question
because I mean,
how many people do you know that are in
bad relationships?
Continue talking about it but don't,
aren't doing anything about it.
Like they're not brutal.
They're not leaving it and it a brutal
are cause there's,
did you just like,
why?
But a lot of times it's because it's
familiar and it's date what there's
somebody said,
um,
you know,
you get the love you think you deserve
and it may be easy for us looking
outside going,
oh my gosh,
it's so easy.
You should just like leave this
relationship.
But a lot of times the person like
doesn't think they can do better.
Or maybe this is like playing out some
dynamic they had with their parent or
you know,
you sort of need to understand why
you're in it before you can actually
make the choice to get out of it.
By the way,
there's a lot of delusional people out
there that are like,
I deserve a lot more than I'm getting.
That's true.
That's not really there.
What do you do when someone comes to you
with unrealistic expectations or they
don't want to see themselves like you
know,
you,
you tell them what they need to do or
what they should consider and they argue
with you about it.
Well,
I just really ask like,
is what you're doing working like is
your working?
If you can show me your ways working
then great.
My way's fine.
This is fucking the other people.
Everybody else.
Everybody else is all messed up.
I'm good.
God dammit.
Yeah.
I need you to coach everyone else.
I know.
Yeah.
If we could just change other people.
It's everybody else's fault.
Yup.
Do you ever have to tell people you're
not going to work with them?
I've had one person I had to tell that
too.
Yup.
Just one and it was,
you know,
I think it was,
it was just not a good fit and she just
wasn't ready,
willing.
The super committed to her story and
sort of wanted me just to cuddle it,
which I wasn't willing to do.
Yeah.
Sometimes people just want someone.
That's what I've always wondered about
therapy.
Like I have friends that have been the
I'm like,
okay,
what do you do when you go there and
talk about your problems and then what
happens?
Well,
they give you advice and then what
happens?
You don't have to shit.
You know,
like there's a lot of people that just
want to go somewhere and want someone to
listen to them talk.
Right?
Right.
They'll go three,
four times a week and they're still
fucked up.
Yup.
I'm like,
well that isn't working.
Yeah,
it doesn't and I think my intention
always is to really give people the
tools,
not just advice really helped them heal
really good.
I've had amazing teachers have been
really,
really lucky and they've really taught,
they haven't just given me advice,
they haven't just given me motivation.
They've really given me tools to heal
and change and that's,
that's what I try to do in my work with
people is show them that that a as
possible and they and that it can do it
and give them the tools to do it because
that's what that's going to last longer
than any kind of like
pep talk.
It was funny,
we were talking before the podcast
started about going to a seminar and
someone asking how many men here feel
vulnerable and like no one's putting
their hand up.
How many women here feel vulnerable?
All the hands went up,
all the hands went up.
And I mean,
part of it I think is a little
delusional because I think a lot of men
are way more vulnerable than they really
think they are.
But also this does just a different
thing going through live.
I mean there's that expression,
the fair sex or,
but being a female,
being a woman means you're,
you're physically different.
Yup.
You're up a bunch of people that most of
them could beat you up.
Yep.
You know,
that's,
it's a different way to walk through the
world.
That vulnerability though is that
creates another level of anxiety,
right?
Like walking down a dark street,
you see someone and it's a man and he's
walking down the dark street too.
You're like,
oh,
you know,
yeah.
It's,
it's scary and it's something that,
you know,
I as a woman,
like I'm always aware of it.
Not always,
but a lot of the time,
you know,
cause I,
I know that like,
like you said,
I could get beaten up.
Like,
it's between me and a man.
He's probably going to,
I mean I'm pretty strong but
not that strong.
And I,
I think what's also beautiful about
women and just the feminine in general
is that vulnerability.
But because like at sometimes it has,
it feels safe.
I think that's why a lot of women like
kind of have a protective armor and are
guarded and sometimes more on there like
masculine energy in the world is because
on some level we feel like we have to,
we have to like protect ourselves and
whereas that,
that vulnerability you really is the
thing that makes us women in so many
ways not.
And I think we confuse vulnerability
with weakness because vulnerability to
me is being open,
being available,
being um,
soft but not weak.
Weakness to me is more about kind of
going into the victim me and going into
that poor pitiful me and the feeling
sorry for and on all of those kinds of
things.
I think there's beautiful power and
vulnerability,
but when we're talking about just
physical strength,
yeah.
I mean for the most part men have the
advantage on that one.
It's just we need all the pieces,
right?
You need the whole spectrum of human
beings,
right?
And you know what I mean?
Especially in terms of,
you know,
you did the traditional way of looking
at things.
You know,
masculine men are attracted to feminine
women and Feminine Women are attracted
to masculine men and we both need each
other.
But a lot of times,
especially when you're dealing with
damaged folks,
you're dealing with a man who has a
vulnerable woman and the man's all
fucked up.
So he takes it out on a vulnerable
woman.
And the vulnerable woman is like under
the,
you know,
the pressure of the relationship or the
suppression of being connected to this
man.
And so you kind of dealing with the same
dynamic that you were dealing with when
you were in school or someone's bullying
you and you get it in this relationship.
Then instead of someone appreciating you
for the difference in the softness
versus the hard,
the Yin and the Yang,
now you have someone who is exploiting
that,
right?
And you see it with women too and they
see it with like aggressive women and
weak men.
Yeah.
That is,
to me,
one of the saddest things I ever see is
when you find the aggressive women and
the weak man cut.
Probably because I'm terrified of it
ever being mean.
You know,
I don't think it will be.
I don't think,
well,
I mean if it was,
you know,
nobody wants that.
Nobody wants the woman who's yelling at
Ya and,
and it goes,
we go cuckoo cuckoo.
I that happens a lot and then,
oh,
a lot,
a lot.
It's Kinda crazy to me because,
you know,
I see women emasculate men quite often,
not maybe on like a huge scale to the
degree you're talking about,
but just like the little comments,
like I'll be out with a couple and the
woman will say something and it's,
it's kind of emasculating burn.
If the roles were reversed and the guy
said something like that to the woman,
I don't know if it would go over,
you know,
guys just kind of take it
on on sometimes.
And then when I see that,
I'm like,
well a lot of men feel emasculated by
society in general,
just by the roles that they play in the
office.
And the,
just the,
the,
the physical act of going through life.
It's civilized world and also constantly
needing people's affirmation,
needing people's acceptance.
And,
and you,
you sort of become what people want you
to be,
even if that's not what you want.
You get in these relationships and you
see it all the time where a guy sort of
accept a little bit and then they accept
more and then they don't want to mess
up.
And then they,
I have a bunch of friends that have like
really domineering,
overbearing wives or girlfriends.
And it's weird.
It's weird to be around them.
Like,
dude,
you know,
you can leave.
Like,
he just like,
this is just a person.
Do you think they,
cause they're scared,
they're scared and it becomes the thing,
you know,
that's,
that's the thing,
this is the thing.
Or go out of the fucking wife,
we're going to go home to the wife,
you know?
And it's,
it's,
it's very strange.
It's very strange when you have someone
in your life that's essentially like a
parole officer,
so many life that gets to tell you what
to do and you're not allowed to do
certain things.
You're not allowed to watch certain
things or like certain things and they
control you and they own you.
I mean this,
this,
and I think a lot of these people that
are doing that much like the girl who
bullied you or any,
anybody who does that to someone,
they,
they do it out of,
out of fear.
They do it at an insecurity and they
also do it out of this bizarre instinct
because they can,
I state this girl,
she wasn't a bad person,
but she used to like to fight and I
don't,
I do not.
I do not like to,
I don't like that kind of conflict.
I don't like,
like in a relationship conflict.
I don't do,
I don't like it.
I don't fight and argue.
I just rather leave.
I'm like,
I'll end.
I'm into discussing things,
but when people start yelling and get
crazy,
I'm like,
fuck this.
I grew up,
I grew up around domestic violence too.
I grew up with the,
so I saw it when I was a kid.
I just,
I'm not interested.
And um,
so we broke up,
but we stayed friends and then years
later,
um,
we went out to coffee and like,
how's everything?
What's going on?
Oh,
I'm living this guy.
It's not going good.
And like,
why?
She's like,
she's telling me how she yells at this
guy and she can't help it.
She's like,
I can't help it.
I just fucking yell at him and he
doesn't do anything.
He just takes it.
And she's like,
when he takes it,
I just want to fucking smash him.
She's like,
I just can't,
she goes,
I don't want to yell at them,
but I can't help doing it.
And then when he's gone,
I'm like,
why the fuck did I do that?
And she had this weird,
almost like a natural impulse to
dominate this guy.
Like if you ever seen two dogs,
one dog has the upper hand on the,
on the dog and he'll go near the dog and
the other dog.
And that's just,
that's just their world.
That's just their world.
But the other dog never gets a chance.
And sometimes it's not even a size based
thing,
like it might be the exact same size
dog,
just one dog just decides the bitch and
the other one's the dominator.
And that's just how it goes.
Right.
Well,
she was in this position with this guy
where she just had this compelling
desire to fucking yell at them.
And I go,
well,
what are you yelling at him for her?
She's like,
anything,
everything.
She goes,
I just,
I just fucking,
I want him to tell me to shut the fuck
up.
Yeah.
She wanted him to out manner.
But isn't that crazy?
Like what a bizarre instinct to like,
to,
to push and like she was frustrated at
herself.
She was frustrated at him,
but it's almost like she was compelled,
like,
she's being drawn to the great magnet,
you know?
It's like,
Oh yeah,
hell,
but I'm gonna scream at him.
Right.
Well,
it's interesting like how we project on
to other people,
you know,
like whatever.
Some of them was going on inside of her
that was like creating that dynamic in
him.
And she could have left at any time,
but it was like she was so trying to get
a reaction out of him honestly to
probably see if he cared.
Like she probably equated.
All right,
well him taking it means he doesn't
care.
So how much can I push?
How much can I push?
How can I match?
Can I push so that I can see that he,
he'll react enough cause that means,
do you think that's what it is?
That she didn't think he cares if you
think she just thinks he's weak and it's
just frustrating to her that he's weak?
Well if it was just that,
I think she would have left a lot
earlier.
There was something she wanted.
Like we don't keep doing it over and
over and over again unless there's
something more attached to getting.
Like,
you know when we're just went and we're
like,
Oh man,
this is stupid.
We get out of there.
But when we find ourselves in situations
where it's like it's happening over and
over and over again and we continue to
get frustrated but we're not leaving,
there's something we're attached to
trying to get from our behavior.
So there was something she wanted and
that there was something in it for her.
Otherwise she had been out of there a
lot sooner.
I wonder.
It was also,
she was trying to do the acting thing
and she was constantly frustrated.
Yeah,
she was constantly just taking it out on
him.
Yeah.
Well that it was,
it would be really interesting.
Like I'd watch these like almost sort of
manic things.
Like there would be these moments where
you know,
she would be preparing for an audition
and she'd be hopeful yet nervous.
There was a lot of anxiety and there was
all this,
here's the thing and it's going to,
things going to go on the,
hopefully if this happens,
this guy is connected to this and that's
going to happen with that and then boom,
it didn't happen.
And so there's this massive let down,
right?
This is cigarette smoking and depression
and you know,
all this angst.
Yup.
And um,
I got the fuck out of there.
Yeah.
This dude got in there like,
and he caught it.
He caught the second wave of anx.
Yeah.
When I met her she was just moving here.
And so she wasn't completely bewildered
by the experience in the machine yet.
Yeah.
And um,
it's also,
I think for some people choosing things
that you do for a living that are
healthy for you.
I think there's a lot of people that get
involved in careers that require too
much of their time.
You don't really want to do it,
but you get caught up in it,
whether it's being a lawyer or being a
doctor or being something that has a
prestigious title when you feel like
there's something great tech,
but really in the back of your mind,
there's something else that you probably
would be way happier doing.
That was me.
I was going after it for the wrong
reasons.
What do you want to do though?
If you weren't doing the life coach,
I know you enjoy doing what you're
doing,
but do you have like if somehow or
another you were independently wealthy
and you didn't have to coach all these
crazy people?
Plenty more.
Not that they're crazy,
but some of them will probably do it.
I mean like I,
you know,
I love people and I love personal
development.
Even if I had all the money in the
world,
I'd still speak.
I'd still do my podcast,
I'd still do retreats.
I,
I love it.
Like I love the human experience.
I love being there for that moment where
someone has a major insight where they
connect dots and it's like,
Whoa,
a massive perspective shift and like all
of a sudden they start to kind of move a
different direction.
It's,
I can't imagine doing anything else.
I mean,
if I could sing,
if I had any kind of music ability,
I think it'd be awesome to be a
rockstar.
Like just to have that rush.
But literally I have no musical ability
whatsoever other than like listening to
it.
I'm just do not have,
yeah.
Well that's great.
So you found your thing.
Now,
how often is it when you talk to be,
but when you're trying to coach them and
help them and you realize like,
man,
you got to do something else.
Like is that a,
is that a factor?
Cause I would think that the thing about
careers is not only is it eight hours of
your time,
but it also kind of defines you.
So every day you're defined by whatever
you do.
Right.
And oftentimes,
like we were talking about like men in
these workplace environments,
there's sort of like,
they're boxed into this predetermined
pattern and behavior that's expected
from them.
You know,
they have shoes with tassels on them and
ties and they have to talk like,
you know,
business talk.
And it's like you fall into these weird
patterns and you lose a lot of your
individuality inside those patterns
because office life and you know,
human resources demands certain things
of you.
Like there's a certain your,
your personality,
like when you in an office environment,
anytime you're in the corporate world,
your personality is stuffed into this
form,
right.
You know,
whatever that form is,
whatever that mold is,
the mold of being a business person,
you know,
you're a woman,
you're a business woman.
You want to be respected and want to use
the right word to say the right things.
And Yeah,
you know,
and,
and talk the right lingo.
But did the,
like a lot of times people are left
wondering who the fuck am I.
Right,
right.
They just get totally lost in a role.
[inaudible] yeah.
And I do like I go do a lot of corporate
speaking and I have a lot of people come
up to me afterwards and they're just
like,
oh my gosh.
Like I'm cause I talk about,
you know,
how we lose ourselves in these roles and
how like a lot of times our adult life
becomes sort of just this like follow
Truman show.
Like one thing after the other,
just like follow this structure that was
set out for us.
We never checked in and said,
do I want this?
Like do I even want this?
You know?
And so to answer your question,
yes,
a lot of times when people come or I'm
working with people,
it is like looking at like,
is this cool?
Is this career right for you?
Is this relationship right for you?
Like what have you created in your life
that just doesn't fit where you are?
But you're in it because you're scared
to make the change.
And,
and also,
you know,
some people really can be happy in
corporate America,
like some people
that works for them.
If you're strange freaks,
I,
I'm,
I firmly really believe that the vast
majority of people that are living the
American dream,
living that life,
doing that nine to five,
the vast majority of them are fucking
horror.
Horrifically miserable.
Yeah.
I really do believe that.
I think it's so defining and it's so,
it's so contrary to the human spirit.
Right?
Right.
And I think most people don't want to
believe that.
They don't want to believe there's,
it's possible that everybody's doing
something wrong.
Right.
And they don't believe they can change
it.
Yeah.
There's no other option.
I don't know what else to do,
especially if they have,
you know,
a mortgage and a spouse and kids doing
loans,
all that stuff.
Yeah.
It's really intimidating to go,
oh gosh,
how do I,
how do I change this?
I think you have to start small.
I think you have to start with,
okay,
I don't have to quit my job tomorrow,
but what are some things in my life I
can start doing that made me feel alive
again?
Like is it a hobby?
Is it like training for a marathon?
Is it what is going to start making me
feel like,
you know,
I'm creative and I matter and I'm more
than just this role as husband,
wife,
mother,
father,
corporate executive,
whatever it is.
So I think that's a good place to start,
is something small you can do to make
you feel alive again,
because anybody has access to that,
right?
You don't have to leave your job to
start creating some things in your life
that can start to shift things.
And then like we were talking about then
it's like the gradual change,
you know,
cause I don't think it's possible for
most people just to quit their job
tomorrow.
They don't think it's possible.
No one,
almost no one.
Exactly.
And not everybody's meant to be an
entrepreneur either and do their own
thing,
but there are always things we can do in
our life to mix it up a little bit and
even just show up differently in our
job.
Yeah,
I just think that for a huge amount of
people,
the amount of time that's required of
them.
Yeah.
Because of their job is so overwhelming
because most people,
let's be honest or not really just
working nine to five particularly most
men,
there's a tremendous amount of overtime
involved.
I was looking at the,
some thing there was talking about,
it was a,
an article on the wage gap difference
and what,
what it really is about,
and one of the things it was about was
the amount of the difference in the
amount of hours that men work and the in
their ambition to try to climb up the
corporate ladder.
And you look at the numbers that people
work and it's terrifying.
There's no lie.
If you're working 60 hours a week,
you don't have a life,
there's nothing left.
Yeah.
If I work here,
I'll do a podcast for three hours and
I'll do a bunch of other stuff and you
know,
I'm trying to fit in things in my day
and I have a pretty loose schedule.
I mean,
I do a lot of things,
but it's pretty loose.
You know,
like today I did UFC stuff for a couple
hours this morning and then I come here
for a few hours,
then I got to work out and then it will
tell some jokes.
But there's a lot of movement in there.
There's a lot of time or I can get shit
done.
Yeah.
Some people don't have any of that.
It have nothing like that made you
different like back in the day where you
could have done that path of the
corporate route.
Why did you make different choices?
It's a good question.
I Dunno.
Probably,
I don't know.
I mean,
I never felt like I could,
I never felt like I could have a regular
job.
Like from the time I got out of high
school,
I never had a full time job.
I had a bunch of part time jobs.
I did some full time jobs where
construction companies and stuff,
but I didn't last.
I would do them for like a month or a
couple of weeks and I was like fuck
this,
like whatever it is about.
And it was all,
it was the main source
of all my problems in high school.
All my problems in high school was I was
not willing to do things I didn't want
to do.
So I would barely get by through high
school.
I go take tests.
They would register intelligence or
measure intelligence.
That'd be great.
Everything's fine.
But I would take actual test based on
what I was supposed to be studying and I
fucking barely paid attention.
I mean I s squoze through high school
with like a c average and most things I
barely got by.
And even when I was going to college,
I was only going to college.
I went to Boston University and uh,
or umass rather in Boston.
And the only reason why I went is
because I didn't want anybody to think I
was a loser.
So I was taking classes at Umass and
busy.
It was a,
when I was teaching taekwondo at Boston
University,
which was like a,
a really good school and I was looking
at all these people that were preparing
for life and to me it was like,
you're going to go eat,
get eaten by alligators or something.
And I was like,
what are you going to do?
You're going to go get a job,
you're going to be working nine to five
for whatever,
whatever fucked up thing that was wrong
in my head.
I would way rather get up in the morning
and deliver newspapers for three hours a
day or drive limos at night.
I,
I had a really unstable childhood.
So in my mind,
anything that you were locked down to
was death.
It was prison and I,
whatever malfunction of my brain,
I figured out a way to make it work for
survival skill.
Yeah.
In some way,
but also a lack of like,
I'm not very disciplined.
It looks like I'm disciplined on the
outside.
I'm not disciplined at all.
I'm obsessed.
I get obsessed with things whether I'm
disciplined with in certain aspects like
with exercise and I do it when I don't
want to do it.
I forced myself to practice and I forced
myself to write.
I forced myself to do things,
but more of,
it's more of an obsession thing.
Like I get obsessed with either a goals
or tasks or things or puzzles or games.
I've have a real problem,
like there's something wrong with me.
Well,
why do you say that?
Does it feel draining?
No,
because like I'll play pool for 12 hours
in a row.
Like I'll,
I'll get obsessed with playing pool and
then I think I'm going to be the world
champion.
I'm going to practice 12 hours a day for
the rest of my life.
I mean,
I'm a sick person.
Like whatever happened to me when I was
young,
like whatever weirdness in involved in
wwe,
I figured out a way to manage it,
but it can get away from me.
It's gotten away from me before.
Well,
I played video games like eight,
10 hours a day.
It can get away.
I go,
I have to manage whatever craziness that
makes me like focus on things.
Yeah.
I see it in my kids,
especially my middle daughter,
she's,
she gets obsessed with things and I'm
like,
wow,
this is crazy.
It's like a genetic thing.
It's like watching a little female,
me and a lot of ways,
you know,
like she read all eight Harry Potter
books and a matter of a couple of
months,
she just,
she is just gets into stuff and then
like you got to go,
Hey,
shut the light out.
You've got to go to bed one more
chapter.
Like,
come on,
you've got to stop it.
But,
um,
it's not like she's seen it in me and
she's mirroring it because it's her own
little weirdness,
you know?
But I think it's obviously she's got a,
uh,
a healthier environment than I grew up
in.
So it's not like a,
a matter of luck not ever,
not ever wanting to be connected to
anything permanent cause nothing is
permanent.
I mean that was part of,
I think with the lessons from my
childhood,
like no one's here to help you.
Not as a,
don't get locked in any fucking job.
Don't get locked in any,
you get ready to move in any time,
you know,
and embracing moving.
Like to this day I'll be,
I'll be like,
I've got to get the fuck on la.
You're like,
everything's here.
I have to do everything here.
The comic stores here,
my family's here,
my kids go to school here.
All my friends live here.
But I'm like,
fuck this,
I'm going to the mountains.
I gotta get Outta here.
Like I have this like no mad shit in me
that I'm like constantly trying to,
um,
to uh,
manage.
So
as much as people like to take credit
for a certain amount of success,
like I can tell you all the different
things that I did that led to me being
successful at things,
but almost,
it's like the function of a mental
issue,
like a big,
a lot of it is a function of learning
how to manage a brain that doesn't work
like everybody else's brain.
That's so I think common for a lot of
successful people especially,
and the differences,
you're aware of how it works and you've
learned how to manage it.
But that,
you know,
that obsessive thing in so many ways it
has made you,
it has gotten you a certain degree of
success and all of those things,
survival skills,
compensatory strategies,
whatever they are,
they have their positives,
they have ways that they really help us,
but then they have the ways that kind of
torture us and a lot of ways.
And I think
growth is really about understanding
what are the ways that this isn't doing
me any good and how can I be mindful of
it.
And also like,
you know,
how do I know now that like that now is
not then like how do I,
you know,
stop being activated by old experiences
in my past and just have peace for where
I am now and take those gifts from the
obsession that's made you successful but
not having the parts that kind of
torture you at the same
done.
Well,
I don't feel tortured.
Um,
so I think in some ways have achieved
some sort of a victory over my whatever
mental issues that I have,
but I can't do nothing.
Right.
That's the reason why I have three jobs
you don't have,
I can't do nothing if I do an end.
I have three jobs and a fucking ton of
obsessions outside of those jobs.
Martial arts,
archery or reading and writing and all
sorts of other stuff on top of
podcasting and doing the commentary for
the UFC,
doing standup comedy,
like that's the only way I feel even.
Yeah,
and I can't have one thing that I count
on either if like I had,
if I only had standup comedy or only had
the UFC,
if there's only one thing or only had
podcasting,
I'd be like,
this is my,
I got it.
I would want to quit.
I'm like,
I don't want to do this anymore.
This is my fucking thing.
I'm just going to be trapped doing this
thing,
talking into a fucking microphone out
into space for the rest of my life.
I've got to go to fucking,
I don't even want to hear myself
anymore.
I've got to quit.
No.
So whatever weird malfunction my brains
had,
I've figured out a way over all the
years of my life to,
to manage it,
but a lot of his physical to managing my
brain.
A lot of it requires intense exercise.
Like when I,
when I intensely exercise,
then I can like,
oh,
all right.
It's going to be all right.
It's going to be cool,
but if I don't,
yeah.
It's like it's all built up and then
there's,
it's hard to enjoy things.
Yeah.
It's hard to just chill.
Like I can't chill unless I earn it.
It gets a,
it's probably a malfunction,
but it's the illusion is that it's not,
the illusion is that it's a discipline
and then it's all,
it's all choices,
but that's really not the case.
Maybe it's just you and how you operate
your operating system.
Are You coaching me now?
Is that what's going on here?
Does that feel like I am?
Yeah.
Maybe it is me.
I mean,
I think people,
and that's not a bad thing.
That's,
you know,
I think that there,
I back to the acceptance thing.
There's a lot of ways I think we're
supposed to be and we look at other
people and how they do their life for
whatever.
And we think that because we're acting
this way,
something must be wrong with us,
but a lot of times there's not.
This is just the way you operate.
Yeah.
You know what another thing is
interesting is,
um,
when I was a kid I was a not very
confident and also didn't like to talk
to people,
get anxiety,
I anxiety.
If I had a talk and I get anxiety,
if I had to like talk to a bank teller,
I go,
I had to wait in line through the
backdoor.
I'd start freaking out like on my way to
the bank teller.
And like if you talked to like people
who knew me from high school and they'll
go,
uh,
did you ever think that Joe is going to
be a comedian?
They'd be like,
no,
like no fucking way.
That guy was at funny,
like they didn't,
I figured out a way to be more relaxed
socially and it wasn't an easy process
at all.
It took forever to the point where now
I'm extremely relaxed socially.
Like now I can talk to anybody.
Like I,
I love one of the things I love about
doing podcasts.
I like just having conversations with
people.
Yeah.
I want to know like you're another
organism.
You're another person.
I want to know what's going on in your
head.
I don't understand your life.
I want to,
I want to own to try to see what
connections you've made,
what,
what definitions you've fallen on.
You know,
what you know,
how you've defined this world,
how you've,
how you've categorized things and how
you're managing it.
How are you,
how are you maneuvering through it?
I'm fascinated by that.
I'm fascinated by the,
the,
the thoughts that people carry around
inside their heads.
Yeah,
me too.
Yeah.
I love it.
And whether or not they're empowering or
whether or not you're a woe is me type
person,
you know?
And what are the puzzle pieces that have
led to where you are?
And I love that you're sharing this
because I think a lot of people can see
you and see your success in everything
that you have and thank you were always
like this and then it's just been easy
cause it's this,
you know,
you're always like this,
but to know you had that background and
you had the social anxiety and this is
like such a stretch,
I think it's really inspiring because it
gives people,
it's like,
oh you,
you can't,
you can no longer argue that you know,
you're just born a certain way and
that's just the way you are.
Like your proof that you actually can
change and you can't get over things and
you can create things that you know you
probably didn't think were possible when
you were 10 or however old you were when
you were going through all that stuff.
Yeah.
I think there are,
people have different starting points.
Yeah.
It's like I was saying that if you want
to climb Mount Everest,
good luck of,
you're starting from Santa Monica.
You got to fucking walk all the way to
Tibet.
It's going to take a long ass time.
There's,
the ocean is going to be hard to get a
grip,
but if you're at the base of Tibet,
if that's where you live,
it's w or the base of the Himalayas,
it's way easier to climb that thing,
you know,
it's still not easy,
but it's easier.
And I think there's a lot of people that
start,
you know,
in the a metaphoric Santa Monica would
their life,
they're really far away from their goal.
Yeah.
It doesn't mean it's not possible,
but it means that there's a bunch of
steps,
whether they're conscious or unconscious
that you're going to have to make in
order to get to a position.
And I still remember fucking freaking
out going to a bank teller.
I think we used to have an all the time,
I just didn't want to talk to people.
I was just in my own head and I was
super insecure and I just could barely
get through shit,
you know?
And so what changed it?
Just doing it over and over again.
Martial arts was a big thing.
The martial arts is the first thing that
I ever did where I was good at it or I
didn't feel like a loser.
It was like I had done,
I was pretty good at art and uh,
yes.
Yeah.
And um,
I wanted to be a comic book illustrator
and that was like a big focus in my life
when I was younger.
But,
um,
I mean,
and I and I definitely took some sort of
identity in the fact that I was good at
that and I liked the fact that people
would say I was good at it and made me
feel good.
But it was different than martial arts
because with martial arts,
um,
it was the first thing that I did where
I felt like I could really be
exceptional I think could be really
good,
like in an are realize that,
um,
first of all I was gifted physically and
then also this crazy brain of mine.
If I could point it to something,
like I would work out at three o'clock
in the morning cause I knew nobody else
would.
I knew they weren't there.
So I had keys to the gym,
so a,
because I was teaching,
so I would go there,
I'd wake up and I would drive down to
the gym and I open it up in the middle
of the night and put in a workout
because I knew that no one else was
doing that.
I knew they weren't there and I knew,
I felt like it gave me an this,
well yeah,
an edge.
But it also,
I felt like there was,
I was getting ahead of them,
you know,
like,
like it was,
it was some sort of a crazy race.
So for between the age of 15 and 21 I
was just completely obsessed with
fighting and that's all I did.
I just,
I didn't,
I didn't know.
I probably barely knew who was
president.
I didn't know a goddamn thing about the
world.
I wasn't reading shit unless it was like
some Samurai book on philosophy in
combat.
Like that was all I was obsessed with
and that's when I was also a got an a
and they were ah,
anthony robins and somewhere around that
too.
But I was interested in like things that
would give me an edge,
personal development stuff that would
give me an edge.
And then through doing martial arts and
then also through teaching,
I think that was a big one,
was teaching classes.
And then teaching at Bu was big too.
Cause when I was teaching at Boston
University,
I was teaching an actual class
taekwondo.
When I was,
at that time I was a,
I'd won the u open,
I had won a bunch of different
tournaments and I was,
you know,
it was,
I was doing really well as a,
as a fighter,
as a martial arts competitor.
So,
um,
they had,
uh,
a taekwondo program at Bu and I was
teaching it and I would have to address
a whole class,
but I would address a whole class as
something that was really good at,
like I knew I could demonstrate them to
them,
some movements and stuff like that.
It shows some things.
I'd asked someone to hold something and
I'd kick it or something like that and
they'd be like,
Holy Shit.
And then they would listen.
Like I could get,
I could,
I was confident in what I was saying
there and it was like the only time in
my life that I can remember being
confident and telling people something.
Yeah.
It's like I would describe how you do
it.
This is how you do it and I'll show you
how to do it here,
but this is how it needs to be done and
this is why.
And this is what happens when you do it
and this is what involved in the
mechanisms of your body and,
and so that,
that gave me the first,
that was like the first feeling that I
got were,
um,
there was,
I,
I knew that there was like a light at
the end of the tunnel,
or at least I knew,
well,
at least this now I don't feel like a
loser anymore.
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
It gave you something to like,
like you said,
be exceptional at yeah.
And I think that's what gives us
confidence is feeling like we've
somewhat mastered something like
somewhat really could understand
something well enough to teach it.
Yes.
Yeah.
Without that,
we're just chasing it.
I think for and trying to get it through
little things we do.
And I think that's why a lot of people
like go from career to career,
job to job or whatever.
Trying to find that little bit of
instead of sticking with something and
like really focusing in on really
studying it.
And that's where I think the obsession
actually served you in a lot of ways.
I think for sure.
And there's also expression than I,
I love to use the martial arts are a
vehicle for developing your human
potential.
Cause cause it's so difficult and it's
so terrifying.
And then the idea of competing and yeah,
in the physical consequences are so
devastating.
If you get hit that you are,
you can't,
you can't have acid,
you can't slack off,
you have to,
you have to really pursue this thing
with an insanity,
like a,
an incredible intensity.
And then through that you realize like,
oh I could do that.
Yeah.
And then from doing that you kind of
realize,
well what if I apply that to writing a
book or doing that or learning how to do
something else.
Or for me it was standup comedy.
Wow.
That see,
stand up comedy seems terrifying to me.
Sarah.
Nice.
Terrifying is working in a fucking
office wearing tassels with shiny shoes.
That's very true.
Stupid socks.
Yeah.
That was terrifying for me to,
Oh God.
I remember like Sunday nights I would
just get knots in my stomach.
Just like,
Oh,
do I have to go and be an awful staff
meetings on Monday mornings?
Like
sucking the oxygen out of your own life
out.
Yeah.
That's why a lot of people start taking
medication.
Yup.
That unhappiness of just what you call
quote unquote real life.
There's been a structure that's put in
place that we've all sort of shuffled
into that doesn't serve us and it
doesn't serve most people.
You'll have wim Hoff on last night,
you know,
he is a [inaudible] about him.
He's amazing.
But one of the things he and I were
talking about,
he was,
he gave me his number about,
what did he say?
Like 7% of people or something like
that,
do things that are creative with their,
their life.
What 7% 70% of the world.
I don't know.
Oh,
let's,
let's get crazy and say it's 15% that's
really small.
It is.
Well,
here's the thing.
100% of kids are creative.
It's true.
Like my kids,
they're both,
they're both always do.
My young kids,
they're both always painting or drawing
or doing something in.
My older kid does music,
so this is like so much creativity that
they,
they feel drawn to it and all that stuff
is something that every kid does.
Yup.
Every kid draws shit.
Every kid plays with clay.
Every kid make stuff with legos.
You all like put things together,
remind,
but somewhere along the line we're
stuffed into this structure that doesn't
serve us.
And if we feel like we have to do it
because we've given,
been shuffled through school and into
college and then we're in debt and then
we have to take opportunities and these
opportunities is a good opportunity.
You know?
It's a good,
good career.
Yep.
It's horrific.
It is an end.
Like to go back to what you were saying
earlier,
like these,
these systems that we've built are so
antiquated and so outdated from politics
to the school system and it all needs to
change and we're seeing it start to,
you know,
or seen it start to,
I think that the way we educate kids,
the way we relate to add and all these
things,
I think so much of Atdd is like the
current system and the way kids are like
can find in this classroom and I have to
follow these rules and sit still all
day.
Like it,
there's no nurturing of creativity.
Right.
Um,
so I think over time a lot of this is
going to start to change.
I hope so because we just can't squat.
I see this,
you know,
with kids all that,
I have three nephews and I see the same
thing.
They're so creative and there's,
they're confident.
They don't care what other people think
of them.
You know,
they don't have a lot of fear.
They,
and when they do do something creative,
they don't judge it and go,
oh,
is it good?
Like they just enjoy the process and
that starts to phase out as we get older
and we get obsessed with other people
thinking,
is it good enough and is this safe and
well this please my parents and like
will I be able to make money this way
and we just get so disconnected from
that childlike creativity and
wonderment,
curiosity and and kind of no fear and
faith in ourselves that we just get
stuck in this kind of checklist,
tassel wearing life.
I think it's another tassels,
tassels,
our enemy.
I think there's another thing that we
need to consider and this is really
important to people that are like,
well this is bullshit,
dreamer talk,
listen to this because this is real.
That corporate worlds only been around
for less than a hundred years.
This is a new thing in modern life and
modern life is new in terms of the
length of time.
Human beings have been alive.
This is a new thing and it doesn't serve
us,
and maybe with technological innovation
and robots and automation and all the
different shit that's coming down the
line,
maybe there'll be less and less
opportunities for you to work a slave
job and you'll have to do something
creative.
It will be more and more compelling,
but this world that we've structured
that doesn't serve us is incredibly
recent and it's not,
it's not rigid.
Like you don't have to do it.
Right,
right.
But it seems like you do,
it seems like you do.
What's actually really cool about
millennials,
you know this,
the generation that's now like 20 to 35
36 ish,
that's one of the things I talk about is
generational diversity in millennials
and they're demanding a different kind
of workplace.
They're more likely to take a job where
they have more creativity.
The culture is like less cubical base.
They have more freedom than a job with
like the salary and the benefits and
they're not relating to work in the same
way.
They're really questioning the old
paradigms there.
And I don't understand like why do I
have to be there from nine to five if I
can like get this done at home,
you know,
a certain amount of time and a lot more
of them are starting their own
businesses and doing the more
traditional path.
So I think we're already starting to see
it change because we have a generation
that's huge.
I mean the millennial generation is
ginormous and they're,
they,
they're demanding different things from
work and making different choices
already.
So it's already shifting.
Sorry,
shifting.
Yeah.
I also think another thing that's
bullshit is the amount of time that's
required to make a living just to
survive.
I mean,
how many people are barely being able to
feed themselves and housed themselves
and they're giving up their entire day
and their entire week.
And you get,
if you're lucky,
you get that Saturday,
Sunday off,
but most of the time on Saturday and
Sunday,
if you have an an office job,
you have some shit that you brought home
with you that you have to sort through.
Yeah.
That it's the whole payment systems.
Crazy and you see like these instead of
celebrities making all this money just
by posting pictures and you've got
somebody going into a job like nine to
five day after day after day,
barely scraping by.
It's just,
I don't know.
Well,
what freaks me out is people that just
move money around and they make billions
like think about like hedge fund people
and people that like,
what are you doing?
You're moving numbers around and you're
making numbers and the pro how much,
how much are you extracting while you're
moving stuff around?
It's the,
like I had this conversation with this
woman who was like the staunch
Republican who was telling me that the
minimum wage was so ridiculous.
She was so adamant that you can't raise
the minimum wage.
I'm like,
why not?
And she's like,
was cause $15 an hour.
It would crush businesses and we'll do
this.
We'll do that.
I'm like,
well,
other people disagree.
Like you don't know whether or not that
is.
I go,
do you want to work for less than 15
bucks an hour?
She's like,
well,
these are entry level jobs and this,
and none of them go,
well,
you're still requiring an hour of
someone's time if your job,
if you have,
if you have a business and your business
can't pay someone $15 for an hour of
their time,
your business is bullshit.
It's bullshit.
Or you have too many employees or you,
you know,
you're not,
it's not set up right,
but you're the person who's at the
lowest rung of the food chain to take
the hit,
not the business.
Like if you have a business,
you came at pay someone $15 for a whole
hour of working,
how much money are you generating and
why do you need all this business?
And why don't you know those employees
do it yourself?
It's not an efficient business.
And I wonder what's going to happen with
automation and with,
you know,
they're,
they're talking about like a tremendous
amount of jobs that are being done right
now by people that are going to be done
by robots.
And it's,
it's just a matter of time.
Yeah.
So it's even more important to nurture
your creativity and know what you can do
besides rely on the man or the
corporation or whatever it is.
Cause I think a lot of people think that
safety and economic security is in that
is in working for someone else course
and working for
bration getting a good job,
climbing the ladder,
shooting your brains out,
jumping off a building.
Yeah.
This,
this,
we don't have that much time.
This is,
this is not,
this is not a long run.
It's really not.
It goes by really some 49 and I feel
like it was 20 yesterday.
Yeah.
It just,
it just happens.
Yeah.
And next thing you know,
I'll be 59 and next thing you know I'll
be 69 yeah.
You know,
and then I'll be able to close my eyes
and hear the yawning grave.
It's coming.
It's coming for all of us.
Yep.
You gotta have fun.
Gotta have fun while you're here.
If in any way possible.
I agree.
I always say that I think regret is far
worse than risk.
Like I,
I'd rather take risks in my life then
regret it safe or staying in situations
that I knew weren't,
you know,
for me,
I mean it,
it's scary.
Yeah.
And there's no guarantee,
but at least you do it.
That's where she comes from.
No.
Yeah,
exactly.
That's scary stuff.
Like Ugh,
that's what forces you to move.
And that's what gets things done.
Exactly.
Every two years I throw away my act and
I write a new one.
I do a special,
like my netflix special,
I abandoned all those jokes and I have
to write a whole new one.
Okay.
That's fucking terrifying.
It's the worst.
But I keep doing it and every time I do
it,
it gets better.
If I keep doing it and I keep focusing
on it,
I'm on.
And all that terror and fear of taking
that chance,
it makes,
makes me get better at it.
And that's a pretty minor thing cause
it's not like that much financial
concern and I'll be okay.
But for someone to take a chance
financially and take a chance,
their future and they don't really know
what,
what the future holds is not like they
have all these things to fall back on.
That's when you fucking dig in.
That's when you make things happen.
Yeah.
And if you don't,
you just,
you,
you just stay soft and lazy.
Yeah.
Then and you never really discover your
true potential if you just stay
comfortable.
Christina's people out there right now
that are listening,
that are getting fired up there.
Listen this right now they're jogging in
place and I'm like,
God dammit.
I want to listen to Christine.
Take a chance.
It's good,
right?
Yeah.
It's really good.
But don't just like here's this broke
the lighter.
Can you really end it?
But don't just like feel motivated.
Like actually like commit to one thing.
You know,
what's one thing you can do to start
shifting your life?
Is it,
like I said,
finding that hobby?
Is it like having a conversation with
your boss?
Is it going after that creative
endeavor?
Like just start,
that's the other thing.
Like people think they have to know all
the steps.
It's like I want to get to the second
floor.
I'm at the bottom of a staircase and
like I think I just have to jump to get
there.
No,
like you go step by step by step,
just like you'd walk up the staircase so
you don't have to know it all at once.
It's just taking that first step and
then that leads to another and that
leads to another.
And like you said,
like it's the scary moments where you
find your grit and you find your
potential and you find out how you
respond to adversity and you find your
true gifts and you can only do that in
uncertainty.
And when you're uncomfortable,
maybe she'd be a clarity adviser.
The clarity advisor,
like some kind of psychic.
No,
no,
no.
Clarity.
Yeah.
Psyche wouldn't be a Clara.
I knew charm.
This is my new.
Oh,
Gotcha,
Gotcha.
I cleared the advisor.
That's good.
I like that.
It's a little wordy.
Yeah,
it's not perfect.
It's,
we're getting closer.
It's a step dad.
There's something there.
Bright like you're,
you don't,
one thing that I tell people that I
think is really important,
it's helped me a lot is write the things
down that you need to do.
Make a list.
Yup.
As far as your day,
like the best way to get shit done is to
stare that Goddamn list and say,
all right today,
did I work out?
Did I write,
did I do this?
Did I do that?
That would take care of that stuff.
Right.
All that stuff that you need to do,
do it at the beginning of the day or
doing it when you go to bed at night,
sometimes even better before you go to
bed at night.
Set your intention for the next day.
Say,
I'm going to get all this shit done.
Right.
I'll give yourself 1520 minutes.
You have it.
Yeah.
Everybody's got 15 minutes.
Everybody does.
Yeah.
And then write it down,
put it,
put it on a piece of paper and then the
next day check that shit off.
Yeah.
Do those things.
And if you could just get in the habit
of doing that.
It's so easy to avoid cause people love
to just be lazy.
These they love the distraction of doing
nothing
insane.
They don't have time.
Yes.
And saying they don't have time but,
but that is one that has been incredibly
beneficial to me is writing things down,
making a list and forcing myself to
check all the shit off that's on that
list.
Yeah.
And doing the things you don't always
feel like doing and and also being
accountable that people like having
somebody that's like calling you and be
like,
did you do it?
Like did you do it?
Did you show up for yourself?
Because it takes momentum,
you know,
like making these kinds of changes.
You have to build momentum.
And if you have that checklist and
you're doing that,
that one thing every day and maybe the
first thing you're going to do is like
commit to making a list every day.
That's a great step.
Once you start showing up for yourself
every day and doing that and checking
things off the list,
you start build self trust.
You start to have more integrity with
yourself.
You start to build momentum and then
it's easy to take the next step and like
do the next thing.
But without that momentum and without
that commitment,
I think people just expect their life to
change like this and it,
like we've,
we've talked about this a lot.
Like it just doesn't,
but those little stops,
they start to make you feel better too
because you start to feel like,
oh my gosh,
I'm not doing the same thing over and
over.
Cause that really is insanity.
One an Einstein who said insanity is
doing the same thing over and over again
expecting a different result.
I think it was like that.
That to me is crazy making
it is.
And also there's a thing that people
have to be aware of and that is the trap
of falling back into old patterns
because they offer you comfort.
That happens to a lot of people that
want to lose weight.
Losing weight is a big one.
They start,
they start off good,
they start losing weight,
they start looking great and then
somewhere along the line,
that old pattern calls to them,
this is us as hell.
Fuck
donut man,
you've won,
or you've earned a donut krispy kreme.
Just get a couple of them with some big
deal tomorrow you get back on the track
and you just never do.
You never get back on track.
Yeah.
And it's,
it's,
it's a really common for people,
whether it's cigarette smoking or you
know,
fill in the blank,
whatever it is.
Old Patterns are really hard.
They're really hard to avoid because
they offer some sort of bizarre comfort.
Yeah.
They're like coping strategies and so
many ways,
I mean,
so many people eat or smoke or whatever
for comfort or to self soothe themselves
and so they can,
you know,
make a new year's resolution and lose
the weight and then if they haven't
found another way to cope with life when
things get hard or
someone upsets them or whatever,
they were going to turn to that old
coping device because they haven't dealt
with the issue underneath what made them
over ate or drank or smoke in the first
place.
Yeah.
And it's,
there's also,
when you're filled with anger and does
all these things are fucked up in your
life.
There's something about those old
patterns that like give you a big hug.
Yeah,
yeah.
They did that like a warm fuzzy old
blanket,
but it's really disgusting.
Covered with bacteria.
That's a good way to look at it.
If people want to get ahold of you,
how do they do that?
How do they go about it?
Oh,
well expectation hangover is my last
book.
Christine Hassler,
instagram,
facebook,
but,
but on twitter there's no,
he and Christine because twitter is
screwed up and they don't let you have.
That's not even a long name.
I know.
It's just too long for twitter.
I'll take it out.
Put twitter it.
What does the spelling I,
he folks on twitter and you can find it
on my twitter,
cause a of this day.
If you go to this day,
which is today,
today's October 25th Oh,
and if you want to listen to me coach
people alive,
I do that on my podcast.
It's called over it and on with it.
People call in,
I coach him live on the,
it's fine.
Beautiful.
You coach people live on the island on
the,
I don't know anything about him with
further Colin.
Oh Wow.
Do you see them or do you just hear
them?
Just hear him.
Yeah.
You're trolled can get trolled.
Trolled.
Yeah.
Dudes are going to know after this
showing you going to happen.
For sure.
You've been getting people that really
need advice off until now.
Now you're going to get people that
really listen to this podcast,
but thank you very much.
I really enjoyed talking to you.
I really appreciate it.
It was a lot of fun.
All right.
Thanks Joe.
All right folks,
uh,
see you next week.
Lots of good stuff coming.
See Ya.
Bye.
Okay.