Scared to ask you too many questions
until we get live.
Well good.
And we're live.
Adam green trees fresh from Australia.
Fresh from the bush.
From the bush.
Yeah.
It's been crazy.
So I was thinking about it and I'm not
even la part.
I was just thinking.
I went from the snowy tops of Montana,
got home pretty much had the family
today.
Death went straight to Arnhem land in
the northern territory of Australia.
Complete opposite,
like just first thing in the morning.
This wedding covered in mosquitoes,
flat barren ground and then.
But now humans like a small indigenous
population out there and that's it.
Then straight from there,
so straight from Arnhem land to Sydney.
Met came in Sydney and then straight
here to La and Florida and it's just
like at night.
How many people live here?
Too many.
There's more people here than in the
entire country of Australia.
That's crazy.
I never lost all his hair and you're
like,
you know,
this is the safest place on earth of the
safest place in the US and those that,
a armed robbery or whatever they was in
Calabasas say today when we flew in and
I went into like a t cell provider to
get a Sim card at.
Dude walks in,
look for dodgy.
I knew something was about to go on the
dude that was so to me,
knew something was going on.
I kept seeing him looking over my
shoulder at this guy.
He grabs a bluetooth speaker and it's
like pretending like he's going to go to
the checkout and I'm just being polite
and thinking there's something going on.
So let's just get him down and out of
the store.
Then he goes to do a full runner for it.
Dude,
straight out the door with this
Bluetooth speaker.
But all mate,
like had these runners on and chased him
down and go to the orpheum.
Yeah.
And um,
I'm like,
every time I come here there's something
crazy going on.
Well,
if you're in the wrong place,
the wrong time is plenty of crazy going
on in the show.
That's just so many people.
There's so many people.
That's what it is.
Yeah.
There's no way around it,
but you know,
fairly safe fit,
shooting water buffalo,
each Sifa.
Then fucking people's bullshit.
That's crazy site for them.
People know when you're Adam Green tree
may be.
It's safer because you know what you're
doing,
but you were telling a story on whose
podcast was it a J.
Scott's,
I forget whose podcast it was.
You were telling a story about one of
your friends that got gored federal
labor that got gored by scrub bullying.
That's not good.
No,
it's definitely not good.
But I did I tell you that story.
So what happened?
He shot a scrabble telling people
would've scrubbed bullets.
Yeah.
So scrubbing bubbles like a,
just like domestic cattle,
but it's been out in the wilderness
many,
many generations.
Exactly the way they look and they have
like a real feral inbred looking.
They're crazy look like rice cooking and
they they crazy dangerous.
Here's a photo of him we looked at.
I mean,
that looks amazing.
That is such a cool looking animal that
was so much different.
And that's pretty much a purebred
Brahman.
That one.
There's that one.
Whoa.
Yeah.
That's.
Looks like.
So when you said it's a purebred Brahma,
that means,
uh,
that's,
that's a pretty good look bowl.
If you go up the top Jaimee,
there's a couple more at the top.
That red one that you just done under
that one day.
That's a pretty typical scrabble a.
that's a,
that's a fellow that I know actually in
Australia.
Stick Ball.
He's got.
Yeah,
he's got a by her,
that's what we have with.
Oh Jesus.
Why do people do that to themselves?
So the problem with these animals,
obviously they don't respect fences and
now going varied and interbreed with log
of farmer's stock and things like that.
Is that,
is that bad for the farmer started?
Definitely.
Yeah.
That they'll just go straight through
fences and yeah,
he'll have a heap of carbs and I
wouldn't be purebred anymore.
And so they're not,
they don't good for rebranding or like
my fixed the same value at the market.
So what is the difference in like the
genetics,
like what do they look?
They look different,
they look different.
So that first bullet Jamie showed was
like a Brahmin bull,
then one of those scrub bulls,
which is just bits of frigging every
sort of bull over a lot of generations
will come in and need and buried with it
and then sort of wrecks the hood.
And when,
when did they get released or when did
they escape?
Well,
it would have been with the cattle that
come into Australia.
So it would have been hundreds and
hundreds.
Yeah.
So they're just sort of morphed and
become wild animals and wild bulls.
Very dangerous.
Yeah.
So what happened was,
Pedro,
I shot these bullets,
dropped,
like dropped unconscious.
He fought it was dead,
walked up to it.
It jumped up.
Like he literally got up to it and it
jumped off and anyway,
it ain't not getting him against the
tree.
Like he ran to get up a tree.
He felt it hit him and it sort of lifted
him up the tree.
He climbed up the tree is the growth
vit.
Then he felt something warm and his legs
and look down and he's got and
everything hanging down.
I read legs,
but use a tough boss that he gravity,
stomach backup and sorta held the.
Implies the end.
The bull actually died.
He climbed down out of the trade,
ended up dawn two times,
I think once in the air because the
royal flying doctors come in,
grabbed him because he's a long way out
in the middle of nowhere.
And uh,
and once on the tables operating table
as well.
He survived all that and ended up dying
of a bloody mess.
Heart attack.
So no way.
Yeah.
When,
uh,
it was on the thing,
he was only 36 or 37.
Do you think it had anything to do with
the that I reckon it was related at all
really?
You would think that a guy could get
past getting gored by pushes guts back
into,
I'm not going to get a heart attack.
That's life's not fair.
Right?
That's crazy.
Oh,
thank you.
Jamie.
I think it was adjusting my shoot
license card as well.
If you don't have shoelaces,
you got those fat tires.
It's a little in the weeds like those.
Everyone asked me about my boots,
I'll get a glimpse of me,
whatever shoes I'm wearing,
my
shoot some awesome animal and they're
like,
what shoes you're wearing?
People are gearheads.
That's a big thing about hunting is how
many people are like crazy gearheads
like what?
You want to know,
what kind of bow you have,
what kind of,
what sites do you run in?
Like what kind of load of old.
It's really interesting to me maybe
because I've done it for so long,
but I sort of don't care about the gears
as long as it works,
as good as it should,
you know,
and that's because everyone asks me to
keep doing these tip things as well and
I hate doing that.
I hate listening to them.
But if you're a new guy coming into
bowhunting,
then obviously you want to know.
Some people love that stuff man.
Like John Dudley's tips that he does,
like he does these live instagram and
youtube,
but facebook feeds or he'll like take a
bow apart,
put it back together again and explain
the cam systems are extreme with it to
Hayes Hayes.
My go to guy,
if I don't know something that I'm doing
that's I'll go straight to Dudley.
Dudley is podcasts.
If you're into archery is called knock
on is the knock on podcast is without a
doubt the most in depth archery podcast
from not just hunting from a hunting
standpoint but from just target archery.
How,
you know,
how important technique is.
I mean he's a real master.
He loves it and he's a super geared to
eight years.
Has Your,
has your cyber October going crazy?
It's going good.
The sober part's easy.
The uh,
the hot yoga,
we're in the homestretch today was a
number 13,
so I got two more.
I'm banging them out this week.
I'm going to do tomorrow and Friday and
be done with it because I want to get
back to doing other stuff.
And when you do a 90 minute yoga class,
it's hard to live weights or run or do
anything else.
You don't really want to do anything
else,
you know,
so I'm just going to bang it out and get
it over with.
Kim's done at once and she recommends.
It was like hell on just the yoga.
I think she had a big drinking session
before she was in Bali and she just made
some stupid promise,
bolonaise woman.
And then the fifth bolonaise woman's
ringing her up the next morning.
Like,
where are you if a yoga came,
just thought it was yoga though.
So she's like,
ah,
I can do yoga in my sleep.
And she gets here and it's like in this
hot room and stuff.
And it might.
It was killing us.
Bali too.
I would imagine.
It's very humid,
humid.
It'd be Muggy as hell.
Ari was talking about that today because
our,
he does yoga in New York,
which is way more humid than it is in
California.
California is dry,
so he was probably loving.
I just.
Oh yeah.
We went to a different place today.
Today we went to a place that was more
mild,
so not as hot,
but um,
it's not,
it's your body gets used to it.
It's interesting.
It's like there's a lot like,
uh,
you know,
I do that cryotherapy style you like did
it to yesterday for the first time in
about three weeks I guess.
And it was hard.
Whereas I do it when I do it everyday.
It's not conditioned to it.
You just get in there and I do,
but it's,
it's quick how that conditioning goes
away.
Yeah.
I hate to just say the peak tufts that I
did,
it was pretty bad job of said to them
yet,
here's are cutters.
No,
I've never killed a bar.
Going to kill the
cells.
You need to come to Australia.
I do,
but I'm scared to be honest with you.
Every time I look at your instagram feed
and I see a brown snake that can kill
you or a spider that can kill your
fucking saltwater crocodiles.
What are you doing?
Playing with crocodiles the other day
were coming into camp.
Dude.
There was a couple of,
I wish I captured it on video.
It was one that she,
I think it was a female anyway,
she must've been coming around the back
of camp unnoticed.
So the windshield was heading back to
the water.
She was literally come and strike
through camp to get back into the water.
And you could,
is that thing.
That photo doesn't do that thing.
Justice.
That photo scares the shit out of me.
That's a real.
That's a real live monster out there.
How big was that fucker?
He's about five and a half meters.
Whoa.
He's giant.
He's always,
you can even see it in the picture of
his body's just a real log crawl.
Five and a half meters to Americans.
I want you to take about 15 feet marco
days.
Um,
so a few people have been taken at this
spot.
Mostly indigenous had been grabbed.
Granted that spot over the years.
And when you see an ancient piece like
that,
there's a chance.
He's a man eater.
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
They just ruthless.
I like.
How old do you think?
A 15 and a half foot crocodile is.
I don't want to comment because I don't
know and I'll probably get it wrong.
I would like to know like how long does
it take them to grow?
15 and a half feet.
So if you could find that Jamie
Saltwater CROC and I'm pretty sure that
I believe over a hundred years.
Yeah,
they,
they live a long time,
right?
Yeah.
So he's ruthless to like people who live
in Florida don't get those confused with
alligators.
Yeah,
there are different completely different
animals.
So we've got the freshwater crocodile
which just lives in fresh water.
Then we've got the salt water crocodile,
but he leaves in both,
you know.
And so a lot of people get that
confused.
I call it's fresh water.
I'll be right there.
Go for a swim.
Uh,
no.
So the fresh water crocodiles and not as
aggressive.
They're not aggressive.
They might get a bit territorial,
but they're not going to grab you to
eight.
Whereas the Saudi will grab you to a.
He just looked like.
And they keep growing throughout their
lifespan,
require more and more food with the
amount.
When the amount of food is unavailable,
they die from starvation.
And the reason why you don't see a
thousand year old crocodiles that are 50
feet long.
Wow.
That's the only reason.
Holy Shit.
The way they died of starvation or as if
they contracted disease.
Oh my God.
They just keep growing.
So that's why they.
That's why these ones in captivity,
because they get hand fed.
Yeah,
probably get the biggest.
That's where you'll see your biggest
crux.
The Guinness Book of World Records,
the Saltwater Crocodile Cotton Australia
as the largest crocodile in captivity
measures 17 feet,
11 point seven,
five inches.
So basically 18 feet.
That's huge.
So that my body,
my body,
Andrew Equals.
Have you heard of your ankles?
No habit.
Oh,
he's,
he's like a youtube sensation.
He's been captured in just about
everything in Australia for the last
millennium.
And um,
he's,
he's seen a six w made a crocodile
before.
When he's one of these guys.
You don't bullshit.
Like if he says he's seen a six meter
crocodile,
he's seen a six meter crocodile.
Yeah.
Well that's just the biggest one in
captivity.
Right?
So that's probably,
and Australia has a ton of food.
Tons of food.
Yeah.
So it's not like this,
this starved to death.
This river system.
We went down there fishing and we've
probably traveled an hour down the river
and a little tinny little boat.
I reckon we've seen 200 to 250 salt
water crocodiles in that time.
She's like,
because like they can't harvest them or
they don't call me out or anything like
that.
Did.
There are laws protecting them so there
is as low as protecting them.
So that's why the place is just riddled
with them at mathematical laws
protecting them.
It sounds like they're on posted.
Well anything that's a night even
Australia is protected.
So like you guys,
you know how you can hunt,
you're white tailed deer and everything
like that.
Australia can't hunt Kangaroos,
you can't hunt any native.
So everything we hunting is an
introduced species and native.
So you can't hunt them and there's been
talk about bringing in like a program.
But I don't know if it will happen but
that's,
that's so weird.
Yeah,
it seems to me to be very strange.
It's like completely different system.
Yeah,
but it makes sense that you guys hunt
all the non native species because
they're invasive and devastate the wild,
the land and the other wildlife.
Like you guys have crazy problems with
feral cats.
We talked about that before and you know
that you have pigs everywhere and nyman
donkeys,
horses,
even the funny ones that people don't
think about like donkeys,
wild horses,
camels.
I think camels probably get a little bit
of exposure.
Then we'll go to all your typical stuff.
You know,
pigs,
goats,
we've got the 60 years bcs.
So if we didn't have any of those
introduced species,
we.
There'd be no hunting in Australia.
So what but what do they say?
That sounds nuts.
So they're only hunting just to get rid
of the invasive species?
That's correct.
How do they control the populations of
the Kangaroos or you can get like a
permit.
I couldn't as a bow hunter or just a
hunter,
couldn't get a permit,
but if you're a professional shooter
lucky shooting for human consumption or
petmate or something like that,
or if you're a big land owner,
you can get like a tag or permits to
shoot Kangaroos then every now and then
to be an organized coal because they let
them get so far out of control that
they,
they eat the ground down to just pretty
much.
Then they lie around and die a slow
death of a couple of months because I
lose nutrition,
you know,
they've weakened,
they don't move and it's obviously,
it's a bit very painful way for to go.
Once it gets to that point,
it seems like they like,
oh,
we need to do a column now.
So it,
all it is,
is we've spoken about these people were
for the greenies,
you know,
these people that really don't have a
good picture on it and see that uh,
Carl or hunting program is actually
better welfare for the animals because
they stay healthier and in check.
Well they,
yeah.
They don't have any predators.
Exactly.
Yeah.
Some places got wild dogs and Dingos,
but that's about it.
Yeah.
And how many dingoes can take out a
kangaroo.
Kangaroos get pretty goddamn bad.
Yeah,
they do.
They take them out,
they try and take down buffalo and
stuff.
But they are.
They really?
Yeah.
I don't think they very successful.
They'd pick off a pig or a pig.
Little something like that.
Yeah man,
you know,
it's just,
I just don't understand why they would
not try to keep the crocodiles and check
if you've seen it.
Hundreds and hundreds of crocodiles like
that because one of those things gonna
eat what's going on here.
Jamie says in Malaysia,
a CROC shut up in front of somebody's
shop and they were trying to get rid of
it and they apparently don't know how
people have held a month ago and while
they have helmets and maybe they're
going to hit,
but it take.
The guy's got a gaffe was what is he
going to do here?
Is trying to throw a tarp on it.
So they called Jesus Christ like a bad
idea.
This is hilarious.
They're all wearing Camo.
Uh,
but why are they wearing red camera?
Or it might be the fireman.
I think it looks like truck right there.
But why the firemen were like,
what do they blending into?
Let's go right in it.
That's a uniform.
You think they got their helmets on?
Put that helmet.
Looks like a motorcycle helmet.
A different country captain diversity
over here.
Jamie Vernon and big data.
That's a good size.
Big fucker.
And he's got his mouth open to like,
he's like,
bitch,
I'll kill you all this gary,
I,
oh,
they're so different.
Like I grew up when I was,
when I grew up actually,
but I lived there for three years.
I lived in Gainesville,
Florida and when I lived there,
alligators were protected.
They used to be protected and we used to
go to this place called Lake Alice and
we would throw marshmallows and the
water and the alligators would come up
and eat the marshmallows.
But then they start snatching people's
dogs.
I remember this one lady freaked out one
snatcher dogs just pull it right off her
leash and she freaked out and that
started happening more and more.
And then the population got denser and
denser one point in time they were
endangered.
Now they're infested.
Now there's so many alligators that
they.
Have you ever seen that show swamp
people that show where they go hunting
for alligators,
which you know,
people make purses and shoes and shit
out of them.
They get 500 tags,
$500 so they can chew 500 fucking
allocated just to keep the population
healthy.
And the food is apparently very good.
The tail meat is apparently delicious.
I think Benny I brought in was just down
there somewhere,
maybe a month back down there and now
like my set of line and hook them and
taking a haven meet.
Obviously the girl off the skins and
things like that.
The leather of the skins,
the meat is very good.
Dudley handsome.
He bow haunts him every year.
He goes to Orlando outside of Orlando.
I'd like to be pretty cool.
That'd be pretty cool.
Well,
they taste good too.
And they're in.
It's a conservation thing too because
it's like you really do need to control
their population.
Yeah.
Australia needs to get to that point.
What?
What's happening now is they're pushing
into domestic waters,
you know,
like Darwin,
the cds,
like build around,
you know,
a big,
big river being lit or a big water
system and the guys would go swim in
there and get taken all the time and I
will people's dogs jumping and they get
taken.
I think I've seen a video,
I don't know if it was Darwin
or where it was,
but um,
some lady's filming and then just say
the back of a crock go on the luck of
jetty and then the,
the face of the crop comes out and it's
got a full size domestic dog and its
jaws.
It was imagined saying that how creepy
side it was swimming in a river system.
Like a,
like a,
seems like a,
like some sort of aqua doctors.
Crazy.
I big dog today.
Just it runs like,
you know,
everyone talks about big foot.
This is the one Jesus look at the color
on it.
God,
that thing is so big,
like fluffy.
That is a monster.
Just a straight up.
I mean,
what are they like?
I think they're more than 30 million
years old.
Yeah,
I think I really,
I don't think they've changed in 30 plus
million years.
I think they just look at everything as
potentially food and that's where the
risk is and that's the assignment.
If it's assigned with a big grizzly
bear,
you know,
they just look at everything as a va
danger so they feel frightened and want
to attack it or it's food.
Have you ever seen Jim shockey's show?
You know,
that show uncharted that he does?
Yep.
Have yet jim shockey's uncharted one of
them ones.
He went to Africa and I think it was the
Congo,
um,
I think it was the Congo River,
south of the Congo River,
I don't know.
Anyway,
it was a river and this,
a native population that lived there.
These villagers,
they lived right on the river banks and
they were just getting taken left and
riper crocodiles.
Everyone in the village had like an arm
missing or chunk cut out of their head.
Is this sit right here?
Jim shockey,
Mozambique,
Mozambique.
There we go.
Thank you.
And Jim shockey's.
Just amazing.
But these things,
look at what they got here.
One of them was feasting on some sort of
an animal.
See,
look at these guys.
They all have like a,
a stump where their arm is and there's
Jim and so they wanted to bring in
professional hunters to try to help
control the population because they were
actively targeting the people that live
there.
And these people,
I mean they,
they live in a very small,
very primitive village and all they have
is the water.
I mean,
that's where they're getting their water
from,
which it off is about to fucking make
the kill shot.
Youtube glitch was fucking.
Oh,
really?
Kept flashing.
What is that?
I needed to refresh it.
It was just,
it happens on youtube from time to time
on,
on the computer or normal.
Just normal.
Yeah,
just the browser.
But um,
it just does the poor people that lived
there.
I mean,
you just got to imagine if this is your
only play.
These people aren't traveling.
They don't have cars.
They don't have.
They're not flying anywhere.
This is where they live.
They have to build these sort of fences
around these little tiny bays.
They build these small makeshift fences
to try to protect themselves from the
crocodiles when they clean,
they clean their food or gather water or
wash their clothes once that risk every
day.
Fuck.
This is one of the reasons why I do
these radical hunts because it makes you
realize how good we've got it,
right?
Yeah.
Like a like we just go to the tap and
turn the tap on and we get water or if
you want to share her a bath,
it's in the comfort of your own house.
These people are just trying to get
water to drink and they.
They could get snatched.
Well,
people have been snatched.
Isn't that ridiculous?
And that's their life and there's no
other life.
They know that their ancestors had been
there and their grandparents had been
there.
Their fathers had been there,
their mothers and now them.
And this is life.
That's why anytime someone complains
about Australia or it in theU ,
s or whatever,
it's like,
dude,
fuck.
Go look at what you have got so easy.
Isn't it crazy?
It's so crazy.
I mean,
I was watching your instagram feed when
you were taking water or this buffalo
wallow and throwing it through a filter
and put it in.
Now when you're a bit concerned about
that because I like when I looked into
the filter,
just even video.
Is that on your instagram?
It might be still alive on the
instagram.
It's on normal.
So normal instagram normally go to cvs
because that way we could see.
So to start as I moved probably 200
buffalo off that water hall and like a
couple of mobs of pigs that were all
like they go and ride out into the water
and try and cool off.
He has a least one big salt water
crocodile in there as well,
but I'm walking out there with that bag
to you by yourself?
Yeah,
I'm by myself.
Correct.
And I'm sleeping in a little cloth
house.
Yeah.
I have a guys back in camp,
but I was just down in the hunt,
Wyoming so that it just said this was
pretty new.
I didn't know if it was older.
Yeah,
I think it's it and yeah.
yeah.
I'm barefoot walking up to the water
with this pumps.
I'm going look at this.
Look at this.
Look at.
This is a big frigging buffalo to
sitting right there in the water that's
old for the water.
Do not drink and then frigging dehydrate
and die out there.
But you drink and Turd water.
Yeah.
That's why I hope the field to work.
Now,
how do these filters work?
How does that.
Well,
they claim to filter out 99 point nine,
nine,
nine percent of all the germs.
It's zero,
zero,
zero.
One.
It's going to fuck you or something on
the edge of the bag that runs down,
you know,
that's probably going to get you.
But um,
how often do you get beaver fever when
you do?
I've never been,
I've never been sick from drinking water
out in the Bush or eating.
That's any of the meat or anything like
that.
Never ever,
ever,
ever talked to dad,
spends time in the bush,
gets sick.
How have you not gotten anybody?
Andrea equals.
And He seems like a pretty hardy dude.
And he's like,
oh,
so have you had this?
And I'm like,
no,
have you had this?
I'm like,
no,
have you had this?
Like not nearly died from this.
I'm like,
what?
I've had none of those.
And I've drank.
There was one time I was so desperate
for water.
This has gone back to when I was like,
looks like actually it looks all right.
It looks pretty good.
Taste off the filter.
The water tastes like Piss piss and I'm
like,
shouldn't have that filter because the
taste is obviously something but it's
still piss.
It's still paced but it's probably
actually really good for you.
Drinking is good friend with Duke in
that water.
Do you put like a c?
You've got a mountain ops bottle.
Do you put some flavor in there?
Just to mask it a bit.
I think I'd run out at this point that
was like 27 kilometer hike that day.
Um,
so you just deal with the taste.
Do you just deal with it and you know
what,
you're that first either.
It doesn't really bother you at the
time.
Well,
when you did that epic hunt up here in
cow in,
um,
we were starting in Colorado.
Right.
And then you went to Idaho,
Idaho,
but I didn't actually hunt Idaho across
through Idaho into the back of Montana.
Yeah.
And trying to find a spot with limited
hunters and more elk and we were all
following you on instagram stories was a
tough haunt.
Those tapes that I left out of it and
unlike,
I'll just save this for Joe,
but well I got really sick like for like
they always just liquid coming out of
frigging every you got sick from waters.
I don't want to admit that.
Hey,
you just said you never got because a
couple of pit people writing me messages
and like that's a good way to get sick.
And I'm like I've done these heaps as
long as you do.
And you drank red on the ground.
Oh yeah.
I actually,
I ate some jerky that had been,
I left it in the tank and the tank got
really hot.
Like the start of the hunt.
It was the heat was soaring,
you know,
and the,
the,
he wouldn't be sweaty in that in the
bag,
but I'll stop and so I'm like,
I'm just going to eat it.
And then it was nearly like two hours
later that I was lucky.
I don't feel real good about 'em.
I've never been tent bound in me life
and I'm just like not just keep
haunting,
don't worry about it.
So this is bad.
I probably shouldn't say it,
but I literally hunt for five minutes
and have to pull me straight down,
you know,
and then go number twos and then walk
for another five minutes and be like,
Oh fuck,
you know,
informed my brains out for a couple of
days.
Two days,
two days.
I think that's because I lost 17 kilos.
I reckon I lost 10 of them in them.
Couple of days.
What's that in pounds?
Seventeen kilos.
It's a lot of pounds.
Thirty five.
Lost that much weight.
Yet I had my pants were falling off me
dude.
Like,
like literally falling off me from being
taught on the to fallen off me.
So this was because you were hiking
every day.
Just how I can everyday I w I hiked over
frowned,
remodels,
hold up for a hundred and 14 miles.
I think it was all up 22 days.
That's so crazy.
That's limited food and um,
you know,
maybe that bad jerky helped as well.
So I'm going to start a weight loss
program or my friend Burke.
It did a yoga today.
He's obsessed with you.
Is going to be on the podcast as well.
Kim sent me a link and she's like,
you should have,
you should listen to this podcast.
And I listened to it and he's like,
I feel like I could be friends with that
dude.
And I'm like,
yeah,
we can be friends.
Then he put frigging on Instagram,
some dude trying to milk.
He's nibbles and we can't be fucking
friends,
but he's won me back either because he'd
done that hilarious video if you dance
in the dialogue was crying.
Yeah,
we did our uh,
13th.
He and I did our 13th yoga class today
and Ren Tom are on number 14.
Two more to go for me.
One for logos.
Those two guys told at the homestretch,
but yeah,
nothing compared to 28 days in the bush.
It was good.
I loved it.
I missed a lot of things.
Like it makes you realize,
you know,
like I said how lucky we are off and,
and I've always been the person that
doesn't take anything for granted
anyway,
but it's just that,
you know,
it really rings home,
the simple thing.
So you just just went out there.
Look,
you didn't necessarily have a good area
that had been scouted out.
Definitely didn't have a good area,
but um,
met a real nice young dude actually
messaged me for instagram at the time.
I could hardly get to any messages and
about.
Anyway,
that was one that I read and he's like,
look,
while you're in this unit,
he picked what unit is he in?
He's like,
come over to this area of hunter for
pretty much my whole life.
And there's a few good bulls there.
Now the first day or the second day that
I was in there,
I was saying three really good bulls and
that's what kept me there because I kept
thinking I'm going to find them bulls
again and I just cleaned off.
I just moved out of the area.
Um,
the whole idea of hunting in Colorado
was because last year I had a couple of
issues with grizzlies in Montana and
doing saw law.
I'm lucky you're a,
you're a decade if you do that again
because you got three young kids and a
beautiful wife.
Like it's a big risk to take,
like I take risks,
but that's one that's out of my control.
You know,
grizzly going.
Yeah.
And so I kept trying to avoid that area
and then when I wasn't fun in bulls,
like,
so I ended up moving out to Colorado,
went to Idaho and walked into the back
of Montana where there's supposed to be
less grizzlies.
And that's where I got charged by
grizzly bears.
A lot of grizzlies and Montana.
Man,
it's crazy.
They're out of control too.
They just frigging like the crocs on dry
land.
You saw grizzlies in Colorado?
I did yet.
Oh,
this is the cutest thing.
I've caught so much flack over that.
Now you're positive.
These were grizzle hundred percent.
Now what does a black.
There's black bear in the same area and
I nearly could do the comparison because
it was a black bear there and it was a
grizzly day saying the black bear first
and I'm like,
oh,
this in.
You'll see the video.
Like,
oh,
there's a black bear over there.
That's pretty cool.
She's got cubs,
so I just want to try and avoid her.
Then looking at these Alpha Bayer and
all this thing.
Grizzlies before this,
things that completely different beasts.
There's no mistake in the two.
It's not like a.
that's just the.
That's a young looking Greasley that
might tell it now.
It looks like a big black bear.
No,
it's a frigging massive grizzly and
compare it to a massive black bed.
There's still a massive height
difference and everything.
The big write up shoulders.
The big square head spotting scope with
you.
Now I did not just have maybe been
oculus and 10,
40 two's 10 by 42 is the mavens yet.
So the same one too.
You got a good look at it.
Awesome.
Look,
but at that point I just figured,
Oh shit,
there is grizzlies in Colorado.
Just the couple of people that told me
all you won't see grizzlies.
They just didn't know the area.
Right.
So I didn't think much of it.
So I did the little film for the buyer
knows and stuff like that and like
there's a big Mama grizzly up there.
She's got carbs.
I definitely want to stay away from her.
Then I wanted the whole my ass out of
that because that's an advice and I
wanted the whole mindset of that Bison
and not sleeping that base in for the
night.
So I've moved on pretty quick.
Got to the top of the ridge,
looked at her again.
She was fading along.
I'm like cool.
Then slept on the other side of the
ridge.
Then come back through there in the
morning,
spotted her again in the morning,
kept walking out of there.
Then I got reception again and then I
had a hit with messages.
There's not supposed to be an ingredient
leads in Colorado.
I'm like,
fuck,
I just,
I just blew it off as in,
Oh,
there is grizzlies here.
Shit,
these guys got it wrong.
Not that it's a massive big deal and
that is not supposed to be at all and no
one wants to admit that there are there.
So this is a no one wants to admit it or
is it you were deep into the tree?
Yeah,
that as well.
So there's a multiple sightings in the
area.
I don't want to say the area because
next year I'm going to go back and
document it with a decent camera and
everything like that to try to get some
video of too and get some real good
evidence and stuff like that.
So I haven't really spoken about a lot
since then because I just got pounded
with messages going,
there's no grizzlies in Colorado,
you idiot.
What don't you want to tell?
Like wildlife biologists or someone that
apparently they already know and I don't
want to admit it because of the whole
protected space.
He's act and everything like that.
Well,
what does that mean though?
Why would they want to admit that
there's bears there?
I think it might be a pain in the ass.
I don't know.
I don't understand.
I,
but I'm keen to get to the bottom of it.
You know,
it's sort of on this Yamaha.
I come back in there again and I'm going
to try and get some good evidence,
but it seems to me that they would want.
I mean,
I don't understand why they would want
to deny the existence,
not able to lie,
but a lot of people are saying this
actually.
I think there's a website where it takes
in people's sightings and stuff like
that and all the sidings and the last
grizzlies known in Colorado.
We're all in this mountain range.
That probably gives a lot of it away.
But the San Jose San Jose mountain
range.
It is.
Yeah.
But no,
it's massive.
Like,
Oh God,
I'm not too worried.
All of the last sightings were there and
I think the last sightings were in the
eighties,
maybe the early nineties there was
grease Liza,
and when you look at a map and you look
at the range,
it's.
It'd be nothing for him to be there.
Still was this bought new ones.
Walk in there.
There's grizzlies in Wyoming,
right?
Connected.
Yep.
So of course they're probably there.
Why do they think that you get up there
and you have a look at this mountain
range and as just 100 percent in grizzly
country.
Oh,
that,
that one there.
I'm the last sighting occurred in 2,600
independent pass officials investigated
but found nothing to 1979 bear had cubs
are likely dead.
That's A.
is that a bear right there for that?
They got on camera.
That's obviously a grizzly.
Yeah.
You could tell the difference.
I saw one in Alberta.
I've only seen one if that is a
colleague.
Yeah.
This thing that I seen towel is over
that,
like we're talking about a fully mature
Mava grizzly.
So you're talking about like a 10 foot
bear.
Yeah,
just a huge bear,
like there's no mistaking it.
This thing would windshields walk and
you could see like she's out here like
this,
you know,
like had,
when I get big and mature you'll see
they've got like a silver back on them,
like a grip,
like a gorilla,
you know,
they've got this silver back on him like
this,
like the last part of the hair goes
silver.
She's that she's the right color,
the right shape,
the right size and everything.
So
hmm.
So you only saw her in her cubs or you
saw more?
Her and her cubs and then Novalon
there's a photo of another one that's
just the cinnamon black bay are.
And I think a lot of few people got
confused and that's probably on my end
from.
I just posted a story about a grizzly
and then I had these other best shot
static results from 2011.
It says actually steamboat springs.
Yeah.
Okay.
That's Colorado.
Nearly look at that as a cinnamon phase.
Black Bay to go to a be wrong.
Go,
go.
Can you make that larger Jamie?
It's as big as it gets.
That might be a grizzly.
Yeah,
it could be,
but yeah,
you might be right though.
That could be a collar phase.
Brown bear,
black bear rather
test looking at.
If it's a younger Greasley then maybe
not.
But she had this frigging massive head
dude like flared out like this,
you know,
the big read on the back and
it'd be interesting if Adam Green tree
was the one who proved that they're
almost dry.
A grizzly bear was in Colorado,
but the point is there's very few people
that are going to the mountain ranges.
Like how far back were you from the
trail head at?
Well,
so I've wrote a really rough trail head
on a mountain bike for so far.
Then that trial pretty much disappeared
out to nothing.
Then I hiked a full,
must've been seven hours because she was
like just before sundown.
So it would've been a good seven hours
in the back then and that's because
there was no elk that's going nonstop,
you know,
and if you watched the video run a lot
of it because it was just what I call
dead country,
you know,
there was not,
not really good looking hunting country.
So you'll see me sort of trotting along
most of it.
So it was a long way back.
There was no human footprints up there.
There was nothing like that.
Ten miles,
15 miles,
probably 60 miles I think it was.
So the odds of people going back there
on a regular basis are probably pretty
slim.
Very slim.
Yeah.
So they probably just don't know.
And now that that's one of the issues
that apparently they're dealing with
NBC,
you know,
in bc when you talk to the people that
live there versus the people that are.
You know how BC has banned grizzly
hunting.
Yeah.
The people that live in Greece,
BC are terrified of that now because
they're like,
we to control these goddamn things.
Like you don't like what they say.
The people that I know that live up
there,
they say the wildlife biologists are
rarely here like they need and the
hunters that people that live up there,
the outfitters,
it's like you need to take like some
sort of a census from us.
Boots on the ground ground.
Yeah,
that's right.
and the way they describe it as like
there was a greedy bowman did a podcast
about this with one of the guys that
lives up there,
that's an outfitter,
and he was saying we encountered them
all the time and they're hyper
aggressive like you,
you're talking about people.
These biologists that are rarely there.
There's not like any like really
involved intricate census that they're
doing with their go really in depth
accounting of all the bears.
He's like,
you got to get information from the
people that lived there and do.
They're going to tell you there's a lot
of them.
Yup.
Well,
they're not smart enough to control
their sales are because a lot of these
people just want to sit back and just
let these animals do.
Will do.
That's the idea.
They want to do NBC.
They think that what they can do is,
I mean this is speculation,
but they think that what they can do is
let the,
instead of let the people control the
predators,
they think let the predators eat all the
game that they can and then when they
don't have enough food to,
populations are naturally going to
diminish.
Yeah,
no,
I like the idea that ain't gonna work.
What can happen,
but it could take 50,
60 years and the problem is along that
you're gonna get a lot of human death,
going to get a lot of pets.
You're gonna get a lot of animals that
are going to invade into farmlands.
It just seems to me that that's not a
wise way to handle it.
No,
definitely not.
And it's also they're going to have to
pay money to kill problem bears and
instead of making money,
but they don't like.
Look,
this whole Cecil,
the lion thing,
I think fucked a lot of people up.
You know,
people.
The idea of some evil person just going
over there and shooting some beloved
animal.
That became the narrative and everybody
sort of has this idea in their head that
this is what bear hunting is.
It's the same sort of thing.
We don't want that MPC.
No,
it's,
it really is something that needs to be
discussed on both sides and I think both
sides have points when it comes to like
quote unquote trophy hunting,
you know?
Yeah,
yeah.
I'm definitely not for one or the other.
It's not like we want to walk them off
the face of the planet.
We just want to see these healthy,
a healthy population
and the people that live around there
and a lot of them depend on moose meat
and deer meat and these bear going to
decimate the populations.
If they don't control the populations of
bear,
they will.
Something else has got to change.
They're going to decimate the game
populations.
Yeah,
sure.
I don't,
I don't.
I actually think the areas that I hunt
in Montana aren't overpopulated with
grizzlies,
from what I've seen just populated.
They just populated.
So this,
the,
the place that I ended up going into in
Montana isn't my usual spot,
you know,
and there wasn't supposed to be as many
grizzlies and that was,
you would have seen the video where I
walk over the rise and then all of a
sudden we locked eyes at the same time
and then she in a split second,
she just comes straight at me and I'll
tell the story because he hates the
people keep asking.
But I'm uh,
I'm one of these people that I practice
with whatever I'm shooting with memory.
When the,
uh,
the free day leafy suits came out,
it was a,
like a camouflage suit and it had like
free tea leaves on it hanging off it.
And I like I got laughed at because I
went to the archery range and shot in
it.
And the first time I shot in the string
of the boat,
hit the leaves in my shirt was off.
So yeah,
Ghillie suit,
like just practice with whatever they
use.
And so my buddies,
a sheriff in Idaho,
he's gonna lend me a hand gun.
So he lends me to hang on.
Like dude,
I've never even tried to hang out and
you just can't get them in Australia
like that,
so I want to practice.
We went out and practiced and we
practiced with a cheaper bullet,
you know,
and it was like a solid solid bullet.
It was awesome.
I picked it up straight away and there
was no dramas.
I was a good shot with it.
Just trying to do a rashad thinking if a
bear of a Getcha it's going to be in a
rush.
It's not like these,
you know,
pull it,
pull the gun out and have a heap of
time.
So I was practicing shooting with one
hand and everything like that.
Anyway,
when it comes to going on the hunt,
he gave me some expense,
pensive bullets,
and now our hollow point with like a
real flat front on it.
So we never shot those bullets.
Anyway,
this grizzly charged,
I pulled the gun out,
she stopped at 20 meters the first time.
Like I just try,
I stayed stationary,
I didn't want to do any radical
movements,
but I just yelled at her.
She stopped at $20,000,000.
She turned back and went to a cub and at
this point I cubs just at the base of
the tree.
She got there as soon as she's saying
that the cop was all right.
She just comes straight back at me
again,
like,
like massive bear,
like rice and strike that made.
I had the handgun to the handguns out
now because I pulled it out the first
time.
This time she come all the way to 10
meters and I,
and I'll actually,
I laid this out just for now,
just tell it how it went.
And I pulled the gun out.
I yelled at her again like that.
She stopped,
she did a big swipe on the ground,
spun and went straight back to the
login.
See soon as she got back to the cob,
this time she rented a side load,
tried to flank me.
You know,
it freaks me out how fast these things
can move.
Like,
like you've seen our foster dad can get
off the mark I and agrees leads faster
than the D or.
And you think of the size of a grizzly
and it can still move at the speed of a
deer or faster.
Like in.
She just disappears into this.
There's all this scrub beside me I can't
see.
So I'm like standing there like,
like just white and where's she going to
pop out?
Because I fought the third time she's
going to,
she ain't fucking around.
She's going to try and kill me the third
time she never showed up and I stayed
there for a little while and just start
backing up.
And that's what I've got the camera out
because the other thing I'm fearful of
is shooting one and not being able to
justify it because you people go to
jail,
get massive fall.
And so I'm like,
all want a document?
They started telling that she's coming
album probably gonna pull the trigger.
I want to document it anyway.
I back out.
She sort stalks along a little bit like
watching me and stuff like that.
Then she disappears and I walk away and
then I realized the guns jammed.
The gun's been in that whole time and I
was like,
let's say shit.
So she did come for me,
like truly come from me.
I was fucked like there was no doubt
about what was going on in those hollow
points with the flat face and I'm
wouldn't load up into the chamber of the
gun.
They hit on the throat of the revolver
and won't go up in there.
So you'd never would have gotten off a
shot.
I would never would have gotten off a
And then I was thinking when the time
that she to 10 meters,
because I thought she was going to jump
me it when she come that time and I was
like,
fuck,
I'm surprised the gun didn't go off
because I'm sure I had the finger on the
trigger.
Like I just remember thinking white and
it happened that fast that I reckon that
second time she come at me when she was
about the 12 or 11 made them.
Or even when she just come past the
original mark that she stopped at 20
meters.
I reckon I pulled the trigger and it
didn't go off and I kept thinking like
there's a slide lock on the gun and I
kept thinking that was jammed up and it
wasn't at all.
Those bullets just didn't fit in that
gun fit in there.
So you never practiced with them at all.
So he entire time you were unarmed yet
tire time.
I was unarmed.
I bought,
I bought bear spray from Cabela's.
This man,
it was like the world was fucking out to
get me a bought bear spray from Cabela's
and it's on the audit and the light.
He didn't put in the bag and I got up
there and unpack the bags on luck.
Where's the bear spray?
Fuck.
I don't even know the bear spray might.
So I was able to.
When she was all me,
if I even had this chance,
I was ever going to pull an arrow out of
the ball and just try and stab her or
auto or do you lie dead and cop it or
what they say with a female grizzly just
try to lay dead because they're just
trying to eliminate a threat to the
cubs.
I feel like it'd be really hard to lie.
Did when something scratching your
heart,
I feel like just the instinct to try and
go back at it,
you know,
they're so goddamn powerful.
So that happened and then I'm like,
you know what?
Like I've got to hike out of there
anyway,
I'm unarmed so I've got to hike out of
there.
I've got to get bullets from somewhere.
A Muslim guy back to the fucking bad
grizzly spot,
you know?
Which at least I know there's elk there,
but I've been trying to not do it.
You know?
What caliber gun is this point?
40th five.
Okay.
So it's a good gun.
Yeah.
But the drama started way before then
because I'm like,
if I'm going to do these hung,
I want to have someone with me like a
hunting buddy.
I'm not going to do that one solo
anymore because of the grids,
because of the grizzlies.
And so I invited Shane Dorian here,
Buddy Shane.
He was common and then the tags in
Montana got really hard to get so he
couldn't get a tag.
Then I was going to have drama,
film the hunt,
but I found that like couldn't film in a
wilderness area so they couldn't be
there and I'm just like,
I'm just destined to go there by myself.
And it was like I already knew some shit
was going to go down,
you know?
It was like everything kept pushing me
in that direction.
Now I go back to Montana.
You'll be right.
You know you're going to encounter
grizzly.
That's it.
So put this thing in front of your face.
Don't put it by your neck.
There you go.
Hello.
Much better.
I think I might've been like this when I
started the show and now I've just come
back and you freaking out.
That's what's going on.
I think I'm trying to get told because
I'm talking about grizzlies and getting
goosebumps.
Just hearing you talk.
I'm getting her.
Um,
I watched the video probably a week ago
and it was just not ever attack or
anything.
It was just have a big grizzly and I had
all them feelings rush back to me.
Like it was like I had a full adrenaline
rush and everything dude,
like the,
my body was for pumping and I,
until the point I was starting to feel
uncomfortable and like,
fucking what's going on.
I'm like,
fuck.
I just,
it was just that grizzly video and
thinking about that grizzly running at
me,
I could see her as clear as die still
coming at me.
I remember saying a shoulder's moving
dude,
as she was just racing.
I can just remember seeing a shoulders
like pulse site and like in all of her
hair moving and.
Oh fuck that.
Yeah.
Did you um,
Rinella just released a podcast?
Two podcasts in a row?
They got charged by a big male grizzly
and Kodiak.
They'd killed an elk.
Non Kodiak.
A fog neck.
Yeah.
Which is why saying grammy's videos.
So yeah,
they um,
they,
they just did a podcast on to podcasts
in a row and they shot an elk and the
fog neck islands,
they have roosevelt elk,
which is a very large elk and deer.
The biggest roosevelt elk is a huge
animal,
like 1400 pound animal and it's crazy
thick brush and they're packing this
thing out.
Took forever.
Right.
So they shot it when they left some of
it there,
they went back to go get the,
the elk and Grizzly bear had obviously
claimed they didn't know they were
hanging around eating sandwiches.
They didn't have their guns out.
Nothing in the bear just came running
in.
Just charged into all of them.
I'm one of the guys a dartmouth wound up
riding on the back of the bear is a
fucking crazy story and they're talking
about it.
Just a giant bear,
10,
11 foot grizzly bear this,
you know,
when people like,
Oh,
do you believe in big foot or.
And stuff like that.
We don't fucking have to.
There's a real live monster,
but we just used to say it.
We call it a grizzly bear.
It fucking can eat.
You owe it,
eats everything.
It eats everything.
They just savage
do so big.
I don't think people understand how big
they are.
I haven't seen a big one in the US in
the wild,
but I saw a small one in Alberta in the
wild and it scared the shit out of me.
Oh,
the one that was on my mile carcass last
year and we spoke about it in last
year's podcasts.
I remember thinking it's faith is bigger
than my whole torso do and I'm just like
that.
Like that should be mythical,
but it's fucking not living here right
now.
And there's states that are protecting
them.
Like Holy Shit.
Yeah.
They want to control the.
They want to help the populations grow.
I think vote would change
really quickly about protecting them.
Even felt fucking night.
You dog will one of your kids or trying
to date you.
I think people,
it would be very hard to get people to
vote if it killed a dog because people
go,
well,
you know they were here first.
It's when they start getting into you.
Our friends up in Alberta,
John and Jen Rivet,
they sent me some pictures recently of
some bears that had moved into the area
because they've been pushed out of their
good area by grizzlies,
right?
Yeah.
There's a lot of grizzlies grizzlies up
there and apparently the talking about
having some sort of a season on them
because people are encountering them on
a more frequent basis,
but again,
that area where they live up in Alberta
is just so dense and it's so dense that
trying to figure out how many bears are
there,
where the bears are,
so that's a good system.
When I put that time and effort in the
fine and the numbers like this,
why the American system is the best
hunting system I've ever come across
because we saw you doing numbers check
and then you release the tags for what
can be taken out of the population to
keep the population healthy.
Student.
It's all done by wildlife is a hyper
revenue there.
It's an awesome system.
Well billions of dollars a year from
hunting revenue in this country that go
to wildlife preservation that go to a
conservation of habitat.
You know,
back country hunters and anglers has a
great website where all this stuff is
detailed.
Making Rocky Mountain Health Federation
does a same similar thing.
It's just they have decreased the
detailed numbers on how much money goes
into conserving these areas and even
repopulating these animals into other
areas.
Yeah,
yeah.
It's a brilliant system so it,
you know,
and.
But it has to be that two sides because
you can't go fully one while fully the
Avo because if it goes fully one way and
we've tried frigging wipe amount,
no one wants that.
So there's got to be that middle ground
there where I think what wayside of the
greenies fought for as well,
you know,
and then it's like,
well we know we can afford the shoot 200
of those grizzly bears out of the 10,000
that live there or whatever it is,
crazy numbers.
Then that's the system we want.
So it's healthy populations or game
every,
every single year for generations to
come.
Healthy populations of game and making
sure that these giant predators don't
encroach on civilization.
Yeah,
that's the thing.
It's like keeping them out.
Once they start wiping out all the moose
and all the deer and all the elk,
they're gonna move towards people like
people need to understand that this is
not a game.
You don't encounter them in Santa
Monica.
Right?
Yeah.
So people like,
you know,
you asshole was just going to kill the
animals.
That's not,
that's not what these people are doing.
You don't understand you.
Not Exactly.
Yeah.
Like you could tell them maybe if they
maybe they've heard you like be around
them and understand what the fuck this
is.
Giant 1500 pound monster.
That doesn't think like,
Oh that dude that I'm going to eight
might have kids.
They just thinking food hall in me
stomach and don't want to fill up.
The greenies would say,
well that elk,
you killed those kids to math.
Why these greenies out?
They're petitioning against fucking
lions killing shit.
Why aren't they?
Yeah.
Right.
Why aren't low like lines are killing
shit.
We were just talking about just part of
the food chain as well.
Do we are part of this whole system.
Courtney do alter on the podcast.
I was talking to her about,
you know,
people occasionally when they're running
these trails.
We running the mountain lions.
We were talking about this lady who
lives in Malibu,
has an Alpaca farm,
a mountain lion,
got Intel,
Pacos killed 11 of them and a goat just
wiped them out.
Just fucking decimated the PO.
That was fruit killing.
And so this lady got a depredation
permit to kill them out and she got all
these death threats from people.
Yeah.
Right.
But it's always like,
do you understand that this now mine,
it's killing animals too.
Two.
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
Way more animals.
I can understand it.
Well,
it's not logical.
It's just emotional and I think a big
part of the problem with two,
there's two,
two parts of the problem.
One,
lack of real wilderness exposure,
like real time in the woods,
understanding what this whole ecosystem
is really all about because it's just a
Predator prey ecosystem.
And when a hunter goes into that,
you really just dipping your toes into
the wild world a little bit.
Yeah,
exactly.
Then the other part of it is movies,
all these fucking bear movies where the
bears are your friends,
they talk to each other and all these
anthropomorphized anthropomorphization
movies,
whether it's Bambi or whether it.
Whereas if you go out into the woods and
see yourself,
you know,
it's a much better understanding and a
much better experience for the more
people get exposed to these movies with
bears talk and they're your buddy.
Then get exposed to an actual charge.
Fucking Mama grizzly bear like you did.
Yeah.
It's crazy.
He wants to kill those payments.
A wipe.
I didn't look at that mother grizzly and
be like,
I want to shoot you.
If you look at the video,
you'll actually hear me gone.
I really don't want to shoot this bear
like she's just doing what her instinct
tells her.
Yeah.
I'm not even cranky Adot,
but I don't want to fucking die,
so it's a terrible way to die too.
That'd be a horrible way to die.
A jaw.
The size of this table closing down on
you wouldn't be good.
Yeah.
Well,
they're going to open up a season
apparently on them near near yellowstone
to many situations.
Yup.
Bears.
Yeah.
That's roughly the area that on the air
and that's where they released a lot of
the problem bears too.
That's what I do.
Yeah.
So I went to an area that they didn't
release problem.
There's no.
Because I'd never say a female grizzly
where I usually hunt in Montana.
They were old miles or loan animals at
least.
And I can't tell.
And the males are less likely to charge.
Well,
it seems like it.
Yeah,
it seems like the males.
Well if a male charged you is to eat
you?
Yeah.
Because you know,
yelled at that one on my car last year
and he wanted to go to the apple.
Why he,
he ran off and frequent disappeared.
And it's interesting because Montana
does not have a bear season,
so these are not animals like Alaska
bears.
Avoid people like the play.
Exactly.
Yep.
Because they're afraid of being shot.
Yeah.
So he like ran off.
I think I only yelled at oil to him that
one last year and he disappeared.
This female grizzly that was running it.
I mean I was calling her a fucking mall
and everything might shake a mall.
What's the mall?
I knew that was an Australian word.
So me and my buddy Andrew Boucles,
who I've just spent last week with him
in Arnhem land in northern territory.
He come,
you'd just be sitting in the vehicle
driving along and it's all quiet and
peaceful and then he would just come up
with something weird like,
you know,
if,
if you had to bring any active back from
the dead to hunt with you for a week,
who would have been fuck honeys and
trying to think about that.
But um,
then I can't have one because I'm like,
he's coming up with all this shit.
I'm going to call it one of them over
this trip.
We just need to come up with real
Australian things,
sayings that aren't getting used
anymore.
And mine was like,
Tyler,
like,
do you have that one?
Like if you say bye or someone instead
of saying by just say Tyler,
I'm fucking get blank stares.
Like a magician would say 10.
Ah,
it's like tyler,
like as in.
See you later.
No,
Tata for now.
What about her?
I know.
All right,
bye.
No.
Oh fuck her.
Raise like victory.
Okay.
Well Mall is like I'm calling someone a
bitch or a skank.
A mall.
You've got skank?
Yes.
Yeah.
So she's running at me.
I'm like fucking ease up your fucking
mall,
you know.
And she's like,
fuck,
is this guy from?
It's probably why she didn't eat.
She was from here.
She didn't even say this,
but I imagine she was thinking,
I don't speak English.
He doesn't even know what a dummy reach
it.
No,
I've never heard of a mold before.
A mall,
like a mall of America.
M O l e like molly.
I get.
Yeah,
but I think it's more of like mall in
your face.
I,
he's,
he's brought all ll slang.
Slang,
term two different Australia,
Australia,
New Zealand.
Oh,
in the United States.
Usually a pejorative or self deprecating
for a woman of loose sexual morals.
Shit,
bitch.
I said big slot or a prostitute.
Damn,
no wonder she was pissed off.
Wow.
Mall Mall.
That's probably like some old shit from
America that we like.
We gave to you long time ago.
We abandoned it.
Then you guys picked it up probably
probably so when you went and got boats,
she went and got bullets for the Fed and
I went and bought bullets.
Jump Straight back into Montana but me
old spot in Montana.
And then um,
I only had three days at that point to
try and cause,
you know,
it was after a bull elk and I'd passed
up a lot of younger animals and like
immature animals over that time.
But um,
I went from the hot heat to got to my
usual spot in Montana.
And why out that was.
No.
Explain that for people that aren't
hunters is.
It is very important.
If you want to consider the overall
health of the herd,
you always want to shoot the older
mature animals because those are the
ones that are bred.
They've passed on their genetics and it
also improves the health of the herd
because then the younger males.
That's right.
I would probably get killed by the
bigger males or have the potential
getting killed in combat when they
clashed.
And that's the whole reason.
If people don't know why they have
antlers
finding it.
Yeah,
exactly.
Yep.
I think my,
my biggest thought in that is I just
want to shoot an animal that's lived its
life.
Like,
look,
if I'm desperate for me,
don't get me wrong,
I'll shoot a spike or a cow or whatever,
but I'm not desperate for meat.
And that point of survival,
you know,
so I just feel a lot better if I shoot
an animal that unlike it's lived its
life,
you know.
And then the byproduct of that is you
get a bigger animal,
so more meat,
you know,
you get a set of antlers,
which is to me a memory.
It's not like about,
I don't cut the head off and just walk
out at the end.
I was like,
I've got a trophy.
And I think a lot of people think that
for me it's a yf respect,
but it's just,
it's a way of respecting the animal to
me,
you know,
so it's,
it's a funny thing.
But yeah,
just shooting a big old,
you know,
and that's why I passed a lot of lot of
young animals.
I had opportunities that was one dials
rod on the edge of this,
like,
like it's like a cliff.
But there was a rock that went out over
the cliff,
like a bit of a pinnacle and I was
actually on the pinnacle and I had this
bowl strike below me and he was like,
I think he was,
he was 30 something made his butt
because you're shooting down.
It's like,
you know,
the range finders science you to that 16
or 17 meters.
And he was just lying there,
had no idea it was there.
Um,
but just a younger bull,
you can see it in his face and his body
and just these analysts.
So.
But it felt good to be there and then be
like,
Nah.
And back out.
And then it was afternoon.
I think that that Greasley went me,
so you know,
I had opportunities to shoot balls,
but I pretty much went 21 days without
an opportunity where I'm like,
this is the bullet I'm going to shoot,
you know,
and I'm getting into the zone,
have this.
The thing that people I think
on the outside don't understand or
appreciate is that it's not just about
getting me,
it's also about getting a mature animal
and it's also about getting a mature
animal because they're way more
different.
Exactly,
yeah.
They are way smarter and Bain for
seasons,
you know,
they just heaps more switched on.
You know,
there are a lot smarter.
So you wanna let's like going into a
fight.
Like you don't want to go into a fight
with someone that's never done
kickboxing and yoga champion kickboxer.
So like that's ridiculous.
Like where's the challenge in that?
How are you going to be better at doing
what you're doing?
If you're just fighting the fight that
you know you're always going to win.
And then I say it very early in that
trip.
I'm happy to go home without a ball,
but I'm not happy to give up on day
three or four or sit around camp and
then go home available.
I want to bust my ass,
you know,
I want to get to point where I say to
myself,
and I did it multiple times on this
trip,
what the fuck are you doing?
Like give up.
This is too hard,
you know,
I want to get to that point where myself
write down because I feel like that's
the most you ever grow,
you know,
in any sort of hardship.
But you know,
it's like freaking campaigns running
this.
Like,
you know,
he's guest going to find a longer
marathon next time.
Well that's what courtney was saying,
that they're considering a 500 holly
block run 500.
I can't even fathom that dude.
Yeah,
I mean how many days would that take?
I don't know.
I can't even fathom going counting days.
It's probably like a week.
It's probably going to be a week of
running.
Yeah.
So it's just,
you always up in it,
you know,
like I'll go to,
I got to pull back a little bit now.
Like I don't like that's about the
maximum that all do.
Twenty to 22.
Yeah.
And then.
But it was a lot longer without the
family because you know,
the flights here and the flights back.
And I went,
I was with Yeti and I went,
well I did the whole Yeti thing and went
to the innovation center and hung out
with Yeti for like a couple of days.
Me and Bendigo.
Brian went down to west Texas hundred
some axis D,
um,
I went bass fishing.
So there was like,
there was like a week and a half on that
trip that probably a lot of people
didn't realize that I'm without my kids
and family,
you know,
that's the hard bit.
I could go and live out there like a
frigging hermit.
But I've got family and I freaking love
them and miss him.
Dude.
You know what I mean?
I'm saying the and like,
you fuck this for me because I'm sitting
on the mountain like,
you know,
this is all me,
my element up there,
like it's out in the middle of nowhere.
There's no people,
there's no lights,
you know,
there's just wild animals running around
and I'm sitting on the mountain.
I'm like,
fuck,
I'm Ms Dot Kim.
But don't you think that that's one of
the reasons why you appreciate them even
more than your family?
So much as it is.
But yeah,
I,
you know,
I said once to Steve Rinella.
We did this crazy hunt and Prince of
Wales and it rained every day and it was
just,
we were just drenched where you're
inside your tent and the tent,
like I turned on my headlamp and there
was just water vapor everywhere in the
tent,
like nothing ever dried out,
sleeping bags wet,
you're miserable.
But when I got home,
I called him up and I said,
man,
I have never felt good.
I'm so happy the sun is out and I'm
driving and I just feel amazing.
I feel like I'm on a drug and I called
him up and I go,
dude,
I have never been happier.
Crazy.
I miserable.
It is.
Yeah.
The better,
you know,
and they have to experience some
difficulty in some hardship in order to
appreciate the good times.
Yeah,
yeah,
exactly.
I've,
I feel like frequent with Kim.
It's like we're new newlywed till the
time and it's probably because I'm away
so much,
but every time I come home,
you know,
overcome a while.
I'm thinking about him flat out,
you know,
I actually just renewed my vows with Kim
15,
15 years,
married,
18 years together.
Yeah.
I think that there's something to that
man.
I mean,
people,
you know,
absence makes the heart grow fonder.
It's a common expression.
I think it's totally true and I think
that I,
I don't think life is supposed to be
easy.
I just did not.
I think you're supposed to do some
difficult cit,
but on,
I think the sooner you realize that then
it does seem easy to you.
Does that make sense?
It's like the sooner you realize that
life's supposed to be fucking tough and
if it's not,
put yourself through some tough shit,
then the better dude then it just,
it it.
Right now I feel like I've found the
recipe just to be happy as hell.
I've been silent.
The last frequent mom fly.
I don't want this to happen,
but I've been signed to Kim and she sort
of gets teed up fucking just no,
I'm happy to die right now.
Logging.
I really may not.
I'm happy to fucking die right now.
I want to see my kids grow and I want to
say my kids have kids and I want to
spend the attorney with eternity with
that woman but on fucking happy to die
right now and that happy.
And why do you see?
Why do you think like that?
Because I feel like I've just lived
through our law for already and I'll put
you still enjoy it.
Every good.
I still enjoy and be happy to die
because I'm fucking crazy.
Probably.
I ain't doin anything out of the
ordinary to fucking die.
But you talk a little bit,
but that's fucked up.
That shit the fuck out.
That's probably not good.
But Jesus Christ.
Did you get back until that dude who
gave you the 45?
Hey,
fuck face.
Yeah.
He was freaking.
They're the nicest people.
It was kay and Ed that were in Oregon.
Yeah.
They're the nicest people.
And I think aid was freaking more than
me.
I'm like,
it's all good.
But uh,
yeah.
Fuck you to know that you had the good,
you had it out and there was nothing
they wouldn't.
Yeah.
Woo.
And then so I had to sleep there that
night because I wasn't walking out in
the dark.
And the worst thing is I'm sleeping on
the,
at the elevation that she's at and
cheese.
I only about 400 meters in a direct line
from my camp.
Oh Jesus Christ is.
So.
Did you sleep well?
So I manually put a shell in the chamber
side one shell and I just fucking.
I actually slept really good that not,
I don't know if it was adrenaline wore
were and often it wore me out more.
Were you convinced that it was going to
fire even with that one shell in the
chamber?
I would have because I couldn't have the
magazine in there because it would jam
on the bullet,
but I could drop a shell in there
manually and that'd be good to go.
I had one bullet.
Yeah.
Russian roulette with no fucking good.
I can add me.
No,
I found that night as well.
Like sleeping with me.
Does your knife not fuck God,
she's probably thinking it's a mosquito.
Notice a fucking thick.
Their skin is so thick because they bite
each other.
Yeah.
Go Watch that.
A grizzly man documentary,
one of the craziest things was watching
the two grizzlies fight.
They were just tearing each other apart,
bite each other's heads,
and when it was over he didn't look like
anything.
Tore us to shreds body.
That's had really good experience in
northwest territories.
You know,
there's black and grizzlies living in
the same area.
He's experienced the two fighting and
has never liked the black bag bear
grizzly.
It's always the grizzly running down the
black bay.
He said one swat from a grizzly bear,
you know,
a bigger blackberries once from a
grizzly bear and the black bear might be
dead,
but it's fucking disabled mate.
One Swipe.
So imagine what one swipe from agrees
grizzly would do to us.
You
know,
there's a picture of campaigns and a
grizzly that he shot in Alaska and he's
holding up.
It's Paul.
It's the to bear that he shot was like
11 feet tall and he's holding up.
It's Paul and the PA is like a fucking
dinner plates.
Gary.
It's like this big,
maybe bigger than it didn't imagine that
bitch slap followed by clothes.
Dude is dry doctorate yet.
Look at the size of that thing.
Fuck the pole.
A look at the tape on that blog.
Blogs.
Yeah.
Oh No,
not again.
Damn.
Your cams.
White teeth.
Want them?
You could just get that charcoal.
Do you drink coffee?
Yeah,
I do.
I wonder if too though.
He drinks coffee.
Yeah.
But coffee month had bleach in it and
are fucking enormous.
Enormous roles.
But like you said,
I mean that really is a real live living
monster.
Crazy.
I love that.
Dude.
They,
I'm just having a joke.
He's a fucking legend.
He's the best.
Yeah.
But um,
I mean,
he know John Dudley saw a grizzly bear
take out a moose with one swipe.
He saw it through a spotting scope.
He saw a grizzly bear hit a moose in the
back and break it.
Spriker and spawn date.
Just they hit sign.
They'll probably one of the few animals
that like hits.
Yes.
I wonder what chance have we got?
You might zero.
You're a bit mad.
Fuck.
Come on,
man.
Breaks the back of.
This is Kate my scollon.
Yeah.
They're just so big.
They're so goddamned big frigging
living.
Bigfoot dude right there.
Yeah.
Big.
It's only like eight foot tall monkey.
They probably fucking what?
Big Foot.
They probably fucked bigfoot Tamala
death.
This fucking where we'll fucking this
gorilla.
Well,
what's crazy is that.
That's a small bear.
Compare it to the short face.
Bear was short nose bear.
What was it?
What was that bear that lived in the.
I seen the face bear.
They think they call it,
which is bigger even than a polar bear.
Kodiak bear.
There's a picture of these guys standing
next to a um,
yeah,
that's it.
That's the Holy Shit.
That's scary.
And that thing had long legs and that
thing apparently was so fast and so
ferocious that it kept people from
crossing the bering land bridge.
Uh,
that's one of the reasons why they think
that people,
it took so long for human beings to make
it to North America.
It's Paul as big as that dude chess.
They're the bigger dude that is.
Look how much bigger there than anything
else.
There's a grizzly polar,
and then the powers of big data
analytics,
thinkful I think 10,000
years.
I think that was the final.
If that's the case,
Jamie,
find out why.
But there's a picture of a seven facts
about the extinct giant bear hug.
Eleven thousand years.
Go back to that last page.
You are pleased and look at that one
image.
It's really a guy up in the right hand
corner.
The guy touching the face.
Oh yeah,
that's what God damn it.
I mean,
that is a monster.
That's a monster from Avatar or from
star wars and that's a real animal that
lived alongside people for a long ass
time,
but see what I mean.
If they would just run her in the wallet
still,
we just have a normal name for them and
it wouldn't be any different cause
exactly.
Seen Him,
dude.
It's like the galaxy,
like you're used to looking at it,
say the Milky Way.
So it's like,
oh cool,
fuck off.
Had that.
Think about that.
Yeah,
that is freaky dude.
Oh yeah.
I've always said that if space wasn't
real,
like if there was a roof over the world,
but there was one place where you could
go,
you could see space.
Everybody would want to take a trip to
that by a 100 percent.
Yeah.
For all of us to look at it.
You just got to get away from some of
these shitty law where you have some
amazing pictures,
man.
Image.
Go to first.
Is it first image on instagram?
Adam is not just an amazing bowhunter,
but an amazing photographer just added
one that I.
because when you're out there and
honestly and like there's no artificial,
there's no light pollution for a long,
long way.
So if you look closely at that Phsi,
the,
the orange lights,
the fire.
But see the clouds in the background,
there's a fun just a campfire that week.
But if you look behind that,
that's lightning in clouds.
So I ended up getting the far the
lightning and in the milky way blazing
and for the,
that is an amazing picture.
That is amazing,
isn't it?
I'm just a dude.
I can't like I'm there and I don't go to
sleep til one or 2:00
in the morning cause I'm just lying
there looking up.
We'll take photos and I'm just like,
what the out there.
Like how crazy is that?
That picture is incredible.
That's beautiful.
So that's over our heads every night.
That's another thing that you just sort
of take for granted,
you know?
Yeah.
And like you said,
the light pollution.
I mean we just,
we love cities.
They're nice,
they give you,
you know,
supermarkets and restaurants and shit,
but they also ruin your view of the
universe.
Totally.
It's not worth it.
Not Worth the trade off is almost not
worth it.
Just don't fucking pigs now because with
so you know,
there's so many options out there and
food,
I reckon our taste buds have changed and
everything.
Gold,
no doubt.
Our taste buds have changed for sure
because it's stuffed back then.
Wouldn't be bland.
But what if you just ate those real
simple items now it'd be blamed as hell,
you know,
I need source on,
I need to put sold aren't need to do
this and you're not.
And then yeah,
just feel like with turn and then the
frigging pigs because there's so many
options for food out there that were
just keep shoveling and we'd just take
it all for granted as well.
One hundred percent.
But I like it.
I like dinner after this we're going to
go to a restaurant.
Sit down.
Yeah,
exactly.
Not.
Think about it and we'll have good is
that when I come back from this 22 days,
$2 fantasize and over foods,
I put the 17 kilos straight back on.
What were you thinking of?
Just fucking anything.
It was proposed at one.
Is there one thing you like?
As soon as I had burger burger,
but like a full work burger,
like a jerk burger that's just packed
and there's a couple of places that mean
came usually got home and I was just
dawn,
like I'm about to salivate.
So like both the time spent away and the
time and civilization.
That's the thing is achieving balance.
Yeah.
It gets getting the balance.
Yeah,
exactly.
Yeah.
Because the civilization is awesome.
It's great to be able to go to a doctor.
Yeah.
And when you get away from all that and
you are out in the walls,
they,
that's huge.
Fully realized like fuck,
how good do we have it?
Like you hop in a car with air
conditioning,
you drive from point a to point b,
like you know,
and I always think about how life must
have been back in the day.
Like it wasn't driving from point a to
point b because I had have taken fucking
a week dude.
Now you just jumped in the car and go.
It's all temperature controlled.
You stop at a service station,
you get fuel,
fucking I'm thirsty.
I'm going to get a drink while I'm in
there.
You know,
like that's just one,
one example of how crazy it is.
Yeah.
Now when you are in the Bush,
when you,
especially when you're an art land,
you find a lot of pictographs and a lot
of these.
Yeah.
Because there was such a huge indigenous
population up there.
Well there still is,
but you know,
you're looking at.
I put one up the other day,
it's a video,
it's just Indians.
The stories that Jamie might find it,
but a main equals or looking at some
paintings and then I looked down and
like there's a whole human remains
tucked in the rocks.
They're ripe wrapped in pipe.
A box which is a jet pilot back in
America.
Chocolatory I don't think so.
Cool.
A pipe voc because it's like the,
the box literally rips off at like a
soft tissue paper.
And uh,
so some mobs,
like indigenous people would rather do
the indigenous people call like a group
of them.
Well you drive here.
You were talking a mob of hogs earlier,
you said that mobs,
a group of indigenous youth,
that's what they call themselves,
right?
Yeah,
that's correct.
Yep.
Yeah.
So I don't like the term like tribe or
anything like that because that's very
American Indians and things like that.
So they would say like what they hear.
I wanted to really get into this because
this is some stuff we talked about at my
house.
That's your podcast last time.
Oh Wow.
Look at those pictures.
That's amazing.
Yeah.
So they real beautiful rights and now a
very,
I don't know if I'd call them artistic
because this just seemed to be what they
did,
you know,
wherever it's that dream time,
you would've heard about their dream
time.
So wherever it's recording their dream
time,
you know,
um,
the indigenous would do these,
these rock arts and uh,
sometimes I'd be carving.
So if you go to like the Dapi damp,
but Lego in Western Australia,
which is in the Pilbara region that are
all carvings in rock,
like literally scribed in the Rock and
um,
the day title that you'd get,
like,
it's so hard describing a rock that get
this detail in this rock that was just
amazing.
They use a pioneer with.
I'd grown up different stones and get
different textures and colors and see
those hand prints.
Those hand prints have been put up.
Their hands go on the wall and then they
spray it out of their mouth.
So they might like.
And essentially it's like a spray
painting,
you know,
but they're using their mouth.
Those other ones would be painted on and
you see some really crazy things.
Like,
I reckon that's an aim.
You that white thing,
if you have a good look at it,
there's so many paintings on there
that's a picture that I took a couple of
years ago now.
But there's so many paintings on there
now that you have to stare at it for a
wall and then pick a different one.
Now you know,
and like there's a documented so these
ones aren't,
so I'm one of about two white fellows
that have been to this area and a
traditional able to took a say like a
traditional loan.
I took us up there,
she couldn't go up there and 90 raising
we were allowed in,
there was because this mob of people
that they don't exist anymore,
the last of them has passed away so it
was okay to go in there.
So I'm to take you into the full story
with like beaten down this Bush track
for hours and hours and we pull up at a
little creek system and she just sort of
pointed that out.
She said,
look,
if you know,
if you go up to the escarpment air and
into a cave or whatever,
you'll see,
you know,
the,
the artifacts and everything that's out
there and this.
So this is untouched.
Like crazily untouch this spot,
you know,
go in there and it's like a frigging
lost city,
but all natural,
like rocks just pushed up out of the
ground.
And then you say the mouth of the cave
and a couple of paintings on it.
Then you walk into the cave and this
cave is 60,
70 meters long.
It's probably 30 percent or 30 meters
wide.
And the roofs probably,
let's say 10 meters tall and the hallway
for this cave systems,
those paintings,
like he can't ever had,
they even reached the top of the cave.
Like there's no big rocks or anything
sitting around anymore.
They still the grinding stones there,
Joe,
where they'll grinding up the different
paints,
you know,
because that's what they'd do.
They'd,
they'd grind it up and work it into a
paste to paint with.
That's all still sitting there.
And there's 30 human reminds just
sitting in the cave in a,
like in a pile there as well.
And uh,
so the indigenous story goes,
you know,
and this might be a part of the dream
time,
I don't want to get this bit wrong,
but it might be a part of that,
like a dream time story and how it
happened.
But the drain time story is the kids
descended off the from the cave down
onto,
from the escarpment down onto the flat
and the kids were told not to kill any
serpents,
like don't kill a snake,
you know,
they're off limits.
And uh,
the kids go down there and they can't
find anything to eat.
And I find a serpent,
like a young snake.
So they grabbed this knife and cut its
head off and it doesn't die.
It keep squiggling and moving around.
And then,
um,
so they keep chopping or that they chop
it into little bits and it keeps
squiggling around and won't die.
They bash it with a rock and I won't die
at keep squiggling around.
Then they fry it in a fire and the fire
still doesn't kill it as just in pain
and squirming and squiggling around
there.
And the mother serpent,
you heard this commotion,
the kids go back up to the escarpment
and into the cave.
But the mother serpent comes up and they
never used to be a creek there.
And she come up with such a rage that
she carved the creek through the land.
So this is how a lot of their dream time
stories go.
And uh,
so she carved that creek in that were
actually camped on.
She went up,
she found the people in the cave after
fine,
her,
her young dead,
and she lead a fly all the way around
them.
She raised into the cave and she burned
them out and she burned them to death.
So that,
you know,
that's,
that's the indigenous story.
The,
the white fellow story is the
indigenous,
and I'm not saying one's true or one's
not true,
but I'll tell you how the story goes.
The white fellow story is,
that was one of the first cattle
stations in the northern territory of
Australia and the indigenous,
we're picking off cattle to eat and I
wouldn't have known any different,
right?
It's an animal.
Um,
and uh,
the station owners found this out like a
fan,
that way the indigenous will live in and
I took them food as a gift,
but it was all laced with poison and
they end up all dine in the cave.
So,
you know,
there's two,
two versions of the story,
obviously.
Yeah.
It's the second one.
I don't want to say because who frigging
knows,
but I definitely know that nick isn't
going around lighting fires.
Probably not,
but I know what you're saying.
Yeah.
If you listen to enough dream time
stories,
you know,
and that like that will,
they have for a long time,
you know,
here that was so hot,
that was so good at hunting because you
know,
a lot of people say,
oh,
the indigenous didn't come up with a bow
and arrow.
They didn't need to like wine events
aren't and you didn't need that was so
good with boomerangs and species and you
know,
the way that they wanted that they
didn't need a boner.
You know,
it was insane.
So there are beautiful rice,
but they're still very young to western
society.
You know,
I think we spoke about this last time.
Jamie,
can you find it?
How old?
Well when was like the northern
territory of Australia really pioneered
because that's the population of
indigenous that we're talking about.
They've been thrown into this western
society,
you know,
that we have come through slowly with
that.
That essentially that was still in the
stone age because you know that that's
all I needed within territory in 18,
25.
The area occupied today in the northern
territory is part of the colony of New
South Wales was first settled by
Europeans in 18,
24 at Fort Dundas.
Port Essington in 18,
63 control of the area was given to
South Australia.
Isn't that crazy?
It's not even 200 years old,
dude.
That's crazy.
Yeah,
and so these people have been there for
how many thousands of years before that
look.
Look that up too because I don't want to
get it wrong.
One of the things that you were telling
me that I thought was really
fascinating,
we were just hanging out at my house was
how many different languages they have.
Yeah,
yeah.
There's like,
I think there's over 700 dialects and
you could literally have a mob of
indigenous on this part of the mainland
and just a little bit further down
another mob of indigenous,
and I wouldn't speak the same language,
says the northern northern territory
provides evidence of settlement around
60,000
years ago.
I think it's just been blown right out
of the water and it's a lot longer than
that now.
Really?
Yep.
Recently?
Just recently.
Yeah.
I remember reading something.
That's right.
What's the super recently like a week
ago or so.
Yeah.
And as I'm so now findings to suggest
that I'm Egyptian,
come over at some point,
especially these two brothers and one of
the province is a story that goes.
One of the brothers was really sick and
you know,
he had to look after him and um,
uh,
I,
I can't remember how it ends,
but you know,
that Egyptians had come here just
because of some of the signs that they
found in those days was like a story
noted down on some rocks and things like
that.
So it's really crazy.
The history behind Australia when you
think of it like that,
and when you think of how young it is
here it goes.
Aboriginal architectural discovery in.
How do you say that word?
Cock.
I do Kacadoo.
Yep.
Could do rewrites.
The history of Australia,
northern territory.
Aboriginal people have lived in
Australia,
a minimum of 65,000
years of chemo,
of archeologist has established 18,000
years longer than it had been proved
previously and at least 5,000
years long that had been speculated by
the most optimistic researchers.
Wow.
Crazy.
I.
Yeah,
pretty crazy.
It's a long fucking time,
man.
Pay Five thousand years.
Today.
The story about the damp Jacoba Lego
area in the Pilgra,
that's what I mentioned earlier.
That's right near where I have my
business and as I have a 70,000
rock arts on the archipelago itself.
They still don't know the significance
of it.
70,000,
but there's a story that goes.
The indigenous that lived on the
mainland with cy,
much different than the people that
lived on the islands like cold on the
canoe people or the boat people that if
those canoe or boat people live or come
near the mine land,
the indigenous mob that lived on the
mainland would clear out of there might
get out of it because I was so different
in the way that leave.
The way they spoke,
the way they looked was so different
that it was like a foreign person to.
I'm now scared of them,
Jesus Christ.
It's just amazing how many different
dialects.
It's insane.
Isn't that what you were saying,
that you could just go a couple of
kilometers away and they spoke a totally
different way?
That's correct.
Yeah.
I couldn't understand each other.
Nope.
So,
so with my business,
like I've been very fortunate to work
closely with a lot of indigenous people
wherever it's Arnhem land,
um,
where I go hunting a lot or it's with my
business because in my business I've got
a joint venture with an indigenous
business owner,
which is,
I'm sure she's a lovely woman.
She's awesome.
And I also have a thing where I employ
at least 25 percent indigenous local
indigenous people and I actually usually
blow them out the 50 percent at some,
which is,
which is awesome.
You know the deal,
it's mandated by a treaty or the
government.
Really the,
the mining,
the mining companies that I work for
would prefer an indigenous joint venture
owner of 25 percent.
Then what I've taken on is my,
for myself is just,
I want the 25 percent or more indigenous
employees as well,
local indigenous people.
So I've been,
I've been close to a lot of them and you
hear a lot of their different stories,
but one of the things is um,
where my business is the man,
the.
Sorry,
the woman has the say in the
relationship,
everything,
financial,
everything like that.
But just two hours away the man has,
it's the complete opposite in the main
has the site and everything.
So it's just two hours away.
But anyway,
some of these indigenous,
you know,
have married into,
someone from two hours away,
like the Pilbara region and they're
always like,
oh,
can we move back to onslow?
Whether we're.
The man gets to say it's really,
really funny,
but I'm just like that in my
relationship.
It's whoever's the most fucking pissed
off in the day gets a little bit of
both.
So That's interesting.
So if they moved then they would switch
roles,
switches and that happens all the time.
So they just accept it.
Yeah.
They just accept it and the whole tribe
agrees.
That's the whole model agrees that never
exists,
doesn't,
it probably doesn't run so smoothly
there even though he knows that the
other real and it's really hard for a
lot of westerners.
Don't understand.
He's a solitary one story about uh,
I'll,
I'll Kevin traditional liner that go
hunting out on his land.
He's,
he's been out on camp with me for a
couple of weeks and he hasn't had any,
anything about water and like a bit of
red meat that I've shot him and stuff
like that and finish that.
He's been catching for himself.
Anyway.
He's got family coming out and he says,
you know,
it gives them a little grocery list that
they could bring from town for him
anyway.
They bring the groceries and like,
I don't think in la he hasn't know.
He hasn't had anything to really drink
or you know,
he's just had the real basic stuff for
fair wall.
They get there,
nothing's been taken out of the bags,
but once I hand it to him,
I just start reaching whatever he's
grabbed out reach and like,
so he got a couple of bottles of coke
and all the kids and relatives of
drinking the coke and like they leave
and we put about this much coke.
He gets a pack of cigarettes or lead
hands going like grab cigarettes.
He doesn't look at them once.
Like he doesn't go to say no.
Like I haven't had a smoke for a couple
of weeks or a drink for a couple of
ways.
Doesn't even blink dude or anything.
Just everyone takes and they just leave
him with a little bit and all this
thinking,
fuck.
If that was me I'd be like,
Oh boy,
I haven't had frequent cigarette smoke
but I haven't had a cigarette for a
couple of weeks.
Like ease up and it didn't bother me one
bit because that's how I.
Oh,
but when one of them has something that,
that he doesn't have,
he's quite welcomed the reach in and
grab whatever he wants as well.
They say that was an issue with a native
Americans as well,
that they didn't understand property.
Yeah.
Don't understand property and just
sharing what they do and it's just
normal.
It was this property thing came out of
the Europeans.
They didn't understand.
So they would do the same thing,
would take the animals,
would take the food.
And it was normal for.
So if someone had left something,
some of the accounts of European
settlers were talking about that,
how native Americans seem to have no
understanding at all.
Why people would be upset that they
would.
Someone would take their problem.
Yeah.
And you say that in the fuel of the
movies as
well that know they've kept that
dialect.
But um,
the other thing that I was going to cite
is,
so it's something to be like high
ambient,
you know,
like we,
like we used to talk about going on
walkabout and things like that.
Like a lot of the guys that I would get
would get their first Pi and then not
show up to work the next morning and
like come back two months later and just
walk straight into the depot.
Like,
like,
hey boss.
And I'd be like,
uh,
I haven't seen you for a couple of
months,
might look,
what are you doing?
I'm here for work.
Well not obviously because I'd get
there,
pay their paycheck and I'd just be happy
and go off with it for those couple of
months or whatever.
And they're not all like that.
But a lot of them would do that.
And it took me a long time to
understand,
especially being a business owner and
just wanting everything to run nice and
smooth.
That that's just how a lot of them are,
you know.
And it is something to be envious about
because the other thing that would
happen is in the mine sites are pushing
for indigenous employees at this time
and I'd load them up with indigenous
employees.
Then there'll be a deaf,
you know,
in the family and a funeral.
Like they won't bury their dead until
everyone from the mobs there.
So and because some of them live so far
out and Bush,
it could take a week for a funeral or
some funerals go for weeks and weeks,
months dude.
And these guys wouldn't show up.
And I'd have the client ringing me up
saying,
you know,
like,
what's going on?
You guys aren't here today.
Well,
if you want indigenous employees and
indigenous business,
this what happens in,
you need to understand their culture
now.
There's been a lot of um,
cultural awareness.
Um,
a lot of cultural awareness has gone out
there to the mine sites that now they're
all understanding that as well.
So they know if there's a funeral on
that they're not going to have their
indigenous people there anymore.
So the indigenous people have an
adjusted.
No,
they haven't.
No.
They have to a certain degree on some
things,
but not a lot.
And I shouldn't have to worry about.
Yeah.
But when they take off,
they don't get paid.
You got to get work,
goes off on a walkabout and comes back
two months later.
Did you just take them back in?
Oh,
I am now.
Yeah.
We usually do just because it's just
cultural awareness.
I'm aware of how their culture is.
And that's interesting because uh,
when,
whenever an invasive culture moves into
an indigenous culture because this
battle,
right?
Try to figure out whose,
whose lifestyle winds out.
Yep.
And that's decimated the native American
and I'm thinking all of the cities and
more populated places in Australia
definitely has,
you know,
but I've just been lucky enough to go
into some of these remote areas where
that's not the case still.
Yeah.
And like I said,
you look in on them and you're just
like,
I wish I could live my life like that.
It's like they don't want,
I don't want some of the things that we
want,
you know?
Yes.
They probably.
Well,
I don't know.
I mean maybe they envy some of the ways
that we live as well.
I don't fucking think so.
I think some of them do.
Yeah.
But I look at them out there out Bush,
you know,
like when their ride out and it's just
like this is the way law should be
lived.
It's like there's no rush to do anything
cold,
get anywhere and just they just live in
life.
Dude.
Well that's how you like to live too.
I mean you like to like just be out like
when you're at your cabin,
spent a tremendous amount of time at
your cabin just out hunting.
Pretty chill now.
That's the thing about where you live.
I mean you have so many invasive
species,
so much,
so many deer and pigs.
You could just go like that.
Yeah,
it's amazing.
Yeah.
So I do get to hunt a lot.
So you just eat wild game constantly.
Yeah,
pretty much like your wedding mouth laid
out.
Woo.
She's wild pork.
Hi.
Those like meatballs which are like,
which was like a deer pig mix for like
three days.
Dude.
God,
breakfast,
lunch and dinner.
So good.
All that wild.
It was awesome.
And it was,
it was an awesome experience to go out,
harvest that,
meet me self,
then put it on for like 60,
70 people at the wedding.
Yeah,
it was cool.
I'm like,
this is from right here.
Like right here off the farm.
That's crazy.
Yeah.
No,
you're living man.
You need to come over dude.
You've got to kill all those bugs first
to say that Scorpion,
that Brittany know,
because I've always been like,
I'd actually never been bitten.
I got bitten by a spider on the arm
once.
What's an orb spider?
They're not too bad,
but like this side went numb.
We'll at least saw idea.
Okay.
That's bad dude.
Yeah.
But it's not like bad luck.
It's going to kill you real sick.
So jerk off the day before the wedding.
Yeah.
That's a god.
No,
he's,
that's the fellow they had beat me,
but they're not so they're not too bad,
but I'd never looked up.
Um,
I've never looked up scorpions before
because I've never been bitten mine.
And I've just heard a few rumors that
you can get really sick from the little
ones.
And I picked up a bit of timber walls
building,
like the bond that I was doing,
an original photo was just a splinter
that cracked me and then do this hand
felt like it was about 10 times the
size,
like in 20 seconds,
his hand just felt like it was just
swelling up.
It wasn't,
it looked fine,
but then you could see my veins popping
out.
You could feel the like the poison
running up me arm.
It come all about these,
um,
sort of disappeared once I got into my
chest and like I ran over to the cabin
with me Buddy Antonio there.
I'm like fucking lookup Scorpion Bites
right now.
Like one just cracked me and it's
excruciating.
And uh,
he looked it up and he's like,
worst case scenario,
have a cardiac arrest.
But it's in very limited cases.
So I'm like,
well,
what's the normal case?
And it's just excruciating pain for up
to two or three days,
two or three days.
Anyway,
once it got into my chest,
it sort of disappeared.
I did feel a bit nauseous and stuff like
that.
But then two,
I am in the morning that drifted down
into these leg on the opposite side,
like woke me up like it was just killing
me.
Like you little fucker there.
Only this fucking big too so I can pick
a punch.
Yeah,
about an inch long.
Just a tiny little thing like that.
That didn't happen to me thing.
Christ necrosis.
Yeah.
But I understand you can like it you,
it's not,
not freaking good,
but the day of the wedding,
while we're all getting ready to meet
good friend Ben Chambers was there all
have a freaking building sentence deal
or whatever I was doing and I hear a bit
of commotion.
I look over,
he's frigging wrestling,
have to spotted blue belly black snake,
which we've actually never had on the
property before.
And they really aggressive like,
hey,
sorta tried to hold it out of a.
So I couldn't latch back and get him.
Like I've got all these people showing
up for a wedding and there was a
frigging venomous snake running around.
Venice is a black snake.
Uh,
I've heard that they give you a real bad
migraine but they can do the sign,
like,
you know,
you can have cardiac arrest,
you can have a bad reaction to it.
So there's a lot of shit that can go on
there.
But um,
my eight grabs this stick and a red
belly,
black snake,
wackier and then usually let go these
things in the Torres for grabbing you
and just pumping you with venom.
That's what makes them the worst of the
black snakes.
Now just grab onto you and keep pumping
you with venom and they won't,
they won't do a drive by it.
A lot of snakes do a drive by it and uh,
but anyway,
this is like the friggen an hour away
from the wedding started dude.
And he's tangled in this snake up random
stick.
Then he lets it go like further away
from the cabin and when he lets it go,
it spews up a bloody brown snake.
And I sent you a video once before have
a snakes.
We went up another snake,
this thing,
beautiful full brands,
Nike and then took all snakes are super
poisonous.
Exactly.
Yes.
I probably should have left it alive
because it's taken care of the brand's
native population.
It has a taste for what kills.
You shouldn't lift the pride as a
cabinet.
I mean,
if it only gives you a headache.
Yeah,
but most of the time,
like in Australia and I've like,
I've walked thousands of miles,
dude.
No,
never,
ever had a problem.
That's why you need to come out.
Boy,
that's not a convincing argument.
Count.
Come visit the farm.
I'll take you out to the cabinet.
Sounds good.
Can I get an armored suit?
Kevlar,
underwear.
It seems like a terrible idea.
I brought you that buffalo skull because
I'm like,
you're fucking never coming,
so I'm always bringing you one of them.
White buffaloes.
I would come to Australia.
I just.
I'm not going buffalo hunting.
You guys are out of your fucking mind.
You pretty safe.
Pretty safe.
No crocodiles.
Rock it out.
Is that the snake?
So that's a red belly things beautiful.
He is pissed off seats.
Flattening these neck out like that.
God,
it's so beautiful.
Yeah.
That's a red belly.
Black staff.
They're pretty harmless.
So pretty.
I've actually had me head back on the
stick before and I had it was cold rod
up beyond me head and they'll lift up
and have a look in the grass and he
lifted right up beside me on my mood.
I don't want to get bit and then he just
relaxed and chilled out.
So you just had to just lay that second
from the left.
Jamie.
That looks like a spot is that says this
says blue bell in here,
but you much much of it.
Yeah.
That's one.
That bright shiny black box to the right
click on these.
They just stopped all those videos.
That is a gorgeous creature.
It's not uncommon to see a few of them
for the summer boy hunting,
but they,
like I said,
they really placid.
So those are set.
But how the fuck do you do me a favor
while you look at it.
Andrew equals.
I saw this thing on your instagram.
Yeah.
And then you'll find him on youtube.
Then he's got these video where he
catches,
I think it's two brown snakes and a red
belly black snake and he puts them down
rabbit holes and then they chased the
rabbits out electronic.
They trying to get shelter.
They chased these rabbits out and he
ended up catching the rabbits.
It's frigging hilarious.
So he uses either.
He's like,
he's older videos.
I just seen it.
That one there.
Do.
I mean the top one?
Just the one or the one above it.
This one here,
he's doing something wild rabbits with
thinks not it.
Nah,
that one day.
This dude's a freak.
Hey.
Hey Holly.
Shit.
That was a few years ago.
It was pretty Australian.
He's various drained.
I can't keep doing this shit.
Your fucking numbers coming up rather.
So these snakes are what kind of snakes?
Dave to red belly.
Black snake.
So those will kill you?
Nah,
I won't kill you.
Those or had a bad reaction.
Yeah.
Their headaches.
Snakes and making them.
Well one of them's try and do.
Now it's getting a bit revved up.
Yeah,
me just walking around.
He's got some serious control.
So when they lift up the strike,
he drops them down a little bit,
you know,
because I can't fight against their own
weight like that can grab it.
He just saw gun in his hand.
What the fuck is wrong with this?
This is your buddy?
Yeah,
he's my buddy.
He's a bowhunter now.
He doesn't hunt.
Why should he high?
Just fucking hands while he's wearing
gym shorts.
Dude.
He's just done Africa maybe a couple of
years ago.
He chases a pride of lions off a fucking
kill.
What chase is the product lines?
Bluffs amount.
It has elephants chasing him down,
dude.
And he outruns elephants in sign.
Does he have a death wish?
He must have.
Do you think he does either.
He's got some screws loose.
At least.
Can you identify the taste of.
Oh,
I've been there before.
It says.
Yeah.
So he drops his snakes down the dry run
out?
Yeah,
he drops him down the hall.
What he does is he grabs a rabbit.
Rabbit rabbit.
Yeah.
So he has run into a net.
I'm not sure.
One or the other.
Yeah.
I just watched him wrestle a full size
bull buffalo what?
Yeah,
he pretty much.
He lasted this bull and on film.
And this is on this last buffalo.
A water buffalo.
The one that you fuck her.
He lasted.
Is One of those.
But because the hair,
the horns are,
you kind of get the last one hone.
So it comes off my um,
I've got along video.
It misses him by.
I don't,
I recognize a couple of feet.
This thing is on his ass,
but he can run.
But I'm like,
dude,
one trip.
And you fuck the.
How fast is the water buffalo?
Fast off the mom.
It might just the head like,
just the white in the head could squish
your body in half if it got you against
the grant or a tree.
So I imagined the rest of it's whole
body white grown.
And you do to turn you in the and
pepper.
What's the end game for this guy?
What's he doing this for?
A thrill.
I think I've done some stuff with them
out there.
A backpack done.
So look at this monkey having a root in
the back.
This is Africa,
this sample clip.
What is he doing?
He's Kinda chased one of the baboons.
Fuck.
Oh,
Jesus Christ.
Why is he chasing baboons?
Traveling's will fuck you up.
A nearly dies on this trip.
Something by it.
More funding.
Get some.
Oh my God.
So he just chased off all these baboons
by running at him.
This is not seemed.
Why's that?
What concerns me more than anything is
that other people are going to copy.
This guy is 100 with thin.
Yeah.
Because he obviously is very skilled.
I mean if you could call it skilled,
knowledgeable.
What's the word?
He's done it before.
He's experienced shit.
He comes to Christ.
Hooky.
Tenanting took a.
he's got no shirt on folks.
He's wearing gym shorts and he's uh,
he's.
Can you give me some volume so I can
hear this crazy.
Fuck talk
in that last little bit of footage.
You can see me rolling on the ground.
Old Close.
But even in these animals understand
that they understand one,
look at me with my two legs,
two arms standing upright.
My vision forward.
These animals understand that I'm a
potential threat to them.
I'm not food on the friend.
A fresh fuck.
Crazy fucking crazy.
One of those lines.
Just the guy just needs the guy.
No,
you're fucking not been travel.
I'm ready to put this down.
That tissue paper skin that we have
covered the fucking water balloon and
blood.
We call a body.
They used to tear and open like freaking
buffalo and shit.
Shit ain't nothing man.
Oh Jesus.
What is he doing?
Why is he have a crocodile?
Why is he putting the last around a
fucking crocodile?
This guy's crazy defeated to coconut.
He fed it a coconut.
Yeah.
Mind defeated a coconut.
Why not like to put it in its mouth so
it can't bite?
Okay,
give me some volume as crazy.
They must be in Africa because you can't
stay.
Says,
this is what I did.
The same thing.
I started talking to animals and I'm
like,
fucking like,
they don't understand English.
There's no use telling him to calm down.
I'm not fucking eight year.
If the student doesn't even have
pushover.
Crocodile is around three and a half
thousand pounds.
Compare this to us humans and it's only
200 pounds and you'll soon realize why
this guy was a title as niche as boss.
Crazy fucker has a coconut in the
crocodiles mouth and he's trying to get
the crocodile,
the crack a coconut for forum.
Oh my God,
dude,
he's,
he's awesome.
You know.
So what does this do for a living?
Fucking youtube and stuff for the
network.
Tickle,
tickle,
tickle.
He's actually a real moment to tell you
the truth.
Really just lives in the bush.
Yeah,
Jesus.
But I mean,
doesn't have to feed himself like he a
job.
Hayes,
he doesn't cry the shit he's about to do
some massive trek dude with nothing and
just walk through some wild country.
And so one of the reasons why he was
anonymously and with me up north was
he's trying to learn off the indigenous
about a lot of the Bush Tucker luck.
A lot of the food that he can find out
in the bush,
like yams and different like fruits and
stuff like that.
He knows all the wildlife stuff that he
can eat,
but the indigenous has spent,
you know,
a long time trying to work out what they
can incarnate and there's heaps of
things that you can eat,
but they've got to be boiled for a
certain amount of period.
You can only eight to this far into it
and things like that.
I've watched you fucking cock at dude.
There's a,
there's a,
I don't know if it's a route or type of
fruit and you definitely can't eat it,
like crush it up and they put it in the
water and it takes a lot of the water
and all the fish float.
Oh,
I've seen that in South American.
Yeah,
I got yet.
So imagine how long it took to work out.
That actually looked like.
That's crazy,
isn't it?
That's another thing that they eat in
Bolivia.
Casaba.
Yeah.
I've never heard of that.
I haven't.
No.
It's a route that if you eat it raw,
it's super toxic as a whole really
involved process where you have to.
You have to soak it and then you have to
drain it very similar and then it turns
into A.
There's actually Sinai that comes out of
it.
Yeah.
See if you can find a video,
Jamie,
on preparation of Casaba and this
cassava is apparently Rinella was
telling me about it.
That's what it was.
I had read about it before,
but Rinella was telling me how poisonous
it is that the stuff that they like,
but that good.
That's like birth gay lover.
That's what it looks like.
So,
um,
they,
they have these buckets around the camp
fire.
You've got to find a better video than
this.
This cat.
So good.
All the rest of her recipes that.
I mean,
some of those preparing.
Yeah.
Well there's a really involved process
in order to cook it.
Yeah.
So yeah,
you get it right or you're dead.
You're dead,
you know?
Yeah.
Just amazing that they figured this out
so you have to do all this stuff to it
and prepare it.
And the actual buckets of liquid.
They were saying Rinella was talking
about how they just leave them around
the camp and he was like,
what if,
what if a kid drinks that?
They don't.
So she's cooking it up.
Just got some way to special anyway.
Anyway,
but yeah,
I mean how long did it take them to
figure out that if they can grind that
plan up,
throw it in the water official Pamela
died eating their cells because it looks
like a fruit.
Yeah.
And there's so many in the Australian
outback that look and smell and even
taste good.
But man,
I'll kill you.
Baseball crazy when you think about the
trial and error involved in figuring out
what you can and can't eat.
Mother,
motherfucker.
Now we've got all these books.
Least that takes the,
takes the mystery out of stuff like
that.
But even then people screw it up.
Oh,
official time with mushrooms.
I nearly did it the other day.
There's one that it's um,
it's sort of tastes similar to an apple,
but a little bit like on the sour side,
if it was an unripe apple,
it's completely edible.
There's another one that looks nearly
exactly the same,
but it drops the same pink flare at the
bottom of it.
It's got this little spike that comes
off it and so I'd been walking around
eating these other ones because I didn't
have hardly any food and then I'm like,
oh,
there's a freaking whole heap of me and
I grabbed,
grabbed them and just put them in the
backpack,
got to this waterhole,
crack that open and just force shit is
at the same time and then I smelled it
and straight away.
It's not the same time.
It didn't have the same seeds or
anything,
but how quick of a mistake to make and
that one,
that second one that I grabbed his
really frigging poisonous too.
So it's like,
oh yeah,
I need to carry a Bush Tucker book with
me,
but at least those books out there now
food things.
Yeah,
I've seen those ads around.
they use them for Sushi apparently.
Like the really a skillful Sushi chefs.
They slice through this thing and filet
it put what the fuck.
The smallest mistake in preparation
could be fatal,
but Tokyo city's government is planning
to ease restrictions that allow only
highly trained and licensed chef to
serve the dish.
Fuck all that.
We'll just have a fucking eighth and
normal fish cross too many crazy
assholes.
But I think it's for people,
they like the thrill of knowing that
they're reading something that could
kill,
you know,
if prepared incorrectly.
He sounds like a fucking nail company.
Montana.
So how good that elk taste though.
Knowing what all the way through it.
Well,
because all the stuff and by the end
like you can,
you can only have limited food with you.
And then even though I come out of the
wall,
you know,
for like I come into town and bought the
bullets,
I didn't go to a store and be like,
I'm going to load up on a heap of other
food and shit.
Got For me.
That was going to wreck the trip,
you know?
So I just go into town,
grab the bull bullets.
Yeah,
fucking wood.
It was a challenge to live off the land
I did.
Yeah.
I wanted to live off the land.
I must have brought some food with you,
right?
Yeah.
Like,
so the first probably the first 11
daylight.
Pretty good.
What did you bring with you?
Your meals?
You know,
little energy bars,
just because everything's got to be
light,
you know,
so most everything was dehydrated or
just like a light type of food is
simple.
Simple as it is.
And then heaps of chocolate bars.
Actually,
they're not that light,
but fuck,
you need them when you're out there,
you need to pack that energy back on and
keep going.
So he hates the chocolate bars.
And then specific ones.
Do you use or just anyone you can get?
Just I can get just regular chocolate,
snickers bars.
That shit locked up,
right?
Yeah.
Calories.
Just calories.
Half the chocolate bars in America.
I don't even know what they are.
And then I opened them up and I'm like,
ah,
that shit,
you know,
because I did it so deep.
Different back in Australia,
but we do have sneakers,
but like we've got a Mars bar.
You don't have a Mars bar here.
It's called a Milky Way.
No,
we have Mars idea,
I couldn't find them anywhere and then
be favorite it.
Oh,
they have mars bars here.
I must have went to the wrong store was
fucking dirty,
but I bought the milky ways which are
different back in Australia as well.
And they are more similar to a Mars bar.
So.
But yeah,
so the first 11 days I pretty well,
but I'd still,
if I could spare food,
like if I could shoot a grouse.
Oh elite,
that if I come across barriers I'd eat
those.
M and I sort of had contact with um,
April Voki who's like really into the
outdoors and fly fishing and stuff.
She knows a lot of Australia.
I did,
yeah.
Yeah.
And she's,
she's hunted with us a few times and her
get along like a house on fire.
So it works out good so far.
Good House.
You don't have that same eva get along
like a house on fire.
That seems like a terrible way to get
along with your fucking furious.
That's a few of those weird ones and I'm
like,
how'd they even come up with that one
right there?
You know,
like jump the gun.
Did they actually jump the gun?
Yeah.
Well that's jumping.
The starting block already sent.
Bang.
Jumped the noise.
No,
jumped the gun.
Makes Sense.
It makes more sense to get along like a
house on fire unless you have the fire
because you're fucking burning up your
gun blazing so you could look at it like
that as well.
See where you're going with that.
Yeah.
Um,
so April was sort of my go to person.
Like if,
if I had reception,
I'd take a photo and be like,
can I make this?
The worst thing is because she,
sometimes she be busy.
I'd be collecting heaps of them.
Like I'd need that and she'd be like,
definitely not.
And I'll be like fuck,
but I'm most things just from taste and
a few things already knew.
But there'd be some areas,
especially up high where those beers
were,
where I was seeing that grizzly in
Colorado.
There was barry's everywhere and that's
obviously one of the bays where they,
oh,
okay.
You ate those berries.
Just like frigging raspberries,
blueberries.
There's those rows,
nips.
Do you know those?
They look,
they don't look edible and they're
pretty hard,
but they're really good for you,
but you hate too many of them.
They'll make you feel itchy.
Itchy.
Yeah.
Which I never felt itchy,
but I didn't want to get to that point.
Like walking around hunting.
Really?
They make you itchy.
When we instituted crack,
what was the word?
Was the word that you used?
Bush something.
Bushtukah.
Bush Tucker.
What does that mean?
Taco?
You Americans need that?
Come up with a scratch.
You fucking mall.
Can't say fucking as ing.
Ing.
It's got to be a n
on the end of the fucking.
You'd say Ian,
where you would say I am.
And then put an apostrophe.
Yeah,
right.
Fucking fucking fucking mall there.
You gotta say I was trying to fit right
in.
Perfect.
You'd get to get used to driving on the
wrong side of the road.
No,
it's the right side.
I'm pretty sure.
But yeah,
so April was my go to.
What does that mean though?
Bush?
Tacos.
Food.
So food.
Bush Tucker talk his food truck.
Taco Tucker.
Tucker.
Yeah.
Talk.
Let's go get some tucker.
Yeah,
let's go and get some tacos.
Go get some top.
Have you ever heard that young Jeremy
know that is,
this is normal.
It is very normal for who?
For dry heat.
And it's just like a dialect that you
picked up with the outback.
No,
it's pretty fucking.
Thank God for Google show called Bush
food is any food native to Australia and
use assessments by the original
inhabitants to aboriginal Australians.
But it can also describe native for or
Florida Flora or fauna.
Um,
so that was something.
Did you pick up from the indigenous
people?
No,
I think I'll just rise like that.
You know,
so it's just a phrase grew up out in the
Bush Tucker,
the woods.
Mar Lou is what you call a kangaroo.
Yeah,
they're indigenous names Maher.
Lou,
Bard.
Dewar.
Uh,
what does that word that looks like it
could be magpie geese.
And what is that one?
What does that,
how does that word Yali.
That's the name you.
Yay.
You Halle Berry.
And so do the people,
the indigenous people they date
Kangaroos?
Yeah.
Yeah,
definitely.
Kangaroos,
wallabies.
Go in and see every kangaroo.
Yep.
Um,
it's a very rich red meat,
like a really,
really rich red meat.
Good.
It's delicious.
And it's super lean,
like there's no fat content to it.
And so do you buy it in a store?
You can.
What the fuck is that man?
That's bullshit.
Yeah,
that's right.
it's bullshit.
How is it bullshit guys?
Holding Brown sounded real.
Grub?
No,
it's like a wood grabber.
Witchetty grubs.
That good?
Aiden.
Oh.
So it's not really that big.
Wide.
Not that day.
Good grubs there.
That'd be witchetty grubs in good grubs.
Hold on.
So you see those?
Oh,
thems.
Good grubs.
Like you,
you'd go eat those.
Have you seen that video?
GRUBS went up.
They building the cabinet and I'm
stripping the bark off it.
You will see all those grubs and I get
them and cook them up and eat and eat
them.
Just like paint up out at night,
but better.
They taste like peanut butter.
Yeah,
they do.
Yeah.
Really?
Probably even better than peanut butter.
What kind of peanut butter do you guys
have in Australia?
They pretty good.
What does that?
Uh,
honey and honey and sugar ants.
Those are good.
Yep.
And if you run out of like a,
if you're running out of tea or you
know,
if you want a hot drink and you're out
in the bush,
then you'd boil your water and then
you'd get a heap of those in a leaf or
on a leaf and you dip them in hot water
and it makes like a nice tea.
But it's like sweetened already from the
ant.
I carry like a sugary taste on them.
Whoa.
So that little thing on there but is
actually honey.
Yep.
They have a little bubble pack.
Well it's not really honey,
but it tastes like honey.
Really?
Yeah.
It looks like honey though.
Well what is it?
I'm pretty sure that anything that can
produce honey,
that's crazy though.
The Bar,
that's their abdomen essentially,
right?
Yep.
So it looks like those black things
settled as a separated.
Rather.
It's,
we'd look fucking some in photoshop.
So strange.
So they're tiny.
Strange because we don't eat it.
But imagine those things were grown on a
farm or and harvested for mass
production.
No different than lame or I know what
insects do.
We ate none,
which is frigging weird.
Why wouldn't we ate insects?
They food.
People are starting to eat crickets and
frogs and crickets being bugs.
Yeah.
A lot of people eat crickets these days.
Cricket,
protein powder.
It's very popular in America.
I think it will become,
I shouldn't say very like there's two
people in all of America.
We'd becoming more properly.
They have,
um,
I think they have a nice cricket protein
bar that you can buy.
I haven't tried them but I send a
Mexico,
but I've heard good things about them.
But I've been in Mexico and we went to
this resort and when you check into your
hotel room,
they have like a little bowl of fried
crickets really with chili powder and
stuff.
Proudly strange.
What is that?
That the company and they sell crooked.
Oh,
xl.
What's his Goddamn pop up ads?
So Ekso Exoskeleton is curriculum.
I can understand why we wouldn't eat,
but we should have six.
Well,
not only that,
but vegans should shitty them because
it's a great way to get be 12 and most
people don't really care that much about
bugs.
It's like the,
the,
the thing about Vegan seems to be a
sentient animals and worrying about
killing these.
I'm feeling life for them and if they,
if that's the way they feel,
they could be far healthier.
Eating mollusks mollusks are a big one.
They don't feel shit and they're fucking
stupid.
Like marks they say are dumber than
plants are more primitive than plants.
The fact that they move is what freaks
people out,
but what does a Vegan eat?
A Venus fly trap.
Would they eat that fucking moves to
plant on the move.
They just take a left on the move and
grow.
Exactly.
But crickets are really good source of
protein,
so if someone wants to get animal or
some sort of living proteins,
particularly like the nutrients and
amino acids that you can get from that
kind of protein,
just look into insects don't die.
You fuckers.
I'm going to stop my insect farming to
it,
bitch.
Fuck.
This is.
Hey,
become a millionaire.
Seems like a tough.
I mean,
trust me.
Fuck.
Is it a tough sell with aiden?
Little lambs?
Well,
not only can't dry.
We're eating kangaroos.
And how about crabs and lobsters?
Which water?
Yeah,
crickets in particular.
Tastes good.
I'm telling you man,
I was grabbing on those crickets in
Mexico.
They had like a nice chili powder on
fried and like luxe,
other like crunchy kind of savory,
a little savory.
They were good.
They would like.
I would buy him.
Yeah,
that sounds good.
Days grabs that.
I'm talking about a delicious to draw
the line.
Not Full.
Delicious.
It's just the full delicious.
That's the whole thing that the
Australian say full fully or full.
Amazing.
Fully sick.
Mad Come.
That is a good expression.
Cut.
Cameron.
I,
I actually,
some people might've been from me saying
that and they were like,
where can I get mad cunt?
Shit.
Your.
They had nice.
Can't because a can't or a bad con and
the shirt that everyone wanted the.
I actually got one printed out but it
didn't come and tell them I was gonna.
Wear it here.
Be Interested.
Just being nice.
Can.
It's as simple as that,
where you guys are very different use of
the word cunt.
Yeah.
Is like a good dude.
Well,
be mad if you say mad con.
That's awesome.
That's,
that's a bad motherfucker.
But if you're lucky,
you're a fucking cunt,
right?
No,
that's interesting.
Yeah.
Have much more range with the word
content.
Do I love Australians?
Like even though you're going to say yes
or no,
they're always like,
Yay.
So they start with you and then they
were like,
Nah.
Yeah,
yeah.
No,
that's a good one.
That's a good one.
Yeah.
Or if you're going to say no,
then go.
No,
you sake.
You shake your head,
but you say no,
it means I don't give a fuck.
You pick what you want.
So yes,
you're nodding yes.
Kim will be like,
you know,
should I this swimsuit?
You know,
and I'll be like,
no,
because whatever,
whatever the fuck I say,
doesn't matter.
She's going to get what she wants.
Yeah.
You know what I've developed.
I developed an amazing ability to not
listen when someone's talking.
That's what I've been doing.
This whole show.
Oh man,
I don't mean I could hear they talk
about stuff that I like,
especially with my wife gets together
with her friends.
They can have a conversation that could
be right there.
I don't hear a fucking thing came lobby
in a field.
Just hearing truth.
You're antisocial.
I'm like,
no,
not antisocial.
I just don't have to talk about
everything.
I'm quite happy.
Sitting there quietly thing think is a
very big biological difference between
the way women like to especially a guy
like you who does so much hunting where
it's very valuable to be quiet.
Yeah.
I've actually had some friends say to me
like that I'm very antisocial and it's
like you're not interested in hanging
out with first and stuff like that.
And friends hunt.
Yeah,
they do.
But I like hunting solo,
like I just,
but it's not like a choice that I'm
like,
I'm not fucking taken humor.
I'm not inviting him or whatever,
but I'm just happy to do it alone.
So if I'm planning a trip,
I don't necessarily plan it around
someone else's time or something like
that.
So they think you're antisocial because
I wouldn't do it.
Well the,
yeah,
and they and they're a little bit like,
um,
they also like,
how can you just go out there by
yourself like that,
like don't you get bored or you don't
miss talking to someone or whatever.
And then,
and it's taken me years to figure it
out,
like why am I so comfortable being by
myself or not saying a word in a crowd
of people at a talk and,
or,
and like,
you know,
my past growing up.
But a lot of it's been from my past
growing up and like I've nailed it.
It's like I grew up with people that
were supposed to be loved.
Ones that didn't show love at all.
In fact they taught you the complete
opposite instead of teaching trust,
like poor distrust because this is
supposed to be a person that's close and
treat your world and they're fucking
treating you like shit.
So you slowly start moving away from
sort of mankind in a sense where we
started association associating people
with a negative feeling.
Exactly.
And so the way that I'd get treated,
you know,
growing up was I'd be better off by
myself,
you know,
I'm better off safer,
Kim sort of that now.
But that's what I mean,
has she directed it?
But um,
yeah,
I grew up all those years knowing,
you know,
not to trust people and people are
fucking actually dangerous and stuff
like that.
So I'm happy being off by myself and
doing my own thing.
And then like I said,
now it's different.
I've got my own family and I know the
complete opposite.
I trust and love and everything like
that.
But it's also the hunting thing for you
that when you're hunting you're just
locked in on the task at hand to a
degree.
Definitely don't want someone with you
that's going to mess it up or not
because I'm not a self that,
that sort of sounds a little bit
selfish.
I don't mean it that way.
What I mean is it like you're focused
now definitely focused on need anybody
else?
But when you're focused you don't,
you really don't need anybody else.
It's just the,
the,
the task,
just you against the elements.
Yeah,
I,
I think it's that it's pushing myself.
It's,
I love the fucking wilderness.
Like it's just as simple as that.
And Joe,
like I always feel like,
like I love the society we live in and
this whole system,
but it's not the system that I've
designed for myself.
Like I'd love to go back 10,000
years,
dude.
Jesus and believe in them and have a
shitty blow though.
Fuck.
Oh yeah.
Arrows would be indigenous to Australia
which are running around with a spear
and boomerang.
Dude,
you'd be happy with that.
Oh hell yeah.
I wouldn't be happy with that.
I'm not knowing what I know though.
So this is the thing with Kim's fucked
it for me.
Like I wish he could just be a real
bitch and nasty and not good looking and
then,
you know,
it'd be like I am going walkabout.
I coming back,
funny expression going walk about that
is a funny expression.
Walkabout.
Yeah.
Just because I would take him so far to
get from wherever they were,
you know,
because I travel a lot.
Um,
there's actually,
there's,
I think there's some hard evidence now
that indigenous Australians because
there was symbols like right down on the
east coast of Australia,
the same exact symbols go all the way up
the coast to the northern territory.
This is a five day drive by the way that
the indigenous would walk that,
you know,
so,
so walk about like Kevin used to walk
from community.
So that's built by the Australian
government to housing indigenous people.
Then they also have a,
we call it on country,
but I'm like at our community Jesper,
he's mob on his land,
you know,
Kevin's a traditional owner just,
but he's Milan,
he's land.
They would walk that,
it would take them five days to walk it
and then so if they went out on country
for a while and haunted and stuff like
that,
which side?
I spend another 20 or 30 days out there,
maybe longer than another five days
walk.
You can see why they called it a
walkabout.
That disappeared.
And that's how the science come up.
When you go away for a long time is
you've gone and walk about because you
literally walk that distance,
they'd be out on country for certain
amount of period and then come back.
So that's why I've sort of adopted as
well,
like when I go walkabout walkabout on
Chemo,
fair bit.
The idea of driving five days that they
could walk it.
And now these are different.
I mean you were talking about all the
different dialects and different tribes
of people.
Now what the hell did they do with they
encountered sometimes I'd have that.
They'd be war and stuff like that
between truck,
between mobs.
They'd be war and things like that
because that I think in most cases
they'd try and avoid it and they'd have
like their corridor that they walk
through.
But uh,
they all had their own land.
What they sort of pretty much caught.
I can't say they all had their own lane
because there's so many indigenous mobs
that.
And there was so many differences
between them that some of them would
just pure nomadic,
you know?
And just just have written language.
I don't know.
I think they've written language
freaking don't quote me on this was like
the dream time and the paintings and
everything like that and everyone tells
him a story.
What's getting lost is it's only the
traditional elders that know those
stories and they got to pass it on to
the next generation.
So this is their story.
This is their paintings,
this is how the story goes when it gets
lost is when the mall essentially dies
out,
you know,
or it's not passed on down through the
generations.
That's just so crazy that there's this
enormous population of people and their
stories not being told.
Yeah,
it seems sad when I think about it.
In one sense it seems really sad,
but in another sense it shouldn't matter
to anyone else because it's just those
people's language and their stories.
So if they die,
it's gone with them anyway.
Yeah.
But I mean it's still,
just for the historical record,
I think it'd be great for human,
just a human life.
Definitely to understand that this is a
really,
uh,
a very little understood group of human
beings.
Don't you height that the mystery is
getting taken out of everything though,
like it's good to have all that
information,
like go on Google and find out frigging
the age of the last ice age or something
like that and which is awesome,
but it also cancels out all the mystery.
Like we know that there's no other sort
of monster crocodile in the waters
anymore because the whole world's like
right at our fingertips instead of being
a hoe out,
have that mystery in their mind.
Like,
oh,
I wonder what's out the back there.
You know?
And that's why I feel like there's no
more last frontiers.
I love Colon Arnhem Land,
the last frontier in places like
Northwest Territories,
the last frontier because there's hardly
any humans out there,
but the truth is it's all been
discovered.
It's all pretty much been documented
pipe that you got some like real
wanderlust dude,
you got side type shit.
That's why I'm like,
I wish I could go back in.
Like there's no way to discover anymore.
Like Stuart Macdonald,
who's he?
He was an alcoholic buddy who's a a is
actually a real famous early explorer
that come into Australia and Australia
was convinced all the people of
Adelaide,
we're convinced that's where the first
settlements were,
that there was an inland ocean in
Australia because there's all these
rivers running out from the center of
Australia and it couldn't be the
opposite as you know,
it's whole fucking desert,
but they walk in and out of there so
many times and so many men died and a
Mcdonald's.
Stuart himself nearly died a couple of
times from starvation and no water
because now walking into the desert.
In the end he was successful and he
ended up walking all the way through to
the top of Australia.
Dude,
there's no fucking water until you get
to the top of Australia.
How did he get through it,
but imagine being back then when there
was all that mystery there was that you
were thinking that there was an inland
ocean in Australia because of these
rivers running out,
but those rivers are ancient rivers.
They're millions of years old and for so
many hundreds of thousand years I
haven't even ran on top of the surface.
They run onto the sand,
didn't the rocks.
I was rivers so crazy to think.
But at some of the stories is um,
he's got an awesome book.
Well,
he doesn't have an awesome book because
he's long gone,
but it's an awesome book.
Erin called Mr Stewart track and um,
there's one point [inaudible]
indigenous,
like they had never encountered the
indigenous and things like that as well.
They walk into the center of Australia
where it was highly populated with
indigenous people.
No white people had ever been in there,
no settlers before that were literally
cutting the first tracks and drawing the
maps dude.
And like they walk in the one spot and
like they,
they had been three days or something
without water.
Like they are on the brink of death and
it's,
I think it's like a miracle.
There's like a little well out there,
like a clay built well out in the middle
of nowhere and it's got this crystal
clear water in it.
They keep the cattle and horses at bike
because Katelyn horses would smell the
water and just go in there and trash it
before the man could get there so they
keep the cattle and horses that by that
going if they on canteens and fill them
up and drink and you know,
all the manager just getting as much
water as I can.
Then they've let the horses and cattle
go so they can have a drink now.
The horses and cattle come in there and
they trampled his whole.
Well,
like it ends up going back to dust
because I gave it all in.
They drink as much water as I can,
like have it all in and uh,
the water pretty much dissipates.
Then they ride out for three or four
days and they can't find water and
they've run out of the water that they
collected there.
They turned back to there and it might
have even been longer.
It might have been a couple of weeks.
I might have been on the way back off
the not being able to go any further.
And I come back there and there's all
these aborigines said dead because the
aborigines were the ones that would put
the willingness.
They walked days and days and they would
just have a water source at the last
point that just go.
They knew water was there.
They drink that,
be able to make it the next three or
four days.
The next bit of water.
They get there.
It's fully caved in.
They can't get to the water.
There's a whole mob of indigenous people
dead there.
They.
They knew they couldn't go on any
further or at least all the ones that
were dead.
They knew they couldn't go on any
further and a dog are there and there
was no water.
There was no world there anymore.
Like the catalog just trampled it.
And one thing like as if that's not
crazy enough,
but one thing that I always think about
is I'm imagining the indigenous people
coming across these who've prints like
that because there's nothing in
Australia.
You've got to think they're the biggest
animals running around in Australia
would like Kangaroos,
dude,
I'd have these little toad legs.
And then they come across these massive
prints for the first time that had just
devastated their,
the last drink and hall before they move
onto the next place.
Crazy stories in this book.
So there's no way to dig down deeper to
restart the.
Well,
I guess.
No,
I guess at that point yet.
So you're already so dehydrated,
but you're walking to a point that you
think that there's water because you
build a well and then there's not
anymore.
Not that idea.
Very much debt they would've given up
because they are hottie people.
But whatever they tried to do obviously
wasn't enough fucking white people know.
Isn't that horrible story why people
ruin everything?
I hate to say we've done a lot of good
thought wrong of white people.
Yeah.
But,
but so I see the mystery behind fucking
just walking into the center,
even though it's a horrible mystery to
go through,
you know?
That's what I mean.
At least a haven has done at the Di in,
in the middle of Australia thinking I'm
going to go when they fish and there's
an inland ocean in somewhere and they
never come across it.
You're at the middle of the desert,
but at the same time it takes away from
all the mystery in life at it
things way different than me because you
have that wanderlust.
Got You.
Have that.
I want to go out and find the hidden
things.
I don't have any of that shit.
Yeah.
I'm like,
okay,
where's the water?
No,
no,
no.
Show me on a map.
Where's the water?
Okay.
Where?
What?
What kind of equipment do we need?
What are we doing?
Do we have backup gun?
We get charged like you and I are very
different in that regard.
I have no desire to go to uncharted
towards Reiki.
It's not.
The risk that's appealing was just a
wanderlust.
It must be.
Just put your finger on that last.
That cave system that you put a picture
up of before that I took photos of a lot
of people have asked like where is that?
But for me personally,
I'd like to keep that undocumented
because it seems once a place is known
as no different than a good fishing or
hunting spot,
it gets fucking ruined.
And that cave system,
for starters,
it's not up to me because you know,
that'd be up to the traditional owners
to want to put that out there for people
to go and look at it.
It's not up to me,
so I can't share that information.
But for me personally,
I don't want that to be documented
because I know as soon as it's
documented,
robish will shop there.
Some decades will shop there and spray
paint or scribble on rule one or some
shit like that.
Some places are better off on
undocumented.
Well we,
the human race has got to evolve past
that and that's a big order.
Obviously that's a very tall order.
But God,
we've got to evolve past
set a fucking white dude.
There's good people and bad people for
the donut man.
Right?
But I think there's more good people now
than ever before.
Definitely more informed people now
where before we just got to keep
progressing along the same lines.
And I think that that progress is
accelerating.
And I would just hope that more people
in the future would have more
appreciation for what that is,
is just like this incredible historical
resource.
Are you seeing these mean we're talking
about 65,000
years of people in this area and who
knows how old those paintings.
It could be thousands of years old,
right?
I mean,
has anybody done leg or carbon dating on
them?
I'm sure there has been a bunch of.
They find those in Texas sometimes from
native Americans to find them in caves.
Just find a cave system.
And then you just encountered these
pictures.
I was hunting in New Mexico.
Uh,
we,
we saw,
I tagged out and then like I didn't want
the hunt and the hunt was done.
Sorry,
I didn't have any tags lift.
I didn't want the experience to end,
you know,
that's why I say it's never ever been,
just killing an animal.
It's about the whole adventure,
the whole package.
And uh,
I was with an outfitter and the guides
like,
oh,
you tagged out,
what do you want to do?
I'm like,
well,
let's go explore it and go walk.
And steel and just take photos of the
country,
saw it or whatever.
Um,
you put that all up on your blog to
write it in a magazine,
a magazine that one on there.
Read that actually it might be on both
sides.
Dot Com.
I think I did a live one anyway.
Go up on top of these Mesa and uh,
you can see these rock a,
like a huge rock and new shakes which
used to be like the Anasazi Indians.
That's how I used to have their housing
and stuff like that.
Perfect spot right up high.
Looking down onto these big meadows.
Like it would've been the perfect place
to if other tribes were coming in,
you'd be able to say them.
And if any animals working for moving
through there,
you'd be able to see them just the
perfect spot.
And we'd get up there.
And as I get to the top,
the first thing you find is a bunch of
pottery.
And uh,
the Anasazi had a certain color,
I think it was the white with the black
writing on the pottery.
And the Navajos had the orange with the
white writing on the pottery and there's
both types sitting in this area,
so I don't know if there's a bit of
confusion or maybe I'm lacking a bit of
information there,
but as far as I've looked into those,
the Anasazi Indians and it's the hallway
or,
and they liked this,
must've been some major.
Saw it dude.
I found a perfect stone.
Broadhead just sitting right there on a
rock and it just rained.
So everything was clean.
Everything was clean.
I picked it up and like my mind boggled
straight away.
Like why,
how did this get here?
Who held it?
Did they shoot it?
Who Shop?
And the history behind it.
And um,
then so we kept walking around.
I found a full ax head dude.
Like obviously the team has gone off the
ax because it's been there for so long.
The team has just brought it,
the nothing.
The ax hates sitting there.
Perfect.
We ended up finding three ax heads,
uh,
Indian pendant,
you know,
if the perfect little hole like scribed
in it.
And just like crazy.
Dude.
Did you bring that bag with you because
it was privately handles.
I was able to take it.
You take a photo,
the of the uh,
broadhead.
Yep.
Good.
All that document.
Those fascinate me.
I was nearly going to give you the
broadest.
I'm like,
that's taken it to fucking deserve it.
You can add the buffalo skull.
I shed a tear.
Just pot with that buffalo skull and
buffalo skills.
It doesn't matter.
They will mean something to Bert was
saying today.
He killed the dog.
The cat things freaks people out about
Australia.
That dog freaks people out as well,
but it's no different than shooting a
coyote here a problem.
Animal dingoes will one of the first.
They believe one of the first introduced
species in Australia and it come with
the indigenous population at some point.
Oh,
so they came with
indigenous people?
Yup.
So the indigenous people out there,
wild dogs is Dingo.
Sorry,
is most of them aren't dingoes anymore
because there's been a wild dog
population that's sort of peppered
through there as well.
Dingoes and w and normal dogs,
like a domestic dog that's gone wild had
now in a bread and I,
I'm pretty sure that any place you can
find a purebred Dingo now is on Fraser
Island in Australia.
They've got a policy or regulations that
is not allowed to be any domestic
animals taken to the island and also the
population stayed pure.
Oh Wow.
So if you live there,
you can't have a dog.
I don't think he can live on the island
at all.
Oh yeah.
It's one of those things.
Yeah.
Kind of weird rules about wade roses
that you can't hunt anything native.
That's very strange to me that they
wouldn't just have to.
But you have.
Kangaroos are on some of our currency,
so they're like our icon.
So imagine eight annual Bodega,
like eight and year American icon.
So that's one way to look at it by
chicken,
but we kind of need a kid news all
frigging wombats or anything like that?
No,
not that I'd probably want to,
but people do eat kangaroo though.
That's why I'm confused.
And the indigenous cancer,
Dingo big,
good looking dog.
She will,
you know,
that'd be Fraser Island dog.
There you go.
So that's a look at them on the lake.
It's a beautiful dog that feels like you
could take that thing as a puppy and
raise it.
There's,
I've got a buddy who had one habit,
goatees little girl,
like try and grab these little go when
he had it as a puppy or not just a wild
one that come into the tent and tried to
grab him ripping a wallet down there.
So what happened?
Um,
he ended up killing the dog.
He founded the next morning and not
shooting it was a wall Dingo,
but Dingo ate my baby and I some truth
to that.
Oh yeah.
I've seen.
How should they go fishing?
Jesus Christ while eating a shark on a
beach,
that theft fucking cool photo as a
gangster ass dog when it got a lot of
meat.
I wonder if someone actually call it the
shark.
And that's another thing that people are
freaking out about it here in America.
It's most recent freakouts people
fishing and catching sharks.
Simon and strike that.
It used to be able to buy Maaco Shark.
It was very common for most flake and
the stuff that you bond shock,
you know,
like when you buy like a bad bit of fish
or something like that from one of them
quick type wise it does fish and chips.
Then most of that's actually flight,
which is just a shock really?
Yeah.
No,
no,
no.
Specific Australia?
No,
I probably hate to.
Do you think they're serving a lot of
tapes of him and there's a ton of them
that get into next net.
That's where they go really taste good.
I've eaten Maaco sharp before and is
delicious.
And electric swordfish.
It's the same as anything.
As long as we're not freaking killing a
male.
Well,
you know what happens is people find out
that a lot of people are killing them
for Finn's.
Okay.
Warning your fish and chips could
actually be shark.
Damn a bad motherfucker.
Boy,
this is drying last nine Bogan.
Okay.
Hey,
good fit rod into Australia last night.
Like bogus.
Cashed up.
Bogans.
Did you tell me that?
You might have told me that expression.
Kim talking smack far so,
um,
but I think what happened was over here
the people found out about how many
sharks get killed for the fins shark fin
soup and there was a big campaign to
alert people about it.
And,
and so then the people that have just
barely a peripheral awareness of
conservation and fishing and,
and animal life,
then they started going to kill sharks.
Sharks.
They're assholes.
Meanwhile they're eating a cod.
Exactly.
Having some salmon for lunch on the
salad.
Would you eat this fish?
A shark called the dog fish makes it
tasty.
Taco.
Yeah.
I need to fuck out of a dog.
Fish me.
It's still a fish.
I mean,
it's not efficient shark,
but I just don't understand why people
would differentiate between that.
And tonight.
How about you assholes that really loves
Sushi.
Back the fuck off of the tuna because
they're killing all the Goddamn tuna.
There's probably more sharks.
There are tuna.
They.
Yeah.
There's some pretty strict regulations
in Australia.
The whole world needs to know.
There's some regulations that have come
into the northern territory of Australia
now because you can actually shoot a
magpie geese with a bow and arrow.
So there's magpie geese and introduced
turkeys like what you guys have here in
the states,
they're the only birds that you can
shoot with a bone.
Our window Australia.
Oh really?
So they just brought in a season for
magpie geese,
which really restricts a lot of the.
Honda's taken too many,
which is fine.
I think that that's probably not a bad
thing,
but then these birds fly to other
countries where there's no restrictions
at all and they just fucking get
hammered.
Dude.
So it's like we're doing everything we
can on our part,
but I just go somewhere else and get
slower than any line.
Well you don't understand.
No issues with the shocks as well.
Like they've,
there's a few spaces that are highly
protected in Australia but they swim
abroad and they fair game for anyone but
eats great whites though right now that
I know of,
but I guess people would if they were
starved,
I would for sure.
I mean,
it's probably just fish tastes pretty
good.
I don't think that gave up too fucking
easy.
That's another monster live and monster
dual.
Yeah.
Legit monster.
There was an instance in San Diego a few
years back were these bunch of these
people were training for a triathlon and
they were swimming in the ocean and one
out of nowhere.
I just came and cut this guy and half of
everybody else just bit him right at the
waist.
This scary dude shot them right in half
chomp besides conserving their live
shark.
Meat can be terribly unhealthy.
According to CNN report from nearly 20
years ago,
the mercury levels in sharks can cause
coordination,
loss blindness,
and even deaths.
Scientists think that sharks accumulate
mercury in their body because they eat
many smaller fish.
That's interesting.
Why you shouldn't eat shark meat.
It doesn't and have a lot of mercury in
it as well.
I don't know.
They say,
I don't like to eat Marlin,
you know,
but I've heard Marlin's good.
I think a lot of those big fish,
especially the prey to the ones a full
of mercury.
Makes Sense.
Yeah,
I mean it's like predators in general
have a lot of weird things going on with
their body if you eat them,
you know like mountain lions can be
tricky.
GNOSIS interesting study like a,
it says at the top of the article,
an estimated 100 million sharks are
killed each year to feed consumer demand
and then the study came from a report of
a 124 sharks that were tested in.
One third of them came in with mercury
levels that were over FDA action level
of one part per million.
So 100 million sharks every year.
One hundred and 24 had a third of those
were problematic.
So 30 sharks were problematic or so 40
out of how many.
But they didn't test that many though,
right?
I mean they didn't test 100 million.
The tests at 140 were bad.
Ooh,
that's not good.
That's not good.
It's real bad you think?
Yeah,
that's terrible.
Doesn't say maybe they were all one area
too.
They could have came out of one shitty
maybe area.
And I've told this story 100 times,
but I'll say it again just quickly.
I had arsenic in my body from when I did
a blood test and he said,
what are you eating?
And I said,
I eat a lot of sardines,
and the guy said,
back off the sardines,
we'll try it again in a couple of weeks.
And the arsenic was gone.
Eating two cans of Sardines Day.
I love sardines.
I don't know why I like sardines on.
Totally love them.
They're great.
Came back road swordfish.
Yep.
Oh,
do not eat shark swordfish.
King Mackerel or tile fish.
Because they contain high levels of
mercury.
I've heard that about tune as well.
I don't know those certain areas.
Some tuna apparently contains high
levels of mercury were assholes.
I was reading something about fucking
crabs.
I put it up on my twitter that crabs are
getting Prozac in the water from human
beings like because somebody fucking nut
bags are on Prozac that it's getting
into the oceans through runoff and it's
affecting crab behavior and it's making
crabs reckless.
And I already saved pretty fucking
reckless.
No,
they're bugs.
Right?
But apparently it's making the reckless
area.
It goes.
Roseanne,
puts crabs in a mood to take deadly
risks.
Shit that with me and Andrew Equals.
I mean what the fuck?
I mean,
how crazy is the human race where we are
giving PROZAC inadvertently to fucking
crabs and they're at a risk.
Apparently they're worried about the
population dying off or at least being
affected.
These crabs
are doing reckless things and it's going
to cause them to get preyed upon or die.
What the fuck man?
Shit,
crap brains on Ssri.
But what is that word?
How do you say that word?
Jamie flew.
Locks is a class of antidepressant
called SSRI or selective serotonin
reuptake inhibitor,
meaning that indirectly boosie amount of
mood altering serotonin available to the
brain.
It's designed to affect people's brains
in a way that can alleviate depressive
symptoms.
But past research has shown that when a
person's flew ox,
team filled,
waste enters,
flew their shit and Piss,
and there's the waterways.
It can alter the shores,
crabs,
reproductive molting,
and digestive behaviors and may even
cause the crabs to abandon their
nocturnal schedule according to the
paper.
Wow.
Humans.
And we're,
well,
we're definitely a mess.
A definitely.
Speaking of that.
Let's get outta here and go get
something to eat.
Yeah,
that sounds awesome.
I feel like I need to get you to say
that you come into Australia,
come to Australia eventually.
I'll do some shit.
Go to a nice restaurant,
have dinner,
come hunting deer killed by browns to
ask you one fucking protect you.
If if I die in everybody who likes this
podcast,
no longer gets a podcast,
there'll be fucking mad at you.
But bringing me to Australia,
it'll be leather skin mocking.
Worth.
It takes forever to eat.
You need to come meet you and Cam.
Alright,
we'll work something out.
Maybe just say go to Hawaii and shoot
axis deer resort.
Come on,
land hunt.
Buffalo sounds terrible.
No,
listen to what nick buff paste together.
Very authentic,
getting chased by salt water crocodiles
and watch brown snakes slithering into
our camp.
Probably like,
thanks for having me on the challenge.
And brother always.
Jamie,
Adam Green Tree.
Ladies and gentlemen.
Uh,
Adam.green
tree on instagram.
And a first.man
dot image.
Adam,
get it first man.
Adam and Eve cain was wearing a shirt
that I think she's adorable.
That's adorable.
All right.
Thanks brother.
Appreciate it,
but it's fun.