Five,
four,
three,
two,
one.
And we're live with Justin Brown.
Justin,
first of all,
I'm very upset that gave you such a
small badge.
What's up with that?
Yeah.
And it's nice and tiny.
They're not law enforcement.
So seems like you should have like,
like you've,
there's some badge there.
The summit forcement,
right?
Sure.
It looks like it doesn't it?
But yeah.
No law enforcement on my end.
And just the biologist.
Well,
listen man,
I've,
I read about your work in um,
uh,
an online article.
I don't remember where it was,
but about coyotes in the urban area all
around Los Angeles and I've been
fascinated by this since I moved to La.
The first time I saw a coyote was in
1994 when I first moved here.
I was in Burbank and uh,
I had an apartment and you know,
one of those,
um,
those uh,
pre furnished Oakwood's gardens
apartment on all of the street,
you know,
where that is not the top of my head,
but it's where people always,
when they transitioned to La,
they get one of these pre furnished
apartments.
He.
Anyway,
yeah.
I'm driving up olive and I saw these
coyotes and is the first time I'd ever
seen a coyote and I was like,
this is crazy,
like this is in Burbank,
this is in a residential area,
and they were just hanging out and I
pulled over and I stopped and I rolled
down the window and I,
oh,
staring at them and they're staring at
me and they didn't give a shit about me.
They were so calm and they didn't run
and I just remember thinking this is so
strange.
He's like wild dogs that live like right
amongst us.
And then from then on I've had some
encounters.
I had a coyote steal a chicken for my
yard.
I watched him hop the fence with the
chicken in his mouth if quite a few
encounters with coyotes,
but I'm,
I'm absolutely fascinated by them.
I mean,
they've been amazing.
I've been working with them now for
almost 15 years,
actually a little bit more than that
now.
And I've seen him do some amazing
things.
I mean,
they're able to live in some of the most
urban environments we can imagine.
I mean,
I'm tracking them right next to,
I don't know if you know where the West
Lake neighborhood is in downtown la,
but if a coyote running that
neighborhood,
which when I first drove through there,
so I worked in Chicago for a long time.
We were tracking coyotes and some
incredibly urban areas.
They're like,
right along the lake shore drive in
Chicago and,
but in Chicago there's some green spots
where when you get down in La,
there's not a lot of open spots,
vacant lots and stuff.
Um,
but I tracked this coyote for about nine
months down there in that area and she
was just amazing.
Like she was running the streets.
She kinda hang out in these little
vacant lots.
And what was even more amazing is that
no one was really complaining about her.
We actually talked to people and some of
the houses and stuff they were actually
fascinated to see on versus being like
they're in my backyard where they do it.
Well.
People have always had a weird
relationship with coyotes.
I had,
um,
Dan Flores on the podcast last month
who's the author of Coyote America.
And uh,
he's a,
uh,
wildlife historian and it has just some
amazing insight until like the
relationship to cody's had way back with
the native Americans,
you know,
they thought they were gods and a lot of
ways.
Yeah.
I actually listen to your podcast with
Dan.
That was great.
Dan's some pretty interesting facts just
in his book in general,
things I didn't actually know about
before.
It's kind of Nice to have a historian
tie in some of the facts I could get
lost,
ask lots of questions about where the
coyotes came from,
how they're moving around.
Um,
and so it's nice to have something like
Dan's book to kind of reference people
to.
I think most people in the downtown La
probably welcomed something like caio
because it's kind of cool,
you know,
and have this thing I can't get around
as long as you don't have a dog or a cat
that it's snatches.
Yeah.
And that's definitely the case.
A lot of people think it's cool,
but they do cause problems.
Um,
I'm actually dealing with one in Silver
Lake neighborhood that keeps going up to
people walking their dogs and trying to.
It's got a den in somebody's backyard is
actually deneen under their deck.
So the decks open and she put our seven
pups underneath this den.
Yeah.
So it's pretty crazy.
Um,
but she would basically,
but he gets closed with a dog.
She comes out and tries to run them off.
And this is pretty common during pupping
season.
This is the time when most people have
issues with coyotes because they're
trying to protect their dens.
I mean we're all obviously protective of
our offspring,
so they think that the dog is going to
find the pups and kill them or
something.
Uh,
I mean we don't really know why they're
doing it.
We assume that's probably the case.
They come up and they,
most of the attacks have been where they
just come up behind the dog and start
trying to like nip it.
It's back and the dog,
the people move on,
people freak out.
Um,
as far as I know,
there hasn't been anywhere that I would
actually like draw blood on the dog,
so it's almost more like,
it's like get the hell Outta here.
Right.
So they're just scaring them.
They're not trying.
They're not actually being predators.
That's what it seems like for the most
part.
I mean they definitely do kill a little
dogs.
Many occasionally end up fighting with
big dogs as well,
but that's rare.
Wow.
So these,
what are they eating?
Like especially the one in downtown?
Yeah.
So that's,
that's interesting.
Um,
we've actually been doing this study
using,
working with a bunch of citizen
scientists and I don't know if that's
the story you read or not,
but we're basically having people
collect coyote scat from around downtown
La and they were actually breaking.
The coyotes got up to look what's in it
and we're seeing a huge variety of
things.
I mean,
lots of fruits and stuff.
They were actually big time into
vegetation,
vegetation type stuff,
a lot of fruits and an urban
environment.
Obviously we got peaches and plums and
all kinds of crazy fruity and stuff that
they take advantage of,
but they're also eating rats and
squirrels,
cats,
um,
insects.
We see things like earwigs and those big
old potato bugs we'll see eating almost
anything you can think of.
They're taking advantage of human trash.
Well,
I,
I've had him in my yard for a long time
and one of the things that surprised me
is how much coyote scad that I find with
berries in it,
like I didn't know that there were
omnivores.
They really are omnivores then.
It's not like a,
like a dog or a cat.
I mean they pretty much everything.
Yeah.
I mean coyotes can take advantage and
that's why they're able to live amongst
us.
I mean,
because even when there's not a lot of
prey available,
they did,
they,
they're able to take advantage of these
different fruiting trees.
Yeah.
You know,
I was talking with a friend about it and
he was saying that he hates them and he
wants to kill them all and all this
stuff.
And I was saying,
but yeah,
but ever noticed that you don't see any
rats,
like we hardly have any rats,
like it's so rare that you see a rat or
a mouse in my area.
And I think a big part of that is
because you hear coyotes all the time
and I think they're eating them all.
I mean they definitely take advantage of
it.
Maybe there's other predators to.
I'm not sure where you live exactly.
The owls and hawks and stuff,
cats and all those different things.
Definitely have of those praise.
Well,
but yeah,
coyotes,
I mean they're amazing.
They are really are fascinating animals.
So this,
this one that got to downtown La,
do you know,
like when it arrived,
I don't know when it arrived.
So I,
I kind of drove through there looking to
see where I might be able to call her a
few animals so we could kind of see
what's going on and how these animals
are persisting down there and actually
do that.
Uh,
how do I see of where they're possessed
them?
Oh,
how do I call her?
Um,
so first we have to capture them.
So we'll put out traps will capture them
and then once I get them in a trap,
I'll go out with a poll,
I'll pin them to the ground and then
I'll hold him down.
Jesus,
I'll,
I'll put a muzzle on them and hold their
feet together and then we'll throw a
collar on him.
We'll take blood to look for disease.
You don't triangles,
we don't tranquilize them.
Wow,
that's crazy.
Yeah.
They actually go very docile.
They're a lot like a dog.
Once you kind of show them that you're
the dominant thing,
they kind of just lay over and you start
to be careful.
Obviously they can turn and bite you if
you don't muzzle them.
But usually once you get them down that
first time they usually just lay there
until you're done.
No kidding.
And it usually takes me somewhere 35,
40 minutes to do the whole thing and
they just lay there.
They're not fighting me anything to deal
with that.
Uh,
I'm sure I do.
I want to see that.
That's kind of a trip.
I would think that there'd be like a
wild cat.
Like I've had a feral cat before and I
had her when she was a kitten or he
rather when he was a kitten and he was
like a spazz,
like you couldn't even hold onto him.
He would freak out and climb the
curtains and Hisson sputter at you.
And now it's like a little domestic cat
that was born outside.
Oh yeah.
We do drug.
Any of our cats we catch.
So we catch a bobcat's.
It's another study that we're doing a
lot of.
Uh,
we've actually had a bobcat project
going on since 1996.
And so we've been calling those guys for
a long time.
They're not docile.
We don't trust them.
Raccoons are another species.
You don't handle those guys on drugs.
Oh yeah.
I would imagine they'll make you pay the
price and that crazy.
Like people don't realize it.
Raccoons are predators.
Yeah.
Well they're,
they're,
they're definitely omnivores.
Like just like the coyotes are.
They actually had a lot of fruit and
stuff they take,
I mean,
part of them living in an urban
environment is they're just taking
massive advantage of our garbage.
Right.
I couldn't just,
I mean we've,
I've seen amazing photos of like 13,
14 raccoons in one garbage can all
feasting down.
I have chickens in my backyard and this
one raccoon was by my chicken coop the
other day and I flashed a light on him
and he walked towards the light.
I was like,
look at this cocky bitch.
He just started walking at me and I got
nervous.
I was like,
I don't have a weapon on me or nothing.
I thought a flashlight.
He'd be like,
well,
let me get outta here.
He's just looking right at the
flashlight,
walking towards me,
you know,
trying to get to the chicken coop.
But you'd be amazed how many people feed
them because they're so dang cute.
Right?
Big Old mask on when people are like,
oh,
they're starving out there.
They can't find their own food,
and so they feel like they need feet on.
And same thing with coyotes to.
It's people feel like these animals
can't fend for themselves,
which is ridiculous because they're not
able to make it there because we're
feeding them.
They're making it because there's
resources for them to take advantage of.
Yeah,
I would imagine they probably play.
I mean,
like I said,
I think in my neighborhood they do play
an important part of keeping the rodent
population down,
but in downtown there's got to be a ton
of rodents as well.
I mean downtown for people that don't
know is like the only area in all of La
that really looks like a city.
Yeah,
definitely.
I mean I,
like I said,
I drove through there.
I mean after track and coyotes in
Chicago,
I didn't think they'd be in some areas
they are in la.
There seemed to be.
Everywhere I look I get photos of
coyotes on our cameras or get people
reporting them to us.
And this one that's in downtown,
it's just a single caio by herself?
No,
actually she's got a whole pack so I
call her and then within a couple she
was actually lactating when I caught
her,
so I know she had pups and then we ended
up seeing her with five pops probably a
week later and there was actually a,
a ambulance that drove by and she just
started howling and all the pups are out
there yipping and this is all like in
this little vacant lot between two
houses.
Wow.
So they just find these areas where
people aren't.
Yeah.
And so before we call it on,
the one thing I always heard is oh,
the coyotes are coming in from griffith
park or they're coming in from Elysian
park and coming into our communities and
they're just here for a night or two
night causing problems and leaving.
Well that's not what we're seeing.
Definitely.
Once we do these colors on these animals
were like,
no,
they've got pretty small home ranges.
They're kind of living just in the urban
environment.
They're not going back and forth while
living with us.
So do you feel like it's a good thing or
a bad thing to have them around or just
a thing?
I think it's just the thing.
I mean it depends on your perspective.
Um,
I think it's bad when people think we
need to feed them,
need to do these things,
like to encourage them and make them
more comfortable with us.
That's not a good thing because that's
when bites and that kind of stuff
happen.
But when it comes to the coyotes and
stuff,
living in these urban environments,
it's really all about us.
It's more about managing people,
getting people to quit feeding them or
quit.
I mean,
one thing I encourage people to do scare
the stupid coyote off like because
there's lots of people that have little
issues that occur with the coyotes.
They're cats get taken or the coyote
start just sitting there watching them.
I had somebody complained recently
because the that was sitting behind
their yard looking at their wife in the
Jacuzzi.
Oh Jesus Christ.
So it's a pervert.
Yeah,
exactly.
So it's like,
come on like,
oh,
he has to do,
if he really doesn't want it there,
go back there and turn the thing off and
tell you that a coyote is staring at
their wife.
Yeah,
you'd be amazed.
The calls we get about coyotes,
people just.
People are still not comfortable with
them being there even though they've
been there for a long time.
It's just people cannot get comfortable.
The idea of there being a,
a medium sized Predator in these urban
environments,
they're like the perfect size to almost
get away with it too.
You know,
they,
it's not like a wolf.
Like if a wolf was around,
everybody be freaking out.
Like it's too big,
but it is like know 40 pounds,
something like that.
And that's that.
That's a big coyote.
What's a small one?
A.
So our average is around 25 to 27
pounds.
Wow.
Okay.
So you're really small.
They are.
And that's why I'm always like when
people are so scared of,
I'm like,
it's really not that big of an animal.
I mean there's a lot of small dogs are
bigger than that.
They're smart though,
man.
They're really clever.
One of them.
He or she essentially what you would say
honey,
Dick,
my dog and tricked my dog into a.
do you know what,
um,
what it's like when a chicken molts they
actually have chickens as well.
Okay,
cool.
Yeah.
So,
uh,
my chicken was molting so I had a
separate her from the rest of the
chicken so she wasn't in a nesting box
and I put her in a cage by herself.
If you let them sit in a cage for a few
days,
they figure out that they don't really
have an egg and then they go back to
their normal behavior.
So,
um,
this coyote was too small to knock over
the cage,
but my massive is big enough to do it.
So she literally tricked my massive into
coming out with her towards where the
chickens are.
He knocks over the cage.
She steals the chicken and hops over the
fence.
Wild.
You see all this happen.
I caught him with another chicken in his
mouth and uh,
I was like,
you motherfucker.
And then I see the coyote jumped over
the fence with the chicken,
like he was with the coyote right next
to it.
He thought it was his friend,
like he was treating the kyle like,
this is my friend.
She's cool.
We hang out together and she tricked him
into knocking over this small pen
because he's like 140 pounds.
He just smashed that thing and broke it
open and she grabbed the chicken thanks
pro oil and hopped over the fence.
And I watched her.
I was sitting there,
I was playing like monopoly or something
with my wife and my kids are sitting in
the living room and I see the coyote
running across the backyard with the
chicken in its mouth and hopped over
this five foot fence.
Like it didn't even exist just just
right over the top of it.
I was like,
wow,
that's crazy.
They're girly smart.
I mean heck,
living downtown,
they've got to be like crossing roads.
It's amazing.
Like I watched them walk up to these
busy roads,
they stop about 10 feet shy,
kind of sit there listening.
Then they'll peek around the corner and
look both ways and then they'll run
across.
Well,
I've heard that they understand traffic
lights.
Now.
There was an article I read yesterday
about coyotes and traffic lights.
If there's real evidence that coyotes
understand when that beep beep,
you know that sound that they use for a
blind people that coyotes understand
that that means the cars aren't allowed
to go and that's when they walk.
Oh,
I haven't seen that one.
That's interesting.
It doesn't surprise me.
I mean there.
It's incredible watching them move
around this urban environment and just
dealing with us and dealing with
traffic.
Like they get around.
I mean they'll come out in the street
all suddenly somebody will peak out in
the street to go into the car and
they'll cut between the cars and go down
the sidewalk like they figured out our
movements and how to avoid us pretty
quick.
How many do you think there are in the
greater la area?
Oh,
I get asked that question a lot and it's
a hard one to answer because we don't
know because they are pack animals so
you could end up with easily.
It could be just two animals in an area
or it could be two adults with seven
young or it could even be five,
six,
seven,
10 adults together with with a pack of
young as well,
because a lot of times the young from
the year before may not disperse.
If there's enough food available,
they'll keep hanging in there until they
are able to find their own territory,
so whenever someone would give an
estimation,
it's really just a rough guess.
It's a very rough guest.
A lot of times what they'll do is
they'll just try to be like,
okay,
this is how big of an area caio uses and
then be like,
okay,
there's this much area in La and throw a
number out there,
but there's a lot of variables that come
in and it has the.
Do you feel like the numbers increased
over the past few years or?
Definitely not over the last few years.
It's possible over the long run because
I know there are some reports of places
that there weren't coyotes,
like the Baldwin hills,
there was some work done where they
identify it,
all the different animals there and
coyotes worn in their list.
So they use trail cams,
like what did they use to identify the
animals back then I think they were
doing a lot of tracks surveys and just
going out there into the field and
looking for them.
A track service.
Meaning like looking at the ground.
Exactly.
Yeah.
And with coyotes they leave enough scat,
different places.
Like if they were looking hard for them
they would've found them.
How can you tell the difference between
cat and dogs?
Cat,
I'm usually,
so dogs get is almost always just dog
food.
Um,
and it doesn't.
These coyote scats ended up getting more
spiraled inside and so there'll be
really tapered on.
The ends were dogs get can be tapered,
but it's usually just drastically
different.
Huh?
Why is it tapered?
A,
it's partially just the way their
digestive system works and they're
getting all this hair in there because
they're eating these animals.
And so it gets more and more spiraled as
it comes out and we can tell them apart
from like bobcat,
because bobcats kind of get this,
they're more almost,
I don't want to call it a pellet,
but they're smaller segmented and
they're kind of just one side's concave,
one side's convicts of each pellet and
so you can tell them apart,
that's actually can be more difficult
for some people than the dog.
And the coyote.
I found some mountain lions,
shit wants to Santa Monica,
not in Santa Monica,
excuse me,
Santa Barbara.
And it was very disturbing because it
was a rope,
like a fat rope of hairy shit.
And I was like,
what is this from?
And I sent it to a friend of mine who is
a,
he's very knowledgeable about animals.
He's like,
it's almost definitely a mountain lion.
It's like,
Whoa,
somebody's got got here.
No,
it was,
it was pretty thick rope,
like a human sys log with,
with,
uh,
all this hair in it.
We actually have alliance study going in
our mountains too.
We've been calling them outlines for a
long time.
Sure.
You've probably heard of [inaudible] in
Griffith Park.
I have.
That's actually an animal that one of my
colleagues collared.
Oh yeah,
that's the famous photo of the Hollywood
hills.
Exactly.
That is an amazing photo of that
enormous cat.
Would that collar on?
Yeah,
that was Steve Winters with National
Geographic.
Got that photo.
I mean,
it's pretty impressive.
He worked hard between him and my
colleague Jeff.
They did a lot of work to get that
photo.
And Jamie says,
go and pull that photo up when you take
a look at it.
Now that is,
that is an iconic photograph,
man.
You know what?
I think we should have that photo in the
new studio.
We should get a print of that.
Can we buy a print of that?
You know,
we're in Silica bioprinted that um,
I believe you can get it from Steve
Winters.
Let's see.
Jamie,
make a note of whoever's gentlemen is
and if he sells that because dad is
like,
that seems so crazy.
It doesn't even look like a real photo
because the Hollywood sign is so perfect
in the background and the cat is fucking
huge.
You know what's amazing about the
Hollywood sign?
There's no lights on the Hollywood sign.
He got that photo because he was able to
do enough camera work that he made the
Hollywood sign Claire Out.
That's just from lights from the city.
Really.
If you look at the Hollywood sign at
night,
it's not lit up like that.
Wow.
Look at the forearm on them thing.
Yeah,
I mean that's like a thigh.
Yeah.
So it's a huge cat.
Yup.
How big do you think that is?
A big male.
I think the last time.
So we've captured him three or four
times now and I think the last time he
was about 101 20.
One 30,
I believe.
I'm not positive of that,
but it's somewhere in that area.
Oh yeah.
He's a good size cat.
I mean,
what's amazing?
He's running in Griffith Park.
He'd never leaves the Griffith Park
General area because he's blocked by
freeways and yet there hasn't been any
conflicts with him and people besides
the time he got underneath that guy's
house living of him.
But Jesus Christ.
That's so weird.
So joggers,
no one gets interrupted by him.
Interrupt is a funny word.
Jack is a better word.
He doesn't.
It doesn't mess with people at all.
No.
We get sightings everywhere where people
report it.
But yeah,
we haven't had anything,
any conflicts with them,
which has been amazing.
I mean he's four.
He's got the smallest home range of any
mountain lion,
male mountain lion that we've know of.
Like.
So what is like a square mile?
Is he just the park?
He's just the park.
I mean he goes,
he's been up by like universal studios
right in there once or twice.
Like in some green strip through there,
but for the most part,
yeah,
he's just hanging out in the park and
dwp property next to the park.
How big is the park?
I wish I could call that number off the
top of my head.
Just roughly.
If you had to guess who?
Yeah,
I'm not good with that.
like 4,300 acres or something like that.
Okay.
See the biggest in America or maybe the
world?
Urban Park.
It's a pretty big park.
It is.
But when you compare that to mountain
lions,
that our main mountains,
we usually think to mountain lions can
live in the Santa Monica mountains,
which is about 150,000 acres.
So his range is pretty small,
4,300 compared to about 75,000 acres.
That's incredible.
And he's mostly eating deer heat,
some coyotes and raccoons.
But it's almost most of the,
most of all of our mountain lions,
all their diets,
dear.
Well,
that's one of the reasons why there's so
few deer in California.
I hear that when we don't,
we don't know if that's truly what's
going a mountain lions,
they do kind of self regulate.
So the big males usually killed the
smaller mills and so they do kind of
control their own populations of some
level.
Oh,
that's interesting.
So the competition,
they kill competent.
Did Not.
They're not cannibals though.
Uh,
I don't believe they eat them.
They usually just kill them.
That's interesting.
So do they kill them to bring the
females to Asteris or they'd do them
just because their competition?
We believe it's just because it's
competition because they're usually
killing those yearling.
Okay.
Males killing them once they were
independent.
Exactly.
So,
um,
and they also,
we have had them kill a female lion as
well.
So really it's not that simple.
Hmm.
Yeah.
That's interesting.
And is this in the park?
You found this?
Yeah.
Wow.
So you find a dead mountain line in the
park.
I mean they have radio collars on them,
so we kind of know what's going on now.
Is there any concern,
like does anybody make the argument that
they shouldn't be there?
Does anybody ever say,
hey,
you know,
this is where I live.
I don't want this cat here.
Why do you guys let this thing is a
giant Predator wandering around our
neighborhood?
Yeah,
I mean we definitely hear that but we
also get the other side as well,
a lot where they want to protect every
lion.
I mean,
same thing with coyotes.
People don't want the coyotes.
They're coyotes.
Even more tricky because we've tried to
kill coyotes for a long time to try to
get them out of areas and we have not
been successful.
I mean,
places like Chicago with coyotes,
I mean they'll go through and do
removals,
like a lot of the landowners will do
removals and the coyotes has come back
pretty quickly.
Interesting.
Though.
It's really not that effective.
Let me start trying to remove these
animals.
Yeah.
Especially coyotes.
Right?
They're so crafty.
Um,
I've read a really disturbing article
about mountain lions where they were
talking about the number of mountain
lions that are killed every year by.
I'm a professional mountain lion hunters
that the government hires because
they're preying on cats and dogs and
that they said that 50 percent of these
animals,
this was around the San Francisco area,
that 50 percent of their diet was
domestic animals.
Like domestic cats and dogs.
Yeah.
I'm not familiar with that one,
but we definitely haven't seen that with
ours.
So this one is just got a good supply of
deer and that's just what it's eating on
a regular basis.
That's what it seems like.
I mean,
even Griffith Park,
that's what they're focused on.
I mean,
like I said,
they also killed the coyotes and
raccoons and stuff as well.
But sure,
that the other thing that was really
disturbing about that article,
because it was the,
the author was trying to make a
connection between missing children,
you know,
they were talking about,
uh,
several cases over the years where
children were missing and never found
again.
And these are the same areas where these
mountain lions roaming and they were
wondering whether or not that had been
the case.
That makes you go,
whoa.
Yeah,
I mean,
I think it's probably more likely human
caused then wildlife caused.
I mean,
maybe we're,
we're way creepier than these animals
are.
That's true.
But do you remember about two years ago,
uh,
there was a case in Cupertino right near
the apple campus where a mountain lion
attack to kid.
And,
uh,
the father had a fight the mountain lion
off.
I mean,
these stories definitely pop up every
once in a while.
But we also have lots of places where
there's lions and there's no issues,
right?
Our mountains,
we haven't had a light,
a human lion issue.
I mean,
we've had livestock taken,
but that's about it.
And we're talking our park.
That gets huge amount of visitors.
Griffin lion will griffith,
but also the whole Santa Monica
mountains,
so we're part of the Santa Monica
Mountains National Recreation area and
we've got at any given time we could
have 12 to 15 lions in there.
Wow.
Really?
And we've never had a human lion issue
besides the livestock.
What is the big issue when they do
attack people?
Because it's always like someone either
running or on a bike,
is it they think that the person is
trying to get away?
Is it like a cat thing,
like a regular kid,
you know,
like if you roll a ball of yarn in front
of a cat that just jumped on it.
Yeah.
I don't think we really have a full
understanding,
but it probably has something to do with
the prey drive because I've read a few,
a mountain lion attacks on people that
had to do with mountain bikes and I was.
I was thinking like why would they want
to attack someone on a bike?
It seems like a bike would be scary.
Yeah.
I mean,
they're an ambush Predator and they're
big animals so they're not used to
having anything bigger than them take
them on so they're not.
They're not fearful of most things.
I mean a lot of times when people see
the lions,
they don't run and so people freak out,
but that's actually not that uncommon
for them just to kind of sit there and
look at you and judge the situation,
try to figure out what they can do with
you.
They should eat you hope that's not what
they're thinking,
but most likely not.
Most likely not like what are the
numbers of attacks on people?
Do you know if you had a.
you'd have to talk to my colleague.
I'm definitely not the lion guy in our
office.
Some much more focused on.
Do you remember the last time you heard
of a lion attack on people?
I'm now and I've taught my head.
I mean it might've been at apple thing
or there was.
There was attack in Orange County quite
a while back,
but that's really it.
It's not that common.
There's a magic number of lions that are
here.
This is a mountain lion in San Juan
Capistrano that's been attacking this
farm.
A buddy of mine,
Ian Mccall,
who's a UFC fighter,
has a friend who owns this farm and this
mountain lion has been hitting this farm
every now and again and the other day it
killed 37 ducks in a goat,
just goes on a rampage and doesn't even
eat them.
Just fucks them up and leaves and so
what we usually see with them is,
I mean because they almost always eat
what they kill.
It's just when they kill something in a
farm,
they usually end up being uncomfortable
afterwards because we come in,
we see the situation,
things change and so they don't come
back because they'll feed on a deer for
a week or more.
So it's,
it's.
I think it's more of a factor when they
leave those things.
It's more that they just all of a sudden
like,
oh crap,
what I do,
I gotta get Outta here.
Why they killed 37.
Then it just prey drive.
I mean they can't help themselves.
They get in.
There's times when they get in pins with
bigger animals to things like llamas and
stuff where they'll end up killing
multiple animals just because they get
into this pan and all.
Suddenly they're jumping around making
all these noises and so then the animals
get excited.
I made it just like dog dogs are getting
after chickens.
All the sudden the dog goes in and kills
the whole flock of chickens.
Right.
Same type of deal.
They just can't help themselves.
Yeah.
There's that one that's in the Santa
Monica Mountains.
What is it?
P 52.
Is that the name of it?
P 45,
45.
I'm guessing if that's what you're
talking about.
The one that killed a bunch of llamas
and the woman got a depredation permit
to kill the mountain lion.
Then people freaked out and started
sending her death threats.
Yeah,
got a little out of control.
It's like it was really creepy listening
to this woman's position because she
didn't know what to do because she's,
you know,
she lives there.
She's got this farm and this big old cat
is,
keeps coming in and fucking up like 10
llamas in a,
in a setting.
Yeah.
So us and National Wildlife Federation
actually started working with her to try
to help pin or animals that better
because a lot of it just comes to making
sure your animals a secure at night.
Is that what it is?
Like you have to figure out a way to
close the areas of the mountain lion
can't get into exactly what did she
take?
Anything that complicated.
We actually held a workshop for people
in the local vicinity and we'll be
holding more to teach livestock owners
how to secure their animals so that
stuff doesn't happen.
Is there a way they can,
um,
do something that like a emits a sound
or something that scares them off.
So there are some devices out there that
are being tested and being used in some
vicinities,
but nothing's 100 percent.
The problem with a lot of devices,
you've got livestock moving around so
they're going to be triggering the
devices all night.
So it,
it's,
it's kind of a tough situation.
The best thing is to try to pin the
animals up so you have to put something
with a roof on it.
So the mountain lion can't get in it
over the top.
Exactly.
So when you're talking about an animal
like that,
like when they,
sometimes they capture them and then
they move them to a new area.
Right?
Um,
that is very rare to happen.
Is it really?
Yeah,
like when we kept our animals,
we don't move anybody just let them go
right back to where they are and we call
our own.
We take blood,
we do what we need to do to them and
then we just let them go right there.
So it was the idea like mess with them
as little as possible.
Exactly.
Yeah.
We didn't have to capture them,
we wouldn't capture them.
We would just throw it.
There was a way to get a color on the
animal without touching it.
We would do that like maybe a dark that
shoots a gps unit in him or something.
Yeah,
whatever the technology is,
if it ever comes up that way,
most wildlife people would prefer
because the least we have to do it on.
The more we're going to understand their
behaviors.
Yeah.
I would imagine this cat and Griffith
Park.
You said it's been captured three times.
Yeah,
that's kind of crazy.
This can be for.
I can't remember.
I'm not.
Like I said,
I'm not the guy that does all the lion
work,
so I just help out.
The cat must be like Jesus Christ.
So they got me again,
like it's probably like I'm so tired of
wearing the stupid jewelry they keep
putting on me.
Yeah.
Why?
Don't know.
You might've saw the pictures to where
he got.
He was really sick with mange.
Oh yeah,
that's right.
Yeah.
And so they got a medication and so we
caught him and we have a topical
medication that we can give animals.
We do it,
the bobcats and stuff.
So what we found with this mange disease
is that it's caused by a rodenticides.
So all these rat poisons we put out
there basically ends up getting into the
mountain lions and bobcats.
And the coyotes,
there seems to be some sort of
correlation between those poisons and
why these animals get sick.
Oh,
is that him right there with mange?
Yep.
That's.
Yeah,
that's fascinating.
That is a real issue with people
poisoning,
um,
these animals so that it also affects
owls.
Apparently that rat poison is causing a
drop in the owl population because our
are getting ahold of these rats are sick
from the,
the.
Oh,
that's interesting.
it's amazing.
I mean,
to think of a mountain lion getting rat
poison.
It's not like they're out there hunting
rats,
but it's because they're killing the
coyotes,
the thinner that are eating the rats
that are sick.
Oh yeah.
It's happening.
So we're a mountain lion would need a
rat.
I mean they might,
but for them to eat enough rats,
they're not just sitting there focusing
around.
So it's really a great source for that.
So they're,
they're definitely focusing more on the
coyotes and the bigger prey.
I can't believe there's that many
mountain lions in the Santa Monica
Mountains.
That's crazy.
Yeah.
And these are colored mountain lions,
correct?
Not all of them.
There's definitely some out there that
are uncolored we can only get what we
can capture.
So.
And so like when you make an estimate of
like,
what'd you say?
15.
Is that what you said?
That we think that's our upper size
limit.
How many of them are collared?
Um,
I think right now we're at around eight
or nine.
Yeah.
I wish,
I wish jeff was in here.
He can answer these questions a lot
better than me because like I said,
I'll get jeff in here next time.
Yeah.
So it's,
it's so fascinating because California
is such a unique area in that we are
very urban,
you know,
but we're real spread out and we've got
the Santa Monica mountains right there,
like in Topanga right there.
I mean to pay.
I have a buddy lives in Topanga.
You go in his backyard,
you would swear to God you were in
Colorado or something.
I mean,
it just,
it,
it seems like the wilderness,
you know,
the mountains are amazing.
I mean it's 155,000 acres.
Oh,
Jamie's got a map he pulled up of all
the mountain lions.
Wow.
We'll get them all.
Jesus,
so obviously the Santa Monica mountains
are just.
They're south of the one.
Oh one basically.
So the park is basically from the
Hollywood hills out the point Magoo and
then incorporates most of Malibu and
then it goes a little bit up into the
hills,
but the mountains themselves are mostly
south of [inaudible].
This is such a unique place to live that
were so sort of surrounded by nature and
a lot of ways and there's so many
different places like you could go to
big bear and an hour and a half and
you're in the woods.
I mean you are literally in the
wilderness.
That's a great thing about La.
Yeah.
I like living here and it's pretty cool.
It's pretty cool.
But people are super uncomfortable with
the fact that this wildlife sort of
interfaces with our urban environment
and that's where guys like you come in,
right?
Yeah.
I mean we're.
We're hoping to help reduce some of
these conflicts and a lot of it comes to
what we do.
It's not so much with animals.
I mean with coyotes,
a huge amount of the issues are because
somebody next door to use feeding them
and so the coyotes hanging around.
It's really common like the people leave
out food.
Yeah.
Sometimes it's intentional.
Sometimes it's not like feeding your dog
outside.
It's never a good idea.
Having fruit trees in your backyard that
are just dropping fruit constantly and
no one's picking it up or cleaning it
up.
That's attract and so it's all bringing
in coyotes,
raccoons,
possums,
skunks,
all these animals are coming in and take
advantage of that stuff.
So do you think they eat olives?
Have we seen all lives?
Probably would take advantage of him
here and there,
but I don't think it's like a super big
food source forum.
I haven't seen any spots.
So we've been doing this diet study for
a little while now.
And Olives or not one that pops up
regularly because my dogs eat them.
That's why I'm asking.
My Dog's catch them when they fall out
of trees and it's the same yard.
Obviously we're the coyotes had been
visiting.
Yeah,
I mean I wouldn't rule it out,
but definitely if you have anything like
figs,
we find tons of figs and the scat.
Yeah,
so they really liked figs.
They do and figs fruit twice a year.
A lot of the varieties of figs and so
they're there a lot so the coyotes just
kind of learned to key in on him.
Oh,
okay.
And probably a lot of calories.
There are two former.
Exactly.
What are those little tiny red berries
that they like to eat?
A pirate Kantha maybe.
Is that what it is?
I think so.
That's not even edible.
The humans,
right?
Not.
I don't think so,
but Kyle is Canadian.
Yeah.
I mean whether it's edible to us or
whether we would want to eat a different
question,
I guess.
Yeah,
there's a lot grind in.
Exactly.
They're eating a lot of things that we
would not touch.
Yeah,
no kidding.
I mean they,
they go pick stuff up off the road and
nasty little it looks like just putting
on the road.
I've seen them grab stuff.
Yeah,
I seen coyotes.
They're just,
they're crazy.
I mean,
there's a lot of these talk about
Katie's going after cats and all that
and there's no question that eat cats.
I've seen them.
One of our collared animals was actually
eating a cat in to have his pack mates
were sitting there just eating this cat
in somebody's front yard,
which I'd never seen.
I knew they.
Adam.
Have you seen that video of the coyote
eaten the cat that someone captured in
Los Angeles?
Uh,
I don't think so.
It's a great video because this,
these people from their car or film in
this coyote that's right there on the
street in busy la and it just staring at
people chewing on this cat that.
Yeah,
that's like Jesus Christ.
We played it for Dan Flores and Dan has
the opinion,
he's of the opinion that a lot of these
cats that are getting killed by these
coyotes,
like here's some coyotes just wandering
across the street.
I mean,
this is really crazy because this is as
urban as it gets.
I mean,
busy street and this kyle is just
hanging out and so these people followed
this coyote all around the street.
Does it look like that as a collar?
What did I say?
No,
no color,
but it,
Dan thinks that the coyotes are eating
the cats because they're competitive
predators.
Um,
so that has definitely been seen with
things like fog of areas.
So just chilling,
eating the cat right in front of
everybody.
I mean,
that's crazy that they actually see it.
I'm guessing they didn't see it actually
catch the.
No,
because the cat is stiff.
Stiff.
That cat is that cat.
It looks like it's been dead for quite a
while,
but he's just chewing on that cat in
front of everybody that coyote actually
you see how it's face looks kind of bald
headed may actually have.
And you think that could be from rat
poison?
Uh,
with the coyotes.
It's a little more complicated than
that.
Um,
we think it's a different type of Maine
they get.
So we don't think that's directly tied
rat poisons.
It could be still,
but where does,
it's kind of uncertain with those guys.
And some of it is because of bugs as
well.
Right?
So Maine is actually caused by a mite.
Yeah.
And it just irritates their skin and
they end up scratching their own for
off.
Oh,
that's it.
Yeah.
Really?
I thought it just felt like it.
That one cat.
So like,
oh,
that's my friend a dude.
That cat is so crazy.
He's just sitting there watching this
coyote.
Yeah.
So what a dumb cat.
Well,
I saw a cat in the middle of a street.
A coyote was walking down the street.
I thought it was a bag of garbage.
I was about 100 yards away and I was
sitting here watching this video,
go to it.
I was like,
oh,
was going to get into this garbage?
Next thing I know there's coyotes
circles at three times.
Walks off also.
Anything jumps up and walks away.
I was like,
whoa.
Did I just see that?
Wow,
I cannot believe it because even like,
I know it's complicated,
but I was like,
that was a pretty easy prey.
They could have just grabbed it.
So coyote is much faster than cast.
Is that what it is?
Well,
and that's an area.
Didn't have to be faster.
The cat was just laying there like it
could have grabbed it at any point and I
wonder why the cat felt calm enough to
do that.
Yeah.
I don't know.
And why they didn't go after it.
I have no idea.
I think it's just,
it's just not that simple that they go
after every single cat.
Yeah.
Well they obviously don't.
Right?
Yeah.
Now you.
So you say that it is fairly common that
people feed them.
It is.
I've just,
with tracking these animals,
I've been to a bunch of places where
people feel like they need to put dog
food or cat food out on the street just
for the coyotes are the skunks or
raccoons or whatever.
They're feeding something intentionally
out there and then the coyotes are
taking advantage.
And do you talk to these people?
Do you have to have.
So I will occasionally.
Usually I just tell animal services
about it and they'll talk to them or if
it's somebody I'm like already having
some sort of communication with,
I'll definitely be like,
eh,
you don't really need to feed these
guys.
They're doing fine on their own.
Yeah.
All you're doing is encouraging them to
come here.
Do they get that?
Do deal with some nutty animal people
that don't get that?
Yeah,
we definitely deal with some people that
don't understand.
They feel like these animals are going
to starve to death or die of dehydration
if they don't put that bowl of water out
there.
So crazy.
So yeah.
Dan Flores had a woman who came to him
and was doing a documentary on saving
the coyote and he was like,
I don't think you understand,
like they're doing great.
They've expanded their range incredibly.
Like they're living in every big city
around.
I mean from New York,
Chicago,
Toronto,
and that's all saying.
Yeah,
it's crazy.
They're everywhere.
Yeah.
They literally are in every state in
every city in the entire country except
for Hawaii.
Except why puts what that is so bizarre
that the think that are in Queens during
they've,
they've found them in the bronx was
amazing.
They've expanded their range over a
fairly short time span to.
I mean,
it's really just since Europeans had
been here that they've been able to kind
of expand out and do that and that's
through all this time.
It was trying to kill him and all that
and so I get a lot of people that want
to remove coyotes from urban
environments.
I'm like,
well,
we've been trying to do that for a long
time and it's not working.
What is the solution then?
The solution is just to sort of mitigate
their impact on us.
I think we need to change what we do.
Yeah,
I mean it's about not making sure we
don't have food out there.
I mean if the more food they have,
it's been shown.
Coyotes can increase their litter sizes
and so they produce more coyotes and so
it's really about trying to reduce the
amount of food that we are responsible
for.
That's also what I read in Dan Flores is
book that the more we impact the coyotes
as far as like people trying to push
them out and pressure them,
the more they produce extra babies like
it.
Especially if they do that roll call
thing when they scream out in the night
and you hear him,
which is amazing.
That is one of my favorite things about
coyotes,
man,
when I'm out at night and like,
you know,
like you're sitting on the deck,
like having a cup of coffee or something
here.
You like,
wow,
this is wild.
Like they are really out here like
grinding.
It makes you feel you're actually out in
the wild a little bit.
Yeah,
a little bit.
Even though like you're sitting on your
deck sound into music.
Exactly.
Tie it to going off.
Yeah.
Drinking a nice cup of coffee or
something.
It's just um,
it's just,
it's such a unique relationship that we
have with that one Predator where it's
like,
I liked them around,
like I would be really weird if that was
a,
you know,
any other kind of like scary Predator,
but coyotes are kind of cool to have
around.
Yeah.
I mean definitely.
I think the same way a lot of people may
not feel quite the same when they're
getting in their backyard,
but I know.
Yeah,
I get that.
Yeah.
I do too,
I mean I'm,
I'm a dog lover,
I've got chickens,
I've got all these things that coyotes
could effect me as well,
but I also realize that there's things I
can do to make sure that they're not
going to get to my chickens are,
they're knocking on my dogs.
Well,
I have a puppy right now and that's my,
my big fear is because I have a golden
retriever puppy and he is like golden
retrievers under if you ever had one.
The early,
the most non dog dogs,
like they don't bark at anybody.
They're terrible watchdogs.
They love everybody and they just have
zero killer instinct,
like zero.
They're just sweethearts and I'm just
worried that he's going to get jacked.
Yeah,
I mean I would definitely keep them
secure until it gets up to that 40,
50 pound range right there.
They're generally pretty safe.
Yeah.
So now they do sometimes ambush them
though,
right?
It happens.
It's rare.
Usually most of the attacks are smaller
dogs.
However,
there are definitely cases where they've
gone even after something as big as your
master,
if that's crazy.
I mean,
it's pretty rare that happens.
Um,
the whole coyote dog things complicated.
I bet you if you googled dogs and
coyotes playing on Youtube,
you would find a dozen videos very
quickly because we've actually looked at
some of that and it's just like that,
that relationship's not as simple as
just like they're going to go after the
dogs know they play around together,
but then they'll kill them and eat them.
Just like,
what kind of relationship do we have,
man?
Yeah.
Well we don't know how often they
actually eat them.
We think sometimes they just kill them
and carry them off because that same
thing they do with foxes.
Really?
Yeah.
So like gray and red foxes,
the coyotes will kill them,
but they generally don't eat them.
Which really when you started thinking
ecologically it makes sense,
right?
Like they're so related that there's
lots of diseases they could be
transmitted between them.
So it's kind of a risk.
Any time you eat something that's very
closely related to you.
Oh,
that's fascinating.
So essentially the same thing as like a
mad cow disease.
Exactly.
Which has comes from the prions,
which is we feed cows,
cow material and then they get that.
What is it called?
Jacob's Krogh.
Spelled disease.
That's right.
Yeah.
Which is the same disease that they find
in cannibals in.
Um,
what is it,
what country is it that they find that
in Indonesia?
I forget where it is,
but it's interesting and it's
essentially the same thing.
Same.
Yeah.
I mean anytime you start and that's just
one disease.
I mean there's lots of parasites and
stuff too that if you were,
they transferred between similarly
related species much easier than it does
to say between a cat and a dog.
Wow.
So I mean there's a lot of spillover and
zoonotic diseases between wildlife and
domestic animals.
Luckily we have lots of vaccinations for
things that I'm sure you've heard of,
like Parvo and distemper,
and so there's,
there's vaccinations we can give our
animals to take care of that.
Obviously these wild animals just have
to deal with it.
You had distemper is very common,
right?
I had a dog down.
Yeah.
But in Parvos it's also deadly to
puppies.
Right?
They get that exactly.
A Parvo is very common in this area.
We actually not just right down the
street here,
we lost some pups to Parvo.
And is this something that's transmitted
through wildlife as well?
It can be a so we're not exactly sure if
it's only wildlife to domestic,
it's probably both.
It's probably being moved between the
different populations.
So I mean luckily if we vaccinate well
we can reduce that spread but people
have to be good about vaccinating their
animals.
So do you guys have a mandate like when
it comes to studying a coyotes and when
it comes to dealing with them,
like what is the overall emphasis on,
is it on just understanding their range
where they are or is it,
do you try to do something with them?
So our role is to try to help protect
wildlife within national park areas.
And so what we try to do is we try to
get as most understanding we can so we
can help reduce conflicts,
help reduce disease transmissions,
help,
just basically help the whole ecology of
these animals to make sure there's not
things coming into our populations that
are,
are going to end up affecting them.
It's interesting because,
you know,
think like when people start cutting
budgets and they start looking for like
a,
well,
where can we reduce spending?
Like there might be a few people that
come along and go,
hey,
why don't we give a shit about these
coyotes,
you know,
does that,
does that come up?
I mean,
that always comes up anytime budgets or
dealt with.
But for us,
for an important thing for us is just to
make sure that we do everything we can
to protect our resources within our
park.
And so we,
we have identified that this is a
potential risk for our local wildlife.
And so that's why we've started studying
the things like the mountain lions,
the bobcat's.
So our park is completely surrounded by
urbanization.
Um,
we have lots of influences.
I mean our mountains are about 50
percent of it is privately owned and so
there's a lot of chances for
development,
so it's important for us to understand
how development is affecting the
wildlife so we can help try to mitigate
that in the future.
That's awesome.
Now when you are dealing with these
animals and you're collecting data and
information,
do you guys share it with people that
maybe a other peers that you have that
work in much larger areas and do you
find like similar patterns and similar
similar results?
So we generally share it through
scientific publications is usually how
stuff is shared between us.
Um,
that being said,
we definitely talked to other parks like
it.
I just recently went there to help them
do some raccoons stuff.
Um,
and so we will definitely share
information to try to help deal with
similar issues.
And so I was up there for about three or
four days and we talked about lots of
things,
but one things they've had with coyotes
is people feeding them out of the car.
So like people will drive through,
they'll take food because the coyotes
hanging off nearby and they'll throw it
out the car to the coyote.
The coyote got so habituated to that it
would just be coming up to every car and
start jumping up on cars low.
And so they're like,
this is.
They ended up having to remove the
animal because all these people just
ended up feeding it.
They would go up and scare the thing and
they would,
I think they even tried,
I think they said they tried to paint
ball at,
um,
but it ended up learning who they were.
Like they learned their cars that
learned who they were.
So every time they would come up the
kite,
it would disappear back into the bushes,
even if they tried it in their own cars,
but it would still do it to their own
cars.
The coyote recognize them now.
Over time it ended up learning to
recognize the people.
They're too smart.
They are.
Wow.
That's so interesting now.
And I definitely noticed that even with
trapping and stuff and we're trying to
capture these animals,
I feel like there's times when they
definitely kind of avoid the area
because some of these animals had been
on the air for years and so we,
we try to capture them as many times as
we can to keep them on there.
So our callers only generally last
somewhere between a year and three years
depending on what kind of color we put
on them.
And so a lot of times we want to keep
them on long term so we actually
understand the whole life cycle,
what's going on.
Um,
and so we'll go in and try to capture
them again,
but they're there.
They're smart,
they kind of learned to avoid once I
start going into an area,
well coordinated.
Dan is a big part of their cleverness.
And also their adaptability comes from
them being preyed upon by gray wolves
and their relationship with gray wolves
and gray wolves had left and then come
back to North America.
And in the meantime,
coyotes kind of thrived.
And when they came back,
there was a period of thousands of years
of them being preyed upon by these gray
wolves.
So they've adapted all these different
sorts of mechanisms in order to stay
alive and to avoid predation.
And one of them being that they expand
their range.
So as we've tried to kill them,
one of the things that Dan was saying is
that when they do that roll thing,
if someone's missing the female will
actually have larger litters and then
they'll expand the range.
So when you shoot one you think like,
Whoa,
we're keeping the coyote population
down.
No,
you'd probably raised it up by like 10,
15 percent and expanded the range by a
few miles.
Yeah.
I don't know if it's just based off the
calling.
I've heard that before and there's some
dispute about whether that's the full
case or not,
but definitely because there's lower
numbers,
there's definitely more food resources
available and so it makes sense that
they would read then reproduce more
because we definitely know if food
resources go up,
coyotes can increase their numbers.
So.
Oh,
that's interesting because he was saying
that it's a direct result of them being
preyed upon you.
Do you think that's probably in dispute?
Well,
the preyed upon hot or killed or you
know,
removed,
I mean truthfully doesn't matter how the
animals,
how the population decreases and the
fact is that it's down.
So then pray numbers go up and so then
there's more prey and so then they
reproduce more because Dan was implying
there's a direct correlation between,
there's a physiological event that
happens inside the female that when the
population grows smaller,
their litters grow larger in response to
the population being smaller,
not necessarily in response to the
increase of food supply.
Um,
as far as I know,
the only things I've read,
it's usually Dave associated somehow
with food supply.
So it was probably,
maybe a combination of those factors are
very well could be.
I mean,
it's complicated,
right?
These are crazy with what they can do.
It is absolutely fascinating how
adaptable they are though.
Is there anything like them?
Um,
I mean when you start thinking of things
like crows,
they can be pretty adaptable to.
They can live in a wide variety of areas
that through three d space they moved to
the air.
That's a different sort of bargain.
Yeah,
no,
I mean the coyotes,
they definitely,
there's not any of has pieces the move
around the country,
like they have a very able to live in
the most urban environments we can
imagine.
I mean places that people generally
think of maybe raccoon and be able to
live.
I know in Chicago they've gone into
areas where they have coyotes living and
they did not have raccoons living in
those same locations or if there were,
they were recommends were very rare and
you,
the coyote seen to be able to persist,
which is amazing for an animal that
size.
Um,
it just shows how intelligent they are
to be able to move around us and be able
to take advantage of us.
Is it because they've,
they've run faster,
they're just,
it's probably a combination of things.
They learn how to deal with roads.
I mean,
anytime you get these urban
environments,
like one thing I always like to say,
so like the West Lake neighborhood,
it's one of the most dangerous
neighborhoods for pedestrians.
Yet this coyotes running this
neighborhood all the time and it didn't
have any signs of ever been struck by a
car.
Do you think the smartest coyote is
smarter than the dumbest person?
Yeah.
Whoa,
that's deep.
Deep.
Yeah.
I mean they live in places that I don't
know if I could live there.
Wow.
So now what city has,
is there any city in the country that
actually has a legitimate problem with
coyote?
Depends who you talk to.
I mean,
La,
we definitely have our issues.
I mean been bites.
There's been other situations been
bitten.
Yeah.
Elysian park had some bites.
There's bites down in Orange County or
mine had some bites.
Are they biting homeless people?
Are they biting people?
Take naps.
What are the.
It's all over the board usually it seems
to be tied to people been feeding it and
so it's almost coming up and biting like
people on the hands or people on the
leg.
Um,
I don't think any of them know.
The ones I've heard had been like,
where they're trying to take the person
down real type thing.
They've all been more like where they're
coming up and none of them,
none of them have.
Yes.
Do you heard about the woman who was a
folk singer in Canada that got killed a
couple of years back by coyotes?
Yeah.
I actually went up there a couple of
years after that.
They actually got a study going on,
coyotes up there.
They radio collared a bunch and I went
up there and helped him capture the
first couple of animals to kind of see
what's going on.
And that's just a crazy scenario up
there.
It's way different than what we see down
here.
The coyotes first or there,
eastern coyotes,
so they're a little bit bigger,
but they're also,
they kind of,
there's very few food sources up there.
They're dealing with snowshoe hares,
which their cycles kind of fluctuate up
and down.
And so sometimes there could be tons of
food and other times there can be almost
none,
but they've learned that they can take
advantage of Moose during the winter and
they're actually killing Moose in the
snow,
which you think of this little 40 inch
pound animal.
Take it on this huge Moose.
But they're seeing it.
They do these snow surveys and they're
finding these dead moose that were very
clearly killed by coyotes.
Wow.
So a full grown moose.
Yeah.
That's insane.
A full grown moose is like more than a
thousand pounds.
Yeah.
No,
it's,
it's amazing.
I mean,
obviously these moose in the winter,
the snow gets deep right there.
They're definitely.
They can get stuck in things.
And that type of scenario.
How do they know that it's coyotes have
killed him in a wolves.
There's no wolves there.
Wow.
That's crazy.
Yeah.
I did not know that a coyote could kill
a fucking moose will.
And they had them radio collared.
So they were able to see the coyotes at
the carcasses and stuff too.
Wow.
So when they have the radio collar,
how much information are they getting?
Do they get like a full,
like if you could see a map,
would you see like the trail,
like everywhere they go?
Um,
it depends.
So the colors have different settings,
so their gps units,
so there's always a trade off between
battery life and the number of locations
you can get.
So you could,
if you only cared about a two week span,
you could have that GPS unit take a
location every 30 seconds and you can
map it out.
But generally we're interested in a
broader timeframe.
So a lot of times we're getting.
So like the Lions,
a lot of times it's about eight
locations a day and that's a pretty good
size color on the coyotes.
I usually do somewhere around six and
then I'll do these little bouts where
I'll do 20 minute locations a day and so
then I'll get more intensity to,
and then I can map out like where they
come up to roads or where they do
different things where they're feeding.
Um,
so yeah,
you can get some pretty detailed data on
how they're moving.
So what kind of a battery source are you
using on these colors that you can get
such a long,
like how long does it like if you
stretch it out the longest,
how long can they last?
So there's different sides of the
collars and so like the lion callers
are,
they can be two d cell batteries in them
which are just Lithium d cell batteries.
Um,
and those go about two years with a two
D cell battery.
Wow.
Um,
you can put them on tiny little things.
I mean people have done not what gp s
yet,
I don't believe,
but they've even done like little bugs
where they've put the.
So the colors have to different things.
They have a gps and they have a vhf
function.
The vhf allows us to actually go out and
track the animals.
So when you see the biologists out there
with those antanas,
so you literally know where they are.
They are.
Yeah.
So that's how like all of these
observations I've talked about,
that's how I see them.
It's because they have that little
beacon that goes off in a color and so I
can track them with that antenna and see
where they are and get pretty close to
them and see them,
what they're doing.
That's incredible.
So the,
the,
they literally the last two years with
two D cell batteries.
Yep.
And then when the two years are up that
you don't know where he is exactly the
well,
what's amazing about the lions is that
we can recapture them.
We have really good success rate getting
those guys back.
And so jeff's been amazing.
I mean he's been able to get these
animals time after time after time.
And that's why like a p 22 has been
captured so many times because we have
to replace the collar.
So it's usually about every two years we
had to replace the collar.
So it.
So how are they tracking that cat?
Um,
I mean there,
we've done multiple things.
We've gotten lucky one time and he was
actually down in a hole and me and jeff
were actually there and we darted the
thing and it just fell asleep in the
hole,
which was pretty sweet.
So you saw in a whole like a hole in the
ground.
It was kind of a,
a drainage channel was kind of eroded
away and he was kind of down in this and
there's a bunch of brush covering it and
so he felt pretty comfortable I guess
and he just stayed there and so we were
hiking into don't know if we were
looking for a kill or if we were just
checking on him.
I can't remember what we were doing but
whatever.
We saw him and so we're like,
well let's try to Darden.
And so I stood there and waited for jeff
to go get the stuff and jeff was able to
darden when he came back and the cat
just laid there like we put a dart in
him.
He growled out us.
He laid back down and fell asleep and we
were able to process them.
How crazy is that when a cat growls at
you?
Uh,
it was actually pretty freaking cool
guys.
It's pretty amazing being that close to
such a big animal.
Just how far away were you?
Probably from me to your wall.
Oh No,
really?
Oh my gosh.
It's so pretty.
Oh my God.
Do you have a backup gun or a Taser or.
We carry person America Shield.
Get them out there in the captain
America Shield.
Come on.
Gotcha.
I would think that would actually be a
good move for a cap.
Right?
Like a big Ole like gladiator shield.
I'd probably be confused.
They'd tried to Jack you run into the
shield.
Where is he?
Nice.
Yeah.
I don't think I want to carry that
through the brush though.
Good point.
No,
we,
we do carry bear spray.
Does that work?
I mean we haven't had to use it.
So retail,
you just use it once and tell me.
Because I was thinking like I run
through the hills.
I was thinking,
you know,
I do.
This is an area where I run where it's
really desolate.
There's no one out there and I know this
bobcat's there,
um,
but I also now know that there's a mount
line there because a buddy of mine saw a
mountain lion there and it had a collar
and then he heard about a mountain lion
that got killed on the five freeway and
he checked a website.
Is there a website that shows you that
track,
like,
were where the animal has been?
Um,
there are that we can see.
We don't share that with other people,
but I wonder how he found out he,
he knows a lot of people.
Maybe he asked somebody but,
but found out that it was the,
the was the mountain lion that he saw in
his neighborhood and he lives pretty
close to the five.
Okay.
And so,
uh,
he was,
explaining that,
you know,
like he saw it.
Yeah.
I mean,
we don't have any cats that are up there
near the five.
So probably he could have probably just
looked at that map that you guys put up
there.
Even it could have easily been one of
those because there's just not many up
in that area that we have collared,
but they do occasionally get hit by
cars.
Right?
Yeah.
That's actually one of our biggest
causes.
Mortality these days is them getting hit
by cars.
So we,
we work a lot with Caltrans to try to
improve permeability of the roadways for
wildlife and protect them from being hit
by cars.
I know there was a ramp that was being
proposed that they were going to put a
ramp over the highway.
Right.
Oh,
here it is.
Caltrans proposes wildlife overpass on
the freeway.
Now where were they?
Kind of try to put that.
So this is supposed to be near Liberty
Canyon.
This is,
where's Liberty Kenyon?
Um,
it's just a little bit west of here near
a Gora Oh,
okay.
Um,
yeah,
so this,
this overpass,
it will be big from outlines,
but also lots of other wildlife in our
mountains.
So we have seen that the 101 freeway is
a major barrier to gene flow.
And so things like,
even coyotes,
even though they are able to live in
this super urban environment,
not one,
oh one.
And the development along one-on-one is
serving as a barrier that they're not
getting across regularly enough to keep
the population genetics up.
So genetic diversity south of the
freeway is a lot lower than genetic
diversity north to the freeway.
Right.
Now for Bobcats,
mountain lions and coyotes.
I have a friend who works at the tone
ranch.
Do you know where that is?
Yeah.
I have a buddy that works there too.
Oh yeah.
I was actually just there this weekend
and they were explaining to me that they
had a camera trap on one of the
waterholes and they saw 16 different
mountain lions.
Wow.
They've got 16 photos of 16 different
cats that are on there.
A huge ranch,
270,000 acres.
It's enormous ranch.
Yeah.
I,
um,
I don't know how they could identify
each individual lion.
That's my first question is how to do
individual.
Um,
but yeah,
the mountain lions,
they can be quite a few of them.
I mean,
a lot of times with mountain lions will
come back obviously with,
especially with something like a water
source there.
Um,
so I would,
I would question whether it was
different or not,
but yeah,
I mean it's a place like the hone.
I mean,
it's amazing,
right?
There's lots of different prey animals.
They're from elk to deer to a special
place.
It is,
it's really crazy.
Just mean everything.
The wildlife,
the flowers,
the pigs,
like it's just a crazy,
crazy place.
It is.
So many pigs there.
It's,
it's a nutty farm,
nutty ranch and it's so large.
It's just amazing.
Like my buddy's like cowboy up there and
so he took me for a tour to kind of see
the ranch and it's,
it's amazing.
Yeah.
Well it's the biggest ranch in
California,
270,000 acres.
It's almost hard to wrap your head
around how big it is,
but when you're there and you go,
how far does it go?
And then you go see that third mountain
range.
We go to that.
You're like,
what?
Yeah,
over to the desert over.
it's everywhere.
And then the water for Los Angeles goes
through it.
If you see that gigantic water pipe that
goes through the,
uh,
your iphone ranch.
Yeah.
And you go,
what?
That's where all the water goes.
It goes through this thing.
It's just,
it's just crazy.
That's amazing.
Yeah.
Well,
it's weird that we have a place that's
an hour and a half outside of La that
has elk.
I know this like,
we're so lucky.
Like it's,
it's just such a unique spot a lot of
ways.
Yeah.
It's amazing.
I mean,
used to be tons of elk here,
right?
Like all the Tuli elk,
they used to cover the whole area at the
stories of Tulio pick out in the San
Joaquin Valley.
They're just amazing numbers of elk.
So yeah,
we'll also.
Grizzly bears and grizzlies.
Yeah,
that's,
there's a,
uh,
there's a town up near to home that's
named after the last guy that got killed
by a grizzly bear in California before
they wiped them out.
God,
I'm trying to remember.
I'm trying to remember the town's name,
dammit.
But the,
uh,
it's been confirmed that he was killed.
They actually exude his body and found
it broken up into pieces and one of his
legs was chewed off like,
wow,
like you really did get jacked by a
grizzly bear.
Apparently we had enormous coastal bears
and that's why they wiped them out.
It was just like when the settlers came
here,
they were like,
okay,
fuck this.
We've got to kill these goddamn things
because they were like,
you know,
Kodiak sized enormous bears,
but obviously they did a good job since
we don't have a single grizzly left in
California.
Yeah.
That's one animal.
Lubeck.
Thank you.
Jamie Beck.
That's,
that's one animal where people are not
clamoring for reintroduction.
Yeah.
You know,
like let's truthfully,
there's no area left for them,
like the area that grizzlies occurred.
We've developed,
turned in agriculture and urbanization.
So bringing grizzlies back.
I mean,
you hear it every once in a while
somebody say that,
but I'm like,
they're too big and they need too much
food and too much of that food is living
animals and that would be a problem.
Well,
even if that's.
I mean,
even all that,
if there is no habitat,
where did you put on?
Like they're not sure they're not going
to live up in the high mountains.
That's what we have.
Say That's what we have protected is the
Sierras and those types of things.
That's not grizzly habitat.
So when we do have quite a bit of black
bears,
right?
We do,
but they can live up in the mountain.
They do much better in that scenario.
Yeah.
It's really fascinating to me how the
whole thing is sort of like a,
a balanced system and they all sort of
keep each other in check.
You know,
California is a good example of that
because it's one of the few states that
has a large healthy mountain lion
population,
but they don't allow hunting of mountain
lions.
So because of that you have less dear
but.
And people will complain about that
hunters,
but also because of that you have less
car accidents with deer.
Yeah.
Like if you live in like A.
I have a buddy lives in Iowa.
You have to drive slow because the
fucking deer just jumping out in front
of the road every 50 to 100 yards.
I mean,
it's crazy how many,
especially during the Rut when they're
breeding and they get silly.
See just dead deer every couple miles.
He had dead deer on the side of the
road.
Yeah,
I mean we're a lot different obviously
than the midwest like you're talking
about too.
We got a lot less vegetation or a lot
more lawless rains.
We have a lot less of that good quality
vegetation for the deer.
So our deer numbers are also going to be
in check partially just because we don't
have the highest quality habitat for
deer and most of our areas is what,
what are they?
Just eating grass and stuff,
right?
Like what are they either date?
A lot of.
Browse,
a lot of brush sage,
right?
These,
a lot of sage.
They can definitely eat sage.
There's a lot of like deer brush and
just lots of variety of types of broaden
and you walk through there.
There's tons of different varieties that
they eat.
Um,
we actually have a couple of deer radio
collared right now that we're following
and they're,
they're always browsing on something
when I see them usually something
taller.
And how do you capture them?
We dart them.
So you do,
do you set,
do you trap them?
And then Darden,
like we freed artem.
Okay.
So how do you do that?
Um,
you basically just try to find where
they're at and he's basically hunting
basically hunting with a rifle.
So it's a lot like archery basically.
I mean we're ringing just to be like
really short,
right?
Yeah.
So somebody really good with the dart
rifle and probably get up to 70 meters
or so.
Oh really?
I'm not that person.
I'm about 30 meters with mine.
How many deer have you darted?
I've only started to here.
Um,
but we're hoping that we still have four
more we need to do.
So is it an air rifle?
Uh,
so there's two different types.
There's one that's basically powered off
of a 22 shell.
Then there's another one that's powered
off CEO to.
Hmm.
And so do you practice with this thing?
How do you get good at it?
Yeah,
you practiced.
I mean it's,
it's like a rifle.
You got a scope and all that so you can
kind of,
you get it all it in,
but the ballistics must be terrible.
Oh they're bad.
And it's even more complicated because
you want it to arch really lightly.
You want to hit the end of the soft as
possible because if you hit them hard,
they're going to run and the drug,
it's not like the drug takes them down
immediately.
We usually have about 10 minutes for the
animal to go down and.
Oh Jesus,
you'll never find them.
Exactly.
So it's really about like arching that
shot in there really softly hit them as
soft as possible and then lot of times
they don't go very far.
Wow.
So like what's the feet per second of
the dark?
Oh,
I don't know.
We haven't,
we don't have the chronology or you
don't have a radar thing that you shoot
it through and we don't want to borrow
mine.
Sure.
Yeah.
I want to know.
Yeah,
because I think that's interesting.
Like what?
Like [inaudible] you must have like the
the drop must be huge.
It is like how do you cite in a scope
for something for people to know what
we're talking about.
Like if you shoot a rifle,
rifle,
a bullet goes very fast so you could
shoot out into a 100 yards and it
essentially is going to go exactly where
you're aiming at.
But then when you go to 200 yards it
gets a little tricky and you have to
adjust your scope because it'll a little
bit.
You get to 300 yards,
it'll drop a little bit more.
Four hundred yards in oud is where it
gets really weird.
Like you're dealing with wind drift,
you're dealing with drop.
So I would imagine that a dart is not
going very fast so it probably drops
quite a bit.
It does and it's heavy.
They're fairly long there.
I don't know how many grains is it?
Half inches.
I don't know how many grains they are.
They don't come those measurements and
I've never weighed once.
I'm not positive,
but obviously because they are going so
slow,
they're dealing with wind drift at.
Yeah,
five meters,
then you can start doing it.
So if you're not aerodynamic either.
Right?
It's not horrible.
I mean it's basically looks like a
syringe with a needle on the end and we
have some feathers on the end.
Oh,
so you have like flushings to make sure
I wouldn't call it fletcher genes.
It's,
that's what it looks like.
Yeah,
exactly.
Like that.
Twenty ml air for 10 point.
Oh,
ml dart was at me.
So that's a,
you can put 20 milliliters of air for
the tin.
That dark.
That's holds 10 milliliters of drug.
Oh,
I see.
So that's not the exact drug we use.
We use one called a,
I believe it's a nude art.
It's a little different.
It actually has a.
So ours,
at least the ones we use for the deer,
we use these types as well.
But for the deer we use ones that have a
little charge and um,
so when it hits it discharges basically
by like a shell would gunpowder in there
that trigger triggers off Jesus Christ.
Wow.
So you have to sneak up on these deer
and then do this.
Yeah.
So what I was going to tell you what
kind of,
how we adjust for that distance,
because that's the last question you
were asking.
So the nice thing about our rifles
versus a regular rifle.
So you get one chill and that's what you
go with us because it's air powered,
we can adjust our pressure.
So to account for that distance,
we know at 20 yards we do two bars of
pressure at 30 yards we do three bars of
pressure,
that type of thing.
Wow.
So we have a little bit more
adjustability than typical rifle would.
So you walking around with a range
finder and then you're,
you're changing it on your rifle as you
go along?
Yeah.
As we make our decision we.
Because we don't like we don't walk with
it charged.
We,
I mean our darts in there ready to go,
but we don't fire.
I mean we don't have our,
our pressure up until we know what deer
we're taking in the distance.
And Are you aiming for center mass?
Hip.
Hip?
Huh?
Why hip?
Because that's where the biggest muscle
is.
Oh,
I see.
Okay.
So the DA,
the drugs enact intramuscularly,
so if you accidentally hit the ribs,
it's not good.
It's not great.
No,
it's still will probably put them to
sleep.
The needles aren't long enough that it
should do much damage.
So I'm gonna hit a vital right.
I mean you can never say never,
but yeah,
it shouldn't,
but it's not going to kill him.
It shouldn't know.
Um,
and that we practice a lot to make sure
we hit where we want to hit.
How do you practice?
Do you have a rubber deer that you shoot
at a.
We have archery targets that we shoot
at.
Yeah.
Wow,
that's interesting.
And do you use a regular rifle scope or
do you have like a scope specifically
designed for darts now?
It's a regular rifle scope.
No kidding.
Wow.
So how often do you practice in?
Um,
before we do it,
I practice quite a few times.
I go out like I don't practice daily
like you do with the archery,
but I practice pretty regularly when I,
right before I was starting,
these last two were kind of taking a
break right now because they're falling
and so we don't want to dart them while
there.
Of course I'm dragging and dropping
fonds we weren't until fonts a little
bigger.
That's interesting.
Have you ever missed one?
Um,
I haven't taken that many shots.
Did I miss any of my shots?
How many of you darted?
Just the two.
Just to.
Yeah.
And we,
this is our first time doing dear stuff.
So fish and game came out and helped us
with these guys and which was great.
And you have to dart to Moore's that
would just said for more.
For more.
Yep.
And why six?
Is that just like you just want a good
study number that.
So we're looking at roadways and trying
to identify crossing points for what I
mean we're not just doing dear,
we're doing other species as well,
but we're trying to identify where we
can make improvements,
things like that.
Wildlife overpass in other areas.
So that's why we're doing that and so
we're just trying to get a sample size
that we can kind of work with and the
colors aren't cheap so it's,
it's about resources and what we have
that we can use towards the project and
what and what are you trying to gather?
Like what,
what,
what data?
So it's all movement based data.
So they,
these are gps collars,
they transmit us,
can be anywhere from I think the color
60 points a day down to I think my
lowest eight points a day.
And so it'll tell me,
it'll give me an idea of where the deer
are approaching the roadways and how
they're moving relative to the roadway
so we can help come up with mitigation
to improve their ability to get across.
Oh,
okay.
So it's all about their migration and
where they're moving around and keeping
them away from danger.
Yeah.
I mean I wouldn't quite call it
migration,
but close enough.
That's the idea is just to help them
build,
to get across.
Now,
are they Columbia blacktail?
These are not.
These are mule deer in our mouth.
Mule deer.
No.
Kenny.
And are they like a pure mule deer?
I believe so,
yeah.
The black start a little bit north of
us.
I don't remember exactly where the cut
off line is.
But so like right around here,
like in the hills and like encino and
stuff like that.
Those are mule deer.
Mule deer.
Wow.
That's interesting.
Yeah.
I always thought that too because I,
I've deer hunted for years and I've
always thought blocked hill.
But no,
once I got here and started working with
them I was like,
oh,
these are on mule deer.
No,
how did they make the differentiation,
how they understand that there's some
just physical characteristic differences
and I think there's been some genetic
work done as well because traditionally
when you think of mule deal,
you think of a large deer with a big
rack.
Like mule deer have enormous racks.
Like that deer right there.
That's a mule deer.
Yep.
Like if you saw one of those around
here,
you'd be like,
Holy Shit.
Like you never see a deer that big
around here.
No.
I mean there's some decent deer in these
mountains.
But yeah,
it's.
I mean,
but mule,
not all mule deer,
that big course where there's mule deer
that are still quite small.
That's just what we're dealing with here
is the smaller end.
Do you think it's because of the
predators,
like they never really get a chance to
get that big because there's the
populations are pretty small or is it a
genetic issue?
We think it's a genetic issue.
I mean there,
this population's been kind of isolated
for a long time from others,
but California generally is not thought
of to have monster box even though
there's plenty of mule deer in this
state,
so it's more just the factor of what's
here and so north of us is where the
blacktail are and were like,
where did that,
what does that range begin?
I wish I could.
I'm not sure off the top of my head.
The inner breeding,
correct.
I'm sure there is.
Yeah.
And they're viable.
Are they hybrids?
I would assume they're viable,
but I am not positive.
Hmm.
Yeah,
I'm not.
I'm definitely not fully up on all the
deer literature.
So what other animals are you guys
concerned with?
Like their,
their,
their safety and populations.
So I mean we're worried about the whole
community.
I mean we do things with frogs.
Salamanders,
we do surveys for snakes.
Um,
we actually have a red legged frog
reintroduction.
Reintroduction.
Yeah.
So there's people complaining.
Not enough red legged frogs.
Well there used to be here and we had a,
well we don't really know why they
disappeared but they disappeared 30
years ago or so and they were left in
one little pool in one place.
And so we're just trying to help them
get reestablished,
do it.
Don't let Donald Trump find out about
this cut funding frog what we need that
money to go to bankers.
Yeah.
I mean it's just seems fascinating to me
that we do have these programs to like
help out like a frog.
Yeah.
I mean it's all better but man hours,
right?
A,
it takes some but it's not huge amounts.
May.
It's one person going out and doing
these projects and it's not like that's
their only job.
They have lots of different things they
did right.
So it's just one small part of their
job.
So they just bring like a bucket of
frogs and thrown into the bushes.
It's not quite that simple.
They have to move egg masses basically
is what they do.
What they do when they move the egg
masses.
Do they move the mom as well and,
or the,
the,
the frogs just develop independently and
the new area.
Yeah,
they develop independently.
They would even do that in their own
area.
The mom doesn't care for their frogs or
any of that to bitches bitches.
So when they do that,
when they,
um,
when you drop off these egg masses in
this place,
so this frog will be born or hatch in
this area rather.
And they just assume this is where they
live?
Yup.
Oh that's interesting.
So if you took a fully developed frog
and put it there,
probably wouldn't know what to do with
the area because it would be a new area
for it.
It'd be like,
why am I here?
Yeah.
This isn't my project either.
So I'm not 100 percent on it,
but from my understanding is that they
will try to move back towards their
native range and then they don't end up
making it,
so it's better to do the tadpoles or the
eggs and then they'll hopefully stay
there.
That's cool.
So what is the benefit of having these
red legged frogs around?
They're just a part of the ecosystem.
We think it's a good idea to exactly it.
Just trying to protect the overall
ecosystem.
We don't really understand.
I mean we like to think we understand
all this ecology and all that,
but they're,
it's,
it's complicated,
right?
We don't know the interaction between
all of these species.
So a lot of it's just trying to make
sure that our full suite of species is
there.
So our ecosystems healthy as possible.
So when you reintroduce the red frog,
will there then be subsequent studies
about the impact of the reintroduction
of the Red Frog red legged frog?
And it's hard to know at this point.
I mean it's all based off funding,
like there's potential there,
but right now we don't really know.
Sorry,
let me,
uh,
propose this to you.
What if you had an unlimited budget?
What if I made Justin Brown king of the
world and I said,
listen dude,
you can do whatever the fuck you want
with the all this money and what,
what would you do if you make any
promises here?
No,
I wish I could.
Obviously I don't have that kind of
power,
but of course if I did though,
if I said,
listen man,
I'm going to give you an unlimited
budget to take care of this wildlife as
you would see fit,
what would you like to have done?
Well,
one of the first things would be that
wildlife overpass you see for our
released.
If you're talking about doing things for
what's good for the local ecology here,
that would be probably the highest thing
on my priority list because that is
something that's not just affecting one
species.
It's affecting everything that's within
our mountain range,
which is fairly large hundred 50,000
acres that there's just completely being
disconnected from other wildlife.
So to me that that's our number one
thing.
The other thing is,
so we have lots of issues with these
poisons there.
I would try to find alternatives to
these poisons that are being spread
throughout the environment because
that's a major issue for our wildlife.
Yeah.
That is a giant issue when you see the
main on that cat and he's.
I think that that all comes somehow or
another from rat poison,
like whatever that happened to rat
traps.
Like I will just use a trap and people
don't like to see blood.
Is that what it is?
That's my best assumption because
people,
you try to recommend traps and they just
won't do it,
but there's such a trickle down though
when you're using those toxins,
you know,
it sets.
That's frightening to me because that
gets to people in some way,
shape or form.
Yeah,
definitely.
that's,
that's my worry as well.
It also leaks into the ground.
Like there's,
there's all sorts of weird effects that
you can get from poisons.
Yeah,
and we don't even understand the facts.
We put tons of toxicants out there that
we have no idea the actual longterm
effects or how it's gonna change things.
I mean,
like these rat poisons,
there was a long time,
they said it wouldn't move up the food
chain,
but we are quite clearly seeing it move
up the food chain to have a mountain
lion die of rat poison.
It's crazy too.
They dive in.
Yeah.
We've had three mountain lions dive rat
poison.
Wow.
And you believe it's from coyotes.
That's what we think.
Yeah.
So one of them,
they went back to a few kills that it
made right before it died.
And they found that it killed a couple
coyotes.
Uh,
wow.
Wow.
No,
it doesn't kill the coyotes.
Uh,
who knows?
The coyotes could have been really sick
at that point.
And maybe that's how the mountain lion
got it anyway.
Exactly.
So because with these poisons,
a lot of times these animals don't die
for four to 10 days.
Oh God.
So they're walking in circles.
I don't know if you've ever seen like
wrath walking circles that are running
into buildings,
like I've seen it a couple times about
walking around and that's generally what
they're dying.
They're dying,
they're dying of dehydration basically
because they're just bleeding out
internally.
Yeah.
So that was actually in Dan Flores,
his book is that they had developed
certain types of coyote poisons that
were slow acting so that they could
trick these coyotes into eating this
stuff and the other coyotes wouldn't
know where the caio got sick from
because it took so long for them to die.
It wasn't like strychnine where you eat
it.
You watched the other one die and that
that's also what rats do.
Did you ever see that documentary on
Netflix?
I heard you mentioned it,
but I still haven't seen it yet.
You got to watch it.
It's amazing.
It freaked me out.
It's nuts.
Like when when they show the amount of
rats that are in New York City and they
show all the people dealing with them
and they show them in the sewer system
and everything,
it's mind boggling and then they talk
about how the rats will literally send a
young dumb rat over to the poison and
they want that rat eat the poison and
died and they're like,
fuck this,
we're out here.
And they all take off.
Like they've got a whole system for
dealing with poisons.
Yeah.
Well,
because they did the same thing with rat
poison.
It's my understanding they,
they kind of come through different,
more for the poisoned to try to make
them last a little longer.
So the [inaudible],
the rats will do the same thing.
The coyotes do not to eat it.
So that didn't surprise me.
They saw that documentary.
I'll have to watch that.
There's no way to mitigate the problem
now.
I mean,
the rat population is so large in New
York City.
They think there's many rats as there
are people or more.
Yeah,
I believe it.
I mean,
I've been in little intersections down
in la at night and just rats,
it looks like the ground is moving at
times and these crazy locations,
like most of the places you go,
you don't see that many rats,
but then all of a sudden you'll hit this
called a honey hole for frats and
they'll just be like,
whoa,
look at what the hell's going on here.
I was in New York City way back in the
day.
It was so long ago.
There was payphones and uh,
I uh,
had to make phone call and I was getting
gas so I pulled up this gas station,
put the pump in,
filling up my car and I go over to this
payphone to make a call and as I mean in
the time it took me to walk from the
pump to the payphone,
I'm watching rats jumped onto the wheels
of my car,
like they're jumping on the wheel and
crawling up and down to like,
I don't know if they're looking for food
or they're looking to get into the
engine for warmth or whatever,
but apparently people have a real issue
with rats getting inside the hood of
their car and like nesting there,
like climb in there for the heat and
they stay warm inside the hood of your
car.
Good Lord.
Yeah.
I mean they're so adaptable,
but they instantaneously did it.
I mean,
I pulled the car up,
put the pump in,
walked,
turned around like,
what the fuck?
I'm not talking about like one rat.
I'm talking five,
six,
seven rats just hopping up.
And another one would hop up and one
would hop down.
It was terrifying because I was trying
to figure out,
okay,
am I going to be driving,
there's going to be a rat on the floor
and then I'm going to hit the gas
instead of the.
So I'm going to freak out like a little
girl.
Yeah.
It was terrifying.
Yeah,
that would be creepy.
But there's just so adaptable.
I mean,
and it's,
it's another,
essentially we don't like to think of
them as a wild animal,
but a rat is a wild that lives in this
weird symbiotic relationship with people
in urban environments.
I mean,
it's amazing there.
That is the one species.
It's probably more adapted to us than
the coyotes are obviously because they
are able to live in almost everywhere
that we live.
Yeah.
And they're,
I mean,
they serve a purpose in some sort of a
weird way.
I mean,
and if they were removed,
I wonder what the impact would be.
Yeah.
I mean,
I'm sure we'd probably have more nesting
birds and some of that kind of stuff
because we know that rats definitely
impact bird species.
Um,
and who knows,
there may not be,
if there were,
wasn't rats,
whether coyotes or some of these other
small predators would be around the
urban areas because they're obviously
another prey source know.
But trying to get rid of rats is a whole
nother ballgame.
Good luck.
Yeah.
That's,
that's the one that's probably harder in
coyotes,
theaters and nuke that city.
You'd have to get everybody to agree and
then they'd probably move back in within
a couple of years.
Yeah.
It's just,
you're not going to do it.
So this proposed bridge across the 101,
what is,
is there a roadblocks as it a funding
issue?
Is there anybody that is against it?
As far as we know,
there's not anybody really against that.
There might be a few people in the
nearby community that's worried about
more mountain lions come in or
something,
but we don't think that's a realistic
thing because that holding capacity from
as far as we understand.
So we don't think that's going to be a
major issue.
Um,
but it's really about funding.
We're trying to.
National Wildlife Federation is leading
the charge to try to raise,
I think the cost is over $50,000,000 to
do this.
Yeah.
So it's,
it's a big price tag.
Um,
the bridge is going to be quite wide.
It's going to be natural covered and
it's going to ask to go over the road
and the one on one both.
And so.
Oh,
it's going to be a big bridge.
So I hope wide.
Is that who I wish I could call that off
the top of my head.
I.
Yeah,
sorry.
You'd have to look it up.
I think it's probably on that thing he
had up earlier.
So you probably deal with a few hundred
yards or something.
Yeah,
I mean it's almost as wide as it is
long.
Oh Wow.
Yeah.
So it's going to be big.
It's gonna also how it's going to be
used for hiking during the day as well.
So it's not just for wildlife so people
can go across it.
Exactly.
Because currently there's no easy way to
go from the Santa Monica is in the south
to the cme Hilton,
the north,
which are all public property.
So there's no way to get across there so
people can hide,
they have to go down on the Liberty
Canyon road and cut across there,
which is kind of sucky.
So how does one raise money for
something like this?
Do they try to have like a go fund me or
do they just rely on the state budget?
No,
it's all they're doing fundraising,
trying to get people to kick in.
I believe the Annenberg has already
offered to donate a million dollars
matching,
so they've got to raise another million
to get that amount.
It's all for the most part,
I believe it's all from either
conservation agencies or from private
donations.
So if you were king of the world,
that would be the first thing that you
would work on.
As far as wildlife in California,
I'm definitely for our region,
yes.
What about other issues?
Other issues?
I mean habitat protections just
obviously incredibly important.
If we want to keep all of our species,
so protecting more land is is always a
valuable thing to make sure that,
or at least to make sure what
development we do is done in a proper
way.
Now when you say protect more land,
would that be like buying up available
private land when it comes for sale and
then turning it into public land?
Um,
to some level I would consider that.
I don't know if that would be my
ultimate goal.
To me it's more important to lock it up
so it's natural versus public versus
private.
Oh.
So like to stop a development stop,
major developments from coming in and
putting things right in places that are
going to be major blockages to wildlife
movement.
Boulder's kind of interesting in that
way where they buy up all the available
property and then turn into open space.
So you can't develop on it ever.
Yeah.
They're really smart with that because
they,
I think boulder is an amazing place and
that they've really recognized that they
have this incredible sort of beautiful
little community that's surrounded by
this inescapable beauty of the
mountains,
the rockies.
You don't get much more beautiful place
in around boulders.
Makes Sense.
I mean,
if you want to keep your communities the
way they are,
you kind of have to protect some of the
land.
Yeah.
They're not into anybody developing
there.
They're like,
no,
let's not do that.
It's a really wise of them,
but it's amazing that they've a managed
rather to go so long without being co
opted by.
Money,
you know?
Yeah.
I mean that's kind of the name of the
game.
I mean,
obviously we need developments because
our populations keep growing.
So to me it's not always realistic to
say we need to protect every piece of
land.
We can protect what development we do.
We need to do it smart and make sure
that things are protected in the proper
places.
Is there any other wildlife issues in
and around this area that,
uh,
are being addressed right now?
Um,
I mean that's,
that those are the two biggest things
going on that we're,
we're,
we're actively trying to deal with.
Um,
yeah,
I can't think of too many.
I mean there's always the little
nuisance issues that everybody's trying
to deal with where a coyote is in
somebodies yard or going after dogs or
whatever that we try to deal with.
But those are the two major ones would
be connectivity,
um,
habitat loss.
And then just poisons.
And are there a lot of raccoons in this
area?
Um,
a lot.
I would.
It depends what you're comparing.
Healthy population.
Yeah.
There's a decent number of raccoons if
you're comparing it to somewhere like
Chicago.
No,
we don't have goggles.
Larger population records.
They're just much more adept there.
They're just the way the landscape is a
lot more mature trees,
mature forest,
which is what raccoons,
like a lot more water.
Um,
which are all things that attract
raccoons where we're a lot drier.
Raccoons can occur within like our
mountains,
but they do seem to be more focused near
roadways and some of that stuff taken
advantage of whatever resources are
there.
Well,
a big garbage hunters too,
right?
They definitely take advantage of
garbage.
They'll also eat lots of fruits and
stuff.
So some of the scats you see in your
yard that you think are coyotes.
They could be raccoon as well.
Um,
they eat a lot of berries and stuff.
So yeah,
I found some skunk poop.
Real friend.
Yeah.
My friend who recognized the a mountain
lion poop.
I sent him some stuff and I said,
what is this?
He said that skunk poop skunks are
amazing.
Like I,
before I started tracking these coyotes
and downtown La,
I would have never thought skunks could
be down in that area.
There's actually a decent number of
skunks like in that West Lake
neighborhood.
I could not believe how many skunks that
I smelled.
Skunk and Hollywood last night I was
driving through.
It could have been strong weed,
but I don't think it was.
I'm pretty sure it was an actual.
Scott was leaving the comedy store and
it just stunk of skunk and I was like,
how weird that these animals have
figured out a way to live right here in
like right near sunset.
Yeah,
I know.
And they're little short legs.
Not Super Mobile,
but yet these stripes gunk seemed to
have figured it out.
Yeah,
they,
they were going after my chickens to the
little creeps.
Really?
Yeah.
Dare there.
Apparently they like to eat chickens.
That's interesting.
Yeah.
One night I actually had a.
We were sitting in the house,
me and my wife just hanging out and all
of a sudden I hear my chickens going
crazy out there and I'm like,
we both got up and took off running and
we have a lot of feral cats around our
house and I was like,
oh,
this thing cats are in there.
We go looking around.
Our chickens are flying all over the
yard because we hadn't gotten out and
closed the door yet because my chickens
can kind of free range my yard and we're
looking around.
We don't see anything else and I open up
the coop door and there's a big old
paths.
I'm just sitting there grinning at me
so I didn't get anything.
It didn't affect,
didn't grab one of my chickens even
though one of my chickens was just
sitting there like looking at it in
squawking.
It's like you should be doing trying.
He was trying,
but he just didn't.
They're not very fast.
They're not.
Yeah,
they're with possums.
You like for me there another species.
You don't need a drug to handle agent.
Just you can just grab them up by the
tail.
Usually in.
Oh really?
Hold on to them.
Yeah.
No,
you can just run up to them and grab
them.
People do.
There's definitely.
There was a guy doing his masters work
on possums and he would drive around
town and when he saw what he had jumped
out of his car,
he'd be out hanging out with his
friends.
You'd see a possum jump out and grab it
and cram it in his trunk.
Oh,
Jesus Christ throat.
It is trump.
Yeah.
That's dedication right there.
What did he do with it once you got it
in his trunk?
He was colored.
He's doing kind of like what we do here.
Trying to identify their movements and
what's going on with them.
What did they find out?
Anything unusual?
I don't know.
I've never saw his talk.
I wasn't like.
I ran into him at a conference one time
and we got chatting about what he did
and I was like,
that's pretty hilarious.
It is really weird how many animals we
live around.
I mean,
it's really weird.
There's so many different and such a
wide variety,
especially when it comes to birds.
You know?
One thing that I see a lot of is,
well,
there's a lot of hawks in my
neighborhood and we did this thing in
our backyard where we had a a wrought
iron fence and we changed part of it and
put a glass fence and these hawks hadn't
figured it out and they would swoop down
and slammed into the fence headfirst.
We got quite a few of these poor hawks.
Yeah,
I can imagine.
but it's just amazing how many you find
out there and how many predators and
there's the occasional golden eagle in
this area too,
right?
We get reports of them coming through
every once in a while.
Yeah.
It's not rare by any means are super
common by any means,
but they come through now and when you
say,
how would one know whether or not you're
looking at a Golden Eagle?
It's just because it's really big.
It's really big.
There's some other little
characteristics that I'm not as good
with,
but they're significantly larger than
like the red tills,
which would be the one you'd be most
likely to confuse it with?
Yeah,
just the wide variety of different
raptors and these.
Yeah,
it's,
it's amazing.
I mean red shouldered hawks once smile
will be traveling for bobcat and we'll
catch a red shouldered hawk on our
traps.
It's like,
oh,
this is so cool.
We've even caught a great horned owl
once and so it's pretty neat seeing some
of these animals up close.
Yeah,
I'm worried that the owls in my
neighborhood had been poisoned because I
used to have quite a few of them and
used to hear them all the time.
It used to hear them hooting all the
time and one time I went out on my back
porch and there was one sitting on the
fence and it was huge.
I mean I don't know how big it really
was because I'm sure it was kind of
freaked out by it,
but I,
I was shocked.
It was at least two feet tall and it was
just sitting on his back.
I mean,
at least that tall.
no exaggeration,
but it looked like it was like four feet
tall.
It looked,
it looked.
I couldn't believe how big it looked.
Great personalities are huge.
Huge.
Yeah.
I think they can carry away foxes to
study in Bakersfield that they've
documented and house coming down,
grabbing the kit boxes and carrying them
up to their nest sites.
I had a video on instagram.
It's still up there that I got online of
this.
A owl swooping down and jacking a hawk
and it's next.
No.
Have you ever seen that?
I haven't,
but I've heard about it.
My one of my coworkers actually as a
falconer and he when he released or what
did he do?
One of his Hawk's got away from him and
he said the tree was as being swarmed by
grade horns.
He stayed there all night trying to keep
the.
Trying to help his hawk stay alive.
No kidding.
Now he's crazy.
Owls eat hawks.
Yeah.
I didn't know that until he was telling
me that.
I'm like,
that's crazy.
I mean,
great horns are huge though.
Check out this video because it's really
nuts.
Do you know how long I was?
Legs,
legs.
Never seen that before that.
That's crazy.
Hard to find something even close to it,
but wow.
Yeah,
they're amazing.
I got a,
I worked at cal State Bakersfield in
there.
They had a raptor rehab thing and I got
the handle.
Great horned owls.
When those guys flap their wings,
it's like,
whoa.
It was pretty crazy.
I comparable to the the Golden Eagle,
the Golden Eagles.
Definitely more powerful,
but the goal of the long or the great
horned owls were pretty amazing.
Our perception of them is so interesting
because they're a serious predator,
but most people don't think of an owl as
a predator.
They just think of them as some wise
forest creature that gives advice on
fire.
They're obviously not a threat to you or
me,
but obviously your cat,
they could potentially grow 100 percent.
Right,
and who knows?
Those people get smaller and smaller.
Dog.
Watch this because you see the eyes and
the distance.
See the eyes.
Check this out.
I love this video being,
wow,
the other arc doesn't even know what
happened.
He's like,
what's up?
What's going on?
What's was that when a man.
Is that a juvenile?
I do not know.
I don't know.
They look a little fuzzy.
Yeah,
they do a little bit right.
Especially the one in the back,
the one that gets jacked act.
Wow.
But the way it gets jacked,
it's like,
boy,
that thing's dead before it leaves the
nest.
Those claws and towns are so gigantic.
They are.
They're amazing.
That's kind of why we want them around.
Right.
Rabbits and rats and everything else and
also because they're cool.
Yeah.
I mean now I think that's a big thing
about coyotes too and I,
I wish some of these short sided folks
that don't want them around because
they're worried that they're going to
get their dog and all this different
stuff.
Like,
man,
we're really lucky that we can see these
things.
I mean,
nature is cool.
It's cool to see.
Yeah,
well that's amazing now being in
downtown La,
but a lot of these people that live down
there,
they don't ever get to see wildlife
right now.
All of A.
suddenly there's this medium sized
carnivore running around their
neighborhoods that they get to see and
some people.
I mean,
it's funny,
I talked to one person that's like
scared to death of this thing and the
next person's like,
it's the coolest thing they've ever seen
in their life.
Right.
And it's always that balancing act.
I mean I,
to me,
I've always been pretty fascinated with
them.
Yeah,
I identify more with the people think
it's cool.
It's just,
it's really like we,
we're talking about,
we're really lucky we live in a very
unique area in that we have this big
city,
huge city and then just outside of it we
have all this wildlife,
like real legit wildlife you can get
from downtown La to 100 percent
wilderness in an hour.
That's crazy.
They were less,
I mean,
yeah,
you can get into Santa Monica.
It's pretty quickly from those spots in
La and it's,
you get in there and it's pretty
amazing.
Well listen man,
I really appreciate you coming on here
and sharing all your information and
educating us on this stuff.
It's super cool and thanks for
everything you do.
And,
uh,
it's just,
it's really interesting that you get to
share all this stuff that you're
learning about these things.
They appreciate it,
man.
Thanks for having folks.
We'll be back tomorrow with my pal out.
Magical.
See that.