I'll never forget.
Five,
four,
three,
two,
one.
Yes.
How the fuck is it?
Been so many years and you haven't been
on here.
This is ridiculous timing,
everything.
There's times you go super busy and you
too.
It's really good seeing yet fucking
awesome seeing you,
man.
It's really awesome seeing,
yeah,
this is a weird thing because we're
having this conversation and people are
listening to it,
but at the same time,
uh,
you know,
you're one of my favorite people and I'm
fucking known you forever.
We were friends when we were both
hungry,
scrappy young comedians with no idea
what the fuck was going to happen.
Right know.
And we were both like,
Whoa,
what the fuck is going to happen in the
future?
Well,
you know what that's like,
there's a bond that you have with people
that like you and I were essentially in
the same place and are in our lives in
the same place,
our comedy careers at the same time.
And you know,
I tell everyone I remember what I,
what I liked about you,
how real and honest you were.
You were.
And you were also like,
oh,
you want to do is play pool,
which I didn't know shit about pool and
I can't.
It's all right.
We got to play pool and I would sock and
I can tell you get bored real quick and
then you'd have it.
You go to a pool halls and you'd fucking
work out.
Did you want to go to the gym?
Like all right,
we'll go to the gym,
but you beat up like an hour and a half
and I got to say is,
I watched your whole career grow and
grow and grow.
I can tell when the fighting came along
the UFC and my,
am I wrong to say you probably were the
happiest.
That was not the greatest job ever.
It was because you never changed all you
all.
I knew you as a tough guy.
Honest guy played billiards,
worked out.
I've heard you say,
dude,
I'll fucking choke you out right now.
These guys were at a craft table for a
Disney show,
which,
which shows us what was the
baseball show?
Oh,
hardball.
That's right,
dude,
you are the fucking pioneer.
Harven Dude,
I have a photo of us,
a monkey.
I have a photo of us that I have to
bring in.
I have to bring it in because I got,
fuck,
I've got to find no exact where I put
it.
I don't have to find a no exact,
it's you and me from like 1993 we look
like babies are babies.
We look like babies and with Ruthann
remember the agent?
Yes dude dude,
that was a funny role.
That was a,
that was one of my favorite examples of
a show that could have been a really
funny show written by really funny guys
and the network's juice all over it.
They just stuck their own.
This is my now and they ruined it.
Ruined it did.
But you get,
you were there at the pilot,
you're on the,
you're on the craft line.
Craft services,
which to me that was the greatest party.
Even filming anything.
I was still,
this is free,
go like guts.
So there was a guy,
young fucking little guy,
just,
he probably wants to be an actor,
but he's serving rice to us and he said
he has a shirt,
says I love karate
and you're just fucking,
is it?
Here come,
you're fucking,
you're all hot tub.
And he got to dig.
You take karate and the kid goes your
yet get off.
I,
I don't know why.
I don't know if it's said kickbox and
whatever.
He said,
I'd fucking crazy socks.
It's the fucking worst.
Didn't know what,
there's no way.
You're not mischaracterizing this
conversation.
No,
it does.
No way it happened like that.
Like I just walked up till God deal
rice.
It's like,
dude,
karate socks.
No,
no,
no.
He had his shirt Kinda Kreidie shirt and
that was enough.
None of it.
You started poking questions for him.
You were like asking is teligent you
like,
hey man,
what's you,
uh,
Eh,
we'll get you into karate.
And then he would go something like,
you know,
I like the martial arts.
And then you would say,
dude,
you should take this.
He was like,
no,
I think karate guy would win it.
And then I saw you just like,
dude,
I'm telling you right now,
fucking crush it.
But the point of that conversation was I
couldn't,
I just never saw anyone like you and my
life.
I,
you're like a fucking that moment we go,
the sky is so he's an he didn't you?
You were fearless.
I'd never seen anyone so fearless in my
life and I've always looked up to you
for that
bag.
I definitely never been fearless.
I'm not a feel of the person just took
that.
Oh No,
no,
no.
Not at all.
I'm fucking around.
But I've never been fearless.
I'm scared of everything.
But this is how you,
uh,
how you respond to it.
It's how you respond to fear whether or
not you're scared of some of the
unknown.
Most people shy away from the unknown,
you know?
Okay.
That is very true.
But it's hard to get honest because
sometimes there's a lot of deeper
factors in is a lot of eyes on you.
You don't think your kids are eyes are
on you,
you to expose him to stuff.
So it's a little like,
um,
I'm a feared to be,
I fear being aleut too honest at times.
Right.
I see what you're saying,
Byron off.
That's right or wrong.
Right.
I know.
Look,
you kind of protecting yourself or your
kids in a,
in a lot of ways from how you are,
because you don't want them to kind of
be as wild and crazy as you were when
you were young.
Like with the pot thing and stuff like
that.
Well,
like here,
let me ask you this.
Okay.
If you're,
let's see how old your you have.
How old?
$3.
Okay.
I have three doors.
If one door to goes and you could tell
they're starting to kind of get into
pot.
They want to grow faster.
Why do you want to let them,
don't you think you were doing it when
you were like 14?
Yeah.
14 now I'm going to say
seven.
Tina's,
I was a late bloomer,
so I got into it a little bit with some
friends when I was like 12 and 13 yeah,
we got some pot.
Well,
yeah.
Wow.
Yeah.
But I didn't get it.
And that's my middle daughter.
Yeah.
It happens to do you leave them alone,
leave those little fuckers alone.
They get ahold of some music.
That's what it is,
man.
You know,
with us,
we would,
uh,
we would go over this fucking dude's
house and we'd listened to bad company
and we'd,
uh,
we'd get some pot.
See the,
I was still into sports at that time,
but so when I discovered it,
okay,
I was into the metal,
right.
So we would go in the basement and we
turn on and bornite when I heard,
when I heard,
and I dunno if that's another weird part
of me,
why was I attracted to that?
I heard them,
I heard that fast,
furious.
And that made me ape shit.
It's great for a young guy,
for a young guy that's the music that
sort of represents your hormones.
You know,
John got out,
you know,
you're fucking 17.
You're like,
yeah,
you know,
and,
and also your suppressed all the time.
Like everyone's like,
calm down,
settle down,
not so loud.
Right.
Stop fucking each other.
Hold on.
And then some music comes up and it
just,
you know,
it releases all that madness.
Yeah.
It comes out.
You feel it,
you feel the music understands you.
I know.
But I fear,
here's my biggest fear as a dad getting
addicted to shit.
Yeah.
And get pregnant.
While those things are both,
uh,
the reality is that everybody faces when
you're young,
you know,
and,
and also biologically everybody faces it
seems like with pills.
I know so many people that have gotten
addicted to pills.
I mean,
it's an epidemic.
I'm,
no,
I'm known if I had a sit down and have
all the people that I've been close
enough to to call on a regular base and
say,
how you doing?
What's going on?
You know,
have conversation with them.
Yeah.
Maybe a dozen have been hooked on pills
and I know three people that have died
from it.
Well,
there weren't,
I don't remember pills and weird
kids did it.
They didn't happen.
They didn't exist at all.
You would hear like,
some people get in like vicodins and
shit like that,
but those were always like crazy people.
Don't you think kind of though
it's,
they're all prescription pills,
right?
Yeah,
yeah.
No,
yeah,
no,
absolutely.
Definitely.
Right.
So if they're prescribed,
does it seem as like,
oh,
they figured out how to legalize really
bad trucks down?
Well,
they definitely did.
They figured out a build trust does more
because we'll wear these white lab coats
and we had to tell them and we write out
the little card and just take three of
these a week
and be able to stop.
That's another suppressed guy.
But that guy listened to some death
metal from feminine,
you know,
let me get this fucking car after
selling heroin all day with a lab coat
on,
that's a dark.
There was an article about this one.
It's insane.
There was an article about this one
family that has a,
um,
has like a giant steak in that market
and they've made billions and billions
of dollars and it was breaking down like
how much money they made and how many
people are hooked on it,
how many prescriptions there are.
It's like they're just,
they're drug dealers like the legalized.
Well if you looked at this in the
future,
like when they look back and they say,
oh,
remember those opium dens and the
cowboys had remembered from Wyatt earp,
was it wider wild bill Hickok one of
them fucking movies.
They went to the opium den that Chinese
people got them all fucked up on opium
and we were like,
Whoa,
those are dark times.
This is way worse than that.
I agree.
And it's happening underneath our noses.
Look,
don't you see?
How do you stop that?
That's a good question.
Cause you can talk about it forever.
And I think,
I think you've talked about enough.
I even brought up to people and it's,
it's sort of the old again.
You face it.
What do you do now?
We can talk about it forever,
but what do you actually do?
Teachers just talk about it and let
people live seep into people and he
think he's telling the truth or you
think they know what they're saying?
Dude.
That why things decide for themselves.
Any,
um,
anything that you're going to let your
kid figure out for themselves.
You're like depriving them of
information.
Right?
So I think what you gotta do is be like
really honest about it.
And I'm with my oldest daughter,
the young girls don't know that I smoked
the weed,
but we just had conversations about it.
I said,
listen,
there are some things that are dangerous
and there are some things that are just
not dangerous at all.
And pod is the one that's not dangerous
at all.
Like my,
my wife and I had a conversation with
her about it and you know,
it's a weird sort of a conversation
cause you're,
you're talking to someone who on the
verge of being an adult,
right?
So you're kind of bullshitting them
still but not really course.
Whereas if they were an adult you'd be
like,
Look Pot's not hurting anybody.
I smoked pot before I go to bed.
I do too.
And then everybody would laugh.
Hahaha.
You know,
from here on,
I like it right before her.
I'm sorry.
And then you know,
you have these little conversations with
people with,
with adults,
but when the kid that about th that come
in and don't,
don't,
don't tell him.
Right.
You want to keep somehow or another this
innocuous thing from the kids.
But meanwhile you'll sip a glass of wine
in front of him.
I'll drink a glass of wine from my kids
all the time.
I've let them try wine.
I've let him try a sip of wine and try
this gas tank and then it becomes a
funny thing they talk about,
remember that time I tried to wine?
Oh my God.
So grabs.
But it's socially accepted.
Yeah.
To let them taste how disgusting adults
tasting beverages are.
But,
but smoking pot in
front of them or around them would be
horrific.
It's so foolish sheets,
you know?
Did you know anyone?
I remember I knew a kid and he was up
the street
and he smoked pot when his parents and
his salmon,
we're going to go in there and smoke pot
when the parents,
but my initial,
I don't know,
my,
my instinct was like,
oh,
that's weird.
It's just weird.
I can't hit it.
That's weird.
I guess it is,
but I don't know.
You know?
I mean,
it's not really,
if,
if having a drink with your dad's not
weird,
how come you can't,
having a beer with your dad is not
weird.
I'll give you for instance.
Okay,
sorry.
My Dad,
he,
he never drank with me.
He never said,
but he was,
everyone else would say,
sky's fucking like brewers.
You're dead.
This guy's nuts.
Like my father's nuts.
I didn't see that side of him at all.
So not until it was my 21st birthday.
Like I just knew him as his fucking Dad,
right?
World War Two vet and shit like that.
Serious guy.
Very serious.
Never left.
And I think he left twice the filthy or
the funny and his laugh was just like,
that was,
that was killing him that you fucking
corona.
So
I swear to God.
So,
um,
when I was 21,
he said,
let's go have a beer.
You're a man now.
So we went to his place,
swamp water,
als when I was in Florida and one out
and have a couple of beers.
He's saying some ca he doesn't talk,
he'll say stupid jokes and I don't
really understand.
I'm bored.
I go outside,
catch a buzz and we got this will help
the fucking night I come back and catch
a buzz means smoke a little weed.
Yes.
I come back in.
Um,
and he's,
there's a crowd around him and I swear
to God because he was older,
I thought he,
I thought he was down.
Everyone was looking at the old man up
for it.
Go there and he's fucking holding court
with the whole bar and he's,
he's killing,
he's destroying.
And so then I turned around like,
who is this fucking guy?
I want to hire him.
He's fucking hilarious.
And I just couldn't understand.
I never saw this man.
So I had a beer,
he had a beer,
we caught buses and we had the phone.
I never saw,
my father was funny and I said,
where,
why didn't,
why didn't you show me this side
earlier?
I would hear this from all my friends.
He goes,
you weren't fucking ready.
That's hilarious.
But I kind of feel that way with certain
kids.
Do you know what I mean?
For me.
This fucker,
like for instance,
I can say,
I think,
I think this kid,
you know what if they,
if they go in that direction,
I think they'll be okay.
This one,
it's not so much donut.
It's this one against stop.
Yeah.
They do have different personalities
like that,
right?
Yeah.
And you've seen like,
it's,
it's almost like a,
I'm gonna let you out of the fence.
Don't listen.
Don't go pass f fucking tree during the
woods.
Walker went nowhere did I not say don't
go into fuck it.
He's in the woods and then they come
back.
Oh I'm sorry.
It's,
yeah,
I fear this one's going to go some kids
freedom is super intoxicating.
You got to wonder what it is.
Is it anything that we set up in those
kids when they were young?
Did we suppress him too much?
And so they just had this intense desire
to be free.
Cause I think there's something to that.
This,
this desire to protect someone.
It kind of backfires when you're raising
kids in some ways because if you try to
protect him too much,
then they,
they resent you.
And then they,
they pushed back the other way.
That's why I like girls who have like
really strict parents when it comes to
sex were always like the biggest freaks.
Like we all knew that right?
Catholic school girls worth the biggest
freaks of all time.
It wasn't even close.
It was well it was that or like a broken
home,
you know,
no one's around,
I,
Hey Daddy,
well the zone,
any negative pressure,
right?
Any negative comes out in one way or
another.
My coming out like you and humor or
might come out of anger.
It might come out in addiction,
but any negative pressure that you
experienced as a child,
whether it's bullying,
uh,
you know,
going to a new neighborhood,
parents break up no attention,
you know,
alcoholism in the family,
whatever the fuck it is,
it just finds its way to the sun.
You know,
your rights.
That's where all our music comes from.
I mean,
that's where all the best stuff comes
from.
It comes from some kind of pain,
some,
some kind of like need to never feel
that pain again,
need to celebrate the happiness of life.
Because you felt that pain and you
understand it and
right.
Isn't that what knowing?
How am I?
No,
no,
no.
But you try to tense.
When did it start with you?
Like once the first time where you saw
something and went,
oh my God,
whoa.
With kids.
Yeah,
from the jump dude.
Just from the jump.
Just from the time they were little tiny
babies,
just start looking at him and he'd go to
these,
this is a little calculating beings.
This isn't simply a baby.
Like we have these narrow
classifications for human beings.
Like,
oh,
he's an old man.
He wouldn't try to fuck her,
you know?
Or He's a,
you know,
he's a young kid.
He doesn't understand.
No,
they fucking understand.
They understand.
They just don't have all the words yet.
They understand a lot more than you
think they do and they're just
constantly calculating.
They're constantly taking data.
They're learning
and we're still doing it,
man.
I mean,
you and I are better at talking now in
our forties and we were in our twenties
you chest,
you just brought back.
I feel like I just went to therapy.
Does the basic,
I just found where my anger came while
you were talking,
I was getting visual flashbacks of where
it really started.
My sister,
I remember my sister got,
um,
horrible divorce harvest harvest,
really strict.
She was getting hit.
Oh right.
So I just remember mom,
my mom getting those phone calls and
blah,
blah blah,
and did it.
So no,
it's not funny.
But,
so I remember going there,
we'd go in the middle of night,
get there and you know,
she'd be bruised.
You could tell she was hit,
which is already,
you're fucking traumatized.
You're seven,
eight years old
and you just,
you witnessed the violence.
And then,
um,
I remember the fucker came at the house,
didn't know we were there.
And my dad was like,
hey man,
why don't you be a man,
be a man.
And he said,
if you earn all,
man,
I fucking make you eat them words.
I remember my father going,
your dad,
and he's trying to get out in my mind,
it's like,
God,
fuck it,
and please,
please.
But I remember that anger
and then I,
that's how I discovered fucking
metallica.
Whoa.
From that,
that exchange,
that aggression.
I needed something.
I would go in my basement tear shit.
And so how old,
how old are you at the time?
I tell him off,
I've tended,
I was 14 like do
you know what?
I used to have a lot of internal
arguments like I should have said I
would have is I should have said they
would go on for hours.
I'd be in my fucking car and traffic.
Yo You,
if you fucking thought about it,
this word,
you know like you don't come come up
with some better thing that you could
have said or some some slicker thing
that you could have said.
Well I did.
I still do that though.
You still gave up on it.
I forced it out.
We'd it like it's a weed in the garden.
No,
I'll do it for a good half hour bathroom
on the road.
Are you kidding me?
Try not to man.
I try not to.
I try to,
as much as I can focus my thoughts on
things that are actually beneficial to
me.
So like if it's something like that
where I know what it is,
I know what it is,
so I ran into some fucking idiot.
I know what it is.
I'm not going to dwell on it.
Right.
You know what I mean?
Just I'm going to move by instead of
like making that a part of my life.
I don't want to anybody's goofy behavior
to be a part of my life.
It's so exhausting.
It's exhausting and it's not necessary.
You could figure out a way.
It's an exercise.
It's not easy to do,
but when you get frustrated by someone,
you got to learn how to just concentrate
and things that you want to concentrate.
Just don't let the other
things in.
And then after a while you get stronger
at it.
It's like a weight or it's like a
muscle.
Rather you lift weights with it,
it gets stronger.
So like putting your intention on things
that you actually enjoy instead of
festering on some fucking stupid
argument you might've had with your
girlfriend two months ago or with your
boss last week,
or retard in twitter or someone on
twitter.
Yeah.
Or someone you ran into the gas station
and said something fucking stupid you
for no reason and you said I should have
fucking smack that guy.
You know,
you just
close it up because you
just,
you,
yeah.
She can't let,
we can't let those things grow.
That's what it is.
When you feed them,
they grow,
they do grow and then it goes easier for
them to grow.
It's almost like they've set the fucking
seeds.
A matrix of seeds in your head or any
other retarded thought would just
fucking sprout wings and fly away real
quick and don't let them.
It happens to most to when you're,
when you're growing like as a person
every time.
Every time I think I'm growing like,
wow,
I'm expanding in life to bring him down.
Show him his weakness.
Yeah.
Say he can handle twitter.
That's what happens to me.
I'll get a fucking tweet from,
I don't know who this person is.
I don't care who this person is.
I can hear it.
It took me a little while to get over
that.
You know what,
man?
I don't blame them.
I used to blame them and I still make
fun of them,
but I think it's a t,
it's a tool.
Twitter is that is too weird and tiered
to,
and it's never been,
it's never existed before.
There's never been this ability with an
anonymous name to just be shitty to
someone or just communicate with someone
or even have any kind of contact with
someone positive or negative because I
think there's a lot of people out there
that are addicted to the positive too.
I mean like girls,
girls on instagram that had taken yoga,
booty pictures and by the way,
don't stop.
I'm not saying stop.
All of a sudden.
Just balance it out.
Those pictures are wonderful.
Keep them common girls.
I'm not saying don't,
don't take pictures of your well
sculpted,
but you should enjoy the praise that you
get from your Labor in the gym.
Not saying that,
but I think definitely people they get
that becomes addictive to them.
They start gravitating towards it.
Of course they do.
It's like war of the,
it's a war of the mines.
Mines all coupon,
20 to fourth episode conspiracy.
It's a conspiracy.
Is that what a conspiracy.
Imagine if they'd created twitter
because they knew.
They were like,
look,
we have to figure out where to control
people in the age of information.
Well,
here's the thing.
Let them just communicate with each
other freely.
They'll start so much conflict.
I'll never be able to deal with us
taking over the world every time they
get along.
Just tear the pot just a little bit.
Send the fun.
Yeah,
let's keep,
keep race relations and check.
Everything's always going to be chaos.
Show them someone getting beaten by an
office out immediately and you have that
tape from 1980 I supposed it up.
Make it look like today.
Send
the funder
time gang to dad and dad had died.
I can introduce some new phrases to get
them upset that me nothing.
I think I'd like to see a debate.
Well,
surely my crowd is angry than yours.
Really?
Let's have a bottle off.
Let's limit the words they're allowed to
say freely.
We need more restricted words.
How about retard?
That's an easy one to stop.
Let's get rid of retard.
I always wish repulsed by retaught.
You know what?
I've always found tranny to be quite
offensive.
Let's make training on the list as well.
Then I'm going to go forward,
but pushing too hard.
They're going to push back.
Oh,
they'll forget to meet Lee.
Oh really?
Quick race walk.
Why don't we pass a bill on trend
candace and put it in the limelight
because we all know everybody talks
about that every day.
You know what?
We can never resolve gay marriage.
We need it.
It's not peace.
We must move it.
Don't lose the queen.
You lose the queen.
You lose the game.
That's our,
Jake matches our queen chess table of a
social construct.
What?
I was a little kid,
we argued about gay marriage.
When I moved from San Francisco to
Florida.
I was probably like,
I think I was 11 years old and I
remember that was a big thing that
people were upset.
They were trying to make gay marriage
then,
so that was like 1970 something.
There's still arguing about it.
It's the same cycles every and nobody,
nobody,
nobody sees it.
It's weird.
It's crazy.
I got to tell you,
you don't.
You get every four years the same thing.
Here's,
here's the debates.
Gay,
gay marriage,
abortion.
Abortion is a big one on a
portion stick.
Trump.
How do you feel about killing babies?
Are we cool with it?
As long as I don't want,
sorry,
I don't get to see it.
Oh No,
no,
no.
You don't say shit.
We put a vacuum cleaner up there.
There's nothing between you and the
tissue at all.
You don't see anything.
Okay,
cool.
As long as I don't see it.
Well,
how big do they get?
How big do they get before they suck
them out of there?
Yeah,
they can get pretty big.
Don't he wants to have this
conversation.
Nobody wants coming inside.
People feel so good that nobody wants to
have this conversation.
Everyone's like,
let's,
let's just keep it around.
Just keep it around,
stop describing it and the uncomfortable
way,
that's like I'm describing it.
It is like fucking mellow and bland and
factual way as possible and it's
uncomfortable.
It's fuck like what abortion actually is
and I'm not saying that you shouldn't be
able to do it.
I'm a hundred percent pro choice.
I'm 100% a woman has a right to do
whatever she wants with her body and I
definitely don't think a man should be
able to tell you what to do with your
body.
100% but the end of the day,
that's a little baby and you're using a
vacuum to suck it out of your body.
Like it's odd,
but it,
but it's not odd.
It's not like a judgment because I agree
with it.
I think he should be able to do it.
But isn't there an up to a point because
it's like,
it's like three cells,
like it was enough cells to fit on the
very tip of a pin and it just gets
sucked out of the vacuum.
Okay.
I don't really see the issue.
You know,
if you're,
if you're like a tribal guy in the
woods,
are guys,
get the girl pregnant,
they realize we're not going to be able
to fucking before this one and you're
Charlie's wife or boot booze wife,
we got to get rid of.
You can't tell me they don't.
They're not eating berries or
fucking running hard into a tray.
So what I mean like I have a abortion
stomped at this angle and this is where
you run.
If the calming your body and you don't
want to baby,
you run towards the abortion had dumb
fucking take one right in the gut.
It's like a perfectly shaped tree.
God Damn.
Yeah,
for sure.
Somebody must've figured out somewhere
along the line there's gotta be a way to
stop this fucking kid.
But the point is
you're a sex edge that that's,
if I had that as sex education in fifth
grade,
I would've thought everything a lot
differently.
My head,
you come in and describe it all.
Listen,
I know you guys getting into it and you
know,
these are the risks.
And you said everything you just said
like wow,
I would have changed my whole
perspective on moving forward.
Well,
you know the egg,
the egg shoots into this.
That's what they teach you.
And so the teaching nonsense coming and
people feels awesome and there's a
reason for that nature.
Just trying to get you to make more
people because nature is still the same
setup that was around when we died real
young when there wasn't that many of us.
We could,
you could wipe out some,
you know,
we were shitting in the street so people
were getting plague and how they'd have
rats,
they would carry these diseases and
fleas and not deaf.
Fought like a gene off from tossing her
own feces.
A gene off.
Yeah.
So why do we have to come a lot?
I've got to make a lot of people just to
keep the fucking party rolling.
And I think that's one of the things
that's going on today when you're seeing
people become more of like,
a lot of men are gravitating towards
being more feminine.
And then you hear the phrases like toxic
masculinity,
like phrases that we never heard.
We were young that almost like
denigrates the concept of masculinity
and some sort of a weird abstract way.
But I think it's because we realize,
hey,
we don't need to fuck as much anymore.
We don't need to go to war as much
anymore.
Like,
like we're,
we're progressing into some sort of a
digital universe that we're moving into
and it's not going her car,
so much chimp meat,
you know,
so much chaos in blood.
So I as a culture,
people were sort of moving away.
That's why when something like the UFC
comes around or,
or heavy metal or something,
like something just openly aggressive,
like guys like you or I will go,
yeah,
let me be me.
Then me being me.
Oh my God,
I've trying to drag me to the future.
That should be politics.
That should be,
I would see that as politics one day.
Some guy who was in the room,
you want to be the governor,
guess he's in the ring summit.
There was a fucking photo that I took
off of a twitter today.
I think somebody put it up,
I'll find out who put it up.
Um,
but it was a,
just a little sign that was outside
someplace in Texas that said,
uh,
instead of having a president,
why don't we just all agree really hard
to be cool.
And uh,
and I saw that.
I was like,
what?
That's so that's so fucking simple,
but isn't that going to be what it is
one day?
Like isn't it kind of moving into that
sort of a direction?
Isn't that what going to be one day?
I hope so.
Just everybody be cool.
Just relax.
I think that's what's we're,
we're moving away from all of the
fucking,
the weird base physical needs that we
constantly have to feed.
Right.
Moving away from those.
But don't you think whoever is aware of
that anticipates that
and they're already counteract during
you mean though?
Like the powers that be the pal is that
became the the evil cabal
and an old room.
Know what I mean?
Books,
leather bound books in the wall.
If you have a leather bound book,
you're an asshole.
How about that?
And if you're one of those guys with a
bunch of books behind you,
Polish tradition in gold,
fleeting pleading,
I don't think they can manipulate it
nearly as much as we think they can.
I think they definitely manipulate the
things they can and I think this world
has gotten so out of hand that it's on
its own.
It's working on some kind of crazy
instinctual momentum towards progress.
I think those old dudes for sure killed
Kennedy for sure.
I've seen the arguments for,
I've seen the arguments against somebody
killed Kennedy and it wasn't just Lee
Harvey Oswald to,
everybody's got this either or thing.
You know [inaudible] Harvey Oswald acted
alone?
I don't think so.
I think he's definitely was in on it
though.
I think there's a gang of people in on
it.
I think he was one of the people that
was in on it.
It's highly likely that Lee Harvey
Oswald was out of his fucking mind.
Crazy asshole working for the government
doing some weird shit and Russia comes
back over here.
Mary's a Russian lady.
There's all sorts of wackiness to it,
but when,
okay,
good opposite.
I'm just rambling,
but what is all that
that that was back in the 60s that's
what is all that manipulation.
So I'm going to [inaudible] and they
were trying to figure out how to retain
control.
Kennedy wanted to break up better
reserve.
Oh,
a bunch of people.
First of all,
he wanted to get rid of the CIA.
He wanted to get rid of the NSA.
He wanted to get rid of a bunch of
agencies.
Do the CIA or the NSA,
one of those.
He wanted to dissolve.
He wanted to get rid of the Internal
Revenue Service.
He wanted to get rid of the federal
bank.
Like Kennedy had some radical ideas.
He wanted to change a lot of things
about the way the world was.
And he also wanted posting and and mass.
Did you ever read,
no one ever hurt?
Did you ever hear the whole speech?
But then the,
the famous one he did.
It's always the end asked.
Not that thing,
but did you ever hear the whole speech?
I'm sure I did everything.
What you're saying he was a bad mother
fucker,
dude.
He was little.
He was saying like,
you know,
hey listen,
there's enough means we can all get
along.
Oh Geez.
Just really have a fucking hippie yet.
Did you ever hear the stuff that he said
about secret societies?
No,
dude,
play this cause this is from that stuff.
I know.
I'm not saying you can't know.
Look,
I've,
I believe her dope.
My friend Eddie Bravo,
who I love to death.
He loves every single one of them.
Every conspiracy that comes along,
he dives into it.
Fucking hook,
line,
sinker.
He loves them.
I love their funding and fund to fund
because he had the dads get my little
house in my little lawn and to Vince
foster.
Look it up.
Did you ever hear about that guy who is
running drugs through MENA,
Arkansas gay.
He's in then move.
Yeah.
They would trap and coke at a place.
It was barry seal's.
He's working for the CIA,
dropping coke out of planes and they
caught these kids,
found it.
They killed the kids.
Was that the game show guy?
No,
baby.
Oh yeah.
Chuck Barris.
Yeah.
Yes.
No,
Don buress is our friend.
It's not,
what was his name?
Did they make a movie about that guy?
Yeah.
Chuck Barris.
It was kind of like a,
uh,
like a fake movie,
but pretending that he was at a hitman
or something.
Yeah.
I fell asleep.
Watch at once.
It's one of those movies.
So you know,
I would get exhausted with this talk is
to be really,
really
paranoid.
Hey,
let's listen to the heroin.
I just did you go?
What do you do about all that?
Good,
longer speech.
Good.
Perfect.
The shorter version won't want to hear.
I know.
It's exhausting,
dude.
This'll get off the shit out of you.
Ladies and gentlemen,
the very word secrecy is repugnant in a
free and open society and we are as a
people inherently and historically
opposed to secret societies to secret
oaths and a secret proceedings.
We decided long ago that the dangers,
excessive and unwarranted concealment of
pertinent facts far outweigh the dangers
which are cited to justify it.
Even today,
there is little value in opposing the
threat of a closed society by imitating
its arbitrary restrictions.
Even today,
there is little value in ensuring the
survival of our nation if our traditions
do not survive with it and there is very
grave danger that an announced need for
increased security will be seized upon
by those anxious to expand its meaning
to the very limits of official census
ship and concealment that I do not
intend to permit to the extent that it's
in my control and no official of my
administration,
whether his rank is high or low,
civilian or military should interpret my
words.
He had a night as an excuse to sense of
the news,
to stifle dissent,
to cover up our mistakes or to withhold
from the press and the public the facts
they deserve to know for we are opposed
around the world by a monolithic and
ruthless conspiracy that relies
primarily on Kubot means for expanding
its sphere of influence on infiltration
instead of invasion on severity one
instead of elections on intimidation
instead of free choice on guerrillas by
night instead of armies by day.
It is a system which has conscripted
vast human and material resources into
the building of a tightly knit,
highly efficient machine that combines
military,
diplomatic intelligence,
economic,
scientific
and politically was about a
motherfucker.
We could just listen to that whole
speech and just bail on this podcast.
But
what does everyone give the trophy to?
What does it say on every poster?
What does he most famous for?
Not that's all they took was that last
end of the speech.
You said ask not what your country,
you didn't who remain,
who that all should have been on it.
So that is also a part of the same
speech is that same spectrum,
same garden
that I can,
I'm not going to act like I'm a
historian here.
It is the same guy who said that and you
never hear that.
Spend some shows here.
The other part can be never heard that
said that.
You know,
that's the sickest speech I've ever
heard by any president ever.
Then again,
I don't listen to anything.
I'm a two minutes in,
I'm out.
Well it's hard to listen to them because
you know it's horseshit.
It's horse shit.
And they all talk like presidents,
you know what I'm saying?
Like they don't just talk to you,
they'll talk to you in this.
Like there's a,
there's like a pattern there.
They're locked into that.
You can't read
when someone talks to you as if you were
a person in the audience.
You know what I mean?
Like there's a pattern and the way he's
talking,
they don't reveal much about their
actual motions.
They put on a mask you put on,
when you do a speech,
like a pelt politician,
you're putting on a verbal mask and
you're not allowing people to see much
of you.
That's why when we see a little bit,
you know like when Hillary Clinton's
shrieks and people like why,
why is everybody concentrating on it?
Because you're getting to see a little
bit of her.
We,
you see a little bit of her through the
mask,
right?
She's got this two inch thick political
mask that she's put coats of paint that
have now hit two inches thick from all
the years of doing this.
So when you hear a shriek,
it's no different than if you watch a
third grader and a play.
Right.
When those kids come out,
it's the same monotone.
Uh,
yeah,
that they don't know their lives.
They don't care about their lines.
When I,
when I watched the politicians talk,
it's no different or paint.
It's more fucking painful to watch that.
Then my third graders,
horrifying play every single year they
do well.
That's one of the things that bummed me
out the most about Obama.
When I first saw him,
when he was first in office,
when he was first running for president,
I was like,
this guy is going to be like a new
Kennedy.
Like this guy's going to be like this
guy who changes everything with the way
he talks and the policies that he
creates.
He's a young articulate,
I mean he's essentially close to our
age.
He's like three years older than us.
He's,
he grew up in our age,
grew up in our era.
But don't you think
he's putting that situation somewhere
along the line to like,
listen,
yeah.
Nice.
You get to have a nice little run here.
But there's some other rules you need to
abide by.
You understand?
I can I say that with southern accent
southern as you know,
I pitch southern.
It just,
it sounded scary but meaner and it
scares me more if a northerner gives me
a threat.
Uh,
for some reason southern or scares me
more cause I really,
it's more medicine that,
you know,
it was a burt reynolds movie.
Which one?
The fuck was that movie.
And then when the swamp as first movie
deliverance,
deliverance squeal like a pig.
Remember that scary fuck traumatized.
That was our,
when people grew up in the east coast or
the in the northeast,
when you're in,
you heard those movies,
you saw those movies around there.
That was like our introduction to look
scary southern people.
Oh,
so what do you think Obama,
would you want Obama come on dude.
I thought I was,
I thought it,
I was looking at the future.
I thought it was looking at someone who
was going to change everything.
I thought,
I'm like,
here's this guy who's like everything we
always wanted.
He was a Bush was like this guy who was
almost anti intellectual in a way.
It seemed like he would take these like
real shortcuts to the way he thought and
the way he expressed himself.
Real obvious shortcuts.
It wasn't,
he didn't express himself in a way where
he was trying to get really intelligent
people to say,
okay,
this guy is well thought out when he was
doing was he was expressing himself in a
way where he was trying to get like
really dumb people to think he's one of
them.
And there's two different kinds of
people.
You know,
there's,
there's someone like Obama when he was
running for office.
Well,
here's a good,
here's a good example,
Ron Paul's great example,
right?
Ron Paul is obviously very intelligent
and he speaks to both the intelligent
people and talk to the people that might
not understand all the concepts that
he's discussing when it comes to big
government or intervention and foreign
policy intervention intervening in a
foreign countries.
When he does it,
it's like very clear and concise and
particularly well chosen words.
So Obama was that guy like to me it's
like Obama was like the opposite of the
guy who was appealing to her dumb
people.
Obama,
you know,
he's appealing towards Obama was
appealing towards youth and hope,
you know,
hope and change was like the big part of
the uh,
well all these years later,
what's,
what's really changed that much joe?
Just think about this though.
Okay.
All right.
You get to that part.
I get it.
I'm with you 1000%,
but,
but the realistic,
like a realistic view,
don't you think?
Where you look at every great hero and
there's that fear of death.
Like,
oh,
I like salmon.
These concepts.
You talking about the key kids.
Nice kids look real nice over there.
So he wanted to change.
It's awesome.
Um,
let me show you a little video of Mr
Kennedy's last guy had that big dump
fucking speech to remember John Lennon.
Wasn't he cute?
Huh?
Do you think they killed?
Imagine all they send Dad Wacko.
Oh,
I fucking Wacko.
She son of a bitch.
But isn't it more likely that people are
obsessed with John Lennon?
Because these ladies are amazing
artists.
Could be like that little girl that got
shot in Florida last week.
Horrifying.
But do you think that she was a part of
the Illuminati?
Was there like some sort of a plan to
stop her and her,
her message of freedom or was it just
crazy?
No.
Anything.
If it wasn't in love with her,
just a young girl was the singer I went
for what I'm saying?
Yeah,
most likely it could be crazy.
Fuck.
I know that a lot of crazy fucks.
I'm just saying I th I think everyone
wanted that from any politician.
Right.
But the mid,
that politician,
you can't,
you,
you can't denied it.
The first guy to actually has free reign
and he faked everyone out and he got to
that point.
It's gotta be nearly impossible to go
listen if they shut off the phone,
if they shut all communication down
right now it's cause they don't like
what I'm saying.
Boom.
Until you have that brutal honesty.
Could you imagine going to happen?
Hero man,
what'd he gets out of office and tells
everybody exact what the fuck happened.
Did he say that when he was president?
Because it would kill us kids.
Yeah.
Oh,
no one's very sick.
This is terrible.
The government,
they're watching,
they're listening to everything we say.
The NSA,
they recorded.
Isn't that really funny?
They're blower watching me.
Yeah.
What are you gonna do different?
Really?
Board watch me.
Here he goes again.
Another fucking speech.
She was 17 year olds.
This another thing,
people think that there's this like
gigantic conspiracy to watch over
everybody.
And I'm going to bring up the,
uh,
the guy who broke into the White House.
You know,
the story broke in the White House and
no guy broke in the White House,
got arrested a couple months before.
You know,
the only two people have ever broken
into why not?
I do remember this one was from like
1912.
A guy broke in.
They tackle them quick.
This one was from a year and a half ago
and the guy who broke in,
he got arrested,
I think it was in an in September,
but he got,
he got pulled over in July with four
rifles,
two handguns and a fucking machete in
his car plus a map of Washington with an
x where the fucking White House is.
So he gets pulled over with that two
months before he winds up breaking into
the White House.
Like this is how poorly they're watching
us.
Like this idea that there's this a bunch
of evil geniuses that are watching 300
million people's every moves.
It's ridiculous.
They can't watch anything.
There's not enough people.
And the people that are watching,
they don't give a fuck.
They want to go home.
Right.
The guy broke into the White House and
one of the things that he was doing,
he ran across the lawn and the guy who
was supposed to be watching the dogs
took his earpiece out cause he was
talking to his girlfriend on cell phone.
Wow.
He had a second radio.
They keep it back up.
Right.
Oh he forgot that in his locker.
This is the kind of people that are
guarding the world.
So like this idea that there's like
these super geniuses that are in control
of every move and they hired a hit man
and hypnotized him.
Manchurian candidate style.
No are you?
I was talking to my girlfriend hard.
It would be to talk someone into killing
someone for you and then getting shot
and killed himself or getting locked up
in jail for the rest of her life to how
fucking hard.
That would be really hard.
It would be almost impossible to count
on that kind of pulling it off to like,
cause you would have to get someone
who's probably never killed somebody
before and that's going to be their
first killing.
You're going to go kill John Lennon and
then get locked up in jail for the rest
of the life.
You convince this guy's going to do
this.
Like how are you going to get this guy
to do this?
Most of them are going to fuck it up.
Like how we're all the fuck ups,
you know?
How come,
how come a bunch of people haven't
fucked up and missed and not pulled it
off?
Now they're always successful because
there are just fucking crazy people.
They're just fucking crazy people.
I agree for all those ones that we think
there's some grand conspiracy,
it's much more likely that people
retarded way more could be,
but there's a few fucking real ones like
that Kennedy speech where he must,
didn't know he was in deep.
He must have known,
he knew about Scotland bones and all
those crazy little fraternities and
those guys belong to where they fuck
each other and take polaroids and
blackmail each other for the rest of
their lives.
If we don't go to war with Libya,
certain cache of photos won't be
released to the press,
you know?
Right.
It's really that simple.
It probably probably compromise them
when they're young in some sort of a
weird way and get them to do gay stuff
probably.
Right.
I mean,
look,
I have no clue if you're running,
Huh?
If she were funded like one of those
Yale clubs.
Yeah.
That's the best way to shut them all up.
But what he it,
well,
of course.
Yeah.
It get some gay porn on them,
right?
Of course.
And it starts your religion,
16 millimeter and some dark dungeon in
Connecticut
this year,
right?
Charlie?
They got the fraternity logo on what's
the skull and bones logo look like?
So fucking cool.
Something death metal,
maybe even all the skull and bones shit
came out of the same pressure.
You know,
when you think of it then all those
rich,
rich guys that are rich fucking dads who
aren't paying attention to them and
they're going to boarding schools it.
Oh,
look at it.
Ooh,
you can't,
whatever you do,
don't make a t shirt with that on it
with your name on it.
People would be so upset.
So what is,
I don't even know what this is.
Is this cell phones?
I butcher.
It would be here too long.
I butcher it too.
It's,
it's a fraternity or a group that,
uh,
a lot of former presidents belonged to.
Like John Kerry belonged to it and
Bush and,
uh,
it's just a Yale fraternity,
like our club.
A secret club of many,
many people who wind up being leaders in
the free world.
Well,
yeah,
pull it up.
So I stopped butchering it,
but it's one of those things that people
point to when they look at evidence.
The 15 what does it say?
The 15 most powerful what members of
skull and bones,
the most famous secret society and
America,
skull and bones was cofounded Yale in
1832 by the father of a future
president.
And it's come to signify everything that
attracts and repulses the public about
and quotes the elite.
Rumor has it that Yale Junior class
members are tapped for membership each
fall by some measure of leadership,
influence and breeding among the
business titans,
poets,
politicians in three us,
presidents that are rumored to be
members.
We've picked out our honor roll poets.
What fucking poets and what they're
talking to other ass.
That's one of the things.
It sounds good.
Wow.
Look at this.
Look at the all the members.
William Howard Taft Clay class of 1878,
a former president,
uh,
Amos Alonzo stagg class of 1888 Yale's
greatest football player.
What did he do?
A bunch of uh,
sports stuff.
Okay.
Uh,
sports stuff back for black people
figured out sports.
I don't count those.
I really don't.
When you playing when Lebron James was
alive?
No.
You're barely playing basketball.
Okay.
William Avril Herrmann.
Look at this guy.
Future governor of New York,
a presidential candidate.
I see a bunch of people that we've never
fucking heard about,
but people that were governors and look
at that pres.
Prescott Bush.
Let's have that.
Pull that up.
Let me see if you thought w was a wild
man.
His college years,
you should have met his granddaddy
Prescott.
The future senator from Connecticut was
apparently a real cut up.
Who along with some other bones men is
believed to have dug up and absconded
with the skull of the legendary native
American Warrior Geronimo during World
War One.
Whoa.
He Stole Geronimo Skull.
That's pretty gangster.
Legend has it.
The journos head is still inside skull
and bones headquarters known as the tomb
at 64 high street in new haven.
By the way,
new haven is a shit.
No offense to anybody who is in new
haven.
Is it better?
No,
it's not.
it's a bounce back cause the gentrified
yet they used to be a comedy club there.
I remember that place.
Joker's wild.
I don't remember it lot.
Was it in a fun hotel?
No.
It was just a comedy club there.
Yeah.
Wild dude owned it.
Crazy guy.
Saw Him beat a guy up with a shoe.
Yeah.
Some guy was talking shit,
I forgot what,
what happened?
What have,
I forget what caused the fight cause I
was on stage and uh,
he pulled his shoe off and hit the
fucking guy in the head with the wooden
part of his shoe.
His heel of a shoe.
Yeah.
So I don't know what the guy did to him.
The guy must have hit him or something,
but he was a wild man.
But that whole area was like super
sketchy.
Like drive it around to the club.
Dark and creepy.
It was lit.
It was,
it was borderline like sketchy.
Yeah.
It's weird that skull and bones is
there.
I don't know.
He's scared.
No,
not scared.
Let's kill the shit out me man.
With Prescott Bush character and it
scares you.
It scares.
It's Darth Vader,
Dun Dun Duh Dun Dun Dun Dun.
You know what's interesting?
They talked us into believing that
George Bush was from Texas.
Okay.
Where is he from?
Connecticut.
How about the Maine and Connecticut?
His Dad was from a Zad from Maine,
right?
Didn't they grow up in Maine?
Pretty sure,
right?
They're both on this list.
I was just trying to see if it says no.
There's a gang of uh,
people on that list at why not being
present.
It's just stop and think about how crazy
that is.
But she'd be,
be a little wound up being president
there was getting this vote.
Yeah.
Well the phone you get to vote.
Do you think that maybe they hired
Donald Trump to just act like a total
complete shit head?
Because they knew there were so many
Republicans that are shitheads they
could just get them to the,
to the podium and then he would crumble
under the weight of Hillary Clinton.
It's the greatest professional wrestling
act ever,
ever.
Really is
going to build walls.
How many shows have we sold
the extra,
extra,
extra large as a flying off the shelves.
The wall just got 10 foot bigger.
That's what I said.
That's what I told him.
He's a,
his deliveries,
very pro wrestling,
his delivery,
super pro wrestling.
He's professional.
Fuck it.
It's brilliant.
Teach what's washed the part where he
says the wall just got 10 feet bigger
because it is a guy in a movie.
What do you want to make America great
said.
They will not under any circumstance.
I said the wall just got 10 feet higher.
Look at that guy behind him.
Pause for a second,
pause for a second.
Then
that guy behind him,
that's silly man.
Right to whistling.
Look,
we're looking at him on the left.
That guy,
the guy right over his right shoulder.
Okay,
that guy.
See that guy?
That guy is a problem because guys like
that,
they're not supposed to make it this
far.
They're supposed to be eaten by wolves a
long time ago.
They're supposed to be like that guy
that keeps surviving and game of
thrones.
It's with the wildling lady with the
buddy.
That guy is more bad ass.
He keeps figuring out a way to survive.
But this guy,
there's,
there was a Duncan trussell podcast he
did receive recently with Tim.
Hi Decker and Tim.
Hi Decker,
who was from Tim and Eric.
Hilarious,
amazing guy.
He nailed it.
And one of the things that he said that
just really resonated in my head,
he's,
he said there's always been this desire
that people have to identify with the
strong man and two to give in to submit
to the strong man and that that's what
he is.
He's the strong,
super confident man and that guy over
his shoulder is the kind of guy that
looks like,
you know,
probably probably a nice guy.
I probably sweetheart maybe eat a little
more than he should and it doesn't go to
the gym when he should and you know,
the alarm clock goes off.
It's hard for him to get motivated.
So he's just not,
he doesn't have a lot of get up and go
and he looks at this fucking trump guy
with his orange skin and it's crazy
hair,
makeup,
hair like a,
like a Kennedy.
Could you imagine given that due to pot
cookie and a mirror and go,
hey bro,
what's going on up here?
What is this?
What's going on?
What are you doing?
This is,
this is madness.
Like you're better off having bald spots
than that.
If you have,
you know,
you just go like short trimmed hair with
some bald spots.
Like just that's way more gangster than
what you're doing.
Like what you're doing.
It's kind of crazy.
Like no ones that doesn't know insane
hair does not look like that.
It just doesn't look like that in the
wild.
And
like what you've done is you've used
some sort of chemicals to concoct
something like you've concocted this,
this resemblance of what your hair used
to look like and his face.
Is it really that?
Is that the lighting or is that orange
or is it really that red and orange?
They do him up that he's got some people
to do him up and the kind of people that
do him up or probably like the kind of
people that really like him and they
kind of like some orange skin,
they want to fight both.
It's war paint.
They want to fight.
It's white people.
Warpaint
well why doesn't he do the under eyes?
Like if you're going to do your whole,
your face like that.
Do you think he wears like giant goggles
when he gets in a tanning booth?
Is that what's going on?
Like why is this
is just white.
Surely he knows what he looks like.
Right?
But then,
but then you look at his hair and you
go,
well why is he doing that?
Then you know,
why isn't he just Jason stayed it.
He just tapped into,
he just watched Fox News and just sweat.
Okay these guys,
these guys need a hero.
I think he's just got an extraordinary
sense of confidence in some weird way.
People are attracted to confidence.
Yeah.
Well that's what high decker was saying.
Hi Decker was saying that this desire to
submit to the strong man is like,
what's going on here?
And I'm like,
God bet.
That's right.
I bet that's a lot of it because we've
been talking about these guys,
that campaign for him,
like how excited they are.
I didn't know if it was,
I don't follow politics at all.
So I apologize.
Marine papers as turned off a while ago,
but just from sitting back and watching,
he's the only guy and I don't know if it
was planned that way or like I said,
it's professional wrestling.
Like here's what's going to happen.
You're going to go here.
Then you're going to bow.
Oh,
why do I have to flip into this fucking
20 visits?
You're going to buy out the polls.
Love them.
That's stopping.
I'll put you back in a fucking office
where I'm just saying he's pissed now.
He's been in government 15 fucking
years.
It cause he would go up on this podium
and the only thing what people responded
to,
he would call people out and people
loved that.
They already give that to you.
24 seven shows like Kardashians and all.
It's so twitter,
every insult,
insult.
That's the new fucking little guys
power.
He gets up there.
He insults people.
I'm calling you out.
CBS.
He does.
Whenever you know it,
they're like,
I've never seen anyways.
He's not empowered.
How it working?
It's fucking brilliant.
Keep them all yellow
script.
It's fucking lives go what's going on?
They're jamming
too far out.
No,
you're perfect.
Yeah,
you've got
it nailed.
I mean,
not that,
that is a guy who's a manager in a pro
wrestling show.
That's the manager.
That's like,
if he was like representing Bruno San
Martino and he's leaning them towards
this,
the squared circle,
he'd be like,
yes,
yes.
This is hall Colgan's manager Donald
Trump.
This is what he's going to do.
If he loses and Hillary wins,
he's going to manage Hulk Hogan and the
whole is going to have to go back to wwe
is going to make a comeback because he
to Gawker is not going to pay him.
And so,
uh,
he spent all the Gawker money and that's
gonna be,
that's gonna be the plot.
He spent all that Gawker money cause he
thought,
I thought we lived in a country that
abide by the rules.
I thought when you go to court or you
lose,
you pay up.
So I bought a house in Florida.
I really liked this house.
I don't want to lose it.
So finch and I came to an arrangement.
I come back here and kick you are candy
ass president.
W W was what are the disease?
The president of wwe.
His ass.
Yeah.
I mean Vince Mcmahon and hall Cogan.
They have a match.
Cause Vince always wanted to have a
match with Hulk Hogan and they go at it
and he makes $50 trillion.
Oh look at that.
Donald Trump and vince mcmahon.
It's already happened.
He was on it a couple of years ago.
They shaved.
I think he's telling you he shaved his
head.
Shaved Vince's head.
Oh good Lord.
Let's look at this.
This is hilarious.
What a good show.
Vince is.
A smart man will tell you that.
Brilliant guys making a lot of money.
Why didn't he run for president?
He'd when he would,
when he'd fucking win.
How scary is that?
If Donald Loses,
he might win.
Dude,
it doesn't scare you that that many
people,
there's people that still believe in big
foot.
Wait a minute.
Back host,
and I had bobcat Goldthwait and here a
couple of weeks ago arguing that big
foot footage was real.
No,
you didn't.
Bobcat is a big foot believer at,
first of all,
he's going to waste.
I see it.
Yeah.
No,
no,
no.
For Real.
He's got a movie.
He's got this movie called Willow Creek.
It's really good.
It's not a,
it's not a comedy.
It's a horror movie about big foot.
It's like Blair witch,
so he doesn't believe it's rewritten.
Believes it's real.
And he went to the big foot conference.
You still sell that?
Nope.
No.
I know bobcat.
He really believes it's real.
He know only to,
he believes that that video,
that Patterson footage of the fucking
deal in my suit.
Yup.
That one.
Yep.
It takes,
that's real hundred percent yes he does.
Is he does.
I know.
It seems crazy,
right?
I think he was playing,
you know,
a lot of people do.
Every time we talk about this,
I get fucking hate tweets from big foot
lovers,
just big foot lovers.
Oh,
big,
big for love it.
If he was just fans on TV,
this famous big foot.
And I love the ghost that they're always
fine.
They're all trump supporters.
It's weird.
Right?
But no for real.
Bob Cat really is a big foot believer.
Wow.
That's odd to me.
I don't see him as really thinking that
way.
Well,
I don't know what it is.
My used do it my mom.
That's how I realize my mom was a little
dopey cause as a kid not being serious,
they've lost the bigfoot show and I'm
thinking as a little kid I believed it.
They would interview literally people on
a rock like a hippy and it's like,
yeah,
he was just hanging out and he was kind
of in his head and my mom go ice,
believe it.
My father is gone.
She,
Jesus Christ.
There probably was something at one
point until there was,
well,
there was definitely an animal called
gigantic [inaudible].
You know about that?
No.
What is it?
Oh,
Jim Brewer.
What does it all up?
The photo of John Carroll Pythius next
to a human being.
It was a huge bipedal hominid that they
found bones of in Asia.
In the 1920s there was an apothecary
shop and China and an anthropologist was
in there and it was studying some of the
teeth that they had any recognize this
enormous teeth tooth to be a primary
tooth of unknown origin.
He's like,
this is way too large to be a gorilla.
Like what is this?
And where'd you get it?
So the people brought him to this
apothecary shop.
There's a photo of a recreation of a
gigantic Pacific is next to a guy,
the orangutan?
No,
no,
no.
There's a,
just go back to the images.
Please go back to images.
Scroll down,
you'll,
you'll definitely find it.
It's gigantic.
Pithy gets next to a person.
Can,
I just shows you in scale.
But it was a,
so they found bones.
Okay.
And they found lower job bones that
would indicate it was a bipedal ape.
Okay.
So I guess it's the position of the jaw
is different.
If you're on all fours,
then if you stand up so that,
that's it right there.
All right.
So this thing lived as recently as a
hundred thousand years ago,
and maybe more soon.
But this is like,
they didn't even know about it until
1920 when they got these bones.
So in 1920 they had those bones and they
had them once carbon dating was
invented,
they dated those bones to a hundred
thousand years ago.
So that was a real animal.
Can I just tell you,
if you,
you need to change the whole edge.
I would go to school every day.
If this was school
as a kid,
like learned about big foot and we know
we went
everywhere we went today we just sat
there like,
dude,
fucking bad that I'm not coming up going
back to school tomorrow.
Ah,
well there's cool shit to learn man.
This is cool shit.
Like this is cool.
Anthropology,
I'm not sure if I deny it though because
you have to.
You have a tid.
Listen,
that's a real animal.
Well that's a a hundred percent
confirmed animal.
That's a confirmed.
They just found it.
Who,
who founded archeologists,
they dug up and anthropologists,
they studied these bonuses.
We're getting $400,000 of shares and
funds.
If we don't find a goddamn tooth or
something,
we got to file out like Dag every
fucking place.
We can't Charlie.
And there's place.
I know PRC interest.
It's just another way to get money.
Yeah,
but they have the bone,
so you can go see the bones and other
anthropologists studying the bones.
The bones get the guys to white coat.
We approximately say that.
I would say estimated 13 myths,
13,000 possibly upside.
That's 130,000 years ago.
This thing roamed the US.
I can't have
putting it out in the real special one
time magazine and the,
what's it called?
What was the fucking monkey call?
Gigantic Shark.
Good to pick a pickup and a stress
discolored.
Read all about it and pay $10 you don't
mother fuckers,
but why is it any weirder than a gorilla
grill?
I can see,
and we physically can see it.
That's almost not,
you know,
they didn't even know mountain gorillas
existed until the 20th century because
white people never went that way.
Yeah,
exactly.
And when they first got photos of
mountain gorillas,
they were like,
what in the fuck?
Yeah,
no,
these are real 1920s yeah.
Find out when they found,
when they first discovered the mountain
gorilla,
I want to say it was the early 19
hundreds and uh,
you know,
that's an animal that we just take for
granted is definitely being real.
This is a lot of those gym.
There's a lot of those.
This is a guy who's been dedicated his
entire life to trying to find a giant
sloths in the Amazon.
This guy is convinced that the giant
sloths in the Amazon still live mountain
girl was first discovered by a German
officer in 1902 nine two oh two captain
Robert Vaughn Beringia.
Prior to this time,
only lowland gorillas were known to
exist.
The mountain gorillas subspecies is
derived from the captain Robert Vaughn
bearings.
Last name gorilla bearing g Barend.
Gee,
what does that gorilla Bringi Bringi.
That's his name.
Robert Vaughn.
Prng what?
Why they have to have it twice.
Gorilla Benji,
Benji,
what's around in 1902 like what's going
on?
Not a lot.
Photos are only 40 years old thinking
that before that they were drawing shit.
That's,
that's how crazy that is.
Like sticks.
Yeah.
And drawing and well,
I mean painting.
I mean,
you know Michelangelo and all that,
all that's trip was before that.
But that was how you got images back
then.
You had to paint them when we don't,
we don't really,
we take photographs for granted so much.
We don't realize that the photograph was
invented in the 18 hundreds.
I mean that's not that long ago.
All right.
Now why was this guy even think about
this?
18 hundreds you didn't really have great
shoot.
Why,
why are you just going up in an area?
Why theirs?
Cause he's nowhere near from Africa
where it was the guy,
well there was a lot of explorers back
there in Africa because they had found
it and they started to colonize certain
aspects of,
of Africa,
like the colonized South Africa,
which is why they all use a nice word
for it.
Slaving.
Yeah.
Dutch.
The Dutch came to Africa and uh,
they enslaved people and they made these
settlements and they tried to make
settlements in the Congo itself.
But the jungle just
swallowed everything.
Always.
They would make,
they would spend all this money and have
boats go down there and they built these
beautiful mansions in the Congo,
but the Congo always ate it up.
It's just too wild.
They just couldn't,
they couldn't tame the Congo.
They thought they were going to go there
and,
and figured out how to tame that thing.
Teach them all about,
uh,
Noah's Ark and things like that and
their abcs and they just couldn't
survive.
Six months.
You can survive in the jungle itself.
Like the jungle itself was just so
fucking wild.
There's no taming the Congo.
Like you would have to have like a full
scale Western invasion to tame the
Congo.
We would have to clear cut and start
chopping down giant swaths of the forest
and putting up malls and blowing coal
into the air and lighting everything on
fire.
And we still wouldn't win.
It's just too much of it.
It's too big.
She had been able to shows the Congo
gets all the shows.
No.
What's so shows where the true,
they throw you out there naked and
afraid.
They don't go to the Congo.
It's the one place that I haven't been
yet.
He ain't gonna make it.
We don't have enough insurance to cover
you in Congo.
Nagin and Fred means eaten.
You get eaten.
But can you imagine it's 1902 think of
everything.
You've seen your life at that moment,
right?
It's not a whole lot to see
and you're going up the mountains and
surely there was a tribe guy or
something that was like,
well,
it Booboo,
give him that little term like don't go
up there.
He didn't know what he was saying.
Finally,
go up there.
Imagine first time encountering a
gorilla.
Jesus.
You've never seen anything like that and
your life.
Is that a fucking huge,
what the fuck is that?
Yeah,
I've seen maybe a hippo.
Is that a hippa?
Like can you imagine just squaring off
and if that thing you ever see,
like when a gorilla charges
Jesus and that guy,
that guy,
I would have flipped out.
Yeah.
Imagine being in a time when there was
no photographs and visiting the jungle
in Africa and seeing all the wildlife.
Seeing a lion sees a fucking line and
what do you win that's going to protect
you from it.
A lot of guys had been eating who was
this shame?
That's supposedly the picture.
I was just reading a story about when
they found it.
This is like the,
his encounter.
The first one they shot.
I'm going up a volcano or something that
said,
wow,
man,
that they were tracking them and it took
them hours to even find it on a high and
a half the body by the time they got
some of it or something.
Whoa.
This is a picture shot.
The gorilla body by the time they got to
it.
Yeah.
Oh,
I'm not quitting.
They said they had shot two.
They killed to the shot too.
I'm not sure if how they killed it.
It didn't say it,
but they retrieved it by rope and they
found that it was about 200 pounds,
the one they found.
Dude,
Africa is still crazy.
Have you been there?
No,
I was going to go to Tanzania this
summer,
but I heard that you have to take all
kinds of crazy shots.
No,
no,
no.
You take a malaria shots.
Yeah.
I think he'd take two shots.
Yankee tickets?
Yeah.
Did you take your kids to Africa?
Did you?
Yeah.
Where'd you guys go with Tanzania?
Did you?
Yeah,
it was sick.
Was it?
Did you lose?
It's there.
You can follow.
You can follow a,
there's a tribe there that you can
follow for like two,
three days.
They take your hunting.
Yes.
It's Kronos.
It was a,
there was a part of her.
I got really spooked out because the guy
we were with who just has a spear,
he's just sitting there with a spear and
he said,
uh,
you know,
stay here,
stay here.
And he was going after some low animal.
It was just me and my daughter.
Like,
oh my God,
why do we do with an African?
Yes,
Jamie.
We'll think of that like,
here I am from Florida,
now I'm spear hunting with some African
dude and my kid.
What the fuck,
man?
It was weird,
but it was awesome.
It was really awesome.
You should go on it or shows your mind
now I should,
I have a friend who went there and he
was on a hunting trip and uh,
poachers were in the area and when they
see poachers,
they just start shooting anthem shooting
at the poachers to shooting at them.
And he's like,
you have to shoot them when you see them
because they will shoot you and they
will kill you.
And they were getting shot at by
poachers.
I'm like,
so you were in a gun fight poachers?
Yeah,
cause they want that Tusk,
they didn't kill anybody but Simon Tusk,
a lot of it is just meat.
It's like these people just starving to
death.
It's crazy like that.
Who's coming in to get all this ball?
All sorts of different various variables
that you got people that are poaching
for like Rhino Horn,
ivory tusks and stuff like that.
That's all you really hear about.
But then you got people that are
poaching just for meat.
They go on someone's private land and
they kill the animals and they call them
a poacher.
What they really are.
It's just fucking poor people.
That's it.
So anyway,
wow.
These people,
you know,
sometimes the poachers were shooted them
and they shoot at the poachers and so
when they're asking,
I'm like,
what do you do if you shoot one of
these?
And he goes,
most of the time we let the Hyena sorted
out.
Wow.
Let the hyenas sorted out.
Like Cue,
I'm managing your shooting people and
just leaving them for [inaudible] is to
eat.
You've got human eating hyenas in your
backyard essentially,
and you're watching it
and that's,
and you're accustomed to it now.
They must have seen it at least once,
right?
Yes.
It must have come upon a guy that they
just shot,
checked on the body and seeing the high
end is tearing it apart with that noise.
Ooh,
they're the creeps.
The green there,
the creepiest,
they're so weird.
So weird looking with their big back
legs or the big front legs and shorter
back legs.
They look there there.
They're mysteriously dark.
They're all lopsided.
They're not like flat.
You know,
like a dog is flat,
right?
Hyenas or like like a ramp.
Yeah.
They go,
they slope down this slope downward.
Really big jaw.
Oh,
look at that fucking thing.
Look at the size of the God hyena
industry and some interesting facts.
Oh,
history.
Look at the,
go back to that picture again.
Please look at the fucking mouth on that
then.
And they don't fear law.
They'll go after lions to look at the
teeth on that thing.
That's insane.
That doesn't even look real.
Like if that was in a movie,
you'd be like,
fuck,
I'm glad that's not real.
Africa's is so gangster.
That's,
that's the real deal.
Yeah.
You know what's weird is like,
that is where life started and where
life started.
It's where it's the most ferocious.
Think about all the different animals
that we did.
You know,
that there was a lot of animals like
this that lived in North America.
And there was a Hyena that was like a
fast running Hyena,
a type of Hyena here in North America.
This guy named Dan Flores.
He's got this book on the,
uh,
American Serengeti and he was on my
buddy Steven Ellis podcast talking about
it.
He's a wildlife,
a historian,
a nature of the story.
And uh,
he was talking about how crazy the
animals were in North America,
just,
you know,
a hundred thousand years ago,
they don't even know what,
what,
what caused the mass extinction.
But there was a bunch of crap.
They had a lion here,
there was bigger than the African lion.
It's called a step line.
So is this from the divide?
Because I'd even realize that too,
until I was good.
The content and the bering strait.
Yeah.
But there was also like just mass
extinctions here for some strange
reason.
And they really don't know.
They don't know.
No,
you don't.
Horses like native Americans didn't have
horses.
The Europeans brought the horses to the
native amount.
I didn't do that.
Yeah.
But here's where it gets really crazy.
Horse has evolved in North America.
Horses evolved in North America and went
extinct and the only horses had survived
with the horses that had been captured
or had gone across the bering strait and
made it into Asia.
Those are the horses that survive.
So then when like Arabian stallions and
shit came back from there into North
America again,
they had literally originally evolved in
North America.
All the canines evolved in North
America,
like wolves,
Hyenas,
uh,
or um,
um,
what of those dingoes all those things
originally came from North America.
Coyotes,
maybe not dingoes is that an Australian?
It's a strain.
But do you think they brought them on as
part of something?
They brought a lot of shit over to
Australia.
Australia is filled with animals that
don't belong there and they don't belong
anywhere else.
No,
they're all bald is a lot of,
well there's like kangaroos which are
only there.
His real hair.
It's panda bear,
Panda bear.
One of the heads.
A better the Free Koala bears.
Oh,
Koala bear.
Koala bear got some weird shit man.
But um,
they also have like,
they have a ridiculous amount of animals
live in there.
And then they brought in cats to kill
some of the animals and then the cats
got out of control and now they have a
feral cat problem.
They also have,
you know,
it scares me.
I will never have too many things you
can eat and kill you.
Oh,
I think more than Africa.
You can't swim in the ocean and they get
the saltwater crocs.
Oh,
the saltwater crocs
and the worst outcome.
Shark attacks South South Africa in
Australia have like the worst shark
attacks.
Snakes,
they get the worst snakes,
bugs,
spiders,
all kinds of spiders.
It'll fade house them.
But the people are cool as fuck.
Yeah.
Australian people are some of the
coolest fucking people you'll ever meet.
I'm a big fan.
Big Fan of Australian people.
If you had a move,
is that where you'd go?
Well that's a good spot to move because
it's on the other side of the world.
So if we blow this thing up and we need
somebody with a greenhouse and Sydney,
that's the move.
Because if,
if,
if we don't make it,
if America doesn't make it,
like save yellowstone blows.
If don't blows up,
kills everybody in the continent.
You got to have to go somewhere where
the transition would not be that that
difficult.
And Australia I think is the furthest
away with a transition would be easy.
What if it got too crazy and it was way
too many people in Australia,
they leave.
We're like,
you can't.
We were cutting the border.
It's say do that,
you know in Australia.
That's one of the reasons why Australia
so awesome when a bunch of immigrants
show up in a boat then like not so fast
fuck face.
They turn them around and they sent it
to some shitty island.
We got home real was here and to make
him eat bugs.
Yeah,
it's not good.
It's not good.
I'm not kidding man.
They're brutal.
They're,
they're like,
they're anti immigration policy is like
widely criticized,
but it's one of the reasons why
apparently it's a,
it's,
so who was it that told us about that?
Josh has apps.
Was he the one,
the first one to tell us about that?
So some,
one of the guests who was from
Australia,
it was,
I believe it was josh was explaining how
crazy they are about stopping
immigration.
They just illegal immigration.
It's like a no,
no over there.
They just won't let it happen.
That wood,
that wood,
that's like a scene of a movie.
Something goes down here.
Yeah,
man.
These are people going down there and
then not letting you in.
Now there's,
sorry,
there's so many [inaudible] world,
but there's only 20 million people in
all of Australia or something like that.
I think Australia itself,
the whole continent of Australia has the
same amount of people is California.
Really?
Yup.
And it's as big as the United States.
You can't live on a lot.
Is there a lot of desert there?
Well,
you can't if you're a pussy.
What if you're fucking man,
just move out in the 23 million.
So it's probably less than California.
Yeah.
California is probably like 30 million.
If I had to guess how many people are in
California?
No official population,
it's probably gonna be a little under,
but easily that money.
Yeah.
They're not counting Mexicans either.
No.
Friends of my Mexican friends.
But listen,
I wouldn't have my fucking paperwork
either.
Fuck it.
38 million of Jesus Christ,
just calc.
And that's not even including illegal
aliens.
Right.
You know,
another fucking crazy thing.
Somebody brought this up somewhere
recently.
I forget who it was.
Maybe I read it somewhere.
Um,
they were talking about what percentage
of native Americans,
uh,
like in Ra in Mexico,
like Mexico has a lot of people that,
a percentage of their genes are native
American.
The same as the people that came from
Siberia,
but in Mexico.
Yeah,
yeah.
That I believe that genetic differences
between Mexicans and native Americans is
like very small.
Well,
there's a lot of times,
and I'm not to offend anyone,
I'm just being honest where I,
I can see that a lot.
No,
I couldn't tell.
Is that person Mexican or is that person
a native American?
I swear to God,
I just did the other day at Frickin
citywalk
trying to be racist and I wasn't sure
which way to go.
How do we culturally appropriate that's
a barrel or a feather
and I know it.
Yeah,
makes sense.
Yeah.
They all came down from Asia
along with all these fucking crazy
animals.
And this Guy Dan Flores is talking
about,
they had a single,
a short face bear.
Is that what it's called?
Jamie?
Short face bear is fucking enormous,
terrifying bear that they think was one
of the reasons why people didn't come to
North America sooner because there were
so dangerous.
There were huge like bigger than
grizzlies and super predatory and so
like when people were coming across the
bering strait there,
it's probably just getting picked off.
Oh look at that thing.
Oh look at it's giant and it's chasing
down a buffalo in this photo.
Some youtube videos.
Fuck yeah,
the Chrissy just chasing the moose down
the street.
Yeah.
It just takes him down and he's,
he's,
he knows he's going to get them loose.
Is half eaten,
still running?
Just looking back.
He's sick.
I'm going to catch up to you.
It's fricking,
it's horrifying.
It's scary,
but it's also real god,
these things still exist and can eat you
at any moment.
We still part of the wild and all we
are,
we've just made cities.
Here's one that's the one I'm talking
about chasing this buffalo giant ass
grizzlies chasing the buffalo.
He's half torn up already so big and say
that that buffalo got burned in some
sort of a volcanic fire or something
like that.
That was,
that was an already injured buffalo.
Look at him.
He's already had enough.
Oh God.
They're so terrifying.
Look at his mouth.
He's foaming is foaming.
Look,
he's got an air.
Oh,
he's in the air dude.
And he probably weighs 500 pounds and he
leased and he's booking it done street
shit.
He probably was more than 500 pounds.
That's a buffalo.
He's probably like six or 700 pounds.
What am I guessing?
What do you wait,
what am I fat shaming a bear.
Why might,
why don't care?
Anyways,
I'm obsessed with a number.
Did you see,
um,
I don't know if you're watching this.
I just watched it on the plane.
Uh,
what's the Leonardo Dicaprio one?
Where he gets told the revenant?
Yeah.
The,
did you see the scene?
Yeah,
the bear scene.
Yeah.
That's the first time I actually,
I don't know what you think of it,
but that's the first time where I saw
how quick that can ha they,
I thought they made it real how a bear
can just,
yeah,
within a second he's on,
he was over there so big and they move
so much faster than a person can.
We,
we,
we judge everything based on what we can
do.
Like we see an animal way like okay via
to run towards him right now.
How long would it take?
But the timeline that an animal can
close in on you versus what you can do
to them is so goddamn different.
Like you just don't understand how fast
they are.
Spat all my rage.
I am still just a rat cage where you
live in New Jersey.
New Jersey got a crazy bear problem.
They're overrun with bears in some
areas.
Um,
there's bears but they're black bears.
Yeah.
No one not as scary.
They get spooked out really easily.
They're scavengers.
They're just looking for garbage.
They don't care about you.
They are for the most part.
They definitely do term predatory though
when they get really hungry.
Some of them are predatory.
I know a guy who was camping with some
dude.
It was his first hunting trip and he got
attacked in his tent by a 500 pound
predatory black bear.
Huge hungry,
older black bear.
Just took a chance.
Went in the tent,
just try to Jack.
I'm in his tent.
His friends shot the bear,
shot through the bear and hit him in the
wrist.
So he wound up getting a broken wrist
from the,
from the rifle and they,
uh,
chase the bear out of the tent and shot
it in the woods.
Wow.
How about that for your first fucking
camping trip?
Totally.
No,
you're not going to see animals bears
here of these fine.
Most of the time nothing happens.
Most of the time they run away,
but they killed that kid at rutgers was
like a year and a half ago.
A kid,
uh,
who got eaten that rutgers.
Rutgers,
yeah.
He was outside of rug kid.
Kid from rutgers outside in the woods
and,
uh,
took a photo of the bay or right before
it ate them too.
They've got a photo of the very bare
that one up killing him.
Apparently they ran and they saw the
bear and they freaked out and ran when
they ran the bear chased them.
And uh,
one of them.
What can a bear,
was it black bear?
Black Bear?
You know,
they ate meritus hiker,
snap photo of bear before fatal attack
and West Milford.
That's the bear right there.
Yeah.
I mean if you,
if they have an opportunity to eat you,
then each year they eat each other.
I mean,
if you kill black bear and leave it
there,
the other one's lead it.
Wow.
That's scary.
And they're gangster.
That's near my house.
Well,
there's,
that's a real animal dude.
I mean,
you guys have a lot of them in New
Jersey and we saw him a couple of times
in the last two,
three years.
They would come up on my back deck and
tear down the a bird feeder.
Whoa.
Just right outside the,
it's,
and they're big creatures.
Yeah.
How big was the one you saw?
Um,
maybe like,
like a big dog.
No,
it's a little bigger than it is.
Bigger than a dog.
Like a couple hundred pounds.
Probably some 300.
That's a fucking big animal,
man.
Look at that.
Holy Shit.
Bear takes a dip and New Jersey's family
pool.
Yeah.
That's a big one too,
man.
God Damn.
That's a very big ass bear to find
swimming.
You're fucking pool my net.
Holy Shit.
The size of them.
Yeah.
See that's a mature old bear.
That doesn't give a fuck.
Right.
That's just so weird.
They live with people in New Jersey of
all places.
There's one,
there's two.
There's two wacky black ones.
There's um,
there's a good video in my nephew's
neighborhood where the two black bears
are going at it.
Oh,
far rockaway.
Yeah,
the one that we played that before.
And then there's one in Jersey that
walks on its hind legs.
Yeah.
Did you see that one?
Yeah,
it's big foot,
bro.
That's a big foot,
big foot video for you.
I think that's exactly what those were
saying.
Bears can do that apparently all the
time.
They can walk on their hind legs.
They just don't do it very often.
Look at that thing.
That's weird.
Yeah,
but he walks through the neighborhood
like that.
If you were like at dusk,
right?
Right.
And it was really dark out and you saw
that thing walking through buck glint of
moonlight,
you would swear it was a giant gorilla.
Yeah,
that's big foot.
I listen.
Yeah,
I know him before I joked at big foot,
but I saw him last night.
It's like a dead thing.
But for real,
like a black bear can easily get to be
seven feet.
Yeah.
So if,
if you got a seven foot black bear it
and you see it walking through the
woods,
or even a fucking six and a half foot
black bear when she get her pants.
Yeah,
you're going to swear it's way bigger
than it was just walking on his hind
legs.
Nobody ever underestimates or giant two
foot to walking on two legs.
Gorilla.
You don't underestimate the size of the
thing.
You overestimate it.
Right.
You know,
if it's six feet tall,
he's like,
he was fucking eight feet tall,
right?
Yeah.
Oh my God.
New Jersey is pretty rural.
People don't realize that.
They think of New Jersey as being like,
like were Tony Soprano loved or they
think it's Newark Airport.
Hoboken.
Yeah.
There's a lot of woods in Jersey.
And you also have the shore and the
Jersey Devil and Jersey Devil.
I've uh,
I might've heard of him.
I might've heard them.
What does it sound like?
Um,
it's a little bit like a screech owl.
Ooh.
Yeah.
Screech owl.
It could be,
that's a problem.
There it is.
This the devil.
It looks like a camel.
Fucked a dragon.
Now I will say this.
I will say this,
one night my wife and I were sleeping
and on the roof.
That was really did have,
it sounded like something landed on that
roof.
That was me,
bro.
Nah,
look at it.
It's got,
it's a goat with wings.
Is that the Jersey Devil call it is
that,
was that the photo?
Look at this.
See,
here's the thing,
right?
Jersey devil doesn't scare me as much as
the fucking alligator that pulls babies
out of a Disneyland and drags them into
the lagoon.
That's a real thing.
That's,
can you,
can you imagine a,
it just,
I've been in that with my kids.
I've been in that they need to have
signs.
I think they do.
It says don't go on the water.
It didn't say that's filled with
dinosaurs.
Didn't say this man eating dinosaurs in
there.
That's where I think the problem's going
to lie for them.
Where if you're from Florida,
I still live there.
We you have you heard about it all the
time.
Small dogs.
Two year old toddler.
I lived there too.
I lived in Gainesville between ages.
What,
what,
what year was it?
It was like the early seventies.
We lived there for like three years at a
you youngsville.
Yeah,
and uh,
round Lake Alice.
He'll look at that thing.
Yeah.
Oh,
they climb fences.
Now,
have you seen this?
This is so scary,
but I talked about this in the podcast
recently when I was a kid and we lived
there.
They were endangered and so you couldn't
hunt them.
Nobody hunted them.
And now they have so many of them that
they give out hunting tags.
Like for that swamp people show you ever
watch that show?
The kill alligators?
That guy had 500 tax.
He could kill $500 how many fucking
alligators do they have when you give
someone 500 tags?
Yeah,
it's crazy.
It's a real problem.
Then I would say,
so look at this guy.
He's climbing a fence.
Jesus Christ.
Look at that fucking thing.
I mean that is straight out of,
that's the Chinese hundred million years
ago.
Yeah,
that's a dinosaur.
I don't think they've changed in a
hundred million years or something crazy
like that.
There's some nutty number.
It's like 50 million,
something like that.
Like how long dinosaurs are a alligators
have been exactly the same.
You're just food.
Just food.
That's all you are.
I don't see,
I don't see your wife or kids.
I just see food.
It's not like you look at the baby deer
with the Mama dear and you go,
I can't shoot her.
She's got the baby.
You're about the splash about and
alligator that someone posted this video
of what?
What?
This alligator was like right next to a
splash mountain.
I'll pull up that way.
There's a worker in Disney.
Watch all,
Gosh,
I'll close the people get to it.
Let's call.
It was like,
wow,
I can get away with a stick.
Why like 2009 I think.
Oh,
how do you not just kill that thing?
You got to kill it.
Look,
it's,
it's little enough right now that you
can kill it.
That's a little baby alligator.
Get to it as well.
That's a small alligator,
right?
Oh No.
Loud right next to it.
He's right next to it.
Yeah,
look,
oh my God.
They just tolerate that kind of Shit in
Florida.
That seems like a really little
alligator by the way.
He's little,
but he could do a little damage.
Fuck that alligator up.
I'll tell you right now.
I will fuck that alligator up.
I'll grab it by its tail.
Now.
Bounces head right off that sidewalk
over and over again.
They'll turn it into a Dick Holster.
I'll make him cradled my balls
for the rest of time.
Look at this guy.
He's going to get a net and try to scoop
it up.
What does his asshole dude with a net,
you need a gun son scale like the end of
the pool skimmer.
Go get yourself a crossbow,
shoot that fucking thing.
Right.
And it's caveman brain.
Caveman brain.
Wow.
What's wrong with me?
That's a,
that's a lizard.
I mean that's a heartless,
thoughtless creature that exists to eat
things to say it's all does that coming
to this is more of now than they've ever
been before and this trend continues.
You got a real fucking problem because
when I was living there,
so I'm trying to figure out what year I
was born in 67 we lived in Florida until
I was a law.
No,
we lived in San Francisco from age seven
to 11 so I was 11 years old,
somewhere around then what year was
that?
What year?
[inaudible] 73 I'm way too stupid.
If it was 73 probably about five years
old.
Six,
seven years.
73 Oh six yeah.
So swimming on,
so somewhere around some,
we're talking somewhere around 1977
okay.
Okay.
So you like 10 to 12 these are kind of
prime ready to go.
So just think about this year,
1977 now think about 2016 so in 77
they're protected.
In 2016 you can kill 500 of them.
What the fuck is it going to be like 50
years from now?
What is it going to be like in 2066 you
had to be able to go anywhere near there
or is it just going to be some crazy
Congo type situation where every time
you get out of your car,
so I'm just trying to eat you and kill
you?
I think they're going to the Amera coble
under the guise of president trump,
president trump will guide us.
He lives in Florida.
I live in Florida.
We will kill them all.
We will have golf.
He likes golf,
right?
He's a golf guy.
Guys get golf courses and shitty
designs,
golf courses.
So he's not going to tolerate people
getting eaten by what if like Jack
Nicholas,
one of those older dudes was at an event
and something just debt,
big 15 foot of that.
They got on video the other day.
She says enough is enough and jumps out
and grabs him right by as polyester
pants right by the deck just right over
back front from where the eyes are,
the Dick side and then the bottom is on
the asshole side and just clamps him
right up the middle like a paper clip
and drags me the rights.
Flips him a couple times because it
doesn't give a fuck about CBS filming.
Some golf show doesn't give a fuck.
It's not going to not kill you because
this is a CBS Golf Day.
That's right.
Why?
The women are doing wonderful today.
Women golfers have really come a long
way.
Oh Jesus.
Alligator comes out,
eats a lesbian drags,
just drag it right into the water.
It doesn't give a fuck about your show.
It's going to 50 million year old brain.
This is three brain cells and they're
just trying to find things.
Things that can eat,
eat,
fuck,
take nap in water.
They found Nile crocodiles in Florida.
Yeah,
they found quite a few of them.
They have a shoot on sight thing for
Nile crocodiles now.
I said,
you see him?
You have to kill them because they're
already,
they've already found,
I believe they found four and uh,
it's,
they're definitely laying eggs.
They're definitely breeding.
And uh,
if they found four,
there could be hundreds.
Like they literally don't know how many
Nile crocodiles there are in Florida and
you're not going to radically cut them.
So you just have to do your best try to
curb the population.
It is like modern day Tarzan Shit.
Oh yeah.
Hi.
Drive to civilized ours just to people
fun.
The beginning.
Now we put the jumbo to them.
Why do you think it's a coincidence?
And it's all happening in Florida and
then the 10 Tony Montana,
cocaine cowboys,
all the coke,
all the pills.
Okay.
All the oxies Florida gave out more oxy
prescriptions and the rest of the
country combined.
Really?
Oh yeah.
All that Shit's going on there with
alligators and Nile crocodiles and
fucking vipers in people's yards.
All these crazy snakes and pythons and
people just add,
I don't want to take any of it anymore.
They throw it out there fucking back
door.
That's what they did in Florida,
right?
The pythons.
Yeah.
10 1520 I get huge and they eat people.
Oh yeah.
Fuck yeah.
The elite people lead everything.
You go to sleep.
That's another thing.
Just lives.
Eat and sizes you up makes its way
through your air ventilation system.
It's as fat as the pipe that your air
condition comes out.
Look at this Nile crocodile identified
in south Florida.
Jesus Christ is just last month.
This is another one.
Fuck Man,
those are 21st God damn dangerous there.
The the willdabeast.
Exactly.
They're really a scary because there are
way bigger and way more aggressive.
Like you can't be anywhere near them.
They're very different like temperament
wise and alligators.
Send them beast.
Yes,
yes.
Let's go.
We don't have weapons.
Allowed them to buy their own piece and
they'll leash them upon themselves.
I love that.
Dot.
Did them unleash their own punishment to
their stupidity.
They'll weaknesses creed.
They will continue to the [inaudible]
themselves.
What about the ones who are strong?
Get them pills,
make them weak.
Oxycontin.
Oxy doesn't sound like something though.
Kill Ya.
Sounds like a cool chick that we know
she plays in a band.
Hey,
where's oxy?
Oh Ah,
oxen went to visit her family in Sweden.
Oh,
that's cool.
She's a bad ass.
That's oxen.
I see.
Beautiful Hair.
Big Smile.
It was like a scooby doo band.
Oxy would be like their friend that
comes over and plays along with them.
You know,
she's just,
this is not even a hint of any sexual
attraction with anybody.
Knocks.
He doesn't fuck no one fucks.
No.
She just makes the situation better.
Yeah.
She's just cool.
She comes back over and the band plays
cool song and credits roll programming
programmed America and fed them
alligators.
Apparently alligators tastes really
good.
No they don't.
No,
no.
What makes you say that you've eaten
them in flow?
At least that's what they said they
were.
Oh,
like you've had like those alligator
tail and fried gator.
Yeah.
Got to eat it fresh and say gotta eat it
fresh,
but apparently has more protein per
pound of meat than any other wild game.
Really?
Yeah.
It's like his is up there as high as
anything else,
like higher than even like elk and um,
and buffalo and bison and things like
that.
I hated it.
Ah,
see,
find the find out.
That's true.
I don't want a lot of people it was,
it was added to he,
yeah,
I thought it tastes like shit.
She,
but I think that's because it's prepared
bad.
I think you're getting it from some sort
of a like a fucking Fridays or something
like that.
Like kind of a chain.
They say if you get it the right way
fresh and then cook it like the correct
way,
it's apparently very delicious or
probably just,
yeah.
Yeah.
You're probably right.
I might've get it cause I didn't,
I remember the restaurant was like a
special,
so it was fine.
Like a trial run in some guy's cousin.
Like trust me,
you just cut these up.
Yeah,
you fry them.
They're amazing.
46 grams of protein per serving,
so holy shit,
that's insane.
Let's start eating them.
That's incredible.
I think that's way more than anything
else.
If that's okay,
I'll find something new and meet the
other meat.
That's incredible.
Hold on.
Well this is only 3.2 ounces for 3.2
ounces.
It's 46 grams of protein.
That's insane.
That is what it says,
right?
It says 3.2 ounces.
Yeah,
dude,
that's incredible.
That's the main,
it makes sense.
You're reading a goddamn dinosaur
dinosaur.
You eating its tail.
That's what you eat.
It's all,
yeah,
it's all muscle to cut it up into like
steaks.
That'd be prepared.
Good though.
Yeah,
I would.
I would like to try it.
I mean,
I'm just talking out of my ass.
What's that?
Much as a domestic beef and for the city
twice as much as domestic beef.
Well,
why don't we feed people fucking
alligators.
Don't we give it a run?
Yeah.
He gives all these people worried about,
you know,
like a large scale consuming of beef and
the harm on the environment.
We got to kill these goddamn alligators,
so why don't we just start fucking eaten
them,
eh,
grow alligator farms and kill these
fuckers and you'll lose weight because
you're eating pure protein.
Right.
So you're right.
I don't know,
does it probably,
you probably get all ramped up.
I bet if you eat that stuff,
it's probably a soup.
Primal for Eaton,
an alligator.
Your Dick probably gets hard as a rock.
I mean,
have you ever thought that?
No,
it's got to happen.
That only make sense.
Like why else would do eat like mountain
lions?
Do you know people eat mountain lions?
The,
yeah,
the Loin,
the muscles in the back straps,
the muscles that are on the outside of
the spine.
That's where like the tenderloin is on a
beef cow,
like inside connected to the spine.
That's the same that does the same meat.
They like to get off of mountain lions,
but I mean why would anybody eat that
unless you were a really hungry or be,
it makes your tent cards crowbar.
Just imagine if we all found out there's
like a type of food.
It just makes you rock hard and they're
trying to give you pills were actually,
here's the answer and she needed
mountain lions need to study math,
crocodiles and shit.
I think,
I just think we're just so disconnected
from these animals that we have like
some sort of a weird fairytale idea what
these things are just wandering around
Disneyland like they should have guys
that they hire to go kill these fucking
things.
Like,
why are you letting these things live?
Because we're out of your mind.
There's too many of them.
They're going to keep breeding.
They eat everything.
They eat.
Dogs and cats and children.
The gators.
Yeah.
They're going to fucking keep eating
things like you guys and this idea that
all life is sacred.
Your life is fucking sacred.
Stupid.
They're going to eat you.
They're gonna eat you.
Why wouldn't he damn.
Well,
they're going to eat you.
They're definitely going to eat you to
eat you.
If you don't eat them,
then they're going to be so many of them
that they're definitely gonna eat you.
Yeah.
Keep simple wildlife biologist strategy.
Do I have just kill everything mallee or
stand there?
They help the environment.
They do that.
That's one thing about coyotes,
like everybody hates the coyotes out
here.
You know how many rats we would have?
It wasn't for these fucking cards.
What do you,
what would you rather have?
Would you rather,
I think cody's,
we're cool.
Of course.
When I lost the chicken and one
recently,
did you really?
You got chickens.
Tell me chickens,
your gut.
I just got five new ones of God.
Um,
do you just want to any for now for
eggs,
they're like pets.
So do you let them walk around the food?
Do they eat fleas and ticks and all
that?
They had everything.
They had all kinds of bugs there.
They're a little dinosaurs man.
They were really cool but you can pick
them up and,
but I got the new ones.
They're a little chicks.
They've actually gotten pretty big
really quickly.
It's crazy how quick they turn from a
chicken to like a little chicken.
What happens if you start?
What do you do with the other chicks?
Like what do you,
when the glory introduced?
There's my checks.
There's a,
these are the new ones.
These are the farm I have,
um,
a large hen house.
It's really big.
So they can wander around in there and
they're all protected from the coyotes.
It's an enormous thing.
But then I also let them out in the
yard,
but I got to keep him away from my dog.
He's decided that he can kill them cause
the coyote talked to him.
Coyote honey dictum.
Yeah.
The coyote became friends with them and
then talk to them and to go in and break
into a one of the side coops and kill
him on the chickens.
So hearsay.
Yeah,
you have to take chickens.
They brewed sometimes,
which is they get this thought,
there's no rooster if they're not
getting fucked all the time.
They,
the laying these eggs for no reason
cause there's no chickens ever going to
come out of those eggs and not
fertilized.
So these eggs are just,
it's just free food.
It's basically the product of you giving
them food.
They lay an egg and you eat that egg.
Right.
It's really interesting.
But the hen,
sometimes they get crazy because these
eggs never become chicks so they think
they're supposed to like sit on the egg
and it becomes a check.
And so they start pulling their feathers
off and they do what's called brooding
and it'll take a long cycle.
It takes like 28 days for them to get
over it.
Unless you catch them early in the brood
and you separate them from the rest of
the chickens and you put them in a
stand,
like were they a,
you put them in a smaller cage where
they have to stand on a bar.
And once they do that,
because they're not in a nasty,
not sitting in a nesting box,
it,
it goes through the cycle and their
brain,
they're little simple little reptile
brains.
And then you bring them back into the
chicken coop and they act like a regular
chicken.
But otherwise they think it's like a
health problem.
They don't eat.
They start pulling their,
uh,
their,
um,
feathers off of their body.
It's like,
it gets really weird.
So I had them separated and uh,
the dog,
I have a huge dog,
the coyote talk the dog and to knocking
over the,
uh,
the chicken coop to get out the chicken,
like the kyle probably wouldn't be able
to do it on its own because it's not big
enough.
But my dog is a massive,
and so the,
there's a coyote,
Kenny Dichter my fucking dumb ass dog.
That's like,
he came and he's like,
listen man,
we're buddies.
Which you're a doll.
You're,
you're a coyote technically just to
house pet.
No,
they got fun too.
They can fuck dogs and coyotes.
Fuck all the time.
Wow.
He duked them.
Yeah.
They make babies,
man.
Uh,
we ran into a,
when I was filming fear factor wants,
we're filming on this real rural area
and uh,
these people had a bunch of puppies that
were half coyote and have labrador.
Huh?
Yeah.
Coyote came over and fuck their dog,
man,
that was out here.
Yeah.
Like a dirty criminal sneaking into yard
and fucking your daughter like,
oh my goodness.
A little escape convict.
Right.
I don't want you hanging out with them.
[inaudible] it was cold out too.
And these puppies were all huddled up
together and we were like,
whoa.
Now what happens is now what are you
guys going to do?
They're trying to give them away and
there was like,
I don't want to have fuck fucking Eddie.
Exactly.
What the hell is that kind of eat my
newborn too.
It's a weird thing because they really
are all bowls.
Everybody.
Everything's a wolf.
That's why they can all breed with each
other.
It's so strange.
You know,
like a,
a hippo can't breathe with an elephant,
but a wolf can fuck a Chihuahua and may
get pregnant.
Zero dogs.
Yeah,
we're all dogs come from wolves.
That's so strange.
Like if a,
if a,
if a wolf could figure out how to fit
his dick and a Chihuahua and shoot a
load in that Chihuahua,
the Chihuahua,
it could conceivably have wolf Chihuahua
puppies.
Yeah.
Fuck.
And what would it look like?
Like that's again,
like an alien,
like a crazy,
it looked like big foot tude ever seen
those Werewolf mcats?
Yeah,
they scare me.
And there's also some weird,
is that a conspiracy you ever see the,
the weird blue dog thing?
Well what does that Jamie typed in
shallow wolf breed.
It's called a wolf.
Sable Watts?
Yeah.
Is that,
is it a hybrid or it's the AKC
registered breed.
Oh,
whoa.
A little tiny Wolf Chihuahua.
I'm sorry.
What'd you ask him?
I don't even remember
you asked if I'd seen something.
It was some weird blue,
uh,
like blue eyed dog looking thing.
Do you know what I'm talking about?
No,
it hasn't attacked.
It was just,
it looks weird and creepy and they got a
video of it running along a fence or
something.
Oh,
Chub.
Macabre.
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
You know what they think that is?
What is it?
I think it's a coyote with mange.
They think that,
uh,
when coyote is get mange right and it's
real common with animals.
They get it's Mites and the Mites.
That's like the,
they get,
they developed this horrible skin
disease and they lose all their hair and
their skin becomes black and fucked up
and it gets burnt by the sun.
Looks Awful.
It just looks awful.
And yeah,
they look like that.
So that's a Chub Macabre.
Yeah.
What it is is a,
it's a coyote then that doesn't have any
hair.
Yeah.
And uh,
I think there's quite a few animals.
Like if you go download that photo there
right there,
look at that thing.
Oh yeah.
I mean there's quite a,
I mean it's probably in constant pain,
you know,
I mean it's skin is just all fucked up.
A lot of times there's like open sores
all over their body.
There's a dog or a wolf,
wolf bear rather that has manged to
chimps.
Get it sometimes too.
Right.
They have ever seen those hairless
chimps.
Yeah.
A lot of times that's what's going on
with them too.
They've got mange.
I had a dog that had management,
I rescued her,
she had mange and um,
they gave me this like ointment to get,
but once I started feeding our good food
at her hair all came back like real
quick,
just washed her with some certain type
of shampoo.
And then within like a couple months,
like all the mains was gone,
her hair was all big and fluffy and
healthy.
Oh yeah.
Mangers.
Uh,
but that's what the Katuba copper is
just kind of mange.
It looks I started like a year ago in or
what it was going on.
If you saw that man,
if you saw something like that,
I don't sign person,
but if I saw something that freak out.
Yeah.
You think it is a market spinsters
aliens.
Yeah.
That's why the Mexicans believe in the
troop of Cobra.
That's what it is.
That's there.
But they can see that where big foot
though because the coyotes will fucking
kill your chickens and shit.
You know?
And that's probably the he kill a kid.
Oh yeah,
absolutely.
Right.
Definitely.
They,
they killed this girl in Toronto a few
years back.
It was a 19 year old singer from when
she should a country music singer.
It was really promising young artists in
Toronto and she's going for a walk and
they killed her in the forest.
Yeah,
during the day.
That's a bad way to die too,
man.
Oh,
because they you asshole first.
That's right.
That's what they do.
They tear you apart,
it tear you apart.
And if for some reason coyotes,
they,
when they kill a deer,
and I'm assuming they do the same thing
when they kill a human being,
they start with your asshole.
And I'm sure that they tried to
suffocate.
Um,
I don't know,
man.
I don't know.
They just started tearing it.
They might just start ripping you apart
if,
especially if they felt like it could
hold you down because wolves do that to
animals all the time.
They just chew what their legs bring
them down and then you start pulling
them apart while they're still alive.
Yeah.
My buddy found a moose that was getting
attacked by wolves and they found it,
uh,
and it looked like it had been getting
chewed on for over a day and it was
still alive.
This is,
Moose was all fucked up and half of its
hindquarters were chewed off.
And these wolves,
we're just pulling it apart slowly.
And they had been eating it for a day.
Oh yeah.
It's still alive.
Brutal.
Yeah.
Again,
like a settler just going around and
goes,
your brother,
just get to,
you watch it,
brothers.
You get torn up.
Yeah.
And they're reintroducing those.
That's as even more interesting.
They're bringing them back to all these
different parts of the West.
And if you can get to those people that
poisoned them back in the 18 hundreds if
you can get them bring to the future,
that's like,
well,
blah,
blah.
You brought them here.
You know we used to kill these fucking
things.
You guys brought them here this way they
have to stay in the areas outside of old
hip places.
They can't go hiking.
Sa,
Juna,
Stan,
the snow ed escape.
If they go swimming,
we have to crocodiles for the smile.
That genius,
they've must find.
Nothing means of entertainment.
That's well we call him inside.
I'm television.
I don't want to steal.
Hiking is too dangerous.
Hey Dan,
you got fast black bears now,
which we used to trust them.
It's just the idea just big up and how
they eat.
People Sat,
Sat,
nature's the great educator.
You go out there in nature of balances
you out to put things back into
respective and we simply can't have that
need them stupid and electronically
connected and we need to grab all these
tummy starts doing this and start new
societies and why won't they lent Damn
Pipe Poland?
Why won't they sit down in this dinner
when I talk about Ponce De Leon,
Dr
Dodge,
after times of God,
you know,
it always kills me like straight edge
guys like guys who don't smoke,
they don't drink,
but their intellect,
super hardcore music,
whether they're all like strat around
and they throw their arms up in the air,
like the fucking wreck it Ralph Ralph
dance.
I just went to a,
and
uh,
it was in Jersey and I,
I'm fascinated how I'm not really
fascinating.
It's just,
it's tribal watching grown men still go
around slam as hard as they can into
each other.
Just just vent shirts coming off when it
shouldn't come off someone's guys like
in their forties they don't care that
this is the first time I drank in three
months and there and just smashing into
each other,
hurting each other.
It's nuts.
Yeah.
Eliding yeah.
Old Indians used to do that.
Did they?
I think so.
The sets of the show in the movies,
I wonder how much of that stuff's real.
How much is that?
Yeah,
they really did.
I don't know if they've ran around.
I don't know.
It's a good question.
I was not there.
Hmm.
And who was really there if you had the
opportunity to go and view any culture
from the past?
Like if you could be completely
invisible and walk around amongst the
Romans or cave people or native
Americans before the Europeans came,
what would you choose?
Wow,
that's really hard question.
Yeah.
Um,
I think,
I don't know when the time would be,
but the first time where anything was
trying to be colonized,
like changed from being what your
regular like the first time like a boat
showed up in Polynesia or something like
that and some white people got out.
Right.
We're used to being in the fields every
day and,
and you know,
this guy hunts and this guy watches
after the boys and teaches them and this
one zoe and we're all,
you know,
and then all of a sudden they come up
and they're building like you guys
native is why you live in,
he calls for color.
Cocks are
the women are staring at their fucking
balls two feet from the ground.
What are these things?
And they might,
what the fuck is going on?
Jesus Christ cannot fleas.
Guys got a fucking look at his hair.
It's chunked off his fucking Tito.
He's got bones in his fucking here.
Rice.
Can I get a Bible
lesson
and there was this thing called Noah's
Ark.
Sit down.
He's fuckers.
Don't pay attention.
Get you fucking round them up.
Call Dobby and the boys.
We're going to need about 40 these
fucking things.
Climb trees.
What is your character's name?
I love the guy who used to come back
more often.
This is Joe.
They climb trees.
What do you mean that they fucking,
they don't even,
they don't even with our hands and her
at age of fucking car and he's up there
for 20 minutes.
Eat a Gundam.
Leon.
The fuck is going on.
I'm getting eaten by ants.
He's laughing.
Yeah.
Sorry.
No,
that's a,
that's a good thought.
Like the,
that might be like one of the most
important times ever.
Right.
When the people came from Spain and
landed in the West indies,
when,
when
Columbus and the Pinta,
that was where we landed,
right?
The West indies and they encountered the
people that were living there.
The native people that I think that I
would choose that I choose that it's
like the first,
the thing that you could see like to
know that this is this experience right
now is going to fucking change the
future of the world and I want to know
the why,
why we wanted spices and shit.
It was what they wanted.
They wanted gold and salt.
So again,
why like what was so why like all right,
listen,
we need to train them to be like us or
like we don't,
I don't,
I,
that's the part I go,
what?
How did we get from it?
It's,
it doesn't happen overnight where you
wear your running after something with a
stick or you just eat any farming than
wall somewhere in a classroom.
Yeah.
We have to work to make Wayne it give
this guy fucking something.
Is it again?
Like the fittest one tribe is now
starving and now I don't know.
I think will see the other one.
They wanted to expand their territory's.
I mean it's like game of thrones type
shit.
The king wants to bring back more gold.
And so he commissioned a fleet and he
hires a captain and he promises that
captain riches beyond his wildest
imagination.
If you go to these foreign lands,
bring back salt.
And so these fucking people would get in
these wooden crafts that barely had
enough food for them to survive and make
it across that goofy ass ocean where
they,
who knows?
There's no weather report.
There was no iphone APP that I have no
idea what the fuck was coming.
And they were in a boat in the ocean and
there's a lot of them didn't make it
like probably like a good percentage,
like a healthy 10 to 15% never fucking
made it.
I bet you more.
I wonder.
There's a lot of shipwrecks though.
People find them all the time and they
find him filled with gold.
That's it's crazy,
man.
They found a ton of them where people
have gotten super fucking rich where
they found like Roman coins are men and
a gold worth $1 billion or something
like that off the coast of this place or
that place.
The power of grade.
Yeah.
They brought back too much gold and
they're fucking raft saying,
think of that.
How desperate are you to go?
Okay,
we're running out of places to find
gold.
Let's just,
let's just fucking,
but I've heard people who've died who
gives a fuck,
what are we going to do?
He's be headed fucking people,
but kind of get them gold.
Like how desperate,
like when,
how desperate you got to be to go,
we're going to go,
we're going to start hitting other
countries and fucking fight and Hindu,
whatever we got to do.
Think about how terrifying it must be to
have a boat filled with gold and you're
trying to bring it back to Spain and you
realize you brought too much gold and
the boat starts going under and you're
in the middle of the ocean,
but you can't throw the gold overboard.
There's discussions saw,
we've got to get rid of some of this
gold and you're looking out and it's
dark out,
right?
It's just the blackening of sea and the
water is slowly leaking into the panels
in the fucking,
in the galley at the bottom of the boat.
We can't keep taking this on.
We've got
to get rid of this fucking gold and they
have a sword fight and there and they
duke it out and they all wind up dead.
All chopped up and bleeding in the
fucking boat just sinks to the bottom
because they had,
they couldn't make a decision whether or
not they should throw the gold
overboard.
I pawned it
even today,
you could drop a gps pin,
but what are,
what are the guarantees?
You could go back to that location and
retrieve it.
What if you dropped it at the bottom of
the Marianas trench and it's a mile and
a half down?
It's gone.
Good luck.
Good luck fishing it out.
You've got to,
oh,
it's cool,
dude.
We got a treble hook.
My Dad's kind of like a deep sea salt
water set up.
I couldn't fix it.
My Dad's got the ultimate set of tools
to the fishing pole and we're going to
die.
If I hold my breath like a champ,
I'm just going to get under that water
and bring up one coin at a time.
Oh,
like they died because they were greedy.
They died because their boats sank with
too much gold.
Fuck man,
that's crazy.
Or maybe the boat just sank and it just
so happens and a lot of gold on board
and a lot of times they made it with
that much coal on board.
Right?
Yeah.
But there weren't any fucking engineers
that had done stress tests on the
exactly.
How much water to go.
Oh,
and under pressure.
We,
we live in such easy times.
Just carry credit card.
That's right.
But I liked that whole concept at the
animals are coming back.
They're coming back,
dude.
I mean it is what it is.
If you look at Florida,
you were like,
again,
I was talking about living there in 1977
we're talking about a very short period
of time between now and then.
It's just not that long.
This is not,
it's just not,
no 40 years is not long at all.
When you talking about biology to short
amount of time for a radical change like
that for an animal to go from endangered
to ultra prevalent and eating people on
a regular basis.
Think,
think of even this,
the girl that was,
um,
I guess she's an African,
all that,
but I don't know if that just kept it
quiet or secret or whatever.
And maybe it's happened many times in
the past,
but this one particular time the chick
is in the front seat,
she's taking pictures and their windows
down and the lion just,
just,
lily would have grabbed her and pulled
her out.
It was just killed in front of everybody
had done that was the game of thrones
editor
for real.
Yeah.
She was an editor.
Oh,
my game of thrones.
Yeah.
Apparently they told her not to roll the
window down to,
you know,
I guess it's just so tempting.
You feel safe.
You're in that car with the lions saw
that opening and there's a female lion
too.
There's a lot of pleasure.
Think about that.
Those lines,
they tell you when you go over there.
Oh yeah.
They tell you,
um,
listen,
they think it's just a big animal so
they're not really gonna.
He's just got to stay still and don't
move.
Don't make any checking what?
Uh,
and he'll think that it's,
uh,
a big animal.
And so that's your sales pitch.
You're sitting there in the open and uh,
the lines looking at you going,
he's just thinks he's not going to jump.
He,
they told me they,
they would have told me if people have
been eating before,
right.
I would want to be in the back of that
helicopter.
Like that scene in Predator,
we're Jesse Ventura has got the gun
loaded.
He's calling everybody a bunch of slack.
Jawed faggots.
I would want,
that's the only way I would want to go.
I'm going to go with a bunch of dudes
with fucking bandoliers filled with
bullets and locked and loaded with giant
steroid filled muscles.
Just read it out
and never runs out of ammunition either.
Yeah.
I don't need a camera.
I'll put a Gopro in my head will capture
the whole thing.
It's sorted out.
The pictures later,
he says,
let's just get through this.
Let's just get through this.
I'm not opening up the fucking window.
No,
I'm not opening up the fucking window to
take a picture of a giant cat.
It kills things every day with its face.
No,
keep the fucking with Deloris.
Keep the window rolled up.
You crazy bitch and you see that Paul,
it looks like a catcher's Mitt
with fangs.
Just clamp,
gets a hold of your tit and just yanks
you out of the car,
digs into your rib cage.
God even imagined.
It's horrifying.
You sitting there with you fucking mets
shirt on and listen to some good music
on your ipod and it just pause through
that window and digs those closet deep
into the fucking bones in your ribs and
carries you off like,
like when you pick up a little pieces of
Shashimi where the chopstick,
right?
It's that simple.
Yeah.
Does even you come right out of that
window in a second would take you 10
minutes to climb out of it.
It's why we all need guns.
The lineups are coming.
Do you think that after shootings
happen,
the sales in guns go up?
Oh yeah,
for sure.
100% guy.
Right?
People get scared too when all the
rhetoric starts getting around about
ending the second amendment,
taking away people's rights to guns.
I mean,
it's the best thing in the world for
ammunition companies and rifle
companies.
Jamie,
there's a video that people are throwing
around on instagram.
I don't know.
I wanted to ask you,
this is true.
There's a a peep.
Some people from another country,
they're speaking a foreign language.
They're talking in front of a lion
carcass and they've got like,
they're taking a photo and then another
line comes in Jackson off camera.
Oh Wow.
But it looks so fake.
Oh yeah.
It looks so convenient.
Like the fact,
the framing of it where the lion gets
into frame and then jumps over the
camera to get the persons,
they scream and you hear the noises in
the background.
I watched.
I was like,
man,
this is a way to theatrical.
It's way too well framed.
This has gotta be bullshit.
That was my initial instinct,
but was interesting.
Oh,
King's MMA,
put it on their instagram page.
My friend,
a hot fail Codero who's a one of the
best,
uh,
Moitai instructors in the world trains a
bunch of world champions for breezy over
doom.
Hofeld dos Anjos a lot of people.
He's a great guy too.
He put it on his page and he was uh,
it was funny cause he put a caption in
Brazil,
the Brazilian version of English,
you know,
you are in his house now.
Like that kind of shit like here it is.
Yeah.
I get this to any line.
Whoops,
go back.
Here he is.
Look at the um,
okay.
His,
his words are interesting
humans mentality there.
Think it's a sport to kill lions.
Well I guess the lions brother wasn't
going for that.
Okay.
Going up.
But teat Mr Lion,
we feel your pain.
See,
looks fake as fuck.
Right?
Yeah.
Let me,
here,
let me see her again.
I can't replay it.
It'll,
it'll replay itself.
He ran straight to the person who had
the gun.
This is their house and nobody can cross
that line.
That's so hilarious.
See the line comes back into focus.
I don't buy that at all.
I just think that's fake.
Can I see it again?
I think you're going to see shit.
I want to see her.
I got to watch her yet.
I'll just check the Kelly.
Hi Kay.
It's what?
Can I be good stuff?
No did she would have never.
All
right.
Lion comes back.
Is he all those things.
There's so much off their,
first of all why did the line just
abandon these people that are shooting
it?
Did it kill them and walk off real
quick?
That doesn't make sense cause there's
two of them.
If it killed two of them,
I think it would have killed one and rag
doll that around a little bit and then
God to the second one.
It would have taken longer than 10 or 15
seconds and you can add that side effect
and it's a pain.
Yeah.
And then the rifle went off and it's
just nothing happened and that they
missed.
Totally.
They miss twice.
All that stuff seems fake.
Just the framing is the big one and then
they're acting.
Seems like shit too.
I thought they were speaking another
language.
Apparently the speaking English,
but that goes back to in order to think
about things like that show,
I literally sit there and go,
humans will believe anything.
We're not even a thought process.
The will just believe it.
Yeah,
no,
it's the video.
I saw it,
but don't you think that's the,
sorry.
That's also like a smart video to make,
cause that's what people want to see.
Like people hate trophy hunting.
They hate this idea that people go over
there and shoot these lines and then
prop them up and look big smile on their
face next to some weird animal that they
just shot some majestic beast.
Right.
It's weird,
man.
It's all weird.
What's weird too,
that people are celebrating that this is
fucking lion came by and jacked him,
went after the lady with the gun.
You know,
like everybody's like all happy.
The comments,
comments are all happy.
Like I'm not into killing lions,
but uh,
I'm definitely not in the lions killing
people and I don't think that it's like
a,
it's not a revenge thing.
I,
that line would have killed them no
matter what they,
they killed their lions.
That's what they do.
Yeah,
I,
I get it.
I get,
I'll sit there and I'll go like hunting
to me fee like hunting,
finding out like teas on a reserve.
If you aren't going lion hunting or
whatever.
If someone owns the land,
not only that,
they're,
most of these things are a high fence
operations where they have these lines
are fenced in.
Right.
And they go into,
it's like a cheap shot.
To me it's more than that.
I mean it's,
it's kind of like shooting Ligo,
dangerous pet that someone has.
Right.
But technically they're free.
But are they,
a lot of them are not free.
No.
That's some sanding and Africa.
They'd been caught and they tell you,
yeah,
I know.
If we really breed them in the wild in
these,
uh,
these enclosures,
I mean not in the wild.
In captivity,
they breed them and then they release.
Sometimes they release them and these
lions have a very specific area that the
traveling,
and then they release him the lines on
the,
where to go.
So they just hang out and wait.
So when they release him,
then in the morning the hunter in quotes
comes out and sees this line just
hanging out.
Cause the line doesn't have anywhere to
go.
It doesn't belong there.
It's not as territory,
doesn't exactly know what to do.
So he just finds a place to lie down.
So he'll go under a tree and just lay
there and then walk over and shoot these
lions.
It's fucking weird man.
It's like,
what is that like?
That's,
that is barely hunting under the loosest
possible definition of the term bear.
It's barely hunting.
You Know Lion Lions?
Video's fake.
Yeah,
I knew it so he can't get me bitch.
That's a real person is Yolanda.
Oh,
that's why it looked odd.
See I thought it was almost like a fake
line deadline might be in the faith part
and they might've actually moving line
might've been real.
I'm not,
I'll read more.
It's so weird.
But you know what's weird about this
whole thing?
You know,
after Cecil the lion got killed in
Zimbabwe,
now they have to kill 200 lions because
they have an excess of lions because
nobody wants to go there.
And um,
nobody wants to hunt lines anymore
because the blow back that they
experienced from this cecil thing.
So now they're,
they're a sas in the cecil thing.
You know that guy,
that dentist that killed that famous
lion?
Yes.
That's cecil the lion.
Okay.
Remember that whole outrage was really
crazy.
Like everybody got nuts about that.
And because of that,
nobody wanted to go there to hunt so
that they have the lines that are
decimating the undulate population.
So they had to kill 200 lions,
200 lines that would have brought them,
you know,
I think they get $50,000 a lion when,
when hunter comes and pays
to hunt the lion.
So think about that shit.
They like losing my,
it's a fucked up place.
Man is a crazy place.
Louis Theroux has a beautiful document,
if you've never heard me Yap about it
before,
but it's a documentary about him.
It's he,
it's on Youtube.
Him going on this African hunting
expedition with all these Americans.
It's really strange,
really strange jungle street wars,
but the same that not some sentence.
So it sounds like fricking jungles treat
wars with the animals,
but if you really think about it,
you know,
people get mad here because they don't
live like that.
They haven't seen well until like a
lando,
you haven't seen a wild animal snatch.
A family member,
a friend.
Yeah.
A child.
So they're accustomed to like whatever
that thing,
that thing tears me to pieces.
I still,
I remember my mom getting eaten by that
thing,
so yeah.
No,
I have no problem selling him off.
Taking that thing out.
Yeah,
there was a recent,
uh,
there's this guy named Jim shockey and
he's got this great show called
uncharted.
He's just sort of an adventure,
travels all over the world and they
hired him to go to Mozambique because
all these people were getting killed by
crocodiles.
So he's going,
he goes to Mozambique to hunt
crocodiles.
And while they were there,
someone in the camp got killed and eaten
by a crocodile.
Some woman was washing clothes and get
dragged into the water.
You know,
you talked to them and like those,
those people don't,
they don't have any problem with someone
coming over and shooting a crocodile.
No.
Cause they said this said they see it.
Yeah.
There'll be no protests.
Right.
We don't make movies about this.
There was an article in the New York
Times after the cecil thing by someone
from Zimbabwe that said in Zimbabwe we
do not cry for lions.
And it talked about how all the family
members that had been terrorized,
all the people they knew that had been
actually killed by lions.
Like this is not a joke.
Like you guys have this fucking lions
king version of what's going on over
here.
Right.
But even then,
still,
I don't want anybody to shoot a lion.
Just seems like,
just like anything.
Then they'll say,
well what weren't they move?
Well,
you don't know the conditions they are.
You don't know how far they have to go.
If they got to go across the desert or
where you can't say anything to you live
in that to live that way of life that
tries me nuts and people just,
well you know it's going on over there.
No,
I really don't send far away.
It's so different than anything we can
ever even possibly imagine happening in
North America did.
I'm just worried about my teenagers get
pregnant and my mom's kind of been an id
here,
so wow.
They're trying to kick her out of,
of her assistant living.
Why?
Because she's running out of money and
um,
her medicare kicked in and all of a
sudden they're like,
yeah,
no,
wait till you medicare so you gotta find
a place for,
you know,
she'd been here.
It's like,
that's why sometimes when I go in this
direction,
I love going there,
but at the end of the day,
my stance is always,
what am I,
so now watch this.
No,
just what I love the fascination of
thinking of it all.
A crazy.
It always,
but at the same time ago,
I got to take out the garbage.
Now let's talk to this kid about fucking
doing this and see if I can find some
way for my mother alive for another
month.
It just shit like that.
You know what I mean?
Yeah.
You can't be worried about Cecil.
So that worried about fucking cecil.
Yeah.
And I'm not worried about,
I feel horrible and bad events at the
end of the day.
I can't control this.
It's right here.
Or maybe I can,
I don't know about it,
you know?
But I like thinking about all of it.
Well,
the,
the actual variables,
when you stopped thinking about the
future,
they get real grim and weird.
They have to to get better.
No.
Well it's not even that,
like your body,
like as I'm getting older,
one of the things that I'm realizing,
I was like,
get up in the morning,
especially if I work out hard,
it's fucking harder and harder to do
that.
Like slowly but surely my body's not
going to be able to do all this stuff
that I wanted to do anymore.
But it's just not going to work anymore.
It doesn't matter how much discipline I
have,
how well I eat,
it just there's gonna come a point in
time where things just don't work
anymore.
It's just the fact that's the reality of
life.
Yup.
You wake up stiff like Oh and everyday
you're going to wake up a little more
stiff,
a little more stiff,
a little more stiff than the monster,
a little more and it doesn't go away in
a day or how many times.
So the chiropractor and now I'm going to
take a Ning Chung pow.
The new thing come out from eight in the
morning to nine 30 is that that back fat
area meat is going to hurt for three,
four,
five months and I don't know why.
And I'll have 14 different people
telling me different things and then
like take this pill and you don't make
me feel that.
Then we have been alleviating suffering
and Americans from more than 30 years
now,
30 years.
Wow.
Look at my lab coat.
Do not trust me.
Trust protector.
Nope.
My pen protector.
I'm a cautious person.
You must be really smart.
Oh look,
I have a clipboard looking at the charts
and the results and that handwriting is
completely trustworthy.
You can't understand a word I wrote now,
but I see a lot of x's and y's and
numbers.
Do you know,
many people get,
they get,
uh,
they overdose and die because of poor
handmaids handwriting or they used to
now they do everything electronic.
Um,
my wife,
when she was going through Chemo,
um,
she would,
she would take the other thing that
would bounce her out and she went there
and they gave her the wrong thing and
the wrong dose and she came home and she
looked like she looked like the creature
from the black lagoon.
She started getting lumps all over her
body,
all over her hands.
And they're like,
yeah,
no,
that's the uh,
yeah,
no,
it's normal.
That's usually,
you know,
it's one of the side effects.
Just like,
no,
I had,
I haven't had this side effect yet.
This is freaking me out.
Some of the things were going on with
her and charity.
She had
no fucking hair ready and know.
It's awful when people go through it,
it looked like aliens.
People stare.
You're like,
oh my Gosh,
dad
can Jesus Christ,
I support her because she wears the
pants.
So you,
you,
you got that going on.
And I think the end of the week they
were like,
listen,
uh,
sorry,
I just realized you got the,
the,
you know,
the dosage was wrong and that's why,
and the good news is,
the good news is you won't need it next
time because you already met your needs
for that type of thing.
But it's good because it's,
it's uh,
what you got was really good.
So what they try to do is avoid any sort
of malpractice lawsuit.
We'll probably,
yeah,
you don't know.
Like here's what I gave you see the x,
y clips and all that.
I just don't understand why their
handwriting would be so shitty.
Like unless they don't give a fuck.
Like if you're writing a prescription
for someone,
if I was going to write a prescription
for Xanax,
but Xanax was like a lot like Zana Lama
thin,
which fucking kills your Dick like a
fucking sniper.
And this is how you do it and you just
sort of x socials.
I mean you look at some of the writings
that what a doctor's written down
prescription wise and you're like,
no one can read that.
No one can understand that there's a
website that charts them like bad
prescriptions,
like bad hand hand meant writing.
Yeah,
prescriptions class.
Here's the most important class question
of the day.
Why can someone tell me why when we sign
these prescriptions now,
don't forget you're a doctor now.
You're very busy.
You're on call you 24 seven yeah.
You're on call at the hospital.
Why do we make this type of signature?
We're not really sure.
Yes.
Charlie in the back to make sure we
could never really be sued.
Excellent Choice Charlie.
So they make a signature that anybody
could forge.
Forge or I didn't say that.
My Buddy Guido Orlando,
he's a pool cue maker.
He's a great guy and Guido had a
signature.
I'm not bullshitting.
I'm going to blow up his spot.
I want to,
I'll show it to you.
I don't want to show everybody else.
So you want,
I don't want you have steel Guido's
empire.
This was his signature.
I'm not kidding.
It was,
he made an oh,
he made a weird,
oh,
so his wife forge that shit.
Cleaned them out when he got divorced.
She and he fucking hated life after that
man.
Why?
He was so angry,
so bitter,
so crushed.
And I was like,
how the fuck do you think you could just
get by with that crazy signature?
But he,
uh,
which you don't,
you don't,
you.
He's a guy who liked,
wanted to simplify his life.
It was a very smart guy.
He decided to simplify his life.
That's how he did it.
He's like,
oh,
I don't want this crazy sick.
She make me sign things.
I think signing things is stupid,
so I'll just do that.
That's my signature.
He wrote it on everything,
but he thought he was slick.
Mm.
Look at this doctor's prescription.
Wow.
Yeah.
Why don't you just give me a bullet,
shoot me right in the fucking head.
Just this crazy,
this reading that is insane.
Like no one can read that.
I bet he can't even read that.
It's amazing.
7,000 people annually die from bad
handwriting.
It used to be way worse though.
This is a 2006 yeah.
Okay,
so that's probably what it is.
They figured out.
All right,
how much is it costing us in lawsuits
and [inaudible] 14 feet.
How much have we made in the last two
years?
So that would be 50 trillion.
All right then.
This is not a battle then.
It's worth the over doses.
Please.
I talked about Penny's think Dr.
Schwartz maximum four hours a day.
Unless they have to do surgery,
they should be well rested and taken
care of and they should be more of them.
And let me ask you this Jamie,
how many people die from malpractice
guests?
This let's guess this.
I say a day.
A year.
How many malpractice?
Just fuck ups.
Just mistakes.
Accidents.
Um,
I'm going to say like to me
what?
30 grand.
I was going to say 30.
Oh my God.
I lagging,
I might say complete manslaughter.
Running cross the land.
Like fucking fields of buffalo.
Chop Chop.
98,000 a whoa.
Yeah,
I was off by a year.
I was.
Okay.
This is 15 years ago though,
so this is 2000 2009 they did this.
You would think it'd be 10 times better
today though.
No fucking Amen.
She'd be like 20 it's still to be these
teen.
That's how nutty number man.
98,000 people die.
Is that just America due to errors?
Yeah.
Check out mistake that was made on a
prescription.
Can you guess what that says?
Methadone that don't yet know.
It says method date,
which is this is for a child.
Where's the tea?
Yeah,
this is just supposed to be the tea.
Oh my God.
And so a child got Methadone and died.
I must have.
Yeah,
I'm pretty sure it was lost that.
Oh,
I didn't want to hear it and think of
that.
You're the one adhd medicine.
Oh my God.
I think you this.
Well.
You know that's fucking crazy.
Anyway,
you and shit to a kid.
You gave that to your kid and trusted
and kids like,
trust me honey,
you need it.
You saw the man with the coat.
The man with the lab coat tells you that
you need this.
This is going to make you popular in
school and you saw the kids at the rite
aid counter or you take Dave,
they're very trustworthy.
You interrupting class because you've
got something wrong with your brain.
The doctor's going to fix it.
This test shows that and proves that
this test shows right here.
There's something wrong in your little
second grade brain,
sweetie.
It's in a clipboard.
It's right.
It's believable and here's the best
part.
We're for it.
We're covered for this insurance mean we
covered for the kid,
the kid,
it's everything covered.
They're covered for everything.
Beautiful.
Thank you for having this job and
support it as colorful.
Don't.
What's my thought?
Oh yes,
it's good because it's going to help him
method.
Now I'm looking,
I'm researching this Bob and it says,
this is,
this could kill you and this should
never be given to children.
What about the days before Google when
you,
your doctor could give you some advice
and you had no idea whether or not it
was the right advice or not.
But how about even trust in this
scenario when you look it up,
if fiercely says don't give this Nigga.
Well it was the doctor said I should
dude crazy is that it's crazy.
And then the idea that you can't even
make a tea,
you lazy cunt.
You're writing a prescription for a
fucking kid.
Cross a t for child.
Let's see.
And what was this named heroin?
So while she's checking her phone,
thinking about some new Jaguar,
he's going to buy,
right?
I'm going to buy a vacation home this
summer after all my surgery money,
I couldn't hear the noise coming out of
my muffler off.
I'll get a new gal.
I'm success.
Perhaps I should smoke a pipe while I'm
driving around my job wall.
Sophisticated English hats.
They had like peaks on both sides.
Try to impact,
try to bring you down.
You grew up in the bronx,
stop putting on airs,
shut up.
Hasn't,
I've elevated my status status is
elevated private and around smoking my
pipe.
That's you gotta just classy bitch to
drive around with a pipe,
right?
Yes.
Would you like to come and mine?
Contemplates things.
Would you like to come in my yard and
see if the new zebra and Giraffe,
I just pet
face.
I'm just thinking if this is my
neighbor,
I'd be like,
fuck it.
I should probably just humor this guy.
Go see a zebra.
Just so he doesn't hate me.
I don't want to live next to this crazy
fucking zoo owner.
He's going to make some poisonous snake.
You mocked me for my z.
Put into your mouth and now the point is
this snake.
Is he in your room?
It's changed.
We could have been friends.
This damp giraffe just stayed.
All your Bush,
Claire.
I haven't had it would just fucking zoo
keeper keeper.
Imagine your next door neighbor is a
goddamn zookeeper.
What the fuck,
man,
this is what you hear at night.
Oh,
fucking noises.
The beast,
the
woo.
The worst.
Imagine you are in your Land Rover
defender trying to get away from the
encampment.
You're driving away and you get a flat
and you're like,
what should we do?
Well,
we should definitely wait until the
morning.
We can't see.
I don't have a light.
I can't change it.
And then as you're sleeping in that
fucking land rover here,
well,
Hey,
you look out there,
there's 30 of them with their paws on
the fucking hood.
And then you hear way,
way,
way in the distance,
way the distance.
Oh,
that sound.
they're all running.
His guys explained it to me.
Elephants,
why they kill elephants?
He's like,
it's not.
He goes,
it's not just that people want to go
over and trophy hunt these things.
Sometimes the elephants will move into a
village and these farmers,
they have these plots of food for the
village and it's all they have.
And these elephants move in,
just eat everything.
It's not a goddamn thing they can do.
There's nothing you could do.
Nothing.
They can do.
The dinosaur,
a dinosaur just came in and his way,
he's been living forever.
And you to start with spear and it is
three of them or four of them,
right?
They're coming from every angle now,
what the fuck are you going to do?
And so you have all this,
these vegetables are you growing for
your family and you're fucked.
How long did it take you to build his
fucking hut?
Gone.
They just jacked seconds.
It is Jackie.
And if they think you're a threat in any
way,
they just eliminate that threat.
Just go pick you up and throw you.
Yeah Dude,
go ahead.
Get your spear.
You see where you'll French just landed?
Yeah,
because I was arguing.
I was like,
what?
Why would they ever need to kill an
elephant?
Like you don't ever need to kill an
elephant.
And Guy was like,
oh actually here's what goes on.
And I was like,
oh.
So they,
they,
they hire people to go and kill the
elephant or they'll give someone a
permit to kill the elephant.
Then that person pays like 50,000 bucks
or something like that and they'll come
and kill the elephant.
So some guy like that,
those hunters,
the fake hunters for that thing,
they'll pose with it and you know,
show the ivory and everything like that.
And then they give all the meat to the
village and then the village gets 50
grand.
We get charged when I remember I was in
Africa
and the guy was like,
listen,
they don't did they never charge,
they'll charge but it's always to spook
you.
And my nine year old,
oh,
it's in the cheap in front of us,
uh,
with another kid or whatever.
And we came,
we get,
we were by a herd and as things turned
around
and then
the one we thought was going to charge a
different one charge,
they called it a teenager.
It ran and went right for kids.
Jeep hit the cheese and then pushed it
about 10 feet.
And I went through everything where like
it's going to knock over the vehicle and
then just start smushing and this guy
got out of the van and he just,
he starts clapping,
he's clapping,
ah,
bold about dope
and a thing kinda stopped and shook his
head and then went back off it.
It was those things like,
I can't imagine living there and just
what you said because just that flash
where the kid was just in a cheap that
there was no stopping us this thing,
once it started moving,
there was no worry.
Okay.
You have like a two seconds to react.
There is no,
it's coming.
It's coming.
He was far away and within seconds he
was on it and it just,
I watched and shock.
So they just don't want people driving
through.
Is that what it is?
Duran was a territory and they also
have,
they've seen,
they probably seen hunters,
so they associate now chiefs is like,
whoa.
I was just thinking to shoot us.
Well I don't care,
but it lost my brother.
I'm taking it out.
They have crazy memories apparently.
Yeah.
This is,
isn't that the vehicle that came when we
were at the watering hole and he sliced
my get it.
Fuck.
Getting good at it.
You know,
I don't see myself going over there.
No,
I think you'd like it.
Abuse area.
You were on a fucking spear hunt.
Yeah,
but it was awesome.
Stay Buck.
I think about that crazy.
You here behind you
honey,
right through the fucking Cobra.
Oh,
see I didn't even think about stuff like
that.
The heck was I think some Cobra.
Awesome.
Funny.
Okay.
Moons ass.
So I can't really tell what it is.
Imagine how fucked up you have to be
to be a cobra.
Mind.
You Cook,
you're growing poison in your head and
you shoot it out of your teeth.
You bite people and inject them.
You are literally a walking needle.
You're a needle.
Yes.
You're a walking overdose needle.
A poison needle.
Yeah.
Poison needle and some of them use you
just a hundred percent death.
Some of them it's 100% like the,
you know,
I know people get bitten to make enough
antivenom.
You're never going to get it.
Yeah.
Everybody get in time.
Who's carrying that you carry with you
everywhere.
Only lasts a little while.
Who is carrying that could keep making
it.
They make it with horses too.
Do you know that what?
Like rattlesnake venom?
Antivenom.
They shoot horses up with it.
They,
they take a rattlesnake in Jack
rattlesnake venom and the horse,
the,
this,
the horse curlex the antibodies produces
antibodies and they take those
antibodies out.
And that's like the serum entheos really
mean.
At least they used to do
it that way.
I'm pretty sure they still do though.
I know it's,
um,
it's an issue for vegans because if
vegans don't want to use any animal
products and they get bitten by a snake,
like they have to compromise.
That has to be some,
there has to be some compromise here.
Yeah.
I don't get,
I don't get all that.
I get it,
but I don't get it.
I get it.
They want to be nice.
They want to be righteous.
It wouldn't be a good person.
Is it nice?
Is it the fight for matter?
Cruelty in general,
I think ultimately cruelties terrible.
You know,
the,
our,
our real problem is a factory farming.
Our real problem is,
uh,
the cruelty to animals.
It's not eating animals a real problem
going because they're going to die.
They're going to live,
they're going to die.
And I know you can say that argument
about people too.
Why don't you see you be blue?
Because people are people and we're
different than cows.
Okay.
Yeah,
but don't you see to tell you this?
Listen,
we all know this.
Yeah.
This is what I would say.
We all know all of this.
You can go to a factory and see it.
He didn't go to any factor.
Anything.
Chickens,
any Ame,
everything you love.
Write down the plants.
Yup.
Anything.
It's all been manufactured.
Well now what are you into?
What are you can,
you can just get a barking here.
Down the street.
Wear a sign.
Yeah.
At least pork.
Chicken.
Sure.
I didn't really grasp ed where at the
same time you're buying the tee shirt to
watch the bread.
No
show at home or you got about how many
shares with we by today by ban and I
died tonight and I'm fine.
Make America great again.
Hello?
Hello.
They're building walls in Wisconsin.
They're building walls at North Dakota.
They're building walls and half
American.
The only way to keep the Mexicans out of
each individual state is wall to wall
off.
If we want them all off,
we can keep them from getting in.
Once we find them,
we have a mold off in the air,
then we get them,
we send them to Mexico.
The only way he's not one wall.
We need 50 walls in a wall over each
individual state.
That way we can contain anyone who
causes a problem.
First,
we'll start with Mexicans and we'll work
our way up to really a rude white
people.
If you wear any type of cloth around
your head,
you shall be
boss actually said,
but what about do
rags?
What if those come back to Greg's all
sudden become huge.
Okay.
At 14,
uh,
miss happy headings today.
Okay,
but,
but there's going to be a racial problem
cause doo rags.
They might have some pushback on that,
but what about the Bandanna that Bret
michaels from poison?
Worse.
That's a tough,
that's a gray zone
because he's white.
It's crazy.
That's white privilege is a gang.
He's in a gang.
He said he's a rocker.
Yeah,
that's a gang.
So you need tattoos and you need to
sing.
He needed at least one song and he's got
more than one.
Every rose has its dawn.
He's wearing the forbidden garb.
Beautiful Hair.
Not Real beautiful though.
Interesting.
Look axl rose too,
but axl rose.
Axl rose can kind of pull it off better
for whatever.
Well that's strange.
It's strange.
Look.
Yeah.
I don't know.
It's this thing though,
man.
You know.
Maybe that's,
maybe it's a good move if you dress like
that all the time.
That way when you take that shit off,
nobody recognize you.
Anywhere you go.
Maybe that's the move,
right?
That could be.
It could be the move where the Bandana,
beautiful eyes.
Beautiful Man.
Does that real?
I think he put that through like one of
them instagram filters.
Whoa.
Hey,
why are you pulling your pants down bro?
Put a fucking shirt on and get a good
six buck though.
Didn't know his so built.
All right enough,
Jamie.
I'm getting hard.
Let's move on.
Jim Brewer.
What are you doing in town?
But hold on.
Okay.
I can,
I get as much as that drives me nuts and
I,
I can,
I can tip my hat
to him.
Just gone.
I'm in the system.
I got to,
I got to create my wrestling character.
Here's my character,
right?
I live in this system.
We're all slaves.
Are we not all slaves to something?
Do you think he's thinking like that
now?
I don't know.
He's fine money,
man.
It's good business.
Just bought a boat.
He's got a new place in Miami.
She's,
you don't have to worry about nothing.
What does that picture,
what's going on there?
Why did you have lipstick on?
Why not worked?
Worked for awhile.
Remember they all were glammed up.
I remember the early guns and roses
even.
He was glammed up.
Well,
they were very glammed up hair number
and go forget that.
No,
they wear a hairband.
Remember?
Welcome to the jungle.
Remember the video?
Full blown hair.
Oh,
I had that straight.
Almost like Afro when he,
when he landed,
when he landed in La,
remember?
Right.
They did their makeup eye line.
Is that island or is it,
no,
that's a shot there.
Beautiful.
It's just natural,
natural beauty.
They were the baddest motherfuckers at
the time.
Crazy.
How hard that was for them to handle
though.
That was all wild quick apps.
Right.
It's interesting to see them touring
again.
Now,
you know they did coachella.
I saw some videos of it look wild.
Sitting out there.
He had a broken foot,
so he's,
it was doing all his dancing from a
chair.
You see it?
Yeah.
You know you're fucking rock stars are
getting old.
They're dancing from a chair.
They're doing like the chair wiggle.
I felt like I went to professional
wrestling when I was 10 and it was
Andre.
The giant was the ref and I already
bought my shirts.
It was bob backlund against dusty rose,
the American dream,
and I noticed they weren't hitting each
other
and then I,
I noticed they were stumped and her
foot's every time the elbow.
And then I saw Andre the giant take a
chair and not really hit him and I was
shattered.
You saw it in real life and I went,
oh no,
this is all just to show.
How does that happen?
Yes.
It's got a foot brace.
[inaudible] Keith Richards.
That is what a shot himself up with
heroin and dance like a fucking man.
I Bet Keith Richards has never done a
shelter.
Don't you think I fake ny that,
but it's freaking brilliant.
It's brilliant.
I think he hurt his leg.
I think that's all those.
No,
no,
no.
It's just,
just the whole thing.
They're like,
who talked to her like you want this is
they're gonna make $50 billion or
whatever.
They going to $50 billion.
This was the top grossing ever historic.
You'll will never beat it.
It's how much money.
Yeah.
We all for capable allowing.
Wow.
Yeah,
definitely.
They brought him a fuck load of money.
That's how they got axle to lay off the
botox and getting the chair.
Dude,
get a chair for you.
You gotta fucking got a cast.
Don't worry about it,
dude.
You're it.
You hurt your foot.
Of course you can't dance.
Oink,
oink.
They probably saw him dance.
He's so fat and fucked up now.
They probably broke his leg.
They probably came at him with a
baseball bat.
The promoters like I gotta fucking plan.
Oh crap,
you fucking fat junkie.
You get to do this from a chair.
Put a cast on him.
Put Him in the fucking chair.
Huh?
Imagine.
Oh yeah,
they just broke his leg because he was
so fat.
He showed up.
He showed up so fat and they got mad.
I come over there.
It was only one way.
We got to hurt him.
What?
Why you got to hurt him?
Cause cause we can't have him fucking
dancing with his gut hanging out.
We'll just sit him down the fucking
chair.
Put a cast on him.
Didn't Dave Grohl break his leg while,
while he's performing?
Yeah,
I think he and that's his throne.
He was right.
That was just thrown right?
Yeah because he had like a left leg
injury.
So actually just borrowed his left leg
injury chair.
Wow.
Or is it a right leg?
It's reversed in bolt images.
Oh Dave had her right leg injury axolotl
left.
That's pretty gangster.
Get your fucking foot taped up while he
did he fall off the stage or something?
Jesus Christ.
I liked it.
He's a bad motherfucker.
And Foo fighters are awesome man.
You know like I went through Nirvana.
I'd like to sit him down and see what he
thinks about that.
Courtney love documentary.
What's that?
Talk to someone I think we can.
Interesting.
That'd be cool.
What is the Courtney love saying ounces?
I'm crazy documentary.
That's thinks that courtney love killed
Kurt cobain.
Have seen that.
What's it called?
That one is soaked in bleach.
Yeah.
Yeah,
it's,
yeah,
it's got reenactments too.
It's super sweet announcement.
Yeah,
we're super sketchy whenever you have
reenactments here.
Like what?
And the guy was a reenactor is like the
actor from I think thinner from the
movie thinner with Stephen King and he's
like a semi famous actor with,
is that who it is?
Because at the same guy it was all on
the documentary.
Yeah.
He's,
he plays the cop and the reenactments
and it's like okay that's the guy who
plays curt.
But there was a guy who plays the
detective.
It's a weird documentary cause it's
like,
man,
you can say anything you want in a
documentary.
If you use a bunch of reenactments and
you're pretending that you were there
while this happened.
But people,
yeah,
you see my white coat?
Yeah.
It's a documentary.
It's true.
If I say documentary,
we have a script.
We have a story of ARD.
It's reality.
Which means it's his real,
we're shooting in four k.
You get to wear the goggles and
everything.
You'd be positive.
The system that would come out very
soon.
She don't tell him.
I'm sorry.
So we've got to end this and then we're
gonna come back and Jim Brewer is going
to stay with me as we,
uh,
we talked to the Great Russell brand.
That will be next.
We're going to do the Jim and joe show.
It's about time.
We should done this years ago.
Gel.
This was cool.
Thank you.
We're going to keep doing it.
It was cool.
I'm fucking so happy you're here,
man.
I'm having a great God.
Damn man.
We'll be back with Russell brand and a
little bit,
see as soon.
Yeah,
that.