Liquid insulated walls put in five,
four,
three,
two,
one.
Someone's got a new netflix show.
I couldn't think of any other way to
start.
Officer of what I thought.
Oh,
so you do have new netflix specials?
I do.
I don't want this to be like an
interview.
No,
but,
but I,
but I like it.
I'm actually proud of it,
you know,
it's like I'm still proud of it,
usually a certain amount of time will go
by where I'm like,
oh,
like my mom.
Even now I've gotten it better on the
road because,
you know,
I was,
the day after you shoot it,
you go out on the road and you're a
murderer and you have a little fun with
it and then you go.
I.
But I'm still proud of it and it was my
favorite thing.
I've it,
the guy did.
Jeff Rowe is the guy who,
and Scott Moran,
but just everything I wanted,
they did it perfect.
That's awesome.
The look the way I did it at the lyric
but,
and the lyric is great,
but there's no desk is the lyric in La,
the lyric is in La.
It's like at Melrose and melrose and
libray pretty,
but they sort of used it as a shell and
it's already a pretty cool club.
But you know,
the,
the biggest compliment I got,
someone said,
you know,
what's weird about your special I want
to go there and it doesn't exist a what
it looked like,
where is that?
They had good set people date.
It just looked like a cool jazz club in
New York City.
That was maybe but not.
It wasn't small because it was an after.
You know,
sometimes it's small but it's shitty.
It's the look and it's cool.
It's sort of a,
what's the word?
Kitchen?
Yeah.
I don't know what that word is.
I mean,
and that's the look they want.
I didn't want that.
Not that I think that's bad because some
people have done that really well and
it's a cool way to see a comedian just
in a cool little raw space,
but I want it small.
But like,
like it's a jazz club in New York City,
but it's like 150 bucks to get in and it
holds 100 people.
It's like that type of thing.
Run like a theater.
Well,
you helped design one of my all time
favorite clubs,
helium and Philly.
You helped design that place,
didn't you?
Well,
when Mark Mark,
uh,
he acme at Lewis,
Lisa,
you know,
touchy feely,
he'll probably love to give you advice.
So when it was just a warehouse like
cement and I met him down there and he's
like,
I'm thinking of open up a club and you
know,
I told them a lot of stuff I wrote,
I,
I made like well email,
you know,
like six pages of,
here's the very detailed things and you
know,
what?
He listened to a lot of it.
Like I give him credit,
you know,
that's awesome.
Great fucking club.
Like there's something about those
intimate spaces.
Like,
one of the things that I've noticed when
I take people on the road with me and
said,
guys who have never worked at theater,
like it takes a few tries to get.
They go,
oh,
okay,
this is a whole different thing.
There's so many people here.
You've got to kind of project to them.
It's like a different thing.
It's not,
you don't feel them the way you feel
them at the,
in the Oh,
are on like a Wednesday night,
right?
Or um,
comedy works in Denver where they're on
top of you.
You're like,
you feel the people,
they're more,
right?
Yeah.
And then you learn it pretty quick
though.
Yeah.
You know,
do you ever do the belly room at the
store?
I've done it a few times.
And of course it's,
I love little rooms.
Like I love like woman.
I used to do tempe.
You always did that side room on
purpose.
They will do the big place.
But with the side place,
you know,
not to get too,
but you get it.
I was jealous.
I remember I came over,
I was in the other,
the regular one,
which is great.
I was having a good time is but the one
one,
joey and I went next door and watched
you.
I was like,
this is better as well.
Even in DC,
which I think is a good example.
DC has a 60 seat room and whenever I'm
in there I go,
I give it.
I had a two piece band playing with a
black tablecloth on all the tables,
the lights or Gel blue,
so now people are turning corner into
this thick blue room with two guys with
black suits playing jazz as they're
being seeded in eating.
So now I don't feel like it's an
afterthought what you just said and I'll
take it as a compliment.
The other comedian that's in the main
room there,
which is awesome room,
but you look into the little room and
you're like,
it just looks like something's going on
and that's how I want it to look.
No,
it makes sense.
Yeah,
no,
it does make sense.
It's a.
it's more of a hang,
right?
The big show and your style so loose on
stage like lends itself to intimacy.
It lends itself to those nice compact
spot.
Do you ever do the Ice House that the
annex room?
I mean not forever,
but.
Yeah,
I know what you mean.
The craziest.
The Ice House is about as deep as this
room.
That's fucking.
It goes side to side a little bit.
I think the whole room,
that annex only gets,
what is it?
Like 70 people,
maybe 70 people and all the chairs are
like facing the audience.
See that says,
oh no,
no,
you're,
you're sitting here,
you're going to say goodbye to your
friend for a little while,
like some of the Improv and then people
were watching the show like this and
they have to kind of turn to look past
the person next to them.
They're trying to feed you food to like
you're working in a half restaurant.
The thing about,
I will say this about a good club.
Most of the foods been served or I
couldn't do what I'm about to tell you
that I've done so that the club has to
at least be good to go.
Now we get the food that we have,
food we can get out.
But the time the show started we tried
to have the whole room service,
so in the event and like helium does
that.
Uh,
but so I started making this
announcement and I would tell people
because I do my own pre show
announcement,
it has to do with what you said about
when they're sitting sideways.
And I would just go real calm,
real.
I go.
Other than that folks,
hey now's a good time to turn your chair
around.
You're always going to have to annoy
someone to the right or left you.
But now's the time to do it.
And once all the chairs are facing,
the sage will get this thing started.
Play a little house and you know what?
They wouldn't do
it,
but another 30 seconds I'd go.
So we're just waiting for all those
chairs to get turned around and then
we'll get it started.
So it looks like we're close to show
time and the second time,
boom,
boom.
Every chair in the room they're like,
oh,
but you know,
I get it.
It's a pain in the ass.
And if I was in the audience I wouldn't
want to turn my chair around.
But guess what,
once someone made me do it,
you'd enjoy the show better.
And they do.
We got,
you know this,
if you ever do those,
use those yonder bags,
those bags are.
And to make people put their cell phone
in a bag.
Denver has them.
Denver uses them for all their shows
now.
I started using them for all my show.
So you just accompany,
comes in and just does it for you?
Yeah,
you hire them,
they come in and then when they put the
bag,
the phone in the bag,
they still hold onto their phone and
they can leave the room.
If they get a phone call,
like you have a kid or something like
that and someone's watching the kid.
You can always get out of the room,
make call,
but you can't call people when you're in
the room.
And I was having people calling people
and talking on the phone.
You could see them talking on the phone
while the show's going on and people
around them would be getting pissed off
and uh,
someone on twitter comment on it and he
just,
everyone's got their phones up and look,
I know I've done it too.
I'm totally a hypocrite.
When I saw honey honey with Gary Clark,
even performing this little tiny room in
downtown La was a midnight show and like
a Tuesday and I filmed it and I put it
on my instagram.
So I know I'm a hypocrite,
but that was a rare occasion that it
wasn't a comedy show.
It's like a comedy show.
You have to pay attention to what the
fuck's going on.
If you,
if you're filming it,
you're definitely not paying full
attention.
You're going to miss some stuff.
It's just not the same thing when you
filming shit.
Like everybody is just,
even if you're not,
you're checking this and checking texts.
And boy,
we got a real addiction problem in this
country with these,
these are new things.
Is your new object.
I,
I realize because I'm not delusional
that the amount of it,
I can put most of it to breast with
appreciate announcement where I'm at in
my career.
But again,
as you get to different levels,
there's different intensity.
So I don't I get it.
But um,
the uh,
I,
I changed my pre show announcement when
I went to see Brian Regan,
the person next to me,
I,
they were texting,
I couldn't hear them,
matter of fact even had their light
down.
So you think,
well,
what could bother me?
And it did.
And it didn't matter if it was right or
wrong,
I know what it was.
I wanted the person next to him and it'd
be loving him as much as I was loving
him.
And the fact that I saw them on their
phone,
on or even they weren't making a peep,
it started to bother the fuck out of me.
I was getting angry and then I went,
oh,
that's,
I'm going to do the same thing at my
show.
I go,
don't turn your thing all the way down.
I know you think and you'll pull it out
into your knee.
I go,
seriously,
if you pull your phone out after this
announcement,
you,
you look like a dick.
I go and we're glad you're here and you
know what it.
You just have to pick it out an
announcement a little longer,
but it works.
I'm worried about people are really are.
This is a really new thing.
The more I'm thinking about it,
the more like looking
at your phone constantly.
It's really only 10 years old,
right?
Like 2008 ish.
Then the iphone came around 2009 right
before that people were a little text
diy people.
Some people more tech savvy than others.
They really got into text messages,
but once that iphone came out and once
people started doing a bunch of stuff
and apps and stuff on your phone,
it changed the whole game.
You know?
I don't know,
with this topic,
if I'm like I could be way off or I
could be off kilter the way I come to my
conclusion about like,
you know,
it is,
it is a weird thing and even me,
I could acknowledge it.
Otherwise,
if I don't acknowledge it,
you're never going to tell some of the
opposing side if they don't think you
get what you see it,
but it just seems like in the past now
this could be different with.
No,
no snarkiness it.
Oh,
this could be a different thing.
Every time they think there's one of
these things like TV radio too seems
like when we get past,
oh,
I think we'll get past it.
You know what I mean?
I didn't think the world was going to
explode,
but I'm worried about certain.
I'm not worried about the human race,
but I'm worried about the lives of
certain people,
if that makes sense.
Because it's like saying like,
are you worried that cracks can destroy
the human race?
No,
I'm not worried that crack is going to
destroy it,
but I do think you can destroy the lives
of some people and I feel the same way
about this.
Right?
Like the texting,
like it's not just that.
It's like being plugged into electronic
to the point where that's where you're
getting most of your stimuli from.
You're getting artificial stimuli.
My concern,
this is a real concern is that we're,
we're getting really into that and then
we're going to let it take the next step
which is some sort of an implant.
I feel like this is,
we're in a movie within a movie about a
person that becomes a machine and we're
watching this rationalization process as
we slowly get more and more ingrained
and interconnected with technology.
We'll definitely in our lifetime have
somebody 100 percent.
I try like what you were just
addressing.
Like we said before,
like I,
I catch myself and I really try.
Like if I had to give myself a grade on
how much I've improved on,
like turning the phone off,
like loving it for what's great about
it.
I give myself maybe a c minus,
but it means I've made some strides and
like turning it off.
You're not enough.
Not Enough.
Not for.
Matter of fact.
I remember a week ago I was going into
the grove and I went,
I'm not meeting anybody,
and I left my phone in the car.
It was strong,
move strong to ideas,
to ideas and I was high and I didn't
want to write them down.
I went,
Oh shit.
That's the thing about leaving your
phone in the car.
They'll take a picture or show someone a
picture or it doesn't have to always be.
But anyway,
I try to go and,
you know,
never,
never walking through,
never walking through a line that
actually could encourage you to write.
Um,
you know,
you can just use hate writing,
but I mean saying you see,
you can only use your phone when you
have a note or an idea.
That's the only time you could use it.
Well,
that's a loophole.
Like I'm pretending that I don't even
have this phone unless I need to make a
note.
You know what?
I could put it on airplane mode.
You could put it on airplane mode,
then you still have all the other stuff.
Although a ways my pants down.
Oddly enough.
That's true.
Good conversation.
Right?
It does do that.
He pulled my pants up and shit.
That's why I like fanny packs.
People just mocked me relentlessly.
Can I tell you something?
There's no way I say it all the time
when I go,
especially if I have my altoids and then
I have a pipe and then I go,
what the fuck?
You're a pipe guy.
Uh,
I still do for some reason.
They're old school.
It's all toys.
What else?
What do you do?
Like jazz clubs,
pipes?
What do you do?
Like what is your typical way?
Mostly joints or vape pens?
You know,
it's the rolling of the joint that I
have a question for you.
Okay.
And I think you might know the answer.
I smoke.
I'm not going to like,
you know,
pressured,
blame you if something happens.
I know I can switch conversation
completely,
but you might have.
I have two things I want to ask you a
question.
Did I interrupt?
No,
no,
not at all.
Um,
I smoke now seven nights a week.
Wow.
So I'll have like a joint.
I would say if I had to put it in joint
size,
maybe a joint per night.
So it's not that.
Not a tremendous amount.
None of that just at night.
Not that I'm saying I want a prize for
that.
Just for me.
It works better at night,
but I say I quit smoking and I did.
I quit smoking.
I used to smoke around a pack and a half
a month is this as bad pack and a half a
month is pretty.
It wasn't horrendous,
but I quit because I had a of day.
Yeah.
Is this smoking seven nights with a
joint as bad as when I smoke cigarettes?
No,
it's not.
It's not the same thing.
It's not even close.
Not even close.
There's no evidence that marijuana smoke
causes cancer.
You can't.
Do is get respiratory irritation.
You can get.
It can fuck with your voice.
What about Tara?
You can avoid all that stuff is what I
was going to say with the vaporizer
vaporizers,
the way to go,
but it is a different high.
Oddly enough,
vaporizer seems like a little bit more
clean in some weird way,
like when I get high with a vaporizer,
I'm always like,
whoa,
this is like a.
it's almost as if this is gonna sound so
crazy.
There's something that's something that
has to do with the fire interacting with
the plant that connects you to nature.
There's something about a lit joint this
to take it in and you just feel natural.
When I vaporized,
I feel alien when I vaporize,
I feel like this.
What this is is like let's extract all
of what it is to be a living thing and
get to the molecules.
What's the molecule?
What temperature to heat those bitches
up or I can shove them right in your
bloodstream.
That's what the vapor.
I proceeded to vaporize,
hang on hand up like whoa.
Like it's just.
You're not connected the same way.
It's connected a different way.
It's both.
They're both amazing.
Judgment will probably agree.
I agree with you.
Most people do.
I think there'll be like,
yeah,
I know even a joint.
I don't roll joints because I'm lazy,
but whenever someone has a joint and
they put it,
I go,
this is when I.
This just happened.
So yeah,
I get,
I get a little higher.
I like to smoke joints.
They,
it's feels like it's real clear what's
happening.
You know,
like there's a lot of these vape pens.
You got to press five times then hold
them and you're sucking it in.
You don't know what's in that oil man
who's making that stuff and they get
yelled at and yell at you when you can't
do it.
Just press it twice,
right?
It doesn't work with the press it twice.
I got one more thing.
Do you ever fuck around with spray jumbo
spray?
You ever fuck around with jumbo?
Do you know what John?
He put it in the water.
No.
Super Organic.
Really high end edibles and spray.
And this fucking spray will put you on
the moon.
Wow.
Do you have any?
Of course.
Wow.
But I have to drive.
I have some,
some of hanging with me today,
John Bryan Wagner is a shout out.
Like if this is this,
this is a thousand milligram,
like if you drank the whole bottle,
it's a thousand milligrams.
That's too much to have.
I wouldn't have a half of spray
anything.
I'm safe to do it right now.
It's always fun to experiment spread.
Especially because you're saying to do
it.
You know why?
You know why it's more comfortable?
Because if something happens to me and I
can't blame me,
blame.
Let's,
let's do.
let's to do it now.
I'm like the worst crack dealer.
However you can do it now.
Everybody wants to do taste and then I
want to.
I do have a question.
You know,
you might have an answer.
What did you have a half a spray one
spray good enough.
Okay.
Right.
We're in.
What was the other question you think?
Why am I asking you this?
But I think you might've been answered
so,
but I'm being totally honest.
I'm exhausted from dealing with like I,
it's not like it's a big deal,
but it's like the first time you,
whether you could admit major things in
your life.
Like,
Oh,
I have a drinking problem.
Can Be stupid little things.
Yeah,
mine is eating like I'm exhausted from
doing it the wrong way and everything
comes back to me for self control.
So when people want to tell me about a
diet,
I know it's not portions.
I know what portions are.
I just want to eat more so it's all down
to how do I fucking get self control.
I have zero.
I mean if I'm not going to call it zero
self control,
then I don't know what the hell I'm
going to call it.
But as you heard about it for me,
you're hard on yourself.
I think you have selfcontrol todd think
you're a wonderful man,
but you're.
You're hilarious.
And one of the reasons why you're
hilarious because you're so.
You're free,
you're impulsive and that sort of that.
It's very difficult for that to lend
itself to dietary discipline.
It's like when I eat it,
fuck it.
Fucking need it.
Right?
That's you.
But that's also part of what makes you
such a hilarious comic.
It's like you have these impulses that
makes me feel better.
You don't want to comfort,
at least with what you're saying,
you don't want discomfort and you want
to have fun and it's like it's right
there.
They want to,
I want to eat that food.
Fuck it.
Just the thought of me like picture me
at the,
at the cancer shoving cheesecake human
in my mouth and my friends are like
looking at me like todd and I go,
Joe Rogan said that because I'm
creative,
I should eat whatever I want.
He said,
go listen to his podcast.
I shitty.
He told Joe Rogen and you can go listen.
He said,
clear up the mini bar before you get in
your hotel bed,
even if you're not really hungry.
Creative.
Okay.
So I don't have control over this.
There's also a problem.
There's another problem with discipline.
This is a discipline.
I think that hit me already.
Yeah,
for sure.
No,
that's probably just the,
we'd hit you.
It takes a little while for this prayer.
Get usually a few more minutes than
that.
Um,
I forgot my point point about,
um,
the self control.
Oh,
that when you really disciplined people
and comedy,
they don't go well together that much
either because if you're too driven and
too disciplinary,
that's almost always dickie.
It'll,
you know what I mean?
You know what I'm saying?
Like you'd be able to disciplined too
rigid,
too determined and in and to like too
enthusiastic about success.
You get Dickie.
Let me ask you this.
You know,
and I don't.
This thought could be wrong,
like I'm okay with thinking something
and then maybe finding out,
but whenever a comedian,
and I bet there's funny ones out there,
definitely because over the years I
remember my can't think of which ones,
but they definitely exist.
They are funny,
they are funny,
but they've never smoked.
Drank out.
Can you be a good comedian if you
haven't done those things?
I think you'd be a good comedian.
If you're a man,
you could be a good comedian.
If you're a woman,
you could be a good comedian if you're
gay or trans,
you just,
you a good comedian.
If you're a good comedian.
Is that.
Why do I ask that?
Because I'm not.
I should be embarrassed to ask that
because a lot of people that are really
good that don't do shit,
I'll never.
Yeah,
they don't,
they don't have a desire to,
you know,
it's just everybody's brain works
different and some people like the idea
of losing control with a substance is
not not fun.
Right.
They don't like that feeling,
but they can keep their shit together,
you know?
I know a lot of people that don't drink,
they don't do anything but they keep
their shit together and maybe that's
better for them.
They feel like it is.
I don't know.
I,
as I asked that you gave me the answer
that you know to go.
You're right.
But like I asked it means that I had
questioned about that and I,
and I think I've talked about this in
the past and once I was like somebody
was saying,
well he may be,
what if you're not experimental?
But no,
there's a billion ways to,
to do those things.
You used pot to do without the pod.
I think.
Edit that out.
I use yoga for that too,
man.
I love going to a hot yoga class fucking
hard and it's like a drug like you get a
lot of thinking done in there,
man,
when you're just holding these poses and
there's no no music,
no nothing.
Just everybody in the class.
Breathing is a 90 minute class.
There's some sort of psychedelic effect.
There is some sort of cleansing of the
mind and I think that's one of the
things that we overlook when it comes to
mental health that your brain needs to
be cleaned out.
You can't just stagnate and think on
thoughts.
You bring these to your physical body,
can clean your brain out a little bit,
can get rid of some of the stress and
tension and you can see things clear
like those terms.
Stress Reduction,
tension relief.
What does that mean?
It means the way you fucking think,
okay,
you're doing something to your body that
radically alters the way you're going to
think about things and everybody's
supposed to do it,
and one of the problems in societies
that you don't do it,
but you have these instincts that are
built into your body from thousands of
years of what the.
You know the what people ask of their
bodies 20,
30 generations ago were all those same
people.
So if we don't deal with what our body,
just some physical activity getting,
he's got to get the blood flowing.
If you don't,
your whole,
you're like,
you're like an overflowing battery or
something.
I as far as the stopping thing think I
have a great idea for people to do to
get a smidget of what it's like to stop.
If you go,
okay,
I won't meditate or I won't do this.
I get it,
but this,
if you do it,
I promise whoever does it,
that's listening will go.
You'll get a little taste of it and it
all happens naturally,
but it started by accident,
but then we started realizing it's about
stopping.
So like one night it was about probably
10 years ago after dinner or before
dinner,
I had some hot wash cloths and I was
like,
oh,
just I get a Chinese restaurant joking
around,
but we all did it.
And then we realized,
wow,
that really stopped us.
The heat putting it on your face.
So now I make it.
I have a ritual that I do.
I have it all figured out.
I get the less people the better because
the hot wash cloth has a short shelf
life.
It has to be so scorching hot when you
hand that to people.
So by the time they get it to their
face,
you know he can't take warm.
So I use the tea kettle,
pour it all over,
like six of them.
And here's the rule.
The radio goes off.
Sometimes you think I'll leave it on.
I don't feel like walking over and
turning off.
Nope.
Even if it's jazz off and I ask
everybody,
check the pulse of the room.
If everyone,
if you take yours off and you're ready
to start talking,
but you see,
oh,
three people still have it on their face
and I go,
I'll break it,
but just once the.
Once you get the hot wash cloth in your
hands,
I go,
it's going to be hot.
You're going to want to go.
I would taught it's way too hot.
It's hotter than you think it is,
so just get ready.
I give everybody one.
They put it on their face.
No one
even has to tell them to take a deep
breath.
You naturally do after like a second
because you need to see though.
Then you let it out and then I go,
wow,
and then you literally spiritually,
you shut down and then you wipe your
hands.
Literally take some of the dirt off your
answer in the day and we always think,
Holy Shit.
Resetting yourself.
That's a simple way to get a taste of an
a.
We always make the joke,
we're like,
oh,
well,
we're just going to eat and then we're
going to go on throughout the whole day
and then put our food.
Okay,
blah,
blah.
Of course,
stop,
you got us and that hot wash cloth.
It's like,
fuck.
Yeah.
I think your brain has requirements for
those things.
Those kind of things.
I think those,
those kind of moments are really good
for your.
Just good for your outlook.
A reset.
I think that's like the same field than
a,
uh,
maybe a primitive man would get when he
would like walk up to the edge of a
cliff and see like some crazy view and
see nature and birds flying around the
sun.
This was,
you know,
hey,
this is a.
yeah,
I'm getting chased by leopards every
day.
But look,
this is fucking amazing.
Like a renewed enthusiasm about life,
about life itself.
And the simplest things.
Obviously I have a theory.
I don't give myself any credit when I
have these talks when things are going
well,
like it's good.
It helps you know,
like,
but if I can be in a tense moment and
get out of it where I would have been,
I give them that I'll be proud of
myself.
Yeah.
That's the thing about all that
motivational speaking stuff,
right?
Like it's like the guy who's doing all
the motivational speaking,
if he's pulling up in a Rolls Royce and
he lives in a big mansion,
so like,
yeah,
you're enthusiastic.
Look,
everything's going great.
How are you?
If someone takes all this stuff away
then and it becomes like,
can you,
can you be stoic?
Can you be at peace when you're broke
and you're by yourself and some one
bedroom apartment somewhere,
can you,
can you do it all over again?
That's the suburbs,
you know?
Could you imagine if someone told you
Dane Cook was the first one ever heard
talk about this.
So give him credit for that.
He said I would never want to try to do
standup again.
I don't think I could do it like that.
It was so hard to do that.
I would never want to start and do it
again.
Did you ever think like what it would be
like you start again?
Like right now you don't.
You have zero jokes.
You've never done stand up.
But somehow I know that you have this
vague memory of the grind that it takes
to become an actual professional.
I think I do it.
I think definitely,
definitely,
but death because you already know,
right?
You already know you could do it.
It'd be a totally different thing.
A question now that I think about it.
Fuck Dane Cook.
Just kidding.
Dane,
they'll get upset,
but I'm saying if you.
If you think about it like that doesn't
even make any sense because of course
you would know that you could make it so
it'd be way easier even if you just
started all can't in 21 again doing
stand up.
This is ridiculous.
Are you.
Are you 21 again or you just are.
You are.
You didn't have to start from scratch.
I just do it to go get younger.
But then once you made the decision you
would in.
Unless you live in some bizarro world,
we're allowed to live two lives.
You would never even have memory,
right?
You'd need 21.
That's what I would.
You will.
All I'd have to do is just say yes,
that'd be 21.
Again,
this is a stupid fucking question.
Maybe yet.
Maybe you haven't.
Maybe he'd be like,
no,
I said this and that.
I don't think he thought it through.
You said something a minute ago and
that's when I should wait.
Shit.
Was it about the food thing?
No,
no,
no.
What were you just talking about before
the.
We're talking about discipline,
like hard acids and then um,
then we got to like how difficult it
would be to start over,
do it.
I think anything like if you said that
to a brain surgeon,
you want to start from scratch,
start from,
you know.
Right,
right after you graduated high school,
you want to take it from day one,
freshman year,
college.
They'd be like,
oh,
just get them through.
No,
fuck that.
Did you ever think of like,
I know two things I would have done like
before.
When did you start standup?
Eight.
Excuse me.
That was 21.
Did you,
is there a job you.
When you were in high school,
did you think you thought you knew what
you wanted to do?
Maybe for a living?
Not really.
My,
my number one option was teaching
taekwondo,
which already was doing.
That's what I was doing.
Mostly you were already,
but I didn't,
I didn't want to fight anymore and I
didn't think that,
um,
uh,
didn't think that dude be like a real
future in me teaching.
I didn't really like teaching everybody.
I only liked teaching people that were
super enthusiastic because I was,
I was young at the time,
like when I first started teaching on my
own,
I was 19.
I was teaching at Boston University.
I had my own school.
You 21.
Nineteen.
Wow.
Yeah.
And in Boston and Boston.
Yeah,
I taught,
I taught a pass,
fail a class.
Like they can get credit for it and I
would say all you have to do is just
show up and you get an a,
just try.
I'm just trying to get an a.
it's has nothing to do with your
physical performance because the idea
that everybody's starting on the same
page as ridiculous.
Some of these people have serious
athletic backgrounds.
Some of these people never worked out a
day in their life and they thought it'd
be fun to try something new.
So the idea of like grading them against
each other,
I said I'll give you guys all in a.
and I was their age.
Are you allowed to do that as a teacher?
Like they were.
The worst they can do is fire.
Man,
I didn't care because it only paid like
200 bucks a month or something.
It wasn't expensive.
Wasn't a valuable thing,
but it was a prestigious thing.
It's like I'm teaching at a university
and I'm 19.
Did most people get the a everybody got
an a no show up or all the times I
taught.
I taught for a couple of years.
One or two people just didn't show up.
You know,
you're always gonna have that one or two
people just say fuck you,
they fuck off.
But I just made it fun.
You know,
I was their age and so we just,
we did a lot of cool shit and kick pads
and
I taught him about the Turner hip and
stuff and you know how to get power
things you could see them.
It's a,
there's something very enthusiastic
about someone regardless of what their
physical ability is.
Getting a little bit better and seeing
it,
you know,
even if they start from nothing and then
you see just yes,
yes,
you're getting it,
and then see them beam like this.
That that to me was what I was into,
what I wasn't into as people that needed
to be motivated.
They just didn't.
They couldn't.
They would just half ass things.
They weren't enthusiastic.
They were distracted.
Maybe they were talking too much,
like you could do all that stuff another
time,
but if you want to get good at this,
there's only one way.
You have to be really interested in
getting good at it.
You got to be really focused on all the
things you're doing right or wrong,
whatever.
I see a comedian like,
do you go back a year to a club?
You saw a comedian,
he's a newer comedian.
If he has been going up at least twice a
week and it's 52 weeks later,
it's fun to see that type of improvement
and you're like,
wow.
Like,
yeah,
maybe I've gone up what,
300 times since you've been here,
but you can tell if they haven't.
Do you have any friends that you knew
when you were professional and they were
open?
Mike makers.
Oh,
you mean like they're professionals now?
Oh yeah.
You were a full blown professional.
You met them when they were an open mic
or matter of fact.
It leads me to a little plug.
Oh,
it does look like you set a set me up
for it.
But Blake Wexler is a comedian.
He's a professional comedian now and he
met me when he was 15 or 16 at helium
and he was wearing a conestoga shirt.
That's where I went to high school.
So of course you're like,
you know,
and he said he's a new comedian,
so right away went to your high school
and he's doing standup comedy.
He was with his dad.
We talked and I go,
hey,
if you want to come back with your
friend Saturday,
I said,
here's my number.
I'll put you on the guest list.
And then you know,
years year goes by.
I was in Philly,
I called them.
I said,
Hey Blake,
thanks for whatever it was.
It would be a message I was leaving.
Hey,
got your friends on the guest list for
Thursday,
and then there's these messages.
Then we became good friends,
so he told me I saved every one of your
messages about a year ago and I've had
people say that before,
but then they go,
they got to race there when they got my
computer and they lost them.
He came over about a year ago with like
50 messages and so we put them on a CD
and put them on itunes and it's a 12
years of messages from Todd Glass to
Blake Wexler.
Simple name,
but the reason I think it's really pure,
which is a weird way to maybe say it,
but it's just for me to him now.
There was probably three or four at the
end where I knew they'd probably end up
on there,
but I mentioned it.
I go now this whole thing is fucking
ruined because I know you're making that
CD.
So now I'm aware of it,
but most of them I never thought they'd
end up on a seat.
So it's just me talking to Blake and it
sort of tells our friendship.
You see the friendship grow,
but it's there,
there,
there are some very funny to hear them
years later.
That's,
that's a cool.
It's a cool thing to watch someone like
that become a pro.
Right.
And just see them when they're
first starting out and that first year.
So who fuck knows what's gonna happen,
you know,
you did.
You decide I want to try stand up and
then you start going to open mic nights
that first year.
Who knows what's going to happen.
I mean you might eat it a couple of
times and I'd be like,
all right,
this is too painful.
Fuck this.
And what other jobs that painful when
you.
When you fuck up.
I know I couldn't even,
I couldn't even think about getting a
weekend.
Like because you did the MC,
I was on Wednesday and then sometimes
you would a host.
That was a good thing.
You've got to host the open mic night
and then do Thursday best affiliate,
but getting a week.
And I remember once sitting around with
my friend,
he goes,
do you think you'll get a weekend ever?
I'm like,
I don't know.
Like I don't know why I didn't think I'd
get a weekend.
I mean that was.
But that's what you think when you first
start now.
Right?
I know some door guy told me I'd get,
he goes,
you're going to get a weekend.
You know what I thought?
He doesn't know what the fuck he's
talking about because I'm not going to
be so stupid to figure.
Oh Tony knows I'm going to get a
weekend.
But he probably did know he was,
he was around comedy a lot.
He probably knew something,
you know?
Yeah.
He's going to be.
He'll be,
he'll get a weekend,
you know,
I got a weekend.
All right.
Yeah man.
When you,
when you talk and when you're talking to
an open Miker,
it's like you're talking to someone
who's going to make a journey that like
if you had 100 open migrants,
what are the odds that they become
professional?
They,
they make it to,
you know,
a working stand up.
I'm guessing.
I want to guess it's one out of 100.
Well,
it's,
when you say it that way,
it,
it is a bigger number,
but if you take an isolated area like
Philadelphia or whatever city and you
don't have any of these,
you know,
when you go into a town sometimes I'll
know like some of the newer Comedians,
they,
they hang out a lot.
Sometimes they work at the club because
they're new,
but there's like a group of them and out
of that group,
whatever city it is,
I always think somebody's going to maybe
to even maybe three different levels,
one or two at each level.
But there's always a hundred guys.
Right.
Like I started out with meeting the
cream of the crop.
Well you definitely are if it's in La,
right?
Talking about like when you're on the
road lately or New York or when they
come in.
You mean like Bloomington has a scene
and you think a lot of those people you
two years later,
like wow,
look how good they're doing.
And they're in New York now and they're
so in a small group.
But yeah,
on the.
Probably on the all the comedians in
every city that are doing it right now.
I guess it's a lot lower.
Yeah.
If you.
If what I'm saying is from the person
who makes it onstage the first time
every week at the comedy store,
you're dealing with how many,
what do they get?
16 people in a night and probably more
20 people on an open mic night because
they do three minutes each.
Let's just say they get up 20 people a
night.
How many of those people are going to
become professionals?
It's might be one out of 100.
It might be.
Yeah,
and that on that because.
and then how many people?
Some people go up once,
so Mike's are crazy.
I encourage anyone,
if you're not
even into doing standup,
just to go watch an open mic night and
see the mania and the madness and what
some of it is.
Just someone who you.
You what you're seeing as potential,
right?
Or no potential.
You're seeing one of those two things.
Either you see it,
someone where you go,
that person is fucking never going to be
a standup comedian.
There's no way,
there's just no way,
you know,
like there's no way.
And then you're saying,
Huh,
maybe she was funny.
Oh yeah.
Sometimes when you say the first one
where he would go,
no way.
It's not even.
They did a bay.
It's never based on.
We're basing it on something.
It's still a guest,
but we're basically on something pretty
fair.
It's not like they're joke didn't go
over and we're going on.
No,
it's.
Sometimes it's the vanilla illness of
the personality might not lend itself to
be.
Sometimes their brains broken to.
Some people just,
their brain's not working right and they
can kind of get by and regular life kind
of.
But you see them like express himself.
Like I'm going to prepare something and
bring it to the stage and then people
go,
what in the fuck is going on in your
head,
sir?
There's those people and you're just
not.
It's not going to happen.
It may be,
might be perfect for music.
They might be perfect for being the
front of a punk band or something.
This is,
you know,
certain people like I think it might be
one out of 100,
like if you bomb on stage with a song
has got to be pretty bad too.
Right?
But you have like the others obviously
the people that have just so nobody
thinks we're being babies here.
The people that have physical risks,
that's way worse thing,
right?
First responders,
police officers,
things along those lines.
Even in sports,
I always say I could never do it because
in a comedy show and often it happens.
Everybody can win in one night.
Like if you're on the road and you're
with two other comedians or three or
whatever,
there's so many nights where everybody
wins.
But in the sports,
as you know,
I'm always thinking I could,
I could,
I can't oppress you and I'm not even
into sports.
I don't give a shit about sports,
but when I watch a game,
I get a stomach ache for the other team.
I'm like,
ah,
I can't take what some of comedy is a
sport.
You know why?
It's because like you're attacking
things that aren't there.
Right?
Like you're going after stupid laws and
dumb shit that happened and like you,
you're literally by using your words and
the way you're describing things.
Literally having a little battle with
something that's not even there.
I call them verbal.
I hope I say right.
Verbal Shit.
What's it?
When in prison they.
What do they do?
Shifts shifts or so?
White Shank,
shank a verbal shawntia.
Shift them,
shift them with your shank.
We'll be back.
Okay.
Sometimes when a comedian like has just
a turn of phrase that would fuck it.
I always go,
oh,
he's shifted him with his words.
He just a verbal.
I think that was correct.
Correct.
It's fun to watch.
If
somebody knows how to do it.
Good.
That's what roast battle was all about.
Rose battles essentially a support.
They.
They would fucking mock each other,
mock each other's lives in jokes and be
really mean.
You know,
in some of it was like,
oh Jesus.
They would talk about their looks like,
oh my God.
Some of them are.
It's painful and I.
I went and enjoyed it.
I saw it up because it's almost a parody
of a roast battle.
I sold at the comedy store in the little
room and it was crazy.
But when I'm watching I'm like,
I'm too sensitive.
I would,
it would crush me,
it would just fucking crushed me.
I don't want to know the jokes that they
would make and of course some people
don't care,
but to watch other people.
Um,
it was,
it was exhilarating.
Great Joke.
Writing exercise.
It is unfortunately some people are
really good at that and then.
But when it comes to their act,
they don't,
they don't explore as much.
So think about like if you're writing
about someone,
like there's some people.
My point is that there's some people
that I've seen that are really good at
that roast battle.
I see a lot of people do it,
but then you see their set,
their actual standup set and like it's
missing a spark.
Right?
There was a spark that you had when you
were in combat with this other person
because you knew they were going to be
firing at us.
So you were firing at them and it was
all in fun,
but it was also a chance to flex your
comedic writing skills will then when
you're on stage and it's just you,
then what?
What is.
Is there any.
Where's the juice?
Are you upset?
Are you excited?
Are you like,
what are you just pretending it's not a
big deal that you're onstage with a
microphone in front of you because
that's a real problem too or you're
pretending it's not weird that your
voice is amplified,
motivate someone to get.
It's just a great way to say that like,
why are you pretending it's not?
You don't have to jump down,
but come on.
What's going on here?
Where are you?
Why are you pretending you're not fully
aware that people are standing in front
of you,
hanging on your.
Every word.
There was a comedian like that in A.
I won't even say the city,
but they had a.
They had a roast,
a battle,
a roast battle.
The.
There were some people from the history
like Napoleon and it was.
It was great.
That sounds awesome because it was also
a weight.
That's why I said it was a writing
sample because you know if you were
writing jokes you could also make
statements,
political statements and and go back and
no one gets hurt because you're making
fun of Hitler,
but you still have to write great jokes
and one guy that did it,
he was amazing.
Like what the.
And I just thought,
oh,
he should know that he should be writing
because he,
his standup is exactly what you just
said.
And it wasn't.
It was.
But I was like,
oh,
this is.
I hope he knows like,
oh,
that's your strong point.
The thing is the standup,
like when when you're doing something
like that,
you have a little bit more freedom.
It's more open ended,
but on the STANDUP,
right?
People are paying to see you and you.
You're supposed to be getting laughs.
Right?
And when you're not getting laughs is
this feeling of disappointment in the
audience and when you're doing new
stuff,
man,
this is a distinct possibility.
There's gonna be no fucking laughs in
the spot where you wanted there to be
laughs,
you know,
like,
yikes.
I thought that was a way,
funnier idea,
or maybe I just fucked up the way I said
it,
or maybe I just have to stretch it out
and figure out where the good spots are
and then start hacking it up and editing
it,
you know,
but just going to be a real problem with
bombing.
You're gonna,
you're gonna be have to be comfortable
with saying dot joke.
That's just not that good and some
people just aren't.
So they get to that spot and they go,
fuck that.
Let's do some tried and true,
boom,
let's hit them with some proven stuff.
Boom.
I know you got me nervous one night at
the comedy store when you were like,
just everybody.
You were right.
You were like,
okay,
all new stuff.
Everybody knew that was.
And then I was like,
oh shit.
Oh,
because we were supposed to.
That was the show or something where I
was like,
I was up on stage.
I'm like,
Oh shit,
maybe he's never seen this one.
This is.
Well we've done.
Wasn't a stand up on the spot.
So there was nick use of show,
right.
His new new stuff show.
The thing was that,
I forget what it was,
but uh,
that show you're supposed to only work
on new shit.
You're supposed to only work.
We have like a weird rule where when you
sit,
when I came up with it,
we were like,
Eh,
it can't be any older than six weeks old
and he bit,
you have to self police,
but any bit older than six weeks old you
got,
you got to remember exactly because I
wouldn't have fought that because that's
a good move.
Right?
Six weeks,
six weeks is like,
you got some time to.
You're saying it's fresh and it's.
Yeah,
it's,
it's new enough,
but it's also like you should have
worked it out a little bit.
That's more than fair.
More than fair,
right.
It's more than fair.
It might even be four weeks.
Four weeks might be the real.
She'll pull it back a little bit back.
A little three,
three weeks,
maybe three with dangerous three.
That means you've said it five,
six times.
What more do you want?
Sometimes there's a bit that works real
good and then doesn't ever see those
bits.
They just die.
This one's going to be a quarterback and
then sometimes I never know either if I
videotape myself,
maybe I've learned.
Do you record yourself?
I don't.
And I,
and I'm so embarrassed because I know
how good it is to do it.
I did it five or six times in my whole
career and it was,
it did so much good that would think
that because I'm lazy,
you know,
when you,
you know what you're just saying about
you go to a joke and it's just dead,
which,
you know,
just say I started doing this thing and
it really helps me get out of those
moments.
So I'll just,
I'll hit the punchline,
nothing.
So whatever.
I'll go black.
And then it was,
well,
I'll make up a punchline and it was
blue,
but you know what?
Then I realized instantly,
so here's what I just did.
Sometimes in comedy,
Ladies and gentlemen,
you get to an end of a joke and it's not
the crowds fault because you're great,
but it just doesn't land.
And it's uncomfortable for them,
they feel bad for you.
So what I did when I hit that period
about 30 seconds ago,
I just been talking nonstop ever since.
And now we're here and everybody's
happy.
That's perfect.
That's a perfect for like 15 seconds.
And then they figured out.
I always say,
are they going to figure I go,
so about 15 seconds ago I hit a punch
and it wasn't your fault.
And now everybody's great.
Hey.
And then the whole,
like a whole new premise,
whole new premise launches those like,
it's like Jesus Christ,
it's like building a house out of your
planting a seed and then you're watering
the ground and then the tree comes out.
You got to wait for it to grow and then
cut it.
Oh,
you're talking about not a whole new
premise,
like weird out their premises or
premises you've never discussed before.
Things you never thought of before you
go into a whole new way of thinking
about stuff is so much fun,
isn't it?
Fuck yeah,
it's awesome.
It really is.
I still like it really is just and the,
and the.
And um,
you know
the recorder,
like on the phone,
that's changed.
That's because I don't like writing
stuff down and I can say that it's
changed.
Did you do,
do the text speech to text?
Will you just talk into it and writes
her notes for you?
That's amazing.
Every one of my.
I can just put jokes on there,
but in five I,
you know the recorder.
Well that recorder man,
that just cleaned my head up.
Yeah,
recorders.
Giant to pick deal.
Yeah man.
He anything where you can catch those
slippery thoughts.
Like,
I think Neal Brennan said it best.
I think he called his notebook.
He's like,
this is like a net where I attach ideas
and I was like,
Ooh,
that is a great way of looking at it.
That is a great way of looking at it
because some ideas just go away.
Like they're so profound.
It's so profound.
But then a couple of hours later you're
like,
what the fuck was I thinking?
That always used to get me where I'd
have this amazing idea what I thought
was an amazing idea.
And then I go,
ah,
that's such a good idea.
I'll remember it in the morning and I go
to school
lately.
No,
I still pull that shit.
I've never remembered it.
No,
no,
no.
I still pulled out.
I go,
what are you doing if my phone,
if I didn't have my charger now I
finally got a court in next to the bed.
So I always have a cord to plug in my
phone.
But I'd never.
Why do I not half the time.
Never.
And I still have out.
No,
because that's a good idea.
Never Hedberg had a job,
too lazy,
too lazy to get up to get a pen to write
something down.
So I just could fence myself.
It wasn't that funny in the.
But what's great is that that was a bit
he did on stage and it would kill.
I mean,
I,
I didn't do it.
Well I don't remember the way you get
the,
you know,
they used to.
We were thinking,
okay,
I used to do drugs.
I still do,
but I used to to.
Yes.
So lastly we were saying,
I used to do Mitch Hedberg.
I used to do drugs,
I still do,
but I used to to.
I mean,
I still do,
but I used to to.
Okay.
I know I.
let me back up for a second.
So I do Mitch Doing Rodney Dangerfield.
Rodney,
if he did,
Mitch,
I'll be like,
I'll tell you the other day.
You guys are used to do drugs.
I still do,
but I used to to,
you know,
do any Mitch Hedberg joke is Rodney and
it's.
And it's killed twitter the other day.
I guess me if I wanted a banana,
you know,
I said no,
I want a regular one later.
So.
All right.
So I use,
I do,
they use to,
I hope this goes somewhere.
So I used,
I,
I did the uh,
I used to do drugs.
I,
so my friend asked me if I still do
that.
He,
I go,
I used to do the Mitch Hedberg.
I still do drugs,
but I used to too.
I still do,
but I used to to do something and it's
amazing that you kept it all together.
I did for,
of,
used to sense.
It makes sense,
but you nailed it.
You dismounted.
I shouldn't try feet flat on the ground.
So solid dismount.
Lube stumble.
No,
it was good.
Was very good.
Very good.
Thank you.
Mitch.
He's like,
to me,
one of the more amazing comedians ever
because what he would do was a complete
nonsequitors who would go from one non
sequitur to another nonsequitor nothing
connected together other than here.
Here's some other shit.
I thought up.
You know,
here's another shit I wrote down and,
and even though not through probably a
good idea for everyone to know that does
one liners,
that there still has to be an essence of
you.
And I'm like,
even though he's jokes didn't segue
together like they seem you're still,
you knew who he was,
but his jokes obviously like the,
oh,
he had a,
you know,
he definitely had there not just
individual jokes,
just glued it all together.
They were all so silly.
Right,
exactly.
That's the thing about.
I've always said the best way to
describe him,
he's like one of my favorite silly
comedians.
I know.
It's funny.
A lot of people you don't hear,
always complimentary.
Of course it's silly and that's what I
realized later after he died,
like how silly.
He was.
Silly,
so silly.
So that was who he was.
Very silly.
So that,
that's what you know about him,
you know,
he was the type of comedian he would get
into his rhythm,
like I would listen to him a lot of
times on the way to the airport because
uh,
I was,
you know,
that traffic on the way to the airport
is annoying.
He just wanted to just chill out and
giggle.
So I'd put on some Mitch Hedberg I just
be fucking giggling like,
and when you're just smiling when you're
not,
when he's,
you know,
in between punchlines and just have a
big smile on your face because he,
he would put on this silly vibe and you
would get caught up in it because it was
really fun.
And then he had such great writing too
and playful.
It was,
yeah,
yeah.
His Daddy,
I think in Rodney had a lot of that too.
You know,
Rodney's seriously,
seriously underrated comedian and his
style.
There was a great article about it
recently,
didn't we talk about this on the podcast
at Rod.
There was an article that was written
recently about Rodney,
I forget who wrote it like esquire and
one of those things,
but they were talking about how long it
took him to become a good comedian that
it wasn't until he was in his fifties,
but he figured it out and it's like
talking about him boiling down his act
and talking about how many cutting all
the fat out of his act.
If you go back and listen to his early
performances and you could see as more
meandering and then towards the more
standup p and I,
I realized that a few years ago and
you'll listen to the old ones and he
would like,
in other words of Joe,
could be was still rodney,
but it would be like this is more of a,
a joke.
A comedian will tell.
Not really one line to be like,
you know,
like you know,
you're old when your
family tells you.
You know when your,
when your family talks in front of you,
hey,
you know,
my pups in the garage,
we got people coming over,
you know,
pop just sits there and drools.
But that was more like a piece and I
forgot about that.
Rodney and then there's a lot of,
you know,
just a short little stories but they're
not.
And then all of a sudden I saw him,
my board member,
Bob Nelson Nelson opened for him and
then I got to meet Rodney backstage
through Bob and you know,
it is when you think,
you know something,
it plays with everything,
sexism.
You think you know what it is,
but you really don't.
There's still a lot more to learn.
Of course I knew what timing was before
I saw Rodney.
I could tell you I was a comedian for 10
years at that point,
but I know timing is.
But then when he saw Rodney,
I went,
oh fuck,
that's timing.
It was so like I knew what it was,
but I just got a doctor in and what it
was.
I just saw it delivered like the best of
the best of the best and it,
and I go now that I like,
I would,
I mean it was just crazy with the,
at every turn and every and then just
just when you think,
how can he take you anywhere in the band
kicks in and then he's like,
you know,
doing bedding music and all this the
other day and my wife are shit.
And then the pump,
they got bigger and bigger.
Then he started singing this song
because everybody's saying them.
But Rodney did it in his own way.
He starts going,
you know,
uh,
something about to dream that whatever
the song is.
And then he,
he does about 10 seconds of it.
And then he goes,
what the fuck am I singing for?
I'm watching him.
I'm going,
Oh my God,
you ago,
just a band.
But uh,
he goes,
I know that this bad to you.
They're just a band.
But to me a bunch of fucking idiots.
And then the band has their taught
because they're all musicians from that
city.
Obviously they're taught,
you know,
so he goes,
no,
don't tell you what they are.
They're not,
and then they all stand up and they go,
we're fucking idiots.
I got to see Rodney when I was 19 when I
was working as a security guard.
A great woods.
Great Woods is a concert place in
Mansfield,
Massachusetts,
and Rodney was there in the bathrobe
era.
Did you see bathrobe?
Ron Rodney.
Oh,
he went out on stage in a bathrobe naked
with a bathrobe on the Improv.
You would show up and you're saying he
was doing arenas.
This place is big break thousand people.
Isn't that great in a way that he was a
fucking maniac.
He was a fucking maniac.
He was amazing.
He was so free.
He was hanging backstage and apparently
his cock is enormous.
His cock and balls were just hanging
out.
He didn't give a fuck.
He just got this bathrobe on and he's
got his legs crossed.
Is fucking sack is hanging down and the
security guards would be like,
what the fuck,
dude?
I didn't see that.
I only saw him.
It's like a bigfoot sighting and I met
him later in life,
but to me like in 1990,
I hadn't even thought about doing stand
up yet.
It was such a huge fan
of it.
He walked from,
you know,
like,
like you're looking down the hallway to
where his dressing room and he walked
from one room to another.
It was like,
what?
Bigfoot sighting.
Like I always saw him for a second,
but I saw Rodney.
It's like that.
It's,
you know,
I said seeing Rodney was like,
it's not like seeing the,
like you saw Paul Mccartney or you.
Yeah,
you'd freak out.
But seeing Rodney was like getting to
see if you sell Fred Flintstone.
You can't see Fred Flintstone.
He's a cartoon.
Rodney is so larger than life that it
was overwhelming.
You weren't just going taking in someone
that was a celebrity and you see it on
tv,
but there he is.
There he is like three feet from you and
you'd be like,
fuck,
that's Rodney.
What does that between his legs?
No,
shut up.
Kind of getting covered by something.
Is that real?
Yeah.
Oh,
that's his boss.
That's the sack or his dick or both.
He's an animal.
Bob would have bombed out someone of
great stories about like,
and they were so specific and you knew,
Rodney said them and it was just so a
couple came up to him after their
wedding and they go,
uh,
do you know this one?
No.
And they go,
uh,
if he could.
He was trying to gamble.
You know,
Rodney,
we just got married.
What do you think?
And he goes,
oh,
you're both could have done better.
What do you think?
That's a well disguised insult.
I'm telling you,
it's a beautiful joe goes.
People won't know that it was an insult
or they get in their car.
Wait a second.
That means he says we're both.
We're both ugly.
Cancel now.
That's playing ping pong in their head.
Ductile both good and said,
who is that an insult to?
That wife goes,
it's an insult to you.
I think it's both of us.
You Moron.
That's when you find out who the Boston
relationship is.
Joke like that.
Why?
Who has to take it?
It's me who's taking the hit.
Yeah.
Who feels bad about this one?
Maybe you both be honest and just to
make or both.
Maybe a great thing when someone feels
like they're too good looking for the
other person in the relationship and
that you could they be wrong?
Yeah.
That could be wrong.
I mean there are,
there are people that like different
things,
you know,
there's people like different looks.
Some guys like big girls,
you know,
who knows,
people like different shit,
but if you think they don't like you as
much as you'd like them,
can I tell you what you do to prevent
that?
What do you do?
I hope I'm answering.
I hope,
um,
is that like,
because you know,
when people tell stories will be like
and,
and everything was great.
I think this is addressing what you're
saying.
Everything was great and then it just,
he or he or she,
he or she or she,
whatever the relationship is,
somebody else goes and they wanted to
end that.
Everything was great lip look because
what do you want them to do?
Wait,
I'm not saying there's not rules and
feelings and how you present it,
but I think most of the time everything
is great and then you realized one day
you wake up and I've had to me,
I must've been on the other end of this
and they just don't
want to be in it,
but they stay in it because that doesn't
mean they don't not care about you,
so they stay in it and it gets bad.
You see it coming.
But so I always say I always let someone
know.
You let them know you're not crazy that
they learn that by what you tell about
past stories.
And I once said this to someone that was
very early,
early,
early on,
but I said I have a feeling.
I practice it in my head and I was glad
I did it and I was like 23 or four at
the time.
I said,
I have a feeling that I like you more
than you liked me.
And I said,
I,
it's okay.
I go,
let me say this because I don't want
this to be the day where I threw you
off.
If I'm wrong,
I really like you,
so if you're,
if I just read it wrong,
that's great.
But,
but,
but that's the.
I don't think that's it.
I go,
I won't.
Of course I'll be sad,
but I won't hate you.
I won't be.
I'll be okay.
So then,
and then he was like,
you're right.
And because I set it in a way that I
could,
that he would be comfortable to say,
you know what,
if I put a little bit of choke,
a little bit of swell,
but I was okay and I,
and I want to know that.
So that's my question to be delusion.
I don't want to be delusional.
I felt it and I asked and I asked the
pack that the fact that I put that
preface in there,
look,
I need to let you know this is not to
make you feel bad,
but I do like you because I don't want
to find out.
Ten years later I thought you were
giving me walking papers.
So I had to be clear with my feelings,
but mainly let that person know.
And that way I didn't end up in a
relationship for another year where I
knew the other person might.
How could that go bad what I did?
There's no way that could go bad.
No,
especially if you're hanging out with
adults.
Right?
You know,
when I was a kid,
I think one of the things it took me a
long time to get past was it was always
thought that if you talked about your
feelings and your emotions,
that was weak.
That was a weakness.
It's not something you did with your
friends and it's not something you
wanted to do with a girl.
You didn't,
you just,
you didn't want to talk about your
emotions.
You didn't want to talk about how you
actually felt about things.
You wanted to play it stoic.
You want to Charles Bronson your way
through life.
You know,
that's a lot of guys tried to do.
And um,
that not understand like we don't the,
one of the big problems with people
because you don't really know who you
like until you're around them for a
while.
You really don't.
And then sometimes you're like,
oh,
I'm not into this person.
This is the.
I'm so bored.
I can't have any more of these
conversations.
I can't do this.
I can't do it.
I'm panicking.
I got to get out and then.
But everything was perfect.
Everything was going amazing.
No,
no,
no.
You thought everything was going
amazing.
It doesn't mean everything was going
amazing means you didn't even check in.
Right or the other way.
But no,
that makes be bored as fuck with dudes
where it's the same thing.
That's why we say that like,
I'm,
I'm comfortable having the only reason I
get nervous having relationship
discussions when somebody's going to
heavy on women are crazy.
I'm like,
that was any truth to that.
You look at same sex couples if,
if,
if it was traded by.
There's a lot of women.
I think men are crazy.
If that was true,
if there's any truth to that.
It's people.
There's people that are evolved and
there's people that are,
you know,
have a deep level head on their
shoulders.
Because if there was any truth,
that one section was crazier.
There's a science to disproving that.
Then in lesbian relationships that you'd
go,
hey,
how's your relationship?
And they'd go,
well,
of course we argue a teeny bit here and
there,
but no,
no,
we're both women.
So we're getting along great now.
What we got rid of the problem and in
Male male relationships,
the same problems.
It's not like you go,
oh yeah,
we don't have the crazy women.
So when it's two guys date and
everything is great.
No same exact problem.
So it's not the sex,
it's people.
Does that make you,
you're a hundred percent correct.
You could not be more correct.
And there's a real problem.
We got a really avoid this shit.
There's people that'll say things like,
you know,
women are all dumb,
bitches are men are all p Shit and that
that's nonsense.
This,
these gender based generalizations are
so stupid.
There's nice people that are women.
There's nice people that are men.
It's just,
there's plenty of them.
You can't have a few bad relationships
and turn on other people and every
person has the same gender and also like
take a good look at yourself because if
you really,
you know,
there's,
there's some people out there that do
generalize like that,
like look at who look at your shit,
thinking that you're just diarrhea
spraying out into the world.
You know?
I mean,
that's really what it is.
Whether you're a sexist against women
are as sexist against men.
You have such a piss poor way of looking
at things.
Everybody knows you're wrong.
You think that,
I mean,
whatever it is,
any generalization,
whether it's a racist generalization,
sexist,
homophobic,
it's all.
Everybody who's listening knows what it
is.
You know what it is and someone makes a
generalization like you're not.
No,
you're not looking at it,
right?
You don't know nice people that are
black.
You don't know any nice people that are
That's ridiculous.
Like,
who the fuck are you?
how can you make this judgment when I've
met so many?
Like you're not meeting enough people or
they meet you and they go,
oh,
this guy's a fucking asshole.
So they avoid you.
So everybody's got this thing that
they're spreading about you.
Yeah.
That's why younger people tend to,
you know,
just by being around.
I wish there was a place you could go if
you couldn't afford college because I
don't think it's the education at
college that you probably learned the
most from.
It's the being forced to be around other
people.
You Go,
oh,
I'd rather hang out with that group that
I hated because we have the same taste
in music and you learn it because you're
forced to live together,
but I wish it wouldn't it be cool if
there was like,
where can you go if you're like,
well,
I don't want afford college,
but I want to put my kids around all.
Well,
some parents wouldn't want to do it,
but kids could.
I just want to be around every type of
person,
but you don't know to do that college.
That's the thing about college and I
didn't go to college.
I didn't even graduate high school,
but it isn't that true that that's where
a lot of growing does with young kids
when they're fortunately or another.
Some kids,
they're living with really suppressive
parents and the only way they even know
who the fuck they are is if they could
sleep in their own bed with open their
own door with their own key going into
their own room,
lie and then just be alone and be away
from these other fucking people that are
constantly giving you these rules that
you have to follow and have these lofty
expectations for your success and like
fucking Christ.
You don't even know what you want to do
and they want you to do something that's
going to pay a lot of money.
We're spending a lot of money sent you
to sculpt todd.
We want to make sure that you're
productive,
productive todd.
Don't drinking,
no gallivanting in their work,
work,
and meanwhile you just finally get a
chance to listen to some music that you
never heard before and hang out with
some people from some part of the
country he never been.
Maybe you smoke weed with them,
you hang out and you're,
you know,
you're 18,
19 years old and you're just figuring
out the worker a lot of stuff.
Yeah,
and you're free of the fucking parents.
That's a big part of it.
Ben,
free of the parents to in every
generation,
every generation is more aware of how
fucking stupid the previous generation
was.
Like there was some grand grandpappy
days back on the fucking farm when they
would,
they would talk about their grandparents
and their grandparents were wiser than
them.
You know,
that's not the case anymore.
The people today are more informed than
any human beings that have ever lived
ever.
By the way,
you have just said.
The only thing that I agree with when it
comes to [inaudible],
I always say,
look,
of course there's things we should go
back and get,
but mostly tomorrow's a better day,
but it goes when there's something in
the past that,
oh,
that's struggle.
Oh,
we should go back to that and learn
that.
I'm not just saying,
but very rarely does someone get me.
Mostly.
I always go now and I,
I get it from another,
but that is something,
but it explains everything that's going
on right now,
that two kids,
while I always say kids are getting
smarter than their parents,
you smarter and the and um,
it makes me want to be like a,
uh,
a,
a progressive bully.
Like I try to say I called you,
I called her,
he said that about you on.
So mark married,
not that word,
but I go,
I need people that are like,
I think I might've said a bully but on
the right side of history.
So it was a compliment.
Thank you.
And what I meant is a big God.
It's like,
yeah,
fucking,
but that's what I said.
So,
but you still,
you still,
when I say it,
like as a character,
like you still,
you know,
you look,
you still,
you have clean thoughts and you and you
and you've changed your views on things.
But when I say it like I want to be so
mean.
Like I want to be so fucking mean the
other way.
Like I know what you mean like dice
clay,
but with just anybody you don't want gay
marriage,
die already go home and die.
Why can't people live and you ain't even
drop dead.
I hope your baby just the most vicious
things,
but all about people that won't like the
you know all about does it mean.
Yeah,
no,
there's definitely some merit in that.
Just people realize how fucking stupid
is because you're mocking it so
relentlessly and everybody's cheering
along and then someone who might be
entertaining those thoughts is going to
listen to it.
There's a guy on Sam Harris' podcast
this week waking up with Sam Harris.
His name is Christian ecoline and he
used to be a white male supremacist and
you get recruited when he was 14 years
old and was in it for like,
I think he said eight years or something
like that and just was talking to Sam
Harris about these horrific decisions
that he had made and his group that he
had got connected to and they were
committing violent crimes against black
people and like all this crazy shit that
he was talking about.
And then you listen to him now as this
guy in his forties is like super
rational and very intelligent and well
read and it's like saying,
look,
I just got caught up in this ideology.
I went down this road and other people
were doing the thinking for me and we
were all doing it for each other.
It became this horrific group think that
he got swept up in.
I think that's happening with
progressive people too.
I think there's a this,
this,
this need to be right and to shout down
each other and and ruthlessly mock each
other like that has to be used.
Like nuclear weapons,
like only in,
in the case of severe issues were like,
you've got a country.
Another country is about to develop a
nuclear weapon.
They're gonna go after you first or
they've already done it and you have to
disarm their nukes.
Got to be nicer to each other when it
comes to talking about these ideas,
because every time someone from the left
attacks relentlessly and ruthlessly and
viciously,
someone from the right because of their
ideas.
You just start a back and forth.
You're not,
you're not looking at it in a way like
there's gotta be some way to communicate
your ideas in a friendly way.
You know what I do now and believe me,
I'm guilty of this and I when I even
from when I did my netflix special to
now the way I do for jokes or like I
changed it because that whole thing.
Look,
todd,
do you want to take people with you?
Or because someone said,
I don't want to be Tucker Carlson to the
other side,
so flip it in.
So fucking snarky that.
So I go,
okay,
that's maybe what I am.
I don't see it when I agree with the
person.
So if I see someone that's snarky but it
says everything,
I agree,
but I go.
So I do want to sometimes bring people.
So change the way you say go in a little
softer.
Maybe you're trying to bring somebody
with you and bring them over.
But sometimes I want to split the
difference and I could be wrong because
sometimes I think when I'm screaming at
the top of my lungs and I literally have
to take a break on the podcast,
you know about something maybe that
gives and it's about a transgender
issue,
something I'm not going through,
but I'm able to scream it.
So someone that's going through it goes,
God damn it house,
he's so close.
Or when I can yell about a women's
issue.
So the Goddamn it screamed at the top of
my lungs because they say screaming
about what you're not.
Because you can get angrier.
Maybe it gives someone their dignity
back.
Maybe sometimes screaming into the
Canyon is okay,
but not to another person's face right
into the canyon of podcasting or.
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
But when it comes.
But.
But then you have to decide because the
podcast is always a canyon.
I think it's also you have
ability so someone is going to attack
you.
Maybe the only way they have the
abilities to do it in a twitter post or
a blog post.
I mean,
they're all people with their own
opinions too,
right?
Yeah.
That's why you've got to look at things.
You always.
Yeah.
That's why I said I,
you know,
you then.
That's
why I'm very aware that now trying just
way too much stupid fighting.
There's,
there's,
there's debate over issues about real
things.
Like right now what's going on with
this?
What do they call it?
Walk for our lives,
watch for our lives.
Can I go ahead real quick?
Because I prefer I have a few times and
there's a belief in one post I want to
take down because it's a woman that
technically me and it turned into a
sexist words flying back and forth and I
want to take it down.
If I could post why I'm taking it down.
Because I think when somebody,
even when your fans are defending you,
I like when someone corrects their fans.
No,
no,
that don't offend me with those words.
You know,
don't.
Uh,
so you're talking about before about
when the verbiage is,
you know,
so always try to go in.
I think you're responsible if you're,
if you're,
if they're flying things back and forth
and you're in a twitter war,
if somebody's saying something,
go in and say no,
you know the word.
You don't have to start throwing around
these words has nothing even to do with
the topic.
If they're just,
that's the way they express themselves.
Like the way people disagree about
things can change.
Like the way they communicate,
their disagreement can change how it
gets resolved,
you know,
and.
But what always happens is if you go
hard,
they go hard pack and I think we're,
we're dealing with that back and forth
in this country.
And what I was going to say is about
this walk far march for our lives,
our lives is that what I'm seeing that's
very confusing to me is from people who
are gun supporters,
like the NRA supporters who and some of
them have even mocked these kids for
getting attention by going to these
marches and stuff like that.
And they're saying that nobody would
have heard of you or nobody know who you
are.
Like this is a ridiculous way to look at
it.
They,
it's very defensive because they're,
if they're feeling like someone's coming
after their guns,
so they're
going on the attack in some ways that's
just really not recommended.
Like the way they're doing their,
the bench mark.
They're mocking what the what the reason
would be for these kids to be on tv that
got shot at these kids that got shot at
and they're fucking 16 years old and
they're going to be on TV and someone's
mock know would know who you were if it
wasn't for this thing or.
Yeah,
of course,
but they went through that fucking thing
there.
The few kids that have gone through this
thing and the country that are standing
on the public stage and saying,
look at us.
You got to do something.
You can't have the same shit happened
over and over and over again,
and maybe they don't have the most
complicated solution,
but there.
Right.
And they're,
they're,
they're forcing people to talk and if
anybody should be forcing people to
talk.
It's the kids that were around their
friends that got shot,
who realized there fucking parents are
working all day and they come home tired
and no one's going to fix nothing.
No one has the time and the patients all
in bed
with the NRA and all these different
organizations is if they're on the left
and everybody's beholden to their
special interest groups,
so these kids are seeing all this shit
and they know nothing's gonna happen.
Nothing's going to happen.
More kids are going to get shot,
more kids are going to get shot,
and then what are the NRA people do?
They mock these kids.
That's crazy.
At what point does someone pull you
aside and go,
I picture,
I don't believe in violence,
obviously relationships,
but in the old movies when somebody
would have to stop back,
that's just stops full disdain for any
retaliation.
He's not even trying to hit someone
with.
The best part is,
you know,
you hit some with the back of your hand.
The back of your hand is generally more
sensitive.
It's like it hurts.
I'll give you hit someone in the back of
your hand.
You can hurt your hand like I know a lot
of guys have broken their hands in a
fight because they hit someone with a
spinning back fist with the back of
their hand.
It's not protected.
So that's just letting somebody know.
I'm so excited.
Have you?
We're just saying how to be more
peaceful.
I'm,
I'm.
What I'm saying is when somebody doesn't
even mean we're not,
I'm not saying don't have a conversation
and don't disagree.
Of course I'm not.
We're saying the person that wants to
shake you and stop you is once you start
making fun of these kids,
someone even that agrees with you,
that there shouldn't be any.
Isn't there someone on that side,
they can go stop.
And I guess there are,
but when,
when they say,
you know,
you should learn to see rick,
Rick,
uh,
what's his name?
Rick.
I'm the guy who said if they,
the kid should,
instead of looking for someone else to
solve their problems,
they should learn cpr.
Rick Santorum.
Yeah.
That makes you not like,
that doesn't even make sense.
You actually said that doesn't make
sense.
Doctors were tweeting it brilliantly,
like you know,
like that's like,
so you're saying John Lennon,
would that be alive if you'll go a new
cpr,
is that what you're saying?
Right.
You just gotta use CPR to repair that,
blown out liver and they explained that
to him,
but then he talked about combating kids.
I thought that was a great way.
Just some really clean tweets from
doctors breaking it down very cleanly.
This would not.
Doesn't make any sense to them as a
Republican.
So there you go.
So what if I could just stop?
One thing I really feel like is really
important to this.
I think both the people on the right and
the people on the left have way more in
common than they think they have a part
and I think that a lot of the battle
that people in the left habits just
they've chosen to be on the left,
the same people in the right.
They've chosen to be on the right.
So anything that happens on the left,
they completely disagree with.
They.
They immediately go,
oh,
that's a left wing liberal idea.
And they just have these little back and
forth with each other that are
completely unnecessary.
I think the majority of people just want
everybody to get along and not have
crime.
You think Bernie Sanders maybe could
have done that.
Not good to have one,
but what would have happened if he got
the problem with Bernie is the same
reason why he let those black lives.
People take his mic and start screaming
into the thing like,
hey buddy can't do that.
You're running for fucking
president.
You're showing right here that people
could just storm the stage.
Take the microphone from you like you
should say,
I would love to have a dialogue with
you.
Let's do it publicly.
Let's schedule it now.
We'll come back.
We'll get a large group of people and
I'll speak with you on this stage if you
represent this very important political
movement,
but here's what you can't do.
You can't disrespect this campaign
speech because you are literally
stopping people from ever voting for me
if I let you do it,
because that's the fact.
What if he watched him do that and then
go,
you can't let kids just take over your
show.
You can.
You're the guy who's supposed to be
running the country.
You can't even run this fucking thing.
You've got this one thing.
You're standing on a stage in front of
300 people.
Three of them just took your mic.
Congratulations.
You don't have leadership ability,
but what about other than that?
That's a big part.
That's big.
That's not good,
that's not good,
but you know what?
In the moment he made an error.
That doesn't mean that's who he is.
He's part of the problem is when people
are judging you by these moments that
you have,
right,
and it doesn't define him.
He might've done that and go,
well,
yeah,
I was just trying to be nice.
I didn't expect that.
I thought security was going to get them
out of there,
but they didn't get.
No,
they didn't.
Well,
they wound up on the stage with them
screaming.
I thought maybe he.
I didn't see him when he did those types
of things.
A few times.
See the video,
want to see it is kind of interesting.
I thought it was his way of saying,
look,
I get it.
What it must feel like to not be able to
be heard and it's not my fault that no
one's ever listened to you so far,
but what do we have to do?
And then maybe he feels they go up and
they just a sane person would lead.
It would leave the same person.
When you ignore that long,
they just grab a mic and maybe he goes,
I have to be a part of letting this
person spill out.
A little
problem is then who doesn't spill out?
Everybody can spill out.
Everybody can jump up for their own
cause,
whether it's white power or fucking Jews
lives matter,
whatever it is.
You could just decide you have a group
now and your group may very well be
valid,
but you can just decide now you're just
going to yell out when whenever there's
some sort of a political speech and then
it'll be your chance to talk and just
going to take the mic and make it all
about you.
Yeah,
there's got to be.
There are a lot of things we need to be
concerned with.
We need to be concerned with war we need
do we need to be concerned with poverty,
education,
healthcare,
all these different things,
but you can't just represent each one of
these very,
very important groups and jump on stage
everywhere and start yelling.
Do you know what I thought?
Does that make sense?
Yes,
I should be.
I should be just done with you.
No,
no.
Why?
It's because this subject is.
It gets so exhausting.
I know.
Let me add one more thing.
No,
because I,
by the way,
you know,
you have these theories in your head and
then sometimes somebody will respond and
and blow it out,
you know,
just on your omega.
I never thought about that,
but I had this theory.
It was a weird way that I thought about
it.
Well two things.
One kids do.
I'm stealing from the act that teeny
bit,
but just because it's a stat I use in
the kids do.
If there was yelp review,
young adults have an amazing yelp review
for being on the right side.
Who they,
who they root for,
who they are.
I think music
dealing with some left wing democratic
out here.
Kids like what?
Do you ever talked to some kids from
Alabama,
but I'm talking about on the masses of
kids that,
that March.
Oh,
the ones that are ones that march the
ones that get involved.
If you go back and look at like,
you know,
Kent State or you know,
I'm sorry.
I'm sure we could.
We can pull up 50.
But so with that said,
now I'm not saying we shouldn't doubt
them.
If I had a gun to my head and someone
said if we had a crystal ball,
are they making the right choice about
Bernie Sanders?
These kids.
And I go,
Oh,
let me ask you.
I got to talk about that for five.
I got to watch a campaign.
I got to watch a debate.
I can.
How's he going to handle public policy?
How's he going to.
I can't just ask.
They go,
we're going to shoot you in your head.
I go with kids overwhelmingly kids like
him.
Yeah,
he's got to do the right thing and I
think if there was a crystal ball,
here's my theory,
but I've never said this.
I think out loud that maybe 50 years
from now,
just like we're learning about history,
they would talk about him in the way
that,
you know,
this guy came into office,
picks your kids and they're telling them
why maybe 2000,
22 started to be these good times and
there's talking about history and a guy
came in the office and he really didn't
know anything about the.
The he didn't really know about was he
was not.
He didn't know about war.
He didn't know about.
No and no one thought he could really do
it,
but he was one thing that you wouldn't
think would answer our economical
problems.
You can be a nice hearted person,
but that's not going to answer your
economical problems,
but it ended up doing that because he,
he did truly treat everybody kind and it
ended up then when people started to be
treated fairly.
If the world worked better with less
depressed people,
I'm not saying everybody,
but people would torture people.
We had someone empowered.
It was overwhelmingly kind and people
felt the wrath that almost very quickly
maybe we go and then you know what?
No one ever thought this than some of
the economical problems worked out the
work themselves out.
Now that is based on no science.
No.
Well,
yeah,
I'm acknowledging that,
but that was in my head that
the economy is apparently a very
complicated thing that can be
interpreted many ways.
Like there are many people right now
that will tell you the economy has never
been better.
Stock market's booming.
Uh,
black people are more employed today
than ever in history,
and these are like the mega people,
right?
They'll,
they'll jump on that and other people
will tell,
you know,
we're,
we're sitting on a bunch of huge
bubbles,
a commercial real estate bubble and
credit bubble and all this different
shit that could go down at any moment.
There's all sorts of problems.
We're getting automated cars soon.
It's going to put thousands of people
out of jobs if not millions.
You know?
It's hard to figure out who the fuck's
right?
It's hard.
It's when you talk about like a dummy
like you or myself and trying to
prognosticate like what would make
people successful and would make people
not what I.
I don't know about the economic part,
but what I do know is his long as you
have a person who's kind but also from
like a person who's kind,
but you also.
You're not worried about them.
If something happens with China or
Russia,
like we live in a crazy world.
We live in a world where there's really
basically three superpowers but one
motherfucker of a superpower and that's
us,
but we're run by a guy who used to host
celebrity apprentice.
Okay.
Like it's gotten super squirrely.
It's super squirrely and there's all
these other people that are other
superpowers that are going,
what's going on over there?
That place don't look so fucking
healthy.
That place looks a little fucked up
right now and this is like they're
expelling Russian diplomats and all this
crazy shit's going down and,
and potent just one another election and
we're watching this thing go down
between the top three superpowers in one
of them is one by a maniac,
maybe two of them are,
but one of them is run by a guy who
knows a maniac and we put them in there
and a lot of people are still going
along with it and they like it.
So I.
Oh,
I got a question for you.
Okay.
With no,
not,
not like snarky or anything because I
was trying to think like,
you know,
like there's more things you said we
have in common.
Then there's got to be some
commonalities.
Freedom.
Freedom's number one would be one that
you could like.
Because I always think like anything I
could get,
defend trombone,
even if it's stupid.
I go out of my way to defend it one
time.
Someone who,
it doesn't matter what it was.
There were two times and I did.
I went,
no,
that's the.
He didn't do anything or what's
something positive about trump that you
or what they want to build,
they want to pass or something they want
to do that you think I'm okay with that.
Like what?
What are some of those things?
Are there any.
As far as bills,
you're like something you can be
positive.
Even meet in the middle and you said
that and
seen anything.
That made me very excited.
I've seen more things that made me very
nervous.
The offshore drilling,
that makes me very nervous.
Obviously those things break sometimes.
We've had a few of them in our
lifetimes.
The Alaska one,
that was a big one.
I remember that it happened right when I
was in high school or no,
I was right when I was starting to do
standup.
That's what it was like literally right
around then the valve ds had crashed and
leaked all that oil into and just
destroyed this delicate ecosystem with
millions of gallons of oil or whatever
it was.
How many thousands gallons or whatever
the fuck it was,
but that they're gonna,
they're gonna have more offshore
drilling.
That scares the shit out of me.
They they're getting rid of certain
public parks and shrinking them and
opening up these,
drilling these,
these areas for drilling and natural
resources that make people very nervous.
In doing this,
they could be damaging rivers and that
these delicate ecosystems where people
go and hike and camp through and they're
going to close these down.
That's the real concern.
The real is that gonna
people are gonna somehow or another
we're gonna suffer because so that some
companies can profit incredibly off of
natural land,
natural resources that are on public
land.
That's a big fear because that's some
shit that is really unusual about this
country and some some shit that Teddy
Roosevelt saw way,
way in advance.
He saw the benefit of doing this,
of having these massive national parks.
Yeah,
sure.
In in one.
What about positive?
I was asking because you're saying that
that's the number one negative,
all this social stuff.
I mean,
I feel like the most hilarious thing is
that Kim Jong.
Owen actually wants to talk to him.
It's like,
this guy is so crazy.
Maybe maybe I'll just talk to them.
I mean like what he wants to tell
nobody.
Nobody else wanted to have meetings with
that guy.
Right?
He's wanted to talk to a president for
the longest time and they would talk to
him.
Right?
Because they don't want to give them
that good photo opportunity.
At the very least.
That's hilarious.
They're worried about their facebook
page.
Would we witness that if they talked?
Fuck yeah.
We would witness it and trump would
tower over them.
It'd be so creepy.
Trump's a big guy and you see what
happens when you ever seen pictures of
him with desert robin.
Do you ever see pictures of Kim Johnson?
I'm good,
dude.
Kim Jong swoon is a huge basketball fan,
apparently.
And loves Dennis Rodman.
Dennis Rodman goes to North Korea
parties,
right?
Right.
Dennis Rodman,
like if trump was smart.
I know trump hired Amarosa.
Trump's definitely hired Dennis Rodman.
Fucking 100 percent,
like 100 percent.
Say Dennis Rodman.
Please would you be my emissary?
Look at that.
Without big.
Dennis Rodman is as large fellow and
he's not even big compared to like a
really big guy.
Right?
Like Lebron.
What if he had big,
but what's his name?
King a King Jong what?
Kim Jong wound.
They still can't get a picture of Kim
Jong,
Il.
John with Dennis Rodman.
What if you were like,
Eh,
you think it'd be bad if you went like
foot high platforms?
Deadly already.
But he denied it.
Yeah,
he probably would.
And he had long pants trying to cover
them while he's Korean.
Well,
he's North Korean.
Uh,
there's some Korean folks that are
pretty big.
Um,
I remember,
um,
when I was a kid,
the kid who won the heavyweight national
title is named Jimmy Kim.
He was a big Korean kid,
big heavyweight kid who was really good.
Six foot five.
So I don't know how big Kim Jong Luna's,
but I bet he looks tiny compared to
Dennis Rodman.
Two foot three.
I just looked it up on my phone.
Wow.
That was quick.
I think,
um,
it would be a weird meeting,
but it might actually be okay.
It might be good.
This people gotta,
something's gotTa break over there like
what they're doing is just saying the
way they keep those people essentially
hostage.
There's no food.
The people that have escaped had
horrible fucking parasites in their body
and like,
see,
I feel bad.
I don't know.
So guys escaped and got shot at
on the border.
Fascinating footage.
You're saying they keep them hostage.
Who are you talking about?
The people of North Korea,
they're essentially held hostage.
I mean they're there.
They're trapped by dear leader.
You know what they have to do?
Like if when when the dad died,
these people were all weeping in the
street and they had a weep like
outwardly,
loudly,
as long as they could do it,
and if you stop weeping early,
you'd be punished.
And people who they felt weren't weeping
enough got six months in jail.
It's a crazy place and everyone turns on
everyone.
Everyone,
rats,
everyone else out on everything they do.
You're supposed to meet together.
You go in front of this,
these people and you rat each other out
for all the different things you do.
Michael Mouse has a great book about it.
Is it called dear reader?
Is that the name of his book earlier,
Dear Leader or dear reader?
What do affiliates?
Dear reader,
he's a funny guy,
Michael Malice,
but I'm feeling North Korea.
Do you ever hear something?
You're like,
I should know that.
Like I should know it too.
That's one of the things about this
podcast is just being able to talk to it
is dear reader,
being able to talk to people on this
podcast and you get like a little quick
three hour course and what the fuck's
going on in North Korea?
So Michael was amazing for that.
And you know,
who else was Henry rollins was Henry
rollins went over there as a fucking.
A tourist wandered around over there.
That guy is an animal.
That guy goes everywhere and he just
went over to uh,
what was the,
was there a purpose?
Rollins just picks a spot on the map.
You should listen to his podcast.
He did with Ra should fear.
That's the one that really got me.
I mean,
I changed my.
The way I look at Henry,
I always,
I always liked his music,
always liked to spoken word stuff and
Zach thing stuff and this is his
attitude,
just a no bullshit sort of a guy.
He's got a little saying that he put on
the back wall of one of the clubs that I
worked,
one of the theaters that I worked about,
the people that work there,
you know the,
the,
you know how you're,
you're the lucky one,
so you should,
you should be very thankful that these
people who work way harder than you make
way less money than you.
And I'm like,
that's the guy that's like looking at it
the right way.
So he takes us,
he takes the fucking spot pointed down
on the map and he's like,
okay,
let's try Bahrain and he just fucking
travels to Bahrain.
You know,
he'll go to the middle of Africa and go
to Cameroon.
He just travels there.
He doesn't know anybody there.
He buys water when he gets there,
brings his fucking camera and some
clothes and a laptop and he takes
pictures and then he writes it.
It doesn't do any shows or,
and he's a fucking animal dude.
He's crazy.
No,
she hasn't just shows anymore.
It doesn't do shows anymore.
He does spoken word performances.
He doesn't do any music anymore and says
I'm done.
I don't want to do it anymore.
And just writes books and just writes a
lot of articles,
writes articles for like a bunch of
different publications.
But I mean he's super prolific and I
really enjoy his writing.
His writing is,
it's,
it's like,
it's crisp,
it's energetic.
It's
like he writes like the way he talks and
the way he behaves,
like he appreciates your attention span,
you know,
he's enthusiastic about what he's
talking about and he's got some shit to
say.
Bam.
Well,
it sounds like something I,
I'm not a good reader,
but I could get it on books,
on tape because just hearing it directly
yet because I get,
I,
I like when someone speaks to me very
specifically get lost very easily made
to.
Um,
what did I have to say about rollins?
Said he went to North Korea to.
He's an animal.
A guy went everywhere,
but how long will he go somewhere,
like a couple of weeks.
Whatever the fuck he wants.
He's Henry rollins and he has money so
he got to stay in a nice way to do
whatever you want.
There's no nice hotels.
There's places where there is no nice
hotels where there's no nice hold.
You're not living in the lap of luxury
in Cameroon,
know you take what they got and you
know,
you just hang with the people.
It'd be like the locals,
you know,
meet some cool people,
hang out with them.
That's the reality.
The guy was just um,
you know,
feeling as travel,
oats and really got into it and now it's
like a,
uh,
it's recreated.
It's not just recreation,
you know,
it's,
it's a recreation,
but it's also like a life perspective
altering burst that you give yourself,
you know,
you're going to Pakistan and wandering
the streets of Karachi and Pakistan,
like,
what,
how did I do this?
Like,
this is crazy.
And then he's got to actually survive.
He's got to get out of those places.
Man,
I don't know if I could have so much ad.
I mean I know who he,
after you go through something like
that,
your,
your spirituality,
your va and I,
that part I admire,
but then doing it,
I just,
yeah,
I'm just,
I don't want to be in like,
you have to be uncomfortable and hot
and.
Oh yeah.
You get what I mean,
that'd be in trump's trouble.
You for sure.
I mean he's gone everywhere,
but yeah,
I'll just watch the documentary.
There's something about both of those
places tell.
Right?
Oh,
of course he never came places I've
gone.
You have to go camping.
When was the last time?
Um,
what else to maybe.
No,
no,
no.
About a year ago.
A year ago.
Where'd you guys go with two?
Oh,
I shot a pilot.
Sounds so cold camping with todd.
Oh really?
And we went,
we,
we shot it up.
It was me,
Zach Galifianakis and John Doren.
Eddie pepitone and oh,
that sounds awesome.
Close to letting it happen.
It happened,
you know,
it's weird.
We didn't end up.
We shot the pilot even a bad pilot,
but that's the premise.
I really did think,
and I don't ever think this,
but once in awhile I do have it,
just be honest with my thought,
I'll be like,
I think this is going to sell because
it's just camping with todd.
It's like you're on fire.
People are comfortable.
They talked to you have a musical
performance.
Who was playing the guitar?
That was,
that was John Door,
but he was just being silly and um,
as long as he's only being safe,
I will not tolerate some real live
singing by a fire.
And then at the end we did.
We had someone come out with like a
trumpet and guitar and they did a real.
So Kuumba,
Yasser public domain and um,
and then we.
And then we tried to sell it and no one
was really interested.
So it's okay,
you know,
what is that thing that people do where
they like hire someone who play Acoustic
Guitar and sing songs in a restaurant
and they like walk over to a table.
Have you ever seen that?
Oh,
like a Mariachi or not even a Mariachi.
Just a guy with a guitar.
I was at a restaurant the other day and
this woman,
she had an amazing voice.
She was saying that Dolly Parton Song,
Jolene and she just had a nowhere.
Like I went to the bathroom,
came back,
this lady singing a song like I didn't
even have this happen here.
Magicians use to do that.
Oh,
that was the worst dude.
That's the worst.
Wait,
who did that?
It would interrupt conversation.
You'd be in the middle of a
conversation.
I'd like you to pick a card.
Oh Man.
Come on.
I'm not interested.
Thank you.
But if you say thank you,
you're the Dick.
Like I just came here to work food.
I don't want to do tricks.
Like even though I love closeup magic,
I really do.
To me it's the only magic there is,
but yeah,
if you're in the middle of a
conversation,
yeah,
I really do feel chicken meat.
If that's the name of your place,
it's magic and me and everybody knows
you get a magician.
The magician is going to come over and
come to the table and do his stuff in
front of you.
That is totally cool.
Not Against that,
like knowing,
but if you're in the middle of a
conversation and the magician comes over
and all of a sudden once you pick a card
like,
come on man,
we have some shit we have to talk about.
Just because we're in a public place
doesn't mean you can join in like we're
supposed to be.
We're paying,
we're paying here,
and then you can either be a magician or
some people would say conversation
stopper.
Yes.
You've got to go.
What do you put on your card?
Yeah.
It's not even his fault.
Is this the job?
That's his job.
What is he going to do?
Like that's what they hired him for.
Hey,
you want to work for us?
Sure,
I need a job.
Okay,
you're going to be a magician.
You're going to walk around the tables
and do magic in front of people.
Okay.
It's not his fault.
Right?
That's why restaurants fault.
That's why I always err on,
even though I was interrupting the
conversation,
I just,
I get it,
so I'm pretty polite and I uh,
and try to enjoy it and it's usually
pretty short.
But yeah,
I'm always wishing,
yeah,
we're just into this intense
conversation.
It depends on how high you are,
right?
If you're high,
you let the guy talk,
but if you had a cup of coffee,
you're like,
hey dude,
I can't live.
If you give them $500 you need.
If you own or manage a restaurant,
you need a closeup magician.
It's all capitals.
Listen to this.
Only happened to me twice ever.
And it wasn't the worst thing in the
world.
It's,
I just feel like unless it's in the name
of your restaurant,
you probably shouldn't do that.
It's not like something that happens a
lot.
I like magicians.
I love working with the comedy Magic
Club.
I used to back in the day before I used
to book my own show there.
When I would do a show,
I would work with a magician always.
So there's always like one comic,
a magician,
and then maybe one other comic.
I think that's how they did it.
They do it a bunch of different.
Oh yeah.
In the most of each.
Yeah.
That place.
Amazing.
That place is amazing that that place is
also like a museum comedy inside.
Well the,
they have like Popeye's outfit,
but Robin Williams more.
It's framed on the wall and those
signatures in that long.
In the green room.
It's a breezy.
It is array of signatures on a wall from
the last 35 years or 40 minutes.
Yeah,
it's crazy.
It's a long term to be similar and he's
such a nice guy too.
It's um,
I think that's the second oldest comedy
club in the world right now.
I think the ice house was number one and
comedy and magic.
Just slightly younger in terms of club.
And then where'd you,
where'd you go after that?
The comedy works in Denver.
Pretty close for olders.
The how old is economy works in Denver
can only be like 23 years old or
something.
Well I thought it was a 30.
Is it?
You might be right.
Yeah,
you didn't.
Roseanne start there.
Maybe Roseanne started there in Detroit.
Uh,
the,
uh,
it's the,
his name is in the title,
but still we're in the eighties,
right?
I mean they used to be some places.
The ice houses from the sixties.
The icehouse started.
Oh,
no,
I'm sorry.
I didn't mean older.
I just met with next on the list.
Where do you go to these places or not?
Yeah,
but I mean there's like a,
there's a few of the old,
old,
old places that are still around those,
like historical places,
like the comedy store is the most
historical,
but there's a lot of historical places
helium's historical now because how long
has helion been around for 13 years.
Yeah,
that's a spot where universally people
talk about that place.
I feel like Acme Acme in Minneapolis,
laughing skull in Atlanta.
That place is off the charts.
Intimate.
90 people.
Maybe if you've done it.
Yeah.
Fuck a curtain.
That goes amazing.
That's a good example of a room.
You're going down a hallway to a
restaurant.
Picture everybody.
Everyone has to go to a club for the
first time you go.
It's in the back of a restaurant.
You go down a hallway,
then all of a sudden,
even though it's a simple room,
is there's a sound booth,
there's lights,
the curtain shuts,
the lights go down,
and when I think every second year in a
club like that where they have
production,
you're like,
oh,
this is something you know,
like the audience that might not know
what to expect.
Now they know it's going to be good
sometimes even before the show starts,
just the way the police conducted itself
and then the house lights go out.
It's like a big deal.
So I love that.
That room is great.
Spot.
A lot of fun in that room.
It's another one of those really
intimate places.
I don't even think that's 100 people.
Right?
80 five 80 people.
Is that what it is?
Amazing.
Yeah.
Those spots,
man.
I counted.
I have a clicker because I'm going to.
Oh No,
no,
don't know.
That happened.
When someone did that,
like onstage made everybody call out a
number at a club somewhere.
Hope because probably to see like if
there was more than they said
Jacqueline,
he was working on some sort of a door
deal and he thought there was more
people in the room.
Then the club owner told him so he had
the audience individually count out a
number.
What?
Like we're gonna start from this table
over here and when I moved to the left,
your number one.
Ready Sarah go number one,
two,
three.
Hey,
and people would just hook your word to
three more number sitting there.
That proves that people just.
Some people want to yell out.
That was fun for them.
No one.
How many people were going,
oh right,
we don't need to do this,
but I think it was like a 350 seat room.
Wow.
Yeah,
so you didn't have the material.
Maybe it's totally,
totally,
totally possible,
but whatever it is,
that's how we found out.
Went through the whole room and he got
past the number that this guy said there
were and then there was still more
fucking people.
I wonder if that's true.
It's true.
I think it's true.
I think that it's the wait staff is what
told me about it and I think they were
very enthusiastic with their
descriptions.
So you think he caught them like a club
owner trying to hide how many could be
the good clubs that have been around
forever.
Overwhelmingly,
I've had almost perfect experiences like
the clubs that they're all pretty decent
so I forget sometimes what some of the
sheisty are ones because you hear
stories about people in the road like
manipulating the money and stuff,
but you do hear that that that can
happen with some clubs.
I think some club owners develop a very
animalistic animosity.
What?
What is that word?
Animosity.
That's not even a word.
It isn't.
I know what you're going to say though.
I'm writing.
When it came out of my mouth,
right as it was going out,
I was like,
is that a real word?
You know,
you can't exactly towards comedy,
but they developed this animosity
between each other.
The club owners don't want to book you.
You get mad at the club owners.
Then when you make it like,
fuck that guy,
I want more money.
Tell him,
fuck him,
you know,
and you,
there's this weird thing that happens,
like they knew you when you sucked and
then you know,
like as you're coming up,
there's,
you know,
they don't want to pay him more and
you're like,
but I make more now my headliner and you
get into this weird sort of thing with
each other.
You know,
I think that,
that,
that poisons the well for a lot of
comedian club owner relationships,
but we need them so bad.
Like you and I are not opening up a
comedy club is not going to happen.
Right?
We need the Improv.
We need these clubs.
You need the ha ha in north Hollywood.
We need them.
Like they,
like we all have to work together like
should be.
We all figure out a way to be nice to
each other.
Like we need each other.
Yeah.
We're not going to do that.
Let's.
I try and I,
I not only did I try,
I do it too.
As much as I complain about when they do
it wrong.
I always spend twice as much time giving
clubs,
do it greatest shout outs and throw in
love their way.
There's a lot doall,
right?
So important that you know what,
when I go to him,
when I money was coming at
me,
when I go to a brace,
like spring starting to hit me.
How dare you when I go to a place like
Portland,
uh,
the helium and Portland,
Philadelphia,
but where there's a manager or they run
the place.
Look,
I know they're stressed out,
but they're good at hiding it.
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
They're professional always.
And I thought I couldn't do that.
I'd be frantic,
but they're always like,
hey,
how you [inaudible]?
And I think,
you know,
I try to,
I try to go,
wow that,
you know,
give a club like that,
I would not exist.
I go,
I don't even know how they do it.
Like it's so good.
I don't know if I could do that.
And this guy's like,
do you remember Tom Sawyer from San
Francisco?
I know,
I know of him yet.
He never worked for him.
I don't think so.
Really?
He never worked at the old cops know,
a little comms I once.
Did you work at big cobs?
No,
I had opened up for.
I did some shows there like through a,
you know,
like a festival but never through the
club.
Yeah.
Well I just want to beat on it too much.
We're just so fucking lucky that we have
places to do it.
You know,
it's just a weird relationship that
comics and when it gets wet it gets
followed up just because both parties,
both parties have some work to do.
It's really.
If they were in therapy,
you both got some things you can fix and
as long as.
Because it is true,
it's like I'm not unaware of what you're
saying because it's just comedians for
every club owner that may be ripped
somebody off,
which of course they exist.
There's also a comedian that thinks
everybody's ripping them off and nobody
is so,
but it's just that when you're not
getting booked,
it's real easy to develop that sort of
animosity between you and a club.
There's just,
if you're not,
you can't work and you think that other
guys who are not as good as you and
they're getting work and then you get
frustrated and you're young and dumb
already,
you know you can have that sort of weird
complicated relationship.
It's just one of those weird things.
Club owners and artists have always.
There's always been disputes right?
Way Back into the day where they do
jumped off the fucking roof of the hotel
next to the comedy store and that was.
That was at a protest between the
comedians protesting at the club.
They walked out,
there was a strike,
there was an la comedy strike because no
one was getting any money and these
clubs were smashing it and we weren't
getting any of the money.
Like it's always been that.
And that still goes on today,
like the UCB.
UCB doesn't pay people who don't have
to.
If you're doing great,
I mean it just.
Some forces them,
they could keep doing whatever the fuck
they want to do through there.
There's also the of good blood out there
too.
Sure.
But yeah,
there's a lot of good little communities
to or guys put together a comedy night
somewhere,
you know,
and some do a great job at that.
I'm always in always in all that.
When.
So when you go to a comedy night and
someone did it,
you're like,
oh,
they took a one bar and made it a,
you know,
every little thing is right.
Sure.
People get,
some people really know how to produce a
show.
Yeah,
for sure.
It's always fun to walk into that
and they just found a good spot to.
There was a good spot that I've worked
at only once and it was in it and see.
No,
it was really weird.
It was.
I'm telling you,
I mean it was a five minute walk from my
house.
That's when I lived in.
I lived off of white oak and I could
just walk down there and go to this
weird comedy club.
I never worked there the entire time I
lived there.
I never worked there.
When I did one set there and I was like,
what is this place?
This place is what club?
I don't remember the name of it,
but it was a bar in the front and you'd
go past the bar,
this back room,
and it was like all people that I'd
never seen do standup.
I never seen him at the store and there
were some of the laugh factory knew of
some of the Improv.
It seemed like they had either just
started or they were crazy.
It was.
Maybe it was the night that I was there,
but I was like,
this place is nuts.
And how long ago was this?
More than 20 years.
Yeah,
this was like 95 I think.
it was weird.
So weird little comedy.
Like there's this whole another world
worlds out there,
man.
And if you go like into Orange County
and in San Diego,
San Diego's got its own fucking scene.
Right,
right.
You know Santa Barbara,
a Santa Barbara?
Yes.
All these different plates.
Santa Barbara I don't think has that
comedy club anymore.
I heard that comment.
See if Santa Barbara as a common thing
once a month.
They do about.
It might've been like six months ago.
San Francisco has a scene.
They got to see in Seattle's got a
scene,
you know,
there are some scenes out there,
there's some comedy scenes.
It's just like how many of them are
really thriving.
It takes a lot of club owners,
man.
That's the thing is what I'm saying to
these people that don't get along so
good with club owners if they're not
doing it.
We're not gonna comedy hideaway in Santa
Barbara says closed right now.
Ours is.
It does it mean closed forever.
He'll do random shows like 1:00
PM in different.
He still does.
He still has shows.
It's just always under comedy hideaway
and that's where we found it.
Oh,
he's doing it.
They're doing it.
They're.
Oh,
okay.
Oh No.
Oh,
I get it.
So it's a hideaway.
So it's like a Gig,
like oh,
he goes to different spots.
Oh,
okay.
So sometimes you'll be in the same spot
for the weekend.
Sometimes it bounces around.
Oh,
okay.
I know I'm his manager that I'm telling
the kid he's got to be more specific
with the social media marketing.
I don't know man.
It's like that.
But what makes a scene is a club owner
like Wendy,
Wendy from the comedy works in Denver.
She makes the scene,
that's the club owner.
She's the one who puts her finances at
risk.
She's the one who manages it.
She runs two clubs and in those two
clubs she ran.
She runs currently.
She created the Denver scene.
Mitzi created the La scene at the store,
mean Mitsis guidance her like her,
what she tolerated,
what she enforced and what she preferred
and who she gave enthusiasm too.
She,
she like shaped,
shaped so many comics.
Man.
You know.
So there's a few of those club owners
that are like super,
super special,
like really,
really important people.
They,
they just,
they create an environment where shit
pops out of.
No,
I say it's the closest thing,
like presenting,
knowing how to present something,
especially when it's comedy.
I'm an off whenever somebody,
you know,
whatever you think you would do that.
I mean you've designed them.
Do you ever think that you would think
I'd want to own a club because I get a
comedian's can be
hard to deal with.
Some of them are just crazy,
some of them you just,
you just can't,
can't do it.
I get it or I bet.
Well,
you know,
the other reason I was close once maybe,
but because let's say there's somebody I
like as a comedian,
but maybe the tragic hotel,
I don't need to know that and then be
mad at them.
Oh,
what happened?
How come you don't talk to blah,
blah,
blah anymore?
Because I make my club in Philadelphia
Real Nice.
And then he went in and he know they
toured the curtain down in the.
I don't want to not like him for that.
So let me not go to a club and deal with
anybody I know on a business level.
That's a good point.
That's a very good.
People do it and it's hard,
but they'd empathize with what I'm
saying more than anything.
So it also says we're not delusional
when we complain about clubs because it
says,
yeah,
we get it.
There's some,
there's some when they,
when they do it right,
there's some comedians that shit on it.
They ruin a condo that they're trying to
make sure I get it,
but overwhelmingly
it's probably no,
it's trying to be fair.
No,
you're.
You are trying to be fair.
There's just certain amount of people
that are nuts.
They're going to fuck places up.
You're gonna ruin things.
They don't give a shit club or whatever
they do in the relationship that the
club has with some other business,
you know,
it's just,
comedians are crazy.
Here's me on the phone.
What he sheet low for what?
Let's not even normal.
That's not even normal as a good one.
Yeah.
I mean I know he's crazy and then
somebody that I.
well,
you know,
he said he wanted to pay for the steam
cleaning.
Well,
I don't know.
We'll get new carpet styria man when
they spray diarrhea before.
I love it.
You know why?
Because that to me,
if you're saying the wrong thing.
So it sounds like just,
just shitting diarrhea all over,
just the,
but any,
that's not even your fault with a lot of
people.
A lot of people it's like they don't
probably realize what they're doing.
They're doing it.
And they think they're right,
but they're just looking at it from
their own personal selfish perspective
because they're excited about what
they're saying and because they're
engaged in a contest,
it's not just that they're talking about
stuff,
they're engaged in a contest they're
trying to win and that's where the
diarrhea comes out there.
Just throwing it at you and get in your
face.
It's like,
oh,
this is this a contest and they'll suck
you in.
Suck you into it.
See,
that's what I think one of the big
things is wrong with people today and
it's been wrong of me in the past.
Get into these conflicts for no fucking
reason.
It's not worth.
It is no fun in that.
It's stupid.
If you want to get in conflicts should
be doing difficult shit with your life.
There's a lot of different difficult
things to do.
Don't like getting in arguments with
people.
Have you done it in the past ever for
arguments?
People were nothing.
Yeah,
for sure.
Fuck.
You's a in the car window,
you know?
No,
fuck you.
Fuck you.
You feel like such a loser after you get
out of there.
Like what did I even say?
Yeah,
we've all done that.
Somebody cuts you off or someone's on
their phone,
they almost slammed into you and you
freak out and they.
They give you the bird and you're like,
fuck you.
Yeah,
for sure.
And now almost zero,
almost zero,
almost zero.
Most of the time I'm pretty cool.
I just put,
it's a matter of always thinking about
it.
It's a matter of always recognizing like
these are just stupid impulses.
Don't just follow any childish impulse
like some 13 year old,
he's good as first boner.
Like use your fucking brain.
Don't yell,
just use your brain.
I always thought I just more than
anything because it's usually not even
involving me when I still witnessed
this.
The finger out the window.
Fuck you.
Who from a calm place?
Who are you and you know what?
I've seen it a civil person that
probably is about to sit down at a
restaurant and then probably a
relatively nice guy,
but that's this.
If you're 40 years old or 20 or whatever
age.
The younger,
the more understandable,
but when you see,
let's go with a 40 year old putting his
finger out the fuck.
I go,
who are you?
Where are you going?
How can you be the most value to your
children's lives?
If that's the way you express yourself,
don't tell me,
Oh,
I'll do that,
but I know that's got a leak into
everything you do.
You're putting your hand out the window.
40 fault.
Like what?
Who are you?
How are you?
You should treat everybody in the other
car as if they're a giant friendly
linebacker.
Like don't ever say I'll fuck you up.
Don't ever say I'll kick your ass.
Treat them with like some.
Have a little bit of fear of them.
Don't want to be mad at you.
Lay back.
That's how you should treat everybody.
If we all just did that,
we'd all get along great.
You know you don't look at some giant
ass.
I'd go,
I'd go to this gym.
These nfl players go there and it's
Hilarious,
man.
I'm like,
excuse me,
pardon me,
Woo.
Dakota dudes.
Elbows and shit.
Trying to get to the weight stacks.
They're enormous people.
I mean some of these guys are like six
foot four,
300 plus pounds.
Just enormous,
enormous fucking people just show a
little.
Have a little respect.
If those guys were in cars all around
you,
you wouldn't be yelling,
fuck you.
Pull over,
pull over,
pull over.
You wouldn't do that because these guys
will smash you.
They're not even the same thing as you.
That's the reason that it makes me
laugh,
that behaviors,
because it's not always a maniac in real
life,
but they should see their behaviors
maniac like because it is.
It's like,
do you know what it from what?
Do you know where it comes from?
Just not being able to express yourself.
No,
no.
When you're in a car,
you're worried your,
your,
your senses are ramped up.
Like if you're,
if 10 is like full awareness,
you're like six or seven were normal.
I feel like I one like you're already
like kind of wrapped up because
everything's moving fast around you and
try and stay calm and someone's doing
something to try to get your you fucking
piece of shit.
You're wrapped up already.
Yeah.
That's why when you're late,
when you're late for some of the.
Even me and I'm a pretty civil civil
person and I try to stop it,
but if I'm super late and nervous,
I will say to the person doing the most
mundane thing,
what the fuck are you doing?
Exactly.
At least I never go.
I will say this,
go into traffic.
Zero out the window,
zero talking about this is in the kid,
but even in the contents of your own
car,
you have to be.
You should be proud of your behavior,
but at least I know well enough when I'm
doing that,
that's got to be for me and I should
work on that too.
I had a dude scream at me and take his
shirt off to show me his tattoos and
then.
And then he called me a rich piece of
shit.
I was not rich at the time,
but I did have a white suburban and I
guess white suburban made you think?
I mean I wasn't famous at the time.
He didn't know who the fuck I was,
but I don't remember what it was about,
but I remember this dude took his shirt
off to show me his tattoos and I started
pointing out,
I'm laughing.
I'm like,
ah.
I go,
did you take your shirt off to show me
your tattoos too?
So that I don't think you're a tough
guy.
His leg is did.
I'm like,
that is hilarious,
and so I'm yelling this at him and he's
getting more and more red in the face
and I go,
that's hilarious.
You took goes,
I'll fucking kick your fucking ass.
You fucking faggot.
You rich piece of shit.
I'm like,
rich piece of shit.
Wow.
By and I just drove.
At least I was thinking at least I'm
driving this big ass truck.
If like he slammed into me,
he's gonna get fucked up.
Huge.
Nobody thinks to is ever ready for like
to be called out because he knows why
she was so stupid.
He thought I'd be scared of him because
he's got tattoos everywhere.
Meanwhile,
as soon as he took his shirt off,
I was convinced I could fuck them up.
I was like,
this dude doesn't work out.
There's no way he knows anything.
There's no way.
I mean,
he was just like a guy,
you know,
it wasn't like a scary guy,
but he had tattoos everywhere,
like all over his neck and cit and they
weren't even good.
I like tattoos.
It was just such a stupid thing,
but I mean,
I bet if I knew that guy in real life
and we were just together in a fucking
office building and he worked in one
office and I worked in and be like,
what's up man?
What's going on?
Everything cool.
We live in friendly shit.
It's just this weird thing when you're
on a highway and everybody's ramped up.
Everybody's nervous.
You don't even realize you're nervous.
Even if you're calm and you're good,
you're always ready to do this.
You always ready.
Somebody locked up.
She's hit the brakes.
Oh,
look at that is the fucking thing in the
world.
Got Shit.
You're always ready for that.
You're ready for that.
That's why when I go to my house to
Silver Lake,
some people want to get on the highway
and I go,
I don't know.
I don't want to get on the highway.
First of all,
it always ends up being about the same
time,
but even if it's five minutes longer on
surface streets on a highway,
I'm,
I feel like I'm getting too out there in
this highway world.
I just want to go somewhere where I'm
not on the highway.
Do you know what I mean?
On the side road I can handle it,
but on the,
on the highway I just get stressed out a
little more.
So I'm like,
I'll say if it's 10 minutes longer,
I don't care.
Yeah,
there's not a bad idea.
It's not a bad idea.
It's chilling.
It's more relaxed.
Chill.
I'll teach.
Stop.
Slow down.
No one's driving that fast.
Take Pico from center city to my house.
I liked going over Laurel Canyon.
You know when you go into Hollywood it's
like,
it's more chill.
It's Kinda cool.
Get that cool.
Drive down that winding road down and
winding road down is excellent,
man.
It reminds you you're in La.
Yeah,
and I always think of like these bad
motherfuckers that live right there on
the road like,
well,
who do you have to be to be so confident
and people that you buy a house right
there on Laurel Canyon around one of
those corners where someone could easily
miscalculate and slammed right into your
car and slamming your house.
You know those streets like Laurel in
particular,
it's like there's a lot of like
jockeying for position on Laurel.
I saw a guy the other day take a chance,
move and dump into the left lane to
oncoming traffic to pass a guy on laurel
and I was like,
whoa.
That is a.
That is a like you're committing to
being a cocksucker.
Like you're going down.
There's just no way.
You know,
if someone's coming,
you don't have enough time.
And if they're coming up the hill,
like you're coming down the hill,
the same kind of assholishness we've got
a real problem here.
Like you're going into the left lane
that's put that right next to your
house.
What these people's,
their houses are right there,
man.
Like you could reach out and smack their
mailman in the ass to drive by.
It's crazy.
I always think that like on the highway
when there's an apartment building,
so close to the highway that you could
forget something and go,
hey,
I'm pulling around in the overpass,
come over to the window and throw me my
shoes.
Like an episode of the honeymooners or
some shit.
Right?
Yeah.
They have a string.
Maybe they run from the.
I don't know,
whenever I look at a science fiction
movie about like the future,
like a district nine district nine.
Great fucking movie man.
Um,
but one of the things about these like
Super Uber congested cities,
you look at them and you go,
okay,
is that common?
Is that like going to be everywhere and
we going to be really living in this
sort of weird dystopian future.
New York City is in the perfect spot,
right?
Because it's not quite dystopian,
but it's definitely exceptional.
Like those views that you get.
Like a buddy of mine,
he had an apartment in Brooklyn on the
water facing the city,
which I think is even.
I don't know if it's better than being
in the city,
but it's pretty fucking stunning and I
just was in his living room going,
Holy Shit,
man,
this is crazy.
Like this view is crazy.
It's beautiful.
It's stunning.
But it,
if that keeps going right and then it
becomes this monolithic huge favela
like,
you know,
some crazy like completely stuffed with
people and chickens and dogs running
around and I mean like all these future
dystopia movies,
they're all.
Everything is all.
It's not like everything's amazing in
the future.
We have these huge super populated
cities and everything's perfect now.
It's all like way more crime.
Way more craziness.
Oh God.
Well it's just thinking.
I think people are improving and you
think people are improving?
We both do.
We think life's improved.
You're kidding.
No,
no,
but I'm saying there,
there is a problem with the numbers,
the actual raw numbers of us.
Like if you go back just a few decades,
the amount of people was like 5 billion
less and it's not that long.
I mean,
I think you go back to the eighties.
What?
What is,
what we've done this before,
and I know I've,
I always forget and I probably should
remember it,
but what was world population in 1985?
That's when I got out of high school.
Uh,
want to say it was less than 3 billion.
That's what I want to say.
No,
I'm wrong.
5 billion.
Little less than $5.
Million.
Okay.
I feel a little bit better anyway,
during that time from 1985 to 2018,
it's now.
Is it 7 billion or has it hit eight?
Because the world population was real
close to eight.
Seven.
Fuck man.
That's a lot of people gaining more than
2 billion people in just a few decades.
So you keep doing that.
You do that a few decades more.
Does it accelerate?
You must because there's 2 billion more
people having people.
So it's got to accelerate it.
Alright.
Exponential.
Every problem you list.
I feel like I connected right back to
old people.
Like the population.
We just live in a society that have
kids,
have kids.
No one goes,
hey,
we'll learn about yourself.
And when you really know what your
patients are,
then if you start,
you'll see at a certain time you might
be with.
No,
no one is just that type of.
You have to have kids.
Okay.
That's older people,
you know,
that put that thought out there.
The energy problem.
If like kids were,
if we were just letting kids lead,
we'd have electric cars already.
Like they already had that information
back then and we just.
The real problem with electric cars to
the batteries.
Well I mean even still true.
What about just musk is pretty much at
the top of the heap when it comes to
figuring out electric car technology.
I don't think there's anybody that's
ever had it nailed down like him before.
I mean there's a few different car
companies that make really good electric
cars.
Fiskar makes a really good one,
but it's on those batteries.
Like this is like this is not something
we could have had years ago.
And
then what about solar power?
Solar power is absolutely viable.
And especially in California where it's
raining,
it's been raining out here for a few
days and there is like,
it's amazing.
It's like we live in Seattle,
you know,
everything's all green and shit,
but it's sunny most of the time and we
could just be collecting energy for
that.
This,
there's political issues with that.
There's like,
you know,
you'd have to get the infrastructure
ready.
You'd have to,
you could sell back to the grid.
There's that.
People do do that.
There's a lot of like difficulty though.
Apparently Brian Kaylin went through
that when he got his house solar powered
and he said,
is it really a lot of red tape?
And he goes and it seems like they're
trying to discourage you from doing it
and make it difficult for you to do it
for you to switch over to electric.
They because he had his installed and
hooked up for months before it got
switched on with the grid.
It was like real issue.
And then even more so I think if you
want to go off grid so you can use solar
power and have no connection to the
grid,
that's a slippery slope.
And in some places,
I don't know if you can do that.
I think some places might actually
prevent you from doing that,
which is really weird.
They can prevent you.
You will only use all.
No one else has a dog should be
basically that's what they're saying is
what they're saying because that's not
the tone.
They say your power anymore.
But thanks.
No,
you wouldn't be on all great.
How do you think they would sell that?
Like just pull up.
Just guessing.
Like how do they make that make sense?
They would have to have some regulations
like we don't know shit about your
solar.
We don't,
we don't know if it's dangerous.
We don't know what you're up to.
So I mean they could sell it in any way
they want.
If they're doing it in order to save
their constituents money or in to do the
bidding of whatever special interest
group is lobbying for them to do it.
I mean,
that's why they do those things.
They don't do those things because they
make sense.
You know,
they don't do it through those things
because they're logical.
Hey,
don't don't get that free power.
Let me make it confusing to get that
free power.
Make it real hard for you.
Turn on,
I just got to stretch it out a few
months.
You've got to keep paying me for a few
If they can just do that with a million
customers,
you have 3 million more months of
billable hours.
If they wanted to do it that way,
if they just made it a policy to act
slower.
I don't know how it works,
man it,
but I know how money works.
I bet there's truth to what you're
saying.
There's so much money involved and they
don't make power companies because
they're altruistic.
Beautiful.
People want everybody to watch TV.
They do because they want that cash
baby.
You know?
That's why they're going to drill holes
right next to the river.
While the good stuff is flopped.
A salmon,
they just get to get in there.
It's just start drilling.
They don't give a fuck,
man.
People were just who just want money.
Don't give a fuck.
This is what's the problem with guys
like trump?
This is what the problem with the guys
like.
He brings in.
There's so many that the number one
thing is not making money.
The number one thing is sustainability.
That's the number one thing,
living the earth.
That's the
number one thing is can we live off this
earth?
Okay,
good.
Number two things.
We've got to be safe.
Okay,
how can we be safe?
Well,
first of all,
we need to be able to talk.
So freedom of speech is hugely fucking
important.
When it comes to being safe.
You need to be able to say things
without fear of repercussion.
You need to be able to communicate 100
percent honestly amongst each other so
we could figure out how you really feel.
Tell me how you really feel about this.
Then I can understand you.
I don't really understand you yet
because you're hiding how you really
feel about partial,
about life,
parts of life.
That's where freedom of speech is,
so God damn important.
Just one aspect of it being important,
being able to protest about stuff,
all that shit.
You have to pee.
So.
No,
no,
we just did that.
So they just did that the other day and
handed me a note to.
How long have we gone?
Oh,
it was pat miletich.
Uh,
it's 1:30.
What did we start at?
Like 1115.
So you do the math.
I'm too stupid for that already.
That's why we're talking about.
That's why you eat the food.
That you shouldn't be the same reason
that you got that.
Fuck it gene.
Fuck it.
I have to midnight.
Is Jazz hard?
Oh,
I do it sometimes.
I came home the other day from the ice
house Saturday night.
I cooked a steak at one in the morning.
I got the cast iron skillet out and I
put some butter down and I had steak and
Kimchi while I watch TV at 1:00
in the morning.
Whatever the fuck.
It was.
Delicious.
Amazing.
It was amazing.
I'm lucky that I.
The reason I want to stop,
it's not because I get sick.
I really have an iron stomach if there's
such as good,
but it's just,
I,
you know,
it still makes me feel a little bit like
I don't get sick,
but I feel a little heavy in the
morning.
Dude,
I took two whole days yesterday and the
day before,
or a bullshit yesterday I egg rolls.
The day before I had a big bowl of pasta
and I had a cupcake.
I just decided,
fuck it.
It Sunday or Monday,
whatever it was,
Sunday and Monday let's just have some
fun.
So for two days I was eight.
Whatever the fuck I want.
I just decided I want to do that.
I had the worst parts of my career.
I mean,
of my career of farting.
These were,
these were the bombs to end all bombs.
My Body's just not designed to do that
anymore.
It just doesn't want to do that anymore
because I've been eating so clean so
regularly that just a couple of days of
pasta and bullshit and egg rolls and my
body was like,
fuck you.
I felt lethargic.
I was like,
I just want to sit down all the time.
My workout sucked.
It was hard to push myself.
I was like,
wow.
Like this is not good.
Like eating bullshit.
Just this is what most people are doing.
Most people are doing all day.
They're eating candy bars and bullshit
and not getting any nutrients.
You mean candy bars?
Well,
here's what
I mean.
I'll,
uh,
eight very bad.
Why you should eat good.
Got It.
Why don't you,
uh,
why don't you approach it like you're
taking in the artwork of these people
who cook food for you or learn how to
cook yourself.
I cares.
The problem.
Oh,
is that I had during the day I eat
great.
I juice every day like Kale,
carrots,
celery,
ginger beets every single day.
So you don't eat healthy?
Well,
no,
that's just because my only thing I
could do to say,
okay,
well I have the shitty diet.
I can at least say to my body,
I like to think of myself as my body
going.
Thank you for giving us some good stuff.
We wish you wouldn't eat that other
shit,
but thanks for something that's everyday
I'd use,
but then it gets bad late at night.
I mean if it's.
But that's good though.
So you're not all bad.
You have a lot of good habits.
Like you're very aware that you need
nutrients when you do do that stuff and
juice.
One of the things that they say we
should probably look this up right now
because I'm obviously not a nutrition
expert,
but I'm pretty sure they say that
vitamins are absorbed better.
Um,
when you have them with some healthy
fat.
So I think they recommend coconut oil.
Have you have some coconut oil with
vegetables?
When you drink vegetable juice,
it actually can enhance the absorption
of some of the vitamins.
It's good to know.
Yeah.
So some people will mix it in or mix mct
oil,
medium chain triglyceride oil,
fat soluble vitamins.
You won't get enough vitamin D from
drinking vegetable juice.
It's found mainly in fatty cheese,
fatty fish,
cheese,
mushrooms,
egg yolks,
beef liver and fortified foods.
You need vitamin D,
that's A.
Yeah,
that's.
They're saying this.
They're just saying that vitamin D is
very difficult to get if you're a Vegan.
Right.
I do eat food too,
but I like some.
The thing is at night I'm so hungry,
so I'll go to the Vaughn's.
I'll be like,
well listen,
I'm going to want candy no matter what.
And I had dinner at like 5:30.
This is like now nine,
so I don't really need dinner and eat
dinner.
So I'd go,
well I,
I'm going to get dinner.
I'm Roland Candi is second dinner,
whatever you wanna call second street.
So I go,
I know this is bad,
but the last few weeks I'll be there and
I'll be like,
you know what?
I'm going to eat.
I'm on candy.
I'll just get candy.
And then I'm proud of myself because I
didn't like it.
He didn't need food and candy.
Get Food or candy and when I get Candy I
get candy.
It's not like I'm getting like a jumbo
snickers bar.
What are you doing?
I told someone that helps out at the
podcast when they're at the vons to get
me a candy bar.
They brought me back a candy bar.
It little.
I'm like,
are you shit?
What?
Oh,
reese's cups.
I said,
I get some reese's cups.
They brought back to reese's cups in a
pack.
Oh,
little ones.
Yeah.
I go,
when I say reese's cups,
I mean a bag.
The guy had this fantasy.
Now the fantasy that I had a reading
reads cups nonstop for five,
10 minutes because now have gone love,
love reese's cups.
Do you like to do the double a?
The big ones that the.
The,
the,
the big thick ones and I like to have
them with ice cream.
I've done that many times.
All kinds of ice cream.
Chocolate
ice cream.
Fuck it.
I'll have it with strawberry.
I don't give a shit.
You know?
What would we say no to?
I know what I would rather have you take
a double reese's cup,
put it in the microwave for literally 10
seconds and then get the vanilla ice
cream and just smash it on top.
It's absurd.
Absurd to something about ice cream and
some cakes,
like a warm apple pie with vanilla ice
cream.
Woo.
Holy Shit.
Chocolate cake.
With a with vanilla ice cream.
Oh my goodness.
I could warm chocolate cake and vanilla
ice cream.
Oh,
apple pie though with cinnamon and
vanilla ice cream.
Holy Shit.
Todd glass.
That's good.
The French French apple pie with vanilla
ice cream because you get the apple pie
is American motherfucker.
I don't know where he get this French
shit from.
Here's how do they even have apples in
France?
Speaking of Apple Pie.
Mcdonald's should do this.
Take your glass.
Clear glass that you can see,
right?
Right.
They picture the commercial.
They'll shoot it,
right?
Then put the apple pie in their apple
pint and glass and then fill it with
vanilla ice cream and put some caramel
sauce and go.
You call it their apple pie.
Allah mode and it put a spoon and you
get the Apple Pie.
The Vanilla ice cream.
A little bit,
little bit of sauce at the top to.
You should this on the show.
You should go to them with a proposal
that todd glass.
Apple Pie.
It's a great idea mode and they have all
this stuff there to need a spokesperson.
The commercial,
this is my idea,
I was just do it that way.
We get the public on the side.
There's the apple pie in the ice cream,
so some of the tops I was dig in.
It's apple pie,
a la mode.
It's a great idea.
Especially if you could figure out how
to nuke only the apple pie.
Well,
they could,
so they have to put it together is
already hot.
It's in.
They drop it in.
They dropped the ice cream on top.
The ice cream on top.
That's genius.
Takes a couple seconds to make.
Right?
You don't just grab it.
You gotta to drop one in there.
It's very easy to Bang Bang there.
Yeah,
right.
That's a great idea.
That's a really good.
That's the best idea I've ever heard on
this podcast.
Thank you.
Oh,
they have it.
This isn't Mcdonald's restaurant that
made this exact dessert the way you're
describing it in a glass exact same.
The idea is that.
No,
but I'm saying it's that they have all
the ingredients to do it.
They have those glasses they have apple
pie with.
They should just serve it because I bet
it would be a big seller because it
does.
Apple pies are not bad either.
Those Mcdonald's advertise when you want
one.
Those are not bad to know.
What's that?
Two for a dollar?
Is that what they are?
Yeah.
Wow.
That's pretty good.
Here's my bed.
I called junk.
It's junk.
It's food for this junk but not candy
junk food,
so I like to get the biggest Mcdonald's
hamburger there is like whatever it is
that I can get into menu.
I look okay.
Can I get that with nothing on it?
Just a plain burger.
No cheese,
no nothing.
Then I get an egg mcmuffin.
You can either do two things.
One,
you could take all the ingredients off
the egg mcmuffin and put it in the
hamburger so you have a hamburger with
an egg,
a piece of ham knees and it's so good.
Or take the Hamburg or put it in,
let the egg mcmuffin be the bread,
but it's pretty good.
That sounds pretty God damn good.
That sounds like you're doing.
You're doing God's work.
Figuring out some stuff that they can't
figure it out.
They've figured out some impressive
things.
They figured out how to make a fucking
juicy,
delicious pancake.
That's the top of a of a mcmuffin.
Those mcgriddles that is my aunt,
one of my all time favorite cheat foods.
A goddammit griddle.
They'll fucking delicious.
You want to talk about like the good
feeling in your mouth for a buck?
Like how much?
Like how much bang you get for your buck
if you're hungry with the cheese and the
AG.
Holy Shit.
Here's my point.
How much I agree with,
you know,
we're not saying the ingredients or
anything.
If you took that mcgriddle yeah.
I say this with a lot of foods.
I'm just using this as an example
because you just said this,
that actual item,
but I say this with a lot of things.
Put It on it.
You take that mcgriddle,
put it on a chopping block at a French
restaurant in whatever,
and then all you do is put that
mcgriddle on the chopping block and then
maybe put some syrup all over it,
delivered to a table there.
No one's going to go.
It's good,
but it's not like it's going to go.
Shut the fuck up.
Yeah.
You know what I say that about Papa
John's a cinnamon things they do.
You know where they take the bread they
put.
It's not only they put butter on it,
but then the vanilla glaze all over it.
They put it in the oven.
If you were anywhere they go hold about
six in the morning.
It that they put the fresh cinnamon
tarts out,
you know,
and then you took a papa John's put it
on.
No one would eat it and go though.
It's good.
It's sugary.
It's doing the job there.
They'd go.
What?
What if you had a mcgriddle with ice
cream on it?
Wow.
Ice Cream in between.
Like in between the layers.
You put the mcgriddle down with the
sausage.
It'd be absurd to be fucking sausage.
Oh,
I didn't think of the sausage,
so I just thought the bread and the
Syrup and style,
the whole sausage.
Let's see.
You could definitely do it.
I,
I've always loved Hawaiian Pizza,
the pineapple and ham together.
Me To people.
Some people,
you know what I'll argue social issues
into d for free because I think there's
a good side of it,
but some people I'm okay to let go and
people go,
I can't believe someone would like
pineapple on pizza.
Okay.
Right.
I'm not.
I can't believe you like to pick sees.
Jesus says,
okay,
you know what I really love.
I'm a pineapple.
Pineapple and anchovy.
I know it sounds disgusting.
It tastes amazing.
It's one of my all time favorite pizzas.
It might be my all time.
Mine's pineapple and slice sausage.
What are you watching this?
This is a,
a mcgriddle being rolled into rolled ice
cream.
Things that's popular right now.
Oh,
it's almost what you just described but
not quite and it looks actually Kinda
froze it and
then turned it into those things.
Yeah.
You're seeing those.
The chopped it up and flattened it out.
It's like barely food.
So it's barely food.
That's so weird.
What is the top?
So it's the not the inside of the
mcgriddle.
It's just the analysis starts over here
again and they turned it into this
thing.
Donald's do it.
Yeah.
Well,
that makes sense if it's the inside of
the mcgriddle because it's all,
I mean the outside rather because it's
all just that doe he shit.
Anyway,
I was.
They poured the batter on it and then
show.
Oh,
it is everything.
It's the meat to.
Oh,
that's crazy.
How weird might be good,
but I don't know.
It might be good.
Yeah.
Look,
it's probably an interesting way to eat.
I mean,
it's no different than what you're doing
when you're masticating it.
It's what you're doing.
You're making that out of it.
It's just making that already.
Just.
Maybe you don't want to see it.
I found out this past week that ground
beef was invented by the Mongols ground
meat and went to see the con exhibit at
the Reagan Library.
Fuck living back then.
Dude.
You think it'd be hard to start over as
an open mic comic mentioned starting off
in a Mongo camp.
Wait,
why was ground beef invented?
They invented ground beef.
Apparently Mongols invented the Mongol
Empire.
Is either indirectly responsible,
directly responsible,
or they invented like a shitload of
things.
Would that be.
What year would it be?
That was like the 12 hundreds that they,
that they existed,
that they first came to be.
What were they before that?
They just ate steak.
No,
but I mean,
look,
they all,
whatever.
I think they probably just,
yeah,
they just probably looked cooked meat
and just ate the meat and then someone
figured out where you can take tough
cuts because they would eat whatever the
fuck they could take.
Tough cut and grind it up.
You can cook it and eat it.
Easier to figure that out.
You don't eat meat?
I eat a lot of me.
Oh,
you do?
Yeah.
Why I you think I wouldn't eat meat?
I don't know.
You know,
it may be for you.
One of those guys.
Well,
no,
no.
I,
I would say a free.
I would just say I,
I listened to all always open to listen
to new things to sway my opinion,
but I like the stance of I heard someone
talking about at least free,
free free range.
Now I know the opposing view on that
too.
But,
uh,
I just thought,
you know,
if you're,
if you're thinking I get it,
that there is a food chain,
this is what I heard this person
speaking.
I'm not saying it,
but I made.
It's made sense to me.
No,
there is a food chain and we don't have
to torture animals of course,
but there is this,
but you know,
and tortured animals that then I would
be like,
if I was going to,
I wish I could,
if I was going to eat meat,
I do eat meat,
but I wish I did it that way.
I'd be proud of myself if I committed.
When I hear someone that does that,
that will.
I'm like,
Oh,
I have admiration for that.
Would you ever consider killing an
animal that you were going to eat?
Would you ever consider like raising a
cow killing it?
I couldn't,
but I don't.
What about hunting?
Do you think you could hunt?
No.
No?
Could you?
Oh,
you do?
Yeah.
But I don't.
I'm not,
I'm not.
I just
couldn't hunt.
I'm not proper.
I don't want it.
It's not something you're interested in.
I beat you.
Listen,
there's nothing wrong with that.
It's a,
it's like I shot a guy in the face once
at camp who shot a man in Reno.
I shot.
Remember when he's singing that song?
He was in prison,
which I've liked that he went back and
perform there,
that they can,
they're not,
they don't have to be lost.
And then he,
uh,
and he goes,
I shot a man in Reno just to watch him
die.
And they'll go,
well,
let's not glorify.
The guys said.
They like,
listen,
I'm not trying to.
I did doubt about it.
Yeah,
I'm bummed.
I'm singing it.
It's not good.
Don't someone just do a standup special
inside of prison?
Jeff Ross.
Jeff Ross was another comic to a black
comic.
You know the Alley Siddique John.
Very worried.
Is that it?
Yeah.
How do you say?
Is that how you say his name?
Paul.
Wow.
I like the background you have behind
you more than the background,
but I got a,
what's it called?
I think it's bigger than these bars.
Oh,
nice.
You gotta use the bathroom.
Go ahead.
Don't worry about it.
You're not going to say anything right
now.
We could wrap this up too.
I mean,
we've already asked you about this.
Why you go to the bathroom if that's
okay.
I'm just Mongol eating meat thing.
I just pull up this article from the New
York Times.
It said that horse meat being tenderized
under their saddle is a myth.
I don't know if that.
Yeah.
Tenderize under their saddle steak.
Tar Tar was horse meat dish that
originated from the horse eat Mongols,
the central Asia who swept across the
eastern Central Europe 800 years ago.
The most common tales that the tartar
that tater.
How do you.
What would you say that tater tot her
ear horseman would put a slice of
horsemeat beneath their saddle in the
morning and retrieve it tenderized by
the pounding.
Teat Ra for dinner.
They supposedly left their raw meat
eating habit behind and according to one
version of the story,
it was carried by the German sailors to
Homburg or the taste for ground beef
began begat both hamburgers and steak
tartare.
That's interesting.
Is that where Neil hamburger is that
where a hamburger came from.
The guy that goes hamburger,
I'm just to use the bathroom.
What's cool is that.
Okay,
cool.
I wanted to ask about that because
that's interesting.
I wonder if the Reagan Library has old
information in their exhibit.
It says it's been passed around as a
like to say that if you're running a
museum you should probably know that
that's not true unless they.
They figured out chopped meat and this
is not the same thing.
Maybe it's not.
Maybe originally it was,
but I would feel like if someone wanted
to do that,
that would be a way to tenderize meat
now.
I mean I went to the same restaurant I
was describing that I worked at before
was a Mongolian
barbecue grill where we'd cook with
swords,
literal metal swords on a flat top,
but no,
it was supposed to be representing the
shields that the Mongols would cook on
back in the 800,
whatever,
and they were just shredding meat.
That's the only way you could do it.
So they were shredding beef.
I don't know if it's ground,
but like definitely shredded.
So it's always something
when we cooked in the field with Rinella
for the first time,
when we shot a deer,
he pounded it flat like he took like a
chunk of the backstrap and then put it
in between.
I forget what he put it in between,
but pounded it flat before it cooked it,
like to tenderize it and break it down a
little bit.
I just watched a video of a guy pounding
and aluminum foil role and making a
knife out of it is fucking bad ass.
Like a knife,
like a Shiv or a shank.
Watching it go watch the.
I know you like to watch knife making
things.
It's just like it.
It's 10 minute video of him literally
taking the whole role.
Pull it up.
I want to see that.
That's crazy.
Some dude made a knife out of an
aluminum foil role.
That's when you really want to fuck
somebody up,
but you're trapped in a restaurant.
Hey,
I have a question.
Go ahead.
We probably.
Should we go for the close?
Look at this.
Look at this guy.
He's gonna.
Hammer down this aluminum foil until
they could turn it.
Got It all I can to kitchen too.
He just uses the.
A regular old stove gas stove.
So did you just hammer it down and then
fold it?
Is that what he did?
He leaves it here.
I was just kind of skip ahead so you can
just get a good idea for bad unless you
were trying to use that to build your
kids afford.
Then you're a nice person.
You bake a hammer.
Oh,
we turned it into metal that you could
saw.
This is crazy.
Been a lot of time sharpening it down.
Whoa.
This is not.
So he turned it into a real piece of
aluminum.
Oh yeah.
That is fucking bananas.
And he's sharpened.
It is crazy.
But I gave it a handle.
Oh my God.
And then put it in at the end and puts
it in a package and shows like chopping
stuff.
But domain.
You must be so weak though.
I mean it's aluminum.
Oh,
he sells it.
It probably might.
Would you want to buy?
Why would you want it?
Just because I'm an asshole.
I want to buy an aluminum foil knife.
I need it.
Every time people come over to the
house,
you go,
this knife is made out of aluminum foil.
I have a video we want you to watch.
He made a knife out of pasta just
showing that makes it.
Oh,
that's great.
About the story that Chris Ryan told
about the guy who made a knife out of
shit and it was frozen or frozen shit
knife to kill one of his dogs because he
was like a sled dog or.
And he was starving to death.
Wow.
Yeah.
Was that true or did he carve his way
out of an ice hole with a shit shovel?
It's one of those frozen shit shovel.
You're the only guy that comes with
notes.
Do you know what?
I only have.
I wrote.
Can I plug some things for sure.
Definitely.
Okay,
so I'll get this real quick about your
special first.
Where is that?
Our special netflix.
It's called an act happy.
I wanted to call it sucked by pigeon
Dick,
but I was the only one that was raising
my hand.
I wish I was there.
I would have backed you up.
Was was a juggling act,
right,
and who the hell would it not forgotten.
I know,
right?
Suck my page and deck.
That's hilarious.
Can I tell you something?
The last time I went to two times and I
know tell any stories like you know,
oh,
this person.
No,
no.
This is two things I think and I think I
would have learned my lesson because my
book I wanted to call the.
I wanted to call my book.
All I ever wanted to do was meet a nice
girl with a terminal disease and then
then other stupid things I said to keep
the closet door shut.
I would add that as a subtitle,
even though I hated the word closet.
That's how he tried to sell it to him
because they closet and anything to do
with any words,
you know that of Clyde this and out and
so I go,
okay,
if I can call it.
All I ever wanted to do was meet a nice
girl.
It was the first title was with cancer.
All I ever wanted to do was meet a nice
girl with cancer and other.
The other thing,
other stupid things I said to keep the
closet door shut because there's a story
in there about me literally me and my
friend,
you know,
so it does make sense and it's not mean.
It's not insulting cancer.
I think that's still should have been
the title of the book.
The problem is people are going to see
it and go,
oh,
he's just a mean guy that wants girls to
die.
That's the boil down dumb version of
fully look into it in that funny you
didn't even consider that and consider
that.
Well,
you're wishing.
How about terminal disease?
Now you're right.
It brings up a guy,
a dumb guy writing a book,
Hey,
suck my dick and the Diet.
You know what?
That's how you know what?
I'm stubborn in certain ways,
but in other ways all you gotta do it
cleanly explained something to me.
Oh yeah,
they're right.
I don't want to call it that.
I never thought about that to go for the
wrong audience,
to see it on a shelf somewhere and even
I think we should all be able to change
our opinions about things.
I try hard to work on that.
I do too.
I think it's a big thing about being a
person,
be able to look at things and not think
that you are those ideas.
You're a person.
You're not those ideas like you just.
You don't.
Just because you thought of it and you
subscribe to it and you believed at one
point in time it don't let it define
you.
It's just an idea and if it's wrong
beyond just about it and say,
this is why I thought it was real and
people respect that because they'll know
that when you're talking you're saying
what's really on your mind.
Whether you're a writer,
whether you're wrong,
you might be incorrect,
but if you are incorrect,
you going to let them know you're
incorrect and you know what?
The way to look at that,
I think,
and I remind myself every time I talk
about this stuff to say how many of the
things are you doing because they're
right where you just think time equals
validity because there probably are some
things that should you should have been
doing for the last 40 years,
but so let's not go issue by issue.
Here's a wider scope for someone to put
themselves under fair judgement.
If you're 45 years old and you haven't
had.
I'm just throwing out numbers.
I'm okay with up or down the number,
but you'll get the gist of what I'm
saying.
If you're 45 years old and what?
What are we talking about?
I'm sorry I got high,
but if you remind me I'll.
I'll go right back.
I'm not exactly sure where you're going
with it.
Ah,
Shit.
Marijuana is that God damn marijuana.
I don't even fuck her.
Nothing.
Jimmy,
what was he talking about?
Oh No.
Oh,
we'll figure it out.
Don't worry.
I want to do so and then I have to plug
these dates and I remember that we were
talking about people being nicer to each
other.
Uh,
we're talking about
being able to change your comedy
special,
being able to change your opinions on
things and I think it's very important
to be able to just change your opinion
and that you are not your ideas because
you believe something doesn't mean you
should be locked into it because.
Oh,
I remembered.
Okay.
A good way to judge yourself is to go,
if you're 45 years old and you haven't
maybe in the last so many years changed
your view on something.
How about we start with that?
We won't even take issue at hand it.
Well,
what does that say?
There's no way that you shouldn't be
changing.
Simply should,
right?
So if it's not,
it doesn't have to be everything,
but we'd say in a 10 year period where
there are two things that you were
adamant about,
maybe in two areas,
not everything.
Sometimes you're right,
you're right.
But if you can honestly,
not just outwardly to be writing an
argument,
go,
y'all changed my opinion,
but go inward.
No one's around,
be honest with yourself and then you
might be able to go in the dark of your
own asking yourself,
go,
fuck,
I guess I really have it.
Yeah.
And then be aware of it.
And then there starts your change and
we'll be back right after this.
Joe Rogan's our guests to me.
Let me just for sure.
Get these folks.
Let me,
let me just say to you,
if you're in a place where todd glass is
performing so on the best standup comics
working in America today,
very funny guy,
and I do it right.
I get the two piece.
Even while you're being set,
there's a two piece.
It's all right.
The minute you get in there.
Okay.
Jazz,
Texas.
I'm going to go to a jazz club.
It's not even a comedy club.
They reached out.
So in a,
in April 22nd and 23rd.
Where does that?
It's called.
It's in San Antonio,
Texas.
Bam.
I liked the shit gets crazy.
You're real close to Mexico.
Make a mad run across the border.
You're right there.
How far is it from San Antonio,
Texas?
I don't know.
I think they could shoot each other a.
So I say to Texas I met Mexico.
Yeah,
but I like Texas when I was sending him
to.
Not the first time you said it.
Right.
Okay.
If you're that close to Mexico,
like what's the closest city we have is
Laredo,
Passover,
Passover.
The closest I've been in El Paso,
I heard El Paso,
like bullets of hit buildings like the
buildings in El Paso.
Bullets from like the drug war have hit.
I was at Juarez.
Is Juarez right next to El Paso.
Juarez is a particularly dangerous
place.
We don't need to go there,
but hey,
don't go there.
Go see todd glass.
Top performing.
Next fit.
That's what I'm trying to do a fast.
I always feel guilty about.
Well what's your website?
Let Todd Glass Co.
Less comedy.
You even know what it is,
but he gets that.
ProbabLy talk less comedy.
Todd?
No.
Todd glass at todd glass?
No,
not Your email address.
Your website address.
Oh,
I'm not thinking very clearly.
no worries.
Talk last.com
or something.
Talking to [inaudible] dot com.
Then I'll be at the blue room,
the blue room and I hate reading the
blue room in springfield,
Missouri.
And that's uh,
the seventh through the 9th of June.
Two more.
That's right.
Blue room.
I liked the pictures.
A royal comedy theater in a hopkins,
Missouri.
It's a hot.
It's the royal comedy theater.
This is,
this place is.
I love it.
And then it's a in hopkins.
Uh,
am I saying that right?
Missouri,
Minnesota,
Minnesota.
He's going to punch me in the face.
June 20,
first through the 24th.
and then you have to stir crazy comedy
club in Arizona.
Glendale,
Arizona.
Come on down boulevard in glendale.
Stir crazy in Arizona and I need that
just now.
What I just did.
Yeah,
no lie.
My heartbeat.
Exhausting.
Yeah.
Because you're funny.
You don't want to do that.
So difficult.
So hard.
How do people do it?
You were reading pretty good off the tv
in a trance.
Alright brother.
Well that was very fun.
that was great.
That was so much fun.
It's very fun.
I'm todd glass.com.
Go see him and netflix sPecial outright.
Now suck my pigeon deck,
right?
Yes.
Act happy.
Don't look for suck by pitching depth.
Maybe in the maybe the next range given
the cave by.
Wow.