The yes
and we're like,
what's up man?
How are you?
Fantastic.
Thanks for doing this.
Appreciate it.
Appreciate you.
Let me come up.
So,
uh,
why don't you tell people what you do?
Uh,
I am a muscle physiologist,
so I'm a phd in human bioenergetics and
I'm the director for the Center for
sport performance,
which all that basically means I studied
muscle physiology,
why it grows,
shrinks,
repairs,
dyes and all that crap.
Now when you're dealing with athletes
and you're dealing with like state of
the art performance,
how much does that stuff change like
year to year,
like protocols,
like what people used to think was the
way to go,
what's the new way to go?
Well,
if you take a look or if you examine
just the idea of science in general,
it's the understanding that we're wrong.
That totally what science is.
If,
if we knew what the answer was,
we wouldn't look into it.
Like what's the point of doing a study
if we know the answer,
right?
So by definition we're always evolving
in that sense,
but it's quite funny how the central
tenants are really not that different.
You take nutrition,
you take training,
the vast majority of those things are
similar to what they were 20,
30,
8,100
years ago,
so the bulk of it,
what matters for the bulk of athletes is
fairly standard.
What where it differs is the last few
percentage points.
It's getting us that last 10 percent
gains or being very specific so you on a
personal level need this little bit of
difference when you need this tiny bit
of difference,
but the bulk of it really is not that
different,
but when you watch an mma fighters in
particular,
you see so many different methods,
mean so many different ways to approach
things and I never know who's right,
you know,
is it really depends upon who's
successful and they'd go,
well that guy obviously has it down.
Yeah,
that's a major fallacy called the
fallacy of authority,
so or appeal to authority,
which is somebody really good.
Did it or somebody who coaches somebody
really good,
they did it or a lot of people did it.
All.
Three of those are examples of major
logical fallacies,
right?
To break down on Aristotle's reasoning
and it's not what we do now,
they can help us with some ideas of
where to go,
but that's a really bad approach.
So we have to understand like what works
for somebody at a very high levels,
not necessarily going to work for the
bulk of people and particular if like
the great example is is Schwartzenegger.
So when he came out and with his book of
the Encyclopedia of bodybuilding,
everyone was like,
fantastic,
I'll go do those workouts.
You're not arnold and you should be
doing what arnold did when he was at
your stage.
Not at his stage will also is doing a
bucket of steroids.
Well that too,
right?
That's a big factor.
Like if especially back in those days,
they didn't come clean about that stuff.
No.
So guys are like,
Hey,
I call my biceps are ripping off the
bone.
Right?
Or how come it's not working for them.
Yeah.
So all that is really important to
understand what the context of recovery
than nutrition has.
All the other stresses that are
eliminated from his life.
All of that changes what's going to work
or not work for you.
Now there's a bunch of different ways of
approaching things like I've always been
fascinated by the marv method
and now nick curse on takes that method
as well and their idea is that strength
and conditioning is,
especially when a fighters in camp is
more important than anything more
important even than skill work because
you already know how to fight.
Just so strength and conditioning should
take precedent.
Get all that done to get your body to
the point where you have the most
horsepower,
the biggest gas tank,
the best tires,
you know,
the best handling and then you already
know how to fight.
So just approach it that way.
Yeah.
So the guy that actually trained Marv.
Michael.
Yes.
This is the Fullerton guy.
It cal state fullerton.
So he was the cyclist.
Yes.
This,
that's his name,
y e s,
s Russian name.
Uh,
he's awesome.
He's like 85 now or something and if you
want to get massively entertained by
somebody,
like he's a good one because he's just
very opinionated.
But nonetheless,
uh,
yeah,
that,
that is,
I think,
an important one.
If you look at Joel Jameson,
a friend of mine who trains Demetrius
Johnson,
like all those guys,
they have very different approaches and
I don't,
I think the massive fallacies,
it's actually goes back to your original
question,
is thinking that there is one single
answer.
That's the problem,
right?
Whether we're talking training,
nutrition,
recovery,
ice,
will,
any of these modalities,
the major reason we have so much
internet fighting between experts and
why it makes it so difficult for so many
people to figure out like,
well,
what's the right answer is because
searching for the right answers,
the problem to begin with,
we're having the wrong conversation with
all of this crap.
It's not the right place to go.
So those are two very different
approaches.
For Demetrius,
they reduce a lot of the strength
conditioning they do during camp because
they want to get very good with the
train,
with the fighting.
So all that stuff is gone.
So Joel believes in training as much as
we can prior to camp.
And then in camp,
it's time to get better at fighting.
Someone like nick is apparently has the
opposite approach.
Yeah.
I don't think that either one of them is
more or less effective than the other.
It really comes down to the combination
of coaches as well as the athlete.
Some athletes,
and,
and you could attest to this,
and I've seen this a bunch of times,
if they're two days out,
three days out a week out,
some of them get really anxious if they
don't get to practice a skill.
Like I want to be really sharp with my
combinations.
I want to be really good with my
transitions,
et cetera.
And if you take that away from them,
they get very anxious and they don't
like it.
And so you almost have to do is program
at based on this combination of
physiology and psychology.
And that's a bit outside of my realm,
but this is what makes coaching so
complicated is saying,
okay,
well you know what?
For you athlete one,
you're going to do the opposite
approach.
Athlete too,
you're going to be doing the other
approach because you just don't feel as
good.
You're not as confident,
you're not filling the smooth and and
more than anything when they walked down
to that cage or particularly two or
three days before,
they have to feel amazing.
Yeah.
You have to have that combination.
It is weird that like there is no
answer.
No,
there was one like a Mark Hunt is going
to have a completely different set of
requirements than you know,
a Derek Lewis or a mighty mouse.
Johnson or anybody.
It's like everybody's got different
needs and,
and everybody's coming to the table with
a different set of skills and a
different set of problems.
Especially when you look at experience
too.
So what worked for you in your second
fight when you were 20 is maybe not the
same approach you have to take when
you're 30.
I just,
I just got back from New York.
I was in there the last three days and I
was with one of my guys,
Dennis Bermudez and we had this
conversation and when I first started
working with him,
we had to take a very different approach
the week of,
and especially even,
you know,
the hour before the fight because the
way that he got ramped up for a fight is
very different than some other people
that I've worked with.
What we had to realize.
And I remember he called me right after,
um,
one of his recent fights,
uh,
maybe four or five fights go and he's
like,
I'm freaking out because I didn't freak
out in the cages time when really I was
like,
what?
And he's like,
you know,
I'm usually really freaked out in the
cage and this is what drives my
performance.
But this time I was really calm and
collected.
I saw everything and I'm,
I'm nervous that I'm not nervous enough.
So I had to get him in with,
with my good friend Lenny.
Where's the Moses sports psychologist
who works a lot of combat sport athletes
and say,
okay,
we need to get you in a place of optimal
arousal because if you're under aroused,
it's a problem,
but if you're over aroused,
that's a problem as well.
So we had to change the tactics a little
bit between everything from his walk
down to the week of before the queuing,
the things that we say to him to make
sure he's in an optimal state.
Every other athletic worked.
Like all those approaches are completely
different.
We can't have the same thing.
How do you train a guide to do is walk
down all this.
There's a lot we can do really?
Oh yeah.
And I'm not sports psychologist so I
don't go too much.
You know what they do?
Absolutely everything from breathing
drills right to the queuing,
the words you use.
So for example,
in the back,
if you're a Dennis Bermudez five years
ago,
you know Ryan Parsons would have to say
like real vile,
horrible shit.
Like rip his fucking head off.
I want you to bring it back into place.
Like murder him,
rip him to shreds.
That works for some guys,
for dentists at that point,
at that point.
Not Anymore.
Right now it's a little bit different
approach and Ryan and can tell you the
details of what he does now,
but some guys that can you tell some
other people that backstage they're
gonna be like,
what?
Like don't don't say that.
Just like telling me what to focus on.
Remind me my keys in my timing.
And so the guys that are two ramped up
there,
very specific breathing drills,
for example,
we can have them do as they're walking
down the cage as they're in the cage a,
especially if they're the first one down
or the second one down.
So if their first down,
sometimes that's a 10 minute delay
between when they're standing in the
cage and when they actually start
throwing.
Right?
If you're not taking advantage of that
time or if that time is getting taken
advantage of you,
that can have a real problem with your
energy and especially if you get a guy
who is really savvy,
like a connor or John Jones who takes
their time coming down and they mess
with you,
they do different things on the way
down.
That really influences what's going on
with the guy in the cage,
especially if they're less experienced
or maybe attend to the underdog or other
things like that.
So that can all be we be messed with.
Now a guy like Dennis Bermudez is a good
example,
right?
You,
you're
working with him.
He's obviously a world class fighter,
but he always seems to fall just short
on these big fights.
Yeah,
there is.
You know,
this is where it's outside of my
expertise.
I'm a muscle physiologist,
not a psychologist.
Right.
But with his last performance against
Aaron Elca,
who is a really tough guy.
Very awkward.
Really just blood and guts type fighter,
but that was a good matchup for very
good fight.
Good matchup.
Skill-Wise,
it should on paper.
Just so many good matchup,
favorite dentist and a lot of ways where
there's no way to beat around that.
I feel like two things are happening in
that fight.
One,
I feel like Darren Elkins is getting
better for sure.
And he was super motivated and energized
by his performance over Merseyside
backtick,
which is an amazing comeback.
That's incredible.
Crazy.
Yeah.
So,
but a lot of people felt like he was the
favorite.
That Dennis was the favorite going into
that fight.
Yeah.
On paper.
Clearly he was,
um,
from a lot of vantage points,
but it's really difficult.
Um,
you know,
without telling too much,
uh,
Dennis story for him it was quite funny
what happens with the game plan
sometimes and what happens when they get
in there,
even with the seasoned guy like Denis
and I don't know if a part of that was
because it was in New York and Dennis
his hometown,
or if that was because of pat who was
good friend,
fought right before and want to really
crazy fight and the fight before,
if you saw that you just don't know what
goes in.
And then,
you know,
sometimes like in the middle of a fight,
you're like the fights over and like,
I don't even know why we did that.
Just we got into this weird rhythm thing
and we started doing this and that was,
I don't know what happened and that the
rhythm can kind of take over the fight.
And Darren fought an amazing fight.
He did exactly what he needed to do.
Um,
but it was just the,
from my perspective as a scientist,
I one,
I try to stay away from those things.
It's not my job,
but it's,
it's fun.
And this is what makes it exciting for
me.
It's why I work with these folks is
because you can have the perfect camp
physically and sometimes you win,
sometimes you lose.
And so then you go back to the drawing
board and you go,
well,
do we throw everything out?
Do we try something different?
Was it though?
Is it psychological?
Is it physical?
That's the thing to think about
physically.
Fantastic.
What was the physical game plan like you
planned on?
You must have planned on knowing how
Darren fights a super high paced in your
face type of fight that that part's not
a problem for dentists.
He doesn't really get tired and the vast
majority is fights,
but it looked a little bit like he was
getting tired and this fight again,
he can say that,
but from the feedback and from what we
saw,
like he was like,
no,
he just maybe had a hard time focusing.
Honestly,
I didn't ask them very specifically,
uh,
what was going on there.
I kind of give them a few weeks to kind
of get through that stuff before we
start going back.
Right.
What's watched the tape?
Let's go through it.
Went through.
So I want to be careful not offending
him or,
or his direct current,
just like that.
Um,
but yeah,
I mean from my vantage it was like this
was not,
this is not what we were looking for.
He should have just been more active,
particularly in the second round,
which is what really got them in the
east on the third round.
Once you kind of got into it dot Dennis
in our eyes,
lease was pretty dominated that round,
or at least clearly ahead were one and
two were not so good for him.
Um,
but yeah,
I just potentially a focus potentially a
lot of things.
Uh,
he wasn't nothing.
He physically that happened to him in
the fight that he was.
He like,
oh,
I didn't prepare for this.
We didn't think was gonna happen.
This is throwing me off.
He was just like,
I just,
I just didn't go in the second round.
So it's a weird job you have because
you're kind of relying on someone else
to pull the trigger.
You're relying on someone else to make
the moves and you could train them all
you want.
You can get them in incredible shape,
but then,
you know,
ready go.
They're on autopilot.
They're doing their own thing.
Especially me,
because I'm not the guy who's in
practice all day everyday with them.
Like I'm not the Nickerson,
I'm not seeing them 12 hours a week.
I'm out there.
I'm just like,
like Dennis,
I won't even see all camps sometimes
because he's in New York and I'm in and
a in La and so it's like,
so what do you,
do you give them a protocol,
do you give them a schedule?
So my role,
depending on which fighter I'm with,
is completely different.
So sometimes it's one phone call,
the beginning of camp.
Sometimes it's just like,
hey,
this came up when you think we should
do.
How do we go about this?
Sometimes it's a text three times a day
everyday for the whole camp.
Sometimes it's phone calls.
I get,
I try to do like,
this is not my full time job.
My full time job is to research muscle
physiology.
I work with MMA fighters and combat
sport athletes is because I love it
rarely.
So it's almost like a side job.
A side hobby,
yeah.
Yeah.
If you want to think of it that way
because you know,
I have my full time living.
I've got multiple labs to run.
Like this is what I do is publish
research,
right?
I take biopsies of people like hundreds,
tens of thousands of muscle fibers at
this point in my life and when I can
help,
if I think I can,
I will,
but I try not to.
I don't work with general public.
I our lab is different.
I'll put it this way.
Most labs that do the type of muscle
research we do are focused on disease
prevention or treatment.
Right?
So how do we fight cancer?
How do we get people back?
I'm one of the few that actually do this
on the other end of the spectrum,
which is,
well,
let's study optimization like how do we
thrive?
How do we not just get to 80 years old,
but how do we kick ass at 80 years old
and becoming from a performance
background that I have a,
my athletic background.
It just makes so much sense.
I didn't come from martial arts
background at all,
like I didn't do anything until much
later in life,
but I.
Once I started paying attention to mma,
I was like,
there's something energetically,
physiologically far different about the
demands of this sport and it's really
exciting and it's a really complex
problem to solve.
So I just started helping out,
chipping in and then once you get help a
couple of people and they're like,
this is fantastic,
et cetera.
Kind of the ball gets rolling.
So right now basically what I do is
think of it like concierge service if
you will.
Like I don't,
I'm not like,
you can't email me for training program.
Like I don't have an online website.
You can buy stuff from right here.
Like if somebody's like,
hey,
I know a friend who could really need
this or something.
Maybe.
So do you coach people for Diet as well?
Do you do go through everything with
them?
Depending on what they need.
And how do you.
Like,
how do you decide like what a person
needs?
Like I say,
if you know,
Darren Elkins came to you that he might
be very different than Jon Jones.
Like how do you,
how do you decide what a person needs?
So it's depends on if they're local or
not.
A blood work is the easy one,
but the vast majority of what I do is a
lot of conversation.
So I spend a lot of time on phone calls
and skype with them saying basically
walk me through what have you done,
where are you at,
how do you think I can help?
The number one thing I do then is say,
okay,
do you have who else on your team does
this?
Who's helping you?
Let's get on a call with them.
Not so that I can tell them what to do,
but just let me know what your world was
like and then I'll see if I can add some
advice and maybe we'll try this.
I can help you track things.
I can tell you with my experience about
I've seen this happen before or I know
someone that's happened before.
Um,
this is what happened with the best
example was,
do you remember last summer at the Rio
Olympics when that Helen Miraculous won
the gold medal,
the first American ever female to win
gold and wrestling?
No,
I wasn't paying attention.
Oh Joe,
go read the article in sports
illustrated that she wrote afterwards.
She beat,
um,
you know,
I think you Shita was her name,
but she was a three time defending gold
medalist and a 15 times straight world
title.
It was just like rulon gardner when he
beat a Carolyn,
but the female version.
So Helen went down there.
It was crazy.
He was down two to one with like 30
seconds to go in the semi finals,
came back and won.
She was down a point to you.
Is She in the finals?
Ends up,
ends up upsetting her first American to
ever win gold.
Well,
I worked with Helen for about a year on
straight nutrition because she had to
cut a whole bunch of extra weight for
the first time and the whole wrestling
community was like,
you'll never get down to 53 kilos,
like don't do it.
You have to go up.
Because what happened was resting.
This is really weird thing where world
championships is a different weight
classes.
Then the Olympics,
so she was a world champion at 55 kilos
and either had to go up to 58 kilos for
the Olympics,
which had a three time defending gold
medalist and a 15 times straight world
champion or go down to f 2:53
kilos to,
to wrestle somebody who also had that 15
times cert world title.
So pounds wise,
that's like a five or six pounds.
Six pounds.
Yeah,
roughly.
It's not a big deal,
but when you're already like scraping to
get there.
And so she had to make the decision to
go up or go down.
And what happened was she had an
nutritionist,
Eric rebel,
who you may know Eric,
he works at Barnett.
He's been around Josh,
big huge dude wrestler,
but eric was her nutritionist and Eric
reached out to me because he's right
down where we're at and where Helen was
down here and he was basically like,
I know what I'm doing obviously,
but like let's get as big a team as
possible that make the right decisions
as possible.
So that's how I like to work.
Uh,
so when a new person reaches out to me,
I go like,
well,
who else do you have on board?
Don't fire them.
I don't want anybody to get fired.
Let's all put our heads together because
with MMA specifically,
they're not making any income.
Uh,
Olympic wrestlers of the same thing.
She makes like 15 grand a year or
something like he's.
So,
it's what
you have to understand when you're
coaching them.
Like it's not team Dr Andy,
like it's team Helen and all of us have
to be focused on her and it doesn't
matter if anyone knows what I do with
her or not or anybody.
I don't care if you get the credit,
another nutritionist gets the credit.
If you want to actually help these
professional athletes,
you have to let your ego go completely
out the door and say,
why throw people out?
Let's take every information I have
about everything you've ever done and
come together with solutions.
And if somebody else has an idea that
you don't like,
that's up to you to figure it out and
give it to the athlete.
Okay.
So what'd you find out with her?
Like what was the,
what was the issue and how'd you get her
to lose the extra?
So actually it was like a year of
issues.
It was,
yeah,
I mean,
like every day,
every week,
every month something else came up.
So it was like,
we tackle this problem and then we had
another problem.
Iron was a huge one for her iron
deficiency and we had,
she was basically almost flat lined on
her iron,
looked anemic and we had to come in and
go,
okay,
well we're going to add this.
But she was also traveling to Mongolia.
She was going internationally.
So she kept getting sick.
Mongolia,
yeah,
for tournaments,
because you had to qualify the spot.
Dan and she's cutting.
She's had imagined wrestling.
A Mongolian shake is terrifying.
They all moving here at world champions.
Not that terrifying.
They're hardcore though.
This kid shit out of me.
So she had to put her on.
Um,
we had to basically play a game of
saying if we give you the things that
keep you from not being sick,
that's also the stuff that actually
harms iron absorption cheap.
You.
The things like vitamin C for examined
seed to keep you from getting sick,
right?
So that can help you as you're talking
about while she's dehydrating,
so you're saying anytime,
so if you're going to go travel
internationally for a long time,
you can take a big bolus of vitamin C
and it may help you from getting sick
from getting cold.
Does that really affected better than
probiotics?
To heal probiotics that.
We're on that too,
but the point was if you're going to go
on like a two week thing to eastern
Europe,
I'm going to give you every advantage
possible that not probably get a cold
right,
but when wouldn't you do that on a
regular basis?
Like why would you accentuate the Diet,
a traveling trip and give it some stuff
that.
I mean wouldn't you want that boost
everywhere?
So the probiotics are basically a no
brainer all the time,
but I mean you don't see and everything
else.
Yeah,
but you have to be careful because
anytime you go with a vitamin
specifically,
you're going to have potential toxicity
and vitamin C,
absolutely.
Really?
What,
what?
What's the toxicity rate of vitamin C
like?
It's not gonna actually.
Well,
put it this way at generally,
anytime you're getting a vitamin from a
food source,
you're probably nowhere near toxicity
level,
so natural consumption of food.
You're not going to be in a problem,
but you start taking three,
five,
six grams of vitamin C at a time,
you're potentially going to have
problems and it's a whole host and what
makes it really complicated is there's
interaction with other vitamins and
minerals,
so the iron,
for example,
if you give them with vitamin C,
it's gonna help absorption,
but zinc is going to do the opposite and
so if you do these other combinations,
you're going to potentially have
problems or you're potentially safe,
and so we say the campus,
what does that mean?
Do you mean zinc doesn't help vitamin C
absorption or it doesn't help iron
absorption?
Iron.
Zinc actually messes up your iron
absorption.
Anytime you have an a,
b,
vitamin or mineral,
you have potential either co absorption
or you have a confliction,
so you've got to cut things off.
How does zinc conflict with iron?
I don't know the chemistry behind it.
That's weird.
Yeah,
the have a lot of that and you look up
basically vitamin A,
vitamin D,
vitamin K and magnesium,
vitamin K with bone absorption,
so you have to make sure that it.
Like say if you're eating one at
breakfast,
you don't.
Another one at launches at Howard.
If you get it from food,
you're basically safe.
Like we don't really.
This is stuff we don't worry about it.
Even if you supplement like during your
lunch or during your breakfast.
Yeah,
this is what the general answer is.
Don't supplement with vitamins and
minerals unless you have a very specific
reason.
And we did that for the vast majority of
camp,
but she was continually getting sick
because of a variety of reasons.
Some that I probably shouldn't say,
but so we're like,
okay,
fine.
We addressed that and then it was like,
okay,
now you're super anemic,
so let's get away from that.
But what we did basically is get iron
back to a decent level as soon as
possible and then go off of everything
and go right back to food.
How are you failing?
And that one,
she was so low on iron as soon as we got
her to decent level,
like within days it was just like tears
of joy if like I feel so much better.
I'm not,
I'm not sleeping all the time,
but it was continued with the hard part
with her was getting her down and then
you would be shocked.
But the food was like in Rio,
like what?
They told me.
Oh yeah,
at the Olympics.
Oh my God.
Like they told them you'd have a c,
D and then we get down there and she
called me the first day and she's like,
they have nothing.
We've got McDonald's,
we've got popcorn and cookies.
Like there's nothing down here.
Wow.
She's like five Olympic,
horrible.
I mean the basketball players probably
had something but like he's a wrestler.
She didn't have anything.
So they had better food for the more
prominent sports probably probably
because they probably brought their own
chefs.
Yeah.
Oh,
okay.
Right.
So He's dealing with the team and then
she had to be shipped out of Rio to some
other city two hours away or an hour
away or something.
And she's like,
there's no grocery store here.
I can't even walk to the store to get
any,
anything decent.
So we had real problems.
She was,
I'm about to do a opening ceremonies and
we had a plan for food.
Like basically we're going hour by hour,
how do you feel like where are we at
these types of things.
And she wanted to do opening ceremonies
and she called me.
She's like,
I want to do opening ceremonies.
Like,
fine,
cool,
no problem.
This is what I want you to eat.
And whatever it was.
And with the next.
And she's like,
I'm right next to Michael Phelps.
I'm in the front,
like I don't want to get out of line.
I don't want to go back out and neat
because I don't to lose my spot next to
Philips in the front.
I'm like,
okay,
fine.
Well she was supposed to eat whatever
vegetable and food and fat source we
had.
I don't remember.
But she's like,
all they have is cookies and popcorn.
He's like,
I guess I'll just start.
And we actually,
that was one time we didn't do.
We didn't want to do that because she
was at a problem where she was so
calorically underserved for so long.
She or her body would crash quite often,
so we had to keep her nutrients really,
really,
really high or vitamins and minerals to
keep her at a low calorie count,
but her body not freaking out,
so she was like,
what do I do not eat?
And we had to actually go to the popcorn
because of the good fat and the butter
that it had to keep her from not feeling
terrible to get it surprised go to for
popcorn for nutrition at the Olympia and
she was there for like six hours.
They're supposed to be there for like an
hour and go into.
It was a shit show.
That's the most now.
What about other athletes?
Like,
I mean forget about this specific
requirements or someone who has to lose
a ton of way.
Yeah.
Now when you,
when you deal with most athletes,
like what,
what,
what kind of like a strength and
conditioning protocols do you have the
mom?
What kind of recovery protocols like are
using Cryo therapy or sauna?
Like what kind of stuff we're using.
So all of that is,
again,
I think at the problem is thinking that
there's one answer there.
I don't have any athletes that I'm like,
this is what we do.
Hey,
this is our method.
This is that.
I think a generally a terrible approach
is combination of where that who they
with what have they done,
what's their past history,
what do they like,
were they not like what do we really
need to get?
So I try to identify what's compromising
their performance and let's pick the
best solution for that issue.
So you show up and you're like,
your problem is agility.
Your footwork,
you're just too slow in your feet or
we're gonna have a different approach.
Your training.
Then when someone says you're getting
out stretch,
you're getting out strength here.
Like someone's pushing you around too
much.
I don't need to rebuild your feet.
I don't need to improve your maximum
speed because you're already the fastest
and the division.
Maybe your strength is your issue.
So do you do a bunch of tests on them
when they come to you and then you tried
it?
What kind of tests do you do?
So we have an entire center for sport
performance.
We've got six or eight laboratories in
it with a whole host of equipment.
The thing we put the mask on them,
make them run field to Max.
Yeah.
If we need to do so,
we can actually measure the amount of
oxygen and carbon dioxide coming in and
out of the body,
which allows us to get a number called
the vo two Max,
which is the maximum amount of oxygen
that you bring in and exhale.
So it tells us basically year your
maximum cardiovascular capacity and it's
pseudo important for mma.
So the average person's like at 40,
45,
just to give you some context,
that number,
anyone past about 60,
if you continue to go up,
it's not going really make you fight any
better.
So that's one of the things that we did
or we found doing all the research on
the MMA folks is if a point of
diminishing return come around 60.
So if you show up and you're a jake
ellenberger and you're at 52 and I can
get you to 58,
then that's going to help your
performance a lot,
but when you show up in your pack
comments and you're 66 and I get you to
69,
that's not gonna make you fight any
better.
That's not your problem.
What makes you lose in a fight is other
things that you need to spend that
precious training time on.
So when you get a guy or a girl and you
have them in your studio and you start
work,
like what's like the first thing you do
with them?
So it would honestly,
the first thing would be,
well what did the manager or why do they
reach out to me the.
Because usually when they come to me
it's problem fixing.
They don't come to me with like,
hey,
at one seven fights in Roseville.
Fantastic.
Right?
Usually it's,
it's,
this is going on.
I'm losing because of this reason.
That's gotta be frustrating though
because you'll,
when someone's losing the problem is
like a slippery slope.
It's hard to catch yourself.
Oh yeah,
yeah,
well it's,
it's the game to have,
like sometimes they just want another
answer which is just not good enough.
That's a rough answer.
I'm not gonna tell them that I'm not
coat,
but I'm like,
okay,
so we'll all watch the fights of course
talk to their team.
So I'll give you a specific,
ample examples.
So they come to me and go,
hey,
like,
um,
I don't think we're fast enough on the
feet.
This is a problem.
Okay,
well we've got force plates that are
really,
really sensitive measurement equipment
built into the ground and we can have
them do a variety of,
of,
of jumping test,
moving test,
lifting test force plates.
How does it work?
So it's a really expensive scale
basically built into the ground and it
measures it.
Uh,
there is big as your laptop or as big as
the table.
Oh,
so it's fairly small.
as big as the whole table?
Yeah.
They can,
not ours,
but we have one that's maybe the size of
a small coffee table.
Yeah.
And then there's two of them back to
back.
Okay.
So we can do your right foot on one,
your left foot,
another one,
so we can test everything from not only
your forest,
which is like if I,
if I measured your maximum dead lifts,
I would know how strong your back and
your hamstrings and your glutes.
But how do you produce that force is the
big key.
So a good example is years ago we had
some fighters come in and one of them
was clearly not fast enough,
but he wouldn't believe it.
So he was strong,
but it took him a long time to produce
that force.
So to give you a number,
let's say you could do,
you could produce 100 newtons of force,
right?
Just making the number up.
And I produced 100 newtons of force.
But if it took you one second to get
there and it took me a hundred seconds
or half a second to get there in an MMA
fight,
I don't have one second.
So you don't have 100 newtons of usable
force in your sport?
Know that.
It's interesting.
You just said he didn't believe it.
So he didn't think he was slow.
No,
he thought the problems were other
things.
What do they think the problems were?
Who knows?
Coaching like I'm not getting the right
things start.
Uh,
you know,
they had my walkout song wrong.
So you told them your slow dude,
that was my thing where I'm like,
I don't think so.
His coaching staff was like,
we think this is a problem.
Well let's put them on a force plate and
let's see not only how much force you
produced,
because it's strength numbers were high
squatted to lie dead to the law,
but the time it took him to produce that
force,
what's called the rate of force
development,
uh,
his peak velocity,
the time it took him to get to that
velocity.
All that,
when I compare it to him,
to the other athletes and nfl players
and stuff was just like off the charts
bad.
So it,
what exercise do you do to measure that?
So now that's a great example.
So when we have to individual athletes,
they come in.
So say one is the opposite to one of
them is really,
really,
really good at producing fast quickly.
And the other one takes a long time.
So the one that doesn't produce fast or
forced very quick,
we would put them on a drill where we
say,
okay,
the goal of your training is to maximize
how quickly you produce for us.
I don't care how heavy you get,
but this is a reactive strength thing.
This is a speed thing.
So you're going to do a maybe little bit
lighter squats,
but you're going to explode.
You're going to transition out of the
bottom,
you're going to bounce,
you're gonna.
Use Momentum.
You gonna Swing,
you're going to generate fast as
possible.
You're not going to go to maximal
strength.
The other guy,
we get the opposite.
We would take the speed advantage away
from him or her and say you need to be
able to produce more strength without
taking advantage of the speed.
And it's basically comes down to using
the muscle for force or the connective
tissue for force.
And that's really what we can tease out
now,
how much of speed and athletic
performance is genetic and how much of
it is what you've been doing and how
much can you improve?
Yeah,
so that's,
if we actually just completed a really
cool study on monozygotic twins,
monozygotic twins means you're the exact
same DNA,
so it's a sperm went in implant,
the two implanted one egg,
the egg split and you became identical.
Right.
And so we found two twins that were the
exact same DNA,
but one of them had been doing a like
marathons and stuff for 35 years.
The other hadn't done anything in 35
years.
So we had this exact question that's
crazy.
Identical DNA,
one variable different,
which is.
Well that's a huge variable though.
One is a super endurance athlete and the
Ns one,
the other one's a lazy bitch,
something like that or maybe studies a
lot.
Yeah.
Uh,
something,
uh,
I think it was a truck driver.
Wow,
that's so weird.
That's unusual.
Isn't it?
Like extremely unusual.
Usually kind of share similar interests.
If not,
if there are differences,
there are differences.
Mild,
uh,
I kind of do this and you do a little
bit more,
but.
So what were the differences in their
body types?
So we tested them for everything.
A cardiovascular stuff,
vo two Max strength,
all these same tests that we do with the
MMA fighters,
muscle biopsies,
fiber type,
how much fast,
how much slow twitch.
Uh,
all the ones in between.
What we found was of course the
endurance athlete had higher vo two Max,
like no brainer you,
you,
you run a hundred miles a week for 30
years and your brother doesn't do
anything.
You're going to have better
cardiovascular system,
blood pressure,
cholesterol,
all that crap better than the trained
athletes.
But the strength did not favor the
athlete.
The muscle quality didn't favor the
The total amount of muscle didn't favor
the athlete.
The speed didn't favor with the athlete,
really know and want to hear.
The craziest part is the fiber type.
The trained athlete and his quad was 90
percent slow twitch,
10 percent fast twitch,
the untrained was 40 percent slow
twitch,
about 30 percent fast twitch,
and then about 30 percent of some of the
hybrids in between.
Does that make sense to you?
Because the guy was just constantly
running work.
Now what?
That's really weird,
that the muscle quality.
Yep.
Didn't favor the athlete.
I think what it mean,
what do you mean by muscle quality when
you're saying that?
So yeah,
that's a good question.
You can take an ultrasound and you take
an image of the muscle and it looks at
it like a combination of how much
administering muscular fat there is with
the how much total muscle master is in
the size and a bunch of different
things.
So you get this rough idea of quality.
How's it not favor guys exercising
constantly?
Well,
you have to be careful to only one
subject or two,
so we don't know,
but the one implication could be that
yes,
endurance running and cycling is great
for you.
There's a clear health advantage of
that,
but if that's all you do for 30 years,
that's probably not enough to save the
muscle capacity.
We know things that are that are
actually going to predict mortality.
Vo Two max leg strength is one of the
most significant predictors of how long
you live leg strength.
Absolutely weird.
Well,
sort of Tom Platz should live forever.
Yeah,
right.
Some of these guys that squat 900 now
obviously there's diminishing returns.
$400.
I take you to 4:15,
you're not living at day longer,
right,
but think about it this way.
What's the one of the big reasons why
you go from living by yourself to an
assisted living home can't walk.
I can't walk,
can't stand up,
and the biggest one that they're
actually starting to look at now is foot
speed,
foot speed.
Why?
If you trip and you're about to fall and
you can't put your foot out and catch
yourself,
you have to have the foot speed to get
yourself out there,
but these strength to stop yourself from
falling.
That makes sense.
So balance and yet,
well,
it's east centric strength.
The ability to block all those forces
into the ground to catch your whole body
mass from falling or the,
wouldn't it be also your ability to
manipulate your body like yoga?
Absolutely.
To be able to control yourself in
awkward positions at.
The other thing they see is huge
increases in general.
Just physical activity.
When you're stronger,
so when you're really,
really strong and you're 70,
you're much more likely to go to an
extra yoga class.
I'll go and take the dog for an extra
walk.
I'll go grab the thing,
but if I'm super weak and getting off
the toilet is a maximum effort squat,
I'm more likely to just keep in my
chair.
Just stand on the toilet.
Yeah.
Right.
Wow.
That's incredible that there wasn't any
increase in muscle quality,
so that.
Well,
that's also one very specific type of
exercise.
Endurance work.
We're,
this guy was a bodybuilder.
Who knows,
so that's exactly the point.
When you.
The first,
I think the first question you asked
when we started talking was,
you know,
what,
what's the best type of workout?
What we will or what's the,
um,
the new age stuff,
right?
Hmm.
Well,
it goes back to I think every one of us
would agree.
If you want to be as healthy as
possible,
you need to do a variety of training.
Yeah.
It can't just be one modality.
So if you've only done yoga your whole
life,
you're probably going to have strength
problems,
speech problems.
If you've only run,
if you've only lifted weights,
if you've only exposed yourself to a few
of these stimuli,
you're probably in a real problem.
What we've,
what we've done recently actually has
expanded that thinking.
Um,
so my friend Brian Mackenzie and I have
a book that we just came out a couple of
weeks ago on this whole idea called
unplugged where we need to
expand past just lifting and running and
think about what other physiological
exposures do we need that are important
for longevity.
How well do we do when we're hungry?
How about cold?
How about thirsty hot?
How well do we do?
Yeah,
meaning performance wise meaning
everything.
So like are you manipulating diet to
make people perform better when they're
cold?
Like what are you doing?
Every combination.
So if you want to be able to sustain and
perform as well as we can throughout
life,
we probably need to be able to handle a
bunch of different challenges.
You're talking about longevity now,
not like necessarily athletic
performance and will equal athletes.
We would use this under that umbrella
but very,
very carefully.
So for example,
I would not recommend a extensive
fasting in during the middle of a six
week camp.
Part of UFC fights.
Like this is not at all we're saying,
but this is something maybe we implement
outside of camp.
Okay.
So for example,
we have somebody who's very,
very carbohydrate dependent,
right?
And I have a hard time using fat as a
fuel source.
Okay.
Well maybe in during that six week camp,
before UFC fight,
I'm not messing with a tremendous
amount.
We're not going on a new diet five weeks
before a fight.
Like that's not gonna happen.
But maybe,
oh you got hurt,
you got,
you know,
you've got an extended lay off.
Now we start to work on another part of
your physiology.
So that next camp we've got more what's
called metabolic flexibility.
So we have an ability to switch back and
forth before between fuel sources.
Right?
So when you're preparing someone for a
very specific event,
exactly.
Q,
you're ramping up for September twelfth,
boom with this is we have a protocol,
let's get ready.
But then after the fights over then you
might be working on very specific
balancing exercises or that kind of
stuff.
Exactly.
So I'm of the belief that during those
last few weeks,
you need to be very specific to what
you're going to do.
Get on weight,
get focused,
get all these things.
But now if we,
because if we overspecification for too
long,
we have problems.
We have this complex,
these fighting forces called
optimization versus adaptation.
So generally when you're optimizing,
you're not adapting and vice versa.
How's that work?
So for example,
uh,
you brought up earlier,
so we do this stuff a lot.
We've done a lot of studies and
published in this area.
So we're,
we're just learning some of the
physiology behind what's going on with
ice.
And a lot of people ask me this like,
well,
you for ice are pro or against it.
I don't understand why we have to be in
one side of the camp.
Well,
there's,
um,
there's one guy who does,
who,
who doesn't believe in ice.
And Misha tate had them on her podcast
is like the anti ice guy.
He's like saying you shouldn't use ice,
but I've looked at some of the pub med
studies and some of the various.
There's a lot of benefits to ice,
like I don't understand why anybody
would be anti ice,
but it makes sense at all to.
No,
it totally does and this is exactly
where I'm going.
Anti ice makes sense to you or no?
It can.
Ken?
Yes.
In what way?
Because there is.
There's good scientific evidence to show
that there are consequences of the ice
as well,
like in post injury or postworkout for.
So it depends on the workout context.
Okay.
So we'll go to easy examples so it's not
so vague and theoretical.
A post a workout that you try to get
bigger and more muscle mass,
you don't want to do that right
afterwards.
Bingo.
And why?
Well,
because your body has time to recover in
the actual inflammation is supposed to
be good for you.
Exactly.
Yeah.
It's not good for you.
It is the signal to grow.
Right?
So people have this really weird thing
where they like to personify your
humidify chemicals and physiology.
It doesn't know,
it's not good or bad,
like inflammation isn't great or bad,
it just is.
It's a chemical like it doesn't give a
shit at all.
It doesn't know.
It's not conscious.
Right.
So if you were to do and hop in an ice
bath post of a lifting session when
you're trying to add muscle mass,
is gonna fuck up your game?
Probably.
Yeah.
But you're supposed to wait like two
hours.
Right?
It's not the right number though.
The more the better.
Probably more.
Probably four to six.
Oh,
okay.
Why not?
Why mess with it?
And I interference.
I read something about to the two hours
is good after a hard lift.
Well we don't have any numbers to say
optimal yet.
Like they would take a lot of studies to
figure out,
well two's not good but three is better.
So everything she knows rough.
We would have to titrate it up.
We'd have to do a study that says one
group gets two hours,
one group,
it's three hours and then you'd have to
like concentrate our effort.
Like how much exactly.
Effort is just kind of putting it all
have to be in the same training program.
We have to biopsy them all.
Preimposed take blood marks,
a lot of jobs to do.
There's a lot of work.
That's why I'm so busy and there's
creativity involved in it too because
you have to Kinda like manipulate things
and figure stuff out and contemplate.
Well that's why I'm the director or the
CO director and I am the run my own lab
and I've got fantastic postdocs and
students that are actually the operators
that execute
but it seems like everything is
constantly evolving and shifting and
changing and it's like,
well I find myself honestly spending
more time being in the middle of saying
like let's stop all the fighting between
things and let's spend time saying,
well,
what was good about this and what was
bad about this?
Now when it comes to ice,
what about an entry?
Like what are so many twists their ankle
or something like that.
Do you,
do you believe in and icing it right
away?
I have to defer.
Not My area.
Okay.
But to finish the example,
so post lifting session,
maybe not great,
but maybe if you wait six hours or do it
the next day and when we're talking
about ice and we're talking about ice
baths that we were talking about or
you're talking about like a cryo
chamber,
we don't have a tremendous amount of
crowd chamber research,
so I'll have to say,
well actually I should say this with
everything like this is as we know it
now.
Right?
But as I started the show with like if
I'm wrong in a year,
I'm going to say like actually all that
was wrong.
This is part of it.
So what I've read about that
cryo chambers is the big thing is the
anti inflammatory markers in the blood
or the reduction of inflammatory markers
in the blood and improvements inside of
cold shock proteins,
things along those lines that those
would be beneficial.
But if,
if you're saying that,
but you got to be careful and
beneficial.
Okay.
So beneficial for some things,
but they're always going to come in a
compromise is something else.
So maybe beneficial for a power lifter
that may be beneficial for an endurance
athlete.
Does that make sense?
But I'm going to make it worse.
Oh No.
So you have physiology,
which is what I do.
Right.
And this is what science is.
We we biopsy,
we took blood,
we measured one market,
but that doesn't take into context
anything else in their life.
Right?
So for example,
if you get a lift in and you're like,
Oh man,
my elbow always things up on me after I
lift and I bought.
I got a competition in eight weeks or a
show in eight weeks and would be like a
power lifting competition or body
building competition.
And if you get in the ice that takes
that pain away for whatever reason,
physiologically or animalistic or
anything and that allows you to train
more.
Well then we can't see that that was bad
for you.
Or if you were like some of my fighters
who they like,
they feel more accomplished when they do
it.
They feel like they've done some work so
they feel less anxiety because they got
in work.
Well then now we were playing a game
here.
It's more complex when they got in the
exercise or the ice bath in this
example,
the ice bath.
But it would be true of anything.
Right.
So setting them up for a psychological
when.
Oh,
that's fascinating.
So you factor that in,
you have to like,
we're dealing with human beings.
Right?
Right.
But it might not even be real.
Totally,
but really,
but really perceptive.
Right,
right,
right.
Yeah,
I guess so for sure.
I mean confidence is,
is a giant factor.
Absolutely.
With combat athletes.
And there's some preliminary evidence
that suggests perhaps an ice bath.
I think specifically post exercise in
crude model increased mitochondrial
biogenesis.
Yeah.
So now you say like,
well it's bad or good post-exercise
while I'm like,
well,
what's the goal of the training session
now when you say increased bio
mitochondrial biogenesis,
um,
is that within a certain time period
post exercise or is that just period?
Well,
it'd be a,
it'll be when they took the biopsy of
the blood marker.
Right.
What I'm saying,
like within an hour after exercise,
within the sessions.
Yes.
Yeah.
So this one I believe was immediately
post exercise.
So like finishing good event.
Yeah.
Huh.
Wow.
So now you've got a conundrum,
but this is physiology,
right?
It's crazy.
So I get so fucking irritated when
people say like,
no,
this is the thing.
And then they pull up plant flags about
like this.
We do what we don't do it because I sit
in the middle going like,
you're going to be a terrible coach
[inaudible] because you're going to be
in a situation where you're going to
need to violate those rules.
Right.
Wow,
that's complicated.
It is.
I mean this is why we're utterly wrong.
Do you find that that's the case,
his diet as well?
Like I am a big proponent of variable
diets and I think that there's a lot of
biodiversity in.
Well obviously there is where people are
allergic to certain cup type of foods,
you know?
Um,
but I just think this one size fits all
approach to diet seems.
The more I studied diet,
the more it seems crazy.
So I would ask you this,
what do you think about if I came to you
and said I'm going to do one workout
style the rest of my life,
everyone would be like,
that's stupid.
Well,
if you want to be a Yogi says where to
go?
But most of us would say,
Oh yeah,
no,
I
will also.
I just don't think it's fun,
but why do we.
So why is that acceptable to do that
with nutrition?
Then why is that?
I have to be ketogenic and this is what
I do the rest of my life,
or I have to be a paleo or have to be
anything else lie.
In fact,
it's you,
you.
When you said variability,
I assume you mean having a wide variety
of foods in your daily?
Yeah.
I think also a wide variety of foods in
your daily life,
but also I think what works for you
might not work for Jamie or might not
work for me.
Yeah,
I think that's the bio variability,
but we're going to go inception on that
one because you're ready to go another
level.
Okay.
If that is absolutely true and most
people recognize that,
but what we don't appreciate is the fact
that there's not one diet that works
best for you.
Right?
So there might be one day that works
best for me from power lifting,
but it might be different if I'm running
hills or it might be the exact same.
Uh,
what's,
uh,
what the fuck bro it is.
I mean,
what you're highlighting is a real issue
and it's also one of the reasons why
there's a lot of what I would call
confidence men out there and I don't use
that in a good term.
Yeah.
I mean confidence been like con men
because there's,
there's a lot of people out there that
still tell you like,
this is my diet,
this is the way to go.
You got to follow my way and you know,
and they almost always mock other diets,
which is.
Yeah.
How helpful is that?
Not Good.
No,
it doesn't help anything.
It's a big issue in the MMA community.
I see a lot of these guys popping up
where they're trying to make a name for
themselves.
It seems super common that someone wants
to diminish the,
the other people out there doing
different things and like this is our
way and this is the only way is the
right way.
And,
and that's a straight ego shot.
Well also I think what they're playing
to is that fighters in particular want
someone to come along.
Go,
Andy,
I got the fucking solution.
Okay.
You come to me.
This is a fucking house of power.
We're going to get this shit right.
We know what we're doing.
We've got a team of experts to.
He's got a team.
You've got a team.
Yeah.
And then you go,
I'm,
I'm with the team.
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
I started,
I signed up with Joe's team and,
and you really start believing like,
okay,
this is gonna work.
But did you think,
do you think physiology is that
precious?
It's pretty precious.
Not like that.
It doesn't carry mean in terms of like,
oh,
it has to be lined up perfect.
And there's a one magical combination of
everything.
No,
I don't think so.
But I think for some people clearly,
like some diets sure fit better.
Like I had a bunch of friends that went
plant based and not maybe not even
Vegan,
but the majority of their food is plant
based and they just feel better.
Their body just works better than the
vast majority of us would.
Yeah.
Then I know,
but I know a lot of other people that
went fat based then they feel better
too.
I mean like a lot,
a lot of coconut oil,
a lot of Avocados.
That seems to me especially true with
people that are in intense exercise and
I don't know why that is,
but it seems like a lot of dudes that I
know that Lyft,
a lot of weights or that are involved in
Jujitsu or wrestling or anything or this
law explosion.
It seems to me like a lot of fats and,
and fish oils and things along those
lines when they add those to their diets
officially in particular seems to have a
big effect on grapplers.
It seems to help them with joint issues
and a lot of pain and maybe
inflammation.
Yeah,
I could.
Um,
I would say that most people are gonna
far better on a more traditional
carbohydrate diet that are in the more
explosive power strength stuff,
especially at the volumes that mma
fighters are on because of the amount of
output they're doing,
less amount of glucose requirements of
the muscles.
Exactly.
And you have to be careful because this
is the exact same principle.
Either you're adapting or you're
optimizing.
If you're optimizing all the time,
then you're not adapting and vice versa.
So if you push yourself to one end of
the spectrum,
you're going to probably compromise the
metabolic ability to go back to the
other side of the spectrum.
So spectrum meaning what,
like when you're defining it in any way,
but in this particular case,
I mean,
so say for example,
you get very good at metabolizing fat as
a fuel that may come with the
consequences then of being able to use
carbohydrates as a fuel.
So if you're in a sport that requires
that,
that's potentially problematic,
what sport would it require you to use?
Carbohydrates versus ketones?
Anything that's anaerobic.
So almost by definition.
So anything that's maximal intensity,
a difficulty is going to be heavily
carbohydrate for them.
I wish I had got you in here with Dom
D'agostino.
Oh,
you just had him on,
right?
He's,
he's all fat based.
I mean he's a,
a hundred percent Keto and he believes
that key to genic diets have a host of
benefits and that the human body just
functions better on them.
Well,
so here's a good example.
Uh,
I,
I don't know,
dom and I wouldn't say anything about
him without him being right here.
It's not,
not fair,
but everything I've seen of him has been
fantastic.
Like I,
I,
I'm very much supportive.
The vast majority of what I've heard him
say,
but his main lens is being focused on
cancer prevention,
epilepsy,
these things.
But if you look at some of the research,
and I'm not an oncologist,
so I'm going to speak a bit out of turn
here,
but there are now actually
identification of several cancers that
thrive on fat rather than carbohydrates.
Really?
Yeah.
I have not seen this because he was
talking about a host of different
cancers that sugars and you stop them
dead in their tracks,
but yeah,
I'm sure he's fully right.
I'm sure he's totally right on that.
But I did read something about a type of
brain cancer though that is not.
Does not feed on sugar,
right?
Yeah.
So again,
it would be like,
well,
good for cancer or what kind of cancer
alfre prop.
Maybe 80 percent of them.
He's right.
Maybe,
maybe even 90 percent.
I don't know what the number is being
environmentally caused cancer or who
knows.
Right.
But the vast majority of high intensity
exercise is powered by carbohydrate for
most of us who know,
why would it be carbohydrate versus it's
more efficient and it's faster.
Man.
See,
I wish I had you in here with him.
I,
he would disagree with you.
Well,
there's not really.
I mean I got to be careful to say this
faster and it works better.
Like,
well,
you have carbohydrate directly in the
muscle cell.
That's where it's stored as muscle
glycogen.
Okay.
And so it is an immediate fuel source.
So when you're at work,
then those,
your systemic,
those are coming from the entire
circulation.
So when you use carbohydrate for fuel,
you're using the carbohydrate in the
muscle that is exercising.
So if you're doing bicep curls,
you're burning glycogen from the BICEP,
fiber,
not even the muscle,
but the individual fiber that's
contracting.
And how would that be more beneficial
than systemic.
So it's faster.
I'm right there contracting.
I don't have to move it throughout my
bloodstream.
When I use fat as a fuel source,
it has to be,
has to be go through life policies,
which means it's say it's stored fat in
your entire body.
So people right now,
listen to this podcast,
go,
I don't know who the fuck to believe.
It's not a bug on a dude on Monday.
He says,
one thing you gotTa do,
Dude on Wednesdays is another thing.
Yeah.
So that's the.
I guess that's what I would say my
biggest message is.
It's not like a right or wrong thing.
That's the wrong question entirely is
who's right or wrong.
Do you have any athletes who are on a
fat based?
Absolutely.
Who.
Totally.
Uh,
probably those ones.
I shouldn't say that there's Mrs.
Civic Athlete.
No,
they're just like,
hey,
don't talk about my diet stuff.
Who Really.
They say that.
Yeah,
some do.
Okay.
The vast majority don't get.
But Helen did ironman about appellant.
We go through periods of that with her
for sure,
for a lot of reasons.
A,
it's very successful with her periods of
that,
but not when she's competing.
Even during training but not when she's
competing.
Yes.
Not like on competition day?
No,
but sometimes a week of.
So on competition day?
No.
Because you feel like the glucose based
diets are more efficient in terms of
actual physical performance?
Well,
most specifically for rehydration
purposes too,
so because she's dehydrating heavily and
if you don't consume carbohydrates and
the rehydration process,
you're gonna have a real problem.
Oh,
okay.
That makes a lot of sense.
So we don't go there but we'll do it
even maybe like five days out or the
working of or something.
But what we have to be careful there,
and this is one,
again,
this is.
No,
I'm not badmouthing dom at all.
like nothing,
but he's not dealing with somebody who's
generally hypo caloric,
right?
So when we're going through an athlete
who is six weeks of coming down in
calories and if we start cutting out
carbohydrates,
we actually did address that.
He was saying that when you're talking
about kidogenic states in particular,
when you're talking about most people
during regular life,
50 grams carberry carbohydrates would
keep you in a ketogenic state,
but when you're talking about like some
pro athletes powerless,
you're in the hundreds,
100,
250 and you're still cute agentic
because your body is much more
requirements.
So like I told you,
he's smart guy like I'm.
I'm generally on board with what he's
saying is a scientist just like you.
But the problem is micronutrient
quality.
So if an athletes coming down and
calories that and especially if those
calories are coming from carbohydrates,
carbohydrates are their main source of
carbohydrates or plants.
So if we've compromised that and they're
really low in calories,
then they go down to nutrients about
chemicals and that's a real problem.
So we have to be very careful with
getting them into Quito.
If it comes with a compromising of
vegetables,
nutrition,
right,
cold press juices or anything like that.
That's exactly what we do.
Actually.
A lot of the times we did that
specifically.
In fact,
that almost single handedly saved Rio
for a.
It was a real problem.
She had a real physiological crash.
Like just just sucks to think that at
the highest level of amateur competition
they have poor food.
Yeah,
well we had a.
We had to do because especially because
she was basically broke.
We had to like go up real struggle to
find a cold press.
Things that we could get to her that
because we had.
She was on like 40 ounces a day of that
for awhile and it's,
you know,
it's funny we did that and that's,
I don't know,
you could do the math but 200 grams of
carbs or something.
And the second we did that her weight
just started falling.
Really?
Oh,
interesting.
So we added 200 grams of carbs and poem
whites just flu.
And what would,
what do you attribute that to?
Combination of,
of physiological and psychological
factors.
Psychological.
She felt better.
So it caused her weight to drop?
Yeah,
she was stressed out.
She was freaked out the w and that's
cortisol level capture with higher.
Absolutely.
Uh,
interesting.
So she was panicked and she was freaked
out and she was stressed because she
didn't feel good and she's like,
I'm not losing any weight.
And once one,
a part of it was we gave her a system
that she believed in.
Okay.
And so she like,
oh,
okay,
we can do this.
Oh now I also physiological pumps some
nutrients into you.
So I don't know,
like honestly,
I don't know what part of it was.
It could have been all psychological,
it could have been all physiological,
I don't know.
But what we know is it worked and we
gave her a bunch of nutrients and we're
like 40 ounces a day or up to 60 ounces
a day of,
of,
of fresh pressed vegetable juice and
just like clockwork every day,
you know,
this,
this is such a complicated subject and
it's so nuanced and there's so many
different variables that I feel like you
have to be a scientist to really truly
understand this.
I mean,
yes and no.
It's one of the problems with the Bro
Science people,
the people that do not have the real
education and this stuff that are out
there to coaching athletes and and teach
them what to do and what not to do.
It's like,
yeah,
don't really know what you're talking
about and that becomes a real problem.
You have to get care.
Like it's funny because I don't know,
don't dominic said,
but he's example.
I've never heard him plant the flag and
be unmovable.
Movable on idea.
And it's funny because those of us that
do this for a living.
Yeah,
rarely do we do that.
It's the other dicks that do it.
I think you're right.
It's like everyone else is like,
what do you mean?
I get this one on fiber type more than
anything in the planet fiber type.
That's what I do for a living.
Like I could tell you more about that
than vast almost anyone on the planet
and yet I'll still have people who like,
I read this guy's instagram posts,
bro,
you're wrong.
Like I've hunted up,
biopsied hundreds of people have
isolated tens of thousands of fibers and
random under the lasers and studied
them.
And you're gonna tell me because you
read one instagram post or one review
from two lanes.
Look put the.
Well,
people love doing that though.
I mean nuts and they love it because of
that reason.
I know they love to call bullshit on
you.
I don't respond,
so it doesn't matter what it still gets
you.
Now they know.
Yeah,
good luck because I bombed them with
youtube videos,
showing them walking them through the
science and it's like,
all right.
Yeah,
but they don't read or watch that like
blah blah blah.
Dude,
you're wrong on instagram post.
I had somebody on something a few weeks
ago,
some instagram or something and was like
going through.
She was being super respectful so I
didn't mind helping,
but I was like,
okay,
we're done here because I already told
you about my three hour video on this
and you didn't watch it.
Right.
Fuck off.
Bingo.
Three hours.
Videos are hard,
man.
A three hour video is a Goddamn gift
from God because if you stop and think
about how much schooling you would have
to go through to get the information
that's in that three hour video,
it would take a decade.
It took my career and you can boil it
down to three hours and people like,
man,
I'm not interested.
Well,
I went to an instagram page,
this guy or some shit that said,
you're an asshole.
Well I did a five minute videos.
Why?
The first one was like a five minute
video and I just kept getting so much
like blah blah blah.
Yeah,
but you didn't do this.
And I'm like,
really?
You think I missed that?
You think I didn't read that one?
And I was like,
fuck this.
Like here we go,
here's the whole Shebang.
Bmi.
And there you go.
There's the link.
That's it.
I'm done.
And throw it all up there and I still
get the change.
They don't change when you train.
I'm like,
Oh my God,
here we go again.
Now.
Um,
so if someone has like a lot of fast
twitch muscle fiber,
like let's see,
like Mike Tyson in his prime as an
example,
it's like a ball of fast twitch.
Could you turn a guy like Mike Tyson
into like an ultra marathon?
No,
no,
I mean he could maybe complete one,
right?
For sure.
Okay.
So genetically he's elite at fighting.
He's just an explosive individual.
But making him like,
uh,
you know,
fill in the blank.
David Goggins type character.
No,
I mean we have.
So the easiest way to understand this is
plasticity.
Your ability to change your adaptability
is far higher than what people
understand and in fact there's almost a
direct link between the increase in
technology and the increase in the
thoughts of what change and how much
they change.
Oh.
So our ability to measure it.
Bingo.
Okay.
So the reason why we didn't think fiber
type change 20 years ago is because we
didn't have the technology to actually
have the fidelity to measure all the
ones that we were missing.
And those are also probably a
psychological factor in there as well as
from the people that are measuring it.
It's probably easier to say that it
doesn't change then to say that it does.
I don't know that it was just more of
like that was the evidence.
The comp.
Yeah.
Right.
So it's confirmation bias.
The first 10 studies had not shown it,
so therefore you're not looking for it
really hard.
Okay,
got it.
Move on.
Yeah.
Because otherwise you'd be chasing your
own tail forever on that.
Well,
I can tell you right now like it's hard
to,
to get things into,
into publication when they completely
challenged and entire the entire
thought.
An example.
So for example,
if,
uh,
if you were the first one to try to
publish a study,
that fiber types
changed as response exercise training
and 20 years of research suggested
otherwise you'd have a very hard time
getting through review.
They would hammer you for every little
thing that like,
wow,
do you do this and did you do this?
And because we're going to be very
skeptical and that's not a good reason,
right?
Yes.
That's how it should be.
It should be,
right.
A extraordinary claims require
extraordinary evidence,
right?
Yeah.
So I have no beef with that is what the
problem is when the other people who
aren't scientists and don't pay
attention,
like if you don't know what like I do,
then you need to like,
you can talk about it.
That's fine.
I talk about stuff I'm not an expert
about all the time,
but you need to be careful when someone
else walks in the room and goes like,
well,
I do this for a living.
Uh,
then,
uh,
you know,
just concede the point,
but you need to be a little more open
with listening and gone.
Oh really?
Right.
Didn't know that.
Hm.
Yeah.
That's,
uh,
that's interesting.
Can you think of anything that has
changed other than the fiber types?
That's a change the way people look at
things recently because of technology.
Yeah,
I mean,
that's a good example.
Um,
the,
uh,
hyperplasia is probably the biggest one.
And what does that.
So when your muscle gets bigger,
you the diameter of each individual
muscle fiber gets larger.
So it just thickens right?
Well,
hyperplasia is a concept that you
actually add more muscle fibers total,
so you add sells to the entire muscle
and for decades basically if you say
that doesn't actually exist in humans
now as we're improving our fidelity of
our measurement techniques,
it looks like a.
It happens a lot.
We know it happens in other mammals.
How what happens in humans when it does,
it's going to be very difficult and
probably impossible to ever show,
but we have more and more evidence
because we know the mechanisms now
behind the cell growth.
So once we see the physiology and the
mechanics behind it and the molecules
and the gene expression and then we say,
okay,
it lines up with a,
b,
c,
d,
and e.
We just can't show up with f because of
technology.
Now we need to really rethink our
position here.
And that's probably the biggest one.
Now when you're dealing with athletes
and especially athletes that are trying
to make weight like a,
like a fighter.
And do you ever tell them like say like
a Jake ellenberger was a pretty thick
guy.
It's done 170 pounds and you got,
I'm exercising and doing all these
things and you do a body composition of
them.
Do you ever tell them like you got to
lose some muscle like theirs?
Do you ever say that?
Like your 200,
five pounds getting down to one
seventies really gonna fuck you up.
We've done that a little bit in the
past.
People have come and said,
hey,
will you test me and tell me if you
think I can go down to 55 or 85 or
something?
Um,
my general approach is you're better off
staying or going up.
It's almost,
almost always better if they're going to
go stay at a class or go up awake.
I could not agree more.
And you've seen the performances of
fighters when they do go up,
they look so much.
The Jorge Mazda doll is a perfect
example.
Yeah.
Forty,
55 forever fought at one seven.
He's one of the best in the world now.
Donald cerrone and another example.
There's been a ton of fighters that move
up in look so much better because their
body,
like Calvin Gastrula,
he's another great example.
Yeah,
he's a,
he's a diet one though for the most
part.
Like he's,
he gets that dialed.
He should be able to make 70 no problem.
But.
But God damn it looks good at 85,
he looks good.
You see tank,
he's awesome.
But when you see a guy like him and you
know,
you gotta out powered by.
Golly,
Chris Weidman.
What's the line in the sand you draw
where you say,
okay Calvin,
let's put on some muscle and some
strength so that you could deal with the
oil Ramiro's of the world or let's lean
you out and get you off the Tacos so you
can,
uh,
you could fight guys that you're
supposed to be fighting.
Yeah,
that's it man.
That's it.
Internally questioned that if they,
if they really buy in to what I say,
it's,
it's an easy conversation,
but a lot of them won't,
which is fine.
Like,
um,
so I,
I don't,
I don't think you have a good answer
there man.
Like it's tough.
He's a classic example though,
like there's this almost,
I mean it got to be careful.
I don't know his camp,
like I've met him a handful of times but
we've never been in my lab.
I don't know like how bad his stuff his
or,
or how like if he's got medical problems
that no one knows about or if he has any
other issues that are going on and make
it hard.
So that happens from time to time.
So they don't want to just like ice
cream.
Ice Cream is a lot of guys that are
super talented.
They just love to eat,
you know,
man,
it's crazy.
Like a lot of those folks will go to
food for comfort for that and for the
control control.
That makes sense.
Especially in such a crazy world of the
world of competition in combat sports,
especially in this sport where like
winning and losing so finite and when
you get to the top like nobody.
Well rarely people win more than they
lose,
right?
Like it's just so hard,
so hard.
And there's so many with the,
you know,
like in Nfl and major league baseball
and soccer,
there's a clear pecking order.
You beat this person,
then you'd beat this team,
then you get to play for the
championship or an mma.
It's not like that.
Well it's definitely not anymore.
You know,
in the UFC it's real weird.
Like especially the 185 pound division,
like good fucking luck.
Oh you know,
everybody's waiting in line to fight
Michael Bisping.
He's probably going to fight George St
Pierre and everybody be like Luke
rockhold.
So those other guys,
like what the fuck?
When he beat rockhold,
that's my single favorite mma moment in
history.
Really.
I'm not like a noxious bisbing fan or
anything.
But that was the culmination of a dude
who put in so much time and he did
everything to make it a business.
He did everything and then he not only
steps in and fights,
I just killer and rockhold who I thought
was been underrated his whole career.
Like he's this insanely good,
but he'd already,
he'd already lost them convincingly,
you know,
bad subs in the first round.
Yeah.
And older guys don't come back and beat
younger guys in the rematch is ever
right.
Especially on short notice.
Short notice when he had a whole camp
and has every reason to not have
confidence in like 90 percent or more.
Fighters would have just been like,
no,
I'm out.
Like no way.
He takes the flight,
like no one would take that flight
because if you lose twice to the
champion,
you're done.
You're not gonna get third.
Just every risk possible.
And he just nails like this.
Unbelieve clips him and knocks him out.
Yeah.
Amazing.
Like I loved rock whole book.
That was just incredible.
It really was crazy.
And you could really tell that rockhold
just thought he was going to win the
fight no matter what.
It is a done deal.
Totally underestimated.
Bisping's so scrappy.
Like he's one of the most mentally tough
guys in the sport because he doesn't
have like some freak issue while we're
Merrill athleticism or anything.
He's just,
it's just hard work.
He's not particularly fast.
No,
he's not.
He's not super mobile.
He's very skilled and he's got a lot of
physical issues to see out of one I
know.
Is that a bunch of issues with joints
and disks and he doesn't move willing
injuries?
No.
And he's not baked for the division or
anything.
Didn't have people at while.
He's pretty big for when any five.
Well,
not like amazing.
He's not like towering over white men
are rockhold like,
no,
he's not those guys.
Yeah,
those guys are giant.
He doesn't have some amazing skill set.
Either way he can fall back on a world
championship in wrestling to get
through.
Like he just is like pretty good at
everything.
Yup.
Yeah.
Still just finds a tough kid.
He's a guy I would love to biopsy and
figuring out like how much slow twitch
and fast twitch does he have?
Thirty four beats per minute.
Resting heart rate is fit.
Yeah.
He's a big factor.
It's a big factor and that he could push
a tremendous pace and then keep it
going.
Like one of my favorite fights of
Michael's was when he beat Conley.
Oh yeah.
Because he's just overwhelmed them and
just starting to get tired and bisping
just poured it on.
Yeah,
just gave him a beating and that was
sort of a in a lot of ways,
like a,
a shift towards.
I mean he was always a world class
fighter.
There was a shift towards the upper end
of the,
of the division.
It was a big moment for his career too,
because if he lost that,
that's probably about nine tonight for
him in terms of.
Yeah,
you could say that,
but he doesn't give a fuck.
He got knocked out by Vittorio,
comes right back.
You know he got knocked out by
Henderson.
Comes right back.
He's one of the guys.
I've been around him a bit.
He's hilarious.
But he's one of the guys were like,
he doesn't,
he just not going to shake him like
that.
No,
not at all.
He's undeniably tough.
Yeah.
And he's undeniably like,
when he says like,
all fight,
that dude,
he legit.
Oh yeah.
He's there.
And you can say like,
oh,
he's scared of Romero.
No,
he's not scared of any of these students
he's trying to cash in.
When he said,
well,
I think the bisping GSP fight is a
fascinating fight.
It's fascinating.
First of all,
GSPS never fought at 85.
He comes back,
he fights for a world title.
It makes it compelling.
Yeah.
I just wonder if this is unfortunate,
but I wonder how many of these young new
fans I would like to say like post Ronda
Rousey fans,
how many of them even know who fucked
GSP is?
I think there's a lot in my life.
Definitely does.
Well she's a fan,
but I mean I'm wonder if how many of the
new ones,
you know,
the people coming up actually know who
he is and it means it's been a long
time,
you know,
a couple of years,
right?
More than that.
Yeah.
When did he lose to Johnny Hendricks?
I want to say it's three years ago at
least.
At least.
Yeah.
Well Pete Johny Hendricks.
Yeah,
I,
I'm not.
I'm not a big believer in that decision.
I feel like at most that was a draw.
I felt like Hendrix got the most of it.
My buddy troy,
it's brother had 50 k on Hendrix on that
fight during and afterwards he's like,
here we go.
We're done.
Done.
Hendrix thing was interesting because a
Hendrix is one of those guys that you
kind of like what happened to that guy?
Yeah.
You know,
like what?
A lot of speculation on that where you
can all read between the lines there.
Well,
that's,
that's the problem,
right?
Yeah.
There's the Usada speculation.
There's the motivation,
speculation.
There's a lot of speculation.
You also have that thing to what guys
like that,
that put in that many years of wrestling
and you start competing that hard,
that young like that.
That wears on you a timeframe that you
run out of.
Yeah.
There's a like people believe there's a
nine year window as a world class
fighter.
I've heard that before.
It depends on the sport,
but yeah,
that's probably fair as a fighter and
that as a fighter,
like can you get to mma in particular?
Guys have nine years to compete at a
world class level and then the wheels
just fall off.
Yeah.
Get in and get your money.
Get Out.
Yeah,
if you can,
if you can.
Yeah.
That's why 38,
I think.
Bespeaks 38.
That GSP fights,
right?
Move.
Oh,
for $100 move.
Anyway.
What does a business typically do?
Well with like the fighters?
He handles wrestlers decently well.
He's a very good defensive wrestler.
His styles can be fantastic.
It doesn't get tired,
which is what GSB relied on a lot is,
is his stamina.
Conditioning was great,
but that stamina is dependent upon
activity.
Like do even if you're just physically
fit,
but you haven't fought in a long time.
I don't necessarily know if it's
applicable.
Yeah.
Well it's also going to be different too
with.
We'll see what he does weight wise.
Yeah.
So what people don't understand about
when you watch professional athletes,
fighters in particular as a lot of what
happens in that fatigue is either
psychological or it's bad weight cut
stuff.
So now he doesn't have that,
but if he's lugging around extra weight
that he's not used to potentially
problematic depending on how he does it.
Now he's got some smart people in this
camp,
so he's probably going to be fine,
but that's a real problem that he may or
may not be ready for.
Yeah,
if he's lugging around extra weight,
but he was always walking around
somewhere around one 85 slash 90.
He might just decide to compete at that
weight.
That's what I mean.
Like if he stays there,
he's probably fine.
But if someone gets in his head and
tries to get them up to two,
oh,
two or something and then come back
down,
like he's probably not going to feel
normal there,
which he's not gonna run out of gas
because of that.
Like having more muscle doesn't make you
fatigued more.
It's the training that does it now.
Do you have fighters use cardio
machines?
Like do you have,
do you have them use versa climbers or
treadmills or anything along those
lines?
I don't feel like those are super
important,
uh,
differences in terms of we're generally
trying to get most of their physical
activity from training.
Like if you have an extra hour with the
training,
we could get in the week.
You mean by martial arts training,
right?
Really?
Yeah.
Interesting.
So,
but having said that,
if we want to do a small circuit or
something
that incorporates one of those things in
there,
sure,
but I'm never going to prescribe.
If they're not doing it like,
Hey,
let's hop on and let's get an hour on
the elliptical.
Like that's never going to come out of
my mouth.
That's not to say I would never use it.
I'm not throwing anything out.
I'm not pro or con,
but that's chip judicially not where I'm
going to go because it's far easier for
us to help them lose weight through food
than it is adding on an extra hour and
that adding on an extra hour of activity
can be real harmful for them.
Muscularly,
but we're not necessarily just talking
about losing weight.
We're talking about increasing
increasing performance.
Do you believe in any of those machines?
It's not a believer or unbeliever in.
Right.
I would go to it if I needed it.
I don't feel like in camp it's a huge
need with the exception of maybe like a
recovery,
so you want to do like,
hey,
let's go and easy 45 or something on the
bike.
Uh,
but as like a 45 hard,
um,
with the exception of when you start
moving to championship fights.
I do think there's good cause for doing
maybe once a week of saying like,
we do this with Dirk and all the time
like,
Hey,
he loves to ride mountain bikes.
So go out in the mountain bike and go
ride for.
When you're saying dirt,
I mean pat comments.
Yeah,
sorry.
It's okay for people.
Not mostly,
I don't know,
but that's because of it is because he
loves that.
That's his real mental release.
Mountain budgeting.
Yeah.
It's a great workout tour.
Yeah,
it's fantastic.
It's,
he gets in the sun,
he gets away from people,
he gets to breathe and we're not
counting things which can be a problem.
But if I had another athlete,
it was like,
I absolutely hate jogging.
Like it's the worst thing I got knee
problems,
hurts my back.
I'm never going to ask them,
hey,
go jog and hour,
but if you did,
I'm like,
what if someone has knee problems and
you want to get them to do cardio 45
minutes,
something like that.
Maybe in the pool.
A lot of pool work can be really helpful
if they have access.
If they can't,
um,
no one has ever not love the Airdyne or
our assault bikes.
Those are fantastic.
Versa.
Climates are great and I got no problem
with those things.
What is a,
is there a one machine that is like your
standby or go to when it comes to cardio
machine?
Well,
those would probably.
Those are the rower diverse climber,
the rower and the Airdyne.
Yeah.
Aerosault,
any of those things.
Anything that allowed them to move,
that minimizes the amount of technical
teaching you have to do.
So that's.
Most people run horribly.
Um,
this is like a real,
real,
real problem.
Especially wrestlers,
if you ever watch the rest of the run,
it's like you're,
you're a,
you're a knee pain,
you're busted ankle waiting to happen,
so I'm not going to throw that on them.
And they try to teach them a new
movement skill.
It's just not needed.
There's a thousand ways we can get there
if they already run,
well never running background.
And we could go there if they want,
if they want.
Some of them do like it.
Okay,
fine.
We can get there.
But if they don't run well,
I mean technically well,
um,
if they're landing in bad positions that
their fear out everywhere and they don't
want to take time to go to a running
coach like Brian Mackenzie or something,
then we're not going to add that.
We're not going to add a new skill.
They know a lot of,
uh,
Greg Jackson's work.
A lot of his camp,
they do these uh,
hill runs in Albuquerque.
Yeah.
Good.
That stuff going up a hill is a little
different though.
Yeah.
Because generally the foot position of
the hill as much easier to get to.
And it's harder to run bat uphill than
it is on flat ground generally.
So it is something you'd go to.
But that's also probably something where
you don't have as much teaching and
you're an altitude.
So that by itself is going to reduce how
hard you work,
which is going to reduce the stress on
your joints and bones and ligaments.
So that helps.
So all that can be integrated where you
have you reduced the likelihood of them
getting a sore back or knees because you
added some 45 minute running on there.
That didn't really have to happen.
Well,
he'll seem to reduce that anyway because
you're really almost like doing squats.
It's almost like doing or a lunch or
something like that because you just
kind of running and pushing your body up
instead of like the pounding,
the East centric pounding is gone.
Yeah.
This is a very good.
One of the most important things we
stress during fight camp is you want to
minimize the Essentra contractions
because that leads to more soreness and
if you got really sore legs and you've
got to go to movie tie practice and
somebody in the leg like that,
that's a problem.
And so you have to be able to get work
in without getting extremely sore.
So hills are great example.
Aerodyne is like the same thing,
right?
It's pushing the whole time.
It's not landing and impacts running,
rowing,
all these versaclimber,
that's why they're so good at.
Or one of the reasons you can do a lot
of work
is air dine or reverse Karma.
Those things limited in the fact that
like the movement is very specific and
that law is in terms of doing that
versus like maybe like a Kettlebell
cardio workout.
Yep.
You should do.
That's why you need to do a combination.
Okay.
So it's a bunch of different stuff.
Just like we talked with nutrition,
it's variability that gets this is what
we're looking for,
especially when the goal is not that
modality.
So for example,
if you're competing in a kettle bell
swinging competition,
like you should be focusing on that,
but when you're using that for another
modality that doesn't transfer over,
then you need to have a wide range of
stresses.
How do you know like what to tell them
to do though?
So that's the thing is I,
I don't,
I don't think that stress is necessary.
Like who cares?
What do you mean?
So the stress of worrying about which
one to do is not important.
You shouldn't focus on being like,
ah,
should we pick versaclimber today or
should we add,
it should be,
what's the training outcome we're
looking for?
Right?
Oh,
we're trying to improve your ability to
repeat maximal,
sustained 15 second intervals with short
rest and all at the same time,
keeping your breathing mechanics.
Okay,
that's the goal.
Now what modality do we want to use
today to introduce that insult?
And so you think the good move would be
to introduce a bunch of different things
like wild day.
Yeah.
One day,
do the Kettlebell cardio workout another
day do the aerosol,
was that air assault bike puts across
salt air assault,
punch another day.
Do a verse climate climber
as a general quick statement.
Yeah,
absolutely.
But I would say that the smarter
approach would be to step back and say,
well,
wait a minute.
What's the goal of that workout?
What's the goal of this week,
this camp,
this fight?
That's where you then that guides you to
make that exercise choice.
So don't like.
You should never choose the exercises
because you love the exercise.
That's a stupid reason you're getting
angry.
Yeah,
it really irritates me.
No.
Do you measure a resting heart rates,
body fat,
all that jazz?
Not really,
no.
No.
Some folks do it.
Um,
it's not super important for me that you
don't feel like it's important in terms
of finding out whether or not a
fighter's overtrained oh,
that's a little bit different question.
So you can use things like hrv to track
those things.
What's that?
A heart rate variability.
So it'll effectively think of it like a
heart rate monitor,
but it's going to look at how so your,
your heart doesn't disco beat,
beat,
right?
It has variability.
Beebee Beebee,
Beebee,
beebee.
Well,
that actually is,
has some relationship with your
autonomic nervous system.
So if it's really variable,
you're in a good spot.
If you lose your variability and it
becomes
beat,
you're actually potentially being
overtrained.
So your,
your nervous system is a little bit shot
there.
So you can use those in Joel.
Jamison again has done a ton of this
work.
Um,
and you can look at that to,
to have an idea of whether or not the
overtrained so you can use that.
I don't particularly use those things
for a couple of reasons.
Number one,
I know what's going to happen for the
most part over the six weeks,
like as camps going on,
like it's based on performance,
the coach,
the athlete when I've been around them,
like we planned it out so that this is
a,
this is the volume this week,
so that we don't get ourselves in those
situations.
And how do you know how to plan the
volume out?
Like say if you got a gun like,
you know,
fill in the blank.
Chris Weidman comes to you and he wants,
uh,
wants to train with you.
He's getting,
preparing for a five round championship
fight.
How do you know how much work to give
him?
Like how do you,
how do you schedule?
So I would never have the arrogance to
step in and go,
okay,
this is the volume you're at.
Chris,
I've never met you.
Great to meet you,
but here's your volume.
Like that'd be stupid.
Would you have him come and do a test
workout for you?
And I wouldn't have a conversation with
as many as coaches and honestly the
first time I worked with them for
something like volume,
I generally would just shut up and watch
and go,
okay,
like here's,
here's what you're going to tell me you
did.
So write on a piece of paper what you
did for the camp,
what's your plan for the camp?
What have you done in the past?
Then I look and we can assess some
volume and then I can generally tell,
okay,
this is normal for a person of your
caliber of your aid and your experience
or like you're way over what's normal,
but I don't know how that lands on you
and then I watch and as we go along and
it's conversations continuing going,
this is happening.
Your other coach told me this,
you're telling me this is going on blood
working back here,
[inaudible].
I don't know if we're in the right spot
here and then the second or third camp
around.
Then I can have a feel and I can go back
at the previous notes and go,
well,
this is 10 percent higher this year for
three more times here I think,
and then I'll always almost always
matches up with,
yeah,
I'm feeling terrible,
etc.
Etc.
What arE your thoughts
on like plyometrics?
Box jumps,
things on those lines?
Yeah,
box jumps are generally misused so
people don't understand,
especially in and crossfit or an mma or
in wrestling.
People use crossfit for conditioning for
the most part,
which is fine,
but they don't get the biggest benefit
out of it,
which is strength,
speed,
powertrain,
the reactive part of the system,
training muscle spindles,
so absolutely fine as a modality that
they don't get that out,
like how do they.
So for example,
someone does a box jump in,
they're like,
okay,
box jumps,
I Want to get better power my legs,
so they'll go and do like a bar for five
rounds and then I'll go do 100 box jumps
as fast as I can.
You're not getting any faster like that.
You just getting more tired.
That will not improve your power at all.
It won't know because you're not jumping
halfassed,
you're actually jumping at a very sub
max speed the whole time because you're
already fatigued.
Oh,
I see what you're saying.
So if you want to use those for power
now,
if you're using it for conditioning,
fine,
no problem,
but if you're using it for the sake of
improving your foot speed or your power,
your strength,
or your explosiveness,
you should be west rep.
Well rested.
Yes,
yes.
One to three reps take a break,
etc.
What do you think of like that strong
first protocol?
Do you know the pavel tatsu lean idea
that you know he.
He feels that strength is.
It's along the same sort of lines.
What you're talking about.
The strength is essentially a skill.
Oh,
absolutely.
You should not be doing things to
failure.
That the best way to do it in his
estimation,
is to do more sets with more,
more break in between them.
That is very strength one-on-one.
Like you'd have a hard time for a true
strength person disagreeing with a lot
of that.
It's hard to get stronger when you're
tired,
so going to failure is not as now I've
talked to a bunch of people about this
that have started doing this recently,
like within the last year or two and
they've all experienced great results
and that the idea being that you used to
go to failure and then he'd be wrecked
for like three or four days instead of
that,
like say if you could do 10 reps or
something,
you do five and then you take a big rest
and then you do five again and he took a
big risk and then you wind up.
Instead of doing 15 reps,
you wind up doing like 30 over the
course of an hour and a half and then
you're fine the next day.
Well,
I mean you had lujan simmons,
right?
Yeah.
This is classic fucking maniac.
That guy.
He was awesome.
I love that guy.
I always tell my kids,
my students to google him Because you're
not going to get like an.
I could get bored.
Oh,
listen to my podcast with him.
It's one of the most entertaining things
I've ever heard in my life.
He's such a character.
The basic idea.
Um,
well we'll have to back up for a quick
second.
It depends on the goal,
right?
Strength.
If gold pure strength is the goal,
failure also has to be defined.
So what do you mean by failure?
Now?
My family because of fatigue,
right?
Then he's totally right.
Right?
Am I failing though?
Because the two heavy.
Well you do want to go to that failure
for strength.
I also though,
so need to at some
point pick up something that you can't
pick up or really close to camp.
Pick up to get stronger.
Really close to it.
Like you can do,
right?
But you can't do a second one.
Put it down.
Or maybe you could do two,
but you can do three or something like
that.
The,
the very textbook answer is anything
below five repetitions ish is going to
be good for strength to the maximum.
Anything more than five is bodybuilding.
That's what paul says.
He,
that's the.
That's pretty dead on.
I mean he's not too wrong there.
And we're like,
well,
a reason I brought louie up his,
his,
his classic.
We're saying first reps,
so if you did three sets of 10,
right?
Well you had three first repetitions,
So you had three reps that you did after
rest,
but if you did 10 sets at three,
now you have 10 for strips.
Oh,
interesting.
That's right.
So now you did the same total
repetitions,
but 10 of them were done after full
rest,
which means you're gonna have more power
and more force.
Does that make sense?
That it seemed smarter.
That's basically it.
So you're better off doing 10 threes,
then three,
10 for strength for strength or power or
speed.
And then taking a big break in between
them is sort of counterintuitive to a
lot of people.
They feel like,
oh,
I don't want to be a pussy and then let
myself get fully recovered.
I want to push while I'm still at.
Come on,
come on,
broke.
Right?
And they'll help you up.
Come on,
come on,
come on.
Yeah,
I see that all the time.
Meat heads in the gym and they think
that's the way to go.
And I'm like,
man,
I don't know.
And they're gonna.
Well,
they're gonna.
It's the way to go if they want to get
sore,
if they want to maybe prove awesome.
Do that though.
They love to walk around sore.
You know what's funny?
This is like the number one reason I got
into mma was that that question,
like right there,
people kept coming to me with this and
I'm like,
you don't know basics of speed training
or strength training and the mma guys
were so wrong,
and then I.
That's how I got into this for the most
part is people are like,
oh my god,
this is changing like everything.
I'm like,
well,
mma training is.
It's weird.
It's really strange because mma training
is essentially.
It's still in its infancy,
right?
It really didn't even exist until 1993
and then it didn't even really exist
even then until like.
I feel like frank shamrock was the first
real professional mma fighter because he
was the first guy to figure out that you
have to be an insane cardio and he was
the first guy to be able to strike and
also be able to grappled,
be able to fight off of his back and
piece it all together and the cardio is
was.
It was a huge factor,
you know,
he,
he was like,
when he beat tito ortiz,
it was way smaller than tito,
but he beat them because of cardio.
But one of the things that I used to see
early on that was so confusing to me
because I came from a striking
background was how many of these guys
were willing to beat the fuck out of
each other in the gym and like that they
were just going to war but not even
going to war with like good skills,
like going to war while they were
learning for the sake of war.
Yeah.
I mean,
I mean I'm watching them getting and
they're
beating the shit.
I'm like,
you guys are professionals.
Like this isn't like,
this isn't like some idiots.
At the y like you guys are,
you're supposed to be pros like you
could have damage yourself.
The takes years off of your career.
The vast majority of you know me working
with athletes is doing these very,
very basic things like I'm not.
I'm asking not.
The guru was like,
oh,
I know the,
the 18 point blood tests and we're going
to get these.
The vast majority of what I do is go,
oh,
okay.
I see the problem here.
Oh,
we need to do this basic thing.
Right.
You haven't eaten a vegetable in a week.
Got it.
Like that as not as much anymore,
but I used to really?
Yeah.
We get a lot of the pro athlete that
doesn't eat vegetables we get is
honestly it's because probably
[inaudible] assholes like you and they
want your show or something.
I tell people to eat vegetables all the
time.
No,
they.
When they watched this and then like,
okay,
they'll come at me with a thousand
really weird nutrition questions or
something.
A really weird advanced training ones
because I went to a seminar or something
and I'm like back the train up like
you're sparring six times a week.
We've got a whole nother conversation,
like,
oh,
we don't do that.
No,
that's not normal.
Really?
No.
Okay.
Or you're doing that or you're running
35 miles a week.
Got it.
That's the vast majority of what I do
is,
is bring this guy's back to life and go
like,
let me help you sift through all this
internet stuff that's really complicated
and let's take what's actually good and
bad and dial in a very usable system.
So I think people just get overwhelmed
with options for me internet.
absolutely.
Because too many people get on exposure
and get on shows or platforms and they
try to make sure that,
that they are known as the guy that
knows something different.
Right,
right,
right.
Well,
it's like it's not very exciting if I
come up here and tell you like,
oh,
joel has pros and cons to everything.
Great.
Like,
well that's not fun,
but it's good.
I mean,
I think what you're saying is very
important for people to hear,
like the no wait,
they get bogged down in the details,
way too much if things that really don't
matter,
your body's not that sensitive or
sensitive enough where it can't convert
something from from something to
something else and if it needs it,
it will do that for the most part.
So there are some real small things at
the end,
but a lot of what we can do is just get
you on a reasonable program that's
actually possible for you to implement
and that doesn't drive you so crazy or
so is so difficult and so confusing for
you that you get halfway into it.
You abandoned it and then you want to
start over.
Well,
you know,
I always think about dan gable and when
dan gable was young,
I pretty much outworked anybody and he
was just an unbelievable savage when it
came to his training and then that
manifested itself in the competition.
He was just like,
the momentum behind him because of his
roof was training was so intense,
but now he can't even walk right.
When these hips are gone,
his knees or guns got artificial,
everything,
you know,
he's just fucked up because of it.
And soMe guys were willing to MAke that
sacrifice.
But is that,
here's the question,
is that sacrifice necessary?
Like can you be too tough versus smart
in your training?
It's impossible to say,
right?
Because like you said,
that here's where it gets so tricky is
physiology versus psychology.
So if that gave him that extra mental
confidence that he needed to perform
better,
well then it's hard to say that it
wasn't necessary.
Yeah.
Like he was always talking about guys on
steroids that he liked competing against
guys on steroids because he knew they
were mentally weak and they would break.
Right?
So who the hell knows?
Right.
Like you've got,
you have all this conflicting stuff and,
and you try to do this dance,
which is why again,
you need People,
you need a team to do this stuff and
say,
okay,
this is what I think.
So people have a really hard time with
physiological truth or scientific truth
and implementation.
so a very easy one.
Sugar,
right now,
like I don't know anyone in the world
who advocates adding sugar to your diet.
It's a good thing like no one's gonna
say that.
Right,
but what you tell somebody a scientific
truth versus what the message you spread
it spread to either your athletes are a
bunch of people that can be very,
very different because because of
unintended applications are
consequences.
So for example,
there is no physiological harm with
sugar.
It's not bad for you in any way,
but as a message to the general public,
that's not the worst thing to say.
And so most of the fighting that goes
back and forth between any conversation
like this is people saying,
yeah,
yeah.
But the actual effect of it is good.
Yeah,
but the science is wrong and they're not
conceding that they're actually talking
past each other far more than they're
talking to.
You don't think that sugar is bad for
you?
No,
it can't be.
It can't be unless implementation.
No,
no,
no.
what he's saying.
So now we've.
Okay,
so sugar in your diet.
No.
Sugars is where it gets confusing.
Exactly.
Because you want to break down sugar,
having sugar in your diet,
like eating sugary foods and snacks,
having an excess of sugar has dire
health consequence.
Totally correct,
absolutely.
But there's a key word you said there
which was excess excess.
Okay,
so like meaning a piece of fruit,
like a nectarine not bad for you at all.
No,
of course.
Good for you.
And plus fiber.
Absolutely.
Yeah.
But processed sugar,
whether it's removed from that fiber and
put into a cocacola dot becomes an issue
because of concentration issue because
now you can consume that a concentration
that probably wouldn't happen normally.
And quantities that would never happen.
Normally thing go.
So now you could have a person in the
corner of left who that says like,
no,
you're an idiot.
Look at the science says sugar is not
bad for you for a thousand reasons.
And they're technically right.
But when we have conversations to $350,
million americans,
they don't want all that detail in
between.
They want do,
do I do it or do I not?
And so if I have to take a hard line and
I go,
you know what?
Sugar is bad,
don't eat it.
It actually causes a generally good
effect on people.
They go,
oh,
okay.
I didn't know this.
Adding sugar to my stuff is not good.
Don't do it right.
Which is a net good thing.
Although technically individually it's
not true.
I see what you're saying.
So sugar in and of itself is not bad.
excess sugar and processed sugar
and added sugar in mass quantities is
bad and that's what you're dealing with
with the average american diet,
whether it's through breads or pastas or
actually sugar and soda itself,
right?
or sucrose or are or any of those things
and added to it.
And so when people go,
the poor souls go on the internet and
they're trying to figure out like,
wow,
god,
are carbs bad for me or not?
It's like,
well,
you're fighting over stuff that's not
important and we're missing the message
because people want real answers and
you're not helping them give it to them
anyway.
I don't care if it makes you look right
on the internet.
We need to come together and say,
okay,
well here's good,
here's bad and bad and here are the pros
and cons,
etc.
now here's the information for you folks
and it doesn't matter whose book it is
or who wrote it,
like that's not the important part.
Well even having this conversation
though is going to be really confusing
to a lot of people because you're,
you're talking about so many different
variables in by your being
intellectually honest about all this
stuff and saying,
well it's,
you know,
there's no real good answer.
Yeah.
You know,
and it's different for one person is for
another person.
Some,
some people might get over really well
on like macadamia nuts and almonds and
get their protein from,
you know,
and other people they might actually had
an allergy to those things.
Yeah.
And you know,
trust me and tried to be my students.
They get irritated this shit when I do
this to him,
but it's probably
good thing.
But when a fighter in particular is
thinking about their career,
they sort of exist in these six week to
eight week lifespans like their whole
life.
Unfortunately,
or fortunately when it works out well
that they go through these,
ruth was training camps
and to have any variability had to have
any unknown to have any.
So this is bringing up a good point.
This is not a kind of conversation I
would have with a fighter,
right?
Not during,
not specially 10 weeks out from a fight
overload their brain with possibility.
No,
no,
no.
It is very clear.
Like what do you do?
What do you like to do?
What do you hate to do?
What have you done before,
what's worked well,
et cetera.
Okay.
Uh,
so,
uh,
I have an analogy called the cook,
the baker and the chef.
I give you the very quick story of it.
You can listen to the whole episode on
my podcast if you want.
What's the podcast called?
The body of knowledge.
Okay.
So it's on itunes,
all that stuff,
all that stuff.
Body knowledge.com.
It's,
it's actually a not to talk about that
too much is only nine episodes.
It's not like going on running podcasts.
it's like radio lab dan carlin,
but for physiology and finishing.
So not to that extent,
but you get that here.
Yeah.
Okay.
So I like to look at people as either
the easy one is either a baker or a
cook,
right?
So do you know what the difference
between baking and cooking is?
No.
Cool.
most people don't.
Baking is chemistry basically,
right?
You can't.
Like I'm a little tablespoon here.
Maybe a teaspoon.
Baking soda,
baking powder house,
same thing.
That does not work.
You can't bake like that.
Right?
You will not make anything.
You would have a mesh of crap.
And an oven baking is chemistry.
You can do this in this order and,
and then you add this and you cannot do
these.
And other orders.
It's very specific.
like roughly cooking is like,
well all right,
well what's left?
I get some oil.
It gets some hot.
Kind of dicey.
Yeah.
Throat throw some whatever you give them
mishmash,
right?
So people generally I find work well
with nutrition information,
either one of two approaches.
So if I said,
joe,
I'm going to do a nutrition program for
you for the next six months,
whatever you want.
And I said,
you can either do this one of two ways,
uh,
we can work together every morning,
weigh every single thing you eat on the
scale,
text it to me,
I'll tell you exactly how many slices of
avocado to have,
how many jalapenos,
and I'd tell you exact weights and
volumes for everything.
Or we can maybe text once a day or once
a week and we would just go over
concepts and ideas.
Here's what we're trying to get to do
what you want.
Which would you like,
man,
I don't know.
What should I look?
It's not a should.
It's a personal preference.
So some people would.
I cook,
just wants ideas,
give me the concepts,
like one or two things to work through.
Cool.
I don't,
I get anxiety with all those rules.
All the information like I can
implemented.
Like it's too complicated.
I don't have that much time,
et cetera.
I called these people,
cooks,
other people get anxiety.
Like my wife natasha,
when I don't give her exact numbers,
she's like,
well,
is six grams for the eight almonds or is
it nine?
Almost like,
what is it?
Right?
So giving people the information in the
way that they absorb it is important.
So if you talk to a baker,
so chemistry details,
weighing everything out and I go are
just,
here's what I want to do,
a little bit of fat,
a little bit of protein,
some grains,
and it's not going to work for them.
You have to give them a very,
very specific system.
Having a cup of this tablespoon of that,
even if that system isn't perfect.
What about chef?
So chef is someone who knows the
chemistry of baking,
but has the years of experience of
mixing it in different ways.
Now you can go ahead and break those
rules,
right?
Chefs break camp,
cooking result of time.
Baking roles.
So a chef was like anderson silva.
well,
a fighting.
Yeah.
But a chef would be maybe where you're
at in nutrition,
where you like,
I can do that.
I could follow a very Specific diet,
but I know the concept and I know these
rules.
Let me experiment here.
And you have room to maneuver.
The problem is most people want to jump
in and be chefs.
People want to fight like anderson silva
their first day and you get overwhelmed.
I see what you're saying,
so get a detailed understanding about
how your body functions under very
specific protocols and then start
fucking around with it.
Or the opposite.
Start off with a cook approach was to
say,
let's give me.
Let me give you one or two concepts this
week.
I want you to eat one fresh green every
day and I want you to do make sure you
have protein every time you eat.
That's it.
My only role.
Okay,
next week we had a rule.
maybe we got another concept,
and as you get better and you get more
confidence and you get more comfortable,
you can go,
okay,
well how much protein?
Exactly.
Well,
let's just try a hundred grams.
All right,
well that's a that unless they're 150
and we've slowly pushed you,
but generally being a baker,
all those rules weighing everything
generally that's not sustainable for
most people.
now when you coach,
do you coach them as far as their diet
goes?
Do do you actually tell them what they
shouldn't need?
Depends on if they're a cook or a baker.
So a cook.
I do not.
I tell them basic concepts.
Right?
So I talked to them how,
what's going to be helpful for them?
They go,
what you think I should do.
Should I add more carbs or shit out?
Here's what I'm feeling when I'm.
I'll go.
All right.
Where were you at?
Like here's our diet.
Yeah,
let's add more carbs.
How should I do this or this?
Uh,
this one.
Do you generally tell people to avoid
any specific foods or are there any
things that interrupt training or get
into the way outside of the obvious?
No,
no,
I mean the basics.
Candy,
pizza,
right?
Not really,
unless we have some very specific
history with them that hey,
remember you don't react well when this
happens.
Um,
but generally,
I don't know.
When you say like protein,
do you specify fish or chicken or meat
or fits a cook?
No.
No?
If it's a baker,
absolutely.
Absolutely.
And whether it's important that I chose
fish or chicken almost doesn't matter as
much as telling them that the fact that
they all go,
he's got it dialed for me.
Credit,
I got a sense that you have here eight
ounces of halibut.
There it is.
Bam,
right?
Because you'd be like,
the vast majority of the ones I work
with are already pretty good with their
nutrition and it's really more concepts.
Um,
some of them would want the stress
relief telling them what to eat and they
want someone to come in and hey,
like,
do you know anyone that would come in
and food prep,
meal prep for me and yeah,
okay,
we can do that.
Um,
but some of them like it,
some of it is their distress.
Some of them like that control.
So I try to help them.
Again,
it's not about me.
I don't care if my system worked.
I don't have a system.
My system is what do you want to do?
How can I help you and your team?
What can we do?
That's the approach.
Wow.
God,
that seems so.
It's,
there's so many variables and it's so
complex,
which is why I get so irritated you,
you're teasing me earlier,
bucketing all fired up about it.
I could understand,
but I appreciate this intellectual
honesty about these variables and about
how there is not one approach because
again,
there's so many dickheads out there that
are teaching their method in air quotes,
so here we go.
Let's take those dickheads.
Right?
If you're a baker,
landing on one of those systems is going
to be fantastic for you and you're going
to five star review and you're going to
try it out everybody because you're a
baker and you needed a system.
Yeah,
and if,
if you're a cook though,
you're going like,
well,
who cares?
And if a scientist could step in and go
like,
well those are all the problems and this
and this and this and this,
and then everyone's fighting back and
forth.
They were like,
well fuck.
Do.
I guess though he felt like I'm so
confused.
Well,
it's not the right question.
I think what irritates a lot of people's
at some people are finding like this
insecurity that people have and they're
exploiting it by telling them exactly
what they think is right.
It's human,
right?
We
want the next solution.
We want all this stuff.
We want it all dialed into one.
It's a,
I call it fallacy of unicorn.
Like I'm just gonna keep searching
because there's.
There's this one thing and if I fix that
one thing,
everything else align up.
It doesn't work like that.
Yeah.
Now what about vegetables?
Like do you specify the type of
vegetables you like?
Do you prefer a dark,
leafy green vegetables,
general statement beats or the more
color,
the more texture.
The bedroom.
Right,
and like you said actually earlier,
it's the variety that matters.
What these folks as sustainable.
Now having said that,
here's what I'll do outside of camp.
These are conversations we're having,
like I want as many different vegetables
as you possibly can,
different colors,
different countries,
different seasons,
all this stuff,
right?
Let's,
let's cook them sometimes.
Let's steam them.
Let's eat them fresh,
let's eat them raw.
There's pros and cons.
Exactly.
Oh,
now you got to fight in four weeks and
we're 25 pounds overweight.
Sometimes I will take those options away
because it's easy.
Then to control numbers.
If I say,
okay,
here's the approach,
you're going to have a,
b and c at these three meals every day.
Every other day we'll rotate.
Then I've just removed a bunch of
variables from there and they can just
refocus and go,
okay,
boom,
and we can watch the weight.
We're down to half a pound,
we're down half a pound down a quarter,
pound were great.
Let's maybe exchange out kale for
spanish this time or something,
but the hard part about extreme
variability is lack of control and so
sometimes if you're like,
why am I mean not anything you're
telling me,
I'm meeting a bunch of different stuff
and I'm not losing weight.
Well,
maybe they don't understand yet,
but this type of vegetable has a lot
more calories in this type of vegetable,
so we're getting really high up in your
numbers or when you eat this,
the way you prep it,
the way you like it is glaringly dense,
so I will reduce options for them.
So it was funny because if you looked at
one of mine nutrition programs for my
athlete,
you could look at it and be like,
oh,
this guy's an idiot.
He doesn't have this,
this,
and this.
You stupid.
He doesn't have any of this.
And you're like,
dummy.
You think that that three day plan is
what we did the whole year round.
Your argument is someone who's not even
real.
They're real you of all people know the
What about water?
No,
I've always wanted to ask somebody this.
I hope you know the answer.
This is all these,
these ways to treat water,
alkaline water on bullshit,
right?
Mostly.
Yeah,
I would assume so,
yeah.
We actually did a study on that six
weeks alkaline.
What does it mean?
Like what the fuck is alkaline water?
That's ph right?
So it's the opposite of acid or alkaline
is the base,
but I mean,
how do they make the water that way?
Like what are they doing to it?
Oh,
so generally water comes a probably a
little bit acidic,
especially our tap water.
Uh,
and so I would imagine they just do some
sort of combination of salt or d salting
pretty easy chemistry wise.
So to get it a little bit technical,
but just,
I think it's salt to your water.
I think somebody did,
um,
actually did a study of a bunch of those
alkaline waters and tested them in the
store,
like bonding different brands and they
were all over the place.
I said,
eddie wise.
Yeah,
I would imagine that we're not even
close to alkaline,
but just remember it's going to change
and it sits on the shelf when it's
exposed to sunlight and all that crap.
I call it holy water.
Yeah.
It's kind of silly.
I always feel like,
oh yeah,
that's the blessed water.
Like,
come on man,
it's fucking water.
I mean,
dude,
look,
I'm open.
If studies came out and we kept doing
it,
we're like,
oh shit.
There's something here,
but there no studies currently before
with friends.
I'd be like,
that's not a sense that stupid.
I mean a punch of things.
The training mask is training masks.
Yeah,
absolutely is good.
Well,
it's not good or bad.
It depends on what you use it for.
How dare you.
Yeah.
I needed an answer.
I'll give you an answer.
Okay.
So what I'd like to do is give examples
of,
of when good one bed.
Right.
And this is a brian mackenzie.
I keep bringing him up,
but he taught me this lesson.
This is a great lesson in humility.
Uh,
so he's,
uh,
if you don't know him,
he's a,
he was really disruptive in the running
community and the movement.
He's,
he came up,
kelly started at like,
that came up together.
Okay.
Um,
so I wasn't interested in him.
People kept getting at me like,
hey,
go look at his stuff.
And I'm like,
well,
he's a crossfit coach out like
nonchalant,
like crossfit coach.
I have nothing against that.
but at the time I was like,
what does crossfit coach?
No,
right.
Again,
arrogance on my part,
mistake and second,
I'm like,
you're running coach,
like I'm doubling on uninterrupted.
Yeah.
Again,
this is me highlighting my mistakes.
And so,
but then I actually,
funny enough,
paid attention to what he was saying and
it turns out there was something there.
So it's funny how much you hated someone
when you don't actually listen or read
their stuff.
So,
uh,
he was promoting the training mask and
I'm like,
you know,
like everyone else,
I'm like,
does it work evidence so it doesn't
work,
et cetera,
et cetera.
And then I listened to what he was,
how he was actually using it,
so he wasn't using it to simulate
altitude because that's not really
effective,
but he was using it to teach people how
to use their diaphragm.
And that's when I was like,
oh,
I get it here.
So I'll come back and I'll finish this
in.
But the quick analogy here would be if I
handed you a pen and said,
you know,
like does this pen work?
Well,
it may not work as a dagger,
but it worked pretty good as a pen.
So the problem with the mask was it's
flipped,
it didn't work for what it was told you
to work for,
but it worked because in this case,
the active restricting people's
breathing sometime can help them learn
to use their diaphragm.
People who breathe with their shoulders
up and they don't use their stomach and
their diaphragm a lot when you put one
in front of their face,
they don't have that option.
And so they learned to breathe their
belly and user diaphragm.
Interesting.
And so I just didn't give him the time
of day because I'm like,
training mass doesn't work,
elevation,
et cetera,
et cetera.
Right?
Oh,
that's not how you were using it.
What's the benefit of breathing through
the diaphragm with a mask on?
It's not the mask that's important is
the fact that it would use.
It's a quick way to identify if you're
bringing this.
So you figured out it's like a white
belt boss route and has some sort of a
breathing device.
And he,
um,
he was telling me about some studies
that they did with it was showed.
Was it you?
That was mine.
Oh,
beautiful.
My lab,
well,
what he was saying is that what makes
his better is that it's easy to breathe
out the valve open so you can exhale
really good dump your carbon dioxide.
Whereas other ones that have just
smaller holes are not as good.
So we did that study.
Oh,
okay.
And this is actually what turned me on
to brian initially because I'm like,
my boss came to me with the o two
trainer.
I was like,
like this stuff doesn't work bro.
It turns out it does.
But here's a good example.
Um,
so his device restricts airflow in,
but you can change the setting so it can
be a lot of restriction or a little bit
of restriction.
He has lIke filters that you put on it.
So right there boss route and yeah,
the o two trainer.
Exactly.
Uh,
so all those little valves on the left
and right hand side,
they're thick.
TheY have increased airflow or decrease
airflow.
So what we did is we had people come in
four times and they either got the
height restriction,
low restriction,
medium restriction or no restriction.
And what we saw is in every person under
one of those,
sorry,
let me back up.
They came in and either they did some
breathing drills like blowing it out,
inhaling as hard as they can,
blowing it out.
And they did that 30 times and then they
did basically a vo two max test.
So they ran to exhaustion which took
them five to eight minutes kind of
thing.
So we want to see like I was interested
in performance,
like does this actually make me perform
better?
And so they either got a lot of
restriction,
a little restriction medium or none.
Every single person got substantially
better,
like 20 to 30 percent better under one
of the conditions,
but they also got worse under one of the
conditions as well.
So what that told us was this,
if for example,
you went under the high restriction,
so you're like you can't get any aaron.
It actually fatigued your intercostals,
which are the muscles between your ribs
that open up your ribs and allow airflow
in the diaphragm.
and those got fatigued.
So when you did your performance,
you got slower because you were already
gassed.
But if you had really strong
intercostals the lower,
so the real open valve wasn't enough
resistance to actually caused those
muscles to warm up.
So that didn't help your performance.
So what we found is my point here
basically is the individualization of
the approach here is really,
really important.
So there's something there for all of
us,
but you're going to have to titrate out.
You might need heavy,
you might need light,
you might need middle and one of those
situations might actually make it worse
for you.
So the,
the individual variability is the
important point there.
How would You figure out which one you
needed a performance test and what kind
of performance sets would use in this
project?
You can do anything.
You can say I'm going to run a mile and
a half and recording my time and put
that thing in your mouth as you're
running or as your.
As your warmup as your warm.
Yeah.
So you sit there and you put it in your
mouth and you do you just.
So you only use it to do drills.
You don'T necessarily use it to actually
work out the vast majority of the time.
That's what I recommend.
You could do it in your workout,
um,
but it would be for different reasons.
So when you do it,
what would you recommend doing?
Like say,
say if I got an o two trainer,
I've put it in like what kind of
workouts am I doing with this thing in
my mouth?
What am I?
Or breathing exercises.
And again,
you're going to hate this,
probably some of your fans getting
irritated by now,
but it depends on the goal of the
workout.
So if the goal of the workout is to get
the best score possible,
right,
then you do probably 30 or 40 breaths
with the optimal resistance feel great.
Okay.
But at the point of the workout is to
actually improve the strength of the
diaphragm and go then you,
then you put yourself in sub optimal
positions.
It's right back to what I said at the
beginning,
adapting or optimizing a different
thing.
So the muscles in between the ribs,
can you actually strengthen those to the
point where.
I mean that's a huge issue with guys
getting injured.
Absolutely.
You can strengthen those with that o two
trainer with.
That's one mechanism that you can do it
a bunch of different ways.
We have done a.
You've had,
you've had wim hof on,
right?
Yeah,
sure.
So I've been working with for couple of
years now,
so doing initial stuff with him and it's
very clear like we,
we can mess with a lot of different
breathing protocols and get you a lot of
immediate and delayed.
sorry brian,
one more time.
Uh,
he had his conversation with jon jones
on wednesday before the fight.
First time that ever met someone,
put them in contact.
Brian put them through some of these
breathing protocols.
As soon as they hung up the phone or as
soon as they are done,
don was like,
hey,
will you fly down here on saturday?
Flew them down that day.
Had I'm in his corner,
walked him all the way down,
was right next to probably you and dana
are when he's doing all the things.
So like this is how impactful some of
these breathing things aren't.
Our women's was great to get us started.
Bosses device was awesome,
the train master work work concepts,
but now brian has really evolved and
developed and said actually there's a
bunch of different ways we can do it and
he has protocols you're going to have to
ask him,
but he is the one that can say like,
do this for this thing to exactly this
way for this thing and you this
adaptation,
you want this effect.
Wow.
He has it all dialed in.
I go to a cryo chamber cryotherapy place
where you put a surgical mask on your
mom's and your whole body's immersed.
It's not just a below the neck.
Oh yeah.
Yeah.
Have you seen those?
And when I use the wim hof breathing
method,
it's almost like somebody made it 50
degrees warmer.
It's ways.
And I just got back from montauk.
I spent three days and jumping a nice
bass the whole time out there.
Uh,
but we actually have multiple protocols.
So that's more akin to what some would
call the breath of fire.
Is this when you're with dennis said.
Yeah,
we were at an event out there with laird
hamilton and and those folks will brian
also,
they layered and gabby and brian
vocabularies and laird hamilton started
a company called xpt that kind of puts a
lot of this lifestyle stuff into
practice and so they put on these live
events.
They also sent me some of their new
super food stuff that they add to the
creamer stuff.
It's really good.
It's amazing.
Yeah,
it's a little espresso based powder plus
super star.
I like it.
It's fantastic.
yeah.
Um,
so I've been working with for a couple
of years,
um,
since they got started,
but we go out there,
we do these things and so we can say,
okay,
we'll get you through the breath of fire
protocol and you'll feel like,
wow,
you get hot and get warmed up.
There's other ways we can do it that'll
bring you back down where you're like,
yeah,
I'm gonna.
Take a nap.
There's euphoria ones where you can get
like,
wow,
I feel like I'm on psychedelics right
now.
I'm super high tropic breathing,
bunch of apnea stuff.
I'm pranayama stuff.
All of these things can have different
outcomes depending on,
on what you're looking for.
So they have.
Brian has got the system developed now
we're like,
it's,
that's what he did was john the first
one he did,
um,
it was like 10:00
at night and he's like,
all right,
let me relax you to kind of bring it
down.
He's like,
oh,
this is amazing.
But then he's like,
actually got to go train right now.
He's like,
can you give me back up?
it's a garden.
Let's go back the other way.
Sort of backup.
So is there any benefit stuff too?
I'm using those breathing techniques
versus an o two trainer or is it
different situations?
Exactly.
Its situation based.
There's things I like.
So you mentioned what boss says of the
opening valve at the end of the o two
trainer and allows you to dump out
carbon dioxide.
Okay.
The training masks for example,
wouldn't.
Right?
So it's not right or wrong,
it's just depending on what you're
looking to do,
because one thing you can train your
body to do is how well do you perform
when you generated a bunch of carbon
dioxide.
So carbon dioxide is what actually makes
you feel like you want to breathe,
right?
It's not lack of oxygen,
Right.
So I can put you in a situation where
you get a bunch of carbon dioxide build
up and if I don't let you dump it,
then you're going to fatigue a lot
faster.
but that's not necessarily a bad thing.
You could learn to then deal with a lot
of fatigue,
deer with it mentally,
psychologically as well as
physiologically there's going to be
adaptations.
So because of the fact that your body
has more carbon dioxide in the system,
you,
your body adapts to process that carbon
dioxide more efficiently.
This would be the assumption like you
have to be scientifically shown.
Oh,
but this is,
you know,
where we were.
This is the thought process.
You can feel this intuitively.
You're like,
wow.
Um,
and it's also a way for us to get a lot
of training volume in,
or sorry,
a lot of cardiovascular training in
because your heart rate goes way up
without actually doing a lot of physical
work.
And so for mma guys,
this is what we're looking for sometimes
because of physical work and their
training camps so high we can't add any
more volume to them is going to beat
them up.
SO now we can get them a cardiovascular
workout in.
That's easy on the joints and ligaments
and the bones.
So the other approach would be dump all
the ceo two or do other things like
nasal breathing only.
So the whole workout you're only allowed
to breathe through your nose.
When you breathe through your nose,
It actually can release nitric oxide,
which is a basal dilator.
So this is why when you,
only,
when you breathe through your nose,
not only,
but especially when you breathe through
your nose,
huh?
Why does your body produce more nitric
oxide when you breathe through your
nose?
I don't know.
That's weird because you would think
that just breathing wim hoff.
I was asking him like,
just anywhere.
Yeah,
he always says like any hole,
I don't care.
Um,
but again,
women's not wrong or anything like that,
but a whimsy style is great,
but there's many styles is the point I
guess.
Like he'S great.
We've done some science stuff together,
but how do you feel about saunas?
Same thing,
amazing benefits their potential,
but there's no free passes and
physiology.
So when you get something,
you're probably coming to the compromise
that something else.
What would the compromise be when you do
a sauna to know we just don't have
enough evidence on this stuff.
We know we focused on the heat shock
proteins.
That's like everyone knows about those
by now.
Um,
the ability to deal with a uncomfort,
fatigue,
like there's a lot of stuff.
The difficult is when you run a
scientific study,
you get one or two or three variables.
You don't get a thousand,
right?
So we focused on the one or two that
you're like,
wow,
this is moving something here.
But I mean,
just like the example we went over with
the cold,
it's like,
wow,
yeah,
it's great for this.
Or actually it's terrible.
And people say no,
they want to make blanket statements
like heats,
good or cold is good or bad.
Well,
as we study it more,
we start to finding out,
well actually it's good for this and
it's good for this and it's bad for that
and that and that and that.
So we'd have to assume someone would be
the same way.
There has to be consequences to it.
It just depends on application.
But there's gotta be some sort of
benefits in terms of recovery.
Right.
So do you think that someone should do
maybe like cryo one day sauna,
the neck?
Should they do them in the same day?
Like so for example,
a fighter in camp,
I generally don't go out of my way to
recommend sauna because they already get
really hot and training.
You're grappling,
especially if they're doing stuff,
they're getting heat shock protein.
I don't want to go to hot yoga in
particular.
There's this study they're doing right
now at harvard apparently,
uh,
somebody was telling me about it the
other day where they're,
uh,
they're concentrating on hot yoga and
the benefits of hot yoga and heat shock
proteins.
Yeah.
I'm sure they're gonna find a lot like
that.
That's pretty.
I mean that ship's sailed a little bit.
Like we're,
we're confident something.
There's a lot of detail to workout,
but something's going on there.
probably something similar to sauna.
So I generally say for people like you
and like me,
I don't go out of my way to do too much
sauna work because of the way I train.
I get really hot and sometimes we'll
train specifically with a little bit
more clothing sometimes and get kind of
like,
well,
instead of sitting in a sauna for 45
minutes,
let me wear a little bit extra clothing
during my training session and get real
hot dr.
But for the average people,
I think it's a fantastic modality
because there may be only working out
once a week or less,
and you gave,
you can get them hot and we can actually
work on those health benefits.
While we're building good quality habits
and we can eventually lead them down the
path to more exercise.
And emmanuel stewart,
he used to run the crump.
Jim,
um,
he used to crank the temperature of the
gym over 100 degrees.
that was his thing,
like he wanted guys to box like in
essentially like a hot yoga room.
Well,
there's a couple of things too that I've
done a lot of that in my life and I used
to hate it.
We used to just fight for the door,
like wait for the round to go over
wrestling,
wrestling practice theory.
So it really has to mma with it all the
time.
And like the problem was it was scary
because the floor is water.
Oh yeah.
And you're like,
I'm not kicking,
like,
you're terrified.
That's not good.
He was awful.
I hated it.
That's real bad for kicking.
Skip those practices.
A logical.
Um,
but so example,
uh,
I don't think that's particularly
needed.
What the exception of one time when pat
comes fought in Brazil,
it was like 110 outside and it was 80
percent humidity or something.
Which fight was a,
uh,
it was,
um,
uh,
yeah,
I remember that.
Was that fight?
It was outdoors,
I think.
No,
it was indoors,
but if everything was open,
oh,
that's what it was.
So super,
super hot.
Now we didn't train for that or
anticipate that,
but you could see if you knew you're
fighting in a venue like that.
I'm like,
what they used to do in bodog and Costa
Rica and like,
oh yeah,
they would fight on the beach dot.
Yeah,
right.
Just horrid outside.
So you could say like,
well,
in that situation,
maybe it's needed,
but you're fighting in vegas or
something indoors and maybe we don't
need it for that.
Right.
But that doesn't mean you couldn't
implement it once or twice.
I wouldn't go on my way to do it though.
right?
So it wouldn't be a daily thing.
No,
because what's gonna happen is you're
going to compromise performance.
A pacing is a real problem.
Bisping's a great example of this to
dennis was a bunch of people.
If you fight an environment like that,
your pace and the amount of output you
can do is going to slow way down in the
gym,
right?
It can be hot,
you're to gas out and then when you go
to fight and your fight and it's
temperature controlled,
you're not used to that pace.
So if you're used to fighting at the
pace that it takes for you to sustain 10
rounds of sparring and the gym at 100,
10 degrees and then we come in and you
and I fight and I'm ready to go with
this.
You're not ready for that pace.
So it's not that you don't physically
have the conditioning,
but you're just like,
oh man,
I'm just not skies and you know,
you don't feel right.
So you have to be careful of training
too far outside of what you're actually
gonna encounter.
Um,
which is,
you know,
some of these guys run into those
problems when they do.
I'm going to spar 10 rounds so that I
can go five easy.
Yeah.
But your pace for your five is way
different than your pastry or 10.
So you have to be careful there a lot of
questions,
man,
physiology,
dude,
that,
that is part of the problem,
right?
That there are so many variables.
There are so many questions that there
is no real definitive protocol to
follow.
No,
it was a bunch of different ones.
The pursuit,
the way I always say it is the truth is
mostly a lack of perspective.
So when you think that you are on some
unbreakable truth,
it's because you haven't looked at it
from a big enough perspective for the
most part.
Right?
Right.
And there's some,
I'll put it this way and I'm in
biological truth.
That's almost always true in physics.
Truth of that's a lot less true.
Like we're pretty sure gravity is real,
like we're pretty sure and we can
mechanically,
water's good for you.
Pretty sure.
Uh,
now quantum mechanic physically,
those get kind of weird.
Right?
But for the most part that is true.
But science in terms of biological or
medical is a lot less true.
I mean how many times we have to see
that,
where it's like,
this is true,
this is true for 50 years.
Oops.
It's not,
is this all fun for you,
do you.
I mean,
it seems like you're very passionate
about it,
but I mean it's,
it also seems like wow,
it can become stressful having so many
variables and possibilities and I don't,
I don't think stress is even close.
It's,
I would say 99 percent fun.
Like it's stress for me in terms of I
don't want.
I like it would break my heart if I gave
someone the wrong advice and it ruined
their career.
Like that would be the stress stress in
terms of being right or like saying that
much some stuff and being proved I don't
care about that at all.
Yeah.
That it's an issue with a lot of
trainers.
Right?
Were they given bad advice and.
Yeah.
You see it play out in a fight.
I mean one of the reasons I.
I used to do a lot of professional
athletes in other sports or because
other ones I gave that almost up
entirely and I gave up.
I've done some actors and things like
that,
but I generally stay away from that.
Even though the money is far,
far higher for me and those things,
but I did it because like these mma
folks,
like I have a real passion for someone
who's going to put all that on the line
and they're going to risk everything and
they're going to go out there and that
is more exciting to me and I'm like,
that's a fun,
a really fun investment in me and it and
it's worth me investing my emotion.
I mean,
when helen won a golden reel,
like I just lost it.
Like emotionally I was like gone for
weeks,
like just exhausted because I invested
so much into that.
I don't want to do that for somebody so
that they can make an extra million on
top of that 30 million.
Like it doesn't motivate me that much.
So I like working with these folks and
so because of that,
like it breaks my heart.
If you're like,
man,
you gave up everything for this kind of
living and the best outcome for you was
that you made 20 instead of 10 k and
then I lost that for you because I gave
you really bad rehydration advice for
something that's a stress for me,
but the rest of the stuff man,
like it's fun.
It's invigorating for me to continue to
be like,
well we,
we answered that,
but now we don't know this oR this.
Like it's continual progress and and by
like I take karl popper stance on this
one in terms of like science is not
about identifying truth.
It's reducing uncertainty.
That's a good way to put it.
That's all it is.
Right?
I wish I could take credit for it.
It's a good way to put it.
So we just,
we get closer and we know more of,
okay,
we know this is not as an but we're
still.
Do you anticipate a day when we do,
like when it comes to bio mechanics are
there are some things that I would be
confident in saying like basically we
know that this is true,
now you need to drink water,
like basically say that that's true.
Uh,
we need to have a lot of it,
like the verY standard stuff.
Then those are things I'm comfortable
saying this is basically true and as we
go on,
we only keep adding to that list.
SO more things get piled on.
Now we know for a.
I had told this story also on my podcast
about the history of strength
conditioning and how it went from the 19
hundreds to where it is now.
And the quick story is,
there was a guy named peter [inaudible]
who was a scientist and he was
extremely,
he was the guy who started the idea that
lifting weights causes you to lose
flexibility and a,
it's bad for your health and,
and all these things,
right?
This is 1950 2:54,
something like that.
And he's a scientist phd and he calls it
a guy.
He gets a guy named bob hoffman is
called in,
do you remember bob hoffman year from
the generation?
You may remember york barbell muscle and
strength,
like the magazine.
You may recognize all this stuff,
but basically there was a show and I
said,
bring in this,
these weightlifters,
because back then weightlifting,
powerlifting,
bodybuilding was all kinda the same
thing,
is it bring them in and let's put on a
demonstration.
And so they bring in all these lifters
and they put on this demonstration in
front of the whole school in front of
dr.
Carpet,
kitchen.
And uh,
everyone's like,
cool.
They're great.
They're strong enough athletic and
everyone knoWs like the showdowns coming
like everyone's there to watch the show,
but everyone is really there to watch,
like the,
just like they are on the internet now.
It's like let's watch this shit show
afterwards.
Right?
So everyone's done and carpet stands up
and he's like,
that's great,
you're strong and you got a lot of
muscle and all that.
But um,
let me ask you a question,
can you scratch your back?
I think I was like,
sure.
You know where at like what,
where,
and he starts scratching both land and
everywhere.
What he wants to do,
what do you want me to do?
Drops into a full splits,
grabs 50 pound dumbbells,
does a standing back flip and at this
point carpets is like,
oh,
like my entire career is that strength
training is bad for you.
It's unhealthy.
You lose flexibility and these dudes the
strongest in the world just showed up.
Not only are they not inflexible,
but they just did a splits there.
Bodybuilders ring world champions.
So he was at a crossroads right there in
his career to say like,
do I admit in front the whole world
about how wrong my entire research line
was?
Or do I find some excuse?
Well you that.
Well,
he does the,
the honorable thing and goes,
I'm sorry I'm wrong.
And change his entire career research
going on to actually studying three
training and of course shows that
doesn't do any of these things.
We do.
So this is the nature of science is
we're mostly wrong until we actually
study and then we get less than,
less than this wrong.
So that's really where we're at with
with everything.
That's an easy example.
But if you tell somebody 50 years ago,
flexibility or strength training makes
you inflexible.
Still like,
well,
I don't know how they look at this
study.
Look at this study.
They used to be an issue with boxing,
right?
They used to always say boxers should
never strength trained till vendor
holyfield came along with mackie.
She'll stone right and won the title as
a heavier yesterday.
Yeah,
the airport.
He looks great.
Oh man.
It's crazy huge.
He was pulling like walking out of the
bathroom by himself and he had like a
cell phone up to his ear.
Like I'm on the phone,
but I think his cellphone was dead,
but he just didn't want anybody to talk
to them,
which I don't blame him.
No,
he looked fantastic.
I just signed a buddy of mine to his.
He's doing,
do you know he's a,
he's like coach or managing fighters now
or something?
Yeah,
hopefully not financially.
I Don't know.
Event.
Just like buy the biggest house that
exists.
Yeah.
Had that fucking stupendous mansion in
atlanta who was like a hundred and 50
rooms or something like that.
Did you Put that much money in front of
people in sport like that?
Especially when you're balling,
when you and other people were bawling
and trying to ball harder,
got to do what you gotta do.
I don't think mma is ever caught up to
that in terms of financially.
Yeah,
iT's getting close with conor mcgregor,
but honestly his biggest windfall right
now as a boxing match.
So you know,
the thing about a vendor that's weird is
that he never got out of shape.
He looked fantastic.
Yeah.
He's still fit.
He's got to be sneaky.
Plus he's one of the rare guys and I
think he had a fight as recently as a
year ago.
No,
no.
Yeah,
yeah.
Oh wow.
Find out when a vendor holyfield's last
fight was.
I really want to say he had a fight like
a year ago.
Oh,
that's terrifying.
Yeah,
but he's okay.
It's weird.
It's not like,
whoa,
what's this dude?
She just retired or just got smashed
really bad.
Getting bernard.
THat gets amazing.
Yeah.
That was a freak incident,
man.
That's one of the things about like,
why don't they have pads around the ring
case guys fall through the ropes.
Like I can't imagine that they didn't.
They have seen that happen before.
Guys are getting fucked up through that
before.
That's all fight style,
right?
Yeah.
But that was lIke a fake charity boxing
match.
What does it say though in terms of,
uh,
when his last fight,
that's what popped up when I hit last
fight.
Yeah.
But that's not real.
I think you're lying.
I think,
you know,
just pull up his,
uh,
his record wikipedia record.
I'm sure there's a wikipedia on evander
holyfield.
Brian know nielsen a 2011.
Oh,
okay.
So six years ago.
Yeah,
that's pretty recently in consideration.
Oh,
you know what it was,
I believe he was planning a comeback a
few years ago and he was having a really
hard time getting licensed.
oh,
I think that's what it was.
I would still say if you had asked me,
I would've said 12 years ago.
Like I would've guessed way longer than
that.
Well,
he,
how old is he now?
Sixty one and 62.
Okay.
Oh,
okay.
So 5:55.
Yeah.
So We essentially had his last fight
when he was like,
what?
Forty eight,
49.
Something like that.
Yeah,
it makes sense.
That's a stylish.
Well,
I dunno,
I don't really remember his that much.
He didn't take a lot of stuff.
Did he take a lot of shots?
Oh,
hell yeah.
Bruiser.
Yeah.
I mean he took some.
He just had a tremendous chin.
He just did an unbelievably tough guy
and unbelievably fit.
You know,
that was the thing about holy failed was
that unbelievably fit.
Unbelievably game.
Like when he beaT Mike Tyson,
the first fight,
like I remember it was,
you know Kevin James.
Kevin was actually over my house.
We were watching it together.
Really?
We're jumping around screaming like a
bunch of school girls because it was
insane because nobody saw that comment.
You know what I'm saying?
Right.
Yeah.
That was amazing.
He had a career though.
Oh,
he certainly did.
Yeah.
Hope you still got it together upstairs.
Like that's just a tough one.
Certainly is.
Yeah.
That.
It's got to be weird.
I wonder what,
do you ever have that conversation with
a fighter?
I do.
It's not my role,
so I don't bring it up at all,
but if they asked me on like a friendly
advice thing,
um,
and look at will be very careful with
names here.
Um,
but I generally tell them all tO retire,
like regardless,
like my approach is no,
this is a,
this is the,
the risk is not worth the power in the
ufc.
It's just not like there is the
occasional connor,
but this is,
this is the anomaly that proves the rule
actually.
So my advice to all of them is if it's
not a good investment,
it is not worth the risk because even if
you get the wind bonus and the fight of
the night one fight like that is
potentially years.
And how much income could You make in
those 10 years of working?
Probably more than that hundred k.
Well in terms of income for sure,
but for a lot of them it's not really
what they're doing or not doing it for
glory.
Right.
So I mean that's.
but I'm taking it from a logical
perspective.
I'm not telling them what to do.
I'm saying though,
like me as your friend,
I would love for you to never fight
because it was great,
but having said that you do that,
so let me help you as much as I can to
get there,
but I mean you can kind of tell too,
like if you're,
if,
if you just don't,
if you're not in that x factor,
charisma wise and stuff,
you're never going to make that real.
Like life changing money.
We're just talking about money though.
In terms of damage,
do you notice in terms of physical
performance when you're seeing an
athlete move around?
I haven't gotten to the.
I haven'T gotten anybody like that.
Or have you had someone come to you and
say,
hey,
I'm thinking about,
you know,
when I get out,
I'm not exactly sure when.
What do you think?
Yeah,
I mean I would,
I would look at them from the
performance side of it.
I wouldn't look at brain damage and all
I would say,
well here are your numbers in the room
stack up to other folks we've had in
this room and you're far below their
performance wise.
I would say you might have a performance
problem in terms of you might not be
talented enough physically to compete.
Like I'm not gonna make a comment about
your other reasons to retire,
but if yeah,
if I tested you across the board and you
were terrible at everything,
then I might be like,
well,
physically from my perspective,
I don't know if you have what it takes
anymore.
Do you see a deterioration in physical
skills from like punishment?
I don't know if I could really say that,
but that's just because I don't like.
I don't have enough exposure to enough
of those folks to make a qualified
comment on that over long periods of
time.
Yeah.
I would need dozens and dozens of guys
over years to really fairly.
What's the longest you've ever worked
with a guy?
A five,
six years?
Probably.
Yeah,
probably six years.
That's a lot of time.
It is.
And it's not like,
uh,
like,
some of them is not every single,
I'm not talking to him every day and
sometimes it's like once a camp,
uh,
generally what my goal is is to teach
them how to think as much through this
stuff as they can.
And so ideally they don't need me after
more than a couple of camps than the few
chickens want to come to the lab,
get this test that I got a hunch about
this or we did this type of training for
six weeks.
We think we are addressing this problem.
Can we come to get it tested to see if
it actually got better and no problem.
But the other stuff I do is,
like I said,
it's so much usually helping them calm
down through all the nonsense that I can
give them a settling presence in terms
of you,
this is not something you should worry
about or get to here.
So,
um,
buT yeah,
multiple five,
six years and we've got data.
We've got biopsy data off them from over
the years,
which has been very,
very interesting.
Actually.
That was one of the first reasons I
wanted to get into the sport because I'm
like,
I want to biopsy these dudes.
Yeah,
that's got to be really as a scientist,
got to be really an interesting
opportunity to.
Yeah.
We had,
um,
we had one fighter.
It was pretty crazy because he's a,
he was a wrestler and a very,
very um,
he was,
he went through attrition,
like that's his style.
He's not like a knockout artist and like
that.
And he was almost 70,
75 percent fast twitch,
which is.
Yeah.
And then we also look this other thing.
So one of the things that we measured
our lab is called mild nuclear domain.
So the nucleus is what holds the dna and
it tells the cell to grow,
shrink,
die repair.
Well,
like human biology or human muscle is
really unique.
It's one of the only cells in all of
biology that is multinucleated.
So that means it's got not only more
than one,
but it's got thousands of nuclei per
cell.
The obvious advantages that allows us a
lot more plasticity so we can recover
and repair and adapt and adjust really,
really quickly,
which is why we see people's fiber type
change in a matter of weeks.
A paper that came out last year showing
actually high fat,
high sugar diet can change five
prototype.
We've seen carbon dioxide
concentrations,
alter fiber type con,
uh,
things like that.
So the nucleus is really interesting
because the more nuclei you have,
the faster you recover.
It's also what determines how big a
muscle will grow.
Um,
you've heard of like muscle memory.
So that's me.
This is what's doing muscle memory.
That makes sense.
I always wondered if that was real,
uh,
well working right now through it.
Um,
a lot of people are,
but the old theory would be satellite
cell would come in,
it would turn into a nuclei and the cell
will only grow as big as the amount of
nuclei that are around it or that inside
of it.
Right?
And so what that basically means is,
uh,
there's a certain domain or a certain
size that each nucleus will control and
it won't exceed that size because it
loses control.
So if,
if you,
all three of us,
you know,
we're all the nuclei and this whole room
was one cell.
If we wanted to expand the wall we would
have to bring in another nucleus because
you'd be like,
dude,
like it's too much area to control.
So when you go through about a training
a year or something of heavy lifting and
we add those satellite cells that turned
into my own nuclei and we expand the
size.
Well we used to think like if we stopped
training in this and the room gets
smaller,
we used to think that are like time to
kick me out of the room.
He's gone but now will look like
happening.
Is he staying around?
So then when I go to retrain,
I've got more of those nuclei right
there.
And so it's easy.
It's easier.
So I got excited,
hit the mic.
It's easier for me to expand my size
because the nuclear there.
Oh,
that makes sense.
Okay,
so there's an actual scientific reason
for muscle memory.
Yeah,
and you can increase the amount of
nuclear just by increasing the size of
the muscle and that makes it easier to
go back to that if you lose some muscle.
Well,
right.
The demo nuclei would allow for the
muscles get bigger.
Yeah,
so a little bit in reverse,
but basically the same thing.
Dude,
this was really fascinating.
Anything else to add before we get out
of here?
I'm the book man.
I got a book out on all this stuff
called on plugged,
evolving from technology to upgrade your
fitness performance and consciousness
isn't on amazon,
although all that stuff.
Is there an audio book available?
There is,
but I'm telling you.
No,
sorry.
There's a kindle that I would highly
recommend.
You don't get it because the kindle.
No,
you mean that's the digital version,
right?
Why get the hard copy?
Why?
Because the book is really a guide for
how to use some of these training
technologies in your training and how it
can ruin your training and how it can
help your training.
So a part of that is the importance of
doing a couple of things,
getting back to nature and how that,
the physiology behind how that helps as
well as this concept of choosing
suffering and choosing discomfort and
how that's physiologically important for
you.
So a part of the book is built in a way
where the photos,
the layout,
the quality of the paper is all part of
the reading experience.
They don't have that in.
I'm like kindle with the photographs
now.
It's not even close to this.
It's,
you know,
it's all black and white.
The texture of the paper is different.
Have one of those kindle hds,
the ones that are digital and maybe
maybe.
Yeah,
maybe that would be good.
But.
So what you're saying though,
but you recommend the proper.
Yeah,
I mean I don't change.
I don't really care.
Like for the experience of it,
it's still cheap.
It's not expensive.
What's the physiological benefit of
getting back to nature?
Oh,
we have so much.
Yeah,
it's pretty incredible in terms of
everything from visualization or.
Sorry,
eyesight.
Did you listen to that amazing podcast?
Eyesight?
Yeah.
Radiolab did one on the color blue.
I didn't hear that one,
which was,
what's it called?
This is a teaser and I could tell you
the whole story.
What's it called?
The,
the,
I don't know the episode.
Find it if you google the radio lab
episode on the color blue.
Okay.
Basically we as humans didn't really
recognize the color blue until the
bible.
What?
Yeah.
So we had the cones and the like,
the physiology didn't change but we
didn't have a word for the color blue
until the bible came along.
So if you look at any past there prior
to that.
Yeah,
that's probably why isn't the sky blue
on radio?
Radiolab?
Yep.
Exactly.
So what,
uh,
what they've identified is we didn't
have a separate color for several word
for the color blue because we didn't
differentiate blue shade,
so it wasn't important for the world
because blue doesn't happen very
frequently.
And in biology in nature it wasn't until
we had textiles and we started printing
and making cloth and paper and stuff
like that,
that we had all these different dyes and
shade the blue.
So then we developed different shades of
blue in different colors,
so because of that we started perceiving
and focusing on different shades of
blue.
So now the average person that comes in
the room and be able to identify all
these different blues or prior to this,
we didn't care about it,
we didn't focus on it.
So we all just saw that as one color
blue.
So things like that are important.
So what are we paying attention to?
What are we being conscious of?
What are we perceiving?
What are we focusing on?
Has a direct influence on our
physiology.
It's very adaptable to those things.
So how does that make going to nature?
So if we think about it from this way,
what's happening in the exposure when
we're in this artificial environment
versus being in the external environment
like nature.
So what are we not being exposed to now
that we could be exposed to out in
nature?
The third part of the book is the
consciousness aspect,
which is we talked to a lot of people.
Um,
tim ferriss wrote a section or a little
interview thing for it.
Steven kotler did one as well and they
talk about the things like getting into
flow state and the stress relief of it
and all the other psychological benefits
that we have from detaching a little bit
from our constant tech exposure.
Um,
dopamine as another great example,
right?
So if we look at the dopamine rush that
we get from the constant exposure,
not from the actual tech,
but from things like,
oh,
I want to look at my likes,
I want to continue to look at this.
That's completely different than when we
didn't we get out in nature and expose
ourself to physiological elements
similar to the cold and the hot and
thirsty,
the Hungary.
I mean you've been out in the woods and
stuff before,
like you know what it feels like going a
full day without food or being extremely
cold for a few days and then getting
back and then you like the euphoria,
like the sensations,
like you can't really.
Well you can,
but it's really beneficial to have
herself exposed to that.
Um,
and,
and it's a problem now,
but really the book is about like,
wait 20 years.
And think about the problem that's going
to be in 20 years when this technology
thing only gets more advanced and it
takes more portion of our life.
Alright dude,
one more time.
What's the name of the book?
Unplugged.
Evolve from technology to upgrade your
fitness,
performance and consciousness.
Beautiful.
Thanks man.
I really enjoyed it.
That's great conversation.
Really appreciate it.
Andy calvin,
ladies and gentlemen,
ceo.
That was great.