Four,
three,
two,
one.
Boom.
The Lost Art of knifemaking.
It's still alive.
How are you man?
I'm doing good man.
I coming down here.
I appreciate it.
Huge.
I really appreciate you having me down.
Hey listen man,
you've made two awesome.
Well for awesome.
Nice for me.
But this one is one I use all the time
that uh,
I've posted on instagram.
The people freak out as we were talking
about before the podcast said it
actually has meteor in it.
Yeah.
Media,
right?
What's meteor is a big one.
Media writes a little one.
Is that the idea?
Do you know?
I guess
she had the knife maker
so I didn't actually make,
so I made the knife,
I forged the knife.
But the steel is,
is a very special kind of steel that
very few people can actually
manufacturer on a small scale in the
world.
And that was made by my shop made
Petersburg.
And so,
um,
the meteorite is kind of a,
a small element in the whole matrix
because most media,
right is all nickel or all iron or
something like that.
And this one particularly is a lot of
nickel and some cobalt.
And if you're going to make it an actual
usable steel out of it,
you can't really use a whole lot of it
in the overall mixture.
Hmm.
So is there any media rights that are
made at all iron?
Yeah,
definitely.
You just have to find them.
You just got to find the ones.
Yeah.
And they're their impact sites all over
the world.
Like they're hitting the world all the
time.
How does it,
where is it?
Can you just take them like when they
land,
is it yours?
If you find it,
you don't have to report it to NASA or
anything,
right?
No.
Hey Bro,
found some space junk.
Most of them are,
are so small that they,
by the time they hit the actual earth
surface,
they've completely disintegrated or
burned up.
So it's the really massive ones.
And this was part of a impact,
I think in South America.
Oh Wow.
I can't remember where he's like,
it's just crazy to think that this is a
piece of space in there.
Fuck.
Yandian this dope pattern.
Um,
I'm really into crafts from Shit,
man.
I always have been.
I love handmade pool cues and this desk,
which is a handmade desk and I feel like
it's one of the things that are really
appreciate in this modern digital world.
And I also feel like unfortunately it
may be one of the things that's slipping
away.
It definitely is slipping away.
I think with,
um,
you know,
with technology,
technology has been great for us and a
lot of different ways.
Like we couldn't be fucking talking into
a piece of metal
recorded on the computer,
going through a wire flying through the
air.
Like it
does a lot of great things.
But in doing all those great things,
it actually has taken us away from
really creating and working with our
hands.
And so like,
you know,
even this whole like a farm to table
movement where people even growing their
vegetables.
Yeah,
you've got your own chickens.
They're,
they're laying eggs for you.
Like knowing where this stuff is coming
from,
handling,
like firsthand contact with that.
Um,
just having that relationship in general
with it brings so much more value to the
overall experience of eating those eggs
are using that knife or sitting at this
fucking table right here
and it seems like a fairly recent
movement in that direction.
Right?
Like it feels like things got so digital
that people are like,
whoa,
Whoa,
whoa.
What the facebook and the fucking
instagram I want to I,
you know,
I want a wood table,
I want to saw this.
I'm dating myself.
Yeah.
Your hands on it.
They,
I don't want it to meet pastor rick.
Yeah.
I want real stuff.
And there's something about handmade
things,
whether it's a handmade pair of boots
are handmade bag like this.
Like there's something about things that
are made by hand that people get at like
a deep appreciation of,
for sure.
For sure.
Well,
and I think it,
I think it also kind of goes back to,
like I was saying like as technology has
advanced,
we've kind of grown away from these
kinds of what's considered like blue
collar work and craftsmanship kind of
work.
But I think people really are driven by
a sense of achievement.
And when you're doing data entry that
literally millions of people fucking
monkeys can be trained to do,
not to like diminish anything that
anybody's doing but literally like it.
To be able to go into a craft and to and
had the hands on experience is very,
very,
very different.
And that sense of achievement.
Even when somebody comes out of
something and maybe I taught a class on
how to make a knife and it looks like a
fucking Turd,
they're gonna think it looks like the
most beautiful fucking knife they've
ever seen in their life because their
hands and their creativity,
they've touched their energy,
their,
their sweat and pop.
Probably some of their blood is put into
creating that thing and that brings that
much more valuable.
Yeah,
I think that's an issue with people
today that have jobs that they don't
feel are very fulfilling is that there's
no real thing that they're creating at
the end.
Whereas like if you make a table at the
end when you were putting the final
sanding on the final,
you know,
a layer of,
of a stain and you're looking at it
like,
I fucking made this.
Like this is a real thing that I can
touch that I made.
Just like human beings in our current
form,
we have a,
there's a deep connection to making
things physical.
Things end up settling and,
and,
uh,
an appreciation for things that people
have made.
Whether it's a,
a rifle that somebody made or a night
for a,
you know,
a hammer that's that someone's made.
There's something about that that we
just have a real appreciation for.
If you can buy us a knife from the store
that's made in a show,
I mean,
it will work,
you know,
some knife that's made some mass
manufacturing process.
It'll work and it's fine.
I mean,
you'll,
you'll appreciate it,
but you won't appreciate it.
Like,
I appreciate this thing.
Like every time I take this out and I'm
like super careful with it and you know,
and then the handle the handle's made
out of this is Moose antler and elk
right there,
right at the
top and the Moose of the bottom.
So,
and I saw your conversation or listen to
your conversation with Guy Ritchie and
you brought up that there was,
I think actually Jamie pulled it up and
he was like bogged oak and Guy Richie
was like boggo what bog or their
American bugs there.
I don't know if there are any American
box.
It was from a a bog in Russia and it was
carbon dated to 5,400 years old.
Jeez.
So essentially it's been sunken and Abog
and just other knife that you made for
me that has a handle it.
That's how did,
how's wanting to get ahold of Boggo?
So people are raising logs.
Like there actually was a show,
I think it was on discovery channel or
history where people were,
their job was raising logs out of the
ball,
the swamps down in Louisiana and the
south and using,
making use of that wood for tape of
projects and craft projects like this.
So that,
but that's happening all over the world.
And some of that stuff are these ancient
logs that you know,
it's the right conditions where the log,
the tree falls over.
It just sits there and steeps and that's
a big thing for the pool cue shafts,
Lakewood chaffs they like to take these
logs out of the bottom like Lake
Michigan or something,
right.
And then they dry it all out and then
they make shafts out of it.
And there's something about it being in
the bottom of the water for so long.
It does something to the,
to the way they feel.
Right.
What do you got there,
Jamie?
That's ancient bog would the artisan
dice.
Oh,
some dungeons and dragons nerd shit
right there.
Sonny super polished up though.
It looks cool.
Or those dungeons and dragon nerds.
Dinosaurs or dice all decided,
yeah,
sides on that.
Now what would,
that was only for a game,
right?
You wouldn't play tice dice.
Yeah.
They use it for all kinds of different,
they're actually like value holders for
the most part.
Value Holders.
What do you mean?
So like 16.
So the countdown with the Dyson,
so they have an actual place sitting
there that says 16,
15,
20,
whatever.
Oh,
you understand dungeons and dragons.
You might be a Dork sometimes I'm going
to go with a brother and my,
my brother in law is a magic,
the gathering.
Oh,
that and per dork.
That's where people that get kicked out
of the dungeons and dragons.
It's,
it's,
it's just a different iteration of chest
really.
I mean it's just,
it's all strategy is definitely not
that.
What is this?
Oh,
that's reusable handle,
you know,
all bearing made that kids in Montana.
Really good guy.
He's a nice kid.
I met him a couple of years ago and uh,
in Eugene actually they do a knife show
there.
Every image that you just showed Jamie,
that's bogged oak that some other like
big chunks of it that they pulled out.
Wow.
Interesting.
So there must be a community of view
people,
these,
these knifemaking people.
Yeah.
There,
there are quite a few people who have
started getting into the knife making
um,
the knife making,
the world,
the moral of the knife making a really
there the resurgence of kind of
handcrafted hand forge knives kind of
started back in the um,
and it was,
it stemmed off from um,
I think it was a custom knife making
association or uh,
yeah,
cuffed custom knife makers association
and then it stemmed off to the ABS,
which is the American bladesmith
society.
And that was all about the forge blade
and kind of the mission to retain that
knowledge and that history and in the
skills that go into actually taking a
piece of metal and forging a blade out
of it,
like you were blades,
they were forged to shape.
They were a one pr approach is to just
take a bar steel trace out a line,
cut that out.
Whereas talking about it's totally valid
way of doing it.
Um,
forging the forging aspect.
Uh,
especially if somebody doesn't actually
know what they're doing,
they're just like heating up a piece of
steel.
They don't know how fucking hot it is
getting.
They don't know how when to stop hitting
it.
They may be hitting it too cold,
they may be overheating it and hidden it
and while it's way too hot,
they could really actually do
detrimental damage to the material and
turn out a piece of shit.
Um,
so the forge aspect really just brings
kind of an aesthetic and it kind of a
depth of story to help bring kind of a
more to that product.
Well,
it's another level,
right?
Yeah.
It's just another layer of it.
It's not just hand crafting something
from,
uh,
you know,
just a piece of metal that you bought
and you put all the pieces together and
Polish it down,
sanded it.
When did you get into this?
So I,
it's a kind of a funny story.
So I got into this back in 2008 is when
I met Bob Kramer.
At the time I was working in a
restaurant,
uh,
actually in my hometown of Olympia.
Um,
and I was working at a restaurant.
I was moonlighting as an assistant salsa
dancing instructor and doing like,
uh,
like community performances and shit
like that.
And,
uh,
I was 24 and I didn't know what the Hell
I was doing with myself and I didn't
really have much of a direction in my
life.
I was terrible at school.
Um,
you know,
I had maybe 40 credits towards,
towards an Ame,
but I don't even have him like an actual
certification or degree or have any kind
of,
so anyways,
I was,
I was sharing this with my dance partner
and she had just started working for
this guy who was a knife maker and she's
like,
Oh,
you should meet him.
He's really interesting.
Uh,
you know,
you kind of feel like you're lost.
He's been all over the world.
He's even like,
he was even a clown at one point.
Kramer.
Yeah,
he used to be a clown.
He was a clown I think for a year for
ringling Barnum and Bailey.
Um,
and if,
from what I understand,
it was a great experience and he loved
it.
And uh,
but anyways,
she's like,
you know,
I think you guys would hit it off.
I think,
you know,
maybe he could help bestow some wisdom
as to where you're at and where he was
at and maybe what kind of choices or
options you have ahead of you.
And so I met up with him,
uh,
at the brewpub or that I was actually
working at and got some beers because a
fish and chips sit and bullshitting and
it ended up turning into an a job
opportunity.
And neither of us really went into it
knowing that that's the direction it was
going to go.
But,
uh,
he was anticipating,
he had an article coming out in the New
Yorker like in a month and that was
going to really like blow his shit up.
And he had had a couple big articles
like in Savour magazine and he was
featured in Cook's illustrated at one
point and each time,
like,
there's a huge influx.
And so I think in part of anticipation
for that,
he's like,
look,
you seem like a nice guy.
You don't really seem to have a
direction.
Maybe we could work something out.
I can't make any promises to you that I
have full time work for you.
Um,
so he just took you on as an apprentice,
essentially
video with him,
Anthony Bordain.
That's how I found out about him.
He was making a knife with meteors,
right.
Meet with a piece of media right in it
as well.
Same kind of thing.
And uh,
I remember thinking like,
wow,
crazy is this,
this guys hammering this thing together
and put into that.
That was like one of the ways that I got
interested in custom knife making sure
it might.
I'd always had knives,
you know,
like pocket knives and I always kind of
thought they were cool and enjoyed them.
But until I watched that video I didn't
realize that there was a lot of people
out there.
There it is.
Yup.
Him and Anthony,
I didn't realize there was a lot of
people that are out there doing this
from scratch.
And then,
you know,
then I was like,
oh,
I gotta get a knife.
And then,
then I saw your page on instagram and I
remember thinking,
Wow,
this guy does some wild shit.
And I don't remember how you and I got
to chatting.
I don't remember.
I just remember seeing your stuff on
instinct.
You reached out to me on email and I was
like the Joe Rogan and I was like that
kid.
Was it an email?
Was it a instagram message?
Oh actually I'm not sure.
I think it was the email.
Email.
Either way from your website.
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
Oh you use had seen my email and one of
the previous conversation somewhere,
but I was like,
this can't be like the Joe Rogan.
And then as the conversation continued
on and I was like,
cause he also your picture for the
emails,
like this goofy picture of you doing
like Kissy face or something like that
was fucking hilarious.
And I was like me
and I was like,
Holy Shit,
I think this actually might be Joe
Rogan.
This is crazy.
Um,
and but it's doing this craft and doing
this work.
And,
and finding and connecting with people
who have an appreciation for the actual,
like the actual work that goes into it
and appreciating that value,
uh,
has been,
you know,
I like even five years ago when I first
started under my own brand,
there's no way it would've thought I'd
be sitting here hanging out with you
guys.
It was kind of a been a crazy ride for
me.
It's crazy,
right?
Me
Too man.
All of it is life's crazy.
I believe that.
But like I said,
I've always had a deep appreciation for
artisans.
You know,
for art.
What I think this,
I think your knife making his art,
I mean I really do like at this as
Jamie's pulled up an image from your
website that shows this incredible blade
design.
Now this is what I've always wanted to
know.
Like is that Damascus steels that what
that is?
That is Damascus in and it's just a
quick note.
This is actually a post that I did to
celebrate another maker.
His name's Julian.
You can actually kind of see it there on
the right margin.
Now,
the,
he's a South American kid,
the blade,
the blades that you made,
that you have here today that you had,
that you're bringing with you for an
auction,
those,
the patterns on those things are fucking
insane.
How do you do that?
Like how do you make these,
cause it's not just steel for people
that are just listening to this.
Like that one is a great example,
right?
I would really love for people who are
just listening to just please go a
spout,
go spread out.
Go back to the,
uh,
page Jamie.
So I could see the headline string.
It's stuck.
What do you mean you can't shrink?
It got zoomed in and zoom out.
What happened?
I did it with the touch pad.
What did you oh,
the touch pad.
These God damn,
we've got an old ass laptop there.
Um,
m a u m a s fire arts
and m a.
Fire Arts,
my Massey fire arts.
They'll get stuck again.
M a o m.
I fire arts.
Uh,
if you go there,
that's his page.
You'll be able to check it out and order
books are closed.
Yeah.
Bad quarter.
I,
I'm a,
I met three years right now and I just
kind of like,
I had to shut it down because it's kind
of an overwhelming point.
Yeah.
Like it's a good problem,
but it's overwhelming because it's a
fuck,
I can imagine.
Yeah.
And balancing,
doing the work with now the,
you know,
like the marketing and branding,
maintaining relevance through social
media and taking the time to create
content on top of all of that.
It,
I mean,
especially when you're first starting to
do it,
the content part side of it,
it fucking time,
time consuming.
Crazy like long waiting lists,
man.
Three years.
Yeah.
And realistic.
My hair,
it's actually in the,
at least in the knife making world,
it's not uncommon for people to actually
wait longer than that.
This is the same thing with the pool cue
world.
Right.
This is really the exact same thing.
A lot of these,
uh,
famous pool cue manufacturers like
southwest or sugar tree and then they
have 10 year waiting lists and it's just
because they do it right.
It takes a long time.
Everything's done by hand.
They're highly sought after.
And because of that,
like you could buy a pool cue from a,
you know,
a company that makes them through,
computerized process and they're fine.
They play really good.
Just like a knife that you'd buy from a
store that's made by a machine and saw
all done mass manufacturing,
it'll cut your meat.
It works great.
Yeah,
it gets the job done,
but it doesn't feel the same thing.
It doesn't feel,
it's crazy.
Like you can feel the difference between
a handmade thing and a machine made
thing.
It's,
it's bizarre.
It trips me out every time.
Well,
there's a little something that people
leave and things that they make.
I mean,
there really is.
I,
I think it exists in everything that
people make,
whether it's clothing or jewelry or
furniture or anything.
Let me just think there's a little
something that people leave when they
in,
in a thing that they make.
Okay.
What do there's something that you talk
about sometimes about how animals
inherit,
like,
uh,
passed down through genes.
Like,
watch out for this plant and watch out
for these predators and shit like that.
Like the passing something on like that
kind of in a way like where I'm toiling
over something like that for,
you know,
40 dedicated,
solid fucking hours.
Right.
Making sure it's as perfect as I
possibly can make that thing at this
point in my life with the skills I got.
And I think
there's something to that.
I mean,
even if it's just a thought,
even if you just know when you touch it,
like if I touch this knife,
I know that you made this,
you know,
when I'm,
when I'm cutting something with this and
I'm cooking,
I know that you made this.
So maybe it's just,
even if it's only in my head,
it's still,
it just feels different,
you know?
And I,
I,
I don't know.
I mean there's,
there's rupert sheldrake who's a,
I don't know what exactly kind of
scientist he is,
but he has this bizarre theory and he's
a really interesting guy to talk to.
So I would never discount it.
He thinks that everything has memory.
He thinks he just,
you just can't access that memory.
But he thinks there's things that have
memories and he thinks that our idea
that memory is something that only
animals and humans possess is,
is just,
it's probably not true.
And that,
that's probably one of the reasons why
people don't want to buy a house where
someone was murdered.
You know what I mean?
Like the idea is that a haunted house,
even if it's not really a ghost,
like maybe that home has memories,
you know,
maybe like my dad went to Gettysburg and
uh,
he's not woo woo at all.
He's like as fucking straight laced
across the board.
No bullshit as it gets.
And he said,
man,
you could feel sadness.
There.
He goes.
He's just think of how many thousands of
people died at Gettysburg.
And he said,
when you were there,
it's just,
it feels sad.
Like you feel death.
Yeah.
I don't know if that's real or if it's
maybe the knowledge that you have that
there was a war there.
I mean,
I don't know.
I used to do the thing where I would
walk through cemeteries.
I'm just interested like looking at
people's names and like when,
when did they live and what did people
have to say about them or what,
you know,
what's left behind and just walking
through cemeteries.
Like sometimes I would even do it on
Halloween attraction,
my answer.
And it definitely feels weird in there.
I used to run through some guitars.
I used to run through them because I
would,
uh,
I would want to be reminded that life is
short.
Get something done,
make something happen that all these
people that aren't here anymore.
But the thing about cemeteries,
it's like 30 dead when they get in
there.
Right?
I think like the memory thing is like,
you know,
if you're on a boat and somebody gets
murdered on that boat and you're in the
boat and you're like fucking freaking
out,
like,
hey man,
there's something about like,
things like if you had a thing,
if you had a wallet that Mike Tyson
owned,
you know what I mean?
You'd hold it.
You're like,
damn,
you know,
there's something to it.
Morphic resonance.
Okay.
That's Rupert sheldrake's theory,
uh,
to theory developed by Rupert Sheldrake,
British biologist,
a paranormal influenced by which a
pattern of events or behavior can
facilitate subsequent occurrences of
similar patents.
Oh,
that's right.
That is,
um,
that is not about it.
Memory,
that is,
that was his other theories referred to
in a lot of the other ways about memory
is inherent in nature and yeah.
Yeah,
I think that's part of it.
Like I think what I was talking about as
part of his theory of morphic residence,
but morphic residence,
I think he's,
he,
yeah,
he's here.
It says that,
hold on,
scroll back,
scroll down.
So the process whereby self organizing
systems inherent a memory from previous
similar systems.
So when he was talking about with
morphic residence was um,
how mice if they learn,
um,
like say if you have a pattern and
there's like cheese at the end of this
pattern and then they go through a maze,
if one mouse figures out that pattern,
other mouse can figure it out quicker
and there's something somehow or
another,
they learn from each other.
And when chimpanzees were observed using
tools,
other chimpanzees on the other side of
the world started mimicking that
behavior without any interaction with
those chimpanzees at all.
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
Very strange.
That's like fucking butterfly effects
shelter more intense than butterfly
effect because it implies that there's
some sort of collective information pool
that they're sharing,
um,
through the ether that there's some,
something that they are sharing through
some unknown method has crazy.
Yeah.
Well it's been a pr,
it's,
it's actually been shown that there is
some sort of a,
there,
there's something to this and there's a
lot of criticism of it.
So if you're one of those people right
now that's like a strict materialist and
you're screaming out,
I get it.
If someone who's a real rationalist who
just wants only science,
provable.
The thing is,
it is kind of provable because there's,
there is,
there has been some tasks and there's
fierce opposition to this,
which is anything that has like some woo
attached to it,
it's going to have some fierce
opposition.
But Rupert was a really fascinating guy
and he's also a rare scientists.
That's he,
he,
he was,
he was Christian.
Is that what it was?
He's really into,
he has a certain level of Christianity
that he accepts and adopts cause he
feels like it's beneficial to him.
Very interesting guy.
Yeah,
that's,
yeah.
I did a podcast,
you know,
a few years back.
Yeah.
He's a trip him and um,
uh,
there was a mathematician and Terence
Mckenna,
who was the other gentlemen,
they were the,
it was the trial logs.
They had these fantastic recordings.
It was sheldrake Mckenna and one other
guy was also brilliant and they would go
back and forth.
They had these,
I'm Ralph Abraham,
Abraham Abrams or Abraham,
Abraham,
Abraham.
And they,
um,
they did these series of talks and a,
this is one of the things that came up,
like Mckenna was the most woowoo.
Ralph Abraham was the least woo woo.
And sheldrick was kind of in the middle,
right?
Yeah.
Interesting stuff.
If you've ever been around.
Yeah.
The trial logs.
There it is.
There.
The recordings is still available
somewhere,
I think.
Um,
our friend,
a psychedelic salon,
I think Lorenzo has them.
Are they available on line?
Oh,
there you go.
Bam.
Sound Fun.
Yeah,
they're fucking cool man.
Actually play it.
I don't know why you can't play it.
It was there.
I got to take him down now that yeah,
that is the case.
Looks I got removed.
Hmm.
Yeah.
Someone's probably selling it.
It's really cool though.
You know,
you get to see these guys in the 1990s
pre-internet,
was it pre internet might not have been.
It might be like 98 I think Mckenna died
around 2000 ish.
He died posts to hold a site.
Say he died like 2003 or something.
When did he die?
Why am I asking this?
This is all about memory and things as
we went on the fucking deep road off to
the woods here.
But anybody who's listening,
2000.
Yeah.
So he made it to y two K and then he
kicked the bucket.
Um,
anybody who's just interested in really
cool conversations,
it's something to listen to.
That sounds very interesting.
Yeah.
Just three super smart dudes kinda
debating ideas and bouncing around off
each other.
You know,
what I've actually gotten into recently
is listening to old recordings of like,
uh,
Alan Watts.
Oh yeah.
Oh,
he was great reading Joseph Campbell and
just like,
yeah.
I don't know.
Just absorbing it and trying to figure
out what that means to me today in this
like the hero different world.
Yeah.
Watson is a fascinating guy.
Plus that accent made him sound so much
cooler.
Yeah.
Drone [inaudible] yeah.
His actually,
the first time I ever gotten to a good,
uh,
like,
like a meditative space was a meditation
led by Alan Watts from like,
I don't know when the fuck
it was like 60 seventies.
And just the way he explained it for me,
like it was the first time I'd ever made
sense how meditation should,
he's like,
don't try to not think of anything,
but just accept them that the there and,
but also ignore them at the same time.
Yeah.
It was weird.
And then I just totally like,
I felt like I was above myself watching
me.
So just sitting there listening to this
recording,
it was a trip.
Well,
he was such a heady guy.
There's the sound of his voice and just
hearing his thoughts.
When you,
when you hear a really deep thinker like
him,
one of the things that it does is kind
of gets you into that pattern of thought
and you realize like,
oh,
I can probably kind of sorta think that
way too.
We'll just allow myself to be guided by
his words and sort of try to pay
attention to how he's doing this.
Yeah,
he's,
um,
he was an interesting guy because not
just was he a deep thinker,
but his,
the,
the influences of those people.
It's,
it's very different.
Like there's very few recordings even
back then for them to listen to,
you know,
this stuff was based on reading,
um,
and their education and their actual
life experiences.
So they were very unique and original.
They were the really the cornerstones
for a lot of these deep philosophical
ideas,
you know.
And so then when you hear an Alan Watts
recording today,
you know,
maybe someone like me or some other
people that listen to that,
they'll might,
might share those ideas or reflect on
those ideas.
But clearly these are not my ideas.
These are ideas that have come from
these intense cornerstone people,
whether it's Mckenna,
Alan Watts or something like that.
Do you get a chance while you're,
when you're working,
do you listen to shit or do you just,
yeah,
I got all the time to sit in.
The headphones are cause it seems like
it'd be loud as fuck.
Yeah,
so I just got Ahold of these like
Bluetooth head head and like earbuds and
they have this memory phone so they are
memory foam,
ear bud like tips.
So that helps reduce the amount of noise
it's actually coming in.
So it helps protect it in that way.
Just kinda in general,
like a normal,
like a inner ear plug would work.
But also because it's reducing the
amount of noise that's getting in.
You can also listen at a lower volume so
you're not like blowing out your ears to
be able to hear whatever you're
listening to.
Like you wouldn't through normal
earbuds.
Right.
So loud in your shop.
So much noise.
It's whenever I'm working,
like especially if somebody happens to
pop by the shop and they want to see and
like they're just curious and so we have
stuff going on or we can heat some steel
up real quick and do a quick
demonstration.
Usually I don't take the time to throw
all that stuff in and fuck it is so
loud.
I actually feel like my hearing is
become more sensitive since I started
making knives than it was before.
Um,
probably your years of getting beat up.
Well you always have earplugs in.
I always have hearing protection and so,
so my hearing is always protected so I
feel like it's become more sensitive.
I've a sense
of hearing.
I don't know if that's possible to get
your hearing back or whatever,
but uh,
maybe your protect doing better because
of that.
Yeah,
I just,
I hear a lot of things,
like all the things it feels like
whenever I take my hearing or that you
in a hearing protection out,
I'll be at home or something and I'm
picking what the Lux,
that noise and my wife's looking at me
like I'm fucking crazy.
I'm sorry,
one us the case.
I wonder if like,
maybe it's like,
you know,
people don't use their hands and then
the hands get soft.
I don't know.
You can't gain it back.
Okay.
But you might be protecting it longer
and since your habit sensitivity issue,
maybe since it's quiet or all day.
So if you blow it out from like concerts
and shit like that,
that's it.
I tell it was while you can do is get a
hearing aid.
Oh yeah.
What about the little hairs?
The stem cells or some shit.
They don't do that yet because it's
literally what you hearing.
What is,
uh,
like a hair follicle.
It's vibrating.
Blow that shit out.
They haven't synthetically made those
yet.
Throw him yet.
I feel so bad for those old rock stars.
It didn't know any better and now they,
they're just fucking,
yeah.
[inaudible] happened to him.
Huey Lewis can't play anymore.
All of a sudden.
That's the Lord's work.
Just kidding.
Anyway,
it's hip to be square.
Um,
yeah,
man.
It's fucked up.
Like the dude from ACDC.
Who else?
Yeah,
Angus has gone.
Oh Jesus.
Yeah.
Fucking,
everybody's going deaf.
Yeah.
Probably didn't protect themselves.
I think you should have nobody knew any
better back then.
Have you ever seen that documentary?
It's an older one.
Older one.
It was like from the early two thousands
but this woman,
she progressively got deafer and deafer
as she grew older until like I think she
in high school or something and like she
was like practically completely deaf.
But she's a percussionist and she's like
a world renowned percussionists.
There's this awesome documentary is
called a touch the sound and she hears
through her body,
which is a fun trips me out,
but the tones that she's able to achieve
that control,
she has over everything,
whatever kind of instrument she's
playing.
It's an awesome documentary.
Wow.
But she has almost literally no hearing.
She hears everything through her body
too.
So it's kind of interesting to think
like if angus could figure that shit out
then,
I mean he's holding the fucking thing is
the whole time he's standing in front of
the angus,
the lead singer.
Right,
right,
right.
Who's the,
what's the lead singer's name?
Fuck's his name?
Second lead singer.
Brian Johnson.
And I forget that he's gone deaf too.
Hang,
listen,
Brian and,
and angus is like always headbanging
what kind of cte does that guy have?
No,
Jesus fucking Christ.
He shouldn't be doing that.
You were talking about dee dee about
that the other day.
I was,
I was thinking like all through high
school,
like I played football from seventh
grade all through high and like all this
stuff they're learning now.
I'm just like,
Jesus,
what the fuck was happening to me to ct?
We always lead with our head.
Of course.
Yeah.
My neck was always all kinds of fucked
up and you know,
I definitely had some serious
concussions.
Well I'm sure and yeah,
uh,
sometimes it scares me and worries me a
little bit.
Like what does that mean for how old are
you now?
34.
Yeah,
man.
Just turned 34.
Um,
it's scary.
You know,
you're lucky you stopped when you did.
I know,
I know a lot of people with brain damage
meat too.
I,
I'm sure I have some guaranteed.
I must,
I mean,
I don't think anybody rides for free.
I think you get hit in the head enough,
you got some brain damage.
You know,
I got hit in the head on a regular basis
for most,
most of my younger years from like 15 to
like 22 yeah,
I got to hit in the head all the time.
It's just
nobody knew any better,
you know.
And back then you thought that like once
you got like once you were slurring your
words and stuff,
if he just stopped like,
oh he's a little punchy,
you should stop.
Right?
Like that's how people thought,
but they didn't realize that it's
regressive and then like you don't even
really show brain damage like 10 years
after the initial injuries.
Right.
That's when you really start showing
damage.
So some,
some cte just compounds it until it just
becomes unmanageable for these poor
people.
Yeah.
And it's,
I actually,
I can't,
especially after watching concussion
and,
and seeing and reading like articles
about the real life people that this
shit's happened to.
I like,
I have a hard time watching football and
like I used to watch football time.
I've never been like crazy in a sports.
Knowing all the stats and every stuff.
I enjoyed watching like a good contest.
I never really rooted for anybody.
But now when I see like even kids
signing the draft or signing up from
high school to go to a certain college,
I'm like,
man,
that's somebody who's fucking baby.
I'll fucking tearing themselves up.
Like,
is that worth it?
Yeah,
that worth I would like Aye.
Port kids fighting way before I would
support kids.
Um,
doing football,
both of them.
I'd be nervous about it.
And you know,
I mean there's other stuff like x games
type shit.
People that are into extreme sports and
you know,
people that are in the snowboarding,
snowboarders wipe out all the time and
crack their head open ledger.
Can you get a scholarship and martial
arts of any kind?
College,
just wrestling.
I mean,
that's like a big,
that's a big driver right there though.
Right?
Wrestling,
that's where the money is.
Certainly a martial art.
It's probably one of the most important
martial arts.
That's probably it,
right?
Yeah.
That's it.
I mean,
judo maybe.
Is there a school that has judo?
They used to have boxing in schools.
I mean back in like fifties and sixties
and shit,
there was,
boxing was a a legitimate sport in
college but not anymore.
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
It just,
I can't really watch it anymore.
I mean you have to be careful with your
hand eye and your fingers
and shit now you know,
I mean you gotta think like when you're
working with hammers and hot metal and
you,
you must always have to be [inaudible].
Everybody that works in machine shops
missing that fingertip.
Something's fucked up.
This crazy story is to buffer the
buffer.
Like the fluffy little thing is like one
of the most dangerous things because it
catches an edge.
If you're snowboarding,
you catch a bad edge and just plan.
It bites the blade bites into that and
it acts as a hand and just rips it,
flings it wherever it's throwing knives
right back into guys and fucking killed
him.
Oh fuck.
My wife probably hating me.
Say that.
Right?
Yeah.
This is reality.
I've done,
I've actually done a lot of work to get
away from using buffers because of that.
And I'm still like doing great work.
I just,
I have a lot of friends who just,
they'll never touch a fucking buffer and
terrifying.
It's scary.
What does it look like for pizza put up?
Like what,
what would you call it?
Maybe she didn't like it.
Buffing.
Wash it.
I don't know what usually,
usually it's like a,
a bench top thing,
like a bench grinder.
Usually it has like the hard wheat round
stone wheel on one size at it.
That's it right there.
Those mother fuckers,
that's just not one fucking day was
going to kick this going to go.
It's not making me nervous.
That look,
that looks like something.
So if you fucked up and you got that
blade to close and kick it and then that
one is what's called a sizable wheels.
So it's,
it's made from a t that type of rope,
but the,
the ones that are the most dangerous or
the softer cotton wheels because they
want to grab that much easier.
They have more give.
Um,
but yeah,
it's,
and what's interesting is I've actually
been cut less working in a,
in a metal shop than I ever did working
in and burned less than I ever did
working in,
in kitchens.
I worked in restaurants back at house
like for seven years collectively.
And most of that has to do with other
people not calling like hot coming
across and fucking,
I turned around,
they don't call it,
I turned around there,
there with this fucking saute pan right
in the side of my arm.
I'm ready to fucking drop it.
Right.
But it's being in a metal shop,
like you said,
you do have to pay so much attention.
You have to be focused at what you're
doing because literally everything in
that fucking shop wants to hurt you or
kill you.
The second you're not paying attention
to the second you're not paying
attention,
it's going to grab you like their horror
stories of people working next to
machines and they have long hair and it
just fucking
scalps and like just straight heritable
stuff.
Arable cider in the power tool last
week.
Oh yeah.
He got a power tool stuck in his balls.
Who was that
poor bastard?
Yeah.
Got It.
Brian Wilson.
Yeah.
Drill that uh,
he lost his hearing due to not
plot,
putting in earplugs at a car race,
not music
specifically.
There was a quote Brian Wilson from the
beach boys.
Uh,
Brian Wilson from the beach boy or I'm
sorry,
he,
this article has him at the top.
Brian Johnson.
Johnson from cars.
Yeah.
Well,
how the fuck does he know mother fuckers
in AC DC?
Yeah.
Wouldn't you think that'd be loud too,
Bro?
Angus young says it.
He lost a little bit,
but he's,
his quote says that he never really had
a problem with it because that's why he
was running around on stage so much too.
He's never in one place so long.
The room,
that's hilarious.
Wisconsin or ever saw ICDS.
ACDC.
I wonder if people were more
susceptible,
just like some people are more
susceptible to cte.
Yeah.
Remember Rhonda,
Patrick was talking about certain genes
that you have.
What does it apropos,
I forget what it was called,
but whatever genes that make you more
susceptible and more likely to get cte
from concussions problem.
Probably not to be something that
probably makes sense.
Now,
when you're in that shop and you're,
you're,
you're doing all this grinding,
is there any concern about chemicals
like dessert,
chemical ingestion or smells in the air?
I think that because you're,
you're dipping things and you've got all
this stuff that using,
yeah.
Especially for you.
We're working with synthetic.
I mean,
any,
any material that you're grinding,
you're making it,
it's airborne.
Like any of it can go onto your loans.
I'm almost always wearing a respirator.
Oh Wow.
Especially when I'm grinding.
Um,
and it's like double can always like
covering up.
Does it work?
Does a respray are filled out.
All of it.
It makes a huge difference.
In fact,
excuse me,
where have my facial hair right now?
Even this little bit,
what you got,
even that little bit is enough to create
a little gap and it can get through
that.
So you have to shave your face smooth.
Yeah,
usually I keep it pretty well now I'm
now,
how the fuck do you create those
patterns?
Like Damascus steel.
What is that?
Oh,
this doesn't have too much of,
that was not in the Damascus steel
unfortunately.
It's beautiful.
Yeah.
What,
what does create those black that,
there you go.
How do you do that?
We're looking at a crazy image that
looks like it almost looks like someone
drew on it.
This is a,
this is a pattern that just came up with
recently.
It's called,
I call it the brain mosaic for lack of
better term.
Um,
but it just looks like a braid and it's
something I've been wanting to create
and really figure it out.
So essentially to create pattern welded
Damascus,
uh,
first off,
Damascus is kind of a blanket has become
a blanket term traditionally.
And originally it actually referred to
the steel that like the type of steel
that your knife,
this knife,
the media and knife is made from.
And it eventually became a blanket term
for all kinds of kind of pattern steel
in general.
Whether it's it,
it curdles naturally or if it's kind of
forced and created the way that pattern
was made.
Um,
so that's pattern welded steel.
And so you have to start with at least
two different types of high carbon
steel.
Ideally s steels that heat treat in a
similar range.
When you heat them up and squish on
them,
they they move at a similar rate.
And so,
uh,
most commonly people are working with 10
80 and 15 and 20.
Those are just codes for two different
types of high carbon steel.
But essentially you're bringing them up
to a high temperature.
You,
uh,
you squish them either under a big
hammer or under a press.
You can even actually do it by hand,
but you have to do kind of a smaller
bill it to create the patterns and get
it to stick because the trick is really
getting,
um,
getting them clothes evenly squishing it
out.
And it's like,
um,
if you've ever like rolled out dough or
anybody who's ever made like pastry
dough,
like you would use in a croissant,
you tear open a croissant,
you see all those layers in there.
And that's from a piece of dough being
rolled out,
fully rolled out.
And so it's Kinda the same fucking thing
but with metal.
But you have to have the kind of,
uh,
the right kind of temperature
environment,
kind of,
uh,
you,
you want as little oxygen in there as
possible because of the oxygen creates
carbon
or no carbon.
But iron oxide that helps,
uh,
kind of is detrimental to creating solid
weld bonds.
And there are different ways to achieve
that.
But um,
once the 10 80 is the black steel,
the black color and the 15 and 20 is
the,
is the silver color,
and that's a difference in the way those
steels performance harder or more
doable.
So they pretty much on edge more,
they pretty much form almost or perform
almost exactly the same.
They're there.
In fact,
chemically speaking,
they're almost exactly the same except
for the 15 and 20,
uh,
has a high level of nickel and end 0.2%
by volume or by weight.
And so that steel is traditionally used
in saw blades,
especially large big mill band saws.
Um,
you know,
like in Oregon there's like one of the
oldest continuously running,
uh,
wood saw mill.
It's still there and doing its thing
with these giant bandsaw blades that are
like 30 feet and that are uh,
in circumference and they're like foot
wide and there's monsters and foot wide.
You mean like thick?
No,
no,
no.
Like they're only in like maybe a 16th
of an inch thick because you want to
narrow soccer so you're not wasting
material.
But their why to help prevent deflection
to keep it from kind of Swiss band saw.
I'm thinking of a circular saw for some
reason.
Sorry.
Yeah,
band saws.
So circular saw those.
Soccer's are usually probably around a
eighth of an inch to a quarter of an
inch thick.
But it's the same kind of idea is that
they're trimming down these giant logs
so they need a big fucking saw.
Whether it's circular break,
man,
I must be a fucking nightmare.
That's gotta be
such,
you don't want to be standing right
there when that you've seen an original
Samurai sword.
I've seen a few,
actually this one's from the 15
hundreds.
Check this shit out of us.
It.
Oh Shit.
This is the one that,
uh,
Mr Neil degrasse tyson was posing with
the other day.
Yeah,
that's a real one.
That's an actual Real Samurai sword,
right?
Right.
From the 15 hundreds.
See the race skin is nice.
Do you know when it was made exactly?
I don't think they know.
They just know it's from some time
period in the 15 hundreds for sure.
Sit Certificate of authentication that
came with it.
That explains,
I'm just looking to see what the hormone
activity looks like.
So the hormone is,
uh,
you can kind of see this line that runs
parallel to the cutting edge and that
usually indicates where the soft
materials stops and the hard materials
starts.
Um,
and so the idea with these kinds of,
uh,
the challenge with any knife is making a
knife that takes and holds a sharp edge,
right?
For a good period of time.
What's the key to that?
But it's also tough,
which means like you can drop it and
it's not going to break.
So like if you wanted a hunting knife or
something like that.
So,
uh,
a hunting knife,
throwing knives,
those are harder working knives.
So you want to actually bring that
hardness down.
You don't have to bring it down a ton,
but just a few points will make a huge
fucking difference in housing forms.
Yeah,
exactly.
What's the difference in the way that
knife is made?
And this knife,
so they were temporary.
They were heat treated the same.
So they were brought up to like 1500
degrees
from people don't,
not lists are listening.
Not watching this.
One of these knives is a hunting knife
that uh,
how's that feel bad by?
It's great man.
I'll have to love it.
Yeah.
Nice.
Um,
but it's uh,
it's made very similarly.
If you look into the,
um,
the video of it,
the handle's the same and it looks,
it looks very similar.
It has a different knife guard though.
It's pretty cool.
Hold on.
What's that?
Yeah.
The garden keeps you,
it keeps your hand from sliding up.
Yeah.
I liked the way he made the handle too.
It's an interesting handles,
curved and everything.
Where,
where'd you get that pattern for?
Like some dough?
Yeah.
So the first question,
I'm sorry.
I remember at first like what is the
difference in the way they're treated?
Okay,
yeah.
Yeah.
So they were hardened.
So he treating the whole process is
essentially heating up the steel,
make it hard,
and then you put it back into heat,
but a low,
much lower temperature to kind of
toughen it up.
Um,
and so you're pulling some of that
hardness back.
So they were hardened the same way,
but they were tempered at different
temperatures because one is a hard use
knife while the chef's knife is not a
heartbeat.
What is the difference between a temper
and what,
like what does that mean?
So the tempering,
uh,
so essentially,
so I harden it,
so I bring it up to 1500 degrees,
uh,
which is like a adult glowing orange
color.
And then I dip it in a special oil that
I have that's designed for quenching
materials,
not just in knifemaking,
but all kinds of different industrial
applications.
Clenching materials or oil,
sorry,
quenching oil.
What does that mean?
So that's cooling the,
this hot steel down in a very short
period of time and punching it.
Oil,
coal,
oil,
not so actually the,
depending on how the steel needs to be
heat treated,
uh,
you actually want to heat up the oil so
that it's,
uh,
it's thinner.
And it also,
there's this thing that's called a vapor
jacket.
So if you've ever like been next to a
wood burning stove and you drop a little
water on it and you see that bead water
dance around on there,
the same thing happens on the surface of
the blade except for the blade is a
source of the heat,
right?
He put it in that oil.
All that oil is dancing around on it.
So when the oil's thinner,
uh,
it,
it's not as large of a jacket because
when that jacket is large,
so jack encasing that steel,
while it's trying to cool down,
um,
it actually kind of acts as an insulator
and ruin or could potentially ruin.
So not only do you put it in the oil,
but you want to agitate it to kind of
break up that jacket.
Um,
so it doesn't get a chance to just sit
there and all the way around the blade.
And if it was cold it would,
it would be thicker.
And so,
um,
it would make a larger jacket actually.
And also the,
it probably wouldn't be as,
uh,
efficient I guess in cooling the steel
down.
Cause ideally like for most seals,
you want to cool them down pretty much
as quickly as you possibly can.
So you have,
sorry,
go ahead.
Sorry.
So we could keep going.
I was just going to say you,
you essentially have a,
depending on what kind of steel you're
working with,
you have anywhere from half a second to,
uh,
like five seconds to get it from 1500
degrees or sometimes higher to below 800
degrees and the,
so this knife would be more durable.
Is that what it is then?
This knife durable?
Yeah.
Tougher.
So in,
in knifemaking commonly refer to it as
being tougher so it can withstand coming
into impact with bone.
You could chop with that thing a lot
more efficiently with a tougher knife
because this hasn't been tempered at it
as uh,
as high of a temperature.
Um,
it's,
it's much harder than this one,
even though it's a few points,
those few points make a big difference.
And so if you were to take this out into
the woods,
tried to do the same job as this one's
just the cutting it,
it wouldn't necessarily snap.
Um,
but parts of the cutting edge wood up
blow out,
probably blow it and chips.
Um,
I actually recently just from time to
time is good as a knife maker to make
sure that you're still doing your thing,
your heat treating stuff.
All right.
I take a knife and I just beat the shit
out of it for such hop through some wood
and then I actually took it to an antler
and beat the shit out of it too.
And,
um,
it's,
it is amazing that if you're doing
things right,
you know,
10 thousandths of an inch is enough to
really,
to withstand impact of chopping through
would pretty well of course,
unless you're coming into contact with
like super,
yeah.
Nail or super dense knots,
that's crazy because it's so thin,
right?
That's actually on the thicker side.
This is on the thicker side at least,
especially in longer cutting edge.
That's probably twice as thick as it
actually needs to be.
Wow.
Which is crazy,
but it just,
it comes down to the material.
Not everybody or a lot of people
mistakenly think,
you know,
steel is steel,
is steel,
is steel and whatever,
but they're not,
steel is made for many different
applications and they're actually very
specifically designed for those
applications.
So,
uh,
like a structural steel,
this kind of stuff that,
you know,
buildings are built out of very
different from this.
It doesn't have very much carbon in it
at all that way.
So,
uh,
the carbon is what helps make these
really hard.
So lacking that carbon is,
allows it to be way tougher.
So you can bend it all fucking day long.
No,
exactly.
So that's why you want it for buildings
in la where the earthquakes hit and they
wiggle a little bit.
Yeah.
Um,
this is much thinner than a lot of
other,
uh,
hunting knives would be,
which is interesting,
you know,
w with your use of this exotic metal and
your,
your methods,
you were able to do that.
Well and also part of the reason that
you're able to do that is because it's
high carbon steel.
It has a,
which means it has a high volume of
carbon comparatively a then other kinds
of kinds of tool or cutlery,
steel.
It was a benefit of high carbon versus
last carbon.
Uh,
so high carbon allows you to,
to,
um,
especially for the,
the media rights deal,
it's a,
it's a kind of crucible steel called
woots.
And so the patterning you've seen there
is actually strands of carbon are
carbide material.
So all the extra carbon floating around
in the matrix.
The Iron Matrix of this steel jumps on
to these bands called carbides and there
are different elements in vanadium is
one of the elements in this steel that
draws those carbon,
that carbon in.
So what you're seeing are thousands and
thousands of all these ultra hard carbon
bands floating around through the Iron
Matrix.
Do you watch game of thrones?
I do.
When they have like swords that are made
out of Valyrian steel.
Sure.
Pissed off.
Get the fuck out of here with your fake
magic style.
Well,
and what's interesting back in the day,
shit was fucking magical,
right?
Like they didn't understand what was
going on.
Now how did they
learn?
I mean,
what is the history?
I mean obviously that sword,
there's from the 15 hundreds but you
know from back in the Roman gladiator
days and I mean,
how did they understand how to do this?
So the steel that they were using in
Europe was not really that great.
It was at the best shit.
Japanese,
we just were pretty fucking good.
Yeah.
As well as the park,
the Persians and the Indonesians Vikings
material wasn't the greatest.
Wasn't too barbaric,
no time.
It's just,
it comes down to a what they had
available to them.
Right?
Yeah.
So who was the pioneer of like really
durable Badass sword material?
Was it Japanese?
So probably so the Japanese and the
Persian slash Indonesian Persians,
uh,
swords are probably the most legendary,
you know,
they're the ones where like it could cut
through silk floating in the air and
shit like that.
Why is that?
What did they do different?
So it's,
so the Persian steel is steel very,
very,
very similar to these meetings.
Right?
So it's a crucible.
It starts,
it's called a crucible steel.
And so essentially there's this clay jar
essentially called a crucible.
People melt all kinds of stuff in it,
but you can mail melt steel in it as
well.
And so they were making these ingots of
crucible steel and then forging them
out.
And they really,
really very heavily relied on these
carbide bans floating through the
material because unfortunately they
didn't really have a very,
uh,
advanced way of quenching that steel so
that not only do they have the bands,
but they also had hard iron matrix as
well,
that those bands were floating in.
So they really relied on those,
that banding.
So the,
they
just learned from trial and error of
thousands of years of experimenting with
different materials and different
locations that they got the iron from
and different things that they added to
it to make steel.
Yup.
Absolutely.
And that's why like,
you know,
you even watching game of thrones or
other kind of medieval or movies set in
medieval times,
you know,
there were very specific makers who were
the best who could really make the shit
happen.
And it's because they had a tradition
passed down to them.
And you know,
all that's a lot of that stuff was very
fictional.
But in the real world,
that was the same thing.
You know,
you had very specific lineages of people
who had the,
you know,
essentially the most advanced technology
and skills and techniques for creating
the most highest performing weaponry
essentially of the time,
which was like the currency of the
fucking time.
Went to Japan fairly recently in and
filmed them working with a high level
sword maker for a television show.
Trying to remember who it was.
It was someone famous but it was really
bad ass.
They went to this sword maker shop and
you know,
I mean he's doing the whole thing like
hammering it all out and building a
Samurai sword from scratch the way it's
always been.
Yeah.
There are a few of those documentaries.
Um,
so it is trending on youtube there you
got to do,
usually you got to do a little bit of
digging to find them.
Um,
I,
I actually just watched a few of them
like in the last five years,
I do not recall what they're going to
make a Samurai sword.
One of these days.
I might do it eventually.
Just,
I mean I'm always going to do chef
science because that's what I know.
Like,
that's the tool I know the most.
That's the biggest market right there.
There's a giant,
I mean for a super foodies and I'll let
you know.
Well it's not only that,
but if you think about it like there's
a lot,
there's a lot of mystique around
Japanese sores or even the American,
but we knife as well as you know,
Viking swords.
But nowadays,
you know,
people have that shit made but you know
it goes on a wall.
The things that are really getting used
or like a hunting knife and a chef's
knife and you know,
cooking knives are,
are used like almost literally in every
single household around the world every
day,
year round.
And it's,
what's interesting is because of its
ubiquity to our everyday life,
it lacks that mistake because we see the
shit every day.
You don't think much of it versus a
Japanese sword.
People walk in here and they're like,
fuck.
Well I tell you what
thing man,
when people come over to my house and
I'm cooking and they go,
where the fuck did you get that night?
That happens all the time.
And when it's either this one or the
other one.
When I show them the bog oak one,
same thing.
They like two.
I'm like,
yeah man,
check it out.
Now in terms of like this one or the
other one that you made me,
the other hunting knife that you made me
out of Damascus,
which one is like tougher or more
durable?
So they've been heat treated to perform
very,
very similarly.
So the base,
you'd essentially have to destroy them
to really determine which one outperform
the other.
You have to stick it in a bowl and try
to break it.
Yeah.
Essentially use it.
How it's not supposed to be frying,
but it,
they cut it keeps an edge.
So,
well man,
it's crazy.
Yeah.
I mean I,
I get nervous every time I touch the
blade.
I mean this thing slices through things.
Yeah.
Now,
um,
there's gotta be an art to,
uh,
actually sharpening things too,
right?
Oh,
for sure.
And how do you know like the right angle
to a approach?
Sharpening?
It's,
I mean there are a lot,
they're actually a lot of great
information online there,
especially in big cities like Seattle,
La,
New York,
uh,
Austin,
there a Portland as well.
There is super reputable people.
Not only who will offer service,
but I usually offer lessons as I
suggest.
Like if you can't afford it,
you know,
you can dig around,
you can find the stuff online.
But it's not the same as having
essentially having a coach next to you
saying uh,
or yeah.
That's great.
That's perfect.
That's where you want to be doing that
shit.
Do you sharpen both sides?
I do.
So you sharpen the top and the bottom.
I'm sorry,
you mean the sides of the steel?
Would you sharpen it like this and then
flip it over?
Yeah.
Now what are those things?
And they have those metal things where
people go xing,
Xing,
shooshing.
Yeah.
So those,
those ones seem like,
I'm like,
that looks brutal.
I wouldn't do that to a good knife.
It so am I right thinking that way?
Well,
it depends on the type of steel that
your knives made from and then what the
material is that those rods are made
from.
So those are commonly referred to a
sharpening ron's or sharpening sticks.
But the reality is they're not actually
sharpening.
What are they doing?
So they're,
uh,
more accurately referred to as honing
rods.
So what's happening at your,
sorry,
at the cutting edge of your knife is you
have all these micro seriations
essentially if you go,
uh,
take,
take it under a microscope and look at
the cutting edge.
It looks like a saw blade,
but they're like,
they're fucking microns.
Micron is a millionth of a meter.
Like they're teeny tiny.
So,
but what happens over normal use?
Uh,
those teeth,
they bend over,
they flex over or sometimes they
eventually wear out and fall off.
And so what the honing rod does,
especially if they've bent over showing
it right there.
Woo.
Yes,
yes.
You want to ignore like those long
streaks and you're just like the tiny
little thin black.
Yeah,
that's the shit right there in black
line
observation.
Are you looking at you?
It's like someone's doing it tiered
instruction.
But yes,
a youtube video.
Crazy.
That is crazy.
I was like,
are you doing that shit?
[inaudible] hundred x magnification view
from the top.
Yeah.
So that's what's happening along your
cutting edge.
And what happens to those tiny
serrations where it bend over like I was
saying or break off.
And so,
but as they bend over and it's just
normal shit that honing ron by swiping
across at Honing Ron.
And you don't just do it willy nilly,
like you got to do it at the right angle
and all this stuff.
But what it does is it realigns and
hones those teeth back into alignment.
So people mistakenly call them
sharpening sticks because all of a
sudden their knife is sharp as fuck
afterwards.
But the reality is that it's honed those
teeth back into alignment so it can do
its job again.
No,
what's the purpose of the leather strop
so that's just a gentler way,
especially for things that are super,
super,
a razor sharp,
which essentially have been sharpened to
really high finish,
uh,
like 10,000 grit or higher.
So those micro serrations are even
smaller,
which means there are even more
delicate,
which means they don't need as much
force to realign them.
So honing rod or Ho or,
sorry,
a strop is,
that's a human hair.
Yeah.
Jesus Christ.
That looks disgusting.
I just choking on that hair.
So just to give you some reference,
a typical and average human hair is
about three thousandths of an inch.
Well,
uh,
yeah.
And to help put that a little bit more
better perspective,
a 16th of an inch,
like a normal measurement,
one 16th of an inch is 62.5 thousands of
an inch.
So that's like one,
I can't even do the math,
right.
One 20th of a 16th of an inch,
which is fucking teeny tiny.
It's crazy.
It's like split the hair.
Yeah.
Literally.
Um,
there's a big debate and uh,
the world of bow hunting with broadheads
with a what kind of steel to use.
And,
uh,
there's,
there's harder steel that,
uh,
some people use,
but it breaks.
And just saying there's an issue with
that.
And there's,
there's like this big debate,
harder versus steel that has less hard,
but we'll bend more and give slightly
more,
you know?
And then there's,
um,
there's a,
the broadhead that I use,
which is a carbon steel broadhead from a
company called [inaudible].
They make this a broadhead called a
[inaudible] tech.
It's pull up,
um,
g five carbon steel monotech.
So your top tech cs,
they call them.
So you're talking to,
it's just the head like term,
just what a triangular or is it even a
triangle hunting?
The one that I use.
Yeah,
it is.
It's,
uh,
it,
it has a,
it was a three points or four points
here.
He'll pull it up.
You see?
That's it.
Oh yeah,
sure.
So there's three points,
but that's,
that's a carbon steel broadhead.
That's what I shot my elk with last year
with and that things virtually
indestructable.
Yeah,
there's a,
I have a crazy photograph.
I'll show you this crazy video.
Oh,
I put it up on my instagram.
Find that on my instagram where I'm uh,
I was fucking around with something on
my bow at,
at full draw.
I was trying to set something and the,
the Bo went off and it hit a cement wall
and it's stuck into the wall like a
cinder block or solid,
some solid cement wall and didn't kill
the broadhead.
I still have the broadhead back there.
It's stuck into the broad head.
Look at it.
Did it stuck into the broadhead,
the shaft and look what it did to the,
to the Arrow that we'll look at that,
that brought ed that fucking things got
my bet for life.
That things got my confidence forever.
Cause if that does that to concrete,
what will that do to bone?
Right.
You know that we'll go through anything
that's going to kick some ass.
Silver.
One of the things I would say after
seeing that,
especially that first image is the
geometry of
the blades that the actual points,
um,
they lend themselves similarly to how
your hunting knife to sharpen
differently from your chef's knife.
Like the chef's knife material's
thinner,
but they're also sharpened at different
angles because they have different jobs
they're supposed to do.
And so the broader essentially,
or sorry,
the more acute that is,
the more easily that will break as well
as the thinner,
the thinner the material that,
that,
that geometry is living on is more,
uh,
susceptible to breaking that first image
that Jamie pulled up the geometry.
It looked like it was pretty robust.
Hold that up again.
Yeah.
And as well as like,
it looks like it's probably at least 30
thousands of an inch thick,
which is,
you know,
that's about if not more actually the
original image,
Jamie,
we see the actual broadhead in the um,
without the,
um,
yeah,
my friend Brian Stevens turned me onto
these.
He,
he shot a bear through the head with one
of those genes from 10 feet away.
It was coming at him and he's got an
image of the skull.
Then he sent me where you could see the
outline of that broad had through the
bear skull as crazy.
Yeah.
And it and it killed the bear and didn't
even fuck up the air.
I'm like,
I believe it's crazy.
Yeah.
And so a lot of like you see people
doing these incredible feats like
hammering through nails and shit like
that with their knives and like what the
fuck?
The thing that most people are used to
our chef's knife and they think that
they did that with their [inaudible] it
up and 100% pretty much wood,
but with the right thickness coming up
to the cutting edge as well as the
actual lead cutting edge geometry,
like the actual angle that it sharpened
that you could do that shit all day
long.
Now when you sharpen a blade,
do you use something to hold it next to
the stone so that it reaches the perfect
angle or do you do it by,
I do buy,
I,
I actually,
I feel handed it over to me.
One of the things,
especially when I first started
learning,
I would use my finger as a guide,
so that would inform me as to the angle.
So when the edge of my finger would
touch the top of the stone that told me
that was about the right angle and then
when I flipped it over to do the other
side,
I do the same thing with my thumb and
essentially experience.
I just know it from experience.
They do make a sharpening guides that
you can clip on to the back of the
knives as well as little ramps.
Those are all great,
especially if you're starting.
The hardest part about all of this is
the muscle memory portion.
It's figuring out how to lock in and
maintain that angle without wavering and
placing your risks and all that kind of
shit and that just,
it's,
it's like riding a bike or any other,
anything you've ever had to learn in
your life with practice and repetition,
you'll get better.
What do you think about that?
Those machines,
so it's like little,
they're like little linked through the
worst fucking thing ever.
Really.
I have like almost kind of a conspiracy
theory that like the reality is they're
designed to destroy your knife so you
have to turn around and reinvest again
because most people,
but one because of the knives aren't
usually sold for very much money that
are being used with those things.
And when you're not selling them for my
very much,
you're relying on volume and what better
way than to create a thing that does the
job for a little bit,
but ultimately destroys it and you have
to reinvest.
What about those ones where you stick it
in the slot?
It's the same kind of thing.
It's a little slower process,
but you,
you'll notice the problem with those,
the real problem with those is that you
can't sharpen the whole edge.
You usually start at the heel or just a
little bit in front of the heel and then
you do the major work.
I tripped myself out.
I was like,
fuck,
I'm going to cut myself.
This is actually,
it's still pretty sure.
Oh,
it's sharp as far.
Um,
and so the problem is because you're not
getting the full length,
you'll continue to dish this material
out just in front of the heel and then
when you go to cut,
there's this little bit of shit there
that's not doing any work.
It's not doing anything.
Especially when you're relying on that
cutting board.
When the knife comes down to the cutting
board to do some work,
it's not happening.
If I cut my lunch with that today,
nice.
Oh fuck that.
Access that access have access deer and
elk.
Oh my God,
that was killing me.
That comment.
I probably didn't say it,
but I was just like,
Holy Shit.
That looks so fun.
Yeah,
man.
You know.
Well I learned how to cook.
I mean I,
I feel like there's some real art to
that as well from my friend Chad Ward,
whiskey ban,
barbecue on instagram.
He's a lack a,
a pitmaster like legit world champion
barbecue master.
And he's the one that taught me how to
cook slowly at low temperatures and then
sear it after you're done.
I always thought you supposed to just
put it on high.
He cooked shit out of it and then eat
it,
you know.
Yeah.
I mean it tastes fine that way too,
but you know,
when you're dealing with what I really
had to learn,
especially in particular cooking with
wild game is very unforgiving because
it's low in fat.
Yeah.
It's got none.
You're basically eating a sprinter.
Here it is right there.
So that's the end.
I have reverse sear it in a pan with
grass fed.
But here that pain.
Beautiful.
Listen to that sound.
Oh,
oh,
that's the last of my backdrop.
I gotta I gotta get some more meat.
I eat.
I eat so much meat.
It's crazy.
Yeah.
Sue,
it was super healthy though,
bitch.
You fuck what you heard?
Um,
it looks like it works.
No,
well,
you know what too?
There's,
there's something really magical about
wild game and um,
I don't know what the fuck it is.
I really don't and I don't think anybody
does because I don't think there's
enough people out there that are eating
it,
but it has,
it has a different effect
on your body.
It feels different when I eat beef.
Like if you have grass fed beef,
fuck,
like total,
like pasture raised,
like,
oh my God,
the difference.
Do you know about butcher box?
I am aware of it.
Yeah.
Dude.
That companies the shit,
they'll,
they'll send it to your house.
Frozen grass fed,
pasture raised,
like in the pasture finished.
And uh,
it's pretty cheap too.
It's a good deal.
The few top sponsors of this podcast,
and I use them all the time.
I think it's amazing.
It's brilliant.
You know,
and the few times that I,
and it's actually,
I feel embarrassed saying that I've only
eaten really good beef,
happy beef,
essentially.
Only a few times.
Yeah.
It's hard to,
yeah.
Well,
especially in some place.
Oh my God.
When you take a bite like that,
even just that first buy,
it's just like,
it's a whole different world.
And it's like,
what the fuck?
Just the flavors.
Everything.
I have my friend Mike Hawk Ridge,
uh,
he lives up in British Columbia,
like the real,
but British Columbia look way the fuck
up there.
And,
uh,
you know,
he's a hunting guide and,
um,
uh,
got him some tickets for the fights in
Vegas and he and his wife came down and
then afterwards we went out to eat and,
uh,
they were eaten steak.
We ate at a restaurant and they were
laughing like they're used to eating
moose,
you know,
like this beat is like,
it's like this poor little sick animal.
It's all mushy.
You know,
it's like if you eat a piece of wild
moose meat,
it's like,
whoa,
you eat it.
You're like,
Holy Shit.
It's like filled with flavor and it's
just,
it feels like it gives you energy.
It's crazy.
I would totally buy that.
Yeah.
You'll,
what does that people are trying to like
inject young people's blood into the
body is trying to make themselves feel
younger,
like eating it,
putting good,
well sourced.
Like those two things are now.
Right.
I don't know if it's the same,
find out the same,
but I do think that there's,
I mean there's gotta be something to
consuming and incredibly healthy,
vibrant animal versus something that's
like raised in a cage.
Right?
I mean,
this just does just make sense,
but I don't think this is something that
you can,
I mean,
they have absolutely measured protein
content and the protein contents off the
charts.
If you look at the difference in the
protein content of chicken or regular
beef versus Moose or elk,
it's much higher,
much denser and protein like,
like I think something like six ounces
of acts as is 48 grams of protein.
Right.
Which is incredible,
you know.
Well,
it's interesting to think about that to
get to get that same amount of protein.
Like you don't have to gorge giant,
you just,
yeah.
He's just eat that little bit.
Yeah.
You're good little six ounce piece and
you're good.
Even less if you want to stay in
Ketosis.
If you're like in a kito diet,
you really need less than six ounces and
you know,
like three ounces.
Right.
You know,
um,
food is does to me as,
especially as I've gotten older,
I've started doing a lot more cooking
and it becomes a different thing.
I'm,
it's not just,
I'm hungry and he stuffed my face.
Right.
Like the,
the preparing of food,
much like we were talking about with
craftsmanship,
like there's an art to making food and I
mean I'm by no means a chef,
but I can cook a few things really good,
you know,
and I take great satisfaction that I
fucking love it.
You know,
I'll take,
my wife used to hate this,
but we would get home and we're like
more hungry.
You gonna make some food.
Two hours later she's like,
she's like,
yeah,
a lot of people are that.
My brother's the same way.
Like I'm fucking hungry now.
I need to eat now.
Rip Your fucking head off.
What would you need to set up some
cheese and some like Salami or,
so that's what I started doing,
putting out some snack items while I'm
working.
It's just relax.
Where,
where like I could be starving.
I get done with a long ass day grind and
I'll go home and I want to,
I like,
I have this thing locked in my mind that
I want to eat.
I'll take two hours to make the fucking
thing,
even though I'm starving,
I haven't eaten since like one o'clock
in the afternoon.
It's nine o'clock at night.
Do you find that as a person who is a
craftsman,
an artisan,
that you try to have that approach with
like other things in your life too?
Like what you're talking just talking
about with like making food and,
yeah,
sure.
I mean,
I feel like I don't really think too
much about the fact that I'm doing it
this way.
It's just kind of the way I do things
and I'm a little bit more methodical and
um,
I guess not necessarily more thoughtful
than anybody else.
Just like when I'm go to,
when I approached these challenges or
these things they got to do,
I take my time to do them right and try
to do them right the first time I used
to,
uh,
actually when I was working for Bob,
we would have to mock up stuff or build
machines or six years or some shit like
that.
And um,
you know,
he was a very,
his mindset was quick and dirty.
We got to do this,
get this done as quick as possible.
And if it doesn't work the first time,
we'll make some modifications and we'll
try it a second time.
Still doesn't work,
sec time,
so and so forth.
So on and so forth until we got it
right.
Where I would just think it through a
little bit more.
First Time it was all I need it.
But I,
there was a long time,
I used to do a lot of woodworking before
we got in the metal working and I was
uh,
I always had to measure five times and
cut twice.
Right?
Yeah.
And so I started getting to this point
where like,
I really had to think shit through
because it's just,
to me it felt like a huge waste of time
and energy and materials really to go
through all that process.
And then,
so they had to be a long time long
learning curve though,
right.
Until like really learn how to,
especially I would imagine the aspect of
it,
it's probably incredibly difficult.
Well,
and when I was working for bomb,
uh,
the only forging we did was a forging
the Damascus to make the patterns.
Um,
and then we would like cut pleads out
and go from there.
Uh,
I learned forging about five years ago.
Essentially.
I'm working with a gentleman named David
[inaudible] who's also,
he's a master bladesmith.
Uh,
he used to work in Seattle.
He's down in Olympia area now,
but he,
uh,
you know,
he did,
he's a blacksmith by trade that got into
knifemaking and he's fucking skill.
He's super talented,
especially when it comes to the bowie
knives and hunters.
Like he doesn't really great work and
especially his Damascus patterns are
really great.
But to watch somebody move and
manipulate material and really,
like I said before,
like stock removal is a very valid way
of doing it because the cost of the
actual materials,
um,
is very small compared to the removal
stock removal.
So earlier I was talking about taking a
bar and then cutting out the blade shape
and then grind.
Yeah.
Cause you're literally removing stock
from,
from the,
from the starting the parent material.
Would you take what's left and melt it
down?
You could melt it down,
you could turn it and forge it into
other stuff.
Um,
it's,
it's a really interesting practice.
It's actually,
it's kind of like,
you know,
people refer to yoga as a practice and
we're going to be perfect and like
there's never going to be perfection
blade forging,
but there's always an opportunity to
learn something and the practice it.
And so when you see like you have a
decent little chunk,
you know,
you start smashing on that thing and see
what you can get out of it to economize
that material.
And again,
like I said,
you don't really need to do that because
of how inexpensive material is.
But if you think back like even a
hundred years,
like this high quality material,
it's fucking expensive.
You had to get the most out of it as you
possibly could.
And so that's why forging with such a
big deal.
And then as that price went down,
people change the way they manufactured
just because then the time was the thing
that costs the most,
not the materials.
And so they turned around and made it
easier to manufacturer.
They didn't give a shit about the waste.
Now how did you learn handled geometry?
Like the handle on this hunting knife.
So yeah.
Yeah.
So you're asking him is very unique.
It is unique and actually,
uh,
my hand perfectly fits in your hand know
and that's,
that's the goal.
A friend,
a friend refers to it as a,
the knife shaking your hand back.
Like it fits so well.
It feels like you're holding like shake
it for people that are just listening.
Then there's an initial smoothness in
the front and then there's like this
little bump and then like a little step
the bottom and it just locks in your
hand and just feels perfect.
So I was inspired to do that by a maker
named Claude beauchamp.
He's a Belgian maker.
Uh,
I first met him,
odd
Claude Bosch,
Bosch Chevy.
He is,
uh,
he's a Belgium maker.
He at the first time I met him was at
blade show,
which is a huge knife exposition.
It's the biggest one in the world that
happens down in Atlanta every year.
The first weekend of June,
he was my table neighbor and I had never
told him the story,
but the first time I saw his knives I
was like the blades and everything
looked great but that the handle looks
fucking weird as shit.
This handle.
Yeah,
very similar to that handle cause his
has more of like a nice gentle curve
around to the end instead of kind of how
that one's kind of at a clip or an
angle.
Um,
and so finally,
like on the third day of the show,
this really great maker that I look up
to,
uh,
came over and he was just like doting
over clods work.
And I was like,
all right,
there must be something that,
and I have any,
I feel like such an asshole.
Like I didn't even touch the stuff.
I was just looking at it and judging and
I picked it up and I was like,
what?
It was,
it was a totally like,
what the fuck?
Because that same feeling that you have
when you're holding that,
it feels perfect.
I was like it,
it totally shifted my entire mindset and
paradigm around what I thought handle
shapes should look and feel like.
And that has definitely inspired
continued especially for like hard use
knives like especially like for a bigger
blade,
like a Bush knife that you're trying to
chop through stuff with a handle like
that is going to benefit you immensely
because it just,
it feels like a natural extension of
your hand.
And is this your your logo into the
bottles?
My insignia.
So it's,
my name is Marco Mel Masiya.
It's two m's kind of swirling around
each other and it looks kind of like a
flame dude.
I'm such a Dork for this shit.
I love it.
So interesting man.
And then the handle too,
there's something about the,
the handle being made out of Antler,
like the Antler,
the feel that it has in your hand to the
organic materials,
organic especially uh,
antler and bone.
They have this kind of like,
I don't know if you've experienced it
with these,
especially cutting up the like the
greasy meat,
but from,
from my experience it does,
it stays grippy.
It doesn't become super slippery or
anything I handle on my bow is actually
made out of antler.
Yeah.
Had it custom made.
My friend John Dudley had these ones
made from a bull that he killed on
September 11 2001 like,
oh she has the nine 11 bull and he had
these handle's made out of the antlers
of this.
And it does the way it sits in your
hand.
It's like it's got an,
even if you're sweaty or you know
there's something,
you know,
it's rainy out,
it just has an extra grip to it.
Well,
and especially something like that,
like if you're skinning and breaking
down an animal and like it's important,
but it's not going to like,
it's not like one of those moments where
you relying on that grip for your life,
but when you do need that for your life,
like you're trying to do,
or like you're digging in the ground,
you're falling down the hillside and
you're trying to jab
it and get it,
get a hold.
Like that's going to be really
important.
But obviously that's a very rare,
uh,
yeah,
incident when that one happened.
Well,
it's just something cool about it too.
and just like the tactility.
Yeah.
It's just,
again,
it goes back to the,
essentially the user experience.
Like what does it feel like?
How is it different?
Like it makes,
it really does make a difference.
Yeah.
And the,
one of the cool things to me also about
antlers is that they shed them,
you know,
that they lose these things every year
and that every year they grow a new one.
Do you know that it's the fastest
growing organic material on earth?
No,
I didn't know that.
That shit right there,
that giant elk antler that grows in a
couple of months,
I didn't know that falls off.
Right.
They lose it after they're done running.
So after they're done,
like they fell off and they just kind of
immediately started,
like kind of slowly grow.
They grow the whole thing back in a
couple months.
It's radical.
See if you find a video that shows,
um,
elk antler growth,
time lapse,
because it's crazy how fast it grows and
it's all just for war.
I mean,
that's all that is.
It's to show off for the ladies.
Hey,
and it's also for war.
It's interesting,
dear.
Yeah,
that guy,
yeah,
Iraq.
Yeah.
He had that rack just so he could fuck
people up or fuck people,
but also elk.
Yeah.
And definitely people you get close to
him.
Fuck me up.
But look at that.
The following photos were taken about a
week apart over a period.
Look at this April 1st I'll check this
out.
Watch.
Just,
just have it play out there.
It says a over four months,
they show the incredible girls.
So April 1st watch.
This is like at a farm,
a that looks like it is.
It looks like it's an elk farm.
Just let it play out.
April 8th boom.
So seven days later,
look at that.
April 15th Bang.
Look how big that shit is.
Oh Shit.
April 22nd it's getting crazy.
Boom.
April 29th that's nuts.
May Six.
Holy Shit.
I know.
Nuts.
May 13 Kapow what mother fucker May 20th
Glutton crazily material.
Yeah.
May 25th June 4th right.
He's getting ready to go to war.
Yeah.
June 10th he's thinking about Pussy.
Look at that.
It's like now,
now I'm thinking about supposed to be
June 17th I will fuck a dude up.
Comes near me.
June 24th look at that.
And then July 1st that is crazy.
What the fuck?
It's crazy.
And that's not even done.
July 8th July 15th now he's basically
still in velvet and then July 22nd that
looks hard.
Horn to me,
that looks like he shed his velvet.
And then July 29th isn't that nuts?
Bizarre.
So by the time August rolls around,
they're ripe right now,
beginning of September there in hard
horned and they'll go to war and they'll
keep that shit for,
you know,
till the end of December.
Probably December I think.
Maybe January and then they'll,
they'll lose it and then they lose the
fastest growing organic material.
Yes.
By volume.
Weight,
yes.
Okay.
Yeah,
I think by all those things,
because it grows so fast,
it's so heavy.
I mean that's like 40 pounds.
Just have antlers.
Yeah.
And it grows over a couple months.
It's fucking nuts man.
This scene picture on,
I made that up about the fastest growing
organic material,
but I think it's true.
I'm looking at,
it says,
uh,
the first fun fact I found it,
they can grow 10 pounds of velvet per
year.
That's just the valve.
Just the velvet.
Yeah.
Hmm.
But that's probably because a,
it's a velvet farm,
you know,
they use that stuff for human growth
hormone.
I got a lot of baseball players were
taking on a shit.
Yeah.
A friend of mine,
my friend John Rivet shout out to Johnny
Ribot,
he lives in Alberta in his,
one of his friends had an elk farm up
there in Alberta and he grew elk non for
the meat,
but for the um,
for the velvet because that stuff that
grows,
grows so fast and it's so,
so ridiculously potent that they would
take,
uh,
antler velvet and they were turning into
a spray that would equal the effects of
human growth hormone.
How could you do that?
Crossing me?
She's like,
I don't know,
but athletes,
we're taking it,
athletes are taking this stuff and it
was having this just for like growth
hormone reaction in their body aches and
like know it sounds like it's
superficial son.
He'll get it.
Isn't that applied superficially or they
like score?
No,
I'm too stupid to be answering your
questions.
But um,
there's something about deer velvet that
was a for him,
you know,
I don't even know if it worked,
but it was a big thing in the,
uh,
the supplement and fitness industry that
people are getting deer velvet.
The new vibe bought it that you spray it
and it's supposed to give you a growth
hormone.
Would you think of that only beard?
Did you have your hand only been before?
Yeah,
I have.
It's great.
Yeah,
it's great.
Olympia?
Yeah.
Is this from Olympia,
Washington?
Is that what it is?
Uh,
originally.
Yeah.
It think it's brewed in Milwaukee.
Now.
What the fuck?
I know everything's being sourced
overseas.
I mean what,
um,
your,
uh,
from the Pacific northwest,
but now you live in Connecticut.
The state I shit on the most,
this is a whole video out there of me
shitting on Connecticut.
Like people have made a compilation of
me,
Shit.
Oh,
can I shoot?
I'm sure plenty of it's warranted.
Yeah.
There's all of it.
Shout out to my good friend Tommy Junior
and lived in Connecticut.
Yeah,
I finally found it.
So,
uh,
I think it's just antlers in general
are,
are the fastest growing tissue and an
Annie Mammo.
Yeah.
And then she,
Elk Antler is the fastest growing out of
all of them because it's the largest,
so it grows in the same amount of time
that the deer would grow its antlers,
but it's far larger.
You know,
like,
like if that was been more mass than a,
than a Moose,
uh,
no,
no dear.
Would be big Musubi where some Moose,
cause my are here.
They're the biggest,
they're the biggest of all of the deer
species.
Like by far,
you know,
I think like a full grown Yukon Moose
could be as much as 2000 pounds.
A really big rocky mountain elk under
normal circumstances is like a fucking
giant one is pushing a thousand genes.
It's a giant though.
That'd be like a 400 inch bull like that
one that's out for the,
the inches.
The measurement of the size of the
inches of the antler like that.
Do you see that one that's in the front?
That's considerably bigger than this
one.
That was the one out in the front is 382
inches.
That's a giant bull chasing.
That fucker was about a thousand pounds.
He was huge.
Huge.
Moose.
Moose is twice as big.
Hips would see that thing go.
Shut the fuck up,
bitch.
I got to go.
And they just start running for Moose.
They,
they're,
the weird thing about a moose is their
antlers or like a door,
you know,
it's basically like they're so fat
thing.
It's not like pokey mean.
They're basically like they're hitting
each other in the head with doors.
Right?
They're like big old gloves and,
but you seen,
have you seen,
I've seen a few pictures where the,
especially the Moose there,
the antlers get locked up and they're
fucking stuck more deer than Moose.
Yeah.
Because the design of a moose antlers is
like,
it's not as intertwined.
But with deer it happens all the time
because there's a little bit of flex to
the bone.
And so the clash and in the force of the
two of them slamming each other,
they get stuck.
CTE Will they drown?
Oh Gee.
They've,
they've fought like that and then,
you know,
wrestled and wound up in the water and
one up drowning does a horrible video.
I saw of two deer that got stuck in one
of them got killed by a coyote.
Not just get a whole pack of them torn
to shreds.
It tore him and they eat them.
Asshole first,
as I've documented many times in this
podcast.
Um,
it's like a lot of animals do go for the
buck first.
Well,
yeah.
Lions do.
A lot of them do.
Yeah.
I don't know what that's all about.
Um,
but the,
um,
the one deer was still attached to his
dead friend and uh,
these hunters had to help it get
released and they saw one of the antlers
off the other deer is dead deer and
fried it.
And then this other one ran off.
Like what a nightmare that guys lived
through.
Right.
You know his buddy,
it's his ass hole torn apart.
They literally eating him alive while he
stuck to the guy.
Oh my God.
Probably fight.
Yeah,
I have him as well kicking in and it
could he be trying to talk about,
could have easily been you.
I mean literally could have easily been
yet.
There's two dear.
One of them gets eaten alive and the
other one's just sitting there like,
like living with the horror of his and
then these people come over and he can't
get away from the fucking people.
And it's like,
these people are gonna eat me and they
don't even eat them.
They let them go and they're hunters.
They freed him up and let me lose crazy.
Yeah,
you got that.
Oh,
there's one that elk got stuck with a
dead elk.
That's a dead elk.
That's an elk head that stuck on this
other elks.
But see,
I don't know what that was.
That to me makes me think that that
could have very easily been like an elk,
found a dead elk and just started head
butting in and ripped his head off and
got stuck with them.
They kill each other all the time right
now.
I mean all the time.
Oh Geez.
Look at those racks,
dude.
When you hear them fighting,
like one of the first times I ever went
elk hunting,
we were coming over this hill and it
sounded like two dudes slam and baseball
bands together.
Just crack,
crack,
crack.
And when we came over the top of the
hill,
these two giant elk were just running at
each other and smashing each other.
It was a magical day.
It was like one of the first times I
ever elk hunted.
And there's a thing that happens when
you hit a peak rut and when the peak
rudd happens,
they just go crazy all around you.
They're all screaming and it might only
happen once in a season and you just,
if you might be there for that couple
hours when it all goes down,
what's insanity?
Insanity.
There's all around you screaming and
head butting each other.
I can't even imagine him walking over
the top of the hill and it's like
fucking stumbling across are so
vulnerable.
First one,
I got a tree and they're screaming
and they're so big,
man.
It's,
it's a screen.
There's two going at it right there and
you hear him,
they just clash and slamming each other.
Oh yeah,
you hear that?
It's
the boy dog.
Fuck man.
And they don't even know he's alive
right now and they kill each other all
the time.
But the hormones they got going on.
It's like,
I don't give a fuck about anything else.
Yeah.
My friend Cam came across one last year
and uh,
he crept up on it.
He thought it was bedded and he shot it
with an Arrow and it didn't move.
And he's like,
what the fuck?
And he got over to it.
It was already dead and another elk,
it stabbed it.
They stabbed through the heart and it
laid down and died.
Right.
It happens all the time.
They are,
they're always finding them that other
other elk have murdered.
They don't crazy.
Fuck.
They just trying to get that policy.
So I to get the pose,
how much does it right?
Is that a monster?
A month?
Just a month.
Maybe a little bit longer.
There's a second rut.
Sometimes in October when a another
female,
we'll go into estrus and they'll resume
the Rut.
Yeah.
It's magical times.
I can't even imagine stumbled across
that.
It's pretty cool,
man.
It's pretty cool.
You know the,
the real wild,
the actual real wild.
Well you are in Connecticut,
man.
You've got to worry about two things.
Hitting a deer with your car and lyme
disease.
The lime dust.
Okay.
So that's something that we didn't
realize we were moving into.
Oh Man,
I wish,
I wish I told you because you and I were
going back and forth when you were about
to move,
right?
Yeah.
That was definitely one of the things
that,
uh,
we're like,
wait,
what?
They're everywhere and you got to him
everywhere.
Ticks,
and if you're listening to this anywhere
in the east coast,
um,
especially New York has got it really
bad.
I mean there's a lyme disease map and
you see like the instances of lyme
disease and the east coast.
It's horrific man.
And I know fucking at least a dozen
people that have it and it stays with
you for life.
Yeah.
And my friend Jim Miller,
uh,
he's a guy who fights in the UFC.
He's got to take a giant fistful of
pills every day.
I mean he's got it real bad,
real bad and he's still fighting,
still fighting in the UFC
and those deer too.
I've been worried about actually when
we,
especially when we were moving out
because I was driving through
Pennsylvania,
I hit Pennsylvania at like we drove
cross country at sunset and drove from
there all the way to Connecticut and
dark and all I could think is like,
I'm going to fucking hit a deer.
You see so many of them.
Right?
You see so many dead ones on the side of
the fucking room.
Blows my mind.
But the biggest issue has been actually
other Connecticut drivers is the big,
the biggest concern.
My wife and I both have been t boned in
the last eight months.
People in Connecticut just,
they're just given up man.
This hitting the gas and closing her
eyes.
Well,
what's crazy is like I've driven,
I've driven an la,
I've driven in New York,
I've driven in fucking Oregon,
seattle,
all kinds of crazy places,
but they all have like a culture about
how they work and I could not figure out
Connecticut.
And a friend finally explained it to me.
He said,
they're driving as if nobody else is on
the road.
I was like,
Holy Shit,
that makes perfect sense.
The w the choices they make are as if
nobody else is there.
I'll be coming up in the passing lane.
So when he's in the lane to the right of
me,
there's no exits coming up.
There's no other cars for like half a
mile.
I'm cruising probably like five,
10 miles faster than them.
They changed lanes right in front of me.
Why?
Why,
why?
Because like say if you,
um,
you're,
let's,
let's say there's a thing that you're
making like in a poxy,
right?
When you're making an epoxy,
there's several ingredients that you
have to add to it.
Or maybe that's not the best example.
Like say maybe there's a electronics,
just whatever it is that you're,
you're,
you're making say so if you're making a
thing and it requires 10 different
ingredients,
if you are a person in Connecticut,
you have eight ingredients,
you don't have those other two and you
just do without,
without you just deal with it.
You just missing two things and you just
hit the gas and just drive places and no
one knows what they're doing.
And this is a real state.
It's just not well.
And what's also bonkers that we weren't
expecting is that like,
unless you're driving 15 to 20 miles
over the speed limit,
you're going too slow or,
uh,
like a stoplight.
And stop signs are suggestion.
People used right or left,
left where they're going.
Where are they going?
They don't under the state so small,
you could drive through the state and
demand and a half hours,
all sorts of stuff.
They just,
they're so confused now and I'm not
trying to sit here and shit on fucking
Connecticut,
but it's just,
it's just that those things haven't been
a serious culture shock for us.
Despair,
despair.
He hit the gas.
What's crazy is it's a fucking beautiful
state,
especially in the summer.
I'm terrifying trying to drive around
that time out of your car.
You get bit by a thousand ticks and you
fucking can't walk anymore.
The humidity too.
I was not expecting that.
Great on your balls,
right.
Ball sweat.
Yesterday I was in my shop.
I wasn't doing shit.
Like I could have just been sitting here
and like fiddling around with,
I was sweating my ass off
every,
I was just like,
yeah,
mine isn't coast Florida.
What the hell?
Yeah.
Well you're used to,
uh,
you know that Pacific northwest doesn't
really get that hot and the summers are
glorious.
Like Seattle and war against summers.
God,
they're glorious.
Everything's fucking neon green.
Oh.
And the sun comes out.
It's amazing.
It's almost almost makes up for the
winter,
but not quite the lack of winter.
Well,
just the rain,
just the rain stopped raining.
There is a winner.
It's just,
it's not,
it's not frozen.
It's tempered,
but it's just temporary.
Just crazy.
Yeah.
And Do,
and you're like,
I could do this.
I can hang in there.
And then the summer comes you like,
hey,
it's going to be fine.
But like a,
like a beaten wife waiting for your
husband to come home and you're like,
hey,
he's not home now and I've got a great
house.
But he's coming home.
He's coming home.
He's going to be home for eight months.
Yeah.
Just going to piss on your hair for
eight months,
eight months of clouds and fucking craft
beers and just everybody's shooting
themselves.
It's dark up there,
man.
I don't think people are meant to live
like that.
I mean,
I think it's gorgeous and there's
benefits to it for sure.
But,
uh,
I had a buddy of mine,
he tried to convince me to live up
there.
It's hilarious.
My friend Salami,
he moved to Portland.
That's his name.
Okay.
He tried to move to Portland.
I mean he did move to Portland.
He's teaching Jujitsu up there.
It's like,
dude,
I love and it's fucking great up here.
It's fucking amazing.
I go,
you don't mind about the winner.
You don't mind about the rain goes,
no.
He goes,
dude,
the people are so fucking cool.
The restaurants are amazing and the
summers are so good.
Three years later he's back in La.
I go,
what happened?
He goes,
I couldn't do it,
man.
Couldn't do it anymore.
I go,
ah,
I see.
So it's a thing.
It's like you hang in there for as long
as you can,
but you can't hang in there forever.
That what it is.
But some people can.
I can hang.
I've,
you know,
a lot of people have,
what is it,
seasonal depression syndrome or some
shit.
Like it's cause you grew up there?
I don't think so.
Cause my sister and my mom both grew up
there too.
My wife even the hate it,
they,
especially the winter time,
the wintertime when it is that dark
gray,
like it doesn't snow,
it just rains.
It just gets dark.
I guess.
I think part of my issue is,
like I said,
I always worked in restaurants or in
Phuket,
and we're in a shop,
so it's like I'm in a virtual cave all
the fucking time,
so I'm not experiencing that except for
the drive home or to work.
Wasn't Jamie just said sad as I was
looking up seasonal effective disorder.
That's the acronym they give is sad.
Sad.
It's,
that's what it is.
I mean,
they probably called it that on purpose.
I don't think they needed to call it
seasonal affective disorder.
That's not the best feel like shit
because of the rain disease.
Well,
something isn't it?
Something about like the lack of vitamin
D felt light.
I'll tell you what though.
There's light therapy.
I'll take it over Connecticut all day.
I'll take Seattle over Connecticut.
Oh,
all day.
You know what I dream about it sometimes
is Denver.
Even Connecticut.
I lived in Denver for only a few,
a few months.
People that live in Connecticut right
now.
I go,
what the fuck,
dude?
I actually running gag folks.
I don't really care.
When we first moved in Denver.
Denver's fucking beautiful.
Fucking love Denver.
Love it.
What was,
uh,
when I first moved there,
I thought I would,
so I grew up in Washington right at the
base of the puget sound water around me.
I actually used to sail on a racing team
and stuff like that.
I was like,
wow,
I'm going to miss the water so much and
it's so green too.
I got there and I was like,
I don't think I care about the water.
I care about the green.
But the second the spring rains hit,
everything turned green.
All the trees started blossoming.
I was like,
Holy Shit.
And it was beautiful.
Beautiful.
The only thing I hated about Denver,
everybody had a fucking dog and nobody
cleaned up the dog shit.
Oh,
that's fine.
That was the everywhere.
Lazy bitches.
I just didn't understand it.
It's probably worse now.
The other hand,
the free pot,
all the legal pot to everywhere.
But you know what?
What it has that's amazing,
man,
is the view of the mountains.
There's something about being right
there and seeing those rockies that just
humbles you.
It puts it in perspective.
So that's what,
that's what being in puget sounds like
as well because you always got Mount
Rainier.
It's crazy.
Like the road,
the cities were engineered so like
you're coming up and down hills and like
boom,
the fucking mountain.
That's right.
And it's a monster.
Mount Rainier is a monster.
Yeah.
That's amazing man.
We went,
I'm looking for big foot up there once
man,
dog and yeah.
Yeah,
we found him.
We just didn't want to tell anybody.
Um,
that,
yeah,
that area too is so wooded.
It's really incredible when you go
walking through the woods,
like there's,
you don't make any sound when you walk,
you don't leave any footprints because
it's just like feet thick of pine
needles and the models.
This is so soft and it's interesting and
lush and filled with elk manners,
elk everywhere up there.
And like they run,
they're run like 30 feet and you can't
see him anymore because there's just
like so many tree fucking guy.
My inlaws,
they live south of Olympia and they have
16,
16 acres out there.
And,
uh,
like three or I think it's like four or
five that are like clear for like a
field and a barn and the house and
stuff.
Rest of it's all wood.
And then they got black bears that
cruise through.
Their large cats are like podcasts and
links and shit.
Uh,
and elk for sure.
And they have an orchard and the elk are
just up there standing on their handmade
eating that shit up.
They're beautiful.
The coolest watch too.
Yeah,
that's,
I mean,
that is a lush tropical rain forest up
there.
It's so wild.
It's,
it's so,
it's so interesting too.
When you,
when you're up there,
you,
you realize like how diverse it is with
life.
When you're walking around in it and you
see just elk shit everywhere you go
walking through the woods there,
it's just,
yeah,
there's with them piles.
All these pellets.
Marvel's,
yeah.
Yeah.
It's like,
nope.
Don't want it so much life up there.
He's salmon.
There's so much salmon.
There's eagles up there.
I mean,
it's gorgeous,
man.
Here you aren't fucking Connecticut
mushroom hunting.
There's all kinds of stuff really live
off the land.
There's some great spots to go.
Shannon trailing and Olympia area sure.
Of getting out in the woods and just
walking around.
It's,
it's actually been really cool to take
it,
especially when you go back in the
summertime and especially in the
summertime to go visit family,
uh,
to take my little dude.
Um,
my son's two years old,
he just turned two.
And so walking with him,
he's just fucking loves it walking
through the,
and you don't have to worry about the
fucking ticks,
right?
You can get lame shit like that and go
out there and roll around and all you
want,
but going up,
they have a nice little,
like a quarter mile trail goes up
through the woods.
Let me just walk through that thing.
He just marches along the whole fucking
way.
And just that experience of stopping and
listening,
you can hear them,
red tail Hawk crying over the top of
everything else.
And then you,
they have great horn owls from time to
time that could cruise through was
there,
you can hear the little chipmunks and
squirrels and you hear the fucking crows
and a stellar jays and yeah,
everything and stopped telling him,
you gotta hear that and he just stops
and he's so intense and it's,
it's wild to see a little kid who's so
fucking rambunctious.
He's in the house,
but you get a mountain in the woods
overlapping with census,
just listening.
There's sort sorbet everything.
Right.
So cool.
Yeah.
Isn't it amazing to looking at it
through the eyes of your child,
just watching them experiencing all
these things.
It's like you can almost see the little
cogs turning in their head.
Oh Shit.
No,
it's amazing.
That's one thing that I didn't
anticipate before you had children.
It's like watching them learn like,
oh wow.
Like there's a crazy trip you get out of
watching kids learn.
You know,
there's,
there's something about like you learn
watching them learn and it really sort
of reinforces this idea that every human
being is essentially,
I mean they're not a blank slate,
but they are most certainly subject to
the influences of their environment.
What they experience.
They take that data in.
Yeah.
It's crazy.
Like we ha he loves maps.
So we got maps.
Maps.
Yeah,
we got,
you know how like a lot of kids get
those like bedroom,
uh,
math that have like the roads and stuff.
We got one of the war like the globe and
none of the countries are marked down on
it or anything.
But we knew some of the spots and so we
started teaching him,
he knows where like over a hundred
different countries are.
Like he knows that he knows where
they're at.
He can point out the difference between
Cambodia,
Guam,
Vietnam,
Nepal,
rush it and they're like Russia and
China pretty easy.
But then you go over to Europe,
he's like hungry Turkey,
Greece,
he like,
he,
he knows that he knows what Portugal is.
He knows we're speaking.
Show you.
I tell you what Africa is,
I'm pretty sure I know the difference in
Australia,
New Zealand.
The only reason I know them it's cause
I'm playing the game with him.
So we got more maps that have like the
world again,
but everything's marked out and he's
starting to learn all the different
flags.
He knows,
he knows at least it doesn't in a
different flags.
They're so open,
you know,
children there.
I mean they learn language so quick.
They're so open.
Let me think about kids learn language.
By the time they go to school,
they already know how to talk.
They don't learn in school.
Learn how to talk.
When my wife has her master's degree at
the university level for teaching
English as a second language.
So she's with him all day long.
Oh Wow.
And so she and she hurt.
She comes from a family of teachers,
her parents,
both of her parents,
her sister,
her great grandmother,
her grandmother,
all educators.
And I'm supposed to be amazing for her
to be a mom then.
And so she like,
she's with the dude all day long.
Like,
she fucking loves the shit out of him.
But you know,
like you try to spend in fucking day in
and day out with the little dude,
like the little,
the little fucking numbskulls running
around and trying to learn how to
interact with the world is fucking
crazy.
But it's so cool.
And with that background,
understanding how to interpret what's
going on in his brain a little bit.
So to help nourish it essentially to
help like,
you know,
just make things that much more solid.
Like it's fucking crazy.
And he speaks so clearly.
That's awesome.
Yeah.
I got to get out of here,
but I,
they have a blind auction.
Yeah.
Why don't you go grab those dives so we
can show up.
Go grab those real quick him real quick
and we'll,
we'll
tell people about the auction.
But he's uh,
he's got these fucking killer knives
that a,
he's made these a chef's knives.
The one that's going up.
I think so.
God,
look how beautiful that is.
We're looking at his,
a mousy fire arts instagram page and the
design the pattern on this chef's knife.
It doesn't even look real folks.
I mean,
it looks like someone's,
it looks like someone put like one of
those crazy cartoon filters,
doesn't it?
Is that it?
That's the knife right there.
There's that one so people could see it.
Yeah.
Here it is right here.
I'm holding it up.
So this knife is a for auction.
No,
actually is not the,
that one is not this one here in the
cases.
You can pull that out.
And how can people auction,
how can people bid on?
So this is for a benefit for Alex's,
uh,
the Alex or sorry,
La Loves Alex's lemonade stand,
which is for childhood cancer research.
And so online smells,
again,
if you go to a,
my instagram profile,
um,
my laci fire arts on Instagram,
I have a link actually in my bio that
goes straight to the auction page for
this knife.
Now these knives are,
uh,
right now my current prices,
this one knife is a $4,200,
but right now I think the bidding's at
like,
Oh,
there it is 2100.
So there's a chance that somebody could
get it for less than what I would
normally,
when does it end?
The auction ends on Saturday the eighth.
So that's when the actual event is and
I'm actually going to be there at the
event hanging out.
Um,
if anybody's got any questions about it,
talk about it or you know,
just kinda hang out and that's don't
folks,
but you know,
it's interesting like doing this kind of
work is the first time I've ever had
anything that I felt like I could give
back with cause otherwise,
like I was just did shitty little jobs.
But this is the first time I feel like I
have something like an offer.
So in coming up from very little,
very humble beginnings,
this was an opportunity now to feel like
I can give back.
And so I tried to do this from tons of
very cool for sure.
Well listen man,
I'm glad we finally got together.
You mean these awesome knives?
I will cherish them forever and it's my
pleasure,
my man,
amazing craftsmen.
And it was cool to do this.
Thanks.
Thanks for being here.
All right folks.
We'll be back
soon.
You fucks.
Bye.
Okay.