Okay,
the Joe Rogan experience Joe Rogan
podcast by night.
All Day.
Read up on.
That's the first month I ever had.
I might've gotten it from you.
Maybe.
Maybe we're off.
We're recording.
Yeah.
Cool.
That's exciting.
It's that simple.
We're on a hike.
Ladies and gentlemen.
We're a hike.
You were wearing 45 pounds on you?
Yeah.
The packs about five or six.
And the weight plates?
About 45.
Yeah.
Close to your face.
Oh,
sorry.
That's okay.
By the way,
this is how much.
This is what I walked around with.
This is what I walked around with it.
And in Southeast Asia.
Oh yeah.
About this.
This setup?
Yeah.
Well,
yeah,
I mean the way it hooks onto your waist.
Yeah.
And then the over the shoulder and over
the middle to over your chest.
Oh,
for a backpack?
Yeah.
And about the same amount of weight.
Forty five pounds plus whatever else
have hanging on.
Damn.
That was.
So you just carried your life on your
back.
Carried everything.
I have.
Did you bring a laptop?
Fuck No,
you're kidding me.
It's a couple people did because they
were like how to upload pictures that
the two weekers did that.
Right.
But almost anyone who's gone for like
more than a month was like,
you could just go to an Internet cafe,
right?
Yeah.
If you have to.
And you would just log into your Gmail.
Yeah,
exactly.
And then did you,
you had to deal with that notification
thing,
right?
Yeah,
a couple of times.
Even though I started that smell,
just the new gmo,
just for the fucking travel,
they still fucked.
It was still like,
well,
this looks suspicious.
And I'm like,
yeah,
it looks suspicious.
Should I'm in fucking nowhere.
I'm in Indonesia.
Absolutely.
But then like,
can we.
There's no other way.
There was no.
Like,
what's your father's,
you know,
what's your mom's maiden name?
God.
This gorgeous.
Ready,
right?
Yeah.
Did your kids are so fucking big now?
I know.
It's weird,
right?
A little humans.
Yeah.
I couldn't believe it.
When I saw them,
I was like,
I was just like,
no way.
Where do you see the oldest grown ass
woman?
It's very strange,
dude.
And one day we're going to be old men.
Men were kind of old men right now to
kids.
Yeah.
But one day we're going to be old men.
I'm getting grazer ready.
Nobody rides for free.
Yeah.
What does it ask?
Cash.
Aggress.
Yeah.
Everybody pays.
It's crazy,
isn't it?
I mean just.
And everybody thinks,
you know,
it's the sort of the same feeling that I
have when I talked to people about
asteroid impacts.
Nobody wants to believe it's possible.
What some.
It's smashing into a big rock from the
sky.
I've been obsessed with it for years.
We saw one you saw in Joshua tree.
Oh Jesus.
To lit up and it burned for like 15
seconds in the.
Those are so terrible.
It was so cool.
It was red and we're just like,
that's not a.
We were on mushrooms but everyone had
the same.
Same Book.
That's A.
I mean it's a rock.
Yeah.
And it just burned off,
burned off,
burned off until it was just went out.
But it like lasted for awhile.
We were looking for a,
what's it called?
You know,
shooting stars and stuff.
Stars out there.
So great.
Oh yeah,
man.
Probably out here too,
Huh?
Nah,
we get some light pollution that.
A little light pollution,
but it's not bad.
It's definitely better than the city,
but you really want to go out there like
in Hawaii.
Holy Shit.
What?
The stars.
Amazing.
Really?
Yeah.
I was in Lanai last week and the stars
were just stunning,
man.
He just laid back and look up at him.
Like you see the Milky Way.
You see everything.
Everything.
You see that that's.
What's that like?
The line down the middle sometimes you
know that's the thick line.
Yeah.
That's a thick clouds and it looks
white.
What's this?
What's that?
What's this animal dog shit?
No,
that's coyote.
The reason why you can tell,
it's because it has berries in it.
A really?
Yeah.
Kylie's are kind of omnivores.
They're weird little animals,
but they don't attack people,
right?
Yeah,
they do.
They do.
Yeah,
they do.
If they have an opportunity,
we have some sort of a fucking truth.
Yeah.
We'll just.
You alone with the coyote.
Well,
they would go for it.
A woman in Canada was killed a couple of
years back,
19 year old promising folk singer.
There's more coyote.
He could see the hairs in it.
That's it.
Yeah.
That's an animal that's been eating
things that might be a mountain lion,
but I don't think so.
It might be a bobcat.
But um,
I remember that that female Canadian
singer apparently where she was,
the real problem is they have a,
they have a real lack of things for them
to eat.
And so the coyote started approaching.
Well,
the coyotes there will even take off a
moose.
No.
As a pack or by himself as a pack.
They just attack the legs until it can't
go anywhere.
You just keep chasing it and biting its
legs.
Really?
Yeah.
Some of them get kicked in the head and
killed while they're doing it.
I mean,
they just take chances because there's
no food.
They sell food.
So they found this chick walking by
herself.
Whoops.
And it's a horrible way to die,
man,
because they,
you asshole first.
So he was still alive as a girl.
She's still alive.
The turner apart.
They don't kill you first.
They have no interest.
I don't care about eating.
Go start chewing you apart.
And when they got her,
she was still alive,
torn apart.
And then they took her to the hospital.
She died I think where they found her
alive.
Yeah,
pretty sure.
She was just fucked up like half her
face.
You ask first it takes a to eat.
What do you mean?
Ask for.
That's what they do to animals.
They kill you by eating you asshole
first.
Yeah.
That's what coyotes.
Do.
Wolves do the same thing.
They start at your asshole.
Horrible reason for real the most?
Yeah.
For Real.
Like they start at your asshole.
Yeah.
It's a terrible way to die.
So I'm a hiking in these vibram five
fingers shoes.
The coaches,
they're minimalist shoes.
There's like almost no padding.
There's just some tread like heavy
socks.
Yeah,
there's tread,
but there's very little hurt.
You get those?
Um,
what's the thing on your heel when it
hurts?
No,
no.
I mean I'm feel the rocks on the rocks.
It's just toughening up my feet.
So it's doing,
it's making my feet stronger.
The way it's been described to me is
that your foot,
when you're in a regular shoe,
your foot is in a cast.
And that,
uh,
just like how if you ever had a broken
arm,
you get that castle farm has atrophied
or your legs actually.
Yeah,
for sure.
You have the same thing with your foot.
Your foot is walking around in this cast
all the time,
so it doesn't exercise all the strong
strong muscle groups in your toes and,
and these things,
they actually lost a class action
lawsuit I think because a bunch of
people took them.
They started running and doing a bunch
of shit and they got hurt.
Really.
So much assumption out here,
can't believe I do.
It's like,
cool,
this is not important.
Fuck you.
I'm class action because people are
getting hurt trying to run on fucking
boulders and shit.
Well,
because they lost the lawsuit because
people were suing them because they said
that they,
they made a unwarranted claims or
something along those lines.
That's what's killing us.
E-Cigarettes really,
because they were like safer than
smoking.
And the FDA's like,
wait,
why do you think that?
Obviously like,
no,
you can't just go obviously the medical
side,
you have to like test it.
Yeah.
They don't have years and years of
cancer behind prove.
I mean they,
they could easily be causing some new
kind of cancer.
I mean,
who the fuck knows?
I think it also be way safer,
but just like you got to prove that's
it.
So um,
with these shoes,
I'm one of the things that people who
are big proponents of.
I'm like this Guy Mark [inaudible] who
is the author of the primal blueprint.
He's a really well respected endurance
athlete and then went on to become like
coach and does a lot of online stuff and
writes books about diet and exercise.
He says you gotta take it slow because
essentially your foot is just not used
to really working.
That's used to being protected by your
toe.
Basing out for balance,
especially with these things,
these things that your toes are all
individually moving and essentially it's
just providing you a little bit of a
thick layer underneath to keep you from
getting cut.
Oh,
but your foot does all the work.
I've met these people in Cambodia that
had a on this island,
this is a parasite that lives there and
um,
they just get it and you see this worm
inside your leg and shit.
Oh,
Jesus.
Yeah.
And you got to go to the hospital and
take it out.
But like a or maybe drink some stuff.
I forget how they got rid of it,
but it's just like everybody was like,
it's not going to happen to me.
And then like,
yeah,
it happens to,
you just need a little bit of scratch as
you're walking nearby them and they're
like,
we're in a little.
Yeah,
you can see it inside your skin,
like moving.
Oh,
I can fucking wrath of Khan.
I had this guy on my podcast recently,
Dr Robert Sapolsky and he's an expert
in,
um,
well he's an expert.
A lot of things.
But one of the things he specializes in
is this,
a parasite called toxoplasma.
That's the Brazilian one,
right?
Yeah.
And he was freaking me the fuck out you.
Will you have it?
I've definitely have it.
Yeah.
If it's that anger thing.
Oh yeah.
The crazy thing to race.
What did you just get mad and fuck all
the time to get mad and fuck disease?
Yeah.
It's um,
he says 50 percent of the population has
it in the world.
Yep.
Fifty percent.
And nobody in Poland?
No one.
No.
I'm just like,
I'm just stereotyping.
It's so crazy how it works,
how it infects the cat and the only
place where it can reproduce this in a
cat's digestive tract.
And that's how it forced itself to
survive.
Yeah.
By tricking a rat into going near a cat,
it kills the rats.
Fear of cats.
See Again?
You see the little hairs here and there?
Yeah.
That's an animal that's killing animals.
Most likely that's a kylie,
but that's pretty big.
That's,
that's some big shit there.
Bears out here.
No,
not out here,
but not too far away.
Santa Barbara has bears are the rattle
snakes here.
Got To be that right?
I ran over one.
What?
Um,
yeah,
with my dogs a couple years back.
Was a waterfall.
Yeah.
Um,
where I thought it was a stick.
It was a big stick across the ground and
as I was jumping over,
the dog's already passed it.
I realized in the Air I was jumping over
off of that huge dude,
but they're looking at,
you know,
anybody just look and try to stay there
as long as you could know.
I put the dogs away because that was
when I had pit bulls and they'd go after
three times by rattlesnakes.
Yep.
I just have to take them to the doctor
and it's super expensive to get
antivenom.
Damn huge pain.
The Dick,
you know.
Um,
but where were we?
Oh yeah.
Toxoplasma.
Yeah.
It affects the rats,
convinces the rats.
That cat's.
Not only does it take away the fear of
cats,
but it rewires their sexual reward
system and makes them attracted to cat
piss.
That's amazing.
They get hard ons.
Since that's like if there was nobody to
reproducing.
If there was some disease,
it was like no,
fat checks are pretty.
Yeah.
And then you would just have to go for
them.
We just like,
have you heard of this new tick?
There's a new,
a new tick,
a disease for sure.
The answer is no,
I have not heard of it.
Well,
it gives you a meat allergy and it's
spreading through Texas,
so it's called the lone star tick.
So you're allergic to meat after you've
got it.
Literally.
And then what does that do?
Well,
there's a,
there's a chemical called Alpha Gal.
It's like a alpha go lactamase or some
shit and forget how to say it,
but this stuff is in this tick bite and
when it gets into your system it makes
you literally allergic to meat.
And so people who were like rabid
carnivores,
radiolab did an art or a podcast about
it.
And the podcast is called Alpha Alphago.
Alphago,
Alpha Gal.
Gal like a girl.
Yeah.
And so it makes religion to meet.
So to what end?
What purpose?
There's no purpose.
It's just,
it's like lyme disease.
It's a side effect of getting bit by a
tick.
He's Cunty bugs a ton of our bullshit.
Too many men.
If they teamed up.
Yeah.
I started thinking about it when people
said like,
could you be like 12,
12 year olds?
Fuck up 12,
12 year old.
Okay,
sure.
Maybe 100 percent.
What if they're organized?
I don't know.
They don't have a chance.
If they all come at you at once and they
don't care about getting beat up.
First of all,
everybody cares about getting beat up.
You're talking about non humans now.
Well wait,
what if you start training them at a
young age?
I'm going to fuck them up.
They don't have a chance.
The first one's going to get kicked
into.
A person's going to get kicked hard for
sure.
And then panic and then I'm just going
to start smashing,
so.
Okay.
That's a $200.
Go right through those cons.
Yeah.
They're just like,
hey,
go beat up joe.
And whoever beats him up gets a
lollipop.
You don't take those guys,
but if it's a trained army of 12 year
olds,
they're fucked because I'm trained.
Listen,
if I had a fight,
me and 10 other dudes were gonna fight a
500 pound man.
That's more coyotes.
Shit.
That was a weird looking ones.
It's all berry.
Yeah.
Eat Berries.
They eat a lot of berries.
Um,
if I had to,
uh,
get 10 friends.
Yeah.
And we had a fight,
a 500 pound hulking man,
we'd be fucked.
Who'd be fucked?
We'd be fucked.
We didn't,
wouldn't have a chance.
What about 12 like Duncan trussell's.
Could you take that a little bit bigger
than his current form?
Current Florence absolutely wouldn't
have a chance.
One of them in front of me at some point
and all you have to do is hit that one
and the other ones are gonna panic.
That's why I never said about the Bruce
Lee movies when they would come out of
one of the time.
Exactly.
And maybe sometimes two at a time,
but never in the same.
Like it was just like wagon grab them,
just grab them.
The problem with Duncan as he wouldn't
be able to really do any damage.
If he got close,
he could punch your square in the jaw
and you'd laugh it off like via Berakah.
Yeah.
You'd be like,
okay,
that all you got?
Yeah.
But if you had to deal with like three
burke crisis,
right?
I'm probably going to get fucked up.
Yeah.
Even if he's not a trained fighter,
most likely you'd have to.
You have to really make sure you connect
hard on that first guy.
The first guy you have to take out
immediately.
Hard as hard as you can.
Yeah.
You have to blast him.
You'll also have to show consequences
for everybody else to let them know,
like,
hey,
you're not going to get a free shot on
me.
I'm going to fucking kill you.
Stomp their face in as our down.
Oh yeah.
I'd say my dad's what?
They taught him,
the Israeli army and these are the old
days,
you know?
And they said there's a good chance it's
going to be you with no weapons up
against two Arabs with no weapons.
Like that's a decent chance.
And he said,
here's what you do.
Look in both in.
You look at the one on the whatever on
the right,
let's say,
and then you just kick the one on the
left and the balls as hard as you can,
this as hard as you can and try to
incapacitate him that way.
He goes one-on-one,
you'll beat any Arab,
just have this attitude.
Well,
they're so well trained to.
The Arabs were Kinda like,
you know,
militia army's a fucking,
calisthenics,
you know,
and the fucking jungle gym to train and
they goes,
you'd be him and then come back and kill
the first one.
Hmm.
Interesting.
Did you have to raise a kitten and then
kill it?
So favorite then make you raise it like
the eggs and in home ec?
Yeah.
And then,
uh,
then you have to bring a snack,
right to break his neck at the present.
A healthy kitten that you've raised for
weeks.
Wow.
That beautiful pond.
Get a lot of crayfish in those ponds.
Really?
Yeah.
When it was raining a lot,
this would turn into a river and uh,
like during the middle of the spring
hopes the middle of the spring.
It was a pretty thick with water down
here.
It would go all the way up to that high
spot over there.
We're over there.
She was just like see those rocks a
little bit higher,
like maybe two or three feet above where
the water was pretty awesome.
But that was just when all the water was
coming down from the mountains.
It all comes down here,
Huh?
Yeah.
It was the runoff from the snow.
Then followed by the heavy rains that we
had for days and days.
We had some amazing rainfall.
Really?
Yeah.
To the point where my basement got
flooded.
Really?
Yup.
Where people like a complaining about it
in Hollywood because all they say is we
need rain,
rain,
and then it happens two years later and
like enough with this dude,
three days in a row,
people are going to move to this room.
I'm like,
shut the fuck up.
No one feels the Goddamn a drought in
Hollywood.
Exactly.
It was just like,
Nah,
I'm going to run my water while I turn
the water on the waters road here.
And then there's no corn suddenly.
And you're like,
what happened?
Well,
I feel like people need some kind of
weather in order to really appreciate
the good,
the good stuff.
Like you need some rain.
Like that was like growing up in the
east coast.
It snowed.
So when summertime came around,
you appreciated that you were in your
shorts,
like you the time it got to the 60 and
you're like,
let's do this.
Fuck,
good song.
That's my favorite thing about New York.
Everyone feels it together and then when
it's finally gets warmed,
the whole cities,
like,
we did it.
You guys,
we survived.
Some of us,
not all of us.
And then it's like,
let's enjoy it.
Let's go out.
There's something to that for sure.
In a over where I was,
there's three seasons that have for
winter,
summer and rainy.
Oh really?
Yeah.
And when it's rainy season,
it's rainy season.
Well,
I think that it's just like every single
day.
Wow.
Yeah,
I think that's good.
I think it's indicative of sort of
family with what's wrong with
California.
We.
Yeah.
We were like spoiled rich kids with a
trust fund baby.
What happened?
Lizard fucking loser.
But it came right at me.
Jesus who's threatening,
um,
would just trust fund babies for whether
we're just so used to everything being
amazing in January.
All you need is a t shirt.
The fuck is that in January?
Man?
What the fuck?
Skiing and I hung out in jeans and a tee
shirt.
It's insane.
I'm out.
These trails is great.
A great.
Nobody's ever on them too.
I go run.
And these things do the same for the
weekends.
Oh yeah.
That was to me,
it's like I'll never try to do anything
on a weekend because that's when the
amateurs come out.
Right.
I'm like runyon.
Yeah.
It's like [inaudible] don't even.
Don't just wait til Monday.
Yeah.
Because there's got to be a benefit to
doing this kind of Weirdo jobs.
Yeah.
And that is,
you know,
play golf on a Wednesday.
Right?
Exactly.
The appeal goes stuff,
not just the little window until we go
back,
go,
oh yeah,
that's all a pill on the way back.
This is the first appeal.
Now this is the fucking hiking man.
Yeah.
It's great exercise to man.
You get some sun on your skin and hiking
with weight on your backs.
Amazing.
Good for your legs.
So I did a three day hike and me and
mark and some company like take your
stuff to look at another location and
all you do is go with like a daypack oh
yeah,
yeah.
But you know,
15 pounds,
15 pounds is what you got on you and
it's great.
You come out of it so fucking refreshed.
I feel good.
And just like,
okay,
now it's time for a beer.
I've earned it.
You want to pause before the uphill?
We can.
Where's the OCO right there?
Well,
usually around here if I'm running a
mile and a half.
Yeah,
I stopped right at that crest.
You run all this around.
All this and those roots.
Yup.
Wow.
Yeah.
I go hard,
dude.
I'm trying to get in really good shape
for hunting because I'm the kind of
shape I'm in.
It's like Jujitsu shape,
kickboxing shape,
weight lifting shape,
quick hits,
quick bursts instead of just a big
difference between that and hiking,
hiking in the mountains in particular.
Then never give up a golf ball here.
Somebody,
a Paul is up there.
I know you a weird thing about litter,
which I
don't,
but when I'm in the fucking woods,
that's when I have the weird thing.
I always feel like her math and up one
item.
People get weird with me about how weird
I am with litter.
Weird about cigarette butts on sunset
boulevard.
Yeah.
It's like,
do they have Mexicans for this coming?
I chase receipts down the street that
are years.
Yeah,
and I hate.
I hate the idea that I'm literally.
I remember being in Denver wants with
the,
with the,
with the.
When we toured like a policy we get mad
at me and red band was like,
don't fucking throw water on the ground
in beautiful denver thing.
People with cigarettes.
Do they just throw it on the ground
step?
If it goes out the window of their car,
they just don't want to see it.
It's out of sight,
out of mind.
Oh,
what is that?
Is that it took some kind of bug.
It is a tick dude who killed that
fucker.
Why did you.
Why did you kill it?
Well,
there's a million of them.
Go and bite your mom.
Just like Peter Parker,
everyone,
Peter Parker that got killed.
Uncle Ben.
Yeah.
He let him go.
Let them go.
You're right at that ticket.
Going to have lyme disease.
We're definitely gonna.
Be Thinking about it.
Do you ever go back and I get that
fucking meet disease.
That'd be so bad at you.
If it's.
That chick sounds down,
jump right back up.
Find that content.
No Way.
At some time you could find them if you
were totally dedicated.
You think so?
Yeah.
He didn't go that far,
but he's still a small foot square.
That was a tick though,
right?
I think it was flat.
Red looked very ticklish.
Now,
luckily for us,
there's not a whole lot of lyme disease
out here,
but it does exist and it's spreading.
What happens if you have a tick that's
no longer disease,
but it still gets you just make you
weak.
It makes you itchy.
Just county little bugs trying to suck
blood out of you.
I pulled them off.
My Dog's fault.
They swell up.
Yeah.
They swell up with blood and they're
just,
Oh,
they're disgusting.
I was in show doc,
speaking of litter.
Where's that?
Southern?
Southern Vietnam.
Ho Man.
They take about 10 hour bus down.
Damn.
Yeah man.
It's traveling,
but there's just like floating forest
where these trees grow out of this.
Like just this water and then there's
like lily pads everywhere so it just
looks like grass and trees coming out.
But you're on a boat through it.
Yeah,
it's pretty great.
It's pretty great.
But then we get off the boat and get
onto the dock and this fucking Chinese
guard.
They're the worst.
Travelers are the worst.
He just dumped a cigarette and you're
like,
dude,
come on.
Nobody's here man.
There's no street sweeping here.
We're in the fucking woods.
Did you say something to them?
No,
of course not.
Oh,
I don't want conflict,
but also it's like,
what am I going to learn?
Chinese travelers are the worst that.
That's why the Great Barrier Reef was
dead really?
Because he said,
please don't put on sunscreen and
Chinese people.
Like,
I'm just gonna put on all the sunscreen
I have.
How about that?
No kidding.
So they say don't put on sunscreen in
the area of the great barrier while
you're scuba diving.
Also,
you're covered in a wetsuit,
so like you don't really need just a
little on your neck and Parul on like 45
minutes before.
So that's what's killing the
reef is sunscreens are dead reef now
it's dead.
We're going to clear.
Wow.
Which means it might be more than 50
percent debt or something,
but like it's been declared dead reef.
Holy Shit.
One of the greatest things in our
fucking world.
Holy Shit.
Killed by sunscreen and man's
encroachment.
Dude.
I used to get sunscreen in my eyes when
I used to.
Fear factor.
I would do fear factor in that had come
to the store and I still have sunscreen
on my forehead and I would start
sweating and the sunscreen getting my
eyes and it was fucking terrible.
Would stink so bad.
I remember being on stage is crying.
Tears run down later.
Oh,
because you have it all from the day?
Yeah,
I had it on during the day.
Then at the store at night,
I'd be tearing.
I have to explain to people.
Sorry,
I was shooting outside all day and I got
sunscreen in my fucking eyes.
That shit's terrible for you.
Can't smoke at her Kenyon a cigarette or
we'd come on man.
I don't smoke cigarettes.
Oh yeah,
you can smoke weed.
We could smoke some weed.
Arusha,
fear brought weed on a hike.
I like it.
I've cut down a lot on weed.
You should try weed and yoga.
Dude.
I did a bunch of yoga out there.
Did you like 12 times?
You'll like it.
Yeah.
I got to the point where there's one of
my goals.
I wanted to touch my toes and I started
right below the knee and when I did it,
like I found it.
I can almost touch your toes now.
Yeah,
that's a lot more flexible than you.
That's great.
Yeah.
That's one of the best things for your
health.
And then just while I was on boats and
shit,
I was just like,
do it a little bit,
you know,
and you take these classes.
They would teach me some moves and
you're like,
oh reproduce that when I'm fucking
sitting waiting for a bus.
Well,
you don't have a phone,
but if you did have a phone,
you just use your app or a cover
classes.
Yeah.
Well you.
If you have a computer,
obviously when you go on the road or
even at your house,
just turn on a yoga program on now.
Youtube,
just someone who's got a yoga workout.
You follow the yoga workout.
It's simple.
You don't have to go anywhere or you
have to do anything.
Oh yeah.
It's amazing and once you learn it then
you can get an you.
I know you don't use a phone,
but I have an app on my phone that shows
me the move and then times me really
tells me to stop.
Yeah.
Good.
My ipad.
I could do that at home.
Yeah.
Do that.
There were a bunch of things where I'm
like,
I have to miss a phone for that form,
for that.
Well,
what you're doing is admirable though.
You realize your limitations.
I've slacked off heavy on social,
social media backed way.
What?
For what reasons?
Get work done right.
You do understand that that draws you
out.
My writing has gotten much,
much more prolific.
It much better.
I was thinking about your improvement or
the way you pluck out hit your last
special.
You know what I think of it right?
[inaudible] you think a lot of that's
got.
I mean some people said what about
podcasts is always working as mind was
like,
but he was already doing podcasts.
Podcast for years.
You think some of this back of the store
checking out just in front of people on
the back of the store cracked me up.
You crack me up,
cracked me up another solid notch.
You see some other great comics.
Yeah.
Hmm.
Interesting.
Being back there too.
I got energized and
then getting all the support from all
the people because I'm back there again
too and being around like a real
camaraderie.
Seen a real a scene of peers where I
wasn't.
I didn't have that before.
I was just showing up and I would do
gigs and I get out of there like with
Diaz,
you know,
I do other road with you guys and I'd
have fun then,
but when I was working out at the ha ha
or the Improv,
I just go and do my and get the fuck out
of.
There was,
yeah,
at the store I'm hanging,
you know,
hours for hours to one with the car and
he says to not yell or whatever last
week.
Yeah.
It was the first time I'd been there in
a long time.
We used to go there all the time,
all the time.
For me it was like more than a decade.
More than inside a cornice.
How long were you gone for?
Seven years.
Wow.
Yeah.
Crazy.
Wow.
Seven long ass years.
But I had really great sets,
really did good specials and bats
specials when I was gone,
but the bad special that I did wasn't
bad,
but it wasn't real good.
It was 2012.
Ramped me up for the 2014 one which was
talking about because in space,
which was really good.
And then that ramp me up for triggered,
which is probably my best one,
but I think this new one is going to be
better.
People are talking about your newstuff
the store.
I haven't seen her.
No,
but uh,
the door I like.
Oh,
it's like on another level now.
I think it was like,
I don't know what it is.
It's not like rockstars will like 25 as
their prime.
I don't know man.
I'm just,
I'm,
I'm not slacking off.
I think that's what it is.
I think we get to this point where we're
dedicated to something and we get good
at it or we get successful at it at
least.
And then once you get some adulation you
sort of relaxed.
Like I kinda got it.
I know what I'm doing now,
now let me fucking go.
Yeah.
Nobody's gonna make me think about
quitting.
If I do a bad set that needs
improvement.
So now my,
my opinion is totally different now it's
all about,
look,
I know that the only way I'm really
happy is if my is good.
Like if everything in my life is going
great,
but I bomb,
I am not happy.
Okay.
So how do I fix that?
Well,
I have to fucking work more at my stand
up.
I have to just whatever it is.
So I wrote down on my computer and on my
phone a schedule that I have to adhere
to every week and one of them is I write
five hours every week,
a week ago.
It's attainable.
You don't go crazy like seinfeld where
it's like eight hours a day.
It's like I'm not gonna hit that and
then I'll fail.
Then they tell people not to try to quit
smoking their first year because they're
like,
you're,
it's way harder.
So you're going to feel that and then
you're going to.
It's gonna make it think like fuck it.
Just go back to everything.
Yeah,
like don't even try that.
So that's where I think make attainable
goals.
Uh,
yeah.
I also set attainable goals for like
fitness too,
like the amount of times a week I do
yoga,
the amount of times a week I run.
And I think all those,
they like,
they,
they build on each other,
like the momentum of them and it makes
the stand up better.
And then also like just thinking about
the standup,
like thinking about the set,
trying to make it better.
Trying to like,
how much of this is bullshit,
how much of this is ego?
How much of this is just,
I haven't looked at it enough,
I need to get it better.
How much of this is.
I only came out of this one way and I
stuck with that way.
Why don't I come at it another way?
Like,
I've been doing that a lot now.
That's how I see a tail doing that where
it's like,
let me change one word around now.
Back now,
back again when it's like,
I dunno,
just because I've been doing doesn't
make it right.
Yeah.
You never know dude.
Like sometimes you'll,
you'll be excited and you'll switch it
and it'll be way better.
But you don't know until you until you
like get out of there,
you've got to do it.
I always thought that's what hell Bobby
Lee back for a long time was that he was
always like showcase for pussy,
so it was like,
this is the best it is right now.
I'm not going to fucking go one time and
he's a great comic,
but like he's not going to risk one time
trying to differently or try new shit.
Yeah,
I've talked to bobby about it.
I think bobby,
I'm just never did a special.
And if he did a special he'd be forced
to write new stuff and I think his new
stuff would really ultimately be way
better than the stuff he's doing.
Not the stuff he's doing isn't really
good.
It really.
He's really funny.
But I think bobby has ladies are more
developed comic genius potential and
he's just a little nervous about putting
stuff out there.
I think so.
Um,
I don't know,
man.
I just been paying more attention to it.
It's been trying to pay a lot of
attention to it.
Just put your phone through it.
When you drive,
you think about when you listen to the
recordings all the time,
like sometimes I'm listening to music
and I said,
you know what,
I should be doing work.
I should be doing work,
let's dissect this fucking set and I
don't want to and I don't want to listen
to podcasts.
Listen to your podcast or Duncan or
burgers or something like that,
or Joey,
but I'll,
I'll,
I'll go over my head again.
I'll figure it out.
You know,
figure it out.
Yoshi said to me was who?
Who's The guy?
Jets?
Small five to Japanese.
Go in the old bomb squad.
He was there.
Yeah.
When he was like,
when I started and he was like,
I thought it had succeed,
you know,
talking about what you though.
But he goes,
here's what you gotta do you gotta think
about it all the time.
Like I think about digital all the time.
You'll get better.
And I was like,
oh,
I can't.
I already got something for that.
Yeah,
that's a real problem.
You have to have to figure out like how
much energy you put into other stuff
from me,
whether it's archery or used to be pool
pool was the worst because you can't
really do archery eight hours a day.
You'll get too tired,
but you can play pool eight hours day
easy.
She's got a stretcher back.
Once in a while you just get more and
more cycle about it and then it becomes
like,
okay,
how much of this is benefiting me?
Is it benefiting me spending all this
time tweaking about balls going into
holes or is it like a big distraction
because I don't want to put that same
amount of time into writing or into
think about standing mean honestly.
There's a diminishing point of returns
at some point,
you know,
but a thumb of anything else you think
about is time.
You're not spending thinking about.
Exactly.
Now there might be,
like we said,
nothing more than like 34 hours a week
would be successful,
so taking away that time is okay above
34.
Exactly.
Yeah.
It's interesting man.
It's like you also want recreation,
recreation,
work your mind out a little bit.
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
Like I'm going to reload this or say
that I'm good.
Even like video games.
I think if you.
As long as you don't get crazy with
them,
I think they're probably fun and
beneficial,
but the problem is if you start like
super getting into Jujitsu the way you
are in a comedy,
you're comedy's going to take second
position.
Scada York,
when she won that award for whatever
dancer in the dark,
if you work the singer,
she did acting once,
half the awards.
Ha.
Yeah.
And then the will you can do that more.
And she was,
she said she felt like cheating on
music.
Ooh,
powerful bjork.
I saw her house in Iceland.
Yeah.
I saw a beat up a photographer and a
video.
Someone was found around taking pictures
of her and she started beating around
York.
Yeah.
Giving them a new bowls punches.
Some lady was like totally disrespecting
her.
She was just like,
like had a camera like interface and
she's filming her and I guess words.
I don't know the exact scenario,
but they had words,
really.
A Bjork Bjork what?
After that on her,
I believe.
Let me pull up that video.
Which Jamie,
pull up that video.
I'm a little high right now.
I don't really totally remember the
story,
but I'm pretty sure she beat some
persons.
I would love to see.
Who would you most like to see fight who
has no fighting experience?
Anything like that.
Like like a Angelina Jolie and trump to
the death.
So the death.
Absolutely.
Whoever you choose to do that.
I was going to say Angela and Jennifer
Aniston.
Wow.
Damn fighting.
That would be vicious.
Vicious.
Angelina Jolie's got crazy on her side
though,
right?
I think Angelina Jolie.
We take it easily now that I mentioned.
Now they think about it.
She's got crazy.
I was crazy.
She drinks blood.
Yeah.
She had an amulet filled with billy.
Bob Thorton's.
She kept around.
How do you survive that as a career
that's full on publicly crazy.
She's so gangster that's full on out
there.
You don't want to fight that girl.
They'd be like fighting a wild cat.
She bite you for sure.
For sure.
Dude,
you're getting bit.
She's probably gonna fuck you up.
You're going to realize you took her
lightly as you're going unconscious,
so I see where I went wrong.
Mashing your head off the side of a
sync.
I feel like would attack.
She's fucking move like,
whoa.
I didn't see that coming.
She would attack.
You ever see I let them in the remake of
that vampire movie.
Oh yeah.
You don't want that girl jumped on that
guy under the bridge.
That's what Angelina Jolie would attach
to you.
That's a good movie.
I forgot that movie.
I saw the original one too and I thought
this movie is amazing.
And then I was like,
well they're gonna fuck up the remake.
And they didn't.
They didn't.
They didn't fuck it up at all.
Like low budget.
Why?
I don't know.
They just nailed it.
Yeah,
it was really great.
It was good.
Even the remake was great.
Upside.
They did it.
They did it as sort of a new story,
but the same thing and you know what?
It's so hard to do a remake that it has
to be undeniable.
Right?
And so it was good that it was
undeniable and everybody's like,
that's pretty fucking good.
Do you ever see two movies are actually
terrifying.
A kid vampire and the old man who was
like loved her too because he's been
with it for whatever years.
Something about a kid vampire just
scares the fuck out of us.
Holy Shit.
It could be amongst us.
A fucking kid vampire little like four
foot tall thing run at you crazy.
I'm not allowed to hit back party.
He was like,
wait,
can I go this?
And you can't even do anything.
Anyway.
Superhuman power.
Right?
Even that little girl,
she could fuck those dudes up.
There was no chance of ever losing that
had no chance.
No Way.
Fan Pirates are like on a totally
different level.
They're not humans.
Who's that girl?
Actor.
She's good.
She's very good.
Like what I see a vampire is not like
superman though.
Know exactly what are they not.
I don't think you can take to the heart.
Yeah,
but you got to get a stake in their
heart.
Right,
so it's not that you couldn't be at that
point were not done.
He's going to kick your ass somehow or
another.
Becoming a vampire makes you way
stronger.
Do they heal like wolverine?
I don't think they get hurt,
dude.
I think until the state goes into the
heart,
you can't really hurt him.
He should wear heart plates of steel up
dude.
Like Wolverine.
Yeah.
But then they started changing that.
They started changing that,
right?
Like some of the later movies to like,
what was that movie?
Thirty days of night you guys die.
I think daily is like sunlight to kill
them with like silver or something.
Some of them they make up new rules.
Like you can kill them with silver,
you know,
like,
wait,
it's not a wearable that could do that
in a movie.
He just got to like,
oh no,
that was wrong with those people thought
it's actually this.
We got bullets with garlic in it.
You're going to kill them.
Like black.
Remember that.
Like garlic would kill them and then
they had would tip bullets.
Yeah.
So you can use machine guns on them.
Blade,
the comic book Superhero Blade had these
teak wood knives.
He had wooden knives and he would hunt
vampires.
It's stabbed them to death and they were
just had to have a wood knife.
So we got this super hard wood.
Wow.
Yeah.
That was good dude.
The idea of vampires,
I think it's haunted people forever
because I think it's what people are
capable of at their very worst.
Drinking people's blood in human,
just being inhuman.
You heard about some of the shit that
went down in Liberia.
What were during the civil war?
They were capturing children from,
from neighboring tribes would eat their
flesh.
They would eat their heart.
This guy,
there was one of the vice pieces on
Liberia where he talks about and
describes how he would do it,
how he would go to a neighboring tribe,
captured one of their children and eat
his heart.
Wow.
Yeah,
Dude.
I'm going there in December.
Oh my God.
What are you doing all right.
No,
they're done with that now.
A lot of power.
Yeah.
Your friends have all gone back.
I'm going with somebody who was from
there.
Jesus already stay home.
He's my buddy from college.
What do you mean?
Do you know how Liberia got started?
Yeah,
I just found out
we never knew that as kids,
right?
No,
no.
I didn't know about until the vice
series.
Apparently it's a.
They took a US slave colony,
freed slaves back to Africa,
Monroe,
Jesus Christ.
That's why they call their capital
Monrovia.
Liberia just means liberated and then
chaos.
Well,
yeah.
I mean,
whatever had happened later.
Yeah,
but I mean how could.
How crazy is it that that became one of
the most chaotic spots in Africa?
Wow.
I mean,
imagine someone,
npr.
There's like 10 years ago.
They're like,
oh no,
it's safe now.
They want people to come and how dare
they start walking back?
I don't know shit about Liberia by the
way.
If you're from Liberia,
I'm just talking Jamie.
Pull that up.
Place Jimmy.
We'll go this way.
Oh,
I thought it was a loop.
head rush.
It can me a second.
You know where you are.
Get a head rush.
Damn.
We went deep.
Stood up too fast.
Oh yeah.
I got too high.
That's what it was.
That's been nice at air.
Oh yeah.
I have that in New York,
right?
Not really.
You get stuff here or there,
but not the selection and the amount and
the fucking so serious illness about it.
So silly.
Open it up.
Stop.
Yeah.
Plus I was the only back for like a
month,
so it's like haven't really been smoking
that much.
Nice.
Is the land of it?
Yeah.
I give Colorado number one.
Oh,
Colorado is way ahead of callum
Washington state to attend like the way
the Norco and then Soco.
Yeah.
Well you know what?
It's like Washington state or Oregon in
the summer in the mountains of Oregon
gets real flush.
Hard to beat.
Yeah.
I feel like in Oregon everyone has their
own plant in their backyard or they want
to be like,
hey,
try mine.
Try Mine.
Yeah.
Those people aren't fucking around.
I'm actually,
I read an article and it said that they
were not fucking around.
Wow.
Officially.
Yeah.
They come out.
The article is entitled or they fucking
around.
Yeah.
All those Pacific northwest people,
they know how to grow some weed.
Yeah.
Jesus,
by the way,
my specialists out right now.
Today?
Yes.
Today.
Oh,
sorry.
Put this out.
Isn't really a double negative.
It's called one side.
It's present it to you guys so people
can start streaming it right away right
now too.
Yeah.
That's awesome.
You happy with the way everything worked
out to fuck you?
Beautiful.
Fuck yeah.
This is exactly what I had to look at.
Envision on some sort of digital type.
You know,
where you could get one episode on the
other.
Right?
Right.
Back to back.
Just click on them.
It's two different specials but similar.
That's awesome.
Yeah.
And then the actual special park came
out really good.
But I worked at hard talking to you
about it too.
I took all those intermissions in,
uh,
in Scandinavia.
And then you were like,
you gave me some good advice.
You're like,
that's fucking.
They used to it out there,
man.
Do it here.
Yeah.
So I tried to run it here a bunch so I
got the hang of it.
So was nothing new in this weird,
you know,
for the sake of weirdness.
Right.
Well,
it's very experimental man.
I mean you're,
you're doing a lot of cool shit.
You haven't fun.
Yeah.
You know,
that's what I get out of your podcast to
your podcast is an enthusiastic view of
the world.
I mean that's,
you're the end of the day.
You're a very enthusiastic person.
You liked a lot of cool shit.
Know,
like doing stuff,
you know,
and for me like knowing you as long as I
have known you when you weren't doing so
good and you are depressed,
it's so amazing seeing you.
So happy,
isn't it weird bands.
Great.
Forget about the starting to,
to good in comedy and also like
depression to like fucking fine,
you know.
And I mean I'm sure there's a bunch of
different factors
physically,
right?
Yeah,
yeah.
Yeah.
And I think uh,
I know you don't like this,
but I think those pills helped me.
No,
no man.
You're one of the best examples ever.
You and beast.
You remember Brian and war machine.
He also.
Oh wait,
no,
I thought it went wrong.
Sorry.
What do you remember,
Brian?
From a beast from 10th planet?
Yeah.
I sort of remember him.
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
Remember handing her bad ass.
A Jujitsu player.
Sick guard well helped him,
Bro.
Yeah,
yeah.
People want to put everything like black
and whites and it's like when they say
overprescribed,
that doesn't mean it's always going to
be bad.
Yeah,
exactly.
You know,
that just means too much.
It's almost like with anything,
it's like everybody that we know that
has had pain pill problems,
they took the pain pills because they
worked.
Right.
You just kept going crazy.
I mean if we're having a brain fart.
Yeah.
I had to check himself in.
Oh well dude,
buddy,
Brendan Schaub had an issue.
His friends really had to take the pills
from him who's taking them every day,
several times a day for like months and
his friends came over to south side.
Hey Dude,
dude,
no more of these.
And he said he,
you know,
he had to kick it and it was hard.
But he's a disciplined athlete.
He's a strong minded dude.
You know,
he could kick it,
but maybe if you're like a week of
willed person that's more inclined to
give into things.
Maybe you know,
maybe we gave you or maybe if you have a
chemical imbalance,
it makes you look really super.
We'd come off it.
They're like,
okay,
here's the deal.
You got to come off it real slow.
See I was on 100,
let me think if I'm right and 50
milligrams of the Superman.
And they were like,
all right,
and that's what we found that through
experimentation and then they go,
when you coming off it,
quarter 1:25
for a week everyday for a week
and then always monitor yourself.
If you start thinking about suicide at
all,
you got to call me immediately.
Go back on a regular dose.
Jesus Christ,
they tell you to like really like be
careful,
but not everybody does.
And they go,
fuck it.
I'm done with that.
That was my last position I want to go
back to write,
right?
Well I think the better example might be
the pain pill thing because it's painful
for them to stop.
Oh right.
You're like,
they ate.
I mean,
I think they're all crazy.
It's everything has.
It's this way.
Everything has its own crazy.
Hang on,
hang on,
let me look over there.
What's math?
I want to say where this cliff cool.
I mean everything has its own crazy.
But think those,
uh,
pain pills from just the experiences of
people that I've talked to,
not firsthand stuff obviously,
but they seem to grip you so hard.
People just can't shake them.
A lot of fighters,
man,
a lot of fighters get hurt,
have surgery from all the and then take
a few pain pills and then all of a
sudden they got a problem.
You know,
especially if you're a person who maybe
had a problem in the past and he took a
break and you were clean and sober,
living the mma life and then suddenly,
yeah,
and then you hurt your back or
something.
He needed the painkillers.
It just took them.
Don't worry,
I'll get off of them.
I mean there's,
it's just,
you're,
you're challenging people with these
things in a way that I don't necessarily
know if it's fair.
You're challenging them with chemical
addictions to trust for it yourself.
You handle yourself.
It's,
I mean,
I definitely think you should have the
right to do whatever you want,
but I'm thinking like,
because it messes with your brain
chemistry though.
It's like asking a drunk person.
Are you okay to drive?
And it's like they have the worst
judgment right now.
Yeah.
We'll ask them.
You're taking someone and putting him on
a chemical fucking addiction to
something and then say like,
yeah,
but use your regular mind.
Yeah.
You're putting them on a crazy cocktail.
You're saying,
Oh,
you got pain here.
Have some opiates all day and you're
just going to be like in a heroin fog
and then maybe you'll get.
You'll settle into that heroin fog.
I know a dude has got a fucked up back
and I know when he's on.
Really?
Oh yeah,
man.
I talked to him.
It's just whole weirded out because we
will take a selfie.
I'm.
This is not a good place to take a
selfie.
Sat over there.
Why not?
Okay.
By that wall come up.
I believe you
to this gorgeous out here.
I don't want to get these feats slippery
because I got this weight on my back.
Oh yeah.
Oh,
here we go.
Alright.
Delayed.
Yeah.
Yeah,
sure.
No,
I don't have no phone capable of taking
this picture.
That is,
by the way,
anyone thinking about getting a flip
phone?
Everyone has a camera.
If you guys.
They were want to be with that one.
Yeah,
that's true.
Yeah.
I like that white Bush thing on the side
of the mountain.
The white Bush.
Yeah.
The thing I think coming out.
What is that?
I don't know.
La Sex.
Some avatar shit.
Yeah.
Real life.
It's so weird when you look at plant
life and the variety we get,
we just get really used to it,
but if it didn't exist,
it's like the whole world was the desert
sand dunes and you got to see something
like this.
You'd be stunned by the amount of
radiant energy it gives.
You know,
if you,
if the whole world is a desert and all
of a sudden they brought you into like a
creek like this,
like he'd be like,
Holy Shit.
Can I touch it?
Oh my God.
It's alive around me.
These plants,
their life force,
their saying hi.
The forest says hi to some of us are not
that good at listening,
man.
I tried to give as many orthodox Jewish
friend to do mushrooms and he was like,
I don't think God wants me to do that.
I'm like,
no,
you're wrong.
That's fucking telephone that God left
for you to talk to him.
That's a good way of putting it.
I kept saying,
you got to pick it up.
Why else would he put it here?
That's a good way of putting.
It wasn't manmade.
Dude.
That's actually a very strong argument.
Oh God made it stupid thing on the other
side of the glass.
I'm fucking.
When you're bitten someone in prison.
Yep.
Pick up the phone.
Talk,
pick up the phone.
You might be right,
dude.
Write that down.
Somebody texted it to you.
No.
For real though,
right?
They're the only people that disagree
with that or people that don't do
mushrooms or haven't done it.
Yeah.
So Neil said that he took them.
We did them in banff last year and he
said he loves to go to Amsterdam,
and he took like,
I think like 10 grams,
10 grams or something like that.
That's way too much.
And then he was like,
I didn't like it was too much for me.
I'm like,
I know no one should do that much.
Well,
whatever.
Not the real people,
but like nobody knew.
Right.
I bet those crazy psycho night type
characters.
I can't handle 10 grounds to three
eighths.
Yeah,
that's a lot for almost a quarter.
Three quarters of a quarter.
Is that.
Yep.
You did ask him.
He never talked about that.
Did what?
What'd you think about that?
Very interesting.
How different,
how different,
how same.
It's very different.
It's um,
I didn't take a large dose.
Yeah.
I took enough to enjoy it was really.
What does that mean in real terms?
What a tab or something or drop or
something.
I don't know,
a piece of an altoid I'm not.
It was in a candy form,
but um,
what I got out of it was that all of
these things,
whether it's is a great time to talk
about this when we're on the full,
all of these things are somehow related
with things.
All of these psychedelics,
even pot,
even edible pod mushrooms,
Lsd,
all of them are taking to you like
separate apartment rooms in God's
gigantic apartment building.
They'll take you to different places.
Like dmd takes you to a different room.
Mushrooms have a different party show
you,
but it's all in the same,
same realm.
Somewhere go somewhere,
come on in this house with my.
It's not here.
You know,
and acid is definitely almost like what
acid makes you feel like is that it
wants to sort of change what here is,
you know what I mean?
It was like,
what did you say?
I know I think I have a pretty objective
view of how I see reality.
And then acid goes,
bitch,
you don't know shit because it's not
that.
There's something else.
We could change it to something totally
different forever and you'll be.
I know what happens.
It gets this place of,
I guess from fusses over,
so you missed it,
but still catch up.
Go Pretty.
This is,
but I've gotten to the place where it's
like,
like you see the truth a lot on
mushrooms.
Acid is a little different.
Yeah.
Well,
you know,
I felt like it was pretty introspective.
Yeah.
But it was also calming and an
interesting way,
like per perspective enhancing,
calming,
you know,
I think that where you're like
everything's gonna be okay.
Yeah.
But you see it since it was the first
time I did probably go into that with
some preconceived notions.
You never know because I'm Larry Hagman
with some notions from bell.
Let's think I did.
Yeah.
Larry Hagman from Dallas before he died.
Really just doing all these interviews
and he was talking about like important
lessons in his life.
I forget what the context was,
but he said that he took Lsd,
really Larry Hagman and that Lsd took
away his fear of dying and I,
I'll never forget that.
Like he looks so peaceful when he said
that to the lady who was interviewing
him.
I think it was a lady that's bold,
he's a fucking networker.
I've not even been a lady,
might have been a dude and I've turned
them into the lady.
Why draw your own conclusions?
But uh,
I think his,
his statements on it about it made him
not afraid of death and appreciating
like what life is and how life keeps
moving.
Making any sort of efforts to make that
legal.
I don't think so.
I think you've got to tread carefully
with all this stuff because you get one
of these jeff sessions types,
characters kits in an office and starts
Muslim buckling down on muscle and the
laws around,
they don't want state rights to take
place.
You know the elephant.
Elephant Rock in front of a lion.
Right over here.
Let's try to look like an elephant
standing in front of a lion.
That rock formation rock,
the one that looks like a nose and then
down from down from there,
it looks like an elephant.
Whereas the elephant thing with the
trunk.
Oh,
you don't see it?
Wait.
Yeah.
No,
I do see that trunk there and the like,
sheer something else shuts out.
Yeah,
yeah,
yes.
And where's the lion?
But right behind,
right behind it about to eat it.
Okay.
So what I'm saying,
yeah,
it almost looks like somebody carved
that shit.
It seems to me like a rabbit,
so I'm sure,
but it's still,
no matter what it definitely attacking
the elephant or next to him.
Yeah,
something's going on.
I just thought that.
What in God's name were we just talking
about?
We are so high right now,
vampire movies now.
We did that a long time ago.
That Hawk too.
Did you grow up with any sort of
wilderness?
Yeah,
a little bit.
Hiking and stuff like that.
It was.
Well when I lived in Newton.
Newton is like a suburb of Boston.
Yeah,
that's where I went to high school and
there was a lot of woods right across
the street from my house.
The Charles River was right across the
street from my house,
so when I was in high school,
me and my friends would go out in the
woods is right there.
It's like a river and some woods and it
went back pretty far.
We would just always go in there,
we'd go fishing and go fucking around in
the woods and really arts and Shit,
you know?
And then just be out alone yelling and
screaming.
Nobody's around you.
Yeah,
we did a lot of stupid shit.
Everybody's fine.
Yeah.
But it's um,
there was a little bit of woods like
right outside my house and it was by no
means rural.
It's a suburb,
but in the suburbs,
like around Boston,
like you get these areas that are just
big patches of woods,
just haven't done anything to it.
Well,
their forests or like different man a
lot around my place grows.
They're really.
Well let's.
It rains.
Yeah.
The woods in Maine or something like
that.
That's the fucking woods man.
I mean it's thick timber man.
Like when you drive it up,
use the highways.
Like both sides.
Just green on both sides but can't see
anything.
Woods,
woods do this.
There's a road that you take where you
were going to wear a Stephen King lived.
Oh fuck.
Did he live Salem?
No.
Dammit.
Portland,
Maine.
But I can't remember the name.
No,
he didn't live in Portland.
God dammit,
I'm so.
It was Maine though,
right?
I'll come back to it.
Yeah.
Shit was a portland,
Maine.
No,
God dammit.
Main people are going to be so mad as
Maine.
People love me.
You know that mandatory.
What we a main people,
they love Maine.
They love made to call them maniacs.
Oh really?
Yeah.
They loved Maine.
Talk Shit about me and I'll try to kill
you.
He used to go up there and talk shit
about me and they will fucking get up
and yell at.
You really can't even joke around.
I love that joke around about.
It gets so mad.
Well,
do you think where you're from?
Yeah.
From sucks.
All right.
We're like barely establishing
tribalism.
Tribes have states that are competing
with other states still.
You know,
we should probably break off,
right?
Some states have break off.
They're doing it in Europe.
They kind of like,
why are we still together?
Let's just get out of here.
You guys go on your way.
We'll go on ours.
It's all too confusing,
man.
Like I don't understand the military.
You could have like open border
crossings between the mall or something.
Yeah,
but I don't understand how.
How would that work if people just.
If we pulled the military,
is the military the military work
because then we getting invaded too
fast?
Well,
I don't think so because we still have
the same amount of people.
It's still the same.
Like the military becomes weak.
Yeah.
You have to figure out like how does it
get paid and how does it make sure that
it's just protecting us and not under
the will of anybody that has some
various intentions now that there's no
states are now.
There's no power.
You don't want to be like the country of
California man.
I guess maybe when it was back to where
it was in the beginning were the states
really felt like,
no,
I'm a Virginia and then in America,
well let's just be real.
Right?
States are bullshit.
It's the same reason why countries are
bullshit so far to high or smart parts
of Kentucky.
What happened in World War One and what
happened in World War Two states invaded
states.
It's the same thing.
It's like us being invaded by Nevada.
We would lose,
right.
It would probably have a lot of guns
were with people here.
You really think about that.
That's exactly what it's like if Germany
invades Poland.
Right?
Right.
Now they're both in the EU.
Yeah.
I mean both.
Just like right next to each other.
How far away is Germany to Poland?
Um,
how long does it take to drive Germany
to Poland?
If you had to guess drive inside a day.
Inside a day.
Product that.
Yeah.
I bet about that day war with Colorado.
Vancouver to Colorado in a day.
If you had to,
if you took adderall,
you couldn't get to.
You couldn't get to Montana from there.
From here in a day.
I don't know.
We did Vancouver to La took us like 27
hours.
We have three people.
We just kept switching,
only stopped for gas and it took like
27.
So move that line like over some and
then where's that?
Wow.
Yeah.
I think if you could just stay awake,
you can go pretty far for people
splitting it in a day.
Yeah.
If you could just stay awake.
You go pretty far in a day,
but the point is that's the people that
we'd be at war with fucking bananas.
That's what these people went to war
with other states.
Let's don't call it a state.
Don't call it a country.
It's just people on that side went to
war with people on that side.
There was as close as Nevada.
Nevada is only four hours away driving,
but it's close as Colorado at least.
Aren't you going to war with Colorado?
We might win
the.
No,
no,
no.
Do People at bail?
People just start swimming?
They're jumping in the water.
Yeah.
They've got the disposable cash.
Let's go to England to many people just
get out of there.
Just watch from mature.
Yeah,
watch it lightened flames from the
shore.
Oh,
what's a good revolution this time?
It's pretty one.
How do you think we would survive a real
revolution?
Like if something fucking bananas
happened?
Well,
you got to think they'll kill all the
dissidents as fast as they can and run
with like a voice and then shut down the
internet or at least shut down the
Internet.
Yeah.
They'd have to establish their own
internet,
right?
Yeah.
So they could use it
and then um,
that would be so evil.
Yeah.
It's so like a vendor,
but you'd be like,
find them in line.
I'm in line,
I'll do it.
What do you want?
Well,
I'll do it.
And it's like,
well,
it's on the Internet.
Back on,
please let me,
I'll,
I'll find you when we surrender,
can we get back our stuff?
And they'd be like,
I don't know if we can trust you guys.
Yeah.
You guys are already broke from the
team.
Yeah.
We're team players over here ready to
keep moving and then you get some
revolutionary is like,
I need you.
And he was like,
come on man,
I'm not fucking strong like that.
Get somebody else like in our homeland.
Remember that I only watched it until
they hung that dude.
What?
Dude?
The redhead.
Homeland?
Yeah.
Oh,
well after they hung up,
I'm like,
I'm out.
Yo,
I watched before that.
Oh,
that should have been the end of it for
sure.
Yeah.
He was the whole show.
Yeah,
that's who it's bad ass.
Yeah.
How do you kill that guy?
That's ridiculous.
How do you kill them?
Why did you kill that guy?
Contract dispute?
Probably.
It had to be.
Yeah.
Why would he leave it?
Unless you don't want to do this
anymore.
And they will be like,
all right,
we'll just end it.
They went on after that.
Yup.
What's that dude?
But that's just the money growth.
Bangor Maine,
Bangor,
Maine,
Bangor smoke.
Way Too much pot for this podcast.
I believe it was the right amount.
What?
Uh,
so how was it different than mushrooms?
Acid.
How long did it last?
Let's say that.
What'd you do it.
I just took it at the studio.
Oh,
do you want it around outside?
A little bit.
Yeah.
Okay.
Hold on.
The inside.
So maybe I didn't take enough to have
like a super profound acid experience,
you know,
but I've taken it a couple times to stay
up way late.
And the same dosage says no.
Well I took him in Edinburgh last time
and it was like me to stay until the sun
came up and then 10:00
AM not even like just when the sun came
up,
I'd be like,
just kept walking and walking.
But I found hills like this.
So I wasn't looking to go to sleep.
I was just thinking about you and you
just keep thinking though,
right?
Yeah.
Doesn't,
doesn't like edible part.
Do that too,
to just get you thinking in a pretty
profound way to.
I think with those edibles,
that word in casual conversation sound
profound.
You're just not using it for burgers and
stuff.
Said chances.
Ground beef.
It's just such a douchebag phrase.
Who?
Ropes of Shit.
And ropes ropes the ropes.
That's true.
So anyway.
Yeah.
Watch my special offer hardship.
Fear a double negative.
If you're like to tell five friends,
welcome.
10 dead flakes.
So it was good for you,
Huh?
Shit.
Yeah.
It's all the countries I went to.
They can see my special.
Yeah.
Netflix can put something on.
You can watch it at anytime.
Anyplace you have an internet
connection.
A real one.
You can't do it on a plane yet,
right?
You can watch.
You load it up.
Can you load it up?
Some of them they have in the seats.
Oh yeah.
Heading on the airplanes.
We've been.
How does Netflix work and you load it up
on your.
Like on your phone beforehand or.
No,
it's always.
you can only stream it.
Okay.
But I guess that's what solves the
piracy qualms sort of,
but I'm sure people can pull it off of
Netflix and streaming.
I mean a positive,
right?
Yeah.
Anyway.
Whatever.
Regardless of that.
Yeah.
It's still pretty accessible.
Yeah,
it's super accessible.
The point is it's just an awesome
platform and they have so much standup
there now.
It's the spot to be.
They really do have a lot of standup.
It's pretty great.
Yeah.
It's like the place to go for it.
It's pretty big.
And find what you want.
There's so many different choices too.
And you also can stumble into people who
began to stumble.
Yeah.
Kind of like when rolling stone put it
at the top five albums of the week,
you know,
and if you saw it,
you're like,
that's a good review.
I'll get that.
Yeah.
You know,
just like I've always heard about that
guy.
Let me give him,
let me give it a look.
No,
what's a good one you've seen lately?
I can't wait for Roy's.
That Scoville it's out in a month ago
without now.
It's out now.
I know it's always just out now.
Um,
yeah.
He's just always really funny.
Really,
really out there.
I haven't seen it but he's so weird and
different but like not weird.
Weird.
Just like,
I don't know.
I know you got to see it.
It's just always try and crazy shit.
I think I might've might've saw him in
la somewhere once he did this thing with
John doerr where they,
um,
first time I saw it was in Montreal.
I'm hosting that show right now.
Big J and Jimmy Carr.
Okay.
How do I.
was a man.
Get me there.
I have no idea.
Damn.
It's lost in old world of marijuana
frequency into.
Damn it.
Take a break,
collect your thoughts.
Okay.
It was talking about something that's
definitely talking about something in
Montreal at a something we December to
find new people.
Got It,
got it.
So I'm going to show small place and I'm
reggie watts is hosting.
It was just like eight,
nine years ago.
He was big but not like massive.
And it was fun and a lot to people and
say,
Hey,
by the way,
everybody,
good host hosts.
Just weird stuff.
Like does it?
Well,
he goes by the way,
uh,
we had a couple,
we had a comic dropout.
So,
uh,
hope you guys don't mind.
Everyone's doing little lecture time and
everyone's like,
yeah,
fucking sweet.
And then,
um,
he goes through the show a little bit
and then it goes,
okay.
So here's the problem,
like everyone ended up showing up.
So now we're behind.
So we actually have to be at is festival
rules.
So the last two comments agree just to
go on together.
Is that cool with everybody?
And then they do,
right?
Everyone claps and then they both just
start doing their own bits over each
other.
Just like talking to me,
they're not going to go back to back it
all.
They're both just doing their own X.
Oh no.
Yeah,
and I'm telling you,
man,
it should've been funny for 30 seconds
and nine and a half minutes later I'm
dying laughing.
It was so fucking good.
Yeah.
And then sometimes one week go to get
his breath and you just hear not my
light bulb,
you know,
from the other way.
And then it would go like that.
And it was like sometimes some point you
hear like you guys like impressions and
it was like,
yeah,
it was so good.
Wow,
that's amazing.
That's what I was thinking.
I was thinking that's going to be
terrible.
Oh No.
Yeah,
I know,
right.
Didn't.
They didn't plan it?
No.
They planned it.
They did play.
Yeah.
Like how far in advance?
I guess they had done it a bunch,
but register said luck real well.
Oh,
that's brilliant.
Yeah.
Oh yeah.
No,
they didn't just start talking.
Refused to give him imagine.
He'll be amazing if they like.
Yeah,
it was.
Neither one of them got upset.
It was like,
no,
I had these people on this side.
They're pretty good.
How'd you do search?
That's Hilarious,
man.
Yeah,
act out and stuff.
Anyway,
he's always doing shit like that.
So it's just really fun.
I don't know.
So that's what I'm looking forward to.
Um,
I don't know who else is,
so birds are,
so I got to see Louis.
I don't know who else.
How about you?
Um,
I gotta finish on there.
I've got to finish looking.
Oh yeah.
I gotta compile a list so of just when
you feel like at some point you're just
sitting there like,
oh,
you know what,
I'll see a standup special today.
Last thing I saw was burst new.
Special shall I,
I liked versus special.
I think I'm like Ali Wong special.
I never would have got to see that
otherwise.
Yeah,
that was really good.
I like working with her at the store
too.
She's super nice.
Fuck her Jews,
dude.
I thought we agreed.
Yeah,
she's cool.
She's nice.
Let's keep going.
Yeah,
I like that one a lot.
Birds was really funny.
Um,
we sound like a netflix commercial.
Yeah,
I guess we should just trying to pump up
that show folks.
Don't get all shelly on me.
Fucking shells.
Shells.
You know,
who knows where it's at.
Fucking pussies.
Amazon prime is so superior.
Have.
Did you seen the Alexa Jones where it's
like you talked to Amazon.
Has that.
Alexa is the box.
Yeah.
What's it looks at Jones.
Alex Jones.
You talked to.
It's like lumen eyes watching you right
now from the skies.
Alexa please.
Conspiracy theory.
Well,
it's really funny man.
That's funny.
They made a video for it.
What do you think of that story that
people get mad that he was on?
Well,
I guess it's um,
it's super complicated.
Why Blacks?
Yeah,
what Megan Kelly said that justifies it
in my eyes is that she said he's not
going away.
She's like,
look,
he's a guy who's out here is doing this
thing.
Let's find out.
What the fuck are you really?
Yeah,
I like that.
Does I like that?
I don't know.
Well,
you don't want to hear all sides and he
has been around for a while.
He doesn't do that mainstream shit,
right?
No,
not much at all.
So it's amazing how tired you get.
Just a little uphill chasse.
40 five pound plate on.
So this is fucking gorgeous out here.
Yeah,
it's pretty.
Rocks are great.
California has so many of these pieces.
Awesome.
So you just start coming out here now.
Okay.
No,
I've always said there's a bunch of
different places.
I go.
Different paths though because you can
go that way or that way.
We got a really cool place that has more
people,
but it's pretty fucking spectacular.
Really?
Yeah.
I'll take you next time.
Good hiking.
That'd be a cool house to have with your
backyard.
Either one of those.
Yeah.
Oh,
they have steps right into the.
Yup.
Get into it.
It's so pretty out here at this place.
Now.
All these places around here,
like
this is where the fires hit man.
Oh really?
Oh.
Must of torn right up and right over
there.
Houses.
Oh,
every now and then.
Yeah,
but again it goes right up the thing to
pay and gets lit up.
Some dictated.
Throws a cigarette out the window.
I saw a fire start on the back wall of
pink.like
in the parking lot from my bathroom
window.
You see it just a little bit and it
climbed up that wall within like 10
minutes.
It was all fucking gone and over.
Who Jesus Christ
haven't placed wouldn't be really.
Imagine if we get to a point that never
happened anymore.
People just stop robbing people and
beating people up and shed.
Unless it's a prearranged fight.
Imagine how much better the world of God
if just people stopped robbing each
other.
Just like just fucking happier stuff.
I'll have my stuff.
Yeah,
it will be pretty good at.
That never was an issue if trump was
like,
all right,
all the rest of the stuff that you guys
take before.
It's way worse than think,
but I think I know more Roberts at all
if like people as cannibalism.
Yeah.
No.
You think there is that in America?
In America?
Not really.
Somewhere in the world for sure.
There's got to be neighborhoods where
you're pretty safe.
Most of the time.
There was an island in Indonesia.
I were as of 1999.
There were headhunting woo.
Yeah,
it would stop for awhile and then like
another country would come in there and
said,
hey,
you guys go back to head hunting and
they were just would for like 40 years.
Here's something really dark about a
dude.
Chase snapped your head.
Yeah.
They say,
if you drink the blood fucking what are
their names?
I forget now of your enemy that was
fighting you.
It's just super powerful.
Oh boy.
But only if they're fighting you
cheeses.
Good workout,
Huh?
Yeah,
it is.
Especially when you're talking.
Yeah.
We don't breathe.
Right.
Do you have to see what people are
talking shows about the whole time?
That's a beautiful thing about what the
Diaz brothers can do.
Talk and fight.
Yeah.
I hate when they shut them up.
I get so mad at that.
Like this has nothing to do with the
rules.
That's what I'm saying.
Let them talk.
There's nothing to do with the rules.
What is a fucking Dick shot?
No.
Yeah.
I wonder what that is.
If he's running and talking,
he'd be like,
Hey,
shut your fucking mouth.
I just wonder if that's written
somewhere.
I don't think they should say anything.
Yeah,
because then it's like,
dude,
don't get picked to be involved in the
fight.
I agree.
Especially when a lot of fighters enjoy
doing it.
Dennis Johnson or Michael Johnson Rather
Dennis Johnson.
Michael Johnson could only talk trash
with their hands.
That's the new rule.
Fuck that.
So I don't think you should do it,
but I think if you want to do it,
it's your right.
Yeah.
Who's the worst trash talker in mma?
The worst.
Who Have you seen?
Be Like,
oh dude,
shut up.
You're so bad.
This is a good question.
A lot of them do that and they wait for
this applause that never comes.
And you're like,
oh yeah man,
that wasn't a great alon.
Well Randy coture is almost too nice to
be a trash talker.
Yeah.
No,
I mean other people who do it.
Oh,
people would do it badly,
but randy redd never really talked to
randy.
Wouldn't do it.
He wouldn't be.
But do you think that a lot of guys are
doing it now?
Yeah.
To get famous.
But I'm saying,
so you gotta get a lot of those guys who
don't know how to do it right?
Yeah.
Well I could.
Poker players did that a lot where they
started like,
Oh,
if you're flamboyant will get on more,
get more sponsorships.
But you've seen people faking it.
That's true.
And also part of what's exciting about a
guy like conor is that there's only one
of them.
There's a bunch of other people that are
allowed mouth and funny and they're all
doing it back and forth with each other.
He's not the Unicorn that's just kicking
my ass.
Yeah.
Forty five pounds and it adds up after
awhile,
Huh?
Yeah.
Does
he know what I mean?
It's almost like it'd be too much white
noise because there was 10 conners.
You know what I mean?
Yeah.
It'd be annoying.
It's like,
all right,
leave him alone.
Yeah.
If somebody really want to diminish
them,
so just make a bunch of other dudes
talk.
Exactly like nullify them.
I'm the number one Irish fighter.
Yeah.
All of Ireland's on my side have a
massive troll.
Fixed fights.
Got With Gut.
Did you see that video of him faking
getting punched for the mayweather fight
with conor?
Did they were like,
he looks terrible.
What do you mean?
He's just like.
He's like,
it's not as bad as I'm doing it,
but it's one step above what were like,
he doesn't know boxing.
Look at his fights that you had a hidden
camera.
Oh,
have him fucking connor,
but yeah,
I saw that video of him sparring with
that professional boxer.
It's fake.
He knows how to punch.
He was blocking it like with his
fucking.
I don't think it's fake.
No Way.
He was just moving around with the guys
are really good boxer.
I was trying to find his range.
He's trying to be unorthodox and think I
was a very skillful boxer.
I forgot his name.
Maybe you could remember his name for
the outro.
Find that.
Whose name is your bucket list of tears.
No tears.
How's it mind?
You're going to put it out.
Oh,
I want to put it up to the special.
Confuse the shit out of me.
Oh,
okay.
Well,
whatever.
We got it now.
I got it together.
I'm so high.
I forgot the timing.
What was I saying?
Jamie?
Look up that fighter's name.
Who was a skilled fighter that regard
with condom was boxing.
He's very good.
Like you could see beautiful crisp
motions.
He's a solid professional boxer.
I got a really high level and uh,
he,
you know,
definitely got the better of conor,
but that doesn't mean that like conner
wasn't working on specific things or
wasn't working that much on boxing.
When did this happen?
What,
what was he really trying to concentrate
on?
Oh,
right.
Maybe you're just trying to work on
ranch where you're like,
all right,
let me just get close to you and say he
could be trying to work on a lot of
things.
He could be.
It looks stupid bad though.
You're right.
It does.
He could be trying to take as minimal
amount of damage as possible.
Not commit himself very much,
but see what it's like to move around
and spar with a guy who's a worldclass
boxer.
Like they had hidden camera footage of
you like on your back and you're like,
no,
I was working off my back for that whole
two months.
Well,
most Jujitsu guys I think are super
aware of that kind of stuff.
Like there's a lot of guys,
but it would be the similar to that
where he's like,
no,
what you think is bad.
It's not bad at all.
I'm trying to get in that position.
Yeah.
Like you can get a picture of John
Jacques getting stuck inside control
every day with one of his blue belts.
He lets you do it so that he gets you in
a position and was like,
okay,
I'm going to sweep you now.
Next thing you know you're on your back,
but like you can take pictures of it
right there and say,
oh my God,
that guy was getting the better.
John Jack.
He had been inside control.
He'd be like,
John Jack instead of four second clip.
I just played that.
I mean,
you don't really know what you're
looking at,
but you know,
you're looking at a guy who's a super
high level box or that guy looks,
he looks sweet.
I like what he's doing and he's.
He's definitely getting the better.
Connor.
It didn't look good on connor's part,
but again,
I don't know what connor was working on.
I don't know if he was maybe be a,
you know,
how many training sessions he's doing a
day.
What do you know whether he's got
injuries,
why is he just boxing is going to have
an MMA fight.
Is it,
is it before the Nate Diaz?
Right.
When is it exactly that they respond.
Oh,
right.
Oh yeah,
a good point.
It could have been fucking years ago.
Who is he preparing for know?
Was he preparing to throw kicks?
Was he working on his range in the
world?
That merriweather,
who the fuck knows?
I say no way more than I don't know
shit,
but I said no way.
Is it less than eight for May?
Whether.
No,
as far as the rounds like dominated the
fight probably tend to maybe even.
You would be crazy to bet on a guy with
zero professionals that are done.
It's almost rude to boxing to say he has
a chance almost man,
and he's taken on literally the greatest
defensive boxer ever.
I mean,
come on.
Sign.
Good.
Yeah,
exactly.
It's almost like,
come on,
it's like those people think they can
just stand up just just on the spot.
It's kind of similar.
It's kind of similar,
but you connor does know how to punch
and he punches very hard.
Yes,
you're right.
But he's a bigger guy and he's bigger.
Oh yeah.
Yeah.
He's a lot bigger and he's going to
watch it live.
No,
because that's sold out two shows in DC.
Bitch.
Really?
Where you playing some theater?
That's what I grew up.
Oh Shit.
That's right.
You know what's called?
Um,
you never know.
That's the.
I do not.
I'll be there.
Washington DC.
Whenever your theaters called Hey,
Hebrew Academy.
Go head out and that's where you went
for a little while then Jewish day
school.
Wow.
Switch.
Go to the bad kid.
You're a bad.
It's less religious school.
Have you ever met a comedian?
That wasn't a bad kid.
MMM.
Like troubled.
Like,
like and stuff.
Yeah.
At least troubled.
Were there any kids though that we're
not troubled?
I mean,
did your kids get in trouble?
I mean they don't like once a year they
don't get in trouble and you know,
their kids,
they do stupid things so they don't
understand.
Shouldn't even say stupid.
I would say they do careless things
sometimes because they don't understand.
But you know,
real troubles.
Their little hole.
I mean your big one to know.
Yeah.
I don't know many comics who weren't in
trouble a lot.
I feel like people are learning every
generation how to be nicer to their
family members.
Every generation they're getting better
at it now.
I had a buddy when I grew up with in
Boston and his dad was super strict and
dad would fucking hit him and scream at
him and shit and he,
his dad was crazy and you know,
he had had enough of it by the time we
were in highschool and it's,
I don't know,
it's hard to see shit like that enough
of is like malvern off if you had
enough.
His Dad hitting him.
Oh really?
Yeah,
so we hit them back or you just get the
fuck off my back,
but he gets close to that.
But I think what my point is I in his
dad's generation
and that's what everybody did.
They beat the shit out of their kids and
then his generation before that,
they beat the shit out of their kids and
I think like people today are figuring
out how to be nicer to each other.
Like every day we're getting better at
it.
It seems like it.
I really believe that man.
I really believe that.
I,
I really believe that people are getting
better.
Have been,
hey,
how are you just being nice.
I wonder if some of this like,
you know,
the division that's happening now
between liberal and conservative and
like left and right and stuff where it's
make people sort of appreciate sometimes
with me,
it helps where it's like,
all right,
we'll give him a lot of freedoms,
but he's still got som,
like walking into a fucking forest like
that nature.
That's great.
Yeah.
So with that you get the thing too.
It's like look,
whatever.
But let's be kind to each other,
right?
Or No?
Well,
I just think that people.
I mean this is a been dwell on this more
than any other thought in the last few
years,
is that people are all red lined.
What does.
They're all taxed out like as far as the
amount of stress they go through without
physical exercise.
The amount of angst and anxiety they go
through without resolution will be
aware.
Work life just seems to stay in the same
state.
There's so many people that find
themselves in these traps.
I've been thinking about it more and
more over the last few years and what
happens to them.
It's just,
it's just nothing comes good at it,
you know,
so what does that do with niceness?
I think that just trying to look at
trying to look at what's the.
What are the good interactions that you
ever have with people?
How much of them are initiated by you?
How much of her initiated by a situation
that maybe could have gone sideways if
you were a defensive.
We were just high and low labs.
They're like,
what?
And we've all felt good.
There's so much standoffishness here.
I know you look at people and they look
down like,
like almost like try to intimidate you.
It's just like,
for what?
I mean it was gone,
but it was like I just saw a
friendliness before and then it's like
there's still,
there's a difference here,
but there's like this meanness if there.
Well there's some for sure,
but there's also an overpopulation
issue,
you know,
they did some kind of crazy study on a
radiolab podcast.
Again for it you'll have plugged boom.
He talked about how there's this direct
correlation between how fast people were
walking,
like how many steps they take like per
minute on average versus the population
in that city and how many syllables they
say in a certain amount of time,
how quickly they talk,
which are really like.
Because you have no time to actually
formulate words because I wasn't going
to rupture because so many people.
So you talk faster probably Dave Smith.
It get in quicker.
You can't,
you can't just lay back.
Right.
So you have to like rush.
Yeah,
like,
like a big family.
You've got to rush to get that chicken.
Oh,
interesting.
Fascinating,
right?
Yeah.
So they sounded like small towns,
slower walking,
slower talking,
and you could tell by setting up cameras
in two locations on a busy street how
fast people walked.
You could tell the exact population of
the city.
Wow.
Really?
Yeah.
Wow.
I think you can walk fast in New York.
They really do.
It's fast enough.
You can make it to the side.
Yeah.
It's almost like athletics.
They put a hustle to it.
I was walking with a girl and she was
like,
why?
Where are you going?
Why are you running people bump people
too.
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
It's a lot of bumping.
Had somebody to call me a dick.
Oh yeah.
I tried to get by.
She's putting on her coat and I waited
for a minute and they're like,
oh fuck it.
I'll just get buyer.
And then I walked by,
she started walking,
so like,
you know,
hit cholon shoulder.
Not hard or anything.
And I kept going and then she was like,
Dick and I was like,
all right,
I'm not going to get into it.
So I kept walking,
she was like,
Damn.
I kept walking in shoes outside to just
screaming,
oh my God.
How many times?
Probably four times outside to inside.
Have you done this on stage yet?
There's something there,
dude.
Jesus,
let it go by.
You can imagine what a psychopath to do
that the guy was doing that to you.
How scared you can tell you.
Oh my God,
I bumped a crazy guy.
I better get the fuck outta here.
Sorry Bro.
Oh No.
Part of me was like,
at that point,
turning around like,
I'm sorry,
I didn't mean to Hudson.
Hilarious.
We were camping.
This goes to that point and uh,
we're in this good repeat looking at us.
We're walking here with hold on
microphones while we hike.
I got a backpack on with a weight plate
on it.
It's colored like Captain America's
shield.
You have a shirt on.
She definitely thinks we fucked.
Lady looked at me like I was the best
fucking woods annually.
I see him there.
I knew those guys were home.
I think I had a captain America Shield
on his bag is fred and I'll share it on
the other guys in his back pocket.
Let's kill this podcast.
I mean.
Oh,
okay.
because wrap it up.
I gotta I gotta get a move on.
All right,
well thanks Joe as your brother.
This was fun.
So this was a.
we'll just call it.
Hey,
why don't we do this as a swap cast?
Not just you put it out and I'll put it
out.
We'll call it.
Yeah.
We'll do on that day.
Okay.
I'm not going to do an intro or did I
put it out?
Just put it out.
You can do an intro though.
I liked your intros.
One of my favorite parts of your
podcast.
Intros ran out.
He put a lot into them.
Yeah,
I do them over and over again.
Sometimes it makes the podcast a little
more because it's a little something
more,
you know,
you got a really good work ethic,
dude.
You know,
you're a guy who could fuck off for a
few months,
disappeared,
vanished and shit.
But rejuvenator though.
Well,
when you're doing stuff,
you have a really good work ethic.
It's really inspiring.
Thanks.
Yeah,
thanks.
That's nice.
Well,
I think,
you know,
I'm one of the things that I've had like
working.
I like doing this stuff be to one of the
things that I've learned like in the
course of my life that the more people
that I'm around that are doing things
that are inspiring to me,
the more I feel good.
Like I feel good being around people
that are kicking ass.
Right?
It feels good dude.
You know,
like to be around people who were like
tie level to just and also to be around
people that are your friends that are in
Hardee's on whether it's dss on the
show,
this guy's making money,
this guy's got an audience,
this guy's doing this.
Everybody's killing it.
It's,
it's a pretty good time.
They bitch man about the bloggers,
but that's just a small negative with a
giant positive.
Yeah,
it was.
People are always going to have opinions
on what the,
the giant positive is.
There's a lot of people that get to
enjoy your content and overwhelmed.
It evens out like you don't like.
There's a lot of people that are just
looking for things to criticize and
looking to be outraged and looking to
try to figure out what's the next angle
for their outrage and really a lot of it
is really just a kind of creative
exercise.
Looking for easy targets were good
targets and it makes sense to me.
I totally understand it.
Trolling.
Yeah,
but I think that we're entering into a
very interesting time as far as like
your ability to distribute stuff just to
like put it right up.
Cool stuff that people enjoy.
Like podcasts,
you know,
mean a bunch of people we don't even
know.
Just went on a hike with us.
What do you mean?
We're already talking about these folks.
They just went on a legit hike with us
for a few miles.
Don't forget if you heard him get
winded.
It's obviously because he's kind of a 45
pounds.
It is not.
It's not that heavy.
A lot of guys use 90.
There's a lot of guys are doing things.
They put $9,
seven miles.
They're savages.
That's the thing about bowhunters in
particular,
like people have no idea that's a.
that's an athletic endeavor.
One hundred percent.
You have to,
you're trying to keep your heart rate
low,
going up hills to get close to these
animals and if you're out of breath,
you're going to make a shitty shot.
You have to be able to keep it together
under pressure,
like an athletic event,
a real thorough from walking dead.
Not Very.
He gets no pass throughs.
Everything sticks in the head,
a pass through as it goes in your head.
So easy.
Why is it going to go out of your head
so you know,
especially those skulls of those things,
we can punch right through him sometimes
he doesn't get any pass throughs like I
would think across both those mushy as
Zombie heads.
You get clean passes.
We just blow right through that.
Yeah,
right?
Yeah.
Anyway.
Alright,
well fun times,
Arusha,
fear.
I'm bummed out that you're headed to New
York again.
I don't know man.
Mark it out.
This is ufc down there in November.
Really?
I'll be there for that massive square
garden.
Oh,
okay.
Oh Shit.
I'll go to the do.
I'm by myself.
I guess you're going for sure.
That'll be fun.
Yeah,
I'll miss you,
man.
It was my senior few times when you.
When you go,
you can do anything on the road.
We'll talk about that.
Let's talk like as real friends.
We'll shut this off.
Shut this off.