Her low freak bitches.
See they want fame already have the
money.
Right.
Like wanting fame and needing the money
is such a different thing.
That's why the bad girl's club show is
the greatest thing on TV.
I haven't seen it.
Oh,
put it.
Bring up a trailer for it.
If you're listening this is going to be
good.
They just get,
they get it.
Like we talked about this eight pieces
of garbage and then they just fucking
make them drink and stuff.
I'm in a goddamn house for three for
three months and it's,
it still has to go to the hospital from
the fights.
One girl this year showed up in the
first day she was there or the one other
girl just said,
she goes,
these fat bitches are trying to ruin my
birthday and picked up like a rocks
glass and bounced it off.
The girls,
hey like splitter I opened and the and
the things like they have 15 girls per
season because eight of them get kicked
off and they have to bring in
replacements.
Christ.
Season 14 oh will season 15 see if you
can find the season 15 is this year.
That's the one I just watched.
That's to not just grow and go and run
this renters,
they feed them booze from morning till
night.
Girls just digging stuff in her ass.
We're back.
Bitches.
It says Los Angeles,
California four oh seven what happened
this time?
There was a limo.
They came earlier.
The three of us got and we're more in.
We lock the girls out.
That's okay.
I don't want to have with,
then we proceeded to go on about the
other phone,
Bro.
Stay in the house and they proceeded to
destroy all of our personal belongings
in the house.
It looks like a tornado just isn't going
to give you any way
each other's money,
animals,
so they just can't let the worst people
they can find make them fuck with each
other.
These are all girls that in two seconds,
if you would just give them a porn
contract,
they would do it,
but they figure they want to sell more
porns by being a part of this show.
Then you're the girl from the bad girls
club.
Why am,
why am I not hearing about this?
More off this show is,
is fantastic.
They are the worst people.
It's garbage.
Then what they do is then they uh,
they,
you know,
they filmed the whole season,
they edit it,
then they a ferret now while they're
airing it,
these girls now watch the show and they
see that all the girls they thought was
their friend shit talk behind their back
or said they were using them for
something.
All the confessional shit and they're
just build up this more like,
as much as they already hate each show,
now they're more irate than they have
like a three part reunion.
They have to break into three parts
cause people rested during the show.
All real hundred percent real.
They got arrested during the reunion
show.
What kind of a person produces a show
like this genius that has been reading
my mind or tiring.
Yeah,
because man,
it's sure fire attainment,
they're gonna fuck up,
right?
They're not going to get along great.
They just,
they cut out the middleman of,
of all the real world was a show based
on alcohol.
That show was like where it took off.
Where it got exciting was when it'd be
fueled like no one cared about.
This one's trying to get a job in
animation and this girl's an aspiring
singer.
It's like,
no.
It goes,
what happens when you,
when that fucking number,
the guy put his finger in the guy's age,
peanut butter and then that was a whole
thing.
That's what people want to see.
They've cut out all of that like shit of
like watching live their lives and have
real emotional conversations and just
get them boozed up and then they're
like,
ah.
Girls were going go karting today and
then they go kart drunk and then they're
like,
this bitch thing.
She's better than me.
She bumped in front of me.
I was supposed to be next in the go kart
and that bruise.
Then they get dressed for the night and
they'd go out and they fight and fucking
bars and limos.
Then they come home and take off their
shit and put it on better fighting
clothes and then continue to,
something gets kicked out.
Every episode has two fights.
You should be a spokesperson.
Why don't you narrate it?
The show we wanted to do was I want to
do a live show where we get the
transcript.
I want to be like no charlie to get
transcripts of bad girls club.
You just have dudes read.
Cause if you read what they say with any
kind of rational tone of something is be
a fucking nightmare is actually a great
idea for a show I'm in.
Yep.
Dude fights they've had this year
particularly.
It goes uh,
I'm over there trying to twerk and this
bitch is like,
you know,
she trying to twerk next to me.
She's writing my workspace.
Like bitch can't talk like me.
You shouldn't even be on the same level.
And then it's like having fights like oh
adults of his face.
He goes bitch cause you ain't on my work
level.
That's why I'm up in your face cause you
ain't on my worse ca level.
Oh Man.
And then one girl goes,
they throw a punch and then the
confessionals were all like,
I buy that bitch knows who could work
now and there's blood.
They throw toasters.
It's insane.
It's hurt my eye from laughing.
Like I pulled something in my,
I was laughing so hard.
All right.
Amen.
But if we can do a transcript for you,
that'd be good.
Belly room show.
Yeah man.
I got a transcript.
If you guys want to practice,
shut the fuck up.
Okay.
Um,
let's do it.
Is this bad and make it a little larger.
Here we go.
Jenna said,
but this is the one from the deficit of
the ugly duckling.
It was a season ward in 2010 Tanisha,
Tanisha now hosts all the reunions.
She's a big fat black lady.
Hmm.
It's hard to know if you have to,
if you have to get him in to find the
arguments yet.
That's the thing.
Yeah,
because I just doing them in general,
but there's a whole episode would take
too long anyway,
but just finding like a fight weight
when they started getting it.
I get to work level fight.
Oh my God.
Yeah.
And then they tried to happen to like
emotional moments,
like with like a life coach.
But that show would be so much better if
you were narrating it.
Oh,
I love,
since you such a fan,
you should reach out to them and it
really should area,
do they have a narrator?
Nope.
What do now?
Just like the Internet of Commercial
Shit,
bad girls club.
If you hire Jay Oakerson to be your
narrator,
I will do everything I can to promote
your show.
I will.
I will help.
I'll put it on twitter.
I'll make an instagram post and it'll
never stop out on the podcast.
Let's make it happen.
You got it.
You got a gold mine here and do it.
He could do it in an afternoon.
He'll do the whole season.
Okay.