Okay.
Dave Smith,
president of the Kanye West Fan club is
here.
Comic Dave Smith on twitter,
tweeting pictures of your Dick.
He loves them.
I love Kanye and Dick Pics.
I'm glad we got that APP was Hirsi Dude,
thanks for doing this because I loved
you on Ari's podcast man.
You were fucking awesome on it.
It was really cool.
It was very,
it was a welcome surprise,
you know,
not that already.
He's a podcast is not always awesome.
It's always awesome.
But it was like,
damn,
this dude needs a lot of political shit.
And you knew about the Hillary Clinton
thing with the a rape trial that she was
involved in defending the guy looks.
Paul explain it because it's,
it's a fucked up story and I want to get
it wrong.
Okay,
so Hilary Clinton,
this is way back when she was a criminal
defense attorney.
She got a a child rapist off and a real
bad one.
It wasn't one of those good child
rapists.
It was a real way.
But it was like jared bang and 15 year
olds who was making sandwiches,
you know,
gives you a picture pickles,
you suck his dick.
But even like,
you know,
you heard like the,
the way Michael Jackson was accused of
raping,
boy,
that was like the nicest way you could
rape a kid.
It was like take him to an amusement
park.
Yeah.
Talk and I show him the Lama and the
Monkey.
All right.
Child rape is bad.
Let me start with that.
Horrible.
The worst thing ever.
Kanye,
Dick Pics.
Good,
bad.
Just want to be clear on where I stand.
Uh,
but so sheet,
so this guy,
uh,
um,
basically raped a 12 year old girl and
really brutal the details of the story
and she defended the guy and there's a,
there's tape of her in an interview
talking about this years later now.
It's still,
it's back in the day.
It's when Hillary Clinton's doing like a
southern accent.
There's been like six different Hillary
Clinton's that have existed.
This was the southern wife of Bill
Clinton.
Hillary when she was,
when he was the mayor or governor of
Arkansas.
So was that early eighties?
Yeah,
somewhere around that,
around that time period.
I'm not sure.
I'm not sure precisely where the tape is
from.
Um,
but she is,
I mean it's,
it's,
there's,
there's a lot of videos I could point to
online that's,
I think,
strong evidence that Hillary Clinton is
a sociopath.
Um,
I'm personally convinced of that.
Now I'm not a professional and I can't
diagnose her,
but this video is really up to,
I mean,
she's laughing about the details of the
rape case and how she got the guy off
and she laughs about how funny it is
when,
when she basically admits that she knew
the guy was guilty because she's going
like,
oh,
we convinced the jury it was a big
miscarriage of justice and she's,
she says that he took a polygraph and,
and passed it.
And then she says that forever destroyed
my belief in polygraphs.
So she's basically saying,
I know this guy raped this,
this little girl.
But we were able to get them off and she
laughs about having the,
the bloody underwear as the big piece of
evidence.
I mean,
it's really,
really intense.
Intense,
awful shit.
And what's really
crazy about it is that in this world of
like,
you know,
rape culture and Social Justice Warrior
liberal outrage there is just deafening
silence when it comes to the Clintons.
Do you think it's a lack of information?
Because most people don't go looking for
this stuff for stuff like what you're
talking about.
Most people have to find it on Fox News
and go,
what?
Outrageous.
They don't go looking for it.
Cause there's a lot you'd have to look
through.
I mean you'd have to go through all the
Whitewater stuff,
you'd have to go through all that Vince
foster stuff.
You'd have to try to find,
and there's a lot of like weird stuff
about them in their past that you'd have
to sort through.
How much of this is legit,
how much has it,
most people aren't going to do that.
And so it's,
it's not being discussed and you'll have
to filter out like that just nonsense.
Cause that's,
that's the problem with where we're at
now is that the truth is out in the
Internet,
but it's sandwiched in between a whole
bunch of nonsense.
And so you've got to like get that out
of the way.
And the conspiracy theorists would say
that nonsense is there on purpose.
Yes,
that's right.
Because everybody,
every conspiracy theorist,
as it turns out,
when I read more conspiracy theorist,
it turns out they were just working for
the conspiracy and they're against like
Alex Jones.
They all think now is working to tryst
me.
Alison is my friend.
He's just crazy.
There's no CIA involved there.
Well,
that's a fun thing when you get into
stuff that people think is a conspiracy
and then you're like,
oh no,
no,
no.
It's just a crazy guy.
Well,
I've heard conspiracies that involve me
and so when I hear that I go,
oh,
I see how you,
I've,
I've read some shit about me being a CIA
agent.
Like,
yeah,
what a circuitous route I took.
I went from kickboxing to standup
comedy.
All the while,
secretly undercover for the CIA are
going to plant them in news radio.
And before you know it,
he'll be leading public opinion.
Dude,
here's how even funnier one I have Eddie
Bravo thinks that it's perhaps possible
perhaps that Laurel Canyon was all about
a CIA psyops and Jim Morrison and all
these music music musical in the middle
of saying musicians musical,
powerful La Pot,
that they were all a part of some CIA
plan to,
uh,
to like the institute,
the drug movement.
Like I don't even understand the plan,
but the idea is that all these
influential people came out of the,
this Laurel Canyon area and Jim
Morrison's dad was in the CIA and light
take is like Jesus Christ.
Do you know how much fucking,
how busy CIA dads are?
They're never around for their kid.
Of course,
the kid grows up to be Jim Morrison.
It's not that like the dad was there
influencing him with a fucking hypnosis,
one of those watches.
You are going to be the voice of a
generation,
right?
It's not no one engineer or something
like that.
All things being equal,
it's best to look at the,
the most simple answer.
Right,
but outcomes razor.
exactly.
Uh,
I do think like,
I feel like with a lot of those
conspiracy theorists like my take on it
is like you,
you have like the government who,
it's almost like if the government was a
person,
you could be like,
okay,
we've got them on murdering these 50
people and we have it cold hard.
They clearly did it and then you're
like,
yeah,
but I heard a rumor that they also
murdered another people.
I'm like,
can we just focus on what we know?
They do it right.
Like we're slaughtering people in the
Middle East.
We don't need a makeup.
All this other nonsense just to make it
more sellable.
Well,
it's this,
this idea that we're being controlled.
That's the one that's the,
that's the overlying theme I guess,
or the over.
It's,
it's,
if you look at like all of the
conspiracies,
whether their chem trails or whether
it's all about like engineering,
like global warming.
It's like Geo Engineering.
There's all this,
it's all about engineering friends.
It's all about people that are worried
about eugenics.
They want,
like Alex Jones says they want to kill
five.
They want to leave 500 million people
worldwide or something like that,
like this fucking number.
I was like,
Whoa,
whoa.
I think going to be a mortal like did
they know what the fuck they're doing?
Like you,
you really,
you really think that this is a plan.
Kill everyone except half a million.
Look,
I do think there's some really shady
plans that are up there at the top.
I think what they get wrong sometimes is
they think that,
um,
that everything that's happening was
actually controlled from the top.
I think there's plans that people in it
like to build a bear group is real.
That exists and I think they do want to
control the world,
but I think more often than not,
they have like 10 things they want to
do.
Some of them work out,
some of them don't.
Then they roll with the punches on that.
Then they try to change things from
there.
It's not as perfect as like everything
they did worked out perfectly and was,
but you know,
it's a little easier.
It's more,
it's more of a fun story.
If they're just an ultimate control,
well then the have that number,
the 500 million number,
like why is,
how do you know that number?
It's specific.
This is what I heard.
500 million.
Oh Wow.
Wonder if I'd make the cut,
but it still thinking about all the
billions of people and it could.
500 million's not that much.
If you think about 7 billion,
but they're probably going to come off
Indians and Oliver's,
you start to think whether you could
make the cut and my top 500 million,
if they're going to leave 500 million
people and the planet,
this room,
there's some wiggle room.
They're like,
okay,
you're going to need like 60 comedians.
Did you want to get in though?
I mean,
what are they going to do with all those
bodies?
What are I going to do at six and a half
billion of bodies?
How bad is the earth going to smell for
like a month?
Right?
Yeah.
That's a good point too.
It's a very good point.
I have these guys thought this through.
I don't think there's hot the wall and
not only that,
but what did you kill the wrong people?
What if the people that you kill,
we're going to figure out a way to cure
cancer or get us to Mars or you don't.
You just can't.
But that's why that whole,
that's why believing,
which is a much more common belief out
of the conspiracy thing,
but believing that populations a problem
is,
is crazy because like you said,
you never know when that you know,
they,
they'll like uh,
environmentalist.
There'll be like,
well,
if we have too many people and there's
two big carbon footprint,
if you're like,
yeah,
except until we have the one person who
figures out how to save all of us.
Right.
And then that got,
you know,
you need a bunch of people to get that.
You don't get that in a village with log
cabins.
That's right.
They don't figure out how to fix the
world.
They just don't heed millions of people
that need to live in cities.
Food needs to be delivered to them.
They need to be safe and then they can
up with ideas.
This thing is a game of numbers.
You to have mad,
mad numbers man.
We got to throw a lot.
Oh,
I did want to address what you asked
before.
La Pod is powerful.
Powerful what you said before when
you're talking about this stuff with the
Clinton uh,
tape and you said,
why,
uh,
why is it that people are,
they need to find the information.
I think there is some of that,
right?
Because say if they made this a story on
the news,
like if every day they were playing,
they had,
it's amazing the power that media has to
choose what story we're going to make
the story and what story will maybe get
mentioned here and then fallen,
you know,
Fade into obscurity so they could,
the media could make that a story that
everyone has to deal with.
But I've found there's a lot of denial.
Like when I talk to liberals or,
or Hillary supporters and I'll bring
that stuff up and there's a lot of like,
yeah,
well whatever.
Exactly.
Well whatever.
But the same people who are like,
we live in a rape culture and we'll go
after like tosh for making a joke in bad
taste.
And then you're like,
well here's this woman laughing about
getting a child rapist off.
Forget some abstract contributing to
rape culture,
contributing to rape culture,
getting a rapist who would've gone to
jail back out into the streets and
they'll,
so it's like,
to me a mix of the media doesn't do
their job and then people are also kind
of in denial.
Well people are intensely tribal,
intensely tribal and their support for
brands,
you know,
forget about political parties,
political parties,
oftentimes the most tribal,
I mean I follow people that all they do
is mock liberals online and then I fall.
Other people we're,
all they do is mock conservatives and
God they're so similar or the same
fucking people.
There's atheism and then there's these
people that are super religious.
There's all this God Christian stuff on
the right.
And then on the left it's like atheism
is their God.
And I don't mean it in there,
God is like,
it's,
it's an actual religion.
Their fault.
I mean you almost kind of have to be in
that group to be on that side.
It's this weird thing that's going on
where you've got people that are
subscribing to atheism.
Nothing wrong with atheism.
It's not what I'm saying.
I'm just saying God is,
it's so universal on the left that it
seems to me to be a trait that you
attribute with this tribe.
Like almost like you have to accept this
trait.
Right?
And then I think,
and I guess that's maybe a criticism I
have of a like Sam Harris and that's
about,
I know you had him on your show
recently,
but I think a lot of those guys who got
themselves in this camp of we're the
atheists or the ones committed to
rational thought and religion is
terrible.
And now if the,
they'll look at things like,
uh,
the,
the wars in the Middle East and it just
seems like,
to me it seems like they have a tendency
to always try to blame the religiously
motivated violence because I think
they've kind of got themselves on like
team anti-religion.
We're on team atheist,
so the Muslims have to be worse than the
American military because they're,
the religious ones were like
sophisticated and advanced and
everything about the,
the u s military is built on like
science and reason and thought.
And the,
these are crazy Muslims who are just
maniacs.
So we have to blame them.
Even though if you look at the numbers
of dead,
it's pretty staggeringly one side,
like we're murdering them.
Not only that,
we're also in where they live.
So that has to be taken into account.
When we had to get there,
we had to go there.
I understand,
but let's just look at the actual facts
cause it's not cassie judge.
Let's look at the facts.
We are where they live.
Um,
we don't speak their language.
We come in and mass and we kill a fuck
load.
More people than they do.
And the a good percentage of the people
that are in the military.
Christian,
yes,
very decent size.
Uh,
a very,
a very big percentage.
And then a very big percentage of like
the hardcore supporters,
the people like who are really hardcore,
the evangelical base that voted for
George W.
Bush.
A big part of that support is this goofy
religious belief that we need to be pro
Israel because the Jews need to be in
Israel and that's what then Jesus can
come back for us and if some Muslims got
to get slaughtered in the process,
well this is how it's supposed to go,
so we got to protect that.
There's a lot of that weird shit on our
side as well.
A lot of weird old southern money that
goes into that.
Yeah,
there's a great vice piece on those
people.
There's a great vice piece where they,
I forget,
you know,
vice has someone in those online shows
that are awesome.
It's hard to know which one it was,
but they went with these people to
Israel,
these crazy evangelicals who are going
back to the motherland and it's like
they were like,
well,
this is where Jesus is going to camp.
You know,
this is where we're going to set up his
fire here and he'll pull his trailer in
right here like they had,
it was almost like that and his head,
like he was setting up to Budweiser's
one from me,
one for Jesus when he gets here.
Weird,
weird.
But you if you're on the right,
like even Gavin McInnes who I love,
I love Gavin Love Gavin.
Gavin's a bright,
bright guy,
but he's also a Catholic and he became a
Catholic like late in life.
So I'm like,
what are you doing?
Like what do you,
what is this like you,
it's almost like you have to be a part
of something that's religious to get in
on the right side.
Like a Glenn Beck became a Mormon when
he was like 50 like,
hey dude,
come on.
Did you even read it?
Did you read any of the history about
Joseph Smith being 14 when he made all
this shit up?
Magic seer stone that he had to use to
read the golden tablets that contained
the loss work of Jesus that only he
could read with this rock.
I'm torn between whether I hate
mormonism for that or I love them for
that.
I'm like,
Hey,
if we're going to bullshit,
let's just go bullshit.
Like,
yeah,
Jesus,
he lives in Kansas.
I don't know.
He was friends with my grandpa.
Why not?
Well,
the American Indians were actually from
Israel.
That was another one of his,
that this guy spent a ton of money.
Um,
you know,
we were talking with when Sam was here
the other day,
we were talking about how 15 years ago
it was like billions of dollars to get
your genome map.
Now it's like a couple thousand bucks.
And we were talking about how crazy that
is.
Like what would an insane leap,
well,
a few years back,
one of the,
before it became that cheap,
some dudes spent a fuck ton of money.
It was a mormon to try to prove that the
Morman scriptures were in fact correct.
And the American Indians did come.
But we learned from that actually it's
actually want up being good for science
because these guys spent so much money,
we realized,
no,
they actually came from Siberia.
So reinforces the idea of them crossing
the landmass,
the bering strait and coming into
America from Asia.
So they are Siberian like it's,
it's,
it's interesting like the,
the,
the merge or the,
um,
the movement and migration of people
from Asia to North America and down into
Mexico.
And if it's really fucking cool when you
find out that it's not that long ago,
well,
a few thousand years,
you know,
at the most 20,
whatever it was like during the ice age.
It's not that long ago,
man.
It's,
it's crazy.
A history is a weird thing like that.
Like even when we talk about thing and
you know,
you'd be like World War II,
World War Two was like that long ago.
Like your grandfather was there and like
that's,
that's just happened.
Just happened historically.
You have Vietnam and how about Vietnam?
There's one that this conspiracy
theories can really grab a hold of the
Gulf of Tonkin.
Well,
yeah,
like Wah.
That's,
but that's my point when before it's
like,
why are we even wasting our time with
anything else?
Right.
Let's grab that one and hold on to that
one.
That was bullshit.
We know that was bullshit.
Tens of thousands of Americans died in
that war,
let alone how many Vietnamese we just
slot.
It was just like mass slaughter that
people made billions off of that was
bullshit.
Bullshit.
You don't need anymore.
We flag attack.
Yeah.
Look it up folks.
I mean if you're listening to this going
what you sitting on your porch and
Georgia with your lemonade hating black
people just go online and it's fun.
I get it.
He doesn't want to sit on their porch
with lemonade and hate black people.
I know.
I do.
If you,
if you really do read that story,
it's horrific.
And then you realize,
oh well this was deception was the rule
of the land at that time.
This was when they had the operation
northwoods,
um,
thing that had been passed.
And if you haven't seen that document,
that's crazy.
They,
this was signed by the Joint Chiefs of
staff and then vetoed by Kennedy where
they were going to attack American
civilians.
They were going to bomb,
they were going to bomb Guantanamo Bay,
they were going to arm Cuban friendlies
and they were going to give them weapons
to attack Guantanamo Bay.
They were going to blow a drone jetliner
out of the sky,
blame it on Castro and wind up killing a
ton of people.
And they were doing it all just to get
support of this idea of attacking Cuba.
So they were going to pretend that all
these people died,
you know,
and,
and just,
you know,
we're going to add,
I don't know,
how could they take off in a plane that
then,
I'm not sure where the drone technology
was that,
but this was the plan.
I mean it was,
it was a plan that I think Kennedy
himself had to,
had to veto but not sign off on it or
whatever.
Um,
and you know,
they took care of him quickly,
allegedly.
That's the other conspiracy,
right?
Lee Harvey Oswald acted alone,
seems to me to be even a dumber
conspiracy.
Then there was a bunch of people
involved killing that guy.
Couldn't agree with you more on that
one.
But it's,
it's just the,
the north would think it's just a
fascinating,
you know,
glimpse into
the mindset of the people who are,
who are on the inside,
who really do view the world as,
as pawns on a chess board.
And if,
you know,
uh,
if a lie is what it took to get the
geopolitical result that they wanted and
some Americans had to die or whatever,
that's not a big deal.
And,
and I think people should be aware of
that.
Like anyone,
a lot of times,
like you were talking about getting in
the team mentality,
people kind of have this team mentality
and they're like,
well,
they don't,
you know,
if someone's willing to just slaughter
people in a third world country to make
their buddies rich,
I'd be careful with them around your
kids too.
You know,
like they're,
they're probably looking at everybody
like their pawns on a board,
not just those guys.
Yeah,
I think people learn really quickly how
to disassociate.
They learn how to not think about that.
Especially when you're using like drone
technology and stuff.
You're flying a robot and shooting
missiles out of a robot.
And you're watching it all on a screen.
How easy is it to distance yourself from
that if you're the person,
not even he's pushing the button,
but who gave the order to give the,
okay.
You know,
and when I talked to Ed,
Mike Baker on here was a former CIA
operative.
I had been on a few Fox News shows with
him.
He told me all that stuff is done by
lawyers.
They all decided like,
can we do this?
Can we do this?
And the lawyer sit down,
they hash it out and they give him the
green light or the red light.
I'm like,
Whoa,
that is fucking dark when you're leaving
military matters.
And whether or not you attack with a
flying robot to lawyers,
arguably the most heartless creatures
I've ever created in our capitalist
society.
Well that's that.
And by the way,
that's who's running government.
It's all lawyers do it.
Hillary Clinton is,
was that Obama is what Michelle Obama
is.
But Bill Clinton was,
I mean,
that's what they all are.
They're all lawyers,
great lawyers.
There's awesome people out there that
are lawyers.
That's not what I'm saying.
But even if you're an awesome person
that's a lawyer,
you fucking know some psychos.
Let me tell you,
the awesome person who was a lawyer is
the most adamant,
like,
do not put lawyers in charge.
Do your job.
Do you not?
That's like,
look,
I'm a comedian.
But if you were like,
should comedians being charged or it'd
be like Jesus,
no,
we won't.
We won't make it through this podcast.
Yeah.
They shouldn't be in charge of anything.
Even comedy.
We shouldn't be in charge.
Yeah,
exactly right.
Cause then you get like these salt
rooms,
they get mad at you if you talk loud.
But like when people are in charge of
anything they fuck.
Oh yeah.
But uh,
you were talking about the drone wars.
Um,
there's,
this guy is brilliant historian,
Tom Woods.
I don't know if you've heard of him,
but he's got a great podcast.
He's incredible.
This guy like I to me,
like maybe like the smartest libertarian
voice out there.
What's his podcast called?
It's called the Tom Woods show.
Oh yeah.
You should,
you would love him.
I think he would be great on you.
I didn't know he had a podcast.
He's got a podcast.
He's just a brilliant historian.
He nails all this stuff,
but he uses this analogy and I love it.
Uh,
he just goes through,
imagine we,
we used the drone campaign,
like imagine we,
we fought crime that way.
So,
you know,
imagine there'd be like,
someone was like a,
so we've got,
um,
to suspected criminals at a wedding in,
in,
you know,
California somewhere.
And I go,
so the plan is we're going to bomb the
wedding.
Everybody just be like,
oh,
that's not okay.
You can't do that because there's,
there's innocent human life there.
But literally we,
that's just how we conduct the war in
the Middle East.
Yeah.
But they don't,
it's sort of disingenuous because they
don't know it's a wedding.
They just see a group of people gathered
and then they know that the dickheads in
there and they want to blow them up.
And then it turns out to be a wedding.
And we were like,
Oh shit.
Okay.
So still the analogy say that's how we
fought crime.
Here we go.
But we just followed the metadata on
your cell phones and wherever you happen
to be,
we're going to blow that place up.
Yeah.
That's what's important to point out
too,
is that they're shooting at phones and
then they don't even have a visual id on
the person.
They,
they find where the phone is.
They do the find my iphone feature with
the eye in the sky and then they launch
aptly named Hellfire missile at it.
That's dark too,
that they have cool nicknames for their
missiles.
Hell fire.
Oh Dude.
They do all this shit.
Well,
although like you're saying like the
operation names,
operation kick ass,
I said,
Jesus Christ,
it's just fucking 18 year olds blast and
ACDC rolling through some time in town.
It's like Jesus.
Well have you ever seen those pieces
that they've done on those kids that
were,
were involved in operating those tanks?
It would listen to metal.
I mean that's,
that's bizarre too.
You're letting these kids get jacked up
on metal and who knows what else you let
them have.
They probably let them have
amphetamines.
They definitely let them have steroids.
They give steroids to soldiers.
That's,
that's common shit man.
There's a reason they prefer an 18 year
old to a 30 year old.
There's a reason they prefer someone who
is still just as good fighting shape or
whatever,
you know,
essentially.
But then when you're 18 you're,
you're in a different place,
your levels are at a different place and
your,
your willingness to follow orders,
I think as a mother is in a different
place.
We're all essentially like,
you know,
older people being wiser if they've had
enough experiences.
But we're all gathering experiences,
gathering experiences and then
calculating,
trying to figure out,
okay,
why did that go wrong?
Well what does that,
oh here's that fucking thing again.
Oh here's this thought,
let's see how it goes.
And that's why as people get older,
they get less and less tolerant of
certain things because they see these
things over and over and over again.
And they recognize these patterns.
You get more confident in your assertion
of that pattern cause you're like,
I've seen this bullshit six times now.
I know.
And it works that way with politics too.
Like,
that's the common expression about
radicals in college.
You know,
a,
show me a young man who's not a liberal
and I'll show you a man without a heart.
Show me an old man is on a conservative
and I'll show you a man without a brain,
right?
Because after to why you go,
ah,
I see.
You know,
and it's not black and white when it
comes to that issue,
but when you're,
you're dealing with something that,
you know,
a human being that gathers up this data.
When you were 18,
what do you got?
A couple of fucking birthday parties.
You remember the first time you get your
Dick sucked was only six months ago.
Like,
what do you remember?
What do you,
what do you have to base on?
what do you know?
Movies.
You watch a lot of movies.
That's probably what they're basing
it on.
What they think their life's going to
be.
Some fucking Tom Hanks movie,
they'll come back and cry to their kids
when they're younger,
when they're older,
rather about the,
you know,
I served in the war of serving my
country.
Did my country proud.
Now you're,
you might go home with no legs.
Like you're in a crazy situation where
you're killing people.
You don't know because someone you don't
know told you you're supposed to kill
people you don't know.
And a lot of them figure it out.
It's just they figured out when they see
that real shit that you're talking
about.
Cause you know,
there is also,
that's another thing that's very,
very downplayed.
But uh,
that should have been maybe the biggest
story in at least one of the biggest
stories in the last 10 years is that Ron
Paul in 2000 in the 2008 run and in the
2012 Ryan both runs,
he got more money,
more donations from active duty military
people than all of the other candidates.
He got more than the,
all the Republican candidates combined
in 2012 and he got he outraised uh,
Barack Obama both times.
So it's like there's actually a lot of
people in this military,
in the military who see through this
bullshit and we're very happy to have
like the only,
I mean Ron Paul to me is like the only
politician on a presidential level in
recent memory who has been
unapologetically antiwar and not just
not just like this hasn't worked like
this is bullshit racket,
and we started it.
Yeah.
When you get that many active military
on your side,
you really have to really think,
well,
these are the people that are dealing
with this issue.
It's a part of their life.
It affects their families,
it affects their friends,
their loved ones,
all the people they serve with.
The whole thing is it's so hard to
believe that they've been able to keep
this going for so long and this war with
no end,
this war against terrorism is one of the
most devious things because whether or
not terrorism exists,
it certainly does.
Whether or not we have to combat
terrorism,
we certainly do.
Whether or not we have to take measures
to ensure the safety of the people.
We definitely do 100%,
but there's something really suspicious
about an unnamed enemy or an unseen and
Miller and an enemy.
That's just terrorism.
It's like a,
it's like herpes just floating through
all these parts of the world.
Like you don't even have a,
we don't,
it's not even a country with a leader
anymore.
Like now it's just terrorism.
Well,
it works out pretty great if you're like
a weapons company that's making more
money than ever,
or if you,
if you want it to keep this military
budget,
you know,
I mean,
uh,
the,
you know,
people were,
I liberals were all outraged over George
W Bush's military budgets and Obama
greatly expanded those.
And uh,
so yeah,
if you're making tons of money off it,
it works out great to have kind of this
vague concept that we're fighting a war
against.
[inaudible].
I,
I do think terrorism,
obviously,
like you said,
exists.
I think terrorism,
as Pat Buchanan said,
is the price of empire.
And it kind of always has been,
and this is what we're going to be
dealing with as long as we want to have
an empire in the Middle East.
Right.
But now it's not,
it's not like a one particular enemy.
It's this vague threat of attacks by
irrational people.
And then you see them scattered
throughout the world and other places
where they don't have the kind of
security that we do.
Right.
So it reinforces idea or idea that the
TSA is,
and you've got to get through that line
and you gotta be nice to these people.
And though they failed on like 95%.
Did you see that test?
They felt 95% of the like fake knives
and bombs.
These are all getting it and they're
just,
they're just feeling up old people.
Yeah.
They felt me up the other day.
Did they need to check my dick happened
to me at the back of his hand.
He had to go up to both sides of my
Dick.
Did it give you the nice ex ex,
uh,
explanation about how he's going to do
it?
And so we're going to feel what the back
of our hand,
the guy who did it to me,
and like I said earlier,
I'm no conspiracy theorist,
but when they're like,
you've been randomly selected for
additional screening and inside,
I'm like,
what was that last podcast?
Huh?
I hit something.
Is that what you know,
may stuff which,
you know what he said to me?
She goes,
no,
that would be,
that would be more uncomfortable.
But he said before he did it,
I don't know if the guy said it to you,
but he goes up if you want,
we can bring into a private room for
this.
Yeah,
they did say that.
It was like two,
we're going to do this right here.
Right now in a private room.
You Go,
yeah,
you're going to play George Michael's
music.
Yeah.
It's um,
I don't know.
I mean,
but it's so convenient that they need to
kind of security that the NSA was trying
to get,
or they're the kind of,
um,
not security,
but I'm the kind of invasion of privacy
that the NSA was doing with monitoring
your metadata,
the ability to check all your emails and
the fact that what snowden exposed was
kind of everybody's worst fear about all
this stuff was that one day we're going
to get to a point where they're
recording everything and you're always
going to be scared to speak your mind in
the private and public with your friends
because you think they could always
here.
And if there's certain key things that
you say that upset them while they could
just target you.
Like they were talking about people in
the NSA,
we're actively targeting their exes
email accounts.
Oh yeah.
And reading their exes emails.
What does this,
this is just,
of course it's going to happen.
It's human beings.
A buddy,
a friend of mine worked at a bank and he
told me how they had a big problem with
people like checking on celebrities,
accounts,
checking on other people,
other friends of theirs accounts.
It's,
it's human nature.
I think personally,
I think the biggest thing that snowden
exposed more so than any particular
program was that he exposed that that
guy clapper said,
you know,
the clapper was I think just six months
a year before snowden released those
files through Glenn Greenwald at the
Guardian.
He,
he,
before a congressional hearing goes,
there is no bulk mass data collection.
And that's what's amazing about what
Snowden,
you know,
showed you that they will just
understand that they will lie through
their fucking teeth to you.
Like they're liars,
they're not like misguided or they don't
know what's happening.
It's,
it's,
you know,
they're telling you what they think you
need to know so they can get away with
their bullshit.
And that to me is,
is a very important thing for people to
realize.
Well,
that's the,
the real insidious problem with the US
versus them idea is that they're just
people too.
So you've people that are operating
these mass surveillance programs on
other people.
There's nothing like,
there's nothing essentially noble about
them.
They haven't passed any tasks.
They haven't shown themselves to be some
people that are devoid of jealousy and
pettiness and clear thought always.
And they're just the smartest people we
know.
So we give them this position cause
there's so they're like the knights of
the watch,
you know?
Right.
You just go otherwise overlords.
Sorry.
We'll watch us.
They will walk.
They protect us.
I was arguing with a,
what's his name or who you bro brought
up?
Baker.
Uh,
I was on a panel with him on,
on a Fox News show and we were talking
about,
it was the apple when apple versus FBI
thing,
which I guess is still going on.
But uh,
so I was kind of siding with apple and
he was siding with the FBI.
I remember bigger said to me,
he goes,
he was like,
Dave,
what are you worried?
Are you worried they're going to be
checking your emails or checking your
phone?
You know,
like that kind of attitude.
How was like the FBI was spying on civil
rights leaders being run by a cross
dressing maniac like yeah,
I don't trust these people are going to,
I don't trust those people anymore than
I trust any group of people.
You have.
The fact that they think that that
organization has been cleaned up like
how much j Edgar Hoover and what they
did during the bullets.
It's coming out now more.
It's really interesting the stories that
are coming out now about how the war on
drugs was a big part of their plan to
try to break down the civil rights
movement and break down these anti war
protesters because this one thing they
shared in common,
they were all doing drugs.
So he said,
okay,
this will just have a fucking crazy war
on drugs and we just go in and get these
people,
they're going to be smoking pile,
which is arrest the shit out of them and
just break up everything.
And they really did.
And it was,
it's brilliant in terms of like
strategy,
if you're going to go after your
enemies.
I mean it's,
it's a great way to do it.
But we're still suffering the
consequences of Nixon's actions from Jad
or hoovers guidance.
I mean that that was all,
that's the whole pile that that was
operating under.
Yeah.
And then you get this whole,
like it spawns this whole system of mass
incarceration and private prisons and
this whole nightmare or hoover was
awesome though.
You got to love with the bad ass.
Who's wearing a dress like cross
dressing,
banging dude's keeping secrets.
Not only doing that today when it's cool
he was doing this at a time when like if
it came out,
people would be just,
I mean you're ruined.
Well that was how he kept it all under
wraps.
He,
the reason that guy was so into getting
into other people's Shit,
just cause he had so much shit to
expose.
He's like,
well I can't let this get out.
I gotta be proactive.
I just got to gather up data on
everybody.
Fuck Elvis.
Fuck Jimmy page.
Yeah.
But I just went after everybody.
I also think that there's something
inherently,
like if you're in the cross dressing,
banging dudes scene,
you're going to meet other people with
dirt too.
That's like,
you know the other guy who you're,
you're like,
hey,
look,
we both know where in that scene
together,
so you keep your mouth shut.
That's true too.
But I was like,
that's one of those things where people
always say that,
uh,
if you,
are with a partner and that partner,
all of a sudden it starts getting like
crazy,
irrationally jealous.
It's probably because they're doing
something sneaky.
Yeah.
You know,
and what he was doing was sort of that
he was jagger,
hoover was a fucking maniac,
and he was in charge of the FBI.
I mean,
he was just a bonafide,
insane person.
But,
but like you said,
it's like who's to say they're cleaned
up?
I think we always have this,
this like idea that we get comfortable
with the fucked up shit in the past.
So we were like,
oh,
this was so fucked up.
But now it's not like that.
But you know,
we,
we love to look back at slavery or look
back at Jim Crow or look back at
something,
oh,
what were these people thinking?
But if you look at,
I mean mass incarceration for nonviolent
crimes or mass slaughter in the Middle
East or any of this stuff that these
people believe me,
if,
if all the details of what's going on
came out in 20 years,
we're going to have the same attitude in
20 years and be like,
man,
I'm fucked.
I'm fucked up.
Shit going on in 2016.
Well you know what's interesting to me,
there's even tribalism in the
government,
like the CIA and the FBI can't get
along,
which is how,
um,
what's his name?
General.
I'm the guy who got busted for cheating
on his wife.
Patraeus so trays,
that's how betrays got caught.
The at the FBI was spying,
was gone after the CIA.
So not only that,
but it's craziness.
Dianne Feinstein,
who is the head of the Senate
intelligence committee.
Okay.
So they're,
they're tasked with overseeing the CIA.
She came out and said that the CIA is
spying on them.
Like I don't know exactly how they
figured it out,
but she came out and said,
so the CIA was spying.
But yeah,
this doesn't get big story on like a big
story on the new CIA spying and the
people who oversee the CIS supposedly,
we have no clue.
Rand Paul came out and said something
along the lines of,
he was like,
we don't even know who's running this
thing when it comes to government.
So I think the thing that Libertarians,
Rand Paul said that,
yeah,
he said this like a year and a half ago
when he was still doing well.
He actually should know.
That's why that's a scary thing.
Like he actually should,
he's probably talking to me,
but there's also this weird thing where
like,
I don't know exactly how it works,
but there's this weird thing where like
they'll tell you stuff but then you
can't talk about it to anyone if it's
like classified.
So a lot,
there's actually congressmen who don't
want the classified information because
they want to be able to say whatever
they want to be able to say.
It's a,
it's a whole cluster fuck.
But I think this is one of the things
that Libertarians,
uh,
at least the type of libertarian that I
am,
like that school of thought,
it really tries to emphasize,
just don't look at government as if it's
a different entity from humanity.
We're all people,
right.
So it's like,
like you were saying before,
like the CIA and the FBI,
they're not one monolith.
It's different power sources,
different groups of people.
And Yeah,
of course they all are incentivized the
way people are.
And they're a corporation,
like any other business where there's a
bunch of people that are backstabbing
each other trying to get to the top of
the ladder.
Yup.
So they're fucking each other over
inside the tribe.
Yup.
There's a lot of that going on.
It's fucking weird world man.
When you hear someone like Ran Paul
saying,
we don't know who's running this thing.
That's the government,
the whole government of the United
States,
he's talking about,
he's talking about the strings behind
the strings and we don't know who's
running it.
Well,
I mean,
you see this,
this,
it's very interesting when you hear like
a,
like Hillary Clinton,
it came out in one of these,
uh,
in one of her last batch of emails that
that got like released it,
it was like her and her team were
bragging about how she had convinced
Obama to go ahead with regime change in
Libya.
Oh,
that's right.
And then gates comes out and writes his
book and he's like,
look,
I was against it.
Hillary was for,
so it's,
it's just this fucking like,
you convinced the guy and now this
country is fucked.
Well,
she and all.
Yeah.
And well also did you,
I'm sure you saw the time where she was
being interviewed and she was laughing
about Kadafi Diane.
We came,
we saw he died when I said,
there's,
there's video evidence of her being a
sociopath.
I don't understand.
It's not cut off.
He didn't just die right before that.
It's not just that you're talking about
a human being who died.
Okay.
Kadafi died the way that dictators fear
you die.
His people got a hold of him and beat
him and sodomized him to death.
He got like,
I mean,
it's about as disturbing as it could be.
What?
Again,
back to her laughing about getting the
child rapist off.
She then a few days later she's just
cackling it up.
There's a video of a guy stabbing him in
the ass hole.
I mean,
it's insane.
You've seen that,
right?
He takes that knife and he shoves it in
his ass.
Yeah.
While they're talking to them and Kadafi
so fucked up.
He doesn't even know what's happened.
He's like in a state of shock or some
shit.
There's a knife in his ass.
All these people have a hold of them.
They're all yelling alla walk bar.
Yeah,
it's,
that's,
that's a bad way to go.
It's a crazy way to go.
I wonder if that guy with the knife in
his ass,
I wonder if that will be like,
you know that he would,
Jima statue.
They plant the flag.
They'll make a statue of the one guy
with a knife up Qaddafi's ass.
It's like over your fireplace in his
neighborhood.
That will be like,
you know,
that'll be his monument.
I mean,
it's uncle,
he stopped because after you in the ass,
there's a video on youtube,
show it Mama,
and she puts it on the big screen.
Everybody watches it.
Yay.
It's closing your ears.
Bomb bombs going off the background.
Cause Libby's even more fucked up now
than it was then.
That regime change was terrible for the
people who live there.
Oh,
it's not even,
you know,
I think we lose sight of it sometimes
when you,
you'd be like,
you know,
it's like,
oh well they're always fucked up.
So it's a little bit more fucked up.
But,
but Libya was by regional standards,
one of the better places to be in the
Middle East and it is now.
I mean,
uh,
a failed state.
It's,
I mean,
it's just run by thugs and terrorist
organisms,
organizations.
It's,
it's a nightmare.
Yeah.
It's a,
it's a breeding ground for isis now.
Isis is all over the place there now.
She's weird.
She's weird because she gets all these
free passes because she's a woman.
It's very strange because that's,
that's a a giant part of why people want
to support her.
It's almost like,
you know,
we got one of ours in,
we're going to get one of ours in.
Like my wife wants a vote for it because
she's a woman.
I go,
if you have paid attention to what a
country is,
have you really read,
allegedly I should say Clinton toxic and
things.
I'm sorry,
I don't mean it.
I'm saying all this for humor.
She's,
I mean she's not the woman you want to
sound what you're looking for.
You,
she's not a scholar.
Well it's not a wise woman who's got
some really kind words to say she's a
lifelong career politician and like you
said,
and that always,
I mean if you talk to any Hillary
supporters,
it is only sometimes it's not the first
thing they say.
But if you give like give me three
reasons why you want Hillary Clinton and
one of them has to do with her being a
woman.
Yeah.
I think it'd be great to see a woman do
it for change.
And by the way,
that's what she runs on.
She runs on women's issues.
She plays that card all the time.
I mean,
she said like when Donald Trump called
her on that,
she was like,
if I'm a kid is a playing the woman's
card deal me.
And that's her cadence by the way,
it's always this not as knowing you,
you need to be a little more noise.
Just not the pitch.
I don't have the pitch down.
She's she substitute having no charisma
with just volume,
but she's like,
I can just,
if I go louder,
maybe that's charismatic wishes.
She doesn't just have no charisma.
She's oddly transparent in her
creepiness.
Like when she's doing these debates and
Bernie Sanders is calling her out on
taking all that money from the banks and
how she does his speeches for quarter
million dollars and he liked to read the
transcripts.
She just sitting there and while he's
doing that,
just like this weird,
like the seething angry over here.
She's smiling on the outside,
but you know,
deep down she could fucking kill you
like it.
And she's going over her preparation
because they prepped her for this.
So you know,
it come,
it comes out in this weird sort of
robotic I kido move where she's trying
to push it to the side.
Like it's a fucking thug and a Steven
Seagal movie.
It's weird man.
She doesn't really answer it in a way.
It's the only thing that I find a
positive about Hillary Clinton is that
you can constantly,
you can see through her and you can
point to that shit and other people and
go but see how she's full of Shit.
But how about for the woman card thing?
Just the fact that uh,
she's been taking like tens of millions
of dollars from the Saudi government,
something like $100 million from Muslim
dictatorships.
How can you run on the women's issue?
It's like being a Jew,
running on Jewish issues and you do
business with the Nazis.
So this,
this money and does what with it?
Well,
they take it for the Clinton Foundation,
which is like her and bill and Chelsea's
foundation and they do all these
projects and it's all kind of in the
name of charity in the name of
philanthropy.
But it's pretty clearly like you get
like the Saudis aren't giving tens of
millions of dollars to the Clinton
Foundation cause they all of a sudden
decided to be really good people.
They're doing it because they know the
Clintons wield a lot of influence and
this is their way of giving them money.
And the Clintons can use that as
leverage to justify their association
with them.
Cause look all the good it does good
stuff.
But in the meantime they can also do all
these projects and lots of different
companies can make money off these
projects.
And then they get in and we have this
creepy business relationship with Saudi
Arabia who is the worst of the worst.
Like all the shit that we,
you know,
I love a,
I love when the war machine,
whenever there's a war they want,
they get real humanitarian.
All of a sudden like when Obama wanted
to go back in a serious back into Iraq
or when he wants to go into Syria,
it's like,
oh,
these people are getting gassed or you
know,
there's a,
there's a few hundred years.
Eddie is up on the top of a mountain and
they could die.
But when,
when Saudi Arabia is slaughtering their
own people,
when,
when Saddam was gassing people and we
liked him,
that was fine.
It's only when,
when you're on the wrong side of
whatever business deal we are,
we have going on.
All of a sudden they're like,
but think of the people.
All of a sudden John Mccain cares about
Muslim people.
He's playing poker and it's phone.
Wait,
hold on.
This john for a moment and talk about
the people.
It's a little suspicious.
Well it's less suspicious now I guess
then it was in the 1960s and in the
1950s probably before that was even more
fuckery going on.
But it seems like it's more and more
difficult to pull off the really obvious
operation northwoods type shit.
Like there the transparency that we are
enjoying today even though there's still
a lot of questions like what Jeb Bush
was or would um,
uh,
ran.
Paul was saying like we really have no
idea who's running the whole thing at
the very top.
It seems like that's going to be exposed
to eventually it's all going to get
chipped away because information just
travels weight quicker now than it ever
did before and it's just too hard to
hide shit.
You know?
It's like that's it.
That force is on their side too though.
Like we have that force of like
information can spread but they also
have the Predator drones.
Like there was no way a president in the
50s or whatever could have just had the
option to say bomb Yemen,
Syria,
Libya and Pakistan and all these
different countries without sending
troops there are having bases nearby.
So you know,
we have advantages.
They have advantages.
Yeah.
But it's taught.
What I was going to get at is that
what's interesting is what we're seeing
now from the,
like the NSA gathering data on everybody
saying we needed to PK,
but he's safe.
It's almost,
it almost mirrors like with j Edgar
Hoover was doing,
cause j edgar hoover had all that dirt
on him and so to hide it,
he just went after everybody else.
Keep everybody quiet.
Everybody scared.
That mean you could make that same
comparison to this strategy.
The NSA is employable.
Look,
we'll just fucking monitor everything
and then if,
if I say,
oh this dave guys been talking to a lot
of shit,
let's check his emails and it's going to
go back.
Oh look at all this.
I was joking and I just want to say
already I was joking,
but you know what I'm saying.
I mean that's an insidious sort of
device that they can use to keep you
quiet.
Well.
How about the fact that it,
you know,
in 20 years,
right,
if there's some leader who's coming up
who,
who is a would be,
you know,
some type of great leader,
they're going to have grown up just
entirely in the Internet age where the,
if you have all of their metadata
history,
you have everything on that person and
then they can literally just go like,
we want to ruin that guy and everybody's
got something that could be a,
an issue you could insert into a
campaign should ruin them or you know,
if you don't,
you're boring.
Yeah,
yeah,
that's right.
And then I don't want you president
anyway.
If they can't ruin you by checking your
that I don't even want
you,
that's a great way to put it.
If you can't be ruined,
I don't want you to be my leader.
Are you?
You fucking Weirdo.
You pious Weirdo from birth.
Yeah.
It's like you've just been clean,
like going like,
well Ha,
I'll get power Sunday as long as I don't
fuck up and all that.
Oh she looks pretty but stay hungry.
We taught him while he was in his crib.
Keep your cards close to your tests,
Donnie.
But that's like the thing where they
said isn't about George Washington
because they tried to make him out to be
such a great word.
They're like,
his father was like,
did you cut down that cherry tree?
And he was like,
father,
I can't tell a lie.
Like what type of fucking creep was
George Washington?
Or maybe had her like a really open
relationship with his dad or just a dad
who loved him.
Stand out really cool and he knew,
hey man,
somebody chop the tree down.
You've got blisters in your hand.
The fuck's going on,
Bro.
I mean,
there's just really compelling evidence
or maybe yet never fucking happened.
You know?
That's the other maybe more likely.
Yeah.
I mean all these stories that you get
from the 16 hundreds like,
come on,
man,
those are barely people.
Those were monkeys with clothes on it.
They barely know how to write.
And,
and historians like to tell it as if
they know for a fact what happens.
Rather than just being like,
Hey,
here's a nice guests at what maybe
happened.
They'll be like,
he thought about going left,
but then he went right and it was kind
of like,
alright,
yeah.
I've always wondered if one day they'll
be able to create a computer that's so
powerful that it will be able to somehow
through some unseen technology,
take account of everything that's in
place as it is right now in the world.
Then monitor for a certain amount of
time and then go backwards and try to
figure out,
well,
all of these things got into place
because of these events and these
motions and be able to recreate it
digitally.
It sounds ridiculous right now,
but if we can get to a place where they
can literally do an account of
everything that's happened,
everything,
every pebble that's on this earth and
go,
you know what?
We can extrapolate.
We can take all this data and follow it
for a short amount of time and then
within the 99% accuracy,
go back in time and recreate events.
I can,
that sounds so stupid and ridiculous,
but that might be like almost a method
of a virtual time travel.
Like just super calculation.
You just take into account all the
things that we do,
know all the pieces that are in place
right now.
Everything that's there,
all the people that are there and then
figure out how they got their account
for all factors.
Account for everything.
I'm massive,
super calculations.
Impossible for the human mind to even
conceive of.
And then boom,
they have a digital recreation of George
Washington fucking his sister and lying
about the cherry tree.
It was full of shit like to black people
on fire.
Whoa.
George Washington was a piece of shit.
Oh,
allegedly.
I don't mean that for allegedly,
you know what I'm saying?
Alleged cones,
allegedly a piece of shit being
credible.
I mean if they could literally get to a
position where they could do a
calculation that's so complete that they
could feed it into some sort of,
uh,
you know,
someday created virtual reality machine
that will give you like a version of
that.
You can go back and watch the asteroid
that killed the dinosaurs.
If humans can manage to not like destroy
ourselves or we don't have some asteroid
reset or something like that,
we're going to do magical shit like
that.
I'm sure.
I mean,
we're on,
we're already doing magic compared to
what we could do a hundred years ago.
So I mean we're gonna it's the thing is
you can never predict what it would be
exactly.
Like you can never stand back and you
know,
you can't stand back in the year like
1850 and going to be like,
it'll be metal machines running on
dinosaur juice.
You know,
like you just wouldn't know.
But uh,
we'll be doing some magical shit.
Well,
Sam Harris was talking about it and it
was four Rican me out because he was
talking about the power that computers
are going to have once they,
once artificial intelligence become
sentient,
the power that they're going to have to
improve upon themselves and how quickly
that's going to take place,
where thousands of years of progress
it's going to take place in a week.
And you're like,
wait,
what?
And then it's just from there.
Each,
each time the improve,
it improves exponentially.
Thousands more years,
maybe in an hour,
thousands more years in a couple of
seconds.
It's just going to get to some insane
place where he's saying they're
reasonably certain that one day we'll
have a machine.
It's like an Adam machine that you could
shoot out into the universe and given an
amount of time extracting all the
building materials and needs from the
sky,
it will make a planet.
It'll make a planet and inhabit that
planet with intelligent life.
And then we can go there and it'd be
like Miami in the sky.
We'll go there.
There'll be,
I mean,
literally you could create anything.
You might already be living in it.
How we all got here,
even want to Elon Musk's more recents
talks.
He talked about that.
But a lot of people had been saying that
for a long time.
But it's,
it's potentially possible that one day
we're going to have an artificial
reality that's into indecipherable or,
uh,
or you can't tell the difference between
what is fake and what is real.
You will not be able to stay in.
Wish it,
it will,
it will be so good that it will be just
like life.
So if that's the case,
how do you know that you're not already
in it?
Right.
You don't,
you know,
and it's,
it's all,
it's all Mumbo jumbo right now.
Unless you think that it could've
already happened,
then it's not Mumbo jumbo.
And if Harris has,
right,
the real problem with that,
and this is not even his ideas,
this is all these people that are really
at the forefront of all this technology.
We're going to be,
we're not,
we're not going to be,
but something is going to be a god.
I mean,
it literally is going to be able to
create worlds.
Yeah.
It's potentially possible that one day
they're going to have something that
could create a universe.
Yeah.
I mean,
look,
I think there's a,
there's an argument that that's how we
were created.
I mean we're here like we are here.
We do exist.
And truthfully in the reductionist,
atheist scientific way of looking at it,
there's no good reason for that.
But you of course there is.
See,
I don't buy that because the universe is
filled with magical shit.
Like why wouldn't people be here?
Like,
well look at,
look at supernovas.
Look at black holes absorbing galaxies.
Look at,
let me look at solar storms.
Look at flares.
Look at this fucking ball of fire that's
in the sky.
That's a million times bigger than us.
Why is it so weird that people exist?
The whole thing is fucking madness.
Well that's,
well that's I guess,
yeah,
I agree with you.
I'm just saying the whole thing is
magical already.
So what's the,
what's,
you know,
it's humans more magic.
We're not any more magic than everything
that's already out there.
How about the Big Bang?
The whole thing is based on magic.
Yeah.
He'll,
the whole university of something being
created from nothing smaller than the
head of the pin and for whatever reason
instantaneously explodes to sh to create
all the mass,
both seen and unseen.
That's in the galaxy,
including dark matter.
You get through a conversation with this
point where we show we almost should
just come back to just being religious,
like let's just follow the fucking book.
That's what I'm saying like mormonism
where it's so dumb that it's kind of
comforting that you might be beating
everyone.
Yeah.
That all these other people like joining
on this dumb shit and you all agree and
you call each other elders and you're
only 12 there's something about just
belief though,
like like belief might be beating
skepticism of just,
just the way,
I mean I know they do these things where
they measure how your brain acts when
those people are like speaking in
tongues and stuff and you go to some
weird place.
Then just convincing yourself to be
certain of what this existence is might
just put you on a whole different level.
It's like,
oh,
it doesn't even matter what you're
believing and you're just,
as long as you're believing right.
Well,
it exists in a really practical form and
fighting and no,
you're,
you're a big MMA.
For him.
It exists in a really practical form and
fighting because,
you know,
when I,
um,
when I was coaching young people back,
uh,
during the,
taekwondo competing days,
um,
I coached a lot of young people and I
brought a lot of people to tournaments
and stuff like that,
a lot of students.
And one of the things that I've found
was that smarter people had a harder
time with competing,
like,
uh,
like a lot of like the really smart
people that I talked to.
And then I would try to talk to them
about it.
And what I realized is they're more
aware of the variables,
right?
They're more aware of what could go
wrong and that would create anxiety.
And it was very difficult to get people
to just like,
okay,
you have to stay on the path of what
you're trying to do.
You can't look off to the side of the
road.
The fact that this cliff goes a thousand
feet down to the bottom of the canyon,
you can't look at that.
You've got to look on the road,
just the road.
And for a lot of smart people,
they were like,
fuck,
what if I get hit?
What happens if you get hit?
Like,
oh well you're fucked if you get kicked
in the face.
Yeah,
don't get you in the face.
Keep your hands up.
You got to move.
And um,
dumb people were like convinced that
they were going to be fine and I would,
I was always fascinated by that.
I was like,
this is weird because what's interesting
is when the dumb people lost,
it was way more difficult for them to
rebound.
Whereas the smart people lost and they
go,
all right,
well I saw that common.
Now I have to decide whether or not I
still want to compete interests.
Is this the risk I still want to take?
Now I'm aware of the consequences.
I knew it was coming,
so what technically went wrong and how
am I physically?
And you would see people that were
intelligent,
rebound and they would figure out a way
to overcome the challenge or try to at
least.
Whereas lot of smart people or a lot of
dumb people rather were devastated by
losses because it's almost like you took
away that simple belief of theirs.
Now they have to,
you know,
this one guy,
I remember he was talking about how he
was such a good person.
I can't believe this.
You know,
I,
I followed the Lord's word.
I'm a good person.
Why God do this to me?
I was like,
oh no.
Now he's questioning his very existence.
Yeah,
that's rough.
That's a weird thing to see someone have
that.
Cause there's a,
there's an amazing like confidence that
you have to have a,
or like,
uh,
at least you have to get yourself to
that place.
And it took like,
you know,
compete in mma,
like you said,
without looking at the side of the road.
And when you see that broken,
I mean,
when I saw that,
uh,
that Ellen interview with Rhonda Rousey,
Yeah.
That was so crazy to me.
That really made me go like,
maybe she shouldn't fight for a little
while.
Like,
I don't know if I like,
she needs some more time off because
this,
she went from being the like,
I'm going to kill everyone.
No one has a right to beat me.
Don't be a b,
nothing bitch.
And being that chick to being like a,
I wanted to kill myself.
I've got to just have Travis Brown's
babies.
And I was like,
Whoa,
she's gone from being this like
untouchable.
I mean not even like she was like the
best female fighter.
It was like don't even,
she's wrecking chicks in a second and
then to seeing her kind of broken.
Well,
what's interesting is these themed play
themselves out over and over again.
And the traps are all there,
but everybody keeps going for the candy
and they keep getting caught in the
traps.
The traps of Hollywood are always there
for any superstar athlete,
especially fighters.
And you know,
we've seen it all throughout history
with Tommy Morrison gets in the rocky
movie and all of a sudden everybody's
looking at him like Tommy Marson is
going to be the white hub.
And then Ray Mercer beats the living
fuck out of them.
And you just saw like fear and
overwhelming anxiety attack him cause
he's in this movie and he's on the red
carpet and everybody's saying,
you going to be the champ one day,
honey.
I was like,
Oh fuck.
And then it becomes this whole thing.
He's hanging with Sylvester stallone.
They're probably doing blow and banging
hookers allegedly,
allegedly.
But you know what I mean?
It's like it becomes this Hollywood trap
and Rhonda was a Jew and still is a
giant superstar,
right?
She's this undefeated women's fighter.
She's crushing all the competition.
She looks like a destroyer and then the
fucking traps this,
all these movies start coming out,
all this,
all these deals start getting made.
Books start getting written.
All these television shows and all this
stuff and all the traps and all those
traps,
they keep you focus.
They take steal little bits of your
focus,
like I'm good enough to get by without
all that focus.
But there's no way,
because there's another person like you
out there,
there's a lot of people like you out
there and they don't have those traps.
And if they don't have those traps are
going to have more attention that's
being paid right away.
They had an advantage because they have
their full focused on this.
And there's also something dangerous to
someone like Rhonda Rousey.
But by the way,
obviously it's just incredible.
I mean,
she's the reason why women's mma is a
huge thing.
Uh,
but I think there's something dangerous
about being such an amazing grappler
getting a couple of knockouts and all of
a sudden feeling this kind of like,
oh yeah,
you know,
she got the knee to a mcmahon and stops
it with one knee.
And then what was the other chick who
she,
she hit the overhand who face planted
Alexis Davis.
Yeah.
And so now it's kind of going in there
and even going in there with like a
world class,
a boxer like a Holly Holm,
she kind of goes in there with,
they're like,
well,
I can knock people out too.
And I think that's a dangerous,
you know,
all,
you know what is a dangerous
combination?
It's like being a blue belt and he
choked out a bunch of white belts and
you think you're the shit and then all
of a sudden you're rolling with Damien
Maia and he wraps you up like a
Christmas present.
Beats the fuck out of you and chokes
you.
Unconscious easy.
You know?
I mean,
there's levels of everything.
And to deny those levels because anybody
who looked at her fights would see like,
okay,
you have this Rhonda Rousey.
This fierce competitor was one of the
best judo,
um,
examples of Judah.
We've ever seen an MMA.
I mean her judo spectacular reason why
she was a medalist in the Olympics.
I mean,
she's a sensational competitor.
Her grappling is outstanding.
Her arm bar technique is amongst the
best in the world,
but she's knocking out these girls
there.
There's no,
they're nowhere near Worldclass as far
as like kickboxing and striking is
concerned.
Right.
Holly Holm is 100% worldclass she is an
18 time world boxing champion.
I mean she's a kickboxing champion.
She was in,
uh,
an MMA competitor for a couple of years
before she got into the UFC where she
was having these ridiculous head kick
chaos.
Yeah.
She's a beast.
And for her to think that she's going to
treat this woman,
this Holly Holm woman,
the same way she was able to bully like
Batchko Heyah and I say billy,
not in a negative way.
I mean just,
just attacker and go after Batchko Hey,
I was,
she slow and awkward and not that
athletic.
Holly Holm bounces around that cage like
a fucking kangaroo.
Yeah.
She does all these back flips and shit.
She's spectacular.
The athletic and the idea that you're
going to have the same approach they
used on Batchko go,
hey,
uh,
with someone like Holly Holm,
that's just madness.
And that's something that happens when
people get so absorbed with this idea
that they're special.
So absorbed with this idea that,
you know,
when you're on top,
you think you are the fucking person.
You're the woman,
you're the man,
you're the shit.
No one's going to fuck with you.
I'm just wandering through this bitch.
And then you get cracked and then you
realize,
oh,
this game doesn't give a fuck.
This game doesn't give a fuck about your
charisma.
It doesn't give a fuck about the vegas
odds.
It doesn't give a fuck about how much
money you made or how many times you've
been on entourage or amazing.
It's an amazing thing about mma.
It's why I have so much respect for
everybody who competes.
But it's like no one can escape this
game's wrath.
No,
I mean,
j like John Jones still has a lot of his
career to go and he does.
He has one loss on his record,
but it was not dominant you when,
uh,
but you know,
you see these guys,
like you see Anderson Silva and he's
just like,
he's a Ninja.
He's untouchable.
He's the greatest fighter ever.
And then you see him like crying on the
ground with a shattered,
not shattered,
but whatever.
When he broke his shin.
Well,
how about when he cried in the ground
after he won against Nick Diaz?
He fell to the ground
fighter ever.
By the way,
Nick Dsi is just,
it's pretty awesome.
I mean,
the Diaz brothers are just the greatest
fighters of all time.
They certainly are.
Um,
yeah.
But yeah,
well,
from going full circle then when he
comes back and wins in the octagon.
But I mean,
it's,
it's an incredible thing.
It makes you look,
I mean,
when watching Chuck Liddell,
who I just,
you know,
at a certain point you were like,
that guy's just unbeatable.
He's like Superman.
And then to see him getting knocked out
and kind of his chin,
you know,
slowly start to go,
yeah,
it's,
it's like this,
this game just came,
doesn't give a fuck,
doesn't give a fuck about your opinions.
Doesn't give a fuck about what you think
when knuckles hit Chin's legs go limp.
And that's just how it goes.
And we saw that in the rockhold bisping
fight.
You know,
rockhold had this look about him that
almost like he was bored,
that he was just like,
I'm going to go.
I mean,
part of that I'm sure as gamesmanship,
he's trying to get inside bisping's head
that he's so much better than him,
that he doesn't even have to like be
serious and be concerned.
And then bisbing clips him with his left
hook over the shoulder where he's barely
seen it.
You called it,
it was a greg,
is that what you said?
Like a few beats before that we were
like,
Luke rockhold is keeping his chin right
up in the air and he's kind of like a
little lacks of days ago.
Yeah,
I remember you,
uh,
in the,
um,
in the Hennen Barao dillashaw fight the
first one,
which is like a huge upset,
no one saw that coming.
Uh,
and I remember you,
you sang as it was,
you're like,
man,
until the show is really light on his
feet.
I was really relaxed.
Like sometimes you could just see a
little thing in the way they're moving.
They like.
Hmm.
That's kind of interesting.
Yeah.
I was telling you before we started
recording my,
my buddy hilarious comedian,
one of my best friends,
Lewis j Gomez,
he does a radio show with Michael
bisbing.
Right.
And you've had a big Jay.
I'm going to show the three of us do a
podcast,
a legion of skanks you you got to have
Lewis on.
You'll fucking,
I would love to.
He's like Jay.
Yeah,
Jay Jay is a,
I've got a special coming out,
which is going to be just incredible.
What's it on?
A comedy central hour.
Oh,
cool.
I'll coming out on,
I believe it's,
I want to say June 17th,
but I might like one of those days,
it's called a live at webster hall.
It's going to be a fucking incredible
special look for that.
Jay Z,
like one of the funniest comedians on
the planet.
Very funny.
Louis J.
Gomez is just one of the funniest people
I've ever met in my life.
He's a great comedian.
He's like bigger than a standup
comedian.
He's like the Bert Kreischer of the east
coast.
He's just a hilarious person.
Uh,
but so he's doing a show with,
with Michael Bisman,
they do a show called the countdown on
Sirius Radio and he started doing the
show.
I mean this is before bisbing has the
Anderson Silva fight and it did almost
seem kind of like bisping was a great
fight or a big name,
but seemed like he was kind of,
you know,
going towards the end of his career.
Like he had a couple injuries,
had the eye thing and you're kind of
like,
oh he was,
he was a contender.
Well explain the,
I think cause the I think is pretty bad.
Yeah.
You probably know better than he has a
detached retina and his oil in his eye,
they had to inject oil into where his,
I sit so that his retina won't tear
again.
So he has one eye that looks almost like
cross side and it's kind of black like
is like he's on ecstasy.
Like one pupils dilated.
It's very weird
and he doesn't give a fuck.
He's got that one I fucked up and he
doesn't give a shit.
He's still going in there and settling
in.
That guy's born for this,
this,
this motherfucker went out and fought
Anderson Silva won one of the gutsiest
performances I've ever seen him.
I mean he,
the,
the first two rounds that he beat
Anderson were just incredible.
And then the fact that he got almost put
out in the third round and came back and
won the fourth round and it was a fucked
up thing because he was trying to say
that his mouthpiece was out and he tried
to circle to,
I don't know who the referee was.
Herb.
Yeah.
And he's like,
but herb's like,
look,
it doesn't matter like you got to,
I'm not stopping it.
You don't,
you can't call when to stop the action
because you could say that the
mouthpieces out or you could just spit
your mouthpiece that whenever someone,
you know,
like landed a big show,
people do time and people do do that.
But you know,
herb was like,
look,
you can't say to me that your mouthpiece
out,
I know your mouth pieces out,
but you got to keep fighting.
Then boom,
Anderson lands a flying knee on the jot
and then Anderson walks away with his
hands up.
It's so crazy as if he won.
So crazy.
Herb didn't call the fight yet.
So then the bell rings.
So then bisping has to get up and
recover in a minute from getting
chaotic.
It was madness.
He got a little bit of extra time
because Anderson Silva celebrate it.
Yes.
So I think he got like an extra 30
seconds or so.
But I mean,
but then right.
So,
and by the way to,
that's got to fuck Anderson up to cause
Anderson's,
now I've got this like adrenaline dump
and then you saw on his face,
he's like,
what?
No,
we're back to fighting it.
But bisping man,
that fourth round,
he just bit down on his mouthpiece and
walked him down.
Yeah,
I mean it was incredible.
Crazy.
And then after that being the greatest
ever to come and you get on a,
on an injury,
right?
You get a title shot with 10 days'
notice.
He fights the greatest ever.
I mean arguably Anderson's on the
downslide but definitely,
let's not say arguably,
I mean losing twice to Weidman.
He just didn't look the same when he
fought Nick Diaz suspended for steroids,
comes back and,
and you know,
but he's still Anderson Silva.
So that victory,
he gets that victor over the greatest of
all time and then first round knockout
over Luke rockhold you know,
it's fucked up.
I was,
I was literally considering saying that
Luke rockhold looks overconfident and
when you're overconfident you can get
knocked out.
And I'm like,
I don't want to be a deck.
And then boom,
he gets knocked out.
But you did make the comment about him
holding a,
about him not having his head right
there on the center line of sort of
relaxed.
It was super relaxed with his chin
straight up.
He was pulling out of things with his
chin straight up.
It's almost like there was no danger.
And that was one of the things that he
was saying that,
you know,
he was in no danger.
And it was also one of the same things
that Uriah Faber was saying.
Like the difference between me and
cruises.
I can hurt him,
I can take him out.
And then when you see your riot got
caught,
I think it was a second round,
I got dropped and you realize he's in
deep trouble.
Like you realize holy Shit,
like I can get knocked out too.
And all those guys in,
you know,
it's,
it's uh,
it's funny when you get it like Michael
Bisping was guy who the knock on him I
guess was that he didn't have knockout
power or whatever.
You're talking about like a a 200,
I mean fighting at two.
Oh,
I got it cuts down probably,
I'm sorry,
one 85.
So probably someone,
someone who weighs close to 200 pounds.
It's a 200 pound guy who specializes in,
in striking.
Yeah.
And he can fucking knock you out of
course.
And he proved it.
He doesn't,
he doesn't fight like a,
like a brawler like he fights like a
technician.
Yeah.
And when you fight like a technician,
you don't swing wild crazy ass punches
with everything on them with your,
you know,
vandelay Silva style,
you try to find openings and that's what
he did.
He found the opening with that left hook
was really sneaky.
He had missed it before.
He was like stepping in and throwing the
left took over the shoulder and kind of
like stepping into the punch.
And boy when he caught luke,
he caught him at the end of the chin,
which really like fucking spins your
head.
All the torque is perfectly placed and
then you caught him with another
brilliant one right afterwards.
It's followed up.
Yeah man.
Dude.
And you know he's had like all sorts of
fucking crazy injuries.
Back injuries,
neck injuries,
his fucking arm thing.
Yeah,
he's just tough man.
He just keeps going.
It just keeps going.
She had no question about that.
That dude's as tough as they come in.
I know I'm never fixed him just because
he's one of those guys who's like been
around forever and always kind of been
knocking at the door.
So it's nice to see him.
You know,
get his moment well was crazy to see.
Well you see like there's knockout
power,
right?
And then there's like Dan Henderson
Kinda knock out power that it's just
like,
Geez fucking cry.
Like Dan Henderson feels like this table
when you put your arm on him and he's
not flexing.
He's like the,
like Ryan Parsons,
who's a buddy of mine who was his
manager for a long time,
said that he would do massage on him and
he would be exhausted.
He's like,
he's would the guys made out of wood.
So like when you look at them,
you look at me go,
well it looks like a,
you know,
strong athletic guy.
But if you felt him,
you realize where all this power comes
from.
He's like,
he's built different,
there's something going on with him.
And he does.
When you were saying people who don't
put everything into one punch,
he puts everything into it.
I mean,
it's like coming at Ya and it's so weird
the way he moves to,
he moves in a weird way because he's
very stiff.
He's not fluid like John Jones or like
Anderson is very fluid in his movements.
Dan is like very stiff,
but when he uncorked those bombs on you,
they just detonate and you're just like,
what the fuck hit me like hector lumbar.
It's never been knocked out to see
hector lumbar getting knocked out by,
well,
he got head kicked.
He's probably stunned by that head kick
and then he got blasted with that back
elbow.
He was out cold.
He was out cold when he hit the ground
and then Henderson blast them again but
like,
Whoa,
I,
I saw it.
I was like,
who the fuck hits?
Like this guy is like,
it's almost like you want him to hit you
just so he could feel it a bit harder.
Is that the normal what it,
what the fuck are you doing?
I want to start by like standing next to
a guy who he hits like hit him real
close to me.
I want to feel it.
His Kale of bisping UFC 100 was one of
the most brutal one punch shots and the
history of combat sports.
It was just boom,
bisping's dead stiff,
and then Henderson's airborne long
before the referee can get to them and
just slams him in the face on the way
down.
And then from there out,
one of his logos was the silhouette of
him flying through the air and knocking
out bisbing.
So imagine being best bang.
Not only do you have to deal with the
fact this guy fucking knocked you out in
spectacular fashion,
but his logo is flying through the air,
hitting you after you're already
unconscious.
I would,
I would just say,
hang on.
In a few years,
you'll be champ and you'll have a show
with Louis J.
Gomez and everything will be good.
What year was UFC?
200 it's a wild man.
That was brock lesnar.
I want one.
Yeah,
100 yeah.
100 was like,
was it 2012 no,
earlier than that,
probably.
What year was that,
Jamie?
I just pulled something up.
It wasn't ufc one 14 popped up.
It wasn't definitely,
wasn't that right?
It was UFC 100 yeah.
Let me see.
Yeah,
it was the biggest paper view of all
time was brock Lesnar's rematch with
Frank Mir and GSP photo tiago album 2009
2009 it was that long ago.
Whoa.
That's nuts.
Yeah,
that was fucking weird.
It's been a long fucking longer than I
would've thought.
Yeah,
definitely.
I guess it is like a hundred UFC is
later.
Yeah.
Wow.
So seven years later he wins the title
crazy.
You're a look.
There's going to be the same card on the
same card.
Right?
You good?
Look,
there's gonna be some ups and downs.
Your retina is going to get all types of
fucked up,
but you will be champion one day and no
one takes that away from him ever.
Could you imagine if him and Henderson
had a rematch for the title?
Good Lord.
Can that be made?
I wonder if that could be made ethically
because if you look at all the other
contenders,
all the people waiting in line,
Chris White,
Jacques Perrey,
Vittorio,
there's just too many.
Yeah,
there's too many,
but two,
boy,
it's hard.
It's a hard sell because v toward just
knocked out Henderson in the first
round,
you know it's handled.
Yeah.
It's just man,
vito knocked out bisping in Brazil and
you're knocked out rockhold but he just
got smashed by Jacques Perrey.
Everything in the middleweight division
is just completely up in the air and
it's all,
it's all turned up to that.
So weird in MMA will happen.
Like you're kind of like,
oh okay,
I think I know where everything's
sounds.
And then one thing changes and you're
like,
oh,
I don't know anything.
I guess you never know anything because
you're only looking at the guys that are
in the UFC right now and there's a whole
fucking series of murders that are out
there that are just getting ready to
enter.
And there's young kids that are like 20
that are just coming into their own and
in four years they might be the best
fighter in the world.
Yeah,
there's so many of,
so it's like,
could the cody garb brands that are
emerging,
you know,
they emerge then with one fight against
Almeda you'd go,
oh Jesus,
this kid is fucking killer.
And the 135 pound division and one of
the top contenders now instantly.
Yeah,
with one standout performance,
you know,
and there's just good,
there'll be more divisions.
Like you were kind of talking about that
when we were at the store the other
night.
Like you want to see more divisions and
Emma,
there'll be more divisions,
more fighters I think.
Right?
I hope so.
There hasn't been enough progress in
that.
I really think that this should be a
weight class every 10 pounds.
I really do.
I think there's a lot of,
there's a lot of opportunities for not
just more champions,
which I think is better for the sport,
but guys to be able to fight in their
actual weight class would be
competitive.
There's some gaps like 85 to two oh five
man,
there's a,
that's a big gap.
That is a giant gap,
a 20 pound gap.
And you know,
most guys,
they're probably going to be in the
middle.
So if you had an 85 and 95 and a two o
five that's where it should be.
You know?
That's,
I think that's,
that's how boxing does.
And also I think it gives you much more
opportunity for you guys to fight
champion versus champion,
you know,
and to move up or move down like fairly
easily.
I got,
they got an 85 can move down to 75 ways
or than an 85 could go up to two oh five
and they could go back and forth and you
could have some like really awesome a
title unification bouts or you know,
champion versus champion bounce.
Right.
Yeah.
No,
I think I agree with that.
And I like,
I mean,
I liked seeing the people,
I like seeing the weight class.
I love Khan are moving up to fight nate.
I mean,
although I guess you don't need more
weight classes.
You went up to one 70 yeah.
That wasn't even a move up.
That was just like it let's not cut.
Yeah.
Well it wasn't move up and tell me,
am I crazy about this?
But why I,
I've wondered this a lot and I've never
really gotten a good answer on it,
but why do we have the weight cuts?
Like,
why don't we just weigh in an hour
before the event because you want to be
hundred yourself before that,
fine,
but this dangerous guys are still going
to cut weight.
That's how guys die.
Guys die from being dehydrated and
getting hit in the head.
I mean you can definitely die from just
getting hit in the head,
but isn't it?
Wouldn't it add,
and maybe this is just stupid,
but wouldn't it regulate itself because
it's like if the APP,
if the Wayans an hour before the fights
and you're going to dehydrate yourself,
you're going to get fucked up in the
fight.
Like you're not going to have time to
replenish yourself,
but why do this whole thing where we're
weighing in and out 24 hours before guys
are dehydrating themselves,
then refuel it.
Why not just fight the way connor,
nate fought to very good point and be
hydrated.
It's a very good point.
Another point could be to outlaw weight
cutting entirely and to check people all
throughout camp and to make match ups
based on size.
Like look at,
look at two guys.
You know,
you say,
what do you walk around that?
What do you walk around that?
Okay,
you guys will be fighting at that
weight,
you know,
or whatever the weight is when you're in
best shape.
You know,
if you get down to one 75 when you're in
your best shape,
you,
you tell us what that number is,
tell us what that number is.
We'll match you up accordingly.
And we're going to chess people's
hydration levels all throughout camp.
We're going to show up just like you
sought it,
does and test you for drugs.
We're going to make you get on a scale.
I'm going to test your hydration levels.
And when you're at a a reasonably
hydrated level where it's healthy,
that's your weight,
that's what you weigh now.
So if you want to lose weight,
you better lose weight by,
you better do some extra running and you
better drop some body fat,
but you're not going to be dehydrated.
Yeah,
I mean,
seeing as how we can,
we can figure all that stuff out.
It just seems like there'd be an easier
answer.
Now,
of course.
Obviously there's,
there's the commissions in the way,
which I don't,
I don't believe in any government
regulations,
so I don't think they should be there
for any commission has done a fantastic
job.
California Commission Commissions,
no joke.
This guy,
Andy foster who runs it,
I think he runs a great organization and
what he did was the opposite approach.
He let them weigh in from 10:00
AM to 2:00
PM he gave him an open window.
He said,
look,
we're going to be open.
Just come down to wait.
We don't want,
this is what he didn't want.
He doesn't want guys dehydrated standing
around,
weakening themselves for that one moment
where they have to stand on on the scale
in front of a camera.
He's like,
this is all an artificially orchestrated
event.
He's like,
how about this?
We'll have them,
they'll come in,
we'll have athletic commission officers
ready on standby all morning for these
guys to weigh in.
They come in,
they weigh in.
Then once we record it,
make sure they're cool,
they can rehydrate and they have many,
many more hours to rehydrate.
So guys,
we're rehydrating six hours earlier.
Most of the guys showed up at 10:00
AM they made weight and then they had
way more time.
So when you saw people stand on the
scale,
I was saying official weight,
when I was announcing it,
they had weighed in at 10 o'clock in the
morning.
So it was already four in the afternoon.
These guys were hydrated and thick.
No one looks sick.
So at least visually,
no one looked like,
like conor mcgregor looked when he
fought Chad Mendez when they weighed in
and he looked like a dead man.
Dead man cheeks were all sucked in.
It looks horrible.
I mean,
look,
you did good in the fight.
Yeah.
But uh,
he really did.
He cuts a lot to get to one 45.
He's a big boy.
He's way bigger than,
um,
like Jose Aldo and Josie all was cutting
a lot at one point in his career.
I,
by the way,
I've never,
and I'm a hardcore fan,
I've never enjoyed the fight more than I
enjoyed nate Diaz,
conor mcgregor.
I was turning over lots of my mind so
much.
At the end of the fight.
I mean,
I'm like a huge Diaz Fan.
Yeah.
And that was just incredible.
I mean,
I'm 10 days notice.
Yup.
Well that whole um,
two card or that to fight,
um,
event,
the two fights,
the final fights,
the Holly Holm you should take was one
of the most exciting endings to any
fight ever.
When Misha took holly down in the fifth
round a fight when she was losing it
took her back and choked her.
That's insane.
I read an article today where someone
was saying that it was,
that me should loss virtually every
second.
It was from a guy I respect a writer and
she wanted the second,
I was like,
what are you talking about?
The second round she took her down and
pounded her.
I think they did they give her a 10,
eight,
yes.
It didn't just get,
and they should,
she dominated.
So I read this article,
this is espn writer wrote it and I was
like,
wait a minute man.
Come on.
You can't say that like,
why are you saying that?
Like that's,
that's silly hyperbole.
Right.
It doesn't even make any sense.
Um,
and me show it was threatening in the
third and fourth after that holly was on
her bike.
She was like,
fuck this.
Like she was fighting perfect and super
cautious with no chances and barely
winning those rounds,
you know,
just winning them but barely winning.
It wasn't nothing,
nothing big happened and definitely no
threat.
So that victory when Miesha tate choked
out,
holly and Holly's punching in the air,
like how fucking dramatic is that going
out cold punching in the air while she's
going out.
And then nate beating up connor and that
second round after he gets fucked up in
the first round,
beating him up in the second round and
then choking him.
Yeah,
insane.
Probably what two,
two of the most exciting finishes to any
fight ever.
And the,
and the corner thing was just insane
because he was on a tear that was like,
you know,
one of the biggest tears and MMA history
and uh,
to watch it go down like that.
Especially like you said,
like he was winning the fight and then
nate turns it around and it was almost
like on a drop of a dime,
like nay,
nay,
like came to life in that second round
and starts talking shit.
So it was really fun in a home for the
job.
Yeah,
you hit him with that big one too and it
was like,
oh,
has a snake,
like one to two.
He like whap and then he liked slithers
around.
You can't find them with the counter.
He's really good.
And there's no one worse than a nate or
Nick Diaz to get hurt by in a fight
because once they hurt you,
they just like,
they push a pace and then when you get
hurt they like pick it up and pick it
up.
And then all of a sudden,
I mean before you know it,
conner's hit like 25 fucking times on
the feet and he's shooting for a take
down.
Those guys are always doing triathlons.
So even though nate is like you're
taking that fight in 11 days notice and
he wasn't in shape,
he's still in way better shape than most
people.
So like him going five rounds is not
unfeasible.
It's not,
it's not outside of the realm of
imagination.
He's in shape.
He's just not the kind of shape that
he's going to be when they have a
rematch.
And that becomes a real fucking problem.
Cause I think he's going to beat him up
again with nate sad.
He's like goes,
he goes,
I,
if I had a camp,
we wouldn't have fucking touch me.
He goes,
my plan was to go out slow in the first
round and he came out fast enough in the
first round.
So I got tagged a couple times.
But that's so cool.
That's cool.
Stick to the plan,
stick to the plan.
And then the second round it starts
loosening up and opening up and conor
was just dead.
Yeah.
Well I heard,
I mean people are talking to nate about,
cause you know,
going into that fight,
like Connor's power was what a lot of
people were talking about.
Like,
you know,
we put one punch on Josie Aldos Chin and
he's out and he's talking,
he's like,
they can't handle my power.
I don't do courses as well.
But uh,
but uh,
and nate was saying in one of the post
fight interviews where it was like,
I'm spoiling with Andre Ward and Joe
Schilling and like heavyweight boxers.
I'm doing rounds with heavyweight
boxers.
There's nothing you're going to hit him
with that he hasn't seen or kind of
dealt with when he's,
I mean,
you know,
like talking like Andre Ward and Joe
Schilling,
like,
yeah,
decent strike.
You're saying literally the best,
the best,
the best inboxing and the best of the
kickboxing.
Well,
Joe Schilling cuts wait to kickbox at
185 pounds and knocks dude's dead dead
with one punch.
So that guy is sparring with nate on a
regular basis.
Andre Ward,
who is one of the best fucking boxers on
the planet earth.
One of the slickest said that nate gives
as good as it gets when they split.
Yeah,
yeah,
that's crazy.
And I think Joe Schilling,
I might be getting it,
but I think Joe Schilling said he's
never hurt either one of them in a
sparring session.
I think he said that on a fighter and
the kid,
ah,
I believe it man.
Tough fucking dudes,
man.
Tough fucking dudes.
But what's fascinating to me is that he
wanted to jump right back in there and
do it again.
And that nate wanted to,
or that I'm connor wanted to just run it
back and I was like,
wow,
that's interesting.
It seems weird that he gets to do that.
Not so much that he wants to,
but it just seems weird that they were
like,
uh,
like even when Dana White was talking
about in his like,
look man,
we tried to convince them to go down to
one 45.
And he was like,
nate's the y'all.
I was like,
wait,
he's the matchmaker now.
He just gets to go let them.
If you want,
if you want to make a ton of money,
right?
Man,
I believe in the market and that guy's,
that guy's what people want to see.
He can do what he can do.
Whatever he wants to do,
it's going to get a big pay day off it.
But it's not just that the emperor has
been stripped down.
Okay.
So now he's exposed.
So now someone's beating them.
So here's the thing,
what do you do now?
You want to make money?
Okay.
Cause if you want to make money,
you make the biggest fight you can right
now while he's been exposed.
And the biggest fight for sure,
he said,
when I say expose,
I don't mean he's not talented.
I mean exposed,
meaning he's a human and he can lose.
And that happens with every fighter they
lose.
And once they lose,
people go,
oh,
you can be beat.
You know,
we saw it with Anderson Silva.
You saw it with Mike Tyson when after
Mike Tyson fight buster Douglas,
who was a different world.
Everybody was like,
oh,
he's human.
So I say exposed,
not in a disrespectful way,
but got exposed.
He lost.
He got choked out and got beaten up on
the ground and then he got choked out
quick.
So this is not an invulnerable,
perfect fighter who's unbelievably
durable,
right?
Who can take punishment like no man.
There's a lot of those guys in the UFC,
there's champions like that in the UFC
that are like Robbie lawler,
unbelievably durable.
You can't put him away.
It's fucking hard to put that guy away.
We're not talking about that.
We're talking about a guy got dinged up,
shot for a Shitty,
wide open take down,
take him down and got demolished on the
ground and got choked unconscious
quickly afterwards.
So,
all right.
What do you do?
Could that happen with dos Anjos fuck.
Yad could dosantos could do that too.
It's possible.
I mean,
condom might knock 'em out.
You never know.
Conner does have that punch,
but you got to put him in against nate
again because that's the big money
rematch.
And if,
if this guy turns out to be a guy who's
going to win some and lose some and the
beginning of his career,
this unbeatable wild Celtic warrior
character.
Oh that's all gone.
But he's champ.
He's still got a belt at one 45 yeah,
I'm so,
it's almost kind of like a weird
position for now.
But I mean,
here's my question.
When I say for now,
can you really keep banking that weight?
That's what I'm saying.
Well,
I've wondered about that too.
I've heard some people have argued with
me saying like,
no,
he can make the weight.
Cause he was,
he was what it was.
He one 69 against.
So they're saying he basically,
that's what he starts at and he can just
cut down from there.
That's a lot.
But look what he looked like at the,
at the way in.
So maybe you can,
I mean he kind of,
he definitely can do it.
It's physically possible.
I was so looking forward to the press
conference though,
just because I can't,
you know,
you've got this guy in connor who's like
the ultimate shit talker and then you've
got nate who,
I mean the first,
the dynamic of the first press
conference was amazing.
It was amazing.
And at that moment when he was just like
kind of talking circles around nate and
they just broke and he goes,
how about this?
Fuck you fuck your belt.
Fuck this press conference.
Like they just went to gangster on them.
But now like how can con I was so
interested like how can he show up and
talk shit like that.
Yeah.
When nate's got the perfect rebuttal
that anything he has to say,
okay John,
10 days [inaudible] st all kinds of
crazy stuff.
Like the first eight minutes were easy,
eh?
Yeah.
But here's the difference between the
first day I,
her last three minutes,
the last three were a lot worse.
Yeah,
they were awful.
Like you got fucked up,
man.
Do you got to just accept that?
But that's part of his thing is that he
has to like look at things in the most
positive light possible.
And Man,
I don't know.
Um,
I think stylistically it's a troublesome
fight for him because nate is a very
clever boxer and his ground game is a
world away from where connor is right
now.
And I've seen nate role with guys.
He's a fucking legit,
very high level Brazilian Jiu Jitsu
black belt under a very respected camp.
His cardio was outstanding,
his boxing's nasty.
So where's Connor's shining?
The only way I think,
I mean,
I guess there's like,
you know,
it's,
it's really hard to like fight a diaz
brother and beat them.
You usually when people beat them,
it's kind of like they really stick to a
strategy.
You got to kind of take them down and
avoid submissions or like leg kick and
circle.
I hope on Joe's beat him up in that way.
But you know what,
there's also different show up.
Well,
there's also,
you know,
different camps.
You know,
you're coming in,
who knows what kind of fucking injuries
you're dealing with.
You know,
you see a guy like nate come in and look
really kind of lackadaisical against,
um,
Hoffeld dos Anjos den.
You see him come back and look shredded
against Michael Johnson and looks
sensational.
So you go,
okay,
that's what he's capable of when he's on
and focus,
you gotta be ready for that guy.
And I think that,
yeah,
that's the best he's ever looked at.
You and Michael Johnson fight.
Yeah.
You can't think that the guy who lost
dos Anjos is showing up.
You got to think of the guy that came
out and swarmed cowboy in the first
round is coming.
Like,
that guy's a clever fucking boxer.
So where does connor shine?
Knock out power?
That's where he shines.
Like connor can dead dudes,
but he couldn't do it.
Yeah,
they're tough to hit.
They have great head movement and Green
Chins and they there,
they roll with punches.
Well,
the only guy to ever stopped nate was
Josh Thompson and Josh did.
It was a brutal head kick.
And Josh Thompson to this day,
I say it's one of the most underrated
guys.
He just,
he did the stars,
did not align for him,
but he could have easily been a UFC
champion.
He was champion a strikeforce and with
Gilbert and him and Gilbert went back
and forth,
you know,
Josh Thompson's worldclass fighters.
So when Josh Thompson head kicked him,
you know,
it's like Josh to do that to anybody in
that division and then it catches you.
You know,
you're fucked.
He sees the older now and he's just,
you know,
I think he's a guy that like,
like I said,
the stars didn't like perfectly aligned,
but like skill wise and technique wise,
he's a fucking world class fighter.
So when he knocked out nate Diaz,
it's not necessarily an indication that
nate diaz has done because just,
you know,
that's how good Josh Thompson is.
Yeah.
And at the time,
and then,
so nate rebounds from that.
And I think people,
you look at like the losses,
like the Dos Anjos fight,
and you look at that,
the Josh Thomson fight,
and you go,
well,
how good is he?
You know,
I could beat that guy.
But then you look at the Michael Johnson
finding
go,
Ooh that that guy is fucking dangerous.
Jim Miller.
Serone exactly.
Lot of these fights where he just
unbelievable.
Uh,
and I think uh,
it's,
it's one of those things were styles
make fights and you know,
kind of really gotten people's heads by
talking shit.
And I felt like going in,
I was like,
I don't think you're going to get in
nate's head by talking shit.
He's not that guy.
How about this?
My crew will fuck up your whole crew
gangster thing you could say,
by the way,
that's the most gangster thing cause
he's literally just going,
we'll fucking jump you like we're not
playing around here.
And all those guys,
even the guys who seem like kind of Nice
guys in his team,
like jake shields,
you feel like he'll fucking jump.
You guys are fuck area and it'll kick
your ass.
What?
That's some breaking news.
That's it.
Since we've been going live.
The first one is this UFC lifts ban and
reporter Ariel Helwani.
Oh the second one is a little less
exciting.
Wait a minute,
hold on.
Go back to that.
It says reported that wrestler Brock
Lesnar's didn't talks for attorney UFC
200 preempting a UFC announcement.
Officials issued a life band against
him.
The organization reverse a decision
Monday.
That's kind of cool because that means
that like public support made them lift
that,
but it also must mean that they worked
out whatever the fuck it was.
See this is what they were saying and
this is,
this is what I'm hearing.
Okay.
Let me just,
I don't,
I haven't talked to Ariel,
but let me just give you the UFC
perspective.
The UFC perspective was that there was a
mole.
They believe that someone was giving
Ariel information and that information
he was using to scoop the UFC official
promotions.
So the UFC,
which is a private company,
you know,
they don't have to have,
if you don't have to let people in to
your,
your business,
your private companies to come and
report.
And so they felt like he was somehow or
another getting ahold of this inside
information,
releasing it and making them look bad.
Now I get the UFC is perspective that
they would want to know who the fuck is
leaking this secret information and that
they don't,
they don't want this guy taking that
information and then putting it live.
Now,
from what I understand,
the conversation with him was,
don't do this because if you do this,
there's only a handful of people that
know this information.
So we're going to fire everybody or
we're going to fire a bunch of people
and you're gonna ruin people's lives.
This is what I was told.
It was a conversation they had with him
after that conversation.
He leaked the brock lesnar stuff so
that,
I don't know if that's true.
I would have to talk to Arielle.
You'd have to get his opinion.
You'd have to get the UFC as opinion.
You'd have to get the two of them
together to debate whether or not which
story was true.
But this is the side that you're not
hearing.
So all you're hearing is the UFC banned
him for life and everybody was upset.
So I like Ariel.
I think errol is a very good reporter.
I think he's a very bright guy.
I'm good friends with his uncle Gad sad,
who's a,
a full disclosure.
Awesome.
Uh,
just a brilliant,
brilliant professor in Montreal.
I love that guy.
So I like Ariel and I,
the whole thing was bumming me out.
I was looking at my twitter feed.
I was like,
oh fucking.
But th there's certain things like this.
You got to kind of let the dust settle.
So the dust settled,
they lifted the ban.
I'm very happy with that.
But you gotta be careful when it comes
to see.
Here's the thing about this leaking
information.
People say it was just doing his job
reporting.
I get that.
I understand that.
But you have to realize this isn't like
news that is not going to get out.
That's going to affect people's health.
We're trying to make an announcement.
This is a private company that is
spending millions of dollars to promote
these events.
So all you're doing is just like getting
it on you.
You're taking the gun right out that
door and to the right hand side,
all you're doing,
if you're,
if you're scooping it,
is you're shining the attention on
yourself.
What I'd like Ariel for is not him shine
the attention on himself.
What I like aerial fours.
I think he's a very bright guy and I
think he's very insightful when it comes
to fights and strategies and things
along those lines,
so I don't think it's important that he
break the news before the UFC does and I
think if the UFC doesn't want him to do
that because this is private information
in a private company and they're trying
to control the press release,
I don't buy that.
That's necessarily like under the guise
of journalism.
I think it's like there's some,
there's some fuckery with that because
we're not talking about like,
oh he,
he found out about some horrible thing
that happened that someone's covering up
or he found out about corruption in
government or he found out about a
person got shot by the police.
This isn't,
this is not like that kind of news.
This is,
they're going to release it.
It's going to,
you're just trying to do it before they
do it and you're finding it.
If it's true that there's a mole,
you're finding it out through some sort
of a sneaky method that these people all
sign nondisclosure agreements and
they're all not supposed to release that
information because the UFC wanted to
make that big cool announcement.
Now when that big cool announcement
happened at UFC one 99 I was working all
day.
I was doing commentary all day,
so I didn't go online and I wasn't
reading any of the MMA sites,
so I didn't know that Ariel had already
scooped it.
So when I saw that Promo and I saw brock
Lesnar,
can you see me?
Oh,
I was like,
what does that mean?
Was this real?
Like what?
Like that was a real reaction by me.
I had no fucking idea whatsoever that
brock lesnar was going to be at UFC 200
I didn't either.
No one around me knew what was
happening.
We didn't see the promo right in here.
That's what the UFC wanted.
They wanted that and they felt like him
releasing that early ruin that for the
people that read his article and I see
their point of view,
I see their perspective and I also see
their perspective as a private company.
Now people are saying that he's just
doing his job and it's just journalism
folks.
This,
this is not hidden information.
This is not stuff that wasn't going to
come out for sure in a couple of hours.
He knew it was,
everybody knew it was.
So this is a very tricky thing and it's
also,
he had apparently scooped nate diaz
versus conor Mcgregor.
He had done that and that was when,
this is again what I'm hearing.
When they had a talk with them they'll
like,
look,
if you fucking do this,
you're going to ruin people's lives
because you're going to get people fired
because we're going to find out who the
fuck did this.
There's only a small handful of people.
It's not coming from brock side.
It's coming somehow or another from
inside the organization.
So yeah,
I don't got no,
I got no problem with the UFC doing it.
Cause,
I mean if everything we're saying,
you know,
cause obviously I don't know all the
information,
but look,
it's your company,
it's your information.
Yes,
you have a right to tell your employees,
don't give this out.
And if there's evidence that one of them
is what I'm gonna fire that guy.
Yeah.
And this is,
this is the most important part of it
folks.
This is not a free speech thing is not a
freedom of the press thing.
Cause we're not saying that he somehow
or another scoop,
some inside information that we'd have
never gotten out is his,
is not some secret stuff.
She has the right to say it.
Yeah.
No,
you shouldn't be thrown in jail.
Um,
I don't have a kit for anyone being
thrown in the towel,
but I'm saying what I'm saying is it's
not like he unveiled,
he uncovered some inside shit like
Watergate.
This was something that they were going
to have release.
They had a plan and he got word of that
and jump the gun and put it out there.
And he said he had multiple sources and
all this different jazz.
But look,
it doesn't help anybody to release it
early except Ariel,
she's saying it's not like he found out
about some scandal going on and he was
showing to the public,
that's what we like.
We want to drop this in an act.
And by the way,
I didn't read his thing and I loved
finding that news out live at the event.
It was amazing.
Well,
and I look,
I don't give a fuck.
Okay.
I don't,
I mean I think it's Kinda cool that they
had that,
but it doesn't bother me at all that the
information got out a few hours earlier
would I've had the same reaction.
No,
but if I saw it in written word,
I was still at a very similar reaction.
Like what the fuck?
I wouldn't have had the same reaction
when I saw the promo,
but come on,
man,
I'm not into cheesy promos anyway.
I don't give a fuck.
I want to see matchups.
I don't give a shit.
Give everybody the information.
The moment it happens.
I don't give a fuck.
I don't like announcements,
all of that.
I don't.
But that said,
I completely understand the UFC,
his opinion or the UFC position where
they have this company and you know,
people go,
Oh,
you're a company man,
you're fucking sticking up for the
company.
No,
just think about this for a second.
You have a promotional campaign that
you've created.
You've spent more than a million dollars
promoting this UFC 200 commercial.
They have this whole thing and then they
tag brock Lesnar in the end and they
think,
oh my God,
this is the fucking cherry on top of the
Sundae.
This is going to be it.
And then someone jumps the gun and you
find out that it's someone inside your
company,
allegedly that's leaking information.
This reporter and he's getting this
information out and always doing is
essentially scooping it and putting the
onus and the putting the light on
himself.
No,
I think you have every right to want to
fire that person.
Yeah.
And also every right till it's a bad
area.
And I love area I think is a great
reporter.
I,
you know like watching his stuff.
I liked the MMA hour long.
Again,
maybe that information that I got from
the UFC is also incorrect and maybe
that's why his ban has been lifted.
But look,
no one wants a guy like Ariel Helwani to
not have a Gig.
And I think him getting banned.
Honestly,
if you're an Ariel Helwani fan,
you should be jumping up and down for
two reasons why you should be happy that
he got banned because then it makes them
like a martyr and then happy that he got
reinstated because now he's a hero.
So I'm an Ariel Helwani Fan,
so I'm happy.
I'm obviously a UFC fan,
I'm glad they worked it out.
And everybody talk and get to watch a,
we get to watch brock lesnar fight.
Exactly.
But it's these everybody that's freaking
out that he's only doing his job.
That's not necessarily true folks.
It's,
it's a little bit more complicated than
that because it's not like that
information wasn't already coming out.
And if you have information that you
know is going to come out,
right.
A fucking story about what that
information means.
Cause that's what I want at Ariel
Helwani.
I think Eric [inaudible],
he's a really smart guy and he's really
insightful and he's a true mma fan and
he's a guy that is going to give you
some really good insight and some very,
very well articulated thoughts that I
enjoy.
So I'm happy,
I'm happy he's back,
I'm happy.
But that is the perspective that when I
found out about it,
I had to ask.
I called and I had this conversation
with people that I deeply trust and this
was the version that I was handed.
So now everybody knows and it's so
groovy.
So the conspiracy theories can say he's
working with the UFC.
I'm a puppet.
But I mean look,
obviously I love the UFC and obviously
Dana white is a very good friend of
mine,
so you're not going to hear me criticize
them.
You know what I mean?
If I,
if I disagree with them,
you're like,
he's my friend.
So it makes sense.
That's how human interactions work.
He's like a friend and by the end he's
created an amazing company.
He's the,
he's the reason why this sport is out
there and you guys have worked together
for.
So even if you had a falling out and you
were like,
I don't want to work there anymore,
why would you go publicly?
He would never hear that from me and I
would never work for anybody else
either.
I both said like if you leave the UFC or
you're like,
what are you going to do?
He worked for bell tour.
I'm like,
I'm not working for anybody.
If I don't work for the UFC,
I am never doing this again.
Yeah,
I couldn't see you commentating for
another MMA blocking the chance.
No chance,
no chance.
It's not even on the table.
It's not going to happen.
I would just won't do it anymore.
I mean I would be happy to just go back
to doing stand up.
Um,
I like being a fan and honestly,
my favorite thing to do,
I don't,
I love calling fights.
Don't get me wrong.
It's an amazing job of how to for a long
time.
But fight companions are even more fun,
right?
Like companion podcast when it's Eddie
Bravo and shop and Callan and was
hanging out and watch,
oh my God.
And we drank and eat food and talk shit
and have a fights.
Boring.
Someone tells us a story about,
you know,
getting laid or shitting their pants and
traffic or,
I mean,
it's hilarious.
The most fun.
It's the best because we get,
look,
the best seat in the house is kind of
their live where I sit.
So I do kind of have the best seat in
the house.
But honestly watching it on TV might be
the best seat in the house because you
don't get the obstruction of the cage.
I've been,
well look,
I don't like the UFC is,
I've been to,
I don't have like the great fucking
seats either.
I've sat and just,
and I've caught myself sitting there
where you're watching now buddy.
Ooh,
life is changing you up.
Uh,
but I,
I've been sit there where I'm looking,
I'm catching myself just watching the
screen of course.
Big screen a lot and you're kind of,
you are aware of that or you're just
like,
I'm really not even watching this live.
Half the time,
you know they start fighting over here
and you're like,
I have now the octagon is blocking man.
You don't get the commentary unless you
have one of those ear piece things that
they sell.
So like sometimes something's going on
and you're like,
what is happening?
Why is the doctor,
and they're like,
what's going on?
Why is he sitting on the stool?
Why is he on the ground?
Like what the fuck is going on?
And it'll take you like 10 minutes of
frustration to try to decipher.
And then like bruce buffer has to
announce it due to an injury.
But speaking of that,
you get to see the bruce buffer three 60
every time,
which he doesn't do a three 60 it was a
one 81,
three 60 and that's at UFC 200 which
ladies and gentlemen begs the question,
should we convince Bruce buffer to do
something else?
Seven uh,
seven 20 do we convince them to do a
seven 20?
You heard it right here,
but he's getting up there in age.
I don't want him to blow out an acl.
He blew,
blew his acl out doing the jump.
You know he does that thing where he
like he blew his acl doing acl out doing
which in that which fight?
I don't remember.
He probably tell me if I asked him.
He he might not even my,
I'm sure he remembers,
but here we could watch the three 60 by
the way,
this three 60 is 100% my idea,
I talked him into it.
There's any even a video of me talking
him into the three 60 and I'm like,
cause he only did the one 80 and he did
the wine 80 because he accidentally,
it was pointing towards the wrong side
once and he realized that there's
another one dude,
hold up,
bring this to the beginning,
bring it to the beginning and then crank
it up real loud so we can hear it.
You'd do it.
Bring it from the beginning.
Put it in the beginning.
Britain in the beginning.
There you go.
My main goal this weekend besides having
fun and getting to see some awesome
fights.
It's talking Bruce Buffer.
It's the buffer three 63 60 we planted
the seed in his head,
shit,
it was about a year ago.
Talked to him about possibly going from
a one 82 or three 60 could he do it?
But that crazy mother fucker went home
and actually practiced it.
[inaudible] work on them at the
[inaudible] for three 60 brought to you
by the power of marijuana.
So this is the UFC.
What proof?
UFC 100 today's that day,
will we see the buffer?
Three is still stands that I will know
at that exact millisecond of the moment
I decided to do it.
Do I want to do it?
Yes I do.
But let's see how the energy feels
unless say,
oh,
I feel and let's see how the show goes.
If I can do it,
I'll pull it off.
Like fucking take it.
Joey Diaz is sitting there right behind
me while it happened.
I forgot that until he was right there.
Oh,
this is the biggest ever UFC pay per
view.
And that's me with a video camera on
Mike Goldberg hoping that he's going to
do the one 83 60 while look how lean
frank Mir looked at the time.
We look great now get ready for this.
Like he's going to do it.
He's going to do it.
I was like,
he's not going to do it.
That's,
I was so happy.
So there's Red Band Diaz and Ari fear.
Wow.
Everybody looks so young.
It's crazy.
That was seven years ago.
That doesn't seem like seven years ago.
Somehow already had an older haircut at
the time while he was gone for the
mustache.
Look at the time and he had a lot of
craziness going on.
Wow.
That's a long ass time ago.
That's crazy.
Who?
Who is it?
Who has that up?
Does that red bands page?
Wow.
I should put it on my channel.
So we have to figure out a way to make a
seven 20 plausible to spend.
He needs a hover board or something.
So the other breaking news you just
handed me,
is it Kimbo slice died,
died.
I think he was admitted to the hospital
with a heart condition today or maybe
Thursday the other day.
And News is breaking just as we were
coming on when people are trying to get
confirmation on that,
if he actually passed and tweeted it,
oh the American top team tweeted that he
died.
He must have really died.
Wow.
He was a good guy,
man.
I met that dude a couple of times.
Very nice guy.
Fuck man.
Crazy story.
He had man just fuck Internet street
fights into the UFC.
Well first into the CBS thing.
It was a good boxer.
You know,
he's a good boxer in the early days of a
mma,
you know,
he go back and watch like Kimbo slice
Kayo and lead x c just to lead,
see fucked up and trying to put all
their eggs in one basket and have this
guy who was this internet sensation be
their figurehead.
I mean it made sense like financially,
but the people in the know like me,
I was like,
listen,
if he fights someone good,
he's going to get fucked up.
Like I see all these holes in what he
does.
And it was frustrating as a hardcore fan
because it was still at a point like the
UFC is much,
much bigger now.
I remember when they got that fight on
uh,
on CBS,
like mma had never been on a big network
like that before.
So it was very frustrating that the
biggest network was putting it out as if
this guy was the best guy in mma.
And you know,
us like hardcore fans like me and my
friends would be around bitching.
Like Randy Guitar would take them down
in a second.
But he was fun to watch.
Well people forget that elite Xc sorta
had the scoop on the UFC.
They had the scoop on getting on
broadcast television and they had
millions of people watching those
fights.
Didn't UFC like why aren't they in talks
with HBO?
And then it like fell apart and then
elite xc ended up getting the deal with
showtime or whatever was one of the
problems hbo wanted to replace me and
Goldberg and put in their own
commentators.
They wanted to do their own version of
the broadcast because they probably felt
like us as you have seen,
employees would be biased.
And the UFC was like,
that's not gonna happen.
Like first of all,
who are you going to get?
Like how many people are out there?
Especially at the time that even do
commentary.
This is a small handful of people in the
world that are qualified to do mma
commentary at a top level.
It was a big problem.
Big,
big problem with other organizations.
We've been made them almost unwatchable
because the announcing would just be so
terrible.
I mean like nowadays I feel like there
was a while where I thought you and
Goldberg,
we're like the only team who can do mma
without me just wanting to mute it.
Um,
but I actually like now they've got the
alternate teams have gotten fairly
strong.
Like Brian stands.
Really good price hands.
Excellent.
Dan.
Hardee's excellent and hard.
He's really good.
Yeah,
there's a lot of people that can do my
job now.
But back then there was a small handful.
And by the way,
the,
a lot of people that can do my,
other than Jimmy Smith who's really
good,
who,
uh,
works for Beltour,
Jimmy Smits excellent.
He's,
he's as good as me.
Easy.
He's as good as anybody.
He's,
he's,
he's fantastic.
He knows his shit.
He's a real fan.
He's a smart guy.
He's,
he's easy to listen to.
He calls things.
Right.
I'm a big Jimmy Smith Fan.
But um,
other than outside of the UFC,
who do you got outside?
The UFC does not,
not really much unless there's some
unknown gods I don't know of,
which is definitely possible.
But there's,
in the UFC,
there's several guys now,
you know,
you got Kenny Florian,
you got Brian Stand,
you've got Dan Hardee,
there's plenty of people can do it now,
but they worked for the UFC.
So someone like hbo wanted to have their
own team.
You can't just get sports guys.
You just can't do that because they're
not going to understand what the fuck's
going on when the fight goes to the
ground and they're going to miss things.
And it's going to be sloppy.
You can't have that.
You'd have to have someone who
understands and you have to have someone
who can talk.
Like when you watch old school a mma,
it's one of the craziest things about
better that it's being announced by
people who don't understand the sport.
So you literally hear them saying things
like,
why is he typing?
Yeah.
Yeah,
you get,
you definitely get a lot of that.
And we'll usually get a lot of that from
a judges,
which is really crazy.
I have a friend of mine is a friend of
mine who's a judge and in the middle of
a fight,
this woman,
uh,
who was also a judge looked over them
and go,
she goes,
what is he doing that someone had
someone in a Kamora and she's like,
what is he doing?
What's going on over there?
Like she's a professional judge at the
highest level in the UFC.
And she had no,
and this was four years ago,
five years ago.
So yeah,
but this is what I'm against.
All those commissions.
Well,
yes and no.
You definitely need commissions cause if
you don't have commissions and you don't
have medical staff on team,
you don't have like strict standards as
far as you know,
you have to have some government it
especially with something like combat
sports because there's too many fly by
the seat of your pants.
Organizations that don't do medical
screenings,
people could die.
I mean they test.
You have to have like uh,
certainly the companies would have to be
held responsible for that stuff.
Yeah.
But you can't just leave it up to the
companies.
We can,
the athletes that suffer if there's no
medical coverage,
the right there,
you can't have an event like an mma
event where you putting your literally
your health and your life in the hands
of these people that are supposed to
have all their ducks in a row so they
can run this event and measure whether
or not you even get paid is in question
Si.
Because these guys don't have any power.
The fighters,
you know,
there's,
they don't have enough influence,
especially on a small local level,
small shows.
So I'm a big fan of how California does
it.
Like I said,
I'm a big fan of that Andy Foster guy.
I think he's,
he's fucking,
he's as good as it gets when it comes to
heads of athletic commissions.
But I think that you have to have a bond
where you have the money to pay the
fighters before he can put on an event.
And that should be mandatory because
you've done,
have you ever done shows?
We haven't gotten paid.
Yeah,
I have.
It's fucking horrible,
man.
It's,
that's not frustrating.
Especially when you know that you,
there was an audience there and they
laughed.
So Pete,
there's money exchanged,
but where's my money?
Oh please.
You don't have it.
You don't even have a show if you don't
have the show.
Part of the show I had,
I had one where I had to fly myself out
to it.
I didn't get paid and like there were
people there.
The club was the ohs.
Brutal.
It was brutal.
Did you ever get paid?
No.
Never.
To this day there's a Gig Mianna man.
Big J.
No,
some.
We're both on the GIG together.
Both of us didn't get paid.
I was opening for him.
This is years ago.
I both like I was opening for him,
but believe me it probably hurt me more
of the money.
Uh,
I mean,
uh,
made it on money,
but at the moment I was like fucking
broke.
Um,
but I will say then you also deal with a
lot of other shit when you get these
government regulatory bodies like with
the Vegas.
Was it the Vegas Commission that had
Nick Diaz?
Of course,
which I mean has there ever,
if you,
the guy moved up a weight class and
thought the greatest of all time at that
weight class who tested positive for
steroids and they found that he was,
had trace amounts of thc in the system
and he passed a couple of tests,
right?
He pass the most stringent tests
available.
You pass to Wada test to world
anti-doping agency tests.
There were blood tests,
there are much more particular and then
he failed a urine test that the Nevada
state athletic commission.
But he says it's bullshit and like the
Wata people say it's bullshit.
The water.
People were like,
look like there's no fee.
And then they wouldn't test sample b.
There was like some,
some issues with testing of sample B or
allowing the tests of sample b and they
banned,
they tried to ban him for five years.
I gave out the Nevada state athletic
commission,
his phone number,
I put it on twitter,
it's on everybody calm.
They were fucking best there are pissed
off.
I was like,
fuck you.
What would they were like petitions
online and stuff like that.
People would be fired and then they
should be locked in jail.
Yeah,
the amount of incompetence and you have
to have to think that you're going to
take away a guy's athletic career for
trace amounts of marijuana and the
system and not examine the to Wada test
that showed that he was clean.
Oh,
it's just so disgusting.
And this guy,
this guy who,
you know,
Nick Diaz was like,
came from nothing and like made a career
of it.
Was,
was like doing something positive with
his life.
Ruined him.
It's just pot.
He fought a guy on steroids.
Yes,
exactly.
And it's just the greatest ever on
roids.
Yeah,
you should just,
you should,
you should say,
I'm so sorry that we let a guy on
steroids fight against you.
Here's some more pot.
Exactly.
He's don't sue us.
I mean,
the idea that you can just go in there
and run an organization like that and
tell those people that are fighting that
their futures fuck like what they did to
vandelay Silva is arguably even more
disgusting.
Vandelay Silva ran away from a drug
test.
Okay.
Not Good.
Definitely shouldn't do that.
But they banned him for life.
He's never tested positive.
Ever.
Ever abandoned for life gets,
it's insane.
That's beyond fuck debts.
Tyranny.
Well,
it's this guy,
uh,
this the guy,
the cops killed in Baltimore,
that Guy Freddie Gray.
Like essentially what he did was he ran,
they didn't have anything on him.
They weren't there to arrest him.
He saw cops and ran.
And it's like a weird dynamic where
you're like running,
it may be a little suspicious,
but it's not itself a crime.
Right,
right.
Like how can there be such a hard
punishment for running?
Yeah.
You're just,
I mean it just seems strange,
which was a woman.
The Guy ran away and they shot him then
through a Taser on the ground.
That was no different line.
That was in North Carolina.
And I think there was a little bit more
maybe,
maybe you're right.
Maybe it was one of those,
I was wanting to go to South Carolina
because I'm from the north,
we to say,
oh South Carolina ones that are all
fucked up.
The North Carolina,
North Carolina would never,
never,
but then it,
it did turn out that he was like,
he had the cops Taser or something like
that.
Right.
And that and that one,
all the cop through the Taser on the
ground.
Is that what it was?
I don't remember the story exactly.
There's a video of the cop chucking the
Taser on the ground after he shot him.
Like,
cause if set up caught him,
he had a weapon,
you know?
Yeah.
Like what,
a lot of shady shit.
There's something about that balance too
of where like if you,
if a cop is,
it is,
you know,
if a cop grabs your arm and you yank it
away,
so you're like,
assault resisting arrest Jerry,
you're,
you're fucked now.
But the cops can like beat a dude with a
nightstick half to death and then
they're like,
well,
we thought he might've been going for
someone's gun.
Yeah,
yeah.
It's dark man.
It's,
it's,
and also cops just like everything else
we're talking about in government,
they're people and they vary and there's
going to be people that are awesome
cops.
And I personally think that it's one of
the most difficult jobs a person can do.
And psychologically the,
the idea of going to work every day
where all the people you deal with are
going to be lying to you and up to
something and hate you.
Well,
did you,
did you follow it all?
What happened?
Um,
was like a,
I guess a year and a half ago now in,
in New York where the NYP D had like a,
essentially a quasi shutdown.
Yes.
I mean it's,
it's,
and I think what you're saying is
absolutely true.
I mean,
I think it's an incredibly difficult
job.
And,
and a lot of that is because of the
rules we have,
which are kind of crazy.
I mean,
the idea of having to police drug use.
Yeah.
It's a very difficult position to put
someone in because the,
I mean,
obviously first and foremost,
it's a horrible thing to do to throw
someone in a cage for putting something
into their body.
But it's a very weird thing when there's
no complaintant.
It's two people who are making a
voluntary transaction and now you got to
go in like Swat raid and find them at,
this guy's giving a bag of something to
another person.
Go get them.
But,
so for people who don't know,
there was after that,
Eric Gardner Guy,
uh,
got choked out and choked to death in a,
I don't know how you'd put it,
but he got,
he got choked to death.
I'm sorry,
I shouldn't say that.
We had like a heart attack.
He had a heart attack while getting
tackled down.
A legendary selling loosies loose
cigarettes.
Uh,
nothing.
So there were a bunch of protests and
then a couple,
uh,
two cops got shot in Brooklyn,
by some maniac.
Yeah,
I think it was [inaudible] and he drove
up,
he tweeted he was going to do it and
then drove up and shot two cops who
never saw it coming.
It's poor guys got killed on the job.
Um,
and then as a result of that,
they had like an official unofficial
what they called an Nyp d slow down.
And I'm one of the,
it was a spokesman for the police union,
he said,
and I believe it was the New York Post,
uh,
as a result of the shooting,
the cops will only be making arrests
when absolutely necessary.
Well,
that's what he said,
which was weird.
Like shouldn't they always be doing
that?
But anyway,
so they,
but uh,
arrest went down like 80%,
uh,
or at least it was maybe like 60% and 66
cents we have here.
And then it was like nonviolent tickets
and bullshit arrest.
We're down like 90%.
Like they were just basically not doing
that anymore.
And there was this beautiful like month
and a half long period where the NYP d
just wasn't doing what they do.
They weren't over policing everybody and
then they started cracking the whip to
get them to go back to do it because
evidently a lot of money is raised by
these,
you know,
that's the issue.
Glorified revenue collectors.
There's a lot of revenue that gets
gathered up in kind of fucking devious
ways.
Like I've always been disgusted by
parking tickets.
Like why the city owns the fucking spot
where you can leave a car and you have
to give them money to leave a car and
that's how they gather up millions of
dollars and they become addicted to that
gathering of the millions of dollars.
Right.
That's fucking crazy.
You can't do that,
man.
You can't.
Oh,
it's a horrible way to fund a system.
Imagine,
by the way,
just being that guy,
you just being the guy who's going out,
just giving tickets.
Like you just go around ruining people's
Day,
like all day long line.
My friend Brian used to do that.
That must be a fucking weird bad for
your brain.
I'd imagine it has to be.
I mean,
I imagine some of these people,
men who are like literally,
you know,
working,
uh,
like you know,
lower class jobs and have families to
pay for and you're just going to go hand
them a fucking hundred dollar ticket
because the meter expired by two
minutes.
He didn't give us enough money and it's
just changing as laundry or something
and you know,
let it go for a few minutes.
Yeah,
I mean I get the idea that you,
you shouldn't have cars that are
blocking the street.
You should definitely give people
tickets if they're doing something that
has trucks at or tow them.
But to just leave a car on the street,
you have to pay money.
Yeah.
I mean,
look,
I have,
I have a problem with the way government
raises almost all revenue.
I mean I just,
I reject the whole system of,
of like taxation at the threat of
violence.
I think it's like primitive and
barbaric.
And when,
when human beings look back on that it's
going to be the way we look back at like
slavery or arranged marriage or whatever
it is that the idea that the way we fund
our organization,
you know,
like,
like let's say there are these services
that are necessary.
So the way we fund that as we go,
uh,
you have to pay a portion of your income
or we'll fucking throw you in jail.
Yeah,
we'll put you in a cage,
block you in a cage like an animal.
They're just like,
that's the biggest thing.
Um,
when I'm arguing that with people about
like libertarianism versus other ways
that we should organize society as my
biggest thing that I just,
I,
I harp on is just a like,
okay,
who should we throw in a cage?
Who was it morally acceptable to throw
into a cage forcefully?
Like send men with guns to get them and
throw them into a cage.
Like I'll grant you a murderer,
a rapist,
someone who assault somebody.
Okay.
Yeah.
Maybe we go into like theft,
things like that.
Cause cause that is a violation of,
you know,
you own yourself and then you own your,
your possession.
So that's a violation.
But are you,
are you really okay if someone's like,
oh I don't want to fund that program.
I won't like I won't my money and to
fund the war cause I don't believe in
the war.
So now we can throw that guy in a cage.
Yeah.
Or I don't want to,
I don't want to fund them.
Look,
even if you have a really noble charity,
why should you be able to threaten
violence against someone to get them to
fund it?
Well,
that's where I like Gary Johnson,
Gary Johnson steps in and says we don't
need the irs.
It's like,
let's listen.
We don't need,
that's not how we have to make money,
which put taxes on consumption.
I,
I like Gary Johnson.
I wish he would be a little more Ron
Paul.
But uh,
he's away.
I just feel like Gary Johnson has this
way of selling the libertarianism as
this kind of like,
well,
you know,
it's more practical if we do it the
libertarian way.
Huh.
Whereas I like when he's asked about the
wars,
he'll say,
he'll say things like,
um,
he goes,
well,
I think if you look on average these
military interventions of hurt more than
they have helped.
That is exactly how we sound.
That's a really good impression.
Yeah,
I watched a lot of them.
Well,
so my only,
by the way,
that's not necessarily incorrect.
It's just like who,
who would talk about mass murder that
way and it's like,
it's like talking about slavery and
you're like,
well,
I just think overall this is an
inefficient way to get cotton Jesus
dude.
Like and your,
your head abolitionist really,
you're supposed to represent the
abolitionist movement,
right?
With that,
that attitude.
So he's like a moderate radical.
Yeah,
he's just a pragmatist man.
He's just like this.
This makes more sense,
which is just fine.
But I don't really want to sell.
Libertarianism is like,
I think we're fiscally conservative and
socially liberal.
He's like a,
he's a bridge because he was a lifelong
Republican.
Like he's a good bridge to getting
people to consider an alternative party
and maybe one of the only ones it's
currently available.
See I believe in a little bit more like
a case for radicalism.
I think that,
um,
so Ron Paul,
when he was in the 2007,
2008 debates,
she got a whole lot of people interested
in libertarianism and he didn't do it by
being like a bridge to like,
before I tell you,
you know,
slavery is horribly immoral.
Let me first convince you it's
inefficient and ineffective.
And then he went right to like,
this is wrong,
this is wrong.
We're killing people in countries around
the world.
Like this is morally horrible.
And he got a movement going when he was
in those debates.
You know,
Gary Johnson was in one of the major
debates in 2012.
Do you remember anything from his
performance because nobody ever does?
No.
Nobody ever does because he'll go in
there and say things like,
in New Mexico,
I was able to balance the budget was
earning 7% and you're like,
ah,
you have the greatest,
the greatest political philosophy ever
devised by man behind you libertarians.
You have the answer to all this shit.
You're the abolitionists in slavery
times.
And so you really feel libertarianism is
the answer to everything?
Well,
no,
no.
It's not in the same way that abolition
isn't the answer to everything during
slavery.
It's the first moral step to then we can
live in.
What about libertarianism is so
attractive to you?
Uh,
I mean,
I just,
the,
I think it's philosophically sound and
it's,
it's basically just a,
to me it's,
it's a humble understanding of what
existence is.
That we don't really know what this is.
Man's kind of born into the world naked
and we're here with nature and we're all
trying to figure it out and that morally
speaking,
we should all own our own lives and
therefore own your own body and that,
and basically it all centers around
property rights and the nonaggression
principle,
which is just the idea that you should
never initiate violence against the
nonviolent person.
And then you just draw conclusions from
that.
Well,
those are all really standard,
um,
points in libertarianism to get brought
up all the time.
But why is it that libertarianism,
even though it's so attractive to like
young,
intelligent guys like you,
why is it that that has never caught
hold in a mainstream way as an
alternative third party?
Because it really the,
you've had like,
people like that run his independence
that get a little bit of momentum,
but it's always,
people always look at it like,
well,
that's never going to work out.
He's never really going to get there.
You,
you,
you know,
vote for Hillary because she has a
chance.
You know what I mean?
You get those.
Yeah.
Well I think there's a game and there's,
you know,
it's,
um,
there's like the government is a power
center and it's in their interest to
continue having power.
And I think usually most people are much
more,
if they get close to that power,
they're much more incentivized to try to
expand it and try to keep it than to at
any point,
say you guys,
you know,
it'd be a lot more moral if we,
uh,
we didn't have this.
And you know,
I mean,
it's like,
why did slavery persist for so long?
Because you know it's a,
it's a good way to get cotton without
having to work.
Yeah.
I mean people are getting rich off this
thing and they certainly are,
but I do.
I will.
I wonder how much time it has left like
this.
This,
it seems like it's a reoccurring,
reoccurring theme that comes up over and
over again when people talk about the
problems that we have with a running
society,
we were currently doing it.
He said this two party system is just so
preposterous.
It's so ridiculous to say that you have
these two groups and they're both funded
by the same people,
the competing against each other
allegedly,
but yet nothing changes.
And that this is the system and this is
the only way to do it.
Like,
well,
how can we count?
We've got a hundred different systems
and ideas and what does this grand old
party,
what's the idea of there being a leader
for 320 million people?
I mean,
none of it makes any sense at all.
Just be in an elephant she wants.
It's all still so weird how there's this
big,
like this big show about how much they
hate each other,
but then they just come together over
the most important issues feel betrayed.
When I see like Clinton laughing it up
with Bush,
I'm like,
what the fuck are you guys laughing
about?
How many people died when you were in
office?
Right.
And how the media is angle on it will
and you know,
it'd be msnbc or Fox News who was
supposedly hate each other.
But when you see all the presidents
together,
they're all kind of celebrating it.
They're like,
it's nice that we could all come
together and have this,
this toast.
Like what?
What is this?
I thought it was so you're all full of
Shit and how is it that you know you
have these things were so,
so the Republicans hate Obama.
Obama hates the Republicans.
They both think the other ones,
the reason why the country's falling
apart.
But then when like,
you know,
something like the NDA bill where he
says he can arrest American citizens
with no charges and hold them
indefinitely,
we all just get together and sign that,
you know,
that's fine.
And the media,
it's not even like that big of a deal.
Like they just passed a law that said
they can arrest you with that.
Like we just over the whole idea that
you have rights,
we just overthrew that in one in one
bill.
And uh,
but you know,
that'll get like a mention here that you
have to understand that that won't be
used.
Don't worry about it.
That's all for terrorist.
That's my favorite.
Obama actually,
he put in a signing statement when he
signed it into law,
he said,
and I guess this was to like appease
the,
the liberal activists who may be,
would be a little upset with him,
but he said,
my administration has no plans of
detaining American citizens,
but we want to let you know that we read
your emails.
Fuck with us.
We'll see you in a hard,
yeah.
So who's okay with that?
Which is frustrating for everybody that
nothing changes in that this two party
system was in place when we were kids.
It's,
it's in place now and it's quite
possibly it will be in place 50 years
from now when we were dead.
I don't know.
I do think something is changing in this
election cycle and I don't,
I don't know that it's purely a positive
force but there's definitely something
going on.
I mean if you look at what's what's
going on with trump and I'm no fan but
it is a,
it is a moment.
Yeah.
Trump is having a real moment and he is
kind of tearing down this matrix and a
and and Bernie also had an interesting
moment.
It's,
it's very interesting that they always,
the powers that be kind of decide who
these people are going to be and it does
seem like this year people are really
rejecting that on a very grassroots
level.
Like,
no,
we don't buy this bullshit.
I wonder how much longer they can keep
it up.
Well there's no real candidates.
That's the problem.
I said you're dealing with scrubs.
It's like this minor league ball team
that wants to play in the superbowl
because there's some sort of a strike
amongst really good players.
It really seems like that.
I mean come on man,
you're telling me that Donald Trump is
the best we can do or Hillary Clinton.
I mean,
how many of you just as Comedians,
like how many like charismatic,
just interesting people like do you know
show you do,
it's so many different like really
smart,
interesting people.
You sit there like you're telling me we
can't find one who won.
But I think like you said before,
the real problem is that a good person
or any type of honest person would right
away go,
no,
I can't rule 320 million people.
Not only that,
you would never get to that position
because you would be compromised every
step of the way and then you'd become
what they are.
The only,
I mean it's a really rig game and it's
rigged through lobbyists and special
interest groups and money and campaign
funds.
By the time you get to that position
unless you're a Bernie Sanders or Donald
Trump.
And that's what makes it interesting
because they're the only two people that
represents two completely new paradigms.
You have Bernie who is this weird
socialist type character,
democratic socialist character.
And then you have trump who's like the
ultimate capitalist.
And both people represent entirely new
groups because Donald Trump is
essentially at least partially self
funded.
And you know,
now he's trying to get money and
there's,
well he's already the nominee though.
I mean he's,
he's cemented.
So it's a,
it's an interesting position where it's
going to get some support.
Yes.
But so far,
basically trump and sanders both found a
way to do it without taking corporate
money.
Trump found a way to speak over the
media and get the media to keep him in
there 24 hour news cycle and Apulia this
shit out of everybody.
But they're both,
I mean,
I got to say they're not,
I don't look at,
while they're personalities are very
different.
I don't know if anything about their
policy,
the policies are actually like
diametrically opposed.
I think they're both kind of populists
in a lot of ways.
Like Bernie Sanders has more of a re as
more of an ideology,
like this is my philosophy on what
government should do.
And trump's just kinda like,
well,
well let's let it rip.
But they're both kind of like,
let me tell you what you want to hear to
the crowd.
Well,
trump is a carnival barker and you know,
he talks about that in the art of the
deal.
I mean,
his,
his whole style of campaigning is,
is all mapped out in his books where he
talks about this larger than life
persona that he's created in order to
make himself a public figure in order to
make himself more wealthy,
more popular,
and more able to get things done.
I mean,
this is like a strategy,
this,
this whole thing that he's doing like,
and I called them,
we're going to make that wall 10 feet
higher.
Like that's all like Carnival Barker
Shit.
But it's amazing that he,
he's stepped into the game of politics
and almost ripped it open from the
inside where he's like,
I'm just talking like a dude.
Yeah,
I'm not even doing it.
And I don't know how Hilary Clinton's
going to handle this guy.
Well how about when he was talking about
how big his Dick is?
Well he to be fair,
he just said there's no problem.
No look,
it's amazing.
He was insinuating there's someone was
insinuate entity had small hands way a
small penis.
And I just said I want to let you know
there's no problems there.
He made a,
I have a big Dick.
So here's what happens.
Right?
This guy,
this was like I think a couple of
decades ago.
Okay.
There's this guy who worked for vanity
fair and he wrote something about trump
having small hands and trump sent him a
picture like head shots of his hands and
a note being like,
I don't have small hands.
Like he actually responded to them and
this was out there.
Like I heard some people talk about
this.
So Marco Rubio knew if he went at his
hands just to makes sense.
Cause his hands aren't small.
No,
but for whatever reason he said
something.
He goes,
he,
Marco Rubio said he's got small hands
and you know what they say about guys
with small hands and this is the maniac
that is Donald Trump.
She couldn't not bring that up.
So the next debate he goes,
uh,
he goes,
and by the way,
she said,
I have small hands.
I look at these hands.
That pretty good.
Am I right?
And just so you know,
he couldn't stop.
There she goes.
And just so you know,
he implied that because of these small
hands,
that means something else is small and I
promise you there's no problem there.
Yeah,
it was very bizarre.
I mean,
strange.
His fingers are relatively short.
They're not great,
but it's does nothing weird.
Like where you'd have to comment about
it.
They're not presidential hands.
I'll say that.
What's the price?
Abe Lincoln probably has some long ass
crazy.
I mean,
I just,
uh,
it's a,
it's a weird thing to criticize though,
because you're talking about something
that someone can't change.
It's like making fun of someone's ears
when they're running for president.
Like,
hey man,
those are,
but it's very strange.
It's,
it's uh,
but it is a tell to Donald Trump that he
can't not address it.
Like if you,
if you put that out there,
he's got a comeback,
but it worked.
The problem is his comeback was
effective.
Yeah.
So then he wins.
So Marco Rubio,
Marco Rubio,
who's just this weird Mama's boy looking
putts,
like,
like he's just isn't how many charisma
when he would like be jabbing back and
forth with trump.
Like,
dude,
you're an amateur.
Like he's going to chew you up.
He's used to being criticized.
He's used to being arrogant.
He's used to shutting people down.
Yeah.
Well that's again,
that's another one of my issues with,
with Gary Johnson is that I just feel
like,
man,
if the,
if the LP wants to do something,
if the libertarian,
you know,
if they want to,
they want to have a moment here and
you're telling me the hope is if we can
get to 15% in the polls,
then we get into a debate and I have to
overlook the fact that this guy was
already in a debate that nobody
remembers because he didn't do anything
in that.
And now he's got to go debate.
Trump,
trump,
I you got to send someone who's got some
type of,
well he's going to be in the debates
though,
right?
Gary Johnson?
No,
he's got to get 15% he's got to pull
that and he's got to get into the polls.
Then he's got to get 15% in the polls.
It's a whole fucking fight and they also
have to choose which polls,
but I don't think they find him
threatening.
It might actually be smart for them to
allow him to expose,
I mean I think both sides would probably
think that he would expose something
that the other side has and both sides
would probably be under the impression
there an opportunity to capitalize on
it.
Well,
I think the left side,
because he's a lifelong Republican,
sees him is more likely to peel away
votes from trump.
So in a weird way I think they want him
in there because they want to,
they want to hand it to Hillary.
He might be able to take advantage of
some of that,
but I,
I don't know.
I think they,
even though this is a whole different
year,
they really like the,
the control on the two party system.
You know,
the last time,
uh,
a third party really made any noise was,
was Ross Perot and they changed all the
rules after that guy got out of there to
mention like presidential debates.
That's right.
It used to be like the,
uh,
women in the League of women voters or
whatever.
It used to run it.
And then that now that just the
Democrats and Republicans,
right.
Like they were like,
let's never let that happen again.
Yeah.
They fucked up.
They let that a crazy old billionaire by
time on TV.
Remember that?
Yup.
You're being hoodwinked.
I'll show you how know you don't want
some crazy old Texas billionaire on
television in the 1980s or whenever the
fuck it was.
It's,
um,
it's just,
it's one of those things to me where I
don't see how it's going to change.
I look at,
I go,
boy,
they can just keep running this fucking
game for another four years and another
four years and it'll keep going.
And then we'll be like 70 going,
what the fuck?
Man?
Still think so.
I think that's it.
I think we're,
we're on the verge of,
of the collapse.
And I don't know exactly where it verges
like,
I dunno,
you know,
how much longer president trump might do
it.
Maybe.
But if you,
I think if you look at a few kind of
like fundamentals,
we're in the process of an empire
fallen.
Yeah.
Like the far,
far too expanded militarily,
drowning in debt.
And if you really look at the dead,
I mean,
it's not just the 19 trillion.
There's like over a hundred trillion in
unfunded liabilities.
Like all these Medicare and social
security and all these programs there
are,
they're all going to blow up.
Uh,
we've,
we've also got,
you know,
just trillions and trillions of dollars
that are extended being held at these
big banks that there's all these
factors.
And also look at the moral kind of like,
uh,
the cultural decay kind of going on that
trump,
I think kind of embodies.
I think there's a lot of indicators that
were in the,
in the crash process.
He embodies the cultural decay in,
in that one sense.
Then on the other sense,
you've got the co two cultural decay by
social justice warriors and paper super
over sensitive who Ralph Nader's
rallying against.
Now Ralph Nay,
but I pulled this up on twitter today,
a Ralph Nader was saying that the men
today are over sensitive because they
never had to deal with the draft.
He's like,
you're,
you guys are complaining about nothing
like this is nonsense.
Good for Ralph Nader.
Them look at this,
this Ralph Nader on trigger warnings.
Young men are far too sensitive because
they've never been in a draft and that
fucking hilarious.
They're talking about trigger warnings,
but trigger trigger warnings make me
want to fucking hit somebody.
It really does.
It's insanity.
It makes me so,
it's so fucking stupid that you're
supposed to protect people from true.
First of all that is not even have
trigger works triggers work by like
being in a place where something bad
happened to you or hearing a sound or
seeing a thing.
It's not bringing up the act of like if
someone says you know,
Murder,
oh my dad was murdered,
it's a trigger warning.
Why didn't you warn me?
The trigger,
it hit me.
Like that's how,
but that's the whole world's going to
trigger you then.
Then every fucking piece of media,
every movie,
every television show has the potential
for being a trigger warning is really,
and like,
it's not as if like,
uh,
I just hate people and I don't care if
you're triggered and you know,
deal with your past.
Like I think we have a big epidemic of
soldiers coming back suffering from
PTSD.
I'd like to not send them towards so we
don't have to deal with this,
but the idea that we should,
we should change.
We should like nerf foam the world.
Yeah.
In case your triggered.
So a college now can't explore anything
they want to because what if someone had
something violent in their past happen
and then it seems to be a very
convenient thing where,
you know,
like the feminists or the social justice
warriors are like policing rape jokes in
the comedy community,
but they don't ever seem to
be policing like a war joke or a,
you know,
it's like they don't seem to care about
men being triggered.
And uh,
like you were saying,
it's mostly just infantiles bullshit.
It's just these privileged kids on
college campuses who are like want to
shut down a conservative speaker from
talking.
It's a civilian sanity.
Yeah,
it's,
it's so fucking,
the way they're doing is rabid.
It's like there's so frothy at the mouth
and so like taken away with the idea
that they're doing some incredible right
and this has to be done and there's this
justice must prevail and transgender
people should be able to use the women's
room without,
you know,
any questioning whatsoever about where
they stand.
Like there's some weirdness going on
today that is like what we were talking
about when people are young,
when you could send them to war.
Then when you send these young people to
war that they don't,
they don't really have enough data yet.
Well,
there's a lot of that going on with as a
social war and these people don't have a
lot of data either and they're just
furious and foaming at the mouth and
when all is said and done,
the dust settles when they're older,
they're probably not even going to be on
that team anymore.
You know,
you're,
you're probably going to wise up and
realize how fucking goofy those people
you're hanging around with are who are
getting mad at white people for wearing
dreadlocks.
Oh,
my social appropriation.
Cultural appropriation.
It's like,
listen,
we all hate white people in dreadlocks,
but you've actually made me someone I
hate more than white people in
dreadlocks.
That's how much you fucked up.
Not only that,
you don't even know where dreadlocks
came from.
First of all,
why do people have had dreadlocks
throughout history?
That's what you,
when you were comparing the kind of
cultural decay from the trump supporters
and the social justice warriors.
I do see a lot of it just rooted in like
Anti Intellectual Ism.
I mean,
there's just like,
no,
it doesn't matter.
You don't need to know anything you
need.
I mean they'll,
they will shut down.
Uh,
Christina Hoff summers speech.
Yes.
But I think she's amazing.
I saw you did a great podcast with her.
Uh,
but the,
I mean,
she is,
she's a feminist.
She's a liberal,
a liberal feminist who's just going,
oh,
by the way,
your data is a little off.
Yes.
Rape apologist.
Exactly.
She just talks about the facts and she,
she calls herself a factual feminist.
That's her statement.
And there's,
there's something wrong with telling
people they have things wrong to them.
I mean,
this is how crazy the left has gotten
because you're,
you're what,
you're,
you're 20 and you figured everything out
evidently.
Well,
it's just noise.
There's a lot of noise and sometimes in
those noises or some important points on
both sides.
But boy,
there's a whole lot of noise too.
And it's,
it's,
it's a lot of arguing,
a lot of yelling gets done that not a
lot of progress gets made.
Just people digging their heels and they
take aside and they draw a line in the
sand.
And if you've got the people on the
right and the people on the left and
oof.
Yeah,
like you said at the beginning of it
becomes a big like team I identity thing
and then you're like,
then it's just justifying the position
you're already in.
So you're just looking for kind of,
you know,
confirmation bias like my team's right
or my teams.
Right.
And Yeah.
And is everybody so God damn sensitive,
like the gender Pronoun thing is so
fucking bananas.
Like you should know that if you're a
dude and you look like a woman,
okay.
That people are going to get that wrong
on occasion.
Like,
okay,
what,
what do you look like?
Okay.
Do you look like Catherine Zeta Jones in
a bikini?
Well,
if you do,
people are going to say her and if they
say her,
that's not a bad thing.
Oh,
you're assuming my gender.
You know,
there's people out there that they think
that you should name your dog gender
neutral names cause your dog can't
decide.
Like this is a real debate amongst
feminists and social justice warriors
who have animals,
whether or not they should impose their
stereotypes that they have on human
beings,
on their dogs and cats.
But there's some look and it's just
insanity.
But I feel like there's something like
on these college campuses that's almost
like that's housing,
that they're letting them develop these
ridiculous ideas.
And I'll tell you,
I think part of it,
I really blame the college professors
for a lot of this because I think these
are also people who have,
a lot of them have lived in college
their entire lives.
There are people who go to college and
then just stay in college and they get
post,
you know,
graduate degrees and then they teach and
they're kind of letting this happen and
no one's going like,
okay,
shut up.
That's not a real issue.
Right.
Look,
I'm,
I'm all for like,
I'm a completely return.
You should be able to,
if you,
if you have a doctor who's willing to
perform a surgery on you and you want to
identify as her instead of him,
I'll call you her.
Cause who cares?
I'm not going to call you zee.
No,
that's fucking ridiculous.
But you also can't,
even if I'm willing to call you
something,
you can't make it a huge issue with not
everybody is willing to call you that
like this isn't,
let me see or is here.
Have you seen here her that's,
yeah,
there's like 18 of those now yet.
Like Lgbtq is not even close to all the
letters that are on that thing anymore.
Well how about in New York?
They're going to find businesses if they
intentionally mis-gender you so you can
get sued and fine for like a quarter
million dollars have you don't call
someone Z.
Yeah.
See and this is where,
this is where it becomes like a real
fucking problem is it's like,
okay,
you know what?
You guys can have your little fun and
games and your safe space on college
campus,
all you want to.
But now you start bringing in the
forceful arm of government to actually
go fuck over a business owner who's
trying to provide jobs and you know,
feed his kids.
But even it becomes a problem even in
colleges because what if you don't
subscribe to those ideologies and you
gotta go to school with these monkeys
and they're all running around insisting
there their pronoun a,
Z,
h e.
And if you don't say it,
you're a shit Lord.
Like whoa.
Yeah.
Well,
it's also real scared of the fact that
if you've ever,
you know,
had a drunken hookup,
you're a rapist,
which is by the way,
only the man only demand of course.
And that's what happened at Occidental
here.
And,
um,
when we talked about on the podcast
with,
um,
professor renegade history
three
fattiest Russell,
daddy's Russell,
who's brilliant,
brilliant guy.
And,
um,
we were talking about how incredible it
is that they find a way to justify to
people hooking up with text messages
where the girl saying,
come over,
bring condoms.
They have sex and the guy is the one who
is a rapist because they were both
drunk.
That's insane.
The guy got kicked out of school and
he's still in the middle of lawsuit
lawsuits.
It's,
it's,
it's insane.
But it's also like a fascinating glimpse
into how you see things because it's
weird how you,
it's almost like these guys come back to
be the caricature of what the 1950s
chauvinist was supposed to be.
Assuming that women are these fragile,
delicate creatures.
Exactly.
Handle the same thing a man can.
It's like you're really being the sexist
here.
Exactly.
Like all those guys.
Um,
who,
who would like I remember was a big
thing on your show when Jamie Kilstein
was on about the Tosh,
a rape joke.
But I always want,
I wonder what I,
and I've argued with a few people like
that,
who I do now,
by the way,
I'm not throwing this out in the stupid
way that it's thrown out when they go.
More men are raped and women are raped.
That's not,
but why is it seeing as that,
that is a fact,
prison included and stuff like that.
Why is that?
Every time you think of this scenario
where someone's triggered from a rape
joke,
it's always a woman you always like,
what if there's a woman in the crowd
who's been triggered and what if this
like it's never a concern that it could
be a man.
It's cause we were tribal and we break
off into male versus female teams.
If the males are the rapists on both
accounts,
men are raping the women and they're
raping the man.
See,
I told you man,
her shit,
the raping each other,
right?
But no one seems to feel for that rape
victim because of men because they're on
the wrong team.
I'll dude,
you're on a shitlord team.
Kurt made this up point.
Did you ever see the law and order
episode when they did tell you now?
No,
but do you ever seen any Milan order?
They did the one on standup comics and
rape jokes.
No,
dude,
it's no they did.
It's the worst thing that's ever been
made.
Oh Dude.
It's not even like,
you can't even believe how bad it is
until you see it.
It's like this,
this,
this guy.
Makes a rape joke at him not at a comedy
club.
And of course it chills because that's
what happens when you tell a woman in
the crowd.
You hope she gets raped.
Everyone just laughs at the top of the
anyway,
and then,
uh,
and then by the end,
then she gets raped after that because
he made the rape joke.
It leads to rape and then I'll do you
one better at the end.
He's actually the rapist,
the guy telling the rape joke.
It turns out to be the way it was,
like the most ridiculous,
irresponsible thing ever at a Kurt,
Kurt medsker made this point.
I just think it's so fucking funny,
but he goes,
don't think threatened men with rape on
every episode of that show.
Like every episode,
they're like,
you better start talking and then like,
you don't do very good in prison.
And you're like,
well,
really?
You're not going to just go clean that
up.
You're gonna threaten me with it.
But you're going to use that as a
negotiation tactic.
That's so fun.
What's,
it's just shitty show.
Those shows were all shit.
Every one of those crime shows.
What the fuck is it about America where
we want to watch hospital shows and
police shows.
That's all we want to watch.
We want to watch people that are in
trouble is trying to hide from the law
or someone that's worried that mom's not
gonna make it and they're holding our
hand on.
The doctors work in fiercely and the
young handsome doctor,
he leaves after 16 hours and he's
sweating.
He takes his hand and then another guy
comes in with a gunshot wound and back
to work.
Wow.
So noble cut to commercials for fucking
tie deodorant and whatever.
Something about poo and fucking Toyota
trucks and nobody goes to sleep.
She'd wake up in the morning,
I'm tying to consume.
We are a weird fucking people over the
weirdest thing where the weirdest thing,
it's because collectively you have to
look at us as what we are as a giant
super organism.
Like what are we waiting on?
We would look at it ourselves inside of
our culture and our belief systems and
our actions and what gets done and the
pollution in the environment,
but overall,
what is the species doing when you're
looking at it as an outsider,
if you were completely removed from
culture,
completely removed from tradition and
communication.
He just looked at us as like some weird
organism like what is it trying to do?
What's just making better stuff all the
time?
That's all it's doing and all this other
stuff that it does is just to distract
it while it's making better stuff.
All these little chicken dances and
peacock feathers and all the fucking
weird noises it mags and virtue
signaling.
I have a mattress and I'm carrying it
around to my rapist is brought to
justice.
All that madness and all the arguing and
all the craziness is going on.
It's just a distraction.
While it's making better and faster
computers,
that's all it is.
It's,
it's creating an artificial life form.
It's going to do it under this guise of
of of Christianity and Islam and all
these different things.
He's like,
oh no.
Well,
you know as long as the way,
oh no Christians way.
Meanwhile these a robot,
a robot overlord that the switch is
about to get turned on and you're
fucked.
You're all fucked.
But it's almost like you out.
It's,
it's the evolutionary game of numbers we
were saying before.
So you need it.
Throw all these people out to get a tiny
percentage that will be geniuses that
we'll keep this thing moving and then
you need,
the rest of us are basically just waste.
It's like,
yeah,
you're just jerking off and watching
some dumb reality show.
But if you keep fucking keep fucking,
eventually a genius will pop at who will
move this thing forward a little bit and
a little bit.
And then the robot,
we're essentially like a giant hive of
worker ants with potential options.
Like he really can write Harry Potter
and break away from the rest of the
worker ants.
You really can't have a kid.
It's a fucking matching genius cause he
dropped him on his head when he was a
baby.
They don't want to tell anybody why this
kid is so fucking good at math.
There's a lot of that going on man.
And those little fuckers grew up to be
like some Ilan musk character that
starts making electric cars in the
hyperloop that gets you to San Francisco
in three minutes.
There is some weird shit happening and
it's all happened in like exponentially
all around us all the time adding up
while we're worried about trigger
warnings and whether or not trainees can
use the fucking men's room or the
women's room and like that whole
particularly,
I mean that's angry,
that whole culture on the left of
whatever you want to call it.
Like the social justice warrior that
people call it the regressive left.
I like that term a lot.
I like that term,
but it really is just insanity.
I was watching,
uh,
recently the,
um,
did you ever see the uh,
the 30 for 30 on the Duke Lacrosse?
Yes.
I mean it's first
of that,
that accusation,
it's not like there was a,
it was a gray area or like they had sex
and she was a little drunk or they had
like nothing happened.
They didn't have sex.
This crazy person who's in jail for
murder now made something up and it's
interesting to watch it and like looking
back,
you know that what happens,
you know she made it up and seeing the,
the social justice warriors protest to
these guys and the White Knights,
the dudes who are hanging out right next
to the feminist chick going,
these lacrosse guys are out of control
and they should go to jail.
And you're like,
dude,
nothing fucking happened.
How about Nancy grace as you guys never
even took any heat for that?
She was on TV calling for their arrest
on TV,
accusing them of this in front of
millions and millions of people and
somehow or another she didn't get sued
somehow or another,
she didn't get brought to jail.
They should have pulled her fucking show
off the air.
You should.
I mean,
what?
What does it take to get fired?
It takes being a man.
She was a man doing the exact same thing
about a woman doing something horrible.
Oh,
I bet you're right.
Yeah.
He was a team of women and that did
something tear that were alleged to have
done something terrible.
And she was ranting and he was ranting
and raving about these women being
brought to justice and brought to jail.
And it turns out it was,
there was no crime being committed at
all.
You'd have to apologize.
You would,
she didn't even have to apologize.
She didn't do shit.
I can't remember who the other reporter,
um,
you remember at the end of the
documentary,
this is the one who apologizes,
but she actually,
she goes like,
she,
um,
she's like,
look,
I,
she apologized and she wrote a thing,
like an apology to them.
Oh No.
Then they cut back to the,
the articles that she was writing at the
time.
And it's like this insane.
She's like,
these boys all know what happened and
they know they're guilty and they need
to be punished for this,
blah,
blah.
And then she's even in acknowledging it,
she goes,
well,
you know,
I do think the fact that I was sexually
assaulted in college probably did come
into play.
And how core fucking snow.
Well,
guess what,
now you can't be a journalist.
And then not only that,
I don't know what to tell you.
What really happened in college.
Do we know or are you calling sexual
assault,
getting drunk and getting fucked because
that might have happened to cause that's
really acceptable to say today.
Yeah,
and that's disturbing as fuck man.
And look,
even if you were,
even if she was completely,
you know,
in like legitimately sexually assaulted,
not any of these bullshit gray areas,
like it was an actual sexual assault.
The idea that you would you like you're
covering a sexual assault case.
Okay.
And you were sexually assaulted before,
so right away what an honest journalist
would do would be recused yourself.
You would go,
I can't really do this because I'm too
emotionally invested in something that
happened in my life.
But now to not do that,
you're covering this,
something that happened to you that you
would have to be aware of.
I've got to make sure I don't let that
creep into my professionalism.
But you're using that to try to,
you know,
justify go after these guys.
And then after it's been proven that it
was incorrect.
Well she did.
To her credit,
she did apologize once it was proven to
be incorrect,
but still,
like you said,
that's not enough.
But didn't you say that in in the
apology and the apology,
she was saying how she had been sexually
assaulted.
She was kind of using that as a,
as an excuse.
You can't do that.
It doesn't mean it doesn't mean anything
to these guys cause they didn't do
anything.
So they're totally innocent.
Those are someone's babies,
someone's babies,
young boys who grew up to be young men
and they didn't do shit.
And you are writing stories saying that
they know what they did.
It's like if you were a therapist and
you were,
you were seeing like some 16 year old
kid and you told them to cut off all
ties with their parents and then it
turned out their parents were like
really wonderful people and you're like,
you know,
part of it might've been that my parents
were really bad.
So I told them,
they're like,
well then you can't be a shrink anymore.
I don't know what to tell you,
but you're bad at your job.
Yeah.
Well that's cult tactics,
right?
There's one of the big things they do is
tell you to get away from your parents,
get away from your family.
That's a big one.
Which to be fair,
a lot of people's families probably
suck,
so it's really easy.
Yeah,
it's easy.
If you,
if you saw most of the people who end up
in cults,
I bet their families did really suck
too.
They're lucky.
A lot of those people that are in calls,
they're lucky.
They're not sucking Dick for
cheeseburger somewhere.
A lot of them are just morons like,
yes,
look,
there's a frequency that some people
operate on.
It's really easy to fucking hijack
their,
there's a lot of people out there that
are just dumb and you're not going to
fix that.
They're doll doll minded folk that
really could be easily influenced and
that's why democracy is such a fuck
system to begin with because it's just
play.
It's all everyone who's playing to that
who can whip those people up and get on
their frequency,
and then there's smart people that can
be manipulated,
they can maybe manipulated once they
attach themselves to an ideology.
Like we were talking about,
like people on the left that are
avoiding all the craziness about
Hillary.
Like you had a quote that I really liked
that's on your twitter.
You know that if like Hillary was a man
that had done the all the same things
that she like,
what is the quote?
What does it your exact,
I see.
Like I said,
if hillary was a male republican with
the exact same voting record,
all of her supporters would hate her
with a passion.
Yeah,
it's true.
And it's 100% sure.
100% true.
I mean,
it's not,
this is not controversial in any way,
shape or form.
Hillary is is,
you know,
I mean in the stuff I was saying before,
but she's,
she's like courting the left.
She's courting people who are supposed
to be liberals and you'll go,
she's supported every single war of my
lifetime,
every single war.
Well,
nothing that they can get past that.
She didn't support gay marriage up until
2013 even their pet issues.
Yeah,
it's,
she's,
she's a weird one man.
She's a really,
really weird one.
That fucking Libya thing.
We came,
we saw,
he died like,
that's okay.
Like are you kidding me?
What you remember when,
uh,
the fucking Vermont Guy Screamed?
I know we're going to go all the way
Howard Dean and that one yell did men
it,
that's it.
They saw it and they're like,
fuck this guy.
We,
we came,
we saw he died.
Ha ha ha.
Like that doesn't,
you don't think that lady is fucking
crazy.
You don't think that lady's fucking
cars.
I mean,
you're down for her.
That's,
that is a completely an ideology thing.
[inaudible] she's,
she's on your team.
You're going to,
you're going to go along with it.
Just,
it's a religion just like you're,
you're subscribing to some predetermined
thing.
It says,
it's just,
it's weird for me to see,
first of all,
it's weird that she wants to be
president.
Like,
aren't you old?
Like you're an old lady.
How much energy do you have?
Got a ton of money.
You just had your first grandkid,
you got like perspective,
like what are you trying to do?
He's trying to make history as a woman.
Is that what it is?
I mean,
do you want to just like get back at
your husband for getting his Dick Sucked
and in 1991 or whatever the fuck it was?
Yeah.
I mean,
I don't even think it's that.
I think it's,
it's,
I mean,
who knows who I,
you know,
I'm not in their head,
but I think these people are like power
brokers that just want more and more of
it and it's a real,
it is probably a thrill unlike anything
we could imagine to have that much power
and they've,
they've tasted a little bit of that,
you know?
Yeah.
Just,
it seems to me that she's like so old,
but she would just want to chill,
you know?
It just doesn't make any sense to me.
She's,
she's an old lady.
Like she doesn't have good health.
I,
that was the other thing that concerned
with,
she had some health issues,
right?
I think she had like concussions or
something.
Yeah,
there was,
it was hit in the head.
I forget what it was,
but it was when beat the fuck out of our
imagine that turns out the bill just
wailed on her and she wants to keep it
quiet.
Bill fucking Kot he had kicked her.
He's been accused of violence.
Wow.
She has suffered from fainting spells
since at least 2005 and that year she
passed out,
presumably sober while giving a speech
in 2012 she passed out yet again and
suffered a concussion.
Holy Fuck.
Presumably sober is something that if
they ever have to say it,
it's just not good.
You got issues.
We're always presumably sober.
I'm not usually pursuing me,
but all right.
You know,
but this idea that she fell asleep and
hit and hit her fucking head,
like when people fall and hit their
head,
it's one of the worst things about
getting knocked out is not getting
punched in the head.
It's you falling down and getting hit in
the head with the earth,
like their,
their heads bounce off the ground.
That's like a big issue in street fights
and stuff.
When you watch someone get sucker
punched,
they fall down and their head gets
bounced off the curb.
And I think people who have like
epilepsy and things like that,
like that's the big fear.
What happens is that that you end up
cracking your head on the ground.
It's not just the seizure seizures.
Um,
yeah,
there's,
there's something,
I don't know,
Hillary Clinton said recently,
and this would probably be one of the
tactics she tries to use against trump,
but she said something along the gut.
She goes,
you know,
I just,
I don't know if he's the type of guy we
would want having control of the nuclear
codes.
And it's just like an interesting thing
to look at what your like how crazy is
it that any one person has control of
those nuclear codes?
Like we're just counting on one person
to not snap,
to not kill the whole world.
Yeah.
Hopefully you don't ever just like,
I've had enough.
I'm fucking right.
Well,
we know that people kill themselves.
Right?
That alone should just disqualified
human beings from having that kind of
power.
Are Human beings capable of killing
people?
Yes.
For no reason.
Randomly.
Yes.
Um,
what about killing themselves all the
time?
How often?
Every day.
How many people?
A lot.
Oh,
well we can't have people run it.
So let's have a person who's,
uh,
a politician who's in the highest stress
job.
Imagine about,
let's have them just have control of
those codes.
Unfortunately,
that is the green light for the robot
overlords to take over because we can't
trust people.
Will,
the robots are just going to be way more
sober about this.
They're going to make rational decisions
based on logic and mathematics and
possibilities and probabilities and the
understanding of human race that we
really can't comprehend because we're
just monkeys.
Is this when you brains,
you bring me into your giver society.
Now I'm gonna bring you to one of those
landmark meetings.
It was landmark forum meetings.
Yeah.
Um,
I think that it's this entirely,
uh,
it's entirely possible that ai is going
to be how we dictate government in the
future.
Yeah.
Allen Iverson is going to rule out on
the varsity basketball as well,
but they used to call them Ai.
Don't joke.
Uh,
but yeah,
it is.
It does seem like that'd be an
interesting tipping point.
I do feel like I'm more on the side of
technology than on the side of being
afraid of it.
Oh yeah,
me too.
I just feel like it's going to be more
of a,
it's,
it's humans will be guiding it at least
to a certain point and I think it's
gonna make life a lot better.
I think we are some weird CNN enemy type
character,
some weird fucking primitive life form
that has really kind of outdated and
it's not going to,
we're not going to make it.
You think we're going to have to
combine.
We're gonna symbiotic.
We're going to become symbiotic.
We're going to definitely have computer
chips in.
Our brain will start off with.
You'll be able to store your memories
and sharing with your grandchildren.
All we have to do is install this chip
and then next thing you know we'll be
get increase your vision with this
retina implant and we can double your Iq
in three weeks.
Oh fucking sign me up.
But it's hard to say no,
no.
Well I know that your joints are
bothering you,
Mr.
Wilson.
Let's replace your hips with artificial
hips.
Oh,
okay,
let's do it.
Okay,
now you've got artificial hips and
you're like,
you know what?
We found a new way to replicate the
spine without any of the pain and issues
and uh,
we're just going to replace it all with
Titanium and Oh,
okay,
well I'm in.
And then next thing you know,
your,
your bones getting brittle,
sir,
you're getting old.
Well,
fortunately we figured out a brain
transplant with a bio identical body.
We're going to take your brain and only
be outside of your current body for
three minutes.
Whoa,
hold on.
Okay,
what am I now?
Because I'm now,
I'm a brain inside a new body.
I don't want to do that surgery the
first year they come out with it.
I want to wait like a few years,
let them work the kinks out.
No problem with that is those people
that got,
at first we'll take over,
there'll be reading each other's minds
and flying and breathing under water and
you just want to have a chance to
compete.
Good.
Did,
they're going to gather up all the money
and the resources.
They're going to have all the hookers
and then they don't even need hookers
because they can get there.
I was going to say,
take an orgasm just by pressing their
temple Jews in their pants for that.
That'll be a big turning point,
man.
If they can ever create a thing where
like our sexual desires are taken care
of.
Oh yeah.
We don't need,
I mean,
yeah,
that's,
that'll be an interesting,
uh,
just fundamental change in humanity when
people get addicted to that and that's
going to be a virtual reality thing,
but then it will be hollow because
they're going to get addicted to it and
they're not going to be any
consequences.
Like one of the things about sexual
conquest,
I think it's one of the same things with
all sorts of uncertainty.
You never know how it's gonna turn out.
And so there's risk involved and it's
scary and people get addicted to this
risk.
And even the risk of rejection,
I mean it's not like really scary,
like anything could go wrong,
but there's a game going on.
Like,
can I get these people to love me?
Like how do I get these people to want
me?
Oh,
I got to have the right chains on the
right car and show up at the right
place.
And you know,
you need to get the right spot where
there's a table service and you know,
I have to have a bunch of people that
are famous around me so that I looked
like a pimp.
You know what I mean?
Like there's the whole identity thing
and then it validates your identity to
get that check doesn't always work.
Some girls come up and like this mother
fucker think he something and she walks
off like that bitch.
She doesn't even know who I am,
you know?
And they,
they're trying to like figure out a way
to become special.
Well if everybody just has to,
you know,
just download the fuck program and all
of a sudden you're in an orgy with a
hundred thousand tens all lining up to
blow you.
Like where's the fun in that real,
but that's why the human,
the human experience works in strange
ways.
So maybe then that's what we'll be
attracted to.
Like,
you know,
people will want to go back toward kind
of the thrill of the hunt.
He's like,
oh that's easy.
I think it'll be more like a video game
where video games are no fun.
If you get to play on God mode,
you know,
you play a video game on God mode,
he can't get shot.
You run around blowing everything away.
You when it's,
there's no thrill.
They're so easy.
It's no consequences.
The Allen,
uh,
Helena,
what's his name?
Alan Watts.
You ever hear that guy?
He's like a hippie short philosopher
guys.
But he was saying like the idea of like
that's why basically this dream that is
life.
That's why it's like this.
Oh cause we were like all powerful.
But then we got to a point where that's
no fun anymore.
So you want to like have life.
Yeah.
What was his quote?
He was talking about it game.
He was saying if you were going to
construct a game about human
civilization,
that's exactly what you can,
you would construct,
you would construct the game.
That's like what we're doing right now
and this is exactly how a divine being
would play.
Well he,
well the one I heard him,
he was like saying like almost like
imagine like you've already lived
through all those God mode games.
You've got bored of that.
That's why you're here.
Cause you're like,
yeah,
God mode is not that fun anymore.
Let's say,
you know,
try something that's a little bit of a
challenge.
Yeah.
And this is,
you know,
the level of challenge that you wanted.
Well it's an interesting philosophy and
it's an interesting perspective but lots
of this shit,
you know like obviously we don't know
exactly where this is going to go.
And you're,
you're talking like a little bit out
there.
Not that this has even that far away.
I mean if you look at like a Nokia phone
was compared to where you know,
these things are,
I mean it's a,
it's a big difference.
It's not that far off into the future.
But even just little things like I
personally,
I get really fascinated by what the
implications towards government and how
we organize society.
So when something,
I mean we can just three d print guns
and everybody can three d print a,
I mean we don't really need a fight
about the second amendment anymore cause
you've got it.
Everyone's going to have a gun if they
want to have a gun.
And I feel like there will be a lot of
these types of things that just kind of
know a fi a lot of government,
whether or not it's like it doesn't
matter because people can just go over
here and do it.
So we don't even need to have this
debate which to meet should be the way
lots of things are settled.
Like,
I mean who cares about debating over gay
marriage or something like that.
Like people associate,
however they want to associate.
That's one of those non issues that's an
issue to people that are actually are
gay that want to get married,
but the reason why it gets bounced
around,
I feel like it's like a beach ball at a
concert.
They just chuck it out there.
Whenever there's like something really
serious that people want to talk about,
they throw that around as if it's like,
oh,
this needs to be addressed as well.
Then it becomes a distraction and I
think you're 100% right.
I think it gets used as a distraction.
I think it's also something where
government,
it's search itself somewhere and then
there's going to be a debate over it.
Whereas if government wasn't there,
we just wouldn't need to have any of
this.
I mean,
why does it feel the same way about the
women's bathroom thing?
Yes.
Yeah.
It just seems like,
come on man,
how many transgender people are really
using these bathrooms?
Right?
Is this a giant issue and how has this
issue been handed handled up until now
and how has this issue being treated
with more importance than so many real
issues?
So one of the ones that I heard that was
brought up,
which is so bizarre,
is a man who was born a man,
he has a beard,
he does not take hormones,
but he identifies as a woman.
He wants to use the women's room.
He wants you to call him her and he has
a beard.
Yeah,
I met a guy like that.
Fall Asleep.
You're not allowed to because when it
comes to gender,
you can't be preposterous.
You,
if you think you're a fox and you want
to wear a Fox hat,
I'm allowed to mock you.
But if you're a 50 year old dude with a
beard and you have lipstick on,
you want to be called Z,
you're not allowed to say anything.
Now we're talking about gender,
completely healthy,
normal guy.
You fuck you and fuck everybody who
thinks like that.
You guys are a bunch of little nonsense
babies.
Yup.
And you're ruining the way people
communicate.
What do we have left as comedians if a
guy in a dress isn't funny.
Exactly.
I mean come on.
Yeah,
exactly.
That's a really important point.
Well,
my point is that,
you know what my,
I was furious when this Caitlyn Jenner
thing was going on.
When you,
you were supposed to say that she looks
good.
Like no one was allowed to go.
Whoa,
whoa.
What the fuck?
Wait,
hold on.
Surgeries good now.
Like it's good to get your jaw shave
down.
Everybody should celebrate that and say
you look really good.
Like,
no,
she doesn't look good.
60 year old dudes and dresses almost
never look really good.
Yeah.
Like even if,
if she was like,
if it was a chick at that age,
I probably wouldn't be talking about how
good she looks,
but you're telling me a dude in a dress,
those a dick.
Right.
But like had some stuff done to his face
and I have to pretend that's a hot chick
man.
Right.
Frozen face,
Weird Chin thing going on where they
shaved his chin down or her chin down
and then gets a boob job.
Let me tell you something.
If you're a 60 year old and you get a
boob job,
someone needs a fucking hug.
You okay?
Yes.
Relax.
If what if Hillary Clinton got a boob
job and she just was like,
I want to show Donald Trump.
These babies are here to run the
country.
Like,
whoa.
I mean,
this is the,
this is literally what we're talking
about.
I would like her billary Clinton is,
she's at a commensurate age,
right?
How old is she?
64 she's 70 she's close to 70 maybe 60
how old is Bruce Jenner?
He's like 63 or [inaudible] 64 there in
the fucking ballpark.
Yep.
There were in the ballpark.
So if Hillary all of a sudden got a boob
job,
everybody be like,
what the fuck is wrong with her?
But he gets a boob job and because it's
about gender,
we're all supposed to just ignore the
fact that he's got a frozen face.
That's the chins been cut with a fucking
grinder to resemble a female face.
Like what?
All things are Po,
what?
I don't think she's 68 then the same.
Yeah.
Same Dyke out Jesus Christ.
They're exactly that.
They could take out dairy.
He is good.
He's got a dick.
It'll scare the shit out of her as a
dyke session.
You don't want him to show up that you
shit Lord.
He's a shit.
Lord will.
Uh,
but look,
there is something also like the,
I,
I don't,
I'm not like a psychoanalyst.
I mean I don't know,
but are we just going to just because of
like this political pressure throw out
the possibility that it,
it seems to say that maybe you have some
issues that you want to self mutilate
yourself like this.
I mean like this is healthy behavior.
Whatever happened to loving yourself.
Whatever's happened in loving yourself
as who you are.
Like why,
why did that get distorted?
Like well,
how come surgery now is the viable
alternative?
How come injecting a non in dodges
hormones,
exogenous hormones,
female hormones into a male body?
How come you,
how come you have to say that that's a
girl?
Why is gender such an important point to
you?
Like what,
what is it about this that's so
important to you and to,
and to deny that gender and sex or are
like biologically relevant,
you know,
categories that it's not just something
randomly assigned at birth,
right?
I mean,
okay.
For one that of 100,000
babies,
maybe it's,
it's something that's assigned at birth.
I know people always bring up that
example where some babies aren't the
number is,
but there's,
there's,
there's gotta be a lot of people where
they feel like they're trapped in the
body that they don't want to be in.
And that's cool.
If you want to,
you want to,
I'm cool with sex changes.
I'm cool with everything.
I'm not,
I'm not trying to restrict people's
behavior,
but there's something really weird,
I guess it's like an overreaction to
people.
I think in a way it's probably a good
thing.
So people trying to be more sensitive,
trying to be more open minded,
trying to be more accepting.
And that'll probably balance out.
Like we go way out to the left and then
we'll come back more to the middle and
everything will kind of balance it out.
And you'll see the difference between
people that are people that are just
like happier being a woman and then
people that are out of their fucking
mind.
Like there was a radio lab show about a
guy who goes back and forth like he's a
woman then he's a man,
he's a woman,
he's a man.
I just switched.
He's like,
I just switched over now I'm gail.
Like he becomes a woman.
Like,
wait,
you're just a woman now.
Like you were just a man now who am I
talking to you now?
Now Mike,
Mike's back,
something's got it.
I see you're a fucking crazy person.
Look,
if that's not weird is anything weird?
Come on land,
but you don't.
But then people go well with his crazy,
you know what's crazy?
I agree with what you were saying that
there is,
there is almost,
I feel like the general,
like there's a large group of people who
are just trying to kind of not be dicks.
Like you were saying like,
oh,
we're just trying to not be dicks to
people so there'll be good.
But I feel like the people leading the
charge are like trying to kind of wag
their finger at someone.
Like they're trying to go like,
no,
see you're not tolerant.
I'm tolerant.
It's like you're not,
it's a virtue signaling.
That's what Michael Shermer calls it.
He's like,
you're trying to show yourself as to be
more virtuous than the other people.
So you attack them for having a lack of
a strong stance and these things that
you have a strong stance in and so,
and even when he's strong stances,
like really debatable like this,
this whole subject,
you know,
and I'd love the fact that these guys
kept getting busted after they pass
these laws,
allowing men,
transgender women to use the women's
room.
These creepy men were calling themselves
transgender and going into the,
well this is exactly what you knew was
going to happen.
You knew it was going to happen.
Right?
Like,
look,
if you really want people to use a third
bathroom,
here's what you do.
Get the people that support that to fund
it,
get it,
get them to fund it across the board.
Everybody else fuck off.
Like,
how many people are we talking about
here,
man,
that we need a third bathroom.
But that's,
that's why I,
I,
I hate the whole system of taxation and
government and all this shit cause right
there that that can be applied to so
many different things.
Right?
Like even if it's something like planned
parenthood or something like that,
like I'm,
I'm,
uh,
you know,
I think it's a very complicated issue,
but I'd probably lean on the pro choice
side.
Uh,
but it's like what you're going to force
someone who believes abortion is murder
to fund a place that commits what they
see as murder.
Why don't you liberals just get together
and fund it yourself?
Like why do you have to force all these
other people to fund something that you
deem to be a value that they don't
write?
For sure.
That's debatable whether or not taxes
should fund something like that.
Yeah,
I mean,
I don't even,
truthfully,
I mean,
I don't think it's the bit,
I think it shouldn't,
I think they shouldn't.
I agree.
No one should also things to fit if you
believe in it.
Like you said,
you should fund it and it should be
something that the community funds.
Sure.
I mean,
look,
as far as it was,
planned parenthood doesn't just provide
abortions.
They also provide gynecological care.
They provide birth control.
There's like,
this is some really important parts of
that,
but it just gets a lump.
They should have like abortions are us.
And then just like,
let's straight away,
there's no birth control here.
Our birth control is a vacuum.
That's it.
That's all we have,
isn't that,
that was,
you know,
I mean that's probably a,
that that would clear up this.
And then you'd say,
well,
maybe planned parenthood would be a
different entity.
It'd be birth control,
things along those lines.
Well that as a responsible society,
it might be a good idea to invest a
certain amount of money.
Reproductive healthcare like that.
That sounds smart.
And this is another thing that a
technology might,
you know,
solve real quick.
I mean,
once we can kind of create womb light
conditions outside the womb,
it might greatly cut down on the norm,
the number of abortions that are needed.
Yeah.
That's where I'm gonna be real weird
now.
That's going to be real weird when they
decide that the the body,
like women can be far more productive if
their baby is born outside of the body.
Yeah.
But they'll always be like a natural
movement.
Of course.
They'll always be like people who are
like,
well no,
no,
I don't want to do it that way.
Just even now there's people who have
natural child and stuff,
you know?
It's like people like raw wood,
like this table and they're like
handcrafted drinks.
They like,
like that word Mike drinkers were
handcrafted.
Yeah.
I'm going to have a handcrafted hotdog
and even just even just enjoying nature,
you know what I mean?
Like the fact that we'd like to go out
into nature,
like we're so far removed with all this
technology,
but we still want to like,
well I want to like I want to sit in the
place where I would have died from an
infection at 12 I don't want to like
live there,
but I want to like sit there for a
little and then go inside.
I want to lay motionless where the
predators used to Rome.
It is fucking really weird that we call
it the outdoors.
Like I liked the outdoors.
No,
you mean the earth.
You like the actual earth.
We're just,
we're so fucking into being in these
structures that that's our standard
place to be.
The outdoors is rare.
I liked the great outdoors.
Like what do you,
what the fuck are you talking about?
How can you,
like,
we're defining ourselves by the inside
of this structure primarily.
This is,
it's all afterwards,
man.
We're all on this fucking,
I love that.
Uh,
that bit you were doing the other night.
I don't want to like give out if it's
new stuff you're working on,
but there's a thing about just like
paranoia of pot being good.
Oh yeah.
Yeah.
We should,
I hope be paranoid.
I mean,
yeah.
Yeah.
Well,
there's,
there's some,
there's some reality to our life on a
spinning ball that is regularly ignored,
but really fucking crazy when you stop
and think about this,
the reality that we're in a convertible
spaceship and you know,
we don't talk about that,
but we talk about all sorts of goofy
shit.
We're,
we're literally spinning a thousand
miles an hour in a circle hurling
through infinity.
And the more we find out,
the weirder it gets,
the weirder,
the more,
you know,
we think we know something and we're
like,
okay,
this is what a black hole is.
And then we figure something out.
We go,
okay,
it's nothing like that.
It's a no,
and people get mad at Neil degrasse
Tyson because he won't say he's an
atheist.
I think that's another hilarious aspect
of atheism is how tribal atheism is.
I'm been watching these,
his forum where these people are fucking
hurling the most disgusting and evil
insults at Neil degrasse Tyson,
simply because he won't say he's an
atheist.
He's open minded.
And in Neil's like a scientist,
you know,
he's like,
look,
you know,
I'm not a religious person,
but I'm not going to say there's no god.
Well,
why not?
Why wouldn't need not?
There's no fucking evidence that there
is no god.
Well,
there's no evidence that there is a god.
Yeah.
That's what an agnostic is.
That's why I like identifying as
agnostic.
Yeah,
because there's like this atheist as
almost like built up.
They,
they're almost,
it's like so dogmatic and religious in
their beliefs.
Like you have to believe in this.
There is nothing,
nothing happens after daddy would admit
that there's nothing.
Dave admitting that there's nothing.
It's like maybe I don't know nothing to
do mushrooms and tell me there's nothing
and that same,
that same person will completely agree
with you when they're on mushrooms.
Then maybe when they were off they'll go
like,
eh,
it was just a month.
Ego will come back.
It's a whole explanation.
The visual Cortex is being affected by
five,
four,
four o'clock and I'm a field trip to
mean.
Yeah.
Someone I remember arguing with him like
a hardcore atheist about this and they
were like,
hey,
really dude,
that shit that goes on when you're on
mushrooms,
it's just a chemical reaction.
You're like,
yes,
it is.
So is every experience you've ever had
in your life?
Yeah.
It's just the chemical reaction.
Your life is a chemical reaction,
so without the proper chemicals you,
your brain goes crazy.
You had hallucinations.
It's was like,
yeah,
you get depressed,
you get suicidal or you get euphoric.
What do you think?
MM MTMA is.
It's a chemical reaction,
but it's one that your brain already
has.
It's already in there.
That's why it works.
Yup,
that's right.
And you're finding a way to kind of a,
to trigger to use their words to trigger
that reaction that just gets you into,
it's weird.
It gets you into something that you
already knew.
It's not even like new information.
It's just like,
it's something you already knew that you
worked very hard to forget.
We're so weird.
People are so weird,
but it's cool.
It's cool that it's weird because like
Allen Watson sang it makes it all fun.
It makes us game entirely exciting.
I'm fucking super pumped that this
relations full of bullshit,
that this election and this,
this,
this way we're interacting with each
other as all chaos.
Oh,
I like it.
I enjoy it.
I would find it info like w like if you
look at trump and Bernie sanders,
like I don't,
I don't love either of them.
I've,
I've problems with everyone.
I think Hillary's the worst of the
worst,
but I have problems with all of them.
But it's so,
it would be so much more depressing to
me if just like Hillary and Jeb Bush had
just waltzed to the nomination.
It's like,
like if the general sentiment of the
public was like,
we're happy,
we're cool with the establishment.
I love that people are,
are like had had it.
And I think it's a sign of the times.
And I think the Internet is also a big
part of that.
I think people are just so much better
informed than at any other time in the
past.
Oh,
well for,
for us,
I mean for the,
for the libertarian movement,
like that's,
we wouldn't exist without the Internet.
So you clearly identify with a movement
like Libertarians.
Is there anything about being a
libertarian that you don't like were
libertarians or into other libertarians?
Um,
sure.
I mean,
there's like,
there's,
there's personal things about different
groups and then there's some groups of
Libertarians that,
uh,
I genuinely don't identify with it all.
Like there's some,
some kind of like Republicans who will
just kind of call themselves
libertarians but are okay with like
fighting wars and stuff like that.
So I don't like that.
Um,
libertarians can be kind of a weird
group if you get
together and we'll just weird to be in a
group.
I mean,
our subgroups weird,
but that's why I don't,
you know,
I wouldn't be comfortable almost
identifying with any other group to meet
the libertarianism or volunteerism is
really just a,
it's like accepting of a principle that
is,
like I said before,
like you,
you,
you shouldn't,
uh,
initiate violence against peaceful
people.
So I just,
I,
I'm okay with accepting that as like a
fundamental truth to me.
It's more online with being like an
abolitionist during slavery times.
It's just like,
we shouldn't have slavery.
What you do with yourself.
I don't know.
I'm not going to jump into a team of
what job you should have.
Right,
but you shouldn't be forced to pick
cotton.
Yeah,
no,
I mean,
and they're all the political
ideologies,
all the political distinctions.
That's the one that makes the most sense
to me.
I don't call myself a libertarian.
I'm just sorry.
I feel like the whole,
the whole idea of representative
government is so fucking goofy.
I just think that any political party
that doesn't address that is,
it's like we're,
we're spinning our wheels.
If we're really allowing this whole
stupid thing to go on the way it's gone
on for so long,
it was created back when it was really
impossible to communicate with people,
so you had to have a representative.
Like now it's really easy to communicate
with people,
but we have the same system of
government that we had back when people
used to write with feathers.
Right.
It's fucking stupid.
The idea of having a ruler,
it's,
it's insane.
It's so dumb.
And our robot overlords,
they're going to fix it.
They will.
They will liberate us.
They will rise.
They will fix it.
I'm really hoping they're libertarian.
Jamie,
don't we wrap this up?
You were trying to show me something
else.
Is there something else that was going
on?
There's no other story.
Just the Kimbo slice thing didn't.
Yeah.
All right dave,
this was fun.
I really enjoy this,
this more often.
When you,
when you back in town and when can
people come see your standup and where
can they find out about you?
Uh,
well you follow me on twitter at comic.
Dave Smith and I'm,
I do a podcast called part of the
problem,
which is all about like this political
stuff and libertarianism.
And then I do another podcast called
Legion of skanks,
which is just a comedy podcast with
myself,
Louis J.
Gomez and big Jay Oakerson.
We're actually,
we're having a festival.
Okay.
We're having skank fest.
It's in New York City.
It's on June 18th and 19th.
We got some really fun guests for this
one.
Dude.
I liked the name skanky process is
awesome.
Well it dude is going to be a yearly
thing.
Let me tell you who we got coming for
that.
So we got stan hope.
Woo.
Doug.
Stan hope will be there.
Uh,
Ari be on it.
Bobby Kelly,
uh,
Brian Red Redman is doing like a death
squad show of me.
Lewis and a big J and I think some other
really good ones too.
Then I'm blanking out on.
Michael Che is going to be there.
Beautiful,
beautiful,
very fun.
But follow me on twitter at comic.
Dave Smith.
All right.
Yeah.
Fucks.
That's it.
Thank you,
Dave.
That was awesome.
Thank you so much.
Do this much more often.
Definitely.
Whenever you're in town.
All right.
Goodnight everybody.
See You tomorrow.
Bye.
Yeah.