Let's get home.
He Ha what's up dude?
What's going on?
Come on your shirt.
What is that?
You've got a lot going on there.
We take a penguin with shark teeth.
This is my homage to Albert Hoffman in
the creation of LSD.
Oh Wow.
In shirt form.
Oh,
well that's Hoffman talk with Jesus
Christ and then you use all these crazy
animal parts for squares and I'm full
garden blowing out of his head.
Did you know that a road runner can eat
a fucking rattlesnake?
I didn't,
but that's gangster.
There's a video of it.
Somebody tweeted it to me the other day.
I'm like,
there's no way this is real,
but it's 100% real road runner hunts and
killed a fucking rattlesnake and then
eats it and it's eating this thing like
it's way bigger than it and it's just
trying to swallow it.
You've no idea how gangster,
maybe that's a hard runner.
Identifies as a pterodactyl.
Maybe he does.
Check this out.
Watch this.
First of all,
when you really get a good,
you look at them from a distance.
It a little bird.
You're a little,
I'm not worried about you,
but when you look at them like close up
like this and it's high resolution
photography,
you realize like how fucking predatory
these birds are.
Like,
look that,
that the snake takes a lunge at him.
He's like,
Nah,
bitch,
not today.
Snap gets them right on top of the
fucking head.
And look how he does it,
man.
He smashes his head against the rocks,
Yeah.
When people discovered the dinosaurs
were probably birds,
that's even more terrifying.
I a hundred percent believe it.
I've told you the story about my
chickens,
right?
With the feed the mice,
dude,
it's really,
the whole thing is really bizarre
because it just shows you how like
people have these attachments to a
certain species for no reason.
Like a Steven Nela talks about it with
bears.
He calls him charismatic Megafauna,
but there's something about 60.
So eloquent.
You know,
when he's,
uh,
he,
he's,
he's right though.
There's like something about bears that
make some very different in our eyes,
in any other animal and birds,
they have these hierarchies.
So this hawk flew into my fence.
I have a glass fence hog.
Didn't know what the fuck is going on.
Boomp kod jacked.
My daughter's rescue the bird and then
they go to the pet store and buy little
pinkies,
which are these little tiny mice and
they feed them to the hawk.
So they feed this little tiny mouse had
decided the mouse is not as important as
the hawk.
The Hawk has stay alive.
Fuck these little baby mice.
So they feed the baby mice to the
hockey.
It's all of them.
But one my daughter went to keep,
but I said,
you can't keep,
it's going to die.
It needs,
you know,
it needs to have milk.
I'll just feed it to the chickens.
So there's a lot of hemming and hawing
and a lot of crying.
Everybody wants to the mouse to stay
alive.
Ft just fed 30 of them to this fucking
dinosaur majestic hawk.
It's flying monster.
And so I bring it into the chicken coop
and I mean I put that thing on the
ground for not even one half of one
second and they were tearing it apart
and running around with it.
It was their monsters.
That rotor thank just confirms
that I've to 100% new respect for birds
now.
Yeah.
I think it's,
it is interesting how people,
but it's,
you think about bears,
right?
And people have love bears since way,
way back for like teddy bears.
You know,
before there was the internet and these
different things.
There's just certain animals that you
have this kinship towards and certain
like sacred animals when you're down in
the jungle and different places that
always seem to inspire something within
mankind.
Yeah.
And I don't know why it is,
but I,
I think I just sort of accept it now.
Like I don't feel the same way about
bears.
I do about deer.
I think deer are wild and they're cool
and I love that they exist.
But I have a much more predatory feeling
around them than I do around bears.
Bears are like this weird thing.
The,
Oh,
you can eat them too,
you know?
Yeah.
You know,
it's just,
it doesn't have the same feeling.
And as an animal,
there's this insane reality of what they
are,
this enormous like wild dog thing that
can kill you.
And some of them are just giants,
just gigantic wild dog thing.
You can kill you and we'd love them.
I remember sitting in the,
obviously we were out there with the
bears,
just sitting there in the woods and
watching them screw around.
It's,
it's something different for sure.
It's at least in,
especially too,
when they're kind of looking at you like
the connection of looking at the bear
and the bear looking at you.
I think it's different.
Yeah.
It's very good.
When a deer looks at you,
Oh dear,
looks at you like,
what the fuck?
What the fuck are you doing that's
inside?
And the bear looks at you like,
hey man.
Yeah,
that's what doing here.
That's what's the different,
it's like a different whole thought
cycle.
I sometimes think of thoughts like the
small wheel and the big wheel.
It's almost like bears are just on that
slightly bigger wheel like us,
you know?
That's what it is.
Right?
That's gotta be a big part of what it
is.
Like we almost inherently recognize that
they have a level of understanding
that's above the undulates.
You know,
like there's something about those
omnivores.
There's like a level,
especially them,
there's a level of understanding,
but at the end of the day,
like if you see how they behave,
like this is a thing,
especially about grizzly bears that I
got out of that grizzly man movie is
there.
There's so almost robotic in their
predatory drive and their,
their drive to survive.
There's survival drive.
It just,
just moving around looking for stuff to
eat all the time.
Yeah,
there are so big,
you have to eve teach so much when
you're that big.
But the advantages,
instead of hiding all of the food that
you need for the winter,
like a squirrel,
you ease,
eat and eat and eat and nobody's going
to take your food from you cause it's
just fat on your body.
Like the only way to get that fat is the
fight the bear.
And nobody wants to fight the bear so
they can survive the winter a whole
different way.
It's just a cool way to approach it,
but a bizarre way.
It's so fascinating when you see all the
different methods that nature's figured
out to sort of overcome the obstacles
that the environment can throw at you.
It's animals that
can survive.
I was in the ocean,
uh,
recently,
we were snorkeling and I'm looking
around and all these turtles and all
these fish and I'm like,
did they live here?
They fucking live.
I mean I can only stick my head under
there for a few seconds.
I come up,
I got to spray water on the top of the
nozzle.
They fuck it.
There is a living thing surviving in
there.
It's like life has found a bunch of
weird,
weird ways to get along and a bear was
one of the weirdest ones.
Just get fat as fuck.
They get big round in Jelly and then
he's take a nap.
Like fuck this winter.
Fuck that.
I'm not stupid bro.
What am I a moose?
I'm going to walk out there and freeze
to death like an asshole.
I'm just going to sleep like there's the
strategy involved in that.
It's so much deeper than the strategy of
all the other animals,
the other animals.
That's the pig.
One of the big things with I guess a
deer cause they fucking freeze to death,
man.
That's how they went up dying.
Yeah.
I wonder,
you wonder as that evolves that whole
hibernation pattern.
If they're just like taking a little
naps first when that's the fellow and
then f one bear like sleeps two weeks
and all the other bears.
It's like,
what the fuck?
That was awesome and it just sleep a
little bit longer all the time.
How the fuck does that take place?
This is one of those really dumb,
like people who don't believe in
evolution.
Art are arguments.
You're telling me,
you're telling me that's not by design.
Come on dude,
because somebody who's posted a video,
some guy posted a video,
like an animated Gif file of the flat.
He was a flat earth guy and it was just
the earth,
like a flat plane there.
It wasn't even high resolution.
It was like low resolution.
It was flat and he's like,
show me again the curvature.
I'm like,
oh my God dude,
this is,
people are fucking crazy.
Yeah.
Well,
I think that whole people just want to
get a leg up,
you know,
and everything you're doing,
you're just trying to edge someone out.
So if you can believe in flat earth and
it actually is flatter,
you got a little bit of leg up on
everybody else's shit.
The Globe,
right?
So they're willing to take that gambit.
They're willing to place that place that
bet.
Like fuck it man,
I'm going in.
I'm flat earth.
Cause if I'm right and I can say fuck
you to everybody else just a little bit.
That's the ego.
That is the ego I have to do is watch a
couple youtube videos.
You'd be convinced if you don't do
anything else other than that,
like that's the thing.
It's like Jordan Peterson talking about
how we could all become a Nazi guard.
Like we can all believe in flat earth if
we just stretched our mind a little bit
and then a little bit more,
I mean maybe all is the wrong word for
Nazi guard or flat earth,
but I think they could get a lot of us
that you could get.
A lot of us.
I've told you the story about those
fucking rod things that I thought were
real.
I thought there was rods.
You ever heard her?
Roswell rods,
those little w they're supposed to be
insects that are flying through the sky
so fast.
You can't even see him.
And the only way to pick them
up with his video cameras and only way
to actually see them.
So they would find them on these videos
like,
oh my God,
what did you even notice this a time?
And uh,
they decided that there was these
gigantic things that could be,
you know,
who knows how many feet long and they're
like jellyfish and they fly through the
air like fucking lightspeed.
Yeah,
it's those stupid,
it turns out what it was is just an
artifact when you film things,
when you film things with Shitty old
cameras and when they have new cameras,
he,
that's the Rod.
See that thing.
It looks like a twig.
That's what they look like.
And some of them you see like way up in
the sky.
Some of them.
It's just a bug that's flying so fast
that the camera can pick it up.
Right.
So the camera makes it look like that.
Like that last one,
Jamie.
Yeah,
look at that.
See how it looks like.
It's almost like a jellyfish.
We've been through the air.
It's just a video art or like a Bat with
a vapor trail for me.
Yeah it does.
That's that one.
Yeah.
Cause that one's in front of the tree,
but sometimes you see them in the sky so
you don't have a outside of reference.
Yeah.
You know you don't have like,
that one's interesting because it's in
front of the tree.
Like the trees just only,
you know,
a few yards away you can tell.
And if that rod things right in from the
tree,
you can get a guesstimate on how big it
is.
But a lot of the videos of them,
they had them in the sky,
you know,
just flying in the sky for,
I feel like it's 16 feet long.
It's flying.
The speed of light.
I was in Sedona just having lunch and I
was in Sedona is a place where there's
some cool shit and then there's a lot of
wacky new age shit there.
And I was listening to this guy just
talk about orbs,
right?
Like these orbs and he was able to
capture,
I've seen those on film and I've had
orbs in photos and stuff.
All it is,
it's like the,
it's the lens flare effect that creates
like,
I'm not like super into the science of
it,
but I know that I can reproduce it if I
create a lens flare and the thing,
there's going to be an orb somewhere in
the picture.
Right,
right.
So,
but the way they were describing it,
it's like this one,
if you go out it at the right time at
dawn in this special place,
there'll be orbs on the ground.
It's like where they gather.
I'm like,
no bitch,
it's the sun come out.
And every time it creates a lens flare
and your camera,
you know it's,
I would love it if it was that though.
Why is such a party pooper?
Plenty of be amazing if like you could
find balls of light through your round
you like little like organisms are
lifeforms and like if you were more
loving,
they surround you do and you just had to
take a picture of people and tell
whether or not,
oh my God,
it's studes awesome.
Like the seeds from a Wa just kind of
like zone.
They were all just floating all around.
I would deal with that feeling that way
to see it was a camera,
right?
Yeah.
I'll tell you man,
Eddie Bravo had one picture was it was
Eddie Bravo,
a bunch of orbs around them and he had
his hands open like this and the biggest
orb was in his hands.
And I said,
damn,
imagine if we're all,
just imagine if we're all just super
skeptical and we're ignoring something,
I'm going to say fucking real.
Oh,
it's just a camera auto fact.
It's reproducible.
You can go back.
I sure.
Well that's,
I mean it's kind of like once you've
done enough Iowasca and done enough dmt
though,
then you open yourself up to the
possibility that there are things
potentially outside of our ability to
perceive them.
That's Eddie,
right?
They're like,
look,
it's like he's holding it.
It's like you got high enough to see it
before I have his girlfriend spitting on
the camera,
trying to get some more herbs.
Gulen,
like could you recreate orbs?
It's spit,
but look,
if you were going to believe in orbs,
that would be,
I mean shit,
that would,
that'd be the one that I'd go with
whole.
Sure.
He's got to know his hand can see it.
It's clearly a balancing his center,
his love.
It would be the shit if it was real.
It's like all these things would be the
shit.
If they were real,
like there's some ufo videos over Turkey
and I saw it.
I didn't even click.
I you even click on it.
That's how blahzay have gotten about the
UFO or deal.
I don't because I don't believe you
anymore.
I'm not clicking on it.
Yeah,
I would love it if it was real.
Wow.
That's the weird thing about real,
right?
You know,
it's like when you go see something was
such a vivid imagination,
like especially in like the psychedelic
space,
you see something and then there's that
debate,
like is that real?
Right.
And then if enough people,
like if enough people have seen it or
not,
people believe in it.
Like dragons for example.
Like are they real or not?
Well,
they're clearly not in three d space,
but everybody knows and has emotional
reactions to this one being and they
come to you envision.
And so what is that?
Is The dragon real?
What?
What's your definition of real?
You know,
like,
is it the collection of an idea in your
brain?
All of the lights gathering around that
you can share and reproduce.
And then that thing comes through like
an archetype in your brain.
Like it's the archetypes.
There's so many of them,
right?
There's the Chinese Dragon,
the Japanese Dragon,
the Gothic Dragon.
No,
those,
the Medieval Look Dragon.
How many different ones are there
feeling?
Dragons videos,
infinite dragons,
slightly slight variations on the
dragons.
That's,
that's the thing.
It's like it's,
it is an archetype of being,
I've seen them,
they've come to me many,
many times always.
And it seems to be there,
the being of ultimate power,
like a being of supreme power.
And that's the archetype that it
recommends.
There's no animal in the animal.
A hierarchy that trumps the dragon.
And he shows up.
Everybody shut the fuck.
Exactly.
He comes flying in with fire coming out
of his face.
Everybody just settles down this giant
flying Lizard.
A con blow fire.
Yeah.
So it represents that kind of power.
My Tattoo artist actually got a cool
thing.
It's like I never tattoo a dragon
snarling because no dragon would ever
need to snarl.
Like there's nothing he would point,
there was nothing,
a dragon,
whatever,
roar at kind of a snarling,
you know,
cause it is that being of fucking
supreme power.
It's a strange thing that there's so
many different cultures that have sort
of captured that.
And you've got to wonder
how many different things when we
missing from the fossil record,
you know,
and we know of birds exist,
who knows how many things existed that
we just haven't found yet.
It's entirely possible that some weird
fucking lizard existed at some part of
the world and people could say it,
you know,
some weird snake thing that walked and
then the legend spread of that.
And then people saw a bunch of different
giant lizards.
Like if you saw a Komodo Dragon,
if you were just wander through the
jungle and you saw a full size Komodo
dragon and had its mouth open,
you would for sure.
Thank you.
In the presence of a demon.
If you ran away from that,
right,
no cameras,
right?
No cameras.
Got To take things from your imagination
and drawing for people.
What are you going to draw?
You're gonna draw goddamn demon hissing
giant lizard with saliva coated in
botulism.
Those are horrible monsters,
man.
Those are fucking ruthless,
ruthless predatory lizards.
Giant lizards.
And you would draw them.
They would be,
they would be,
you know,
have wings.
I mean if you are just a primitive
person,
you ran into one of those things.
If she ran into a Nile Crocodile,
Jesus Christ,
I put a video up,
a one Jack and it vulture does he that
shit.
This vulture fucked up and got too close
to this lake.
They Jack everything except for the
hippo.
Don't see the crocodiles Jack in the
Hipaa.
No,
they still clean.
They stay clean.
Look how he gets him.
Look at this.
He's just boomed bitch.
Just out of nowhere,
get the fuck at Uhmm.
Gimme that chicken just jumps right back
in there with them.
Oh,
right under the water.
What a what a creepy animal.
Lives in this place where you can't see
it at all.
It's Brown water,
fucking brown water and they can hide in
three feet of that shit for like hours.
They don't have to come up and they just
hear the vibrations.
They know where you are and they just
jump up and chat to you.
I think so much of the way that we
developed was to try and avoid that
situation.
Fuck our soft bodies.
You know all of this brain activity that
we have so much of it you after credit
towards avoiding that exact fucking
monster.
Yeah,
well hence the like the stereotypes that
the stronger the person dumb or the
person,
you know like if you have time to make
all that muscle bitch,
you ain't got time to read any books.
You're not.
You know,
I learn and what that soft dude over
there,
he's going to save us.
That's,
he's over there doing physics and shit
trying to figure out how to make swords.
Your bench press will not help the
asteroid collision.
That's going to be a big one.
That was the creepiest podcast we did
last week for sure.
Graham Hancock and Randall Carlson
freaked me the fuck out again.
It's too easy to not think.
It's too easy to just not think about
the variables.
Too easy to not pay attention to the
fact that we really are just a species.
It's clinging to a spaceship without a
roof that were just clinging to this
circular orb as it a thousand miles
an hour and hurls through infinity or we
were just hanging out on it and we don't
want,
we don't want to think about it.
It's due grazie.
Yeah.
The depressing part of that whole
cataclysmic particularly is we're,
we got all these fucking nuclear
reactors everywhere,
so like one goes off and then those
things get all disrupted and then the
nuclear radiation is the big issue that
you have to worry about.
Right.
Do you see what they did to Chernobyl?
They created a dome that's two football
fields long.
It's gigantic and they're getting case
the entire enclosure plus the astro
realm of led on that.
Yeah.
That's what it looks like.
It's huge.
It's crazy.
It's a crazy engineering undertaking.
If you look at it and go,
what?
Like you just have to imagine like what
kind of resources and how many brains
were involved.
Look at this thing.
They're going to lift this fucking thing
over the dome is this enormous.
They have these designs for it.
They show the fully competed thing fully
completed.
What does it say there?
30 countries are involved in this.
Wow.
Yeah.
I think,
I mean,
the key is we've got to elevate
consciousness to a point where we're
actually looking at these situations and
being able,
and I think that's the point that Graham
and Randall make.
And I couldn't agree more.
Like people have to be at a,
at a level where we can actually do
something about that instead of fighting
with each other.
You're 100% right.
Look at that image.
That's what it's going to look like.
They're just going to drop that down
over the site.
Like Jesus Christ.
That's big and so big.
That's so crazy how big it is.
Look how thick it is.
That's insane.
I mean,
what are the,
what the fuck does that way?
And the weird part,
it's,
it just feels to me that it's not fully
going to work.
Just like putting,
like,
putting like a tupperware over a Fart,
you know?
Like,
are you going to get the whole part in
the tupperware?
I doubt it.
I think the farts out there,
uh,
Shane Smith went down there and uh,
he was in trouble and they were,
they were hunting these wolves.
There's these radioactive wolves
episode.
I was like,
what are you talking about?
He's like,
all these animals that live around that
area,
they're all radioactive.
Like,
oh my God,
it just hulks out and turns green.
Well,
they probably are experiencing some
mutations.
There was some viral video that was
going around the Internet that was
saying that these are fish that lived
near Chernobyl and it showed these just
enormous,
crazy fish slopping around this little
river and they were there.
That was the vial.
But apparently it's bullshit.
Apparently they're just giant catfish or
something like that that just do exist
in some spot.
They're not radioactive.
That is deep in our psyche though.
That idea that radioactive matter is
going to turn something into some
amorphous new thing.
Yeah.
And it's always,
it's always bad.
It's,
except in comic books,
if you're a dude,
it always works out well.
He always become spider ran or the hulk
or you know,
you just got to pick the animal.
You go into that radioactive soup with.
That's true too.
Yeah.
You got to get a good deal.
Like the stretchy guy.
What's the guy?
The and the avengers,
not the vendors.
The fantastic four stretching guy.
That's a shit fucking superpower.
That is shit.
Oh,
you get to bend.
People get to stretch you out like
Taffy.
I'll fucking,
where do I sign up?
You got to go in with a road runner for
sure.
Oh,
he's got a guy next to him and it turns
into fire.
Like what the Fuck I get?
I just can.
This guy can turn into fire and fly
through the fucking hair.
All I can do is stretch.
That is the most bullshit superpower of
all time.
He could stretch.
He makes his arms go into circles.
He could turn them into a figure eight
like what?
I don't know.
I fought with Dawson and street fighter
and his stretchy ability was definitely
helpful.
Does he have stretchy ability?
Is pretty fine.
He could push both his arms out like
that and they go away in front of the
shoe and the leg,
just straight double Dick Punch and then
he's got that,
the foot like that,
like a long ass front kick,
someone out of the sky crowd to say,
I can't name any of the characters in
street fighter,
nor can I tell you what they do.
I don't know anything about that.
I played that a couple of times.
I was like,
this is the old man that hit me right in
this sweet spot and I couldn't,
I couldn't ignore it.
I was just at that age,
you know where you have all the
testosterone brewing but the frustration
because we little and you couldn't beat
anybody up,
right?
So you just play something in a video
game and then you can beat everybody you
up if you're that avatar.
I wonder how many fights have been
started from street fighter?
Like if there was like a running tout.
Do you know what I mean?
Like Mcdonald's has.
How many burgers sold?
How many likes fights started by a game
of street fighter.
Less than Madden for sure.
Less than that because I see right
playing that and it often ends in
fights.
Yeah.
That should be a whole youtube channel.
Like Madden street fights.
They should come with some gloves.
Dudes love their flip all man.
They love,
I listened to bill birth podcasts and
sometimes he'll go like an hour just
talking about football.
They fucking told us we couldn't do it.
Who told you?
Yeah,
us as the US is the funny thing too
cause that's again like the identity
playing this trick.
It's that that lust for tribalism that
we all have.
Like we want to be part of a tribe.
Oh that team is our tribe and you'll
fight for it and you'll feel shitty
about it and you'll feel elated about
it.
I mean it makes the Games interesting
but it also opens you up to a weird
spectrum of emotion.
Yeah.
You're that kind of pride for your
neighborhood,
for your town or your state.
All that gets weird.
Yeah.
Till till you get to America.
That's where we crossed the fucking
line.
Boy.
Mirka you better be proud that'd be
proud of from here.
Donald Trump says he's going to put
people in jail for a year if they burned
the flag.
Here's what's hilarious.
Hillary Clinton proposed this in 2005 I
didn't know that somebody tweeted that
to me on twitter.
I think they're having an affair.
They probably been out the whole time.
I feel like either way we win.
Yeah.
That's what's been going on.
All those little shitty little caddy
remarks.
Yup.
What lovers say to each other.
That's exactly right.
When they get nasty with each other and
then them taking me you fucking
deplorable.
Deplorable basket,
but a bucketed deplorables.
What was it and people,
it was,
people just jumped on it.
They've been the worst at like creating
like memes and stuff and like the worst
at coming up.
They were the worst that like coming up
with a campaign.
Thoughts,
you know?
There was just too,
too many things going on with that
election where it was just like,
wow,
you guys are not not that good at this.
Like this.
I'm with her.
Don't say I'm with her.
Don't say that's Jesus Christ.
How obvious we making it.
It were just voting for a check.
Like how obvious.
Well it's more than that.
It's more than that
man.
This everything is getting squirrely and
I think one of the most brilliant parts
of Jordan Peterson's podcast yesterday
was that he identified in his mind and I
tend to agree with them that one of the
reasons why things are getting so
squirrely as we've removed the
metaphysical underpinnings behind our
understandings of everything you know
and so like all of this social justice
and all these pronouns,
I think a lot of that is that we've
removed the metaphysical understanding
of self.
You know and so if you really don't
understand who yourself is,
then you really can't have self love,
self worth,
self confidence because it's all built
on something else and that surrogate for
self that they create his identity,
who you are,
what Pronoun you are,
what you know,
what tribe you identify with,
what you do,
what your race is.
And then all of these parts of identity,
which really have absolutely nothing to
do with self in the metaphysical sense
become the thing that you defend.
You defend that thing as if it is
yourself.
But it's not.
And I think that's,
you know,
one of the paths that I've taken is to
understand those metaphysical
underpinnings.
I understand what the self is rather
than just trying to work on self worth
and self confidence and self love.
But you got to fucking first understand
the cell.
He was a deep dude,
Ben,
that the stuff that he was saying about
religion,
about the need for this understanding of
good and evil and then how it plays out
and to just stay on that balance of good
and evil and to,
to live.
You know what he was talking about a
true life,
really fascinating because it was one of
those things where he's,
he's thinking at an extremely high
level.
And so when you're following them,
you have to be sure you're following
him.
Like,
damn,
I'm really getting what he's saying
here.
You know,
cause he's talking about being someone
who hates ideologies,
but he's a very religious man.
I think really the most confusing part
of what he was saying was the use of the
word religion because it a little bit
like Danielle,
he and his book create your own
religion.
He's created
his variation of religion that allows
him to use that word,
you know?
But for most people,
the colloquial understanding of religion
is much,
much different.
And I think it was confused.
I think he would probably benefit from
maybe looking at that word and seeing if
it's conveying what he actually means.
But yeah,
I think you're right.
But I think I understood what he was
saying and I think he definitely
understood what he was saying.
The problem is,
you know,
he's,
he's looking at it in terms of that
these archetypal stories are integral to
being human 100% and that they've been a
part of our life for so long that this
recent jettison that our society has
taken away from it.
You know,
we've sort of launched ourselves away
and become more and more cynical about
our roots and our understanding of who
we are in this world.
And like what is important and what is
bullshit,
you know?
And that's all great.
I think that's super important and
that's,
that's what human beings are here for.
We're here to be curious.
But one of the things that I think
people really do really well with his
structure and when people don't have a
structure,
like a reason
to behave in a,
uh,
an ethical and kind way yeah.
Or,
uh,
you know,
a better to strive for.
They struggle without structure and
without truth as the bedrock truth forms
the bedrock.
And I think that's what he really meant
about these religious truth as compared
to scientific truths,
these,
these true understandings that form the
bedrock that you can build everything
else off of like,
again,
going back to self,
like what is the self?
Well,
when you look deeper and deeper,
it's nothing but you know,
the embodied consciousness,
the consciousness within us.
And then when you understand that your
consciousness,
then you can ditch all of these other
things that you're trying to pile on top
of and make it so important,
like all of these identity things.
But you have to get to at least where my
metaphysical understanding is that the
self is consciousness embodied in this
awesome meet vehicle we get to play
around with and experience life and
interact with each other and tastes
things and fight things and fuck things
like it's amazing.
But ultimately,
you know,
we're just that that spark of
consciousness.
Yeah.
Who the fuck knows.
But what he was saying was cool cause
we'll do what he was saying it was when
Peterson was talking about it,
it was this different level of
understanding I think.
And he's so incredibly well read.
No doubt.
I really liked what he was saying too
about you know how and one of the,
one of the metaphysical understandings
that I have it,
I mean I think you arrive at it from
different ways.
I think religion can obviously be a
great vehicle to help you arrive at
that.
You can do it through philosophy.
You can do it through experience.
And I've kind of gone mostly through
that experience route with a different
plant medicines and things.
And you arrive at these different truths
and that idea that you reconcile the
darkness within you,
that thing inside yourself that is
inherently has all the capacity for
evil.
That was brought to me and in like in a
psychedelic experience where I was going
in and I realized that I myself was all
the darkness and all the light.
I was good and bad,
a raid on a spectrum and was capable of
doing every good thing in every bad
thing.
And it was the most horrifying
experience I've ever had.
Like recognizing that I was all of those
things.
But the only thing that made it,
that decided who I was was choice.
And that choice was enough.
But you had to first reconcile the
capability of being everything before
you can layer on that element of,
all right,
I am everything,
but I choose to be this.
I choose truth.
I choose love.
I choose to have faith against the fear.
And that's,
you know,
that's ultimately then who you are.
But going down into those subterranean
depths and realizing that we all have
fucked up thoughts.
You know,
we're all a little bit off here or there
and I think it's super important to
reconcile.
Just like watching that fucking road
runner Jack,
that snake.
We're animals,
we're living organisms and we are living
organisms that are aware of is crazy.
See of genes that we live in is see a
fucking sells competing for survival and
these weird forms with these weird rules
and we're in that.
But what we're,
as far as we know when the only ones
that are aware that we're in it,
unless dolphins are aware,
they can be aware.
If you've ever heard of something called
the false killer whale [inaudible] dude,
I was in Hawaii this week.
We did a little fishing with the kids,
had a great time and we're on this boat
and this Guy Steve,
who was on the boat with me,
uh,
who was one of the guys working on the
boat told me that they had a run in with
these false killer whales when they were
pulling in these 50 pound tunas and this
fucking gigantic 20 foot long thing.
That thing ever seen one of those?
No.
What the fuck dude,
how did I not know that that existed?
This crazy looking weird whale thing
with giant ass teeth and they call them
false killer whales.
Um,
I dunno.
I guess it's like some sort of a dolphin
subspecies or something.
So this a killer whale is too,
they're all cousins I guess.
But this,
this thing snacked this fucking 50 pound
tuna right off the hook.
Just ripped it off in front of him while
he was pulling it in.
And so they said,
oh Jesus Christ,
these things are going to find it.
Let's,
let's get outta here.
We'll go somewhere else.
They went five miles away.
These fucking things.
Follow them.
Five miles and Jak,
two more fish.
Wild,
wild,
wild world out there.
This weekend I had a porpoise steal a
tuna from me.
We were t catching these little
amberjack tuna's,
they're not that big like a big one is
like 20 pounds is like as big as they
get to like most of like 10 pounds,
but they're really tasty.
Anyway,
we're catching these things and I'm
pulling them in and he's going crazy.
This thing is going crazy and the
skipper says there's probably a porpoise
chasing yet.
I'm like,
no fucking way.
He's
like,
yeah,
they do it all the time.
They grow up going around this.
There's this one area where these,
uh,
these tune is live skipjacks that's what
they're called,
non amberjack skipjack tuna and this one
area where they populate.
These fucking dolphins have grown up to
know that they can hang around those
boats and they wait until someone
catches one and then when they fighting
fighting,
it can't move very quick.
So these swim up to it.
Well it's on the line and they just jack
them and he jacked it right in front of
me.
Right in front of me.
I'm like,
no fucking way.
And I see this dark shadow underneath
the water come near this flashing fish.
I had to yank this crazy tug and then
the line goes limp.
Thanks.
Oh,
this porpoise.
Just Jack that tuna right in front of
me.
Do that for the Chinook salmon out in
British Columbia to yeah,
they pull your salmon off the line.
They're smart.
I mean they figured out that if your
line is taught,
the fish ain't moving anywhere.
It's fighting.
It's trying to go this way.
The drag and the real.
That's like easy one to get.
Yeah.
And you never hooked those animals to
theirs.
They're too smart for that.
But I said he's hooked him before.
Oh,
really?
Hooked him before.
I didn't know that they accidentally had
snagged one before.
Oh.
Like body snag.
Like I said,
it got bodies like a dolphin.
The dolphin will eat your fish to see
people.
They'll get caught in nets.
They just can't see him.
But you don't see him get cotton,
those hooks.
Yeah.
They never get,
that was one of my bits that you,
if people live in the water,
you'd catch them all day.
Like this difference between dolphins
and people.
It's like they eat fish but we don't
catch them when you go fishing.
Like it's Kinda crazy.
But the um,
the guy said that they had to pull one
in some,
I forget what the circumstances were but
it got foul hooked and they had to pull
it in and a release the hook.
Yeah.
Taking the,
be really careful with it.
Yeah.
Going back to what you were saying
though about the self being this like
collection of cells.
I think that's really kind of
interesting because the self is so many
different cells that are kind of sending
competing signals to the brain.
All of them trying to almost vie for
their own survival and then the brain
puts out like a prime directive of what
the things that are best for that.
But now that we're understanding so much
of our gut biome and how much that
contributes to the self,
it contributes.
You know,
neurotransmitter production,
immune cell production,
but every time we shit we drop a bunch
of that gut biome into the toilet.
I mean it's,
it's going to feed on the,
on the feces and then we drop it in
there.
So it's like ourself is changing,
you know,
every time we take a dump,
like that collection of things that we
call self,
which are some pathogenic organisms,
some helpful organisms,
some skin cells,
all of it's contributing to self.
All of it's contributing messages to the
brain and it's changing and all the
time.
And I think that's why people,
when they go looking for the self,
it's so squirly cause what is the self,
I mean it changes every single day.
You're a different self when you're
angry or happy or mad or in love as when
you're inspired or after a workout
you're different self.
Then when you start,
we're just this amalgamation but it's
almost an ideology of self to call it
one thing and call it,
oh this is me.
Yeah,
we're really,
we're just this a lot more nebulous than
that.
And that's why people get confused and
they want to cling to something concrete
and ideology self.
Here I am.
I am.
Well you got a v a vague idea of who you
are.
Yeah.
Like you kind of know you know a
neighborhood.
Ah,
I've been down this road.
I know that's road,
but you know,
he could go down a bad road one day,
you know,
go down to someone towed your car and
they weren't supposed to road and you're
like,
oh I didn't even know this dude.
He there's,
there's weird parts of you that come out
and weird altercations or weird moments
of vulnerability and you go,
wow,
I didn't even know that person was in
there.
Yeah.
Like just looking at,
even as much as I think about it,
I'll still get stuck and weird self
land.
Like this past Saturday,
I don't know what it was all the
Thanksgiving from like noon to 7:00
PM on Saturday,
I was a comment.
I was the worst.
I mean,
I didn't even want to hang out with
myself.
Like,
and then at some point like around seven
o'clock I was like,
oh my God,
like what is going on?
Will you let,
did you eat too much shitty food?
Maybe.
Yeah.
I don't know what it is.
I don't want to make excuses.
I just,
you know,
as the my mail menstrual cycle,
it was in what way were you like short
with people where you just like,
I just didn't want to be around.
Everything was like such a big deal.
Not a big deal,
you know like whatever,
whatever little thing came up was like a
life ending life shattering thing and it
was just weird.
It's just weird understanding.
And then it lifted like a fog.
Like just like when the clouds move and
the son Pierce through and I was like,
what the hell was that?
He's like,
so that self is a slightly different
self then the self that came after it,
the self that's here now the self on a
cup of coffee versus that.
And so I think,
you know,
it just,
we try to oversimplify that when really
we're so much more than what we are and
there aren't boundaries.
This idea that you can contain
everything.
This is me,
this is not me I think really doesn't
make a lot of sense,
but we filled some techniques to making
yourself more positive all the time.
Like I think that's one of the things
about the Wim Hoff breathing that I
really like is that when you,
when you do an any kind of breathing
exercise,
I think any,
like even a the beginning of beak from
Yoga,
when you do that crazy breathing,
when you breathe and then your net goes
back.
I think what,
what that really makes you do is
concentrate on the moment and it
releases excess tension to the point
where you have a better ability to be
yourself.
You know?
Totally.
I think there's a lot of burdens that we
don't recognize that cling to us and
we're carrying them around and we don't
realize it until we get them free and
then we'll go,
ah,
I just,
I needed to go run.
You know,
like there's some times you just go,
I just needed to lift,
I need to do something now.
Nothing's bothering me.
Like this same world exists but 45
minutes or rigorous exercise
and he don't give a fuck about it
anymore.
And this thing that was this
overwhelming moment in your life,
like it's all a matter of perspective.
[inaudible]
and the best perspective that I find is
when I can tap into that consciousness
element,
what you can call it,
your people call it your higher self,
whatever.
There's a billion names for it,
but it's the best version of yourself.
You know,
like who you are at your very,
very best when you're filled with the
most love and the most peace and the
most like inner just contentment and
satisfaction,
like your best self.
And then when you can ask,
find ways to access that,
I think absolutely right.
Yoga,
breathing,
flotation,
you know,
nature flow state,
all of these ways are ways to tap into
that best self,
which is usually,
you know,
anchored in the present moment and is
you at your very best.
And from that vantage point,
you see the obstacles laid out in front
of you and maybe they don't go away,
but maybe you can look at them,
you know,
as you should like an advantage and
opportunity to grow stronger,
you know?
Yeah.
Just perspective.
I think their purse,
I think all of those things,
including marijuana and a lot other
psychedelic compounds,
their perspective enhancers.
Yeah,
and I think that's what they're here
for.
We just,
we equate them with the negative aspects
of,
we know that some drugs have on people,
so we know that,
you know,
sometimes they can be bad,
but I feel that same way about religion
and I feel that same way about
government.
I feel that same way about a lot of
things,
just because certain aspects of it are
fucked.
It doesn't mean it doesn't have some
massive benefits for us.
Like even like you could call it like
religion.
A lot of ways it's like bill cosby.
Okay.
Is Bill Cosby did some horrible shit,
some horrible shit.
Most likely.
Right.
But he made a lot of fucking people
laugh.
Yeah,
right.
It's a lot of people.
If you looked at the number of victims
versus the number of people that
benefited from it,
hit him.
You'd go,
wow,
what a complex situation that says you
have this monster who also is doing
amazing work.
Yeah.
Like he's making people show happy
everywhere and he's enforcing this like
really positive way of behaving and
thinking for people.
Like you could never imagine yourself
swaying around bill cosby,
you know he was this upstanding PhD guy.
I think in a lot of ways that's the same
way about religion.
Like if it wasn't for religion and I'm
not an advocate of religion currently,
like to use it currently in the same
form that everybody's using it,
but I'm just saying if you looked at
like humankind as a whole,
if it wasn't for believing that we had
these crazy rules,
then we had to do good.
Otherwise the dad would come and strike
a stat if it wasn't like the fear,
literally live literal fear of God that
kept people from just raping and
pillaging and doing whatever the fuck
they wanted to.
Who knows how much longer it would have
taken us to get to the place where you
can fight over gender pronouns.
Yeah.
Right.
It's almost like a system that may at
some have been necessary.
Yeah.
We don't know that people,
we weren't around people 3000 years ago.
We don't know what they would've done
without the threat and that fear of God
because there was no dna evidence.
There was no,
you know,
inspectors and detective.
So maybe it was necessary,
but clearly now the dogma that's
surrounding it is an impediment to our
happiness and impediment to,
you know,
the,
the better truths that are going to
hopefully make this world,
you know,
a more positive place for everybody.
Well they,
because I think you nailed it when you
said like a program because I think
that's really what it is.
It's almost like a program that human
beings sort of manifested to travel to
the next stage of development.
Like,
look,
we're just not going to get here to
thing and claw.
I ain't going to work,
boy.
Okay.
You know,
we've got agriculture but we're still
behaving like monsters.
You know and they had to just figure out
things to worship,
things to love,
things to cherish,
things to believe in and the new pass
these things down.
I was like this higher daddy,
this higher daddy thing cause that's
what it is,
man.
The problem is a couple of people got
it,
saw that,
jacked it jacked and then manipulated it
for their own power and they want to
talk to the gunk.
Yeah,
exactly.
I mean that whole move of all right,
you,
you can't talk to God to talk to God.
You got to come see me and you got to
build me a big house and you've got to
pay me every year and then I'll
translate that message,
you know,
to the divine on your behalf.
Thank you very much.
My favorite version of that is you ever
see the dude who took pictures of
himself in heaven?
No.
That's awesome.
He fucking,
he went to heaven pastor.
He came back,
he had a suit on and a white background,
white background and he said he was in
heaven.
He took photos and he put them up on
instagram.
The photos.
He was selling the photos of him in
heaven.
Yeah,
I come on son.
I think in order for that to work for
people,
you have to break the brain early and I
think you break the brain by saying
something like fear of God.
Oh amazing.
I thought it was all white man.
Why does it have like a Rainbow Hue to
it?
Is it the same photo?
Hmm.
That's weird.
I could've sworn I might be another
person.
No,
it's the same guy.
It's definitely the same guy.
And that's the same photo.
But the image looked yes.
And that image he,
it was,
it was white and some of images it was,
well I think somebody's added something
to that photo.
I think they put like the,
the sun rays and shit.
That's the one.
The one,
see the one above him with the suit.
Not that one right there.
That kept going to the second row.
Second row.
Yeah.
There you go.
Click on that one.
That was the image.
It was just him with a white background.
He said,
Yo,
I'm in heaven.
Dog.
Fucking know Jesus loves you.
I'm telling you man,
and he was selling these photos.
Slick suit though.
Suit.
What's that?
Ruffled shirt?
What does it say?
What he saw?
We'll burn your heart.
What?
Yeah.
I don't know if that would bring your
heart.
I don't want my heartburn.
I think it's green.
Your heart is good the way it is.
Imagine if there was a heaven and we
were just talking shit.
Imagine if like one day the space
shuttle takes the wrong turn and it's on
its way up into orbit and it just pops
through this little hole and like,
oh shit,
we're and have a Dan Heaven and they get
out,
take their head gear off.
They can breathe.
His angels hanging around up there.
It's like,
you know,
I think it's just people have made that
wrong turn.
Like Jordan Peterson was saying of
taking these things as literal when they
should be metaphysical like we all have
the ability to create heaven and hell in
our own life,
which is a point when we made and then
you know when we are pure consciousness
what I've experienced at least from from
all the psychedelic experiences.
When you,
when the body disappears and becomes
less prominent and you're thinking you
are what seemingly just pure
consciousness,
you know,
there's also that opportunity there for
heaven to embrace all of the love.
And then there's also the opportunity to
look back on your life.
Like,
what the fuck?
You know,
I really,
I made these choices that hurt these
people and that is this almost hell,
you know,
so,
so Helen Heaven is again,
you know,
as above.
So below it's just a mental state,
you know?
And that could be the same,
very same mental state that we go
across.
But instead we tried to make it
concrete.
We tried to,
you know,
Salvador Bosh,
tried to create all of these horrible
things of things biting you and burning
you in vis,
rating your genitals and prying you
apart when all of that is really a
metaphor for what's happening in your
mind,
you know,
not an actual place.
Yeah.
Like the mind of Dick Cheney.
I kinda his Dick Cheney,
go to sleep without pills.
You know,
what kind of,
what kind of dreams does that guy have
right now?
Woo.
And what happens when he's liberated
from,
you know,
from all of the rationalizations.
You know,
like when,
when all of those things is to be like,
like,
you know,
you get in the float tank and you see
all these things that have allowed you
to think a certain way and then you go
floating and then all of those
structures go apart and then you look at
that thing you did and go,
ah,
was that cool?
Was that Douchey?
You know,
like you cause it,
but he's never had that moment.
He's never stopped the hamster wheel
long enough to get still to be able to
look at his life from his higher self
and be like,
Whoa,
what am I doing?
Look at all this momentum.
Look at all the software viruses that my
open open source consciousness has
picked up along the way.
These different fears,
different greeds,
these lust for power,
these different things that have created
this thing that's never stopped.
And the momentum's never gotten quiet
enough for them to really analyze it.
Do they kept that guy alive with
somebody else's heart date?
They cut him open and put another dude's
heart inside of him.
That is fucking crazy to think that
human beings can do that.
We could fix,
they can take out your lungs,
man.
They can replace your lungs with someone
else's lungs.
I think that's all helpful to thinking
about it because the more we lose that
attachment to this body as being like
anything but the machine,
the machine that's going to allow us to
experience consciousness in the physical
form.
I think when we really look at that,
then that's going to be a helpful kind
of metaphysical underpinning.
So we're not so caught up in these,
in these elements that are causing us so
much discomfort and suffering.
Right.
We're not trapped.
Yeah.
And this idea of what we are.
Yeah,
but like isn't it inevitable if they,
if they come up with bionic eyes to let
you stare at the sun,
you could watch netflix on them and
they're way better than regular eyes and
they give the people who lose their eyes
first and then people start going to
scoop these fucking Shitty bitches out
and give me some of them.
Good eyes.
And you get them good eyes and he start,
I mean everybody has a good eyes.
You just walk around and look at each
other a wink,
you know,
you know I got the good eyes.
You've got to go.
You could see each other,
can fucking read sports scores flying in
the sky.
It's the hardware upgrade.
Yeah,
upgrade.
Have binocular vision.
You can decide to zoom in on things far
off into the distance.
Why wouldn't you do that?
What do you like seeing at your shitty
old fucking bloodshot eyes?
Yeah,
bitch ass eyes.
The upgrade,
the hardware and then we just gotta make
sure that we're upgrading the software
and eliminating the viruses,
wanting those system checks to get all
of these bad programs out of our head.
Get the better metaphysical truth
programs like,
like the platinum rule,
like you know,
you,
everybody is you living a different
life.
Treat him as such,
you know,
like get some of these other software
programs running.
Discard the old ones.
Then upgrade the hardware all you want
and,
but both have to kind of come in
conjunction.
Otherwise we'll do what we did with
technology.
Elevating faster than consciousness.
Technology elevates fast and the
consciousness and we just fuck each
other up better.
Yeah,
we definitely do that.
I think
also technology is just,
it's just trying to get us more and more
addicted to it.
I was thinking of this the other day and
I was flying back from Hawaii.
I was thinking of how many people I see
stare at a phone at the airport,
at the fucking mall and a restaurant
myself.
I'm staring at my own phone.
Well,
I'm mean,
I'm not immune to it.
We're all staring at fucking phones and
I'm like,
if I was a pilgrim,
if you took took,
you went back in a time machine,
he grabbed a pilgrim and you dragged
them to 2016 and you said,
what are you saying?
They'd be like,
my God,
they're all,
they're all prisoners to the looking
glass.
He'd been captured like do were like,
it's like threaten their spouse.
They're under her spell.
They stare at a fucking glass screen
first thing in the morning.
They check their email to go to work.
They stare at a screen.
They look at their navigation system.
While they're fucking driving to work.
They get home.
They watched TV before they go to bed,
they check their email again.
They're just staring at fucking screens.
They're living their lives through
screens.
I would think to looking glass.
It's captivated though.
I would think they were under the spell
of glass.
Like there was something about something
bond.
They're not moving.
They're just sitting there in front of
this fucking thing all day.
They're almost does almost no movement.
Almost all the time you're in front of a
screen.
You're just sitting there.
Yeah.
If you saw that and you had no idea what
the fuck had television was or a phone,
you were just a person from another time
period and he said,
what do you think's going on?
Like with these fucking people are under
a spell.
They're clearly under a spell.
Like it's giving them something.
Yeah,
but that's what a spell is and mean.
The fucking when the the the,
the hip dodick dancer dances in front of
you and then all of a sudden you don't
even know where you are anymore.
It's cause you're looking at something
cool.
It's a strip club.
Yeah,
exactly.
There you go.
Know where you are.
Yeah.
You ate the edible did Joey Diaz gave
you,
that was mislabeled on purpose.
You,
this is what you're seeing.
You're,
you're seeing something amazing and that
amazing thing is making you want more of
it so you're,
you're spending more money to get a
better computer to make better
explosions on the bigger screen that has
the better sound and it keeps going
deeper and deeper and every fucking new
phone has some new way to get chicks
excited and you're staring at the newest
and best screen and just locked into
this,
this sort of hypnotic trance of
technology.
Oh,
it allowable allows you to Bluetooth
with your navigation.
So stone syncs up to your car and like
you're still staring at a fucking screen
and not doing anything.
It doesn't matter what's happening.
The same effect is taking place.
You're staring at a screen.
I think what's,
what's interesting to me is I think
we're in this intermediary intermediary
stage where we're watching this rapid
advancement and things are getting more
and more interesting,
but I think there's going to be a
tipping point where technology is so
ubiquitous that will actually,
it'll,
it'll kind of settled into our lives in
a better way and maybe some people will
get completely lost,
but I think a lot of us are already
reaching that point where it's almost
too much and it's forcing us to make our
own boundaries,
put our phone down.
You know,
this idea of put your phone away on this
retreat.
There's no phones here.
We're starting to develop the counter
reaction to it,
but it has to get to the point of
ridiculous in order for us to do,
you know,
have this kind of counter reaction.
I think that's the way it's going.
I think that's like using them.
Fred flintstones breaks
Formula One car.
Good luck.
We're going to put our phone away for a
whole hour.
You know,
it's just sitting there and your bag.
Only the only hope that I have for that
philosophy.
How was espousing is I like I learned,
I thought it's something at burning man
and burning and burning man.
There was,
it's so much shit like you have no idea.
You can't even fathom how many lit up
amazingly beautiful fire breathing,
art creations,
dancing
people,
half naked people,
fully naked people or g tents.
This crazy amalgamation.
I mean I was in this like thunder dome.
They rebuilt the thunderdome basically
and they had people on bungee cords and
two topless chicks were smashing into
each other on bungee cords,
beating each other with foam sabres as
like house music played behind and a
fucking fire breathing dragon car like
rode by breathing fire.
Like that is ridiculous.
Sounds awesome.
It's ridiculous.
But what after you've been there for a
while,
like you realize the Times that you
enjoy the most are getting high with
your homeys in the rv.
You know,
like that's the absolute best time you
have a burning man and those like just
laughing and hanging and drinking a beer
in the rv.
Do you think that's enhanced though by
the chaotic environment and the fact you
have this crazy feeling like,
wow,
we're here,
we're here.
For sure.
That's kind of what goes on at a place
like that,
right?
It's like,
wow,
we're here.
Yeah,
yeah.
All of it contributes.
But then just realizing like we can do
that rv moment anywhere.
Like you don't need to be in burning
man.
You don't.
That is the most special shit.
Like the most special shit is the simple
shit.
So you can take all this technology does
all this awesome stuff,
but it's never going to be like that
hike or that time you're hanging and
playing with your kids or that time you
went fishing or that time.
It's never going to beat that.
You know?
And you start to realize that when it
gets to the ridiculous,
it's just when it's on this kind of
intermediary level that it's hard for us
to figure out,
I think.
Yeah.
Well I think the only way to truly
appreciate the natural world,
excuse me,
to truly appreciate the wonders of the
natural world is to,
to be engaged in it.
Separate of the electronic world,
like if you're on some crazy hike but
you're also staring at your phone the
entire time you're walking,
you're just not going to get the whole
feet.
Like if you,
if you're hiking in Yosemite and you
know some of those incredible views and
vistas and you're traveling around these
amazing nature,
just like you're not going to really
take that in.
If you're looking at your phone all the
time or thinking about what picture
you're going to take.
Yeah,
yeah.
You got a bunch of selfies because
you're inherently,
there's nothing about the phone that is
in the present moment unless something
is immediately popping up.
Right.
It's all about the past.
How I look,
you know,
if the future,
how,
what am I going to post?
What's going to come?
So it takes you out of the present
moment.
I think present moment is really the
only pleasurable state that we have on
the planet is when your presence,
those fucking screens,
man and your ego is just preen.
Yeah.
Look up like 5,000
likes,
5,000
likes.
Yeah.
You put filters on shit.
Get that angle perfect.
God get those.
It's so seductive though.
I mean,
even before,
even before there was,
you know,
these phones and selfies,
there was paintings and then there is
just your appearance in general.
So people would get seduced by the,
you know,
their reflection in the mirror and
looking pretty good,
you know,
and then all the way back,
maybe even before there was mirrors,
there was that time in the brook and
that's where you get that,
uh,
the myth of narcissus who just couldn't
stop looking at his reflection in the,
in the waters of the Stream,
you know?
And that was like the original point of
you start looking at yourself,
not ad sells.
Separating yourself from self.
You'll never be in the present moment.
You'll always be looking at yourself,
judging yourself.
And that's a game you can never fucking
win.
You're not gonna win that one bitch.
W W how much do you think it costs back
in the day to get your portrait painted?
Like if you got your portrait painted
back in the Hellenic Saul's,
you are a bad motherfucker,
right?
You had some cash,
man,
you gotta,
you sat there and looked regal with your
best clothes while some dude just
painted you for how long?
How long does it take?
Well,
they would pose for marbled busts back
even before then.
Like you go back to the Roman and Greek
Times.
That's insane.
That's insane how long that takes three
to get carved in marble.
Yeah,
that's insane.
And you can't move.
But the ego is so seductive.
You know,
you want that.
You want to portray that image and it,
the problem is it's just always so
vulnerable.
Like it never feels confident no matter
how wealthy you are,
how good looking you are.
It's always unshaking ground because
it's all nonsense.
You know,
your consciousness.
And that's enough.
Like you don't need to be all of these
things.
But you do though.
If you're that guy,
he'd be that guy that sits there for the
bust.
I mean,
that's one of the things I was thinking
when I was in Rome and I was going
through the Vatican,
uh,
we were looking at all these different
sculptures of like that there's no way
everyone was jacked.
Like everyone was jacked.
Everyone,
everyone.
Everyone had a six pack.
It's so polite how they made everybody
with a small dicks and nobody felt like,
you know why they did that?
So nobody felt like it was just,
no,
no.
It's interestingly enough,
I asked of course,
and uh,
the,
the guy told me that in the Roman age it
was considered a barbaric.
If you had a big penis like you,
you weren't a person of culture or
thought if you had a big penis.
And whether he's correct or not,
I'm not sure Jamie looked that up.
Please.
But that's interesting that like these
little Dick dudes and say,
listen,
this big Dick thing,
it's a fad.
Okay.
Don't get attached to it.
There were all brutes and assholes.
That's why we're in this mess in the
first place.
It's all those big Dick assholes.
You want a solid,
a solid Roman Catholic government.
You needed a little dick dude with a six
pack,
just jacked.
The tits looks like GSP with a leaf over
his death.
The leaves were a lot of leads or put
over the Dick's later.
And a lot of the leaves,
uh,
the,
that like style of the leaf over the
deck posts,
Constantine.
Yeah.
It happened later after some religious
period,
they just decided to stop looking at
Dick's.
They just like,
what?
This has been in front of us the whole
time.
Oh my goodness.
That's,
I mean,
it's,
it's really,
uh,
like that classic example of let's make
something that we're not,
yeah,
let's make that bad.
You know,
that thing is bad.
So we don't have a big Dick.
But I mean,
I think there were also the honest
inclination that guy's got a hog and a
half though the devil.
He's the devil.
Yeah.
The demons always had giant dicks.
You don't want that girl,
that big Dick Demon Monster.
Um,
yeah.
That guy's got a hog.
Put it away,
Jamie.
Kind of looking at it.
It's,
um,
it's,
it's just weird to think that they were
struggling between like,
I guess a big Dick represented virility,
which represented conquest,
which represented war,
which represents a strife,
like all those big Dick dudes just
coming over the mountains.
Fucking big shaggy beards,
swinging swords and shit.
Brennan.
The Gall,
we gotta stop this fighting himself and
yelling and his bear skins on mushrooms
as he's looking at a line of
impenetrable shield.
That guy,
that guy.
Yeah.
You don't want that guy and his giant
Dick that thought we had a hawk or sure.
Just hair braided around like says Les
Pauls.
Yeah.
I mean if a girl tried to suck his dick
literally sucking on one of those cat
posts,
it's just say Harry Dick Harry.
Like,
look what you imagine a Buffalo Dick
would be like,
oh,
he's just random hairs hanging off of
the shaft of his Dick.
Just dreadlock barbarian Dick.
He probably comes up a bright white,
bright white light toothpaste.
Just raw is the moonlight and glow boom.
Shoots out.
Looks like bones,
like liquid bones from out of his dick.
You could,
you can't have that guy around his milk
deck.
You need a little dudes with six packs
that look like they could go gay at any
moment in time.
Cause they did.
Yeah.
Every one of them was just ready to suck
a cock and conveniently the dicks were
small,
so nobody gagged if that's what was
going on too.
There was a lot of Dick Sucking back
then the guys who made,
it's just a friendly little dick.
You know,
they didn't have those barbarian dicks
deal with wonder when they realize you
shouldn't fuck dudes all the time when
when they realized when they were,
when he,
she's like,
because people who essentially weren't
even gay,
we're fucking dude's right.
Not there's anything wrong with being
gay.
Let's just get that out of the way.
I'm not judging in any way
homosexuality,
but I'm saying that it's,
it's uh,
less likely than being straight.
But back then that was on the case.
Yeah.
Whether you were an actual gay person or
not,
that's the question.
Were they gay people?
There are more gay people where they're
more bisexual people or was everybody
greedy?
I think it's,
I think it's a combination.
I think we're naturally a lot more
bisexual then we act on because we're,
everybody's also naturally quite a bit
and that's,
that's part of it.
But I also think they were fucking kids
back then.
And it was like there was like the
momentum of fucking kids.
Like if you're a kid and you get fucked
by a dude,
like I think there's gotta be a
correlation there between,
you know,
having the desire to do the same thing.
It's just like if your dad beats you,
then you want to,
you know,
beat when you're a dad.
It's this the same kind of an ingrained
thing.
And I think they just got this momentum
of kid fucking,
and then that probably contributed along
with there's the open mindedness and not
being homophobic.
Actually they,
they sometimes are homophobic against
the people who would receive the Dick,
but the people who were supplying the
Dick,
it was like prison.
It's kind of like prison basically.
Like the whole society was prison,
you know,
cause if you're,
if you're the pitcher you're not really,
you know,
it's Kinda normal.
Everybody's a picture.
Yeah.
You just show the character of the
loads,
you know?
And,
and that was like one thing,
if you look at some of the graffiti when
Cesar was taking over power,
like some of the group for graffiti was
calling him like the catcher.
Oh like Cesar,
you catch her,
you know,
whatever,
whatever word that was for that,
you know,
cause that was still a slight like you
were supposed to at at the most virile.
If you're head of the Roman legions,
you know,
you want to be the pitcher.
When I was in high school and my friend
Jimmy lawless I'm still friends with
today,
I love that dude.
But Jimmy Wallace was,
what a great name by the way.
It's right up there with Eddie Bravo.
But he,
uh,
w we knew this dude who was bisexual and
we were kind of weirded out because we
were,
you know,
I think I was 17 and Jimmy was 18.
And you're like,
what the fuck?
Like what do you think?
What does that mean?
Like,
uh,
cause he,
you know,
he goes,
I don't know if I believe in bisexuals.
I think they're just greedy.
He started laughing.
He started laughing so hard cause he was
only like half serious but cause I think
they're just greedy.
I'll never forget it.
It's like so burned in my head as a 17
year old that laughed at everything.
You know,
I had a 17 year olds,
ridiculously stupid sense of humor.
And to this day if someone says
bisexual,
I just think of him going,
well is this,
I mean humans have put their Dick and
everything.
Anything,
anything,
whatever.
Who's these couches for?
Cheap flashlights,
people,
men,
women,
whatever.
How we met.
Yeah.
Well I think we should clarify.
Aubrey and I met when he worked for the
flush,
right.
If you didn't know that I'll be working
for a company that,
a fake vagina.
You have sexual gelatinous fake.
It was like man,
if something form with gelatin or
something,
food,
chores.
Gelatin can't divulge family secrets.
But uh,
um,
it's a,
that's how we met Pete.
People love to just get rid of com and
makes you feel better.
And I think we got to just remove all of
the fucking stigma about it.
Like,
I know it's just,
it's the come release mechanism for the
pleasure monkey and that was actually
like that.
That word was something that came to me
actually my Wasco trip.
But that's what we fucking are.
Where pleasure monkeys.
Like we're here to soak in as much
pleasure,
laughter,
feel all the things that you can fucking
feel to your
body.
Hit all of the pleasure buttons.
Like why would you have a pleasure
button and not push it?
It doesn't make any sense.
Like push all of your pleasure buttons.
Let's feel what that feels like.
Let's go through and finish this
existence in the material form saying
like,
man,
there was like,
you don't want to have that button.
You're like,
man,
I heard that button was awesome,
but I just never pushed it because I was
afraid and it was a religion said this
thing and blah blah blah,
like fucking pushed the pleasure
buttons.
Like let's look shit.
Yeah,
you know,
recognize that that's what we're here
for.
And stop.
Stop stressing so much about it.
Like the idea that you should be guilty
for your pleasure.
Like you don't deserve it.
Like you do.
We still have the echoes of the puritans
that landed here and sort of tried to
reestablish
mean w w what's really similar to a lot
of other crazy religious ideologies,
views on sex,
like really rigid restrictive sex
practices,
you know,
and that stuff's stuck.
It's hard to shake that shit off.
It's hard to be grown adults like you
are with your friends,
you know,
like you are with your friends,
you talk about sex,
you know,
it's just sex.
It's,
it's what people do.
It feels,
you don't say,
oh,
she wants sex,
that dirty,
dirty demon possessed woman going to go,
yeah,
look at her.
She's hot,
but she wants to Dick all day.
Hot Girls.
Like that's probably like what's going
on when you look at Jennifer Lopez,
his ass,
like that's,
that's the ass of a woman that probably
enjoys a dick.
Right.
You'd hope so dude up.
So it seems like there's some system
there,
right?
It attracts them.
She probably likes them.
It's like a flower and the,
the bees land on it and the flower wants
to be.
Exactly.
It's mutually the more fragrant the
flower,
the more it just desiring mutually
beneficial relationship.
But somewhere along the line people
decided to restrict it and they've
really clamped down.
I and I think it was during the hard
times and I think it's just so much,
there's so much to the restriction on
sex that I think also has to do with our
worrying about people not being able to
handle hard times if they come again,
like there's a lot of people I think in
this world with the preppers,
whether people that are just concerned
about the future of the world,
they're really worried that people are
losing could.
And ironically it's funny because the
people that would be more restrictive
when it comes to sex and usually the
right wingers,
but the right wingers are least
concerned about environmental damage.
They're more concerned about fiscal
profits like currently and then the left
wing would be much more concerned with
environmental but much less restrictive
when it comes to sexuality.
Like the,
the idea that you could just run around
having sex with whoever you want and
just experiencing pleasure and not
committing to people.
And having a good time and smoking a
little pot and drinking and dancing and
just enjoying life.
That's not good for commerce,
right?
That's not good for business.
That's not good.
And so if you want people to embrace the
same sort of level of materialism that
you're going to need to make your bottom
line go up every year,
you've got to stop these fucking hippies
and their goddamn fucking dance out in
the desert.
Sure.
So he
burning down the bullshit out there,
cutting back on our profits.
You got to look at that motivation.
And you've also got to look at the
motivation of,
of just control.
You know,
like you take something that someone is
going to think about all the fucking
time,
all the time,
and then make him guilty for that and
make it as sin and make you the one who
can absolve them of that sin.
You got him fucking locked like every
single human on planet earth is going to
sin and they're going to need you to
rescue them from hell.
Fire.
Boom.
It's like the ultimate fucking rear
naked choke on the human psyche,
right?
Because no one's going to be able to
stop themselves from having sexual urges
and thoughts.
And if your thoughts are a sin and
you're the only one who can take it away
from its fucking the world's greatest
con,
the world's greatest con might be making
prostitution illegal,
right?
Like how do they figure out a way you
can fuck anybody you want for free?
Like there's,
it's not like it's illegal to fuck.
It's not like murder,
you know,
like you just can't go around killing
people.
I don't care how much you pay,
you can't go kill people.
That's not what we do.
Okay,
we're civilized.
But you could just go get some coke,
go to a bar,
started doing shots of people.
Next thing you know,
you're banging people.
You put beverly,
even know them,
right?
If you're some fucking wild person,
you could just,
if you're a girl,
especially God damn,
you could travel from place to place to
place and give it away and just get dick
every anywhere you want.
Right?
Well that is okay.
But if you go there and you actually
exchange pieces of paper or coins,
that's not good,
or bitcoins,
what the fuck?
Like how is that possible?
Pick coin prostitute.
That's high level.
I'm more interested at high level.
If I can pay for very high level and pay
for my sex act with a bitcoin really
smart girl too,
they show up.
They just see things differently.
I just think this is saying that you
could pay people for massages,
you could pay people to do your nails,
you can get pedicures and manicures and
you could have people do all sorts of
stuff.
Do you wax you and just don't massage
your Dick?
It's,
it's crazy and I,
you know,
honestly I think it's,
it's this special distinction that that
religion has given him the other,
some consequences of sex.
There's potential pregnancy,
but we've mostly eradicated that.
If you're really trying,
at least if you're trying,
you can eradicate that,
that issue in there.
Some,
there's some diseases,
so there's some consequences.
I get it.
I get,
it's a little different than a massage
where you're less likely to get,
you know anything of where it's a
condom.
You filthy animal,
it's almost zero disease problems,
but the amount of,
the amount of difference that people
give that to like,
like you imagine your girl getting
massage from a dude.
You're like,
okay,
but then he massages her vagina.
Oh man,
the stomach,
the stomach feel funny and you want to
Puke and you want to fight them and you
want to stab him in the throat for
touching your girl and you just think
how wet she probably was.
She couldn't believe how naughty this
was.
She's probably leaking down the side of
her legs.
Oh my gosh.
By came immediately.
As soon as he,
his thumb just gently rubbed up against
her assholes.
Jill toes spread out under feet,
cramped up,
Jesus and everybody felt so naughty,
naughty,
terrible person,
terrible rule breaker violator later of
the trust.
It's so crazy,
man.
We just got it all.
We just got it all,
look at each other and be like,
we're all just fucking pleasure monkeys.
It's cool where you get your pleasure.
I'm not your pleasure dealer.
You know,
let's love each other and just
be cool.
Yeah,
it's going to take a little while.
They can't close to that in the 60s for
awhile.
You know what I mean?
You think about the difference between
the fifties in the 60s I think about
like the people in the 50s were all like
locked down watching Hawaii five o and
shit.
Well actually that was probably the 60s
dragnet.
That's what I was trying to think of.
Did you ever see the dragnet thing drag
net Guy Joe Friday?
It was talking to some fucking Hippie,
some God damn hippie and he's explaining
to the Hippie uh,
how easy they have it and how,
how lucky they should they feel living
in America today.
What all the people that have sacrificed
so much to allow them to dress like
silly people.
And it's so hilarious cause it sounds
like a person to this.
Is it like listen to this is fat and I'm
selfish and you the first generation to
come along with felt dissatisfied.
They all have,
you know about different things.
And most of them didn't have the same
opportunity in the freedoms that you do.
Let's talk poverty.
Most places in the world,
that's not a problem.
It's a way of life and rights.
They're to give you a blank stare
because they may not know what you're
talking about.
The fact is more people are living
better right here than anywhere else
ever before in history is I don't expect
us to roll over and play dead.
When you say you're dissatisfied,
it's not perfect,
but it's a great deal better than when
we grew up a hundred men standing on the
stoop,
Peckham,
Joe Friday's in a purple fucking
strictly and tars talking down to look
like they're the dudes in the back of
the Jimi Hendrix pan that nobody can
tell you their name.
I mean there's like Jimi Hendrix and the
dudes he was with and I'm sure if you're
fucking heavy duty music had,
you're mad at me right now.
I understand,
but no,
this giant Jimi Hendrix Fan,
obviously giant.
I don't know who the fuck he toured
with.
I don't know who those dudes were.
I have no idea.
People when they see other people having
fun and they don't feel like they can
get there,
they want to shit on it.
Yeah.
That's like,
that's like these got looking at having
all this sex get an eye,
they look happy as shit.
Like that's going to,
cause it's that resistance towards
towards joining it that if the actually
just relaxed and,
and did it,
they'd probably feel good but they can't
somehow they feel like they can or they
shouldn't and they won't.
So the reaction is to remove that thing
to squash that thing to make it more
like them so that it feels so they don't
have that,
you know,
those eyes that are looking over there
saying,
oh,
maybe that life's better and what's
wrong with me?
How come I can't do that?
You know,
so people shit on it.
I think the lines are being blurred
though between like uh,
really like hardcore no nonsense people
like a Joe Friday type character and the
hippies,
those lines are getting like,
there's a lot of people that like go in
weird slots.
Like how'd that guy get in that?
Oh,
he's in a weird spot.
Like he's kind of both of those things.
There's a lot of those people now that
you can't really lock them down.
He can't say this is a right wing person
or a left wing person is a no nonsense
discipline.
Get to work person.
And this is a pothead and this is a guy
likes to do mushrooms and this is a guy
who gets up in the morning and runs.
They might be the same dude now.
Like there's a lot of like crossover
between people who are like very
disciplined hard workers but also
experience pleasure and also understand
that this is,
we are a temporary life form hurling
through infinity.
Wake the fuck up and just have fun and
enjoy this because this is madness.
And it could very well be over at the
blink of an eye,
a fucking giant rock.
The size of Pittsburgh can come flying
out of the north and no one catches it
until it's too late and it slams into
the fucking polar ice cap.
And we're diggity diggity done.
We're done.
That's it.
It's a wrap.
There's like 50 of us left.
We eat each other,
you know,
we turned into mice.
The only thing,
the only thing that we're,
that's keeping us from engaging in all
of these other forms that we went to is
this clinging to identity and these and
these fear programs.
We like,
we ditch all that then then you just get
wide open for everything else.
And it's not a new idea like the idea of
the warrior poet,
the idea back then if someone who could
go to battle and like Musashi who could
be the best swordsman and also be the
best calligrapher and also a writer and
also meditate and also,
you know,
have affairs and also do whatever like
passionate love affair,
all of the things like at a certain
point people realize like,
oh yeah,
all the things is best.
And then at a certain point now in our
culture,
or at least getting to here,
it was like you have to identify with
this one thing and that's your thing.
And then you defend that thing and,
and Nah,
man,
chuck and enjoy all of it.
Well,
what I realized from Musashi when I was,
um,
I think I was in my teens when I read
the book of five rings the first time,
what I realized is that he was
explaining this concept that was totally
alien to me at the time as like an
insecure teenager.
He was explaining this concept of to be
balanced at anything,
to be like at your best,
at anything,
you have to have no loose ends.
You have to be loving,
you have to be kind,
you have to be an artist,
you have to be creative.
But you also have to be ruthless with
your sword technique.
And you have to be ruthless with your
psychology and how you engage with your
enemy and you,
I mean,
he was a fascinating,
fascinating guy.
He got bored fighting people with
swords.
So he stopped,
he started using oars from boats.
You start fucking people up with oars.
He's like,
I'm just tired of fucking these bitches
up with swords.
He killed 62 people and one on one
combat with weapons.
Wow.
And along the way he developed this
really
intense,
very rigid sort of guideline for
maintaining the ultimate warrior spirit.
And that was a balanced perspective.
It was really weird because I remember
reading about that at the time and I
thought he just had to be a killer man.
I thought you had to be,
you know,
you had to be like Roberto Duran when he
was young.
You had to be just a savage.
Like that was the only way to be a good
fighter.
He had to be a savage.
It'd be just someone who just came in,
just guns blazing,
didn't give a fuck.
Like Mike Tyson,
the early days,
there was the only way to be successful.
That's what I thought.
And what he was saying is,
no,
you have to be a master of yourself.
Yup.
The master of all aspects of yourself.
And there's no,
there's no more terrifying form of
combat than one on one with a fucking
sword.
I mean,
he was the master.
He was the guy that figured it out in a
very strange time in Japanese history
where he was a Ronin just traveling
around fucking killing people.
Yeah.
I think,
I think some of these times when you
look back some of the philosophies that
developed her or even more advanced than
ours,
because when you have a strong external
pressure,
like the,
like the likelihood of a sword battle to
the death.
Yeah.
That forms this point of resistance
where you got to cut out a lot of the
bullshit,
all the bullshit.
Like you really have to look at the
world in a different way.
And even when there was the threat of,
of fighting somebody at any point,
you know,
that changes how you are as a man,
like that chain.
That's an external point of resistance
that causes you to understand certain
things about,
about the nature of life and the nature
of your manhood.
Whereas now we have so little external
pressure like most of us can go through
life and never get in a fight.
You know,
that's not something that it's in a lot
of people's lives still in some people's
lives.
For sure,
but like you're removed from these
different things and,
and sports offer that and kind of a very
controlled way,
but you take away all of these external
pressures and then you get read.
It gets really squirly because you have
nothing to define yourself against.
You don't have any resistance.
You're like lifting weights on the moon
and no matter what you try to do,
you can't get a fucking squat right,
because there's no gravity.
You know what I mean?
Like,
and so you have to,
you have to go out and I think actively
put yourself in situations that are
going to challenge you,
going to test you.
And it doesn't all have to be physical.
That's just one way in.
Find yourself in challenging mental
situations.
Find yourself in challenging emotional
situations,
emotionally challenging physical
situation,
pulling crazy relationships.
Do they started fights,
right?
They put,
they build up challenging emotional
situations who they can escape them.
They make their own obstacle course to
get through life.
No,
you're totally right,
man.
I think we're good.
We're just experiencing an UN,
like the safest time ever.
You know?
And we're sort of trying to find demons
don't exist instead of
on the ones that do.
Yeah.
And that's to me,
I think I mentioned it a couple times,
but do you know if you're interested in
wanting to tell that story,
but about the time I did,
I wasco because these plant medicines
are that form of resistance.
It is a bit of a trial by fire.
You know,
it's going to,
you're going to confront yourself with,
you know,
some of the darkest,
deepest fears and concerns that you
have.
And,
and that's,
and that's the process by which it makes
you better.
It's not,
you know,
a magic potion.
It's just like,
here's resistance.
How are you going to respond?
And when you respond through that and
you get,
you just get better from it and you
know,
you feel better.
I wonder with,
with California,
with this latest recreational marijuana
marijuana law passed,
I wonder how long it'll be before
someone tries to do some sort of a
psychedelic clinic,
whether it's for a addiction to opiates,
like a and a Boogie Boga I began a
clinic or um,
if this kratom stuff,
you know,
this,
there's shit,
what do you think about this?
Cause I think I did a podcast with Chris
Bell the other day.
He was trying to explain it to me and to
me Kratom in mild doses it Kratom or is
it creative?
I don't know.
Kratom Kratom I'm not,
I'm not really sure.
I don't even,
I'm in mild doses.
It seems to be like,
uh,
like a bit of an energy.
Yeah.
Energy buzz.
And then in,
in heavier doses it seems to be more
like a painkiller.
Like it's almost like a slightly
euphoric but numbed sensations.
It's a really interesting plant.
You know,
clearly I don't think there's any reason
for it to be illegal.
I haven't found personally a ton of
value from it.
And I find value in some other things.
But the only thing I found disturbing,
I said I was getting a bunch of text
messages from people or tweets rather
from people that were telling me that
they had some addictive experiences with
it,
that it was very addicted to them,
addictive to them.
So I don't know if that's true or not.
Um,
I also don't know where you're getting
it and what's in it.
Yeah.
You know,
I don't,
I don't exactly know how pure that stuff
is.
I mean,
this stuff is this,
this is like a retail version of it.
The Guy who sells it came with Chris.
I trust that.
But if you're buying it from a dealer,
which is like essentially what a lot of
people had to do for a long time.
Like what?
I'm not exactly sure what you're
getting,
you know,
it's coming from Indonesia or wherever
it's from.
I would like to see some real tests done
because,
uh,
to me,
I tried it.
I was like,
this is like a mild stimulant.
I kept,
it kind of feels okay.
Like it doesn't feel bad.
Yeah.
You know,
it's interesting once you opened the
doors to that scientific method with
these plants,
you find the amazing results.
And I think that's what we're seeing in
this,
in this revolution of understanding of
psychedelics.
Like I just read an and tweeted about a
study on,
uh,
both silicide been an MDA for like
social anxiety and social anxiety,
you know,
which are one of the things that you
think of the classic school shooters
syndrome,
you know,
it's this feeling of being excluded from
your tribe,
excluded from the social situation and
the anxious and anxiety and all of the
medications that are prescribed for
these different feelings of feeling like
you're not part of the group.
Well,
they wanted to test that with both mgma
and with silicide siliciden and they
found that it was effective with both,
but differently.
So they created this game called Cyber
Ball,
right.
Where they had what seemed like just
random other test subjects all in a
circle
with a ball.
And,
but really it was researchers and then
one test subject.
And so to create social anxiety,
they would play this game of catch and
just not pass the ball hardly ever to
the test subject.
So We'd feel eventually like,
man,
what the fuck?
Why aren't these people passing me the
ball?
Like what's wrong with me?
And so they tapped into some and they
would test that at baseline is placebo,
right?
The,
the,
at least in the kind of concern of like,
man,
what's wrong with me?
Why do these people not want to give you
the ball?
And then they tested the baseline for
Placebo,
gave him the whatever placebo they were
using,
and then they tested it with psilocybin.
And what they found with silicide been
was that it dramatically reduced their
amount of anxiety,
their angst or stress about not giving
the ball there.
They were just looking at him like,
man,
look at these people.
They just don't want to pass me the
ball.
That's cool.
You know,
and so and so,
but they could accurately tell.
Now Mdm may also reduce social anxiety,
but in a different way.
The People Mtma thought they were
getting the ball all the time.
They thought like they had no idea that
they weren't on the ball.
They're like,
Oh man,
I got passed through all the time.
It was amazing.
He loves money,
Dude.
They
just will love and other people catching
the ball.
Yeah.
So,
so happy for you man.
You caught it.
Oh,
you through it.
He got an a I'm happy for you too dude.
Yeah.
That an interesting Mtma can be
extremely beneficial to anybody.
At least one trip.
I just found the only trip that I did,
I was,
I was like,
this is really,
you can learn something from this.
Well it's also,
you know,
like a Mescalin which comes in both what
tumor,
the San Pedro Cactus and pay ot is also
a Sarah to nudge it kind of psychedelic.
So if you haven't had a lot more to MDM,
very similar.
Yeah.
I mean,
MDM may is,
you know,
like a more pharmaceutical approach to
elevating serotonin in that feeling that
this associated with selling Serotonin
in your body,
whereas the masculine drive,
psychedelics do that in a similar way,
but with the little bit more of a
visionary component.
So,
um,
but both have,
you know,
once one is just a more direct
application and I think that's great for
a situation like maps is testing with
ptsd and certain other kinds of
situations because it's very
reproducible.
It's very like clinical reaction of
what's going to happen in the brain.
Whereas something with like what Chuma
gives you this overwhelming experience,
but it's woven in with all kinds of
other different things.
The problem really holy resides in the
fact that these drugs are illegal
because if they,
if they weren't illegal we would look at
them.
It was like,
wow,
this might be solutions for people
suffering from Ptsd,
from this,
from that social anxiety,
social anxiety.
And also kind of gives you your brain a
chance to almost detached like a lens
that detaches from the camera,
get a look at the inner workings of the
thing.
And then before you put it back on,
you kind of get a better understanding
of it.
And so I guess there's a detachment that
MDA has like from some of the nonsense
you've carried around with you,
like clothes that you know,
you've just worn it your whole life.
You don't realize bullshit until you
take something that makes you feel like
this is all so ridiculous.
Like,
yeah,
what,
what I think,
you know,
talking to the psychologist and the
psychiatrist of why it's so beneficial
is we all carry a lot of trauma.
We all carry these things from our past
that are the stories.
And I think that was another thing I
keep talking about the Jordan Peterson
podcast,
but he talked about that self authoring
program,
which is rewriting these stories.
Well,
he was talking about actually writing
it,
but what MDM is doing for people with
Ptsd and with anybody is it's going back
and looking at all of these traumatic
things in our history and our past and
which is also one of the things that in
the studies that they're showing,
they have a psychologist,
psychiatrist who's guiding people back
to these potential traumatic events.
But when you're flooded with Serotonin,
you see things in a totally different
perspective.
You see things from the vantage vantage
point of love and it's all good.
So no matter what situation came about,
you'll see that kind of higher
perspective rather than that fear
response,
that kind of cringing,
that creates more fear and more trauma.
You look at it and you're able to relax,
see it and say,
man,
that was pretty horrible,
but you know what?
It's okay.
Like I'm still okay.
I still have these bright things.
And you repattern the,
uh,
you repattern that traumatic experience.
So when you go to draw that back up from
your past,
you're drawing up a different
recategorize experience.
Like you're rewriting the software
that's,
you know,
always rewriteable like those
rewriteable floppy disks.
You know,
you take that thing out,
you rewrite it with a whole different
hue of your neurochemicals in the
feelings that you surrounding it.
And then when you access it again,
or when it's just carrying around in
your,
in your memory,
then it doesn't have the same sting.
It doesn't have the same trauma.
And that's one of the mechanisms of
action of of MDA and also what they're
looking at with Iowasca Iowasca going
back,
not flooding you necessarily with
Serotonin,
but showing you that if these events in
a slightly different perspective showing
you well,
hey that's actually what made you so
ambitious and so strong and this
traumatic thing that you thought was so
horrible,
it actually brought out all of these
other benefits and it was actually,
you know,
if you really see from the person who
the perpetrators perspective,
you know,
look at all the sadness that created
that look at where he was coming from so
you repattern that traumatic event and
then it's not carrying that sign,
the same dramatic,
terrible weight,
that lifeless body that you're trying to
carry around.
It's just been rewritten.
There's also the perspective that who
you are like as a person right now is an
accumulative effect of all your
experiences.
That's what makes you who you are.
Well,
if you have some mind blowing
experience,
which is what the psychedelic
experiences you are going to change,
like you're going to be a different
person.
I mean,
it might be a,
a microscopic shifted the dial.
Like if you had a safe and you are
clicking click,
click,
click.
It might be like one click click like
after a psychedelic experience and then
you might have another psychedelic
explains.
You might get a double click,
click,
you know,
but it's very small movements,
right?
But ultimately you're a different
person.
So if even if it's a small movement,
that new experience has given you a
chance to sort of mock the things that
were threatening you just momentarily,
just as just a few moments ago,
just four hours ago before he took the
mushrooms,
he like,
God,
why was I worried about that?
That's nothing like it gives you that
opportunity because you're literally a
different person now.
You've had this experience.
The fucking problem is they're illegal.
If they weren't illegal,
you'd be able to eat because it has the
big fear,
right?
How do I know what I'm taking?
Of course,
how do you know what you're taking?
You don't fucking know.
You don't know because big Daddy Pharma
has paid off the fucking big daddy
government to keep it out of your greasy
little hands so you can't trip balls and
live in the woods like a fucking Pixie.
The beautiful thing is though,
it's common cause I think the open,
as soon as they opened the doors to
clinical research,
it's an undeniable force.
Like you cannot deny the evidence that's
coming back from the maps.
You know phase two clinical trials.
You cannot deny the evidence coming out
of Johns Hopkins and these are the
research institutes about psilocybin.
They are helping people with conditions
and you just,
you know,
follow the scientific method all the way
through and all the plants are going to
arrive.
Like we're going to get them all home.
We've got to get trump on drugs for
sure.
We've
got to get the new president to do DMT.
If we got him to do DMT,
it would change so much or just just a
little dose of mushrooms,
Bro.
You don't even have to get crazy.
Take a gram and a half,
just a gram and a half or a little
reset.
Just a little reset,
just a little little sit back and a
little,
wow,
what?
What are we doing here?
Exactly?
I just think this is a unique and
special time and as long as we can be
aware and as long as we,
we,
we verbalize that.
We say it all the time.
This is a unique and special time.
Let's capitalize on this unique and
special time.
Let's use this unique and special time
to establish a new understanding for
this generation and to set things up way
better for the next generation.
Dude,
my parents,
I'm older than you.
My parents were essentially raised by
barbarians.
They came over on a fucking boat.
They had no idea what was over here.
You know their,
their parents did it really like my
grandparents parents did it.
That came over from Italy and from
Ireland.
They were savages,
man.
They were hardly different from the
people that came over on the boats
during the pilgrim days.
There were barbarians.
They just had a little bit more culture,
a little bit more language,
a little bit more.
This.
They beat the shit out of their wives.
They were always drunk.
There are monsters.
A lot of them,
they're just crazy people scratching and
clawing.
Their understanding of life during the
Ed Sullivan show,
their understanding of what the world
was really all about.
It's so far removed from the average 20
year old with a an internet account who
can go on youtube.
As long as he stays away from those flat
earth videos,
he's going to have a real good
understanding of how this mother fucker
works and a way better understanding
than any grown adult with children did
in the 1950s when my parents were kids.
There's no fucking way.
There's no,
you can't compete.
So I think that we have this unique
opportunity to set up the future
society where all of this silliness that
we still have to deal with.
Like the wiki leaks email that came out
about Hillary Clinton has said that she
opposes marijuana quote in every sense
of the word.
You can't do that anymore.
Like that to me,
that people were still willing to
support that.
Like this,
oh this is better than him.
He grabs pussies.
Is it,
are you sure it's better?
Cause I don't know if it's better.
I think the whole thing's a mess.
You can't have people stopping pinebrook
Oh,
it's all both the part with you,
it's all about freedom and anybody that
wants to stop pot,
they can stop sex,
they can stop whatever the fuck you want
to do that they decide they can profit
off of.
You not doing that and you think they
can't stop sex.
Look what religion did to sex.
Sure.
Right.
Look how many people were burned for
their sexual practices at the stake.
Literally like you can ban absolutely
everything.
There's laws on the books that are
throwing people in jail for
homosexuality that will flare up still
now like a k in different places of the
world where they'll kill people for sex.
So it's not that that hasn't even been
tried,
like the,
the ability of the monstrous nature of
humans to be able to impose those
restrictions on people of the
sovereignty of their own consciousness.
And their own body.
You can only ejaculate this way.
You can only expand your consciousness
in these manners.
Like women can't drive.
They have to dress like genies have to
cover themselves.
Genie.
That's so wild.
But yeah,
it's like we got to discard all that
shit and it's idea that you know,
these,
these pastors have more knowledge than
someone who just spent,
you know,
a few days out in the woods doing
mushrooms.
Like,
are you sure you know the other ones
photo from heaven,
he's got a lock.
Yeah,
he's,
he's at all,
there was a story that was out just a
couple of days ago about some woman in
Indonesia that received a hundred lashes
for like being around a man,
being too close to a man.
There's a bunch of people that were
publicly flogged for sex crimes,
but there were sex crimes as similar,
like as,
as,
as innocuous as a woman was too close to
a man.
Like they gave her like 90 lashes or
some crazy shit.
All the little boners on find the
fucking robes west from the people who
are lashing.
The way I hear it as a student gets a
hundred lashes for sex outside marriage
and Indonesia.
So he got a hundred lashes and there was
another one about a woman that dude
looks just like the male dudes in that
fucking sex bdsm dungeon porn from San
Francisco where they took that old
prison out and they all fucking dress
like that and locking people up.
It's the same dude.
He just gets to do it in public.
Oh,
it's even extra kinky.
I got to whip people in fucking public.
She was flogged with a rat and candy.
Say Rattan.
How'd he say it?
Written cane.
Yeah.
At least seven times for being too close
in close proximity to a man.
So they beat her with a cane seven times
for being in close proximity to a man.
That 32 year old male who was with her
was also flogged seven times.
Hmm.
That's interesting.
Let's take a look at that sentence is
structured.
The 34 old one was flogged with a Kane
at least seven
times being in close proximity to a man.
That's the Har.
The 32 year old male who was with her
was also flagged seven times like
that's,
it's not the man and the woman were both
flag flog seven times each.
It's like the woman horror upon horrors.
This beautiful young woman was flogged
because she had sex with a man or
because she was close to a man.
That dude was flogged too,
but fuck him.
You know,
and the woman,
it hurts so bad.
The woman said,
she cited AFP raising her arms in the
air.
What about the dude?
The dude didn't even ask him that.
Even ask the dude.
Fuck him.
He said,
dude,
that fucking CIS gendered asshole with
his male privilege is white mates
probably white in Indonesia.
They probably would have given them a
hundred if he was black.
Yeah,
man,
it's,
I went to the dungeon of the inquisition
in Italy and that's,
that changed my whole perspective on
everything.
Put that back up.
Let's do this one,
but we'll go back to where you were.
Here we go.
Look at this.
No,
no,
no.
Oh,
Jamie doesn't know how to do the
Internet.
Okay.
The a man found guilty of sex outside
the marriage was also flogged at least
22 times by the person delivering the
punishment who is dressed in long robes
and a hood.
His partner who was two months pregnant
is still waiting for her fate to be
decided,
wow,
she's pregnant and they're going to
decide her fate.
Whoa.
In such situations,
officials in the province usually order
the flogging of the woman after they
give birth.
Holy Shit.
That's Indonesia 2016 that is holy Shit.
That's scary.
That is just what happens when people
decide what the rules are.
You can't let people decide the rules
and
and Lou and have false metaphysical
underpinnings,
have that underpinning that.
That's someone who deserves that kind of
punishment,
you know,
have that,
you lose the idea.
There's fundamental things.
That's me living a different life.
What I want to do that to me like do you
understand the actual truth of the urges
that that person had and the truth of
everything?
You start turning everything on its head
and then you get these crazy rules and
abilities like,
and it's not just Indonesia,
like I went to the dungeon of the
inquisition in Italy and it was so much
fucking darker than a cane.
She may feel it when you're in the room
for sure.
It was,
it was nauseatingly especially when you
start seeing that 60% of these fucking
things have to do with your genitals,
like burning rods.
They're shoving and Dick Holes and
assholes and,
but it's all for Jesus the way.
Yeah,
exactly.
For Jesus,
like the absolute antithesis of the
Jesus message when you really look at
it.
Mystically but like if like from the,
from the what,
the metaphysical truths of what he's
espousing and then somehow they go from
that to that.
And I think it's,
again,
it's like that incremental creep,
you know,
towards a little bit harsher
punishments,
a little bit more sadistic,
you know,
and you get more and more and more and
you get that,
you start feeding that urge for sadism,
that urge to,
to not only,
you know,
punish somebody but to do it in the most
horrifying way.
And you know,
that's part of human nature.
We know about the Stanford prison
experiments,
right?
Yeah,
exactly.
Yeah.
If you haven't heard about that folks
look it up.
Um,
it's really interesting story.
They,
um,
they had these students and these
college students at Stanford,
they put them through this experiment
where some of them were guards and some
of them were prisoners and the guards
almost immediately started abusing the
prisoners.
They fucking cancel it.
They had to cancel.
They just stop it short.
Yeah.
It's a,
and I think,
you know,
the problem is,
is that we all try to,
we all try to bury these,
these thoughts,
these darker thoughts that we have.
You know,
like all of us inside of us,
you know,
you look at times of war and you know,
whole armies that would go,
part of why they would go on these
contracts was for rape.
You know,
like we all think of ourselves like as
as men now,
like man,
I would never be capable of of doing
anything hurting anybody else.
But inside our genetics,
inside the things that was passed along
our lineage where warrior cultures that
probably produced are fucking ancestors
through rape,
like that's part of every individual,
these dark thoughts.
This,
it feels somehow good to hurt somebody
else.
And the fact that we deny those
entirely,
they become monsters,
you know,
is where if you just acknowledge and
like look at them and say,
man,
I'm all the bad stuff,
I'm all the good stuff,
it's all good.
What am I going to choose to do?
You know,
what do I want to put out in the world?
And I think that's a really important,
important facet to recognize that,
you know,
we're all,
we're all fucked up,
you know,
but it's our choice to decides,
who we really are and what we want to
bring into the world.
Are we going to make this amazing video
game a better place,
a better game?
Are we going to make it miserable for
everybody?
We encountered,
I've always wondered about,
um,
mob rules.
Like I've always wanted about the mob
mentality.
Like what is that?
Where's that coming from?
Is that coming?
Is that like an acceptance of war?
Like is that,
I wonder if that's some sort of a
survival mechanism when you able to do
horrific shit,
as long as everybody around you is doing
it's all a sudden the,
the,
the collective mindset shifts and new
rules apply.
Like if people are coming over the fence
and y'all have axes and you're coming
out of them,
you're doing things you would never do
on a daily basis.
You're hacking off arms and attacking
people.
And once it's real,
it's real.
Right?
Once the first guy gets an Arrow through
the fucking head and you see the shit
going down,
like you're swinging and it's all going
crazy and everyone around you is doing
the same thing and no one,
no one could go,
guys,
seriously,
no,
what are we doing?
Let's let's stop here and let's realize
we could all get along.
There's plenty of vegetables for
everybody.
Let's stop the rape and get to know
these girls.
They'd cut your fucking head off and let
your house on fire and stab your mom.
They would go crazy.
I mean that's what they did.
Yeah,
blood lust.
This is something,
a thing,
because there's a,
something that happens.
There's a thing that happens to people
when you have that mob mentality,
you could probably look at like Steve,
someone like Steven Kotler can probably
you more about the,
you know,
the adrenaline in neurochemical response
that's creating this version of yourself
that sucks,
supercharged and these certain things.
So your empathy,
you know,
your empathy ratings go way down.
It's like you're looking at the
westworld control board,
right?
And it's like empathy ratings,
way down,
aggression way up like all of these
different neurochemicals that are
changing,
like literally changing yourself into
something that is much more favorable
for those actions.
Right.
You know,
it creates a collective mindset.
The individual,
because it's one of the things you hear
all the time about war is the,
the really noble,
heroic warriors who sacrifice themselves
to save others.
It's one of the main themes that we love
hearing about like the guy who dives on
the grenade to save his people,
to save the guys who are around him.
Like that is something that happens in
that crazy,
that crazy environment of that intensity
of life.
It's one of the weirdest things about a
man is how many people who go through
that say it was the best time of their
life and they'd love to go back.
Yeah.
Well,
presence,
man.
I really think that anytime your
presence,
every time you're present,
you're some of the best time in your
life.
Not like Christmas present.
Yeah.
No.
Like when you're just present,
like when you're,
you're in flow state when you're in war
because part of it is that intense
threat,
you know,
like you don't have time to think about
your email that incessant,
you know,
voice from your phone to check.
Instagram is not in your fucking head.
You're more,
you know,
and that's,
it lends,
some girl's been like dm and and Dan,
let's go on down,
we'll meeting up tonight for sure.
And I think probably at a certain level
of like Tim Kennedy,
he might have those thoughts like it's
just so called for him.
Doesn't fuck well the Musashi thing.
Yeah,
exactly.
That's probably why you actually started
having to fight with oars because at a
certain point with a sword,
he probably wasn't even getting the same
feeling anymore.
Right.
Probably didn't even feel like a sword
battle.
It was like a,
like a sparring match when you know
you're going 20% and you're all relaxed
and shit rather than when you're just
knowing like,
all right,
these people are coming for me.
It's a different kind of mental state
that you get in.
And maybe,
you know,
the or thing was like,
all right,
I'm just not feeling it.
I'm too good.
Well,
he actually realized to that or had a
much longer reach.
So who's cracking dudes in the head from
the outside?
So there was actually a good strategic
element to the or,
and I said,
I'm pretty sure he whittled the or down
like a,
and he would show up super late and then
he said to James,
just be so tired.
They'd be just freak.
Oh my God,
am I gonna die tonight?
They'd be thinking of that for hours and
then finally shows up.
Yeah.
But back then mean,
what do they had fucking Sun dials on
the wrists.
How'd you even know what time it was?
You could definitely get away with a lot
more.
There's a lot of wiggle room for fucking
dawn.
What's done to you bro?
Midday to midday is a real fucking day.
We're supposed to meet Jesus high noon.
Come on.
What does that even mean?
Yeah.
Unless you're around a Sundial.
And even that seems like it'd be hard to
get that right.
Nobody had that on rest.
I was only the flintstones.
Flintstones fucking Sundial.
That's hilarious.
I wonder who the front,
the first dude with a watch that he
carried around.
What a pimp doc.
I must've been clap mother fucker.
He opens it up like a coffin flavor.
Flave size hanging from his neck.
Like when,
let's,
let's just guess when was the first
pocket watch created?
I'm going to say 16 hundreds is that,
is that ambitious?
I say 1712 woo.
Jamie civic.
Very specific.
It's like price is right,
right.
The very first pocket watch.
If you have a pocket watch tape,
by the way,
you're an asshole.
If it's hanging from your vest and a
string and you drinking handmade beer,
you piece of shit.
Stop using mustache wax.
Stop,
stop dressing like you live in a
different time zone.
What did those,
those brothers,
those brothers that used to,
everybody had drank out of mason jars
and all the wood was raw.
All their commercials like they're all
wearing spat.
Damn Tino for wow.
Are Way smarter than I give him credit.
Why don't we were both off by,
I was on Bart over a hundred years to
work about 40 hours though.
But good enough dude.
Why so picky?
40 hours as a whole week.
You could use it for the week for
working.
Huh?
Look at it.
They were small enough to be worn around
the neck or carried it in a bag or
pocket.
Interesting.
Did they have a photo of one of those?
Is someone,
one of those still exist today?
See if it still exists.
Gangster.
Cause you get a statue made out of you.
If you could invent the pocket,
whatever,
you're a dope motherfucker.
Cause he didn't know.
But that was what led to the Apple
Watch.
He didn't know at the time it's going to
be,
you can never get away.
Is that what it looked like?
Hmm.
I wonder,
do you think you'd just slapped that
thing out on the table?
If you're trying to impress a girl,
fuck this giant giant like Harare keys
for archies never stay in the pocket.
Right.
Breaking those things out.
Always wearing like a ring going around
your finger.
Wow.
Look at the mechanism in that thing.
Holy Shit,
man.
That's gorgeous.
That's a thing that people super dork
out about madness.
Handmade watches.
Yeah,
I didn't,
I had no idea.
My friend Mark Della Grad [inaudible],
you know markdale grantee.
Mark del Grande's a watch nut.
So was a Anthony Giordano.
What a fucking coincidence.
Two guineas.
Two shiny guineas.
I really watched nuts,
but uh,
they did.
Anthony was telling me that there's a
anthony's,
the guy was directed all my,
except one of my comedy specials.
I love that dude.
He's directly UFC too.
He told me that,
uh,
there's watches that are half a million
bucks,
like insane for a watch.
I go,
it just is what it looks like a regular
watch.
She's like,
it looks like a regular watch.
What's the deal?
It's really rare then,
you know,
it's very accurate.
The mechanism,
it was like super complex,
all handmade and it takes like six
months to make one.
I'm like,
what?
Take six months to
make a watch.
You know,
you get,
we have this one,
219,000.
Oh my God.
What does that,
what does it look like?
That's it.
That's definitely not it.
Oh my God.
It looks like a transformer.
Click on that.
Looks like a Cobra.
Oh,
it's probably loading.
Still.
See how it's spinning up in the right at
the top.
I don't know.
It's just not coming up.
Huh?
Should we fished?
Be loaded fast.
Wow though.
Holy Shit.
Click on the image.
Just clicking the image instead of the
link.
What the fuck man?
$219,000
for the ugliest watch you've ever worn,
but everybody's going to know it's
$200,000
and that's the rub son.
I uh,
Hubo it's funny.
So my buddy bodie was sponsored by them
and he got a bunch of watches and he
just doesn't care about watches.
So they were just like in the drawer
with like the regular other stuff.
And I finally convinced him to flat to
give me one and it's sweet,
but it's not like a big deal.
Like it's disgusting.
That thing is ridiculous.
That is so like a safe vault that looks
like they would sell it at best buy in
the line before you leave,
where they have the candy.
They got that design from sharper image
for sure.
From sharper image.
That is so ugly.
That is such a weird looking stupid
watch.
Look at that guy.
So site,
look at it.
Look at his yellow eyes like the dude
from sin city.
He's like how rich banks.
Thank God he's so happy.
He's going to jump in his Ferrari and
take it to his private jet and cause
Dick talked to all the way to Monaco.
That'll probably happen.
Look at those fucking ugly watches man.
They're so gross.
Look at the one where the guy's wrist in
the upper right hand corner.
Jamie up there.
Yeah.
Look,
look how big.
That stupid thing is.
Definitely needs to be bigger.
That is crazy.
It looks like an alien locked onto that
dude's wrist.
Like some alien bug like like the
running man fucking the neck,
the neck piece.
They would explode like that.
Watch might just clamp down and remove
your hand.
Blow your hand off.
Squirt,
squirt,
squirt.
Yeah.
Fuck that.
Watch $219,000
that's so stupid.
It's ugly.
Yeah.
Swatch costs just another way to,
none of the way to subtly shit on
people.
Weird man.
Just show your show your status,
your identity and blah blah blah.
It's,
you know,
it's these,
these games,
the games that we like to play to,
to push our,
to what Jordan was saying,
like create that temporary inequality,
you know,
create that appearance of inequality.
I'm better than everybody because I have
this giant fucking safe fault on my,
on my hand that's had a conversation
with this dude about watches and I was
like,
what kind of watches that,
I guess it was one of those,
uh,
mvmt watches as a sponsor of the podcast
and they only cost like 150 bucks and
they're dope.
They're nice,
they're real,
they're really nice looking watches and
he's like,
Oh man,
I thought it was a nice watch.
I go,
but you thought it was a nice watch b.
Dot.
It was a nice watch,
but now it's not a nice wash cause you
know,
it's only 150
bucks.
It's still,
it's still the same watch.
It tells time,
look at it,
see it tells time.
Said,
what is this?
How much is this piece of shit?
5 million.
Oh my God.
It's the same company q bolt.
So you bought this,
whatever.
They've figured out how to find the
retards.
They figured out how to lock them in.
This one down here is 25 million.
Oh my Jesus.
Fucking cool.
What is that?
This is the watch park.
That's like a stellar nursery.
That's what it is.
That's how many million?
25 minutes.
If you're a chick and you can get a guy
to buy you that,
your pussy is gold.
You must have that Super Pussy that that
snap and pussy.
The Richard Pryor used to talk about in
this whole records.
Yeah,
it's the pussy that extends into the
soul.
30 million.
Is it a pocket watch?
The pocket watches 30 million.
So you're an asshole and you spent $30
million cause anyone with a pocket
watches an alcohol.
What is that thing?
Look at it.
It says it was started work on in 1782
and was finished in 1827 by the guy's
son.
Oh,
that's different.
That's different.
That is wicked.
So that that was a long to make that
watch men's.
You get drunk and left out at the bar.
Hey guys,
I'm super sorry.
Did you see a price live watch?
It's worth a couple of houses.
It's worth more than a couple 30 million
to work with a fucking mansion and a jet
in the hamptons.
You can live in the hamptons off a
watch.
Imagine that you get by the whole,
you can just say,
uh,
how you gonna pay.
I'm going to give you a watch.
Like what?
Imagine going back to like going back to
like a primitive more tribal culture and
like explaining how much value you could
get for something silly like that.
You know,
like,
like there was this watch and I could
buy houses and have control vast lands
and get unlimited food and,
and make people evolve varieties,
do all the things I wanted just from
this one little token.
And they'd be like,
well what does it do?
And you're like,
nothing does nothing but it's valuable.
You know,
they would be like,
what the fuck are you talking about?
Like there's not a better arrow.
Like it's not a better,
you know,
it's just this,
it's one of these things that comes up
when you get a a society of of luxury
like we have.
Yeah,
yeah.
That's the status purchase.
The status purchase.
It's interesting.
They're not even good.
That's what a lot of them are not good.
Like,
uh,
I've never bought a rolex for myself,
but the UFC bought me a rolex long time
ago.
It's just,
it's beautiful watch.
Right?
Beautiful.
But he was always running fast,
like five minutes fast.
So I brought it in and I'm like,
I don't know what it is.
But like after a month,
it's like five minutes fast.
The Guy Goes,
oh yeah,
yeah.
They always do that.
So you just got to bring it back and
reset it every month.
I went,
what?
Like you have the change at the time
every month.
This,
this watch,
I don't know how much it costs.
I don't even remember,
but I don't have to change the time.
It's always right.
It's right.
It runs,
it's got a quartz movement.
He's like,
Oh yeah,
a quartz movement is just going to be
more accurate than this.
Well,
why is what wait a minute.
So these are just bad.
They just suck at telling the time.
They still fucking so bad to tell them
the time to like five seconds or five
minutes fast after like,
uh,
just a couple of months.
So you just got to accept that that's
it.
You just accept it doesn't really keep
time.
It's Sordo keeps time.
The status with his dad,
his bracelet that happens to keep time.
How weird is that?
They did not get in it.
You have to check like with sea up.
Nope.
Launches off.
Hold on.
We'll watch like you've watched this
gets off.
Like you rely on the actual real clocks,
like this fucking piece of shit that we
wouldn't be spending like four bucks on
this,
that things right all the time.
It's never wrong.
You wind that bitch up to four o'clock
it and then when it's five it'll show
you it's five.
It's fucking right.
It's always right.
It didn't cost anything.
Yup.
But that's rolex bitch
doesn't satisfy the ego in the same way.
It doesn't get it fired up.
It doesn't let you get to feel better
about yourself.
So that,
you know,
I think when you really don't know,
again,
going back,
you don't know the self,
you want to feel better by your,
about yourself by making yourself better
than somebody else because you have no
other reference point of what it is.
So,
all right,
if I'm better than these other people,
you know,
whether it's something you have or
something you are inherently are the
Melanin in your skin or whatever the
fuck you want to say.
If that makes you better than someone
else,
then you can,
then you can feel better about yourself.
Well,
I don't know who I am.
I don't know if I'm good or bad,
but at least I'm better than these
fucks.
You know?
And then that makes you feel better.
But it's all,
it's all this fucking bullshit game that
we try to tell ourselves.
It comes from the fundamental lack of
knowing who we are and knowing that
whoever we are is enough and it's all
good.
And we're all the same.
You say that,
but Boris,
the guy with that fucking transformer on
his rest,
he was getting his dick sucked right now
while drinking vodka flying his private
jet over the Atlantic.
He disagrees with you.
That girl knows that that's a $250
million watch or whatever the fuck he's
wearing it.
She knows he's bawling adequate control
on his private jet.
It's covered with feathers.
Boris got his whole jet decked out like
an eagle.
The wings actually flat somehow makes
the flying worse that they flat just for
effect and that's when he starts coming.
Ah,
when the eagle wings flap,
while he's looking at his watch,
oh he looks at his watch at the girl and
then out the window in that order,
the best,
the best moment of his life.
And then he shoots himself in the head
cause he knows it will never be any
better.
Everything has been building to that
shoots a couple holes in the plane so
that it fucking crashes and then shoots
himself.
There was,
the Eagle Wings would clearly bring the
plane down.
Actually the minute you activated Eagle
Wing,
that plane is fucking taken.
It taken a nose dive and a captain
solely.
No one's ever gone out on top,
right.
No one's ever had like the ultimate life
like that.
And then you said,
I think it doesn't get any better than
this.
Let's just,
we're good.
We're good.
Boom.
No,
I was watching the Loma Chenko uh,
walters fight the other night.
Did you see that fight,
that boxing match?
God Damn facil look,
think you save a seal.
If I see a woman Chanko the silly I've
heard Wassily um,
but Lama Chanko is a masterful boxer.
I mean,
he just boxed it shit out of this dude.
This dude was undefeated and just
footwork,
just unbelievable footwork and ability
to predict where his,
where the punches are coming from,
his opponent where he's going to have
openings.
And he was just lightened this dude up
in the last round and a at the end of
the last round,
that dude just quit.
He just quit.
He quit in the seventh round.
Just said,
I'm done.
Like he didn't get knocked down.
He didn't get like we got staggered in
the six round or in the seventh round.
He gets staggered,
but it wasn't to the point where you
thought they would end the fight cause
he ended the round on his feet,
went back to his corner,
walked,
sat down.
I was like,
fuck this,
it's over.
And then you know,
in his post fight speech was just
basically saying,
look,
the guy was hitting me too much.
I just thought I saw the writing on the
wall.
Check,
please.
That's smart actually.
What people should do that you just want
to see him for your own,
for your own desires.
You want to see him go out on their
shield.
Like that's the noble way to do it.
Knock you out.
Do you know why Pat Barry vs check
Congo.
Remember that shit?
Yeah.
You just never know.
Never Know Pat Barry vs check Congo was
like one of the craziest one round.
Slobber knockers ever Pat Barry.
I had checked Congo all kinds or hurt
had him staggered and Pat Barry super
aggressive.
He's trying it on and smashing check
Congo and add a know where Congo on
corks all bomb.
I mean,
pat has got check Congo,
all kinds of hurt.
He's rocks.
And with that overhand right co Congo
gets up,
he's tagging them and it looks like he's
almost out of his feet.
I mean,
he's getting hit by bombs here.
He's all kinds of hurt.
Pat Barry sprawl and he keeps a fight
standing as Congo tries to take them
down and hits with another right hand
rock some again,
boom,
another couple punches.
And He,
Pat Barry Looks fucking unstoppable
here.
Look at this again.
But now as he closes in,
boom,
he gets clipped with that right hand in
hand.
How cold?
Two punches later out of nowhere.
Crazy.
I mean that is as close as someone's
comes to the brink of disaster and come
back instantaneously,
instantaneously and won by knockout,
wasn't it?
Didn't Chris leave and do that to
somebody?
Vandelay he did it.
The vandelay starched vandelay vandelay
came out and blast him with the right
hand.
Had him hurt,
but he fell into the trap because lead
punches so fucking hard.
And he always had an iron chin and you
just uncorked one on vandelay vendor and
like,
oh,
nothing happened weekend.
Right.
Did you watch
the bride?
Was it Derek Brunson fought?
Yes.
Yeah.
Well similar in a way,
but more calculated.
Dark Bahnson just got crazy and he,
it fought Robert Whitaker who won the
ultimate fighter Australia smashes
addition.
Was it Australia versus England?
Is that what it was?
No,
I forget what it was.
What did they,
what who was competing on anyway,
whitaker one and a whitaker since moving
up to one 85.
He's just so much better than it was at
one 70 and Derek Brunson just came after
him.
Derek bronze is the same guy who he had
just knocked out,
um,
uriah hall.
He caught him with a beautiful left hook
and heard them and it was just crazy
fight.
And then he came back from that sort of
employ the same strategy against
whitaker.
But what did your,
kept it together?
Kept together?
God,
he ate a lot of shots,
kept moving,
no,
kept his hands up,
kept his composure and then finally
found an opening him boom.
Dropped one on Brunson and then had
Brunson crazy hurt and then moved in on
him.
So it was an awesome,
it was an awesome exhibition for Wediko
show that whitaker could overcome the
storm of like a super confident and
really dangerous guy who hits fucking
hard,
who's had a lot of confidence because of
his most recent success doing that.
I mean,
Bronson came after him,
really,
really came after him.
Super aggressive,
maybe too aggressive for sure.
And now in hindsight you could say that,
but a lot of people other than whitaker
probably would a wilted to that storm.
So it's interesting.
It was a really stern test for whitaker
and showed you how strong he is.
Yeah.
It was one of the,
one of the beautiful aspects of watching
these different,
this chess play out with the whole body
being utilized.
You know,
you're never going to beat it for its
excitement level.
No.
Yeah.
You have to realize
while you're watching it that liked
life,
nobody gets out for free.
Yeah.
Like life.
I mean,
it's almost a microcosm of life.
It's crazy struggle and it,
you know,
it doesn't always end your way is this
is what competition is in mixed martial
arts is the most extreme version of
problem solving.
We have outside of war,
some most extreme with dire physical
consequences.
You get brains like we saw Pat Barry get
k out there,
you know what I mean?
That's the consequences of this game.
But the,
the,
the reality or the,
the take is nobody gets out anyway
alive.
Yeah.
You can,
if you choose to experience this,
this extremely high level,
very short bursts,
understand how much resources you're
burning off,
understand what you're doing and you
know,
proceed wisely.
And when,
uh,
when I talked to fighters who,
you know,
sometimes question like,
man,
what am I doing it myself?
I'm just beating people up.
And that's what I do,
you know,
to remind like remind them that what
really is happening is two people are
coming to an agreement to provide a form
of resistance for each other.
Like at the highest level of what this
is like you're going to come face to
face with someone who's also training
and also striving to do everything that
you're trying to do,
which is what's going to push you up
against that form of resistance and give
an opportunity
not only to overcome physically,
but overcome emotionally,
spiritually,
psychically,
everything.
You know,
you'll have to bring everything to bear
against that form of resistance,
whether it's the weight cut or the
opponent or the training or everything.
And there's something to be said for
that.
The,
obviously the only issue for a lot of
people is that you end up paying that
price,
not only then,
but later if you get the brain damage,
you know,
and that's,
that's the only bummer of it and
something that,
um,
to be considered,
but as if it wasn't for that man.
What a fucking beautiful way to do it.
Like to get everything,
everything all together,
unified in one and provide that ultimate
form of resistance.
It's like unbeatable.
It was definitely the most difficult
physical challenge that we know of
because you're competing,
especially at the highest level,
you're competing with someone who's the
same size as you,
has a commensurate level of expertise as
you and is as motivated as you are to
win,
and you're in this crazy competition
together where you're literally playing
a game of press the button and then who
you know who's who can shut off,
who's central nervous system quicker.
What I'm fucking crazy game you.
You,
you're never going to duplicate the
excitement of that with any other sport.
You come close.
Like I guess football is probably pretty
close for people.
Boxing's probably a right up there in
moments,
you know,
like when one men wall Ma,
let me say that again.
One man,
well Marquez knocked out Pacquiao.
He hit him with that beautiful clean,
straight punch and just flat and
Pacquiao.
That was about as dramatic a moment that
you get in any sort of combat sports.
You see a superhero like pack.
Yeah,
get leveled with one shot.
I'm like,
Whoa,
but that woe is just so much more
prevalent and mixed martial arts that
whoa happens so much more often.
It's a totally different thing.
And I think the,
the more rules that you put in,
in,
in front of that kind of primal
conflict,
you know,
the,
the little bit more,
it kind of separates it.
It makes it a sport.
You know,
like when you see boxers kind of
grabbing each other and doing nothing
about it,
you know,
that's when that moment of like,
oh yeah,
this is a sport.
Right.
Whereas in MMA,
there's fewer of those moments where you
go like,
oh yeah,
this is a sport.
It really just feels like people
fighting to the death.
Yeah.
They're the only moments where you go to
sports.
Like,
you can't grab the fence,
or I am punched the balls,
or Oh,
he pumped it high timeout.
Yeah.
There's moments in boxing where you go,
well,
this is kind of silly.
You know,
how come you can just hang on like this?
How come that guy can't trip you and
take you down?
How come he can't kick your legs?
Right.
You know,
it's really hard for me to watch boxing
sometimes and not think about kicking
someone's legs like,
or someone kicking someone's legs
rather.
Not that I'm running around,
man.
I mean,
I'm see the way they're standing and I'm
like,
yeah,
well there's those little thoughts like
this is effective.
As long as someone's not kicking your
legs.
Yeah,
we know.
But if you're fighting the same fight,
but you're,
you know,
you're fighting someone like Joe
Schilling,
it's going to be fucking kicking the
shit out of your
legs.
Yeah.
You know,
it's a totally different experience and
he's a long dudes.
She's going to be standing way on the
outside and if you don't know how to
deal with that,
you're only going to be able to absorb a
few of those before you're useless.
Yeah.
Or you think of like Badr Hari's like
leaping overhand,
right.
Where he commits everything,
all of his childhood pain and to that
right hand,
right.
You can't do that all the time.
And mma because someone would just duck
underneath it in double leg,
but he's never had to worry about that.
So you know,
it's still still,
he's one of the most exciting
motherfuckers ever and he's fighting
against soon.
He's fighting Rico Verhoeven going to be
on December 10th.
Yeah,
that's a crazy night.
There's a gang of fights that night,
that same night.
Bernard Ha.
No,
no.
Bernard Hopkins is the 17th he's making
his final fight.
But uh,
that same night is a,
the UFC from Toronto.
It's glory and there's something else
going on that night too.
There's some sort of a boxing fight that
night as well.
It does it,
but it's a crazy night.
That's a,
it's a weird fight,
man.
Verhoeven and bought her Harry Potter
hard.
He's a scary dude literally and many,
many,
many ways.
It's so fun to watch.
He's just one of my favorites ever cause
she's like you said,
he just commits commencing this
extremely violent way and sometimes he
gets carried out on the shield.
You know,
he,
sometimes he had goes down.
Really can't shut that off.
Like once he gets that thing going,
I mean he would want to stomp his bone
and after they're down and he's just a
fucking savage.
Yeah,
he's definitely,
I would love to see there a laundry list
of Mexican supplements.
I'm like,
what kind of cocktail you guys run in
here?
He definitely has hair braided around
his dick,
like Princess Leia.
So big.
Now.
Have you seen him?
You've seen the most recent photos of
bought her pull up the recent photos of
bought her hard cause he puts some
photos on instagram of him training and
you know,
took pictures of him with his shirt off.
He like what?
Jesus Christ.
He looks,
he's about to 50 now,
something like that.
And he's a big giant dude.
He's always been a big giant dude,
but he's like super,
super muscled out.
Now look at this shit.
He's fucking,
he's fucking jacked.
But there's uh,
there's some other photos or maybe a
little bit clear if you go there.
It is right there.
That one in the middle.
What in the fuck is going on there?
That dude's gigantic now.
Yeah,
I mean that's terrifying.
That's gigantic.
He's so much bigger than he was when he
first started.
When he first started kickboxing,
he was this long,
tall,
thin guy.
Cause he started like some of his early
fights that I've seen during the k one
days.
Even he was way skinnier like back in
the day and then kicked out like put up.
You want to see something put Badr Hari
versus Stefan Leco.
Um,
and that was just typing Leco yeah,
there it is.
Stefan [inaudible] and this is Badr Hari
look at like what he looked like back
then.
Upper left upper left image.
Yeah.
That's Badr Hari.
Then look at the difference.
Yeah.
Crazy.
He hits stuff on,
go with a spinning back kick to the face
and flatten them.
They had fought previously and Leco
stopped him with a spinning back kick to
the body.
So a,
in the rematch,
she,
he hit him with one of the face.
Crazy but look,
great picture.
Yeah.
Beautiful.
You could see that.
Find the video.
Potter,
Hari Kao,
Stefan Leco.
Um,
there it is.
Okay.
You got to think that this,
this dude's probably put on like 50
pounds or something.
Yeah.
Is this,
this is Leco.
Oh,
this is Dubai.
2014 I think this is the other one.
This is,
that was a,
yeah,
that's it.
You just had it right there.
This is it.
Here it comes.
He throws one in messes.
But look how skinny he is here,
man.
Yeah.
Total different guy.
Different selves.
Yeah.
Here it goes.
Watch it.
He set it up,
set it up with a jab.
He faked it to the body.
That bomb goes up top.
Damn flatline.
Nothing quite like a,
like that Barbosa kick.
Yeah.
Well that was almost a different one
though,
that he did it.
A side kick to the face.
It was a,
he didn't do it as like a wheel kick.
If you watch it again,
rewind a little bit.
He shot it as a straight kick.
Rewind it.
Uh,
he,
he threw it as if you see how he's
throwing it there.
He threw it to the body.
That's a spinning sidekick or turning
sidekick.
He's not doing it as a back kick.
If you did the toes to be down,
but see how he went up there.
That was just a turning side kick to the
face.
It's kind of halfway between,
both halfway between a wheel kick and a
spinning back kick or a turning
sidekick.
But it was fucking beautiful.
Boom.
Look smaller wheel kick when I look at
it there.
But Jesus Christ the perfect Yup.
Right on the blocks and Stefan Leco uh,
who was uh,
he was a great fight or two man.
That guy.
Yeah,
he knocked a lot of dudes out,
saw him knock out Peter Earths in Vegas
One k one was just starting to come up.
They were do it putting on some shows in
Vegas this before the UFC was big.
They thought that k one was,
would I think really still think it
could have if it was promoted properly,
could have like gotten a grip in North
America.
Well that's what,
you know,
Gloria is pushing that boulder now.
Gloria is a good example.
And so as lion fight,
I prefer the rules of lion fight though.
Cause lion fight is full.
Moitai yeah,
elbows.
We went to one of those [inaudible]
Vegas.
Yeah.
That's one of the few things that I go
to see live.
I still like to go see live.
Yeah.
Fuck man.
A high level Moitai in America.
It's like the level of the fights is
very high.
It's just people aren't just,
didn't totally not aware of it yet.
They need to be though.
It's crazy exciting.
It's just,
and there's so much talent.
It's not like this is an exciting thing,
but only like five guys are good at it.
It's an exciting thing where,
especially in the lighter weights,
like Thailand's full of fucking killers,
they got a ton of them in Europe.
They've got them all over the globe.
There's so many good Moy Thai fighters
out there.
They just,
for whatever reason,
we haven't caught on yet.
That's why I think when I think about
this time,
I think it's the best time ever because
we get to see all of these incredible
contest,
still extremely physical,
like we're still at the rising peak of
our physical prowess,
but we're also at the peak of our
technological prowess and the peak of
our ability to access all of the best
foods and access the best ideas and all
of the different things that can shape
us like as pessimistic as people get it
is for sure the best of times right now.
You know,
for the majority of people now obviously
they're hell's on the planet still.
There's hell's that we can put ourselves
in.
There's suffering,
but overall on the macro level,
it's a fucking,
it's the golden age now.
Sure.
Anybody argues with that?
It's an asshole.
Yeah.
I want to go back to a time where you
had to speak with grunt and even in the
future,
like I can't imagine that the,
I guess maybe maybe it would like maybe
we've just seen too many gray aliens,
you know,
where the body kind of becomes less and
less important and everything is focused
on the consciousness.
I feel like you get to that level and
you fucking miss this,
this certain,
you know,
evolution and epoch for the pleasure
monkey where we had all of that physical
access to strive and train and,
and feel all the physical things as well
as,
you know,
reach incredible heights in,
in consciousness and meditation and you
know,
community and these,
these great things.
I think,
you know,
I think really no matter what stage
before or after,
I think we'll look back at this one.
Like this was a special fucking time.
It's definitely a special time,
but I think every time it's a special
time because every time,
no matter where you are and the
timescale,
if you're in that moment,
you're in the most present time,
you're in the most current time and I
guarantee you at every step of the way,
people were logging with nostalgia for
the past.
I bet they were like,
God damn man,
who used to rape is run across the
village.
Chop heads off and shit.
Good old days,
Bro.
Yeah,
good times before they started writing
things down on paper is probably a lot
of people that miss that they miss to
shooting arrows.
Just launched them in the air and
whatever's over there.
Fuck them.
They did.
They made it rain arrows from the sky
and like 50 years after that was over,
some viking king had a slogan,
let Denmark race
again.
Everybody was excited.
Not Denmark rape again.
We let the killings begin a new,
but that was a big problem with Japan's.
If he didn't want to embrace the gun was
like,
no,
you pussies can't be fucking shooting
people with guns.
That's such a bitch ass way to go.
You got to use solar.
It's come on,
come on,
don't be a bitch.
But they,
they,
they've held on too long.
They didn't embrace the gun.
They need to get on that right away.
If they had the Japanese engineering
that you see today in Lexus,
if they had applied that to guns back in
the day,
had same knowhow and discipline,
they have the best gun stayed,
not the best gun,
but you dedicate yourself and become
masters in the world at swordsmanship
and then the gun comes along,
right.
Ah,
fuck this.
Fuck.
This trumps all of my years of work.
But the sword.
Yeah.
Yeah man,
they made it easy.
I mean,
it's sort of like a supermarket did for
versus being a substance,
a living off the land type person.
You know,
if you've watched those shows from a
Alaska where the people are all living
in and grow their own vegetables and
shit and they catch fish in the river,
there's something romantic about it.
Write something that drags.
I love those shows,
man.
I watch those shows.
You know,
you like,
you know,
your purpose every day.
And I think when people know their
purpose,
my purpose is to survive,
get food,
stay warm,
you know,
uh,
make babies.
Like it's really comforting to know what
your purpose is.
Well,
yeah.
And especially if you don't have any
internet like before they got on
television,
I wonder how much access to Internet
even had up there.
Ma,
why watch this one family that
apparently,
you know that uh,
that singer jewel,
do you know who she is?
She has a one snaggletooth but she's
very beautiful and people like the fact
that she doesn't fix her teeth because
she's imperfect yet.
Perfect.
Um,
she's apparently from this one family
that has this,
this show,
goddammit Alaska,
the final frontier.
Is that the name of it?
Uh,
but anyway,
it's her relatives.
Yeah,
I think,
I feel like close relatives that live up
there in this crazy way and it's a,
you know,
real simple like some of them farm and
they raised cattle and they have to like
move their cattle across this area to
take them to where they graze and they
drop them off.
And they have to move them back at the
end of the year.
It's nuts.
And so while they're up there doing
this,
grizzly bears just start ripping their
fucking cows apart.
So now they have to go and deal with
these,
you know,
11 foot tall giant dog things that need
food constantly to consume.
And on one hand you can't blame them
like these fat stupid cows just
wandering around over by the grass.
All they have to do is go by the grass.
There's fucking hundreds of them.
Where else are they going to find
hundreds of things that they can eat?
Nowhere.
Like you just put out a buffet in front
of the Grizzly bear and you're mad at
their eating.
It's bare supermarket.
So they had a,
he had a hunt them down.
It's crazy watching this guy because
although it is reality TV and you do not
know how much of this show is,
bullshit goes clearly,
some of it's bullshit.
There's clearly some setup.
Like I saw one scene where they had a
filleted salmon and the bear was
supposedly getting fish from the river
and it was coming too close to them
while they're fishing.
But you never saw the two of them,
the same frame.
And then you see the bear and the bear
has a salmon that's filleted meaning
like someone cut that Sam and threw it
in the water and gave it to the fucking
bear,
which is like,
come on stupid.
You know.
So you guys are the only people here,
but yet the bear,
you haven't caught a fish yet,
but the bear is a fish that has filets
removed off of it.
Shut the fuck up man.
I'm not stupid.
Yeah,
that's the,
that's the TV game.
But it does give you like a little
window into the wild ways that all of us
humans live.
It gives a window,
which is cool.
Like I got to um,
there's this book before they pass away
and you gave me that book.
Give me that.
But yeah,
it looks amazing.
It's amazing photos.
But then you start reading about these
different cultures,
like actually had the photographer on my
podcast and he was telling me about,
um,
what is his name?
It's called before they,
pat Jimmy Nelson,
Jimmy,
Jimmy Nelson.
So Jimmy Nelson was on the podcast and
uh,
he was talking about the Himba people,
which have these amazing photos or like
a really tall tribe.
And I believe it was the Himba.
And um,
he was telling me about their custom,
they live in just such a dramatically
different way.
So they're,
they're like a pastoral shepherding kind
of tribes.
So they have all of their cows,
but there's very little grass.
So the men have to take the cows on
these long walks to feed them like four
weeks away.
Right.
But what they do is they leave one man
behind in the,
in the village,
and it's his job to sexually satisfy all
the women,
all,
well,
all the men are gone.
And that position rotates,
right?
So that everybody gets their turn as the
one dude that gets to sexually satisfy
the entire village.
One of girls get pissed if it's all this
motherfucker turn.
Yeah.
Hate is dirty.
Dig to watch this little tiny dirty
dance.
There's certain guys that they're never,
they're never on vacation for when it's,
that guy's turning around.
Some girls will hold out,
but like I'm good,
I'm good.
You can go fuck my friends.
I'm gonna wait,
I'm gonna wait until Igor is term.
Igor slangs that good deck.
No,
I wouldn't want that.
I only want her pleasure to come from my
penis.
Penis.
I heard of the massage man.
The way he touched her anus come so
hard,
tim.
With all my being one day I will remove
him from this life with a sword.
It's so funny that someone who you love,
someone else makes that person who you
love gives them pleasure and interfaith
their ass.
She's got her ass up in the air.
She's backing up into his tongue.
Ah,
nope,
no new,
new,
new.
That's the thing that makes you vomit as
a man because it triggers these,
these things.
But it can all be worked through.
Like you can push through the other side
and that's,
you know,
or you could shoot yourself or you
could,
I think we played that.
We played that country song where it's
like I flashed my headlights that are
window.
Yeah.
It all fucking crazy in your head about,
or just be like,
oh,
the pleasure monkeys getting pleasure.
Great.
Yeah.
Well men who freak out about other like
girl there,
girl liking another guy.
Like,
man,
you can't win that one.
You got to let it go.
Because here's the thing.
When someone likes someone,
they fucking like someone and you're
going to accept,
Ooh,
can't believe it's fucking cold.
I'm going to go for a walk.
Nuke it.
Don't do it.
You're going to freeze to dead.
Fuck that.
I like walking naked.
I know you like walking naked,
but he can't go walking naked.
You're gonna fucking freeze to death is
a reality of going outside when it's 30
below zero.
Right.
Okay.
Well this is the same reality applies.
So when someone doesn't like you,
if a girl does not wanna have sex with
you,
but she wants to fuck the rock,
there's not a lot you
could say about it.
Okay?
She's not,
you will,
you know the rock doesn't love you the
way I love you.
I love you forever in eternity.
And it's not even like the body.
It's like the soul now.
It's not going to work.
She's thinking of the rocket has giant
Samoan Dick just ramming it home.
That's what she wants.
Okay,
you got to accept that and you're going
to have to enjoy another aspect of life
other than having sex with one person
who's now having sex with a rock or be
happy for her and be like,
man,
that's fucking awesome.
That's not going to happen once per,
you know,
just exactly.
Look at that photo.
Is that when he's holding one of the,
uh,
he's,
he slings those fucking bigfoot's Bro.
Those primal bells that we have,
he slings that thing around like it's
nothing.
Yeah.
That's an enormous human dude.
It's,
it's possible to make that move,
man.
I mean,
I've been working on it in my own life.
It's fucking possible.
It's hard.
It's hard as fuck.
But you know you can,
you can transcend these things were and
just understand that deeper metaphysical
truth,
pleasure for someone I love.
Makes that person my friend,
not my enemy.
Of course.
In theory I believe you.
But for the sake of humor,
I'm going to keep talking shit about the
rock banging your sister areas.
He's got a gorilla there.
I can't believe he use two hands.
What a bitch.
I throw that around with one.
Yeah,
the rock.
It's a strong human man and you know
what?
Just not just strong like physically but
strongly.
His personality,
the way he projects himself.
Like he's a perfect example of someone
who projects like this very positive
vibe man.
He's like,
this is very energetic,
positive,
happy vibe.
It's very infectious.
Like I see that guy talking.
He does like youtube clips or instagram
clips rather.
A little videos he makes and his,
his positivity and genuine enthusiasm
and happiness is so infectious.
I'm a fucking fan boy of the rock.
I said it.
I fucking said it.
I don't care.
You know,
he's got a great bit Andrew Santina.
I don't,
I'm not going to give out a word of it.
Not a word.
I cannot,
I cannot even,
but if you get a chance,
Andrew Santiago has a fucking hilarious
bit about the rock.
God Damn,
it's good.
It's really funny.
But um,
that kind of person,
man,
like those are fuel,
those,
those are,
that's human fuels.
That guy's like a,
a light.
So like,
I mean,
I,
I've come to look at ourselves like a,
like a software operating system that
can constantly get rewritten a little
bit by even by the people that you're
around,
you know,
whether it's,
you want to look from the point of like
mirror neurons,
you actually experiencing the same
emotional state that the person you're
around and,
or if it's just ideas or thoughts or
whatever you want to,
however you want to look at it,
it's like adding a little bit of code to
our code base.
And sometimes it's helpful and sometimes
it's a virus,
but the more you surround yourself with
people with that kind of positive vibe,
it's like building on the software in a
positive way.
When you're around these more negative
people,
they're implanting different little,
you know,
bugs and viruses that you're going to
have to scan and remove later.
Essentially all open source.
Exactly.
100% open source.
Some beings are open source but uh,
you know,
mine your firewall.
Totally,
totally.
Should I be careful?
Put yourself in situations where you're
adding to that positive code base,
the books you're reading,
the things you're listening to,
you know,
and,
and be careful of the things on tv to
that are adding to the,
you know,
creating more of the viruses.
Reince like supporting these negative
thought patterns,
these,
these limiting beliefs,
these things that are not helpful for
the coaches,
committed to do these things that you
have in your idea and in your mind like
don't be so set in your ideas.
Cause understand that people have to be
just as sat in their ideas in order to,
I'll lash someone for being in close
proximity with a man or to lash.
Someone who had sex with a woman.
You know those,
those people have the same.
Or to wait til a woman who's pregnant
gives birth before you give her a
beating with a stick because she had
sex.
That's the,
those people believe what they believe
just as firmly and a lot of the notions
that we have that we think there are
rigid rules.
They're not rigid rules except dudes
with man buns.
Let it go.
Stop twisting your mustache in a circle.
No more man Bun.
No more pocket watch.
Fuck you.
How about that
says the man with the fanny pack on.
Ironically,
but you know what I'm saying.
Yeah man.
Man.
Bus.
They're not necessary.
What are you doing,
Steven Seagal.
He doesn't even wear one anymore.
He gave it up and we were pat.
I got some man been friends.
They're going to be disappointed.
I know they are.
They're trying hard.
They're trying hard to wear that vest.
Yeah.
Those weird shoes,
the wooden soles,
everybody just j everybody's just
looking for love and they're looking to
judge themselves as a good person,
you know?
And,
and that's,
that's,
those are two things that you can get
yourself,
you know,
you can understand that you're worthy of
love and supply that and you can
understand that you're a good person.
Just being a person.
Like,
you know,
you don't have to be better than
somebody.
You don't have to shit on somebody.
You don't have to have this identity,
you know,
everybody could just relax.
Then I think all of a lot of this
striving and conflict and suffering,
you know,
just fucking falls away.
Like it's so easy to say like that's a
beautiful concept.
You're worthy of love,
love.
But I think people have to experience a
certain amount of difficulty in their
life just to exercise their system.
I think our system is put in place to
have a certain amount of obstacles to
overcome and when we don't have any or
when it's like really simple stuff
that's fucking boring,
you know?
I think people have real problems with
that.
I think we have real problems with our
minds,
real problems physically with our entire
unit.
I think we absolutely need a certain
amount of exertion,
you know?
And,
and my,
I mean in might not even be physical.
Like,
um,
my friend drawn,
drawn Horton and went to Colorado with
him.
We did a gig out there.
He just got into chess just a madman.
But the chest now playing on his phone,
constantly moving things around and he's
like,
you want to play?
I'm like,
fuck that.
I'm not getting sucked into that God
damn rabbit hole.
I see him there on the plane.
Can't wait to play chess since we're off
in the sky.
I'll fucking with his
phone.
Shit.
That's uh,
that is another discipline.
I mean,
they're all disciplines.
They're all these different things that
you try to seek truth through.
I mean,
chess is a form of combat,
you know,
it's just not painful,
but it's most certainly,
yeah,
it's a form of combat.
It's absolutely a form of,
it's a contest.
You know,
if you treat it as a war,
I mean that is essentially what you're
doing.
Like you're breaking it down to a very
innocuous but very safe,
but very obvious what's going on.
I'm testing my intellect against your
intellect and we're going to do it.
Do so through a very established series
of movements of these things are allowed
to participate in.
We have a,
a established playing field.
You know the rules.
I know the real rules.
I think I'm smarter than you go.
And you have that little clock thing
that those dudes to have those dudes,
they fuck they fuck with you.
So they move it quick and then eat that
fucking clock.
Ooh.
And you want to move a quick tool.
You want to say fuck you bitch.
I know that.
Ah,
click,
clack.
And you see them giving up pieces and
moving fast.
That's some mental war.
They're playing a mental,
some sort of a strategic conquest game.
Yeah.
And that's uh,
and you know,
that's one,
like you said,
that discipline,
there's so many ways up the mountain,
but you need a mountain.
You need something.
You need a mountain.
I met.
It doesn't,
it's not mutually exclusive to,
you know,
the self love aspect.
You can still find your mountain,
you know,
without thinking you're a piece of shit
when you stumble because everybody
fucking stumbles.
It doesn't mean you're a piece of shit.
It doesn't mean that you should hate
yourself.
It doesn't mean that you should isolate
yourself from the love of the world
because you feel you're not worthy of it
and is create these negative patterns
like,
yes,
go out fucking fine your mountain.
But when you stumble,
like everybody fucking does understand
that.
That's just life.
Like we're all going to stumble.
You just get up and keep going.
Maybe you bitch,
I'm not stumbling.
I got this thing I'm doing,
Bro.
I'm doing a lot of tight rope walking in
the house.
I got rope set up all around the house,
Tyrell proc into the kitchen.
I figured somebody could do it.
I saw this thing.
This dude lives in the mountains,
just tight ropes to work.
You mean someone tight ropes,
right across these giant spaces.
What w what's to stop people from just
doing that all the time from creating
like a civilization high up in the sky
and if you fall down you're fucked.
So don't fall and uh,
just tight rope because people love to
drink.
That's why that's a problem.
That's why you got to get that
psychedelic honey because it helps you
tyrell better type room over to the
psychedelic honeycomb.
Snatch it while there you gotta stay
calm while they're staying in the fuck
out of you and you still in beehive
stop.
You ever tried,
you ever gone skiing on mushrooms?
You were telling me how awesome it is
and I need to try it because I skiing to
me is a,
it's a weird thing.
It's like I can do it but I'm always
like the consequences of this like
little bit of fun.
It's really not worth it.
Like I do it because my family likes to
do it,
but part of me is like,
don't fall down bitch.
Don't fall down bitch.
Okay,
here we go again.
Don't fall down.
I mean it's fun.
I get it.
And if I was better at it would probably
be even more fun,
but it's like,
dude,
I know too many people that have fucked
their bodies up skiing.
I mean fucked up,
blown their neat cap up to the side of
their hip and their fucking legs broken
seven places and their next never moving
to the left ever again and like,
Whoa,
what happened?
I hit a tree.
I'm one of the lucky ones.
I think that's people.
That's why people liked skiing and even
why people like riding a motorcycle,
it's like the stakes are high.
When the stakes are high you have to
focus on what you're doing then your
present again.
So it's fun.
Yeah,
you got to get better at it.
That's what it is.
Just coming up with bitch ass excuses,
but it's,
it's what's easier.
Snowboarding or skiing,
skiing,
I think really,
at least for,
at least for me when I've tried it
snowboarding,
the falls are way gnarlier because when
you fall and you catch like your toe
edge,
like you slam back.
Oh yeah.
I've gotten,
I hit my head so hard coming from a
steep mountain down into a flat and
caught an edge on this icy part.
Oh,
I hit the back of my head so hard that
the front of my goggle lenses popped off
into the air,
like a fucking pop tart out of a
toaster.
All right.
And I was fucked.
Like I couldn't just,
yeah.
Yeah.
Cause I woke up,
people were like helpfully,
like terrified helpfully,
like you,
okay.
So that probably wouldn't happen to your
skin,
Huh?
They can,
but it's less likely because the way
that you catch that edge and just like
hook up the hookup,
the board and it's like a slingshot and
just slams your head back down.
We're skiing,
you'll like usually skid out or tumble
or,
right.
I mean,
I'm one of those things.
So yeah,
I think the con,
I mean that's why it makes it harder to
learn because there's these fucking
fatal crashes you do on a snowboard.
Yeah.
And skiing to men.
Sometimes some people get too close to
you,
like that's another problem.
Like they don't know how to control
themselves.
Very good.
Yeah.
And they're kind of like out of control.
And so you have to kind of like adjust
quickly to get away from them.
Like,
Oh shit.
Like this lady was coming down like,
ah,
like it looked like she was going to go
down hard,
but she,
she got by me,
I'm like,
Oh shit,
I've got a ductus lady.
And so I had to take a hard left,
but then the trees are right there.
I'm like,
fuck,
I gotta take a hard right and hope it
ain't working.
Boom.
When I started.
But it was,
I was fine,
but I was like,
Ooh,
boy.
Like that can go wrong if you're in the
wrong spot when that happens.
Like if there's a tree there and you
cannot get away from that tree,
like you gotta be real fucking careful
who you zig and zag.
I'll take that bitch out next time.
Like if we're near a tree.
Sorry Lady.
We're both going down together hoping
not to fall.
Fucking good to say don't swerve for the
deer.
Ah,
yeah.
He's supposed to just hit the gas,
right?
No,
no.
He's supposed to not do anything.
She was just let it hit your car,
but that's ridiculous.
That's like saying don't blink with
someone,
punches you.
How many deers do you get to hit before
you realize not to hit the gas like it
takes?
It would be like,
like you ever seen a picture of Floyd
Mayweather eating a jab?
Like he's cutting a punch to the face
but his eyes are wide open and he's
punching back because he's so
conditioned to being
punchy.
So used to it that he can keep his eyes
open as the punches are coming in and
then counter perfectly.
You're not going to have that kind of
resolve with a deer.
No.
You're going to hit that break.
Yeah,
you're going to swerve good again when
them giant fucking meat cleaver bumpers
and they have like people live in
Wyoming and shit.
They have those road warrior bumpers and
the trucks.
It just makes different stakes cut and
I'm like t bone and then it's like,
it's like extruded like Plato.
Yeah.
You have to like some places you can't
just throw it in the back of your truck
either.
You'd have to kind of call somebody and
prove that you hit it that way cause
they want to discourage poaching.
That's it.
Well it makes a lot of sense man.
But fuck deer jumping in front of your
car.
What are the odds that you're going to
go,
okay,
you can't hit those brakes.
Remember they said just don't swerve,
just hit the deer.
I think some people are better at that
super calm moment of like decision
making and crisis.
Like I've been around people in certain
situations that like are you can't
prepare for.
And then there's some people who just
freeze like straight fucking freeze.
Yeah.
And then some people act and I think
like all like off police officers and
military,
they train yourself past the freeze.
But it's funny,
like I was in Australia and this dude
was drinking Bundaberg over proof rum
and he was used to doing this trick with
regular butter proof from,
which is Bundaberg rum,
where he lights it on fire and pours it
in his mouth and it goes out when it
hits his mouth.
But he was doing it instead with over
proof from right.
Was He never done before?
Well,
the thing was over proof from is that
mother fucker doesn't go out ever
period.
Like the wind is not going to get it
out.
So he's pouring his flaming shot and it
doesn't go out and so it's face catches
fire.
Oh Jesus.
Full full on hell raiser face catches
fire.
He's in the kitchen of the house we're
renting and like everybody is just
looking at him,
he's clawing and his face is not
working.
Obviously he doesn't know what to do.
And then I'm looking at them and I don't
know what the fuck to do and everybody's
just staying there.
So I go to the Faucet and I'm like
trying to get water and like spray it on
from the fall,
not the right thing.
I should have put like a towel or a roof
over his head,
you know,
but you just don't think you're not
prepared at that moment.
You know?
And then,
and then so eventually he fucking rolls
around on the ground and gets it,
get figured out.
He got burned but it was more like a
facial,
like took the,
took the first layer off and he had like
a nice laser peel.
Oh yeah.
Like when someone goes does that and it
doesn't say anything and you sort of go,
okay,
did you just visit the sun a little bit
like that?
He ended up ended up being fine but I've
been around other people.
Like another incident,
it was like a home stripper pole.
Right.
And I was there with,
I was there with Roger where ty.
Right and how's you should never buy,
I'm talking about a haunted house or
your own poles alum superbad ago and it
was,
it was tied to the wall and this girl
gets on there and she's swinging.
She's a little bit bigger.
We're all around the raw kind of
laughing.
Everybody's clothes were all just
laughing and,
and,
and the pole goes
like on hinges from the roof.
She's going timber from like 10 feet up
inverted like it's going to be really
bad.
And literally everybody around the
circle just looked like this is going to
be bad.
And Roger just quickly like immediately
moves over and like grabs the Paul
[inaudible] style.
Right.
And that's when I realized like that's a
different dude.
That's a dude that when that totally
random thing happens,
he has the ability to act instead of
just look around like all of us dummies
like damn,
that's going to hurt.
Yeah,
it's a good point.
That's hilarious.
Well Rogers,
the same guy that knocked out that
fucking due to punch that girl in
Austin.
Yeah.
That was a giant giant football player.
Football player.
This is when Roger was fighting in the
UFC and he was,
he's fighting it 155 pounds.
It's not a big guy.
And this a football player who knows
what the story was,
walked up to some woman in,
punched her in the face and I don't know
in the back of the head.
Yeah.
What's,
so they were coming out of a club and it
was actually a club that we used to go
to a lot.
I just happened to be out of town that
weekend,
but we're kinda coming out of the club
and this girl,
like he gets the guy gets an f,
like a fight with one of her boyfriends
or whatever.
And then she's like the whole thing
because he punches a girl in the hedge
whole the whole thing from the
beginning.
But no,
you get us a little bit of red there.
There you go.
Here comes boom.
Okay,
watch this punches are right in the back
of the head.
Boom.
And just flattens or,
and then walks away and everybody's
like,
what the fuck?
Yeah.
And this guy is huge.
And look at Roger.
Roger walks up to him.
He's literally a hundred pounds lighter
than him.
And I'm like,
you're kidding.
And Roger starts talking to him.
He just says,
at that point,
you can't do that man.
You can't do that,
man.
Wow.
And so Roger Walks up and decides,
okay,
I'm taking my shirt off and takes his
shirt off because he doesn't want to do
to be able to grab his shirt like he's
thinking strategically,
like,
which is like way one step ahead.
It's not like he's going to physically
intimidate this guy.
The guy's giant.
And so roger standing in front of this
guy and the dude's big and it looks like
somebody else tried to jump into
somebody else,
tried to jump in on both sides and stop
them from fighting the guy that guy runs
and then roger corners corners and by
the truck,
what you can't see you going on right
now,
corn is and by the truck,
the guy swings,
Roger Somehow gets a minute,
muy Thai clinch and started kneeing him
in the head and knees him in the head
and then he gets them out of hosting and
stomps him and then runs hold pride
rules style.
And this all happens in 1520 seconds.
Maybe not even.
It was really quick,
like,
yeah,
the whole video is only two minutes and
28 seconds long and it became this viral
gigantic kit.
Whatever happened to that dude.
Did he get in trouble for that?
Um,
I don't know.
I don't think so.
I know that the police knew,
obviously the roger hit him and they
just basically shook his hand and we're
like,
yeah,
hey,
all right.
We understand.
You know.
But,
uh,
I don't think anything ever happened to
that dude.
But that was fucking brutal and hard.
Just went full,
full overhand right to the back of that
chick's head.
Yeah.
But he's just that type of dude.
He also saved somebody from drowning on
the beach.
Raj.
Yeah.
He's just like finds himself in
situations and he acts,
you know,
whereas other people,
might freeze or might not.
Well,
he has a brutal upbringing,
you know?
And I think sometimes people that have
overcome brutality when they're younger,
they developed this ability to
understand like,
oh,
I've been here before.
I know what this is all about.
I know what this kind of chaos is.
And there's only one way out of this
thing.
You got to meet it head on where someone
is coddled who grows up and you know,
a cushion room.
Everything.
Everything's dolls,
no sharp edges that that person when
confronted with some horrific situation,
like some giant steroids up,
football player punches a girl in the
back of the head and you've got to act
and that guy's a hundred pounds bigger
than you and Roger just takes the shirt
off.
Right.
It's just like,
well I can't have him grab me.
Yeah,
that's the dude you don't wanna fuck
with you.
Sure.
Unemotional dude.
I really wished that that he didn't have
that falling out with UFC.
Yeah.
People forget the Roger worked or was
the first guy to ever be on the cover of
sports illustrated for MMA.
He was on the fucking cover of sports
illustrated.
He was being groomed as one of the top
guys,
but there was some sort of dispute
between him and the UFC.
Who knows which side is correct.
Who knows what happened,
but he wound up leaving the UFC and
then,
yeah,
he just won his last fight so I have to
do that.
Is he in one now?
Was he fighting over one RC?
One FC.
He's got some real talent,
man.
You know they've got,
ben asked went over there,
but I heard it's crazy.
You know,
he's got some real talent right now.
The bell tour,
welterweight division,
Douglas Lema just knocked out chorus
cough.
You know that guy who a fucked up?
Uh,
um,
uh,
what the hell is his name?
Okay.
What he,
he's beaten a few guys.
Let me think.
Chorus.
Cough.
Okay.
MMM.
Oh fuck.
Did he beat up?
God dammit.
What am I thinking of?
Who Give me his uh,
chorus cobb's last few.
I know he fought Benson Henderson.
He beat Benson Henderson up when Benson
came over to,
um,
to tour and he fought as well to wait
for the first time.
And then a Benson just fought.
You got it.
Oh,
who,
wait a minute.
Why does it say Douglas Lema twice?
Douglas.
He was the opponent.
Who's is this course cough?
Oh,
he lost a Doug Islam at twice.
Are you one the first one lost the
second one.
The first one.
Cause Cor de Lima had a fucked up knee.
That's right.
And then he'd beat Benson and then Lima
just crushed him in the rematch.
Which fight am I thinking of?
Man?
God,
I can't believe,
I can't remember which side it was,
but the Benson Henderson one was a big
one.
Even though it was a decision,
you could tell the difference in size is
pretty significant.
But then when Lima fought Korotkov,
you could see Lima looked way bigger
than Korotkoff.
So they,
and they've got Paul Daley.
Okay.
That's what it is.
So Lima just,
I'm getting all confused.
Lima beat Paul Daley,
who's super legit and he beat him
by decision and then just knocked out
Korskoff I,
for some reason I thought Lima are
thought daily had fought Korskoff I
fucked it up.
But dailies Super Legit,
I mean,
dailies a scary fucking striker.
Sure.
So for Lima to beat him and to be Benson
Henderson who's relatively undersized
for the division and then to knock out
Korotkoff like that,
I mean that was stunning shit.
I think he's world class.
And uh,
meanwhile that guy was ragdoll by Ben
[inaudible] who is the one FC champ
ragdolled.
Both of them were Korotkoff cough and
Lima Bolt Rag dog by aspirin.
Aspen's a motherfucker,
dude.
Yeah.
His minute.
Then another level.
Who,
when did he lose?
When did,
uh,
Douglas Lema lose to aspirin?
Put Up Lima's record again cause uh,
he did I fuck that up back in April,
2012.
Yeah.
See Lima's had some,
uh,
some serious injuries he's at.
He had serious knee surgery,
but uh,
that was quite a few years ago.
But then ask her and did that to him.
He did that.
The korotkoff he,
he's done that to a lot of dudes.
He gets a of those guys and just,
they look like world beaters until he
gets a hold of them.
You get two drags them lyman.
Good.
He did it.
The lyman good too.
Same thing.
It gets all of them,
dragged him to the ground,
beats the fuck out of them.
They can't get up.
It's just crazy.
And he's so relaxed.
When I saw him do that to somebody,
he's like riding.
I'm like a bowl,
like waving to the crowd.
People are booing.
He doesn't care.
He doesn't give a fuck.
It's crazy.
I mean,
I,
it's one of my most a perplexing puzzles
in mma,
but he fought when he fought in,
um,
Bella tour when Jay Hiran went over
there,
Jay Heran gave him a hell of a fight and
Jay Heron,
who was a very good fighter who didn't
do so good in the UFC,
but it was really talented and then went
over and had this fight with a acronym.
Beltour.
I mean,
Jay Heran was,
um,
you know,
a good wrestler with a little bit better
crisper striking than aspirin and magic.
Keep it on the feed lot and ask her,
had a real problem with that.
So that was one of those things where I
was like,
man,
I want to see him against world class
fighters,
know how to stop that take down against
a real good wrestler.
And those that have stuff to take down
who's his size?
But Michael Chandler just beat,
uh,
um,
Benson Henderson too.
They've got real talent over there now,
no doubt.
But it's still one of those things where
nobody watches it.
It's like you look at the ratings,
it's like they're lucky they get a few
hundred thousand well it's the human,
it's the human drama that people love,
you know the,
and the bigger that personality,
the more it's a celebrity of the more
interested you are in the fight.
You know,
like you get to understand this
character that conor mcgregor is and
it's part of the compelling nature of
watching the fight.
Like the personality people want to
identify with it.
It's like some,
I think it's the difference between a
good epic movie and a Shitty epic movie,
like a good epic movie.
You Fall in love with the characters
before the fucked up stuff happens that
propels them on their hero's journey.
You know,
you can't just go straight out of the
gate and show that that whole backstory
happen and then
he's all of a sudden kicking ass like
you want to be emotionally invested in.
Then every time they're swinging know,
swinging a sword or every time you're
watching them punch and take down your
way more invested.
And I think boxing did that with 24
seven the UFC has done that with all of
their embedded,
and I think that's just something that
they do better than anybody else.
They get you emotionally invested into
the fighter and then when you're there,
you know that's when,
that's when you really want to watch.
There's also those epic personalities,
those mega personalities that come
around around every few generations or
once a generation or a couple of times a
generation,
I should probably say like the Tyson's
or the sugar ray Leonard.
So the people that people were just so
compelled to watch,
and connor is just one of those people.
If he was inboxing and having the same
sort of success,
he'll be just as big.
He'd be gigantic if triple g had his
personality and my God,
Oh my God,
I mean Jesus Christ.
But triple g's not doing things the way
connor's doing things.
Not even close because connor has those
little gloves on and you know,
he's fighting mma,
he's,
he's landing these one shots like that.
Just stunned guys and have them rocked
and he's putting them away like he's got
lead in his hands.
Sort of a different thing.
Like you see his fight with Josie Aldo
that you very rarely see that happen.
13 seconds in a world championship
boxing match where someone connects with
one shot flatline.
Somebody that's in the realm of MMA
almost exclusively in early fights like
that.
It's so rare than in a championship
fight.
Someone knocked someone dead in 13
seconds,
but in the UFC can happen all the time.
I mean it just fucking happens.
There's a lot less armor on that button
on the lights out button.
Yeah,
less padding in there.
A lot harder to defend to.
It's easier to defend with those big
gloves.
Yeah.
There's so much going on with big gloves
versus small gloves.
You see guys that have devoted their
whole life to big glove defense and then
they come in in the small gloves just
don't offer the same sort of protection.
Even look at Nicky Hoskins,
main defense.
He gets in that kind of turtle posts
where he pretty much is covering
everything.
That's super important.
You know,
in his head with his gloves and forearms
and Yup.
Can't do that with a little gloves.
No you can't.
But see,
that's one of the cool things about
watching a guy like holt skins that he
can do that like with the big gloves,
like,
oh look,
we can do here.
Right.
You can't hit that guy.
Well,
he uh,
did you ever see his fight with Raymond
Daniels?
Two fights.
Walks him down,
man.
Just beats the legs up,
walks him down.
Starts beating the fuck out of him.
Yeah.
Just absorbs those shots.
Keeps Chop Chop chopping away.
He's a bad mother fucker,
dude.
There's a bunch of those guys now.
I just,
uh,
I just hope that it gets the attention
that it deserves because these guys are,
you know,
they're really risking their health in
such a dramatic way.
Well,
Whitney's working for glory now.
I saw Holla at miss two jets.
I saw that this is going to Germany.
We were in,
um,
we were in here and Joe Schilling and
Eve Edwards and I did a glory fight
companion and we're like,
oh shit.
I look away.
And if
your mother fuckers does,
she like it.
She likes it.
It's um,
you know,
just I,
for some reason I don't know what the
reason is,
but for some reason it's just never
completely like took root in America.
But it's not because of the talent.
I think it's,
again,
you got to tell the stories,
you know,
that's what people want.
You need to have invest way more in the,
in the pre fight,
you know,
video crew.
It's putting out these videos or get a
reality TV show.
So I think that's a genius thing that
the UFC did.
Cause you're exposing people to the
personality of these characters and then
when you watch him fight,
you care.
That's the fucking missing piece.
It's not,
I think they're always looking at how
can we improve the actual sport you got
to improve.
You know,
the people's access inside these
combatants.
And I think that's the,
that's the key.
You don't.
Another thing,
it doesn't seem like there's a number,
like a venue that is anything even
remotely like the venues that used to
exist just like 10 years ago as far as
like putting a fight on showtime or
putting a fight on hbo or putting a
fight on NBC seems like 10 20 years ago
you could've put Moitai on NBC at nine
o'clock at night at some crazy Moitai
night and people would have got hooked.
Like,
Whoa,
this is nuts.
But now it seems like there's so many
options for entertainment.
It's really difficult to like lock in a
substantial group of people just by
putting something on a certain time at
night.
Like they have so many choices.
Yeah,
there's almost too many choices where
almost like overrun with possibilities
to stare into the looking glass and get
chanted.
You know?
It's true.
And,
but I think ultimately that's our
salvation.
You know,
you get all of the choices and then,
then you can really decide what you
want.
You know,
I think we're going to be robots.
This is what I told him.
I really,
not just robots were that.
Anyways.
I think that's the cool part about
westworld is it's showing that like
where his robot,
whereas consciousness,
at what level,
and I think we're just a more
complicated version of that.
Yeah,
man,
don't spoiler alert.
I haven't seen the last episode.
Yeah,
I haven't seen the last ones next week.
That's okay.
I've seen all of them up till now.
I'm caught up,
but a lot of people listening aren't,
yeah.
Yeah.
I think before that ever happens before
there's a place where you can go and
interact with robots.
You're going to be one.
I think it's going to be way more likely
that you're going to take people that
have been injured,
like soldiers that have lost a limb in a
war,
they're gonna replace it with better
limbs than the first person is going to
offer to get their limbs cut off.
It's probably gonna be someone with a
disease where the limbs don't work so
well.
They get them cut off and then they win
the Olympics.
Just start jumping over buildings and
shit.
Next thing you know,
everybody's like,
why don't have these regular legs?
And then one day it's going to get to a
point where you can take your whole
brain,
take that brain sticking into fuck
another body.
I think it's not necessarily the brain.
I think it's whatever that that thing
that we call consciousness,
maybe that originates from the brain.
Maybe it's something something separate,
but the transfer of consciousness,
that's one of those archetipal stories
like a religious story.
The the shape shifter like you find in
so many cultures,
someone who can transfer their
consciousness to another vehicle.
I think that's definitely going to
happen.
Like we're going to be able to transfer
our consciousness into other things that
can hold that level of complexity.
You know,
like as long as it can hold that level
of complexity.
Like I think trying to transfer our
consciousness into a stinkbug would be
really challenging.
Obviously the brain and how it worked,
it's too,
it's putting something that's too big
and something too little,
but if something is of,
you know,
similar complexity,
I think we could transfer our
consciousness into there.
We just got to figure out what
consciousness is,
how you know,
how we measure it.
Somewhere in between the spaces of
quantum physics or maybe that's the
frontier.
Maybe it's somewhere,
but how we transfer that I think will
ultimately figure out,
and I think we know it and I think
that's why it's in all these stories.
They're going to work.
Yeah.
They're going to have conversations with
people.
They say,
hey man,
don't worry about it.
We made a copy of your brain so it
doesn't work.
We just put you back in your own body.
Yeah.
Like,
oh cool,
you made a coffee.
Yeah.
I mean it's copy from November 21st,
2016 do not worry.
Everything from here back.
You're not going to remember anything
from today,
but it's no big deal,
man.
You're going gonna lose a couple of days
of shit going on and you catch up,
get on your twitter or the top trending.
Just objects,
just rides and it goes out a body for a
little while,
stays current,
and then just drops back in.
Well,
now you're talking crazy.
I don't know why he of thing to the next
level.
I just feel like we're going to come to
a point where we figure out how to
express ourselves outside on language.
This is what I believe.
I believe that the intention,
like pure intention,
we're going to be able to broadcast that
through some form of third party
software,
hardware solution,
whatever it is.
Like there'll be able to figure out what
the actual intention of a thought is and
transmit that and so instead of a
sentence,
it will be a series of thoughts that you
can transfer the intention where you
know it without language.
You don't have to have a comprehension
of German to be able to communicate with
a person from Germany because you'll be
able to see whatever they're thinking in
pure intent or feel it or know it or
whatever the fuck it is.
And that's so much closer to truth than
language,
which is always just an approximation.
It's just a symbol for an idea.
Whereas if you could express in pure
intent,
you know like just the feeling of it and
I think that's also what you experienced
sometimes in in the psychedelic state.
You feel what you would think is God and
you can't fucking describe it.
All of the words fail.
Nothing that makes sense when you're
actually talking about it,
but you feel it.
And the intent of that thing is there
and then you just approximate it and
approximate it until it's almost gets
ridiculous.
And it is ridiculous because you can't
put that into words,
you know?
But you feel that and you only way you
really have a reference if you'd
experienced it as well.
Like you're saying this and I'm like,
I'm listening to you say this and I
agree with you.
And then I'm like,
man,
how would I describe it any differently
to somebody?
And I'm like,
well,
let's see what we got here for tools.
Oh,
they don't exist.
There's no tools in the toolbox that
allow you to explain like a really heavy
duty breakthrough dmt trip did.
They don't exist.
Like you can try to approximate it,
but you sang it.
I register it.
But it's only because I have what I
believe to be a similar experience to
what you've experienced.
And even that,
it's just guesswork.
Yeah.
And I'm assuming you're explaining,
you're explaining to me what went down
when you had it.
And I'm like,
well that sounds a lot like how I would
clumsily trying to explain my experience
but we don't know and you don't know.
Don't know.
And that's why we should go out and look
for yourself,
you know,
feel these things,
see these things,
experience these things.
But when you see burning man,
when you go to a place like burning man
and you see what's possible,
I mean obviously I haven't been,
but you've been a few times when you see
what's possible.
When these fucking freaks I'll get
together and rewrite the rules and go
crazy.
It gives you a lot of hope.
It really does because it makes you
realize like these are a lot of people
with normal people around us and yet
they're choosing in this one moment to
behave in this stark contrast to
everyday culture and society.
But there's no litter.
People are friendly with each other to
give it away food.
Like they're only doing it for short
bursts.
You know,
they're doing it for a week at a time.
Once a year,
but they're doing it.
They're still doing it.
And they didn't do it 30 years ago.
It didn't do it 50 years ago.
They're doing it now and they're doing
it in one spot,
but we're talking about it and people
were starting to get together and they
go,
well let's,
we could do this more often.
Like we can do something similar to this
more often proves the concept because it
changes your view of how an interaction
with a stranger could be.
It not somebody who's trying to take
something from you and fuck you up,
fuck up your energy,
whatever.
Like you're all in it together in some
weird way.
And obviously their shit heads at
burning man too.
But you'd get the overwhelming consensus
that you're all in it together.
And it's a,
it's a cool,
cool feeling.
Just transcends these kind of very solid
cystic.
I'll,
I mean,
I would even for myself,
these are my things,
this is my fortress that I build and you
just collapse all that and,
and surrender to a much,
much happier state.
And that's part of the magic.
I mean,
isn't that one of the more genuine
problems with any sort of egalitarian or
more altruistic vision is that people
are not going to reciprocate.
Like,
you know,
like if you could find a like minded
group of people where instead of the mob
mentality going fucking crazy and
grabbing swords and chopping each shop
each other out,
there's the mob mentality of peace and
love.
We're all just sort of everybody around
you sort of adopted this thing.
You know it really radical way that
we're in fucking goggles and riding
bikes everywhere and everything's lit up
a solar power and you're like,
Whoa,
these people are going deep with this.
Like everybody's embraced this,
so there,
so all in every fucking chip is on the
table when you're out there that it
reinforces this different and very
peculiar sort of mob mentality that's
psychedelic trip and,
and,
and happy,
you know,
and that that's possible too.
Like while we're watching mass rape in
India,
you hear about these horrible instances
where these men rape women on trains.
Like what the fuck is going on over
there?
While that's happening,
Bernie man's happening.
Yeah.
It's like there's another,
there's another sort of mob
consciousness that can erupt when it's
considered carefully applied ethically,
morally,
sensitively with an open heart.
Like that can be done to like,
there's a bunch of different states.
Again,
you apply to who,
you know,
a human goes into an environment with
love and radical acceptance.
True in in the truest sense.
You're going to more adapt to that.
Whereas you get in these systems of fear
and control,
you know,
you're going to adapt to that.
And I think anybody that we encounter,
we have that choice of what we're going
to give back to them and turn that tide.
And maybe it won't be reciprocated,
but it can also stop the,
it can stop that trend.
So if someone really,
you know,
if they do something fucked up,
and you can't prevent it and you have to
accept it and move on except that with
love,
show that person love and not this
desire for justice and revenge and
you'll start to switch the pattern.
You know,
you'll,
that's the only thing that ends the
cycle.
The only thing that ends the cycle
ultimately as love,
like violence,
you know,
you get something violent to you,
then you do something violent to them,
then you do something violent to you.
And it continues to go until one person
just holds like,
man,
I see your pain,
I see where you're coming from.
I see you as me.
You know,
I'm sorry you've had been driven to that
state.
I'm going to love you no matter what.
And then all the sudden that person's
like,
what the fuck?
And then it can end that cycle.
And I think that's what we gotta do in,
in society.
That's where we got to do the right and
the left,
instead of continually shooting these
barbs at each other.
At some point the conscious people have
to say like,
you know,
whatever you say,
I hear you.
I don't necessarily agree.
Here's my point of view,
but I'm going to love you.
I'm going to love you as if you were me.
And then that ultimately ends it.
But as long as we're just lobbing
fucking hand grenades at each other,
what fault?
Sounds like a bunch of hippy bullshit
that trump's gonna make a legal,
that's what I'm thinking.
I'm thinking he's throwing people in
jail for burning the flag.
We're taking it old school again,
folks,
old school,
you know,
uh,
the fake Tan that he uses is,
from,
uh,
he takes a native American graves and
the,
uh,
he takes the soil and that's what they
use for the fake Tan is the only way to
get it that perfect cue,
but you can't get it too close to your
eyes,
hence the raccoon look.
But it empowers you.
It gives you energy and such a great
supervillain move.
He just needs it.
Move trump tower,
inactive volcano,
move trump tower to an Indian burial
site,
put a trump tower up right where the
Dakota pipeline is being built.
One trump tower and just show the,
or just show redskins games were wearing
a red hat.
Make America great again.
What the fuck,
ma'am?
Hmm.
Strange Times Change Times,
but beautiful times.
They're the best times they are.
And the more we realized that the best
times,
the more we're going to be okay.
Like right now.
Yeah.
It is entirely possible.
We might get hit
by an asteroid the size of China.
It is entirely possible.
There are out there,
there's giant chunks of the world rather
was at one point time hit with another
planet that's established.
That's what they believe.
They believe the moon was created when
the earth,
we nearly collided with another fucking
planet that did sleek.
It's not happening right now though,
so right now it's just be nice to each
other and have some fucking fun.
Totally.
Let's go champ.
Yeah,
man.
If we can always figure out shit to
worry about,
we can figure out all of these things to
stress us out.
It's our job.
It's our relationship.
It's the fucking media.
If he's long as you enjoy the now,
you're not going to regret it.
If I go back and talk to my younger self
like,
hey young Aubrey,
if I could tell you one fucking thing,
it's to stress less like,
yeah,
think about the possibilities,
but then let it go.
Like enjoy your time because all there
is is the enjoyment of time.
You know all of these goals you have,
they're all false summits.
Like enjoy the whole process all the way
through.
Enjoy to that last moment where the
fucking Chinese size asteroid smashes
into,
enjoy up to that last minute and you
won't have any regrets.
Yeah.
If you can prevent it,
do that.
But if you can't do anything,
don't fucking stress.
Relax.
Yeah.
And then even realize that like goals,
they actually help you be happy.
As weird as it seems like achieving
goals and going after things and showing
yourself that through discipline and
focus,
you can achieve these weird creative
ventures.
Take things to new places.
Yeah.
It's the going for the competitor.
It's the going for the goal.
That's the best part.
It's not the actual achievement of that
goal makes you feel suddenly different.
It's that you're striving for making
progress and then you hit it and there's
that.
Of course that satisfaction,
but then you set another goal.
Yeah.
You know,
and then you set another goal and just
know that you'll constantly be setting
goals.
So if at no point you're ever happy,
unless you're achieving the goal,
you're only going to be happy if
fractional part of time,
unless you're with that transformer.
Watch getting his dick sucked over the
Atlantic elude.
You knew too.
He probably has those cheesy limo lights
inside of his jet where they change
colors all the time.
It's like purple,
green,
red,
yellow.
And he's in there with a bottle of Stoli
activate an eagle feather,
supervised Agora and Gorge Dick.
We're just got so much viagara system
has ears are ringing.
He hasn't breathe through his nose a
days.
He uses coke to open up his nose so that
he can breathe out of his nose while his
deck as hard as titanium.
Anything else?
Nope.
Shanice for me.
Um,
you want to talk about your Iowasca
experience or how long would that take?
I mean,
that's a,
it's a good 15 minute story and fuck it
man.
People are driving right now.
They're like,
keep going,
keep going.
Oh,
let's,
let's set this up.
Okay.
Last time I talked to you after you had
an Iowasca experience,
you were like,
dude,
I think I'm done.
Yeah,
Yeah.
It almost
done.
He's like,
I don't,
I think I'm good.
Maybe some little dmt trips here and
there,
but I think I'm done.
And then next thing I know you're off to
the fucking jungle again.
Let's go champ.
Exactly.
That's called change.
What happened?
Well,
one of the things that I enjoy is taking
people who haven't experienced it and
going there with them going like,
there's no better rite of passage
bonding experience.
So this time I just brought all of my
homies,
like everybody in my inner circle that I
love that wanting to go,
you know,
we all went.
And um,
so for me it's a lot about that kind of
rite of passage experience.
I still really like and appreciate the
plants and I learned a ton and I
sometimes underestimate how much more I
have to learn from the plants for sure.
I don't think so.
It was a combination of that.
Um,
so anyway was set up this trip.
Everybody I know we're going to do Iosco
we're meeting Don Howard,
who's,
you know,
we've done two documentaries with him
now.
Latest Iowasca documentary is with him
as well.
Awesome guy.
He's like Gandalf,
the white wizard.
So we're setting that up,
but I knew this one was going to get
interesting because a month,
about a month before,
sometime in August,
I wake up in the middle of the night,
we're going in September.
I wake up in the middle of the night and
um,
from a dream and in this dream I look
over and to my left side,
I see this demon head and this gnarly
looking demon head nosferatu looking
thing.
And he was just looking away and in my
dream,
he looks at me,
it's fairs at me dead in the eye and
goes,
I'm going to kill you on September 23rd.
Oh Shit.
Like super fucking specific,
right?
So I wake up and I'm a little freaked
out.
I was like,
damn,
that was specific.
So I go to my,
and I knew my Peru trip was over that
time.
I go to the calendar of events,
the itinerary and that night is the
night we're drinking IOWASCA for the
first time cause we were doing what
Chuma afterwards.
So September 23rd was the night we're
doing our WASCO.
And so do you start thinking your mind
was fucking with you?
Like for sure.
Like this is just your setting yourself
up for a fall.
Yeah,
I played out all the scenarios.
Right.
And I'd try to like what was that?
Maybe it was a metaphor.
Maybe.
Hopefully it wasn't for real.
Hopefully you know,
but,
and you know I,
maybe I might've known that date in my
head,
so I'm not trying to think this is
supernatural.
It's all kind of metaphor.
But it was very specific.
So by the time we get out there,
I knew that I had this feeling like,
man,
some shit's going to come up here.
Cause that was like something's in my
psyche that's incredibly specific about
this.
So we're going into ceremony.
And one thing I like to do to prepare
for ceremony,
and I do this for the whole group,
is they do a meditation where it anchors
them to their consciousness.
And I put that consciousness in their
heart,
right?
So cause the head can get really
squirrely and you can get lost in belief
in different ideas and thoughts.
And if you identify yourself as
consciousness,
which I,
I tell them to symbolize is a brilliant
piece of white light in your heart and
you symbolize that and you imagine that,
that there,
that's an anchor.
That's like your anchor,
that's your anchor to home.
And then,
you know,
I,
I talked to him how,
when you imagine that there,
then you can imagine it actually showing
up.
Atomically
like in,
in the rules of quantum physics,
the observer effect,
you observe it,
then it's connected to yourself,
all yourselves connected to all things
in space,
connected to the,
you know,
to the one source of consciousness,
the collective consciousness,
that thing.
And it just kind of anchors you and
keeps you in this feeling of safe.
So whatever's squirly things happening
in your mind,
you do that.
But this is important for the story that
I'm,
that I'm setting up.
Cause you know,
so I do that meditation and that's where
I go into the psychedelic experiences,
anchored to my heart,
connected to the cosmos,
connected to the infinite through that.
And it's a very kind of comforting,
comforting meditation to do.
So I'm going through and um,
I take the medicine and right off the
bat it's like super,
you know,
it's super chill.
Like I'm seeing beautiful scenes like
flowers,
these flowers of light.
And I get this message like,
hey man,
it's this,
this,
this one's going to be easy.
And I was like,
oh,
okay,
cool.
And is like,
we're just going to fix a few things.
So I felt like what it feels like all
these little doctors of light,
the doctor,
Cheetos,
you know,
these little light beings,
good going through my body and start
fixing little different areas,
fixing little parts in my head and
they're fixing little parts here.
And meanwhile my mind is being
distracted with flowers and butterflies
and it's super chill.
The only memorable vision I had was I go
to this shrine in this jungle and I see
this giant monkey human hybrid that's
super happy and it's like they're just
butterflies and everything going around.
And then in scripted in stone it says we
are the pleasure monkeys and that's what
have been,
have been using that word today and has
this like really cool thing like Oh
yeah,
we are pleasure monkeys,
we're here to enjoy all of the best shit
that we can.
And I start thinking about,
you know,
the foods and the people and the
camaraderie and everything around me.
Super Positive.
Meanwhile the light's going through my
body and fixing it and then you know,
as this really idyllic thing and I think
we're at an hour and a half and I'm
like,
fucking,
we're good.
Like whatever.
This demon was not going to worry about
it.
It's fine.
And then right to my left,
I see this gnarly looking Gollum,
Lord of the Rings Looking fucking my
precious knows fraud to demon guy.
And he looks at me and,
and I was like,
you know,
one of the practices that I have is
anchoring to that point in my heart.
You know,
I,
you know,
I encourage the feeling of
invincibility.
Like he can't be harmed,
you know,
this is your consciousness.
It's this peace in your heart.
It can't be harmed.
And I see this demon and it looks at me
and then it jumps,
jumps towards me and it starts biting my
neck.
Whoa.
In my vision.
Right?
So it's gnarly looking demon is biting
my vision.
No,
it's all like,
it's all in this like a movie of me
being played out.
Right.
I think you just going with,
but the emotion ratchet it up,
right?
So at this point,
you know,
I know it's eating in my,
in that vision,
it's eating through my neck and I see
what it's aim is and it's aiming to eat
through my neck and eat that thing in my
heart.
The white light in my heart that I've
been meditating about.
Like that's what it wants.
So in,
in what I thought was this like heroic
act of invincibility,
I was like,
go ahead man,
you want that thing?
Go ahead.
Eat all the way through me.
Get that thing,
it's fine.
You know?
Instead of,
cause I've learned in a lot of these
practices,
the more you resist these things,
the more aggressive they become and the
harder you just get in this,
this dance.
So it was more you surrender generally
the better off you are.
So it's like,
oh you want to eat that thing,
go for it.
So it goes through each through my neck,
through my chest,
and it grabs a hold of that piece of
white light in my heart,
snatches it.
And right at that moment I've never felt
more free.
I feel like I got shot with a bullet.
Like I felt like I went dead completely
dead and fear just shot through my
entire body and I was like,
Oh fuck,
I just gave this demon my consciousness.
I just gave this team in my soul and I
let them have it.
It's like all the fucking vampire
movies,
like they can't come in unless you give
them permission,
then you give them permission and all of
these fucking thoughts are going through
my head.
And meanwhile I felt completely dead,
like hollow from the inside.
Fear was that like 1000% and then the
eco rows of the sham and start getting
more intense.
And I'm like,
Holy Shit,
I'm fucked.
So I started negotiating with this
nosferatu demon guy and I was like,
man,
I'd really like to get my piece back.
Like you mind giving it back.
Like,
you know,
it's all good.
I understand you have your place,
you know,
for polarity to exist,
there needs to be the dark that needs to
be the light,
you know,
it's all good man.
We're all on the same team.
Ultimately we're all,
you know,
consciousness and the cosmos,
he's having none of it.
Right.
And then finally,
is he like he's,
yeah,
he's sometimes talking back and
sometimes just kind of like mocking me
really like kind of laughing and then he
goes,
here you go.
And it gives me something,
and I greedily like a,
like a hungry,
like a hungry child,
like grab it.
And I stuffed it in my heart and it was
dead piece of rock,
like a dead stone.
And it's just this demons just laughing
at me.
Now I have your heart and watch where
I'm going.
And he goes and he takes it and I'm
following him and he,
and you know,
through this kind of like wormhole thing
and he takes it and I see who he's
giving it to and then I go,
oh fuck.
Because he's giving it to the demon of
all demons.
And this is very archetypical and I'm
not religious,
but these archetypes are coming through
in this kind of,
you know,
demon,
Kibo type of sense.
But anyways,
this demon that he gives it to,
I can only call the world crusher
because literally he's of the size where
I'm seeing him hold planets and crushing
them into dust in his hands.
And he's just moving the cosmos.
These giant horns made of this deep,
dark black and red smoke and just
laughing in the ecstasy of destruction
as he takes galaxies and he rips them
apart like the ultimate black hole of
destruction and evil.
And I go,
fuck,
like that guy's got my heart piece now.
I like the little demon gave it to that
thing.
So I'm thinking like,
what the fuck do I do?
I can't even communicate with his demon
world crusher.
Like there's no way,
there's no way I can even talk to him.
He's too big.
So I try to like,
well maybe I can blow myself,
you know,
maybe I can get bigger.
I'm thinking like video game style,
like that's going to work.
Like maybe if I fucking get bigger than
we can talk and negotiate and I'll be on
his level.
Totally doesn't work.
I can't get even near the size of him
and my vision.
So I'm like,
fuck,
what the fuck do I do?
Like what am I going to fucking do here?
And,
and I get the idea,
I was like,
man,
I can't fight this thing.
There's no way.
But you know,
understanding that again,
that the consciousness in the cosmos
needs dark and light.
I understand the value of the polarity
of that something that dark,
you know,
I understand that that's necessary.
It's like,
man,
I got to send this thing love.
So I go and I imagine floating up to its
head and right between its eyes,
I kissed him on the forehead and it's,
I know it sounds weird and for a moment
I see his eyes go google the eyes,
like the Emoji heart thing where the
heart's appeared,
crushers eyes.
And it was really kind of cartoony.
And um,
for that moment he relinquishes and he's
like,
you know,
I can give this back to you,
but we never took it.
No one can take that piece of your
heart.
It's yours.
You know,
it's impossible to steal unless you
believe it can steal.
And it was just like beautiful wisdom.
And I was like,
oh my God,
thank God.
But I was still like shaken up by that,
you know,
I was still kind of fucked up,
but that move worked.
And in that moment where his eyes were
all googly hard,
she was like,
man,
we can't take that from you.
That's your,
so I had this renewed sense of
confidence and so I started kind of
going,
it was kind of more peaceful then it
grows,
seem to be falling.
My trip died down.
I'm going through about all the
relations in my life and the different,
you know,
kind of doing the general work you do on
Iowasca and I get to,
I'm a member of my family who's really
suffering from some mental illness is
really dark,
like a dark mental illness.
And I think that now maybe the world
crusher,
my friend.
So I get the feeling of the world
crusher has that element of darkness is
in him.
So I think in my imagination and,
and kind of call back on that,
on that being,
and immediately it comes up but in a
different shape,
like a giant fucking sea serpent.
And it's wrapping these tentacles around
my body,
like a Leviathan from the deep and,
and,
and I'm like,
whoa.
I was like,
um,
what do you think about maybe letting
you know this,
this family member,
what do you think about letting him go?
And he's like,
you want his soul?
I'll make a trade your soul for his.
And I was like,
fuck,
fuck that.
Fuck that.
Right.
So,
so at that point I was like,
man.
And then I was like,
I don't think I can make that trade.
He's like cower.
And you wouldn't do that for someone you
love.
You're a coward.
I thought you said you were invincible
and starts mocking me.
Clearly not my homie.
Like clearly take the world crashed,
takes his job seriously.
So eventually I have to go like,
you know what,
that's between you and him.
I can't step in there like there's
nothing that I can do for you.
So I just had to let it go and I let
them go.
Not Making that proverbial deal.
And again,
I don't think this is like really
happening.
This could just be an archetype,
right?
Of course.
But so anyways,
from there I was like,
fuck man,
this is turned super dark.
Like,
can I get some help?
Like in since the archetype was demons,
I was like,
can I get a Jesus in here?
Something like some kind of light and
nothing light would come.
Although I did get a cool vision of like
Jesus meeting the world crusher and I
was like,
Ooh,
this is going to be squared like
showdown UFC ultimate Jesus versus the
world crusher.
And immediately they turned super gay
and they started making out with each
other and having sex.
Jesus in the world crusher started like
having sex with each other and it was
so,
it was the wildest vision cause it was
this like the ultimate love affair,
like the two polarities of the cosmos,
like all of the love and forgiveness and
all of the power.
Who was the destruction.
The pack in darkness was the top,
the doctor's bag of Jesus.
Jesus would turn,
he was man woman.
It was like super.
He could be whatever he wanted,
but they were dancing in this like
passionate love affair,
which was like all creation.
So Jesus became man and woman,
Jesus man,
woman.
He was just,
it was just like love versus power and
darken and destruction.
Creation versus structured like the two
polarities dancing but expressed as the
world crusher is devil like creature.
And then Jesus,
you know,
which started as kind of Jesusy and then
went and a woman and then went into man,
whatever it was,
at least gave me a chuckle.
And it was like a moment of like relief
from this really fucking heavy trip.
But I still wasn't getting any personal
interaction from anything on the light
side,
you know?
And so I'm still like kind of a little
shaken up,
especially after,
you know,
the world crusher called me a coward and
I couldn't help you know,
this person in my family and it's like,
fuck.
Um,
so then I see this,
I keep trying to reach out to like the
helpers,
like something from the light and I get
this very faint message.
You know,
sometimes the visions are super clear
and sometimes they're faint.
It feels like you're,
you're kind of reaching for it.
But I'll go with that.
I'll use my imagination is a bridge,
so I kind of go with it.
It's like,
here we have this thing for you and put
it in your heart.
It'll give you extra,
you know,
it'll be what you're looking for.
And is this brilliant?
Ruby like redstone,
right?
It's brilliant.
Ruby stone.
And I was like,
Oh wow,
that's beautiful.
Like I always imagined the thing in my
heart being white but red.
All right,
it's cool.
I put it in my chest and then instantly
I could feel myself getting this like
hunger for power and feeling like the
world crusher,
like I wanted to destroy and manipulate
and I was like,
Oh shit,
that's not the thing.
You know,
that's not,
that wasn't a real gift that was getting
tricked again.
So I pull this thing out of my heart and
for sure like I can just feel the evil
emanating from it,
right?
And I can hear the distant laughter,
the world crusher,
like,
ha ha ha fooled you again.
You accepted this stone.
And so I have this ruby stone in my
vision.
I'm like,
what the fuck am I going to do with
this?
All right,
so I have this place that I've developed
in my meditation.
It's like a little hat.
It's like my happy place,
right?
It's place.
I go and I imagine it in my mind,
it's like my happy place.
So I was like,
all right,
I'm gonna put my stone in my place and
I'm gonna leave it there in my,
in my vision.
Why put it there and the happy place and
it turns to fucking like swamp and bog
and everything.
All the trees are withering like you see
in one of those fantasy movies where the
darkness anchors into a place and all
the life dies around.
And I was like,
fuck man,
I can't put it there.
It's going to destroy this,
this world I created.
It's like I bring it back and I was
like,
I hear this voice,
like just put it in your heart.
You can hold it.
You're strong enough to hold it.
So like,
okay,
yeah,
maybe my heart is the only place I can
put it.
It's the only way it's gonna be safe.
Put it back in there.
Bad idea.
Obviously that was another trick.
But I'm really getting shaken here
because I keep getting fucking tricked
and I keep not knowing what my mind is
telling me that's helpful or whether
it's coming from something else.
So eventually I would like move it out
of my body and I'm looking at it,
I was like,
fuck.
The only way that I can get rid of this
is to dissolve it evenly across the
entire spectrum of creation.
Right?
Take this and dissolve it into the all
so that the entire game,
all of good,
all of bad,
everything can hold this amount of evil.
It's too concentrated for any one thing
to hold.
I got to dissolve it.
And I tried that move with my
imagination and it worked.
Boom.
And the red stone dissolves.
And then all of creation holds that
darkness and that power.
And I'm sitting there and I just,
at this point just fucking surrender.
Like I've just been totally getting my
ass kicked,
you know,
for the majority of this trip.
And especially just having been tricked
and,
and I'm just kind of like in a state of
surrender.
And at that point I feel like kind of
like iron man style,
I feel this like breastplate,
like come slap onto my chest and it has
this really beautiful fire opal stone.
And this thing is helmet come on,
my head pink and his helmet comes and it
has this other brilliant white light and
I feel wings shoot out from my back.
Right.
And it's obviously,
it's,
I lost,
it's shit's crazy.
And,
and I'm flying in the air and there's a
bunch of like eagles and other birds and
it's all like peaceful and all good.
And it was like all of the allies,
like all of the good guys,
all the good team Kinda came through and
they were flying over this world that
was dark and fires and pollution and
chaos.
And they were just bringing this like
fresh air of like white light.
And I was just cruising.
And so for the last 30 minutes of the
trip,
I was just literally like flapping my
wings in division,
just Kinda cruising over the world with
all my ego.
Homeys and,
and it was fucking one of the GNARLIEST,
obviously experiences I've ever had.
No doubt.
That's why it's illegal.
But your speech is going to be used in
the Senate.
They're going to get together with
Congress.
They got to play this speech back.
This is a successful guy,
folks.
Look what he's doing.
Yeah.
It goes down with the God damn jungle
fighting world crushers and Jesus's Gay.
Do you want Jesus to be,
you want that?
Oh Geez,
give me a woman.
Jesus can be a man.
He can be a woman.
He's gender fluid.
Yup.
Wow.
And tense.
And again,
I think the lessons necessary,
it's really just about,
that was the type of resistance that
could summon the very best out of me.
You know,
the move to move to show the world,
Krush her love the move to,
you know,
all of the moves that I had to make.
I was only able to learn about myself
from the extreme pressure of that
vision.
And that's one of the beautiful parts of
the IOWASCA vision.
It tends to give you just enough that if
you show up with your best and you and
you choose,
you know,
choose love and you choose the,
the things that are going to bring out
the best outcome,
you'll make it through,
but it,
but it brings you to that very fucking
brink where it feels like,
man,
you know,
the stakes are really,
really high.
It's interesting because I think stories
like that
and experiences like yours,
although you've got to go somewhere to
experience them legally,
the those stories are what people are
going to rely.
That's like almost like a road map of
the potential experiences that people
are gonna come back with and go to,
dude,
look what he's saying about this.
Do you want it?
Do you want to go there?
Do you want to go?
How do we get there?
You got to go over the mountain.
You go over the mountain to meet the
world crusher.
Fuck man.
Okay.
He definitely came back.
Yeah,
he's back,
man.
He's in Austin.
He's hanging out.
Yeah.
Like one day,
all this stuff is going to be legal and
one day all sorts of psychedelic
experiences,
whether it's masculine or fucking
mushrooms,
whatever,
they're all going to be really
commonplace.
They're going to be as commonplace is
going to get a massage or it's common
places,
you know,
taking a yoga class.
Just right now we're in a weird place
where someone like you tell him that
story seems like a crazy person.
Yeah.
You know,
even talking to me who's experienced a
bunch of shit,
you know,
and I've experienced a bunch of shit
with you.
I mean,
I know you're not,
I mean you're not crazy.
You're just relaying this very odd thing
that very few people who are ever going
to be able to relate to right now,
but one day,
one day it'll be real common and I think
it's more common now.
I think when you,
you saying this now way more common,
do you talk about Iowasca and people
understand what you're saying then?
Just 10 15 years ago,
you know?
Oh,
no doubt.
Because people have had similar
experiences of reference.
I mean,
I think the way that a lot of people
experience this is in archetypes that
you learn about and there's a different
character in the story.
You know,
which something you can learn from like
the Harry Potter movies,
like,
uh,
like Jordan was talking about,
you know,
you can learn from those archetypes,
but it's different when you know,
you get a chance to play as the main
character playing is the main character.
It gives you a whole different series of
lessons.
Like none of these themes that came up,
you know,
our original themes,
these are all deep archetypes.
Even fucking the Lord of the ring,
like the stone,
it was a stone of such evil.
How does it be destroyed?
It destroyed in the fire from whence it
came,
right?
All of creation created in concentrated
and there was dissolved in that.
I didn't think about it then,
but I could see the analogies.
You see the,
um,
the deal with the devil.
You know,
that,
that I'll trade my soul for this one.
You see these archetypal,
but you
know,
I can watch as many faust places I want.
I'm never going to feel what that feels
like,
right.
Until I have the devil mocking me for
being a coward,
for not being willing to make that deal.
You know?
And then you understand these certain,
these certain things in a much,
much deeper way.
And,
and that's,
that's,
I think the value.
It just puts you up in this situation
where you're,
you have stake in the game and you have
choices to make,
and that's where you get the real value.
I think Roger Huerta would've put that
world crushing in a Thai clinch and
slash or right into is fucking stupid
phase for sure.
And that's part of it.
You know,
some of the Shamans,
that's their move,
right?
They're constantly trying to get mastery
and dominion over all of these things.
Wow.
I just find that the more you try and
fight with them,
the more they just love it.
Do you like whatever thing you're trying
to fight,
whatever darkness you're trying to
fight,
the more you fight with them.
They're just like,
fuck yeah,
bring it on.
This is what I do.
You're in my house now,
bitch.
You know,
like you're trying to wrestle with Ben
Asker and like they got the drop on you,
but the minute you change the game and
recognize them as an important part and
send them love,
that's when the conflict ends.
One day.
Ladies and gentlemen,
you too.
We'll be able to go to your local
IOWASCA center and partake and it's
already been approved by the Supreme
Court for a couple of different churches
to different churches I believe.
Right?
Yeah.
And you mentioned center diamond and uh,
uh,
udv.
Yeah.
And they are legally allowed to serve
super high potency IOWASCA.
Yup.
Over Rick Strassman went over there and
did it with him.
He said it was incredible.
They're all wearing like golf shirts,
Hawaiian,
White,
sit up,
sit down,
talk to do different things.
Yeah.
It's all common,
you know,
whether it's religious or whether it's
medical or whether it's,
I think the plants are going to show up
when humans need the help the most.
And I think that's,
that's the spot we're in.
And you know,
I wasc,
it's not for everybody.
Like don't everybody rush out and do it.
Like do it.
If that's what's really calling for you.
If you want to learn more,
I just released that documentary.
It's free.
Just go to drink the jungle.com.
That's the url.
Drink the jungle,
check it out.
Um,
and get an idea if that's for you.
But there's so many ways and you don't
need to do plants.
You can do with your fucking breath.
You can do it with Yoga.
You can do it with floating.
You can do it with legal weed.
You know,
there's so many ways to climb the
mountain.
Um,
but finding those,
those ways to bring out the best part of
yourself.
Essential drink the jungle pigeons.
Don't be scared to drink to drink the
jumbo.
Don't be scared to drink jungle.
Spicy.
All right,
let's end this right.
That's perfect.
Drink the jungle.com.
Yeah,
that's it.
Bye everybody.
Love you.
Love all you guys.
You fuckers,
you.