Hello,
sweet pitches.
That's right.
The time has come.
Once again,
our I should fear as eaton box.
This episode is brought to you by legal
zoom.
Legal zooms away,
a convenient way to deal with a lot of
your legal shit that you would normally
have to go to a lawyer to deal with it
online and deal with it naked can be
drunk.
Nobody can stop you.
You could.
You could say after everything that you
write lies,
you can say that lie.
You can say your call Phil.
Yeah,
you could.
You could curse the world,
curse God himself as you're signing
legal documents.
You could be having sex and getting an
LLC at the same time.
No one can stop you.
You have ultimate freedom because this
all exists in the virtual world.
You don't have to worry about pulling
your cock out at the lawyer's office.
Like what if you were cool with paying
your wife divorced money,
but you wanted to jerk off as you signed
the check.
Yeah.
Just to remind yourself of what a
pathetic fucking full you are.
You get trapped in these terrible
relationships that you'd wind up being
financially committed to these people
that you really never got along with
ever for the rest of your fucking life.
And so as you're writing that down,
you just jerk off all over his desk.
I bet someone want to do it.
Can't do it,
but you can do it at home.
You can get divorced at home while
jerking off.
No one can stop you.
You can,
um,
you can get a will for $69 bucks.
You can incorporate or form an LLC
starting at 99 bucks and nine slash ll
say once you're all so you can do
whatever the fuck you want.
The environment no one can see you face
is totally about community.
It's like that.
It's a limited liability company.
Limited liability.
It's interesting.
Probably should be illegal,
but uh,
if,
if it exists,
you called it,
they're just like that and how we can
come to us.
Yeah,
I'm legal.
Nine out of 10 people that have used
legal zoom,
we recommend the service to family and
friends and you get a special discount
from listening to this podcast.
Make sure you enter Rogan in the
referral box at checkout for more
savings.
And legalzoom is not a law firm,
but they can connect you with a third
party attorney and provide you with self
help services and third part attorney
things.
Probably pretty important,
independent third party attorney.
So if you fucking freak out and you're
like doesn't illegal,
I'm going to prison.
You call the attorney and they calm
down,
please calm down,
dude,
you're gonna be fine.
Here's how you do it.
Did $12,
million,
uh,
12 years rather over 2 million Americans
have used legal zoom.
That's um,
that's awesome.
So legal zoom,
go there and people use the codeword
Rogan.
Yeah,
it's a lot of fucking people.
It's like,
it's,
it's annoying to have to go to a
lawyer's office and do it on their time.
And you know what,
if you work,
we're down.
When I worked at a law firm,
they build my hours at 25 bucks an hour
to the clients.
When I did Xerox thing for 12 bucks an
hour,
they made through legal zoom.com.
He was the codeword Rogan de de,
De,
de.
We're also abroad.
You buy naturebox.
Naturebox is our latest sponsor.
They send you a delicious and nutritious
snacks.
They are better than sugar or heroin.
It's better than math for sure.
Yeah,
they're healthy.
What?
Listen,
it's their snacks,
their carbohydrates.
You know,
there's like rice cakes that I had some
rice sticks.
They were good.
They're delicious.
No Trans fats.
It's a lot more healthy than some shit
that you're going to get out of a
fucking vending machine and some of them
are really delicious Granola,
the salted caramel pretzel pumps.
Those are fucking really delicious.
Some of those that you have over there.
I got the harvest rice text way.
I'd have to try those for later.
Here's one important thing.
They have zero.
Excellent.
Zero high fructose corn syrup,
nothing artificial.
And the honey digital pretzels.
Very good too.
They're yummy.
Yup.
And uh,
it's,
it's better than,
you know,
people do give into temptation when you
don't have options when your only option
is that vending machine and his candy
bars in it,
you'd go with one of that and you feel
like shit.
And this is a way to get snacks that
are,
that are yummy and they're good for her.
Then they're just,
they're not total shit.
Like most of the stuff.
Cheetos and shit like that.
Not that those aren't awesome.
Pretty bad for you though.
Yup.
Not Good.
I lived next to a pink dot.
I just go down there when I got home.
I remember eating cheetos one time.
You and I went to pink dot and we were
uh,
we were eating subs,
subs.
He still have a look at that.
They still have that they do and they're
awful.
Well,
they were good at one point.
Some of them were good.
I had an Italian there that was pretty
good.
But uh,
and I eat all these fucking cheetos.
I must've ate like a giant bag of
cheetos and I felt so bad.
My body was like,
did you do that last?
A little bit of a mouth pleasure.
You fucking ruined the whole body for
hours and hours during your whole body.
Just like leds.
This,
that you just shoved in the machine.
You asshole cheese puffs.
It says unlimited.
This is not the shit you're supposed to
put in your own notebook.
My pleasure.
Well,
these are good for you and they're not
going to give you that feeling.
Uh,
just healthy things like Granola,
a dark cocoa,
almonds which are delicious,
and a naturebox ships for free,
just like nature to us.
I don't know what they mean by that.
To try and try and try to understand
what the fuck they mean ventures just
for fruit.
Now you have to go to nature and pick it
up.
It doesn't to ship.
Live in nature.
Nature shifts or freeze.
If you're talking about pollen,
pollen is,
are there any products?
I'm box.
I don't think we sell poem.
I don't think you're selling
fallen over birds.
Yeah.
You guys got to get rid of that part.
Naturebox hips for phrase to say chips
for free.
That means it doesn't mean anything.
Someone wrote it and they just
shouldn't.
They should have said that.
That's ridiculous.
Next box,
they just forgot.
They probably just left it on there and
no one said anything and it got passed a
bunch of people that weren't that
stringent and they let it slide.
It doesn't ship for free son.
That shit's ridiculous.
Doesn't make any sense.
Nature's blocks were never on her.
Period.
What'd you say?
Nature's blocks when you were never on
her period.
I don't even like box box box or be
better than chips for free.
We're never on our period and now I got
it.
I got pregnant.
Nature's box.
You can come in us.
Don't worry about it.
Shoot one in their junk box.
Don't worry about naturebox.
If you listen to me most sober one,
you don't want to use these slogans.
Naturebox,
shoot one in there.
This whole way to apple.
Picky bars are delicious and they can't
get you breakfast box.
She went in there right now.
Your first order of naturebox,
get 50 percent off it by going to
naturebox.com/Rogan.
That's naturebox.com.
Slash Rogan,
get a handle on your health and your
hunger.
Go to naturebox.com/Rogan
in.
Hey Shit.
Went in there.
That's not herpes.
That's lemon tea post.
Don't worry about it bitch.
Walk it off.
Walk it off at naturebox.
Were also brought to you by on it.com,
o n n I t if you haven't been to on it.
And while we've added a lot of things,
continue to add things that,
uh,
mostly just things that we find that are
beneficial.
Uh,
the idea of on it is a human
optimization website.
What that means is we sell strength and
conditioning equipment and supplements
and protein powder,
hemp protein powder,
but just sell things that we find that
we find that are beneficial.
Um,
these kettlebells that we have made,
we have a artistic talent kettlebells to
the Zombie bells and the primal bells
and what they are is kettlebells that
looked bad ass.
They look like their sculptures.
They're made by this kid,
Steven,
this kid,
these young kids these days with her
artistic talent.
Man,
he might not be a kid on he didn't know
his name his age.
Uh,
Steven Shubin Jr.
He created the primal belt.
YeaH,
the monkey one and apes.
And then he also did the new ones which
are zombie bells.
They're all balanced out because one of
the things about a kettle bells is it's
all about swinging this ball.
There's heavy steel ball and it's all
about balancing it and controlling it.
And if the ball was off,
like with these faces,
it could easily be off.
So we had them.
A part of the artwork is that they had
to be three d to make sure that they
still are a kettlebells that you can
train with with no problems.
I train with mY guerrilla all the time
and it's,
you can work out with it just like a rug
or kettlebell.
You just have to be cognizant of where
the head is facing,
but you should know that anyway and
you'd be fine.
But I trained with them my favorite all
time exercise for strength and
conditioning.
And I don't even mean if you're an
athlete,
if you're an athlete,
they're fantastic.
I mean,
they're really great for also for
educating your body to work as one unit.
you know,
carrying a heavy,
heavy kettle bell into and things like
cleans and presses and things along
those lines.
Um,
but it's Also,
they're great for regular life.
They are great for just being able to
pick up a couch and help move it.
They're great for.
It's better to have a body that works a
little better.
A body that can be strong body that it
doesn't break when you try to bring home
groceries,
get your shit together,
bitch.
That's what I'm trying to say.
I like that.
That little bitch at goblins,
not even his army.
The little one is a goblins over there
saying brian brains.
Obgyn gardens.
Brain zombieland bring goblin.
I think it's a.
I think that's still a zombie dude.
It goblins zombie,
but I shouldn't have.
They should have one that's shaped like,
it looks like a pretty girl going to
work.
Yeah.
It's.
I mean this doesn't look like it goes
face thrilling.
Like funny name but doesn't look like a
zombie to you.
That looks like a zombie.
That doesn't quite get ghost.
No.
No ghost ghost there.
That's solid mass.
Yeah.
That's mad.
You can't see through that shit.
You know,
it's frankenstein and ship anything.
Yeah.
That's a zombie dude gobble.
Oh wait.
Zombies are the ones that know that.
Yeah.
It's definitely not a ghost.
Well,
can't go look like anything who can say
you can see through it goes,
you know what's fucked up man?
It's really fucked up what they've done
with vampires.
What do you mean they've given new rules
to like vampires?
Oh really?
You can go out in the sun as long as
seattle.
Well,
two people did it.
It happened twice.
Once it happened with blade,
which I forgave.
It was.
Why was he a day walker?
He's half vampire.
He was born,
his mom.
He was born and he became half vampire.
Not like totally vampires,
some weird sort of hybrid thing.
But uh,
so stephen dorff was the main vampire
tooth and
could go outside with sunscreen.
Oh really?
Yes.
Ridiculous.
That's the worst.
No you can't.
No,
you better have magic or something.
He can't just fucking put sunscreen on.
You're a vampire man.
You,
you burn instantly.
Hey,
we wrote this when he's outside during
the day,
like we'll figure it out.
Writer.
I don't remember that from the comic
book either because blade was a favorite
comic book of mine.
I was always a big comic book fan.
I love blade.
I don't even remember as a comic book.
Oh,
he was awesome.
He would fight fucking fight vampires
and shed.
He used to teach knife in those,
uh,
those books.
It was cool when he showed up at that
party,
it was cool to look.
Man I know was supposed to fight that
guy.
But I'm a wesley snipes fan.
I think he was awesome.
He's in prison now.
He's out now.
He's back doing movies again.
He,
uh,
he was awesome in blade.
Yeah.
Apparently he was completely craZy by
the time blade to I guess come rogan use
a codeword rogan.
This is,
we're obviously doing a podcast when
fuck the music man.
Our experience here,
we don't have to do this.
The um,
by the time he was doing like blade two
or three,
apparently he was off the handle.
PaTton oswald has wrote a whole blog
entry about it on meeting.
I'm describing it,
describing,
uh,
he might've performed it somewhere.
He,
he might have performed it,
I'm not sure,
but we're hearing about it.
I thought,
holy shit.
It was crazy.
It was like Ryan O'neal and him.
And apparently this was.
Wesley was like,
he was gone.
He was,
you know,
just off the deep end,
crazy on the set.
And so they replaced him with what
patent called much cooler black guys.
They replaced him with another guy,
did the martial arts stuff and yeah,
because I couldn't deal with them.
I don't know.
I don't know what the fuck happened.
Why wasn't he already sort of a movie
star?
He went crazy in between there and there
are probably some substances were
involved.
It's always that.
It's usually,
it's always that.
Yeah.
Then you see them like taken whatever.
You're like,
oh,
oh.
It's also,
I don't think we can imagine what it's
like to be that famous.
I think for some people it's just.
And then you get hooked up with the
wrong people in your life and you're
fucking around with the wrong friends
and getting in trouble.
So many of them.
Elvis.
Yeah,
it's,
it's a well,
the nature of the business,
like if you're a fucking person who's in
the limelight that heavily,
like the nature of the business becomes
very bizarre.
You know the nature of your reality.
You're getting around.
Everyone treats me like a,
like a,
like a commodity.
What we were talking about justin
bieber,
like how justin bieber,
the kids everywhere he goes,
people fucking freak out just to see
him.
Like,
oh,
he's like,
it's some weird alien.
You know,
we,
we can't imagine what the forum now sort
of in a way.
I mean,
it's not an ideal way to live.
It seems awesome.
Like don't feel bad.
He's got all this money,
but know it's so crazy,
like burden to throw on some bread.
Totally told me he got into an elevator
with Jessica Simpson and she,
she turns to the woman who's with us
because he's not supposed to be in here.
Human.
Yeah.
It was just going up through whatever
his room and he was in no way.
Oh my god.
Yeah.
Well,
you know what though?
How do you start expecting that?
It is totally wrong,
but in her defense,
to be her as a woman and be super duper
super famous,
she must be so vulnerable.
IT must be weird to the opportunity to.
For a guy to get in an elevator with her
like men want.
She's not used to it so much.
There's so many men who like and a guy
who knows that he could probably
physically take advantage of her and
can't believe that he's in her presence
and attract environment,
like an elevator really creep.
He would go to town.
He could.
Who would ravage her?
Be horrible.
I mean now you're much more vulnerable
as a woman if you're that super famous.
If you think she puts in a writer when
she goes to a hotel is like,
okay,
but you got to let him know,
no one can ride with me.
No,
you can't do that.
She might have rules at her security
follows security,
security.
She might have rules like she doesn't
want security to let anybody in the
hotel lobby with her won't let anybody
in the elevator with.
I don't know.
she might,
but it's like people don't have to
listen to that normal after that.
No one's allowed to be in the elevator
with you.
Well,
here's the thing about like you and I is
that we're were standup comedians and by
being a stand up comedian,
you're all the time forced to look at
everything,
interrupt you,
looked at yourself,
you look at yourself,
you look at like what you're saying.
You look at the world around you,
you're looking for jokes and things.
You look for jokes and yourself.
You look at for jokes in your own life.
A lot of people don't do that ever,
so they're not thinking ever thinking
about their behavior.
They just doing what they can get away
with and they're acting is fucking loony
tunes often as they can get away with it
is as they continue to get away with
more and more looney tune shit or got
worse and worse,
but that's what the whole diva thing is
all about.
Man,
I mean,
she has so much power to yell and scream
at people like,
why?
Why do you,
why is that?
What's going on there?
I said,
rosetta,
every year,
every year she got,
she had our show.
There's just fired more show runners.
She was on the podcast talking about it.
Really?
Yeah.
it's just like talking to people.
When she talked about how crazy she
went.
Really?
Yeah.
She's pretty open about it,
you know?
I mean,
she's essentially saying what you're
saying.
She's sAying that nobody can handle it.
It's too after another.
They all fall.
It's too hard to be,
but there's no way.
No way.
There's no way.
Yeah.
I've been trying to rush people.
You're scrawny so young too,
you know,
for him to be so young and that habit to
them,
it's fucking wild ride,
man.
That's not a normal ride of life.
You're not a man yet.
You're a child and you're adored.
That's not supposed to happen that way.
You're supposed to feel insecure and see
how they become the joffrey.
Oh yeah,
exactly.
Exactly.
I mean,
he's raised in that.
I'm sure he's not.
I'm sure a lot of it is exaggerated.
He seems like a nice kid.
I met him once.
I shook his hand.
Is dancing in the ufc.
Yeah,
I mean it seems like a nice treat.
Trump tremble.
what do I know?
I didn't know.
It wasn't until I was shaking his hand
like as I was shaking his hand,
I was like,
I was saying her kid,
this was a while ago,
but he's much more famous now than even
he was then.
Oh,
I keys like in some crazy stratosphere
of fame thing now,
but I think we like jesus.
No,
no,
no.
He was just a nice kid.
Just came over and I realized as I was
shaking his hand that it was justin
bieber,
but just said this was like two years
ago.
Probably two,
maybe might even be three,
but nice.
You know,
it's nice as an all well and good,
but idiot man.
Being able to handle that kind of fame.
I couldn't imagine how anybody could not
elvis it.
Peggy,
there's no way.
It seems like there's no way.
It seems like your,
your reality.
Just so bizarre.
Yeah.
If you are just entitled to something,
you were just like,
alright,
I'll take it.
Yeah.
Do you think they're just picking on him
to a point where like,
I mean they're like making new stories
of him peeing in a mop bucket and
they're,
they're making new stories of him being
a 21 year old egging his neighbor's
house.
Oh no,
no,
but it iS real.
But I mean when I was 21,
right.
That's what we all did.
We all did.
But a 21 year old that's got
$500,000,000
or whatever it is.
God,
that becomes more interesting when they
get mad at them in a bucket.
You got thAt much money.
He's got to pee in the house.
The egging,
the house thing.
I kind of disagree.
I don't think there's anything wrong
with that.
Yeah.
I don't think there's anything wrong
with that being a story.
I think that's a real important story.
Yeah,
I agree.
But he got caught,
but it's like that is.
But like all these other things are just
like,
well,
yeah,
you're 19 and slutting it up.
Yeah.
You're from the south,
of course.
That's perfect on on target.
I bet you if you were hanging out with
him,
it would be just like hanging out with
your friends.
Oh,
you want to smoke weed?
Oh dude,
let's get a little faster than the car.
Oh,
let's do this.
And then you have all those things that
you've did.
they've made stories out of all these
little minor details and made it like
every time you go on tmz,
it's something stupid.
Like bieber did this,
he flicked off.
There was smoke coming out of his
carly.
He becomes the show.
See the problem is like when,
when you step out like that and you
drive in a chrome car and he's.
What he's doing is he's stepping out,
he's racing lamborghinis and miami and
he's getting fucked up here and he's
getting fucked up there and he's having
fun.
He's having a great time.
I bet he's having a great time.
he's doing the best I've ever imagined.
A 19 year old kid could do with a half a
billion dollars.
He's doing great.
Like leave him alone.
His dad's around them all the time.
Right.
I don't know what story,
I'm just trying to make good music,
dude.
What the fuck should I do?
He's having a blast is what has
happened.
But boy,
he's on a crazy rocket ship ride.
There's no way he's strapped to the,
to the head of like a missile and shot
through the sky and it's like,
wow.
The fucking,
you know,
the ride fast and very exciting.
But the lending,
what is the lending going to be like
them out like a,
like a virgin anymore.
Well,
how are you going to keep this?
I mean,
how long are you going to keep balling?
how long can you keep balling that hard?
It's
got a chrome car.
He's 19.
He's going to throw an exit.
Is fucking neighbors house.
Shirley temple retired at 21.
Whoa.
She was like,
I'm getting out of the business.
living off residuals.
Whoa.
She lived a normal life.
Wow.
That's crazy.
Yeah,
I feel like 10 years.
Nobody even fucking bother.
Wow.
Huh?
That might be the move.
Just like,
cool.
I get it now.
I'm good.
I'm set on this.
Let me just,
uh,
working on my painting.
I don't know,
man,
you know,
as,
as you see more and more instances of
people that get that super stratosphere
fame and more and more.
Michael jackson's,
you know,
Michael Jackson to me is the most
fascinating character study on human
beings that I've ever witnessed because
I think he is.
He never went down and faint.
Well I guess sort of he kind of did it
and then didn't.
Then we started sort of still in the mix
because people didn't want to believe
that he was a child molester.
Nobody wanted to believe it.
Dude,
that guy,
it became a fucking freak.
He became a monster.
He became a monster monster.
He became a monitor into a monster.
He became this white skinned vampire
like guy with alien eyes pick nose.
He had his.
Yeah,
he had his eyes worked on to the point
where his eyes were like really big and
why it was weird.
He had a bunch of weird shit done to his
face.
He had a temple,
put it in,
play the superbowl,
and he denied ever having anything done.
Yes,
yes,
yes.
He denied having anything done like went
to have my nose fixed,
but that was because something went
wrong and then he pretended to have a
baby with somebody.
Yeah.
What was that?
And the kids came out white with one
with one with elvis's daughter to live
baby with her.
Well,
no,
no.
He didn't have a baby with her,
but uh,
he had with this one woman supposedly
she was pregnant with his kids and the
kids came out totally white.
Totally white.
Completely white.
Like it's one of the weirdest things
ever and I guess you're supposed to do.
I don't know what you're supposed to
question and believe in him.
I don't know the guy.
Do you remember when he was going
through that?
When he's doing the interview in vegas?
There's going through that.
Like store?
Yes.
It was like,
totally,
you know,
the famous pretty nice.
I'll have to have those plays and this
guy behind there's lyric just like,
all right,
that's $200,000
was $150,000
each.
There's a toweling it up.
You just keep going.
Yeah.
Doing the interviewing.
Ordering shit.
Just walKing through,
it was kind of like a cry for help,
man.
Sort of.
that video was kind of like a cry for
help.
What did that kid say?
This is that guy that's saying that
Michael Jackson molested him when he was
a kid and now he's like trying to get
money out of this state state saying you
waited too long to add,
so it's not as funny anymore.
It's our money.
What do you think though,
man?
You know,
there's also the possibility that he
didn't molest kids or he.
There's nothing I know about the world
that would say that that's a realistic
possibility,
but yeah,
it was.
Could it be that people were trYing to
take advantage of a guy that's just
fucking really weird?
Yeah.
Maybe that's the only way people aren't
like at his door with pitchforks is as a
possibility while he's dead it a door
today.
No,
no,
no.
He died the weirdest death.
However.
Yeah.
the guy who's taking this with me
getting put under every night and that's
how he's going to send someone to jail.
Yeah.
You imagine humanity,
you take it to the next level of sleep,
you're getting fms,
the tie to yourself to be okay.
How about sleeping pills?
So that's telling to fit in like a
nightmare.
Well,
uh,
I just think if we just let michael,
if you just lay your head down,
just count sheep for a little bit of.
Well that's tells me you're not
listening to me.
Try it without the stuff.
Yeah.
He wasn't willing.
He wasn't even willing to endure that.
Nope.
We're not going to be staying up another
night.
Ties me and their doctor was so crazy.
He just did it.
He was getting paid so much fucking
every night,
but it was,
I guess that's super bad for you.
I guess you're not supposed to ask.
It seems like that would be a no
brainer.
Like do you sleep?
Yeah.
So not really.
I wake up more refreshed.
Moistened had a side effect of that
particular type of anesthesia is like,
no,
you,
you wake up and you feel refreshed.
It's like there's some sort of a trick
to it.
Oh really?
I'll have to like 30 minutes.
I kind of remember reading that I should
probably pull it up.
I think there was a particular type of
anesthesia that he was eddie bravo's
class.
I felt so refreshed afterwards.
That's different.
Yeah.
You wake up and I was like,
when he was like,
yeah,
you can get back in there.
I was like,
kennedy.
Really?
I just felt like I felt like rusted.
I felt like a nap for 30 minutes.
So is anesthesia.
Do you guys remember what it was called?
What do you mean?
the type of game of war?
The anesthesia that they got him with a
pro bowl fall.
Oh yeah.
Propafol purple fox who was sort of a
pro falls benefits per pole.
Fall full joint.
Even once I can't go to sleep.
What else you got?
That's,
but I haven't been.
We've got to go to the idea that someone
could get that far gone to get that far
gone where they just need to be put out
to other doctors were like,
michael,
I can't do that.
Like get the fuck outta here with dr.
Was like,
all right,
I guess I'll do it.
I guess this dr.
Thought he was going to be able to keep
them alive and if he kept him alive,
he would be still pulling money out of
michael for a long time.
I mean,
that's the only reason why it makes any
sense that anybody would agree to do
this is because need money or they want
the money.
It's so.
I mean,
there's a reason why it's not legal.
It's not ethical.
It's scary.
It's scary that you can get a doctor to
agree to just put you under every night.
It's so crazy.
Oh,
I'm trying to find the disadvantages.
Ended up going to sleep every night.
I might buy the gas.
Yeah.
I'm,
I'm just the disadvantages of,
uh,
of using it.
Let me hear him just a.
By the way,
I'll be in chicago at zanies this
weekend.
I'm want to want to know more powerful
chicago.
Zany,
small club.
Cool place.
Yeah.
there had been supposed to be one of the
best clubs In the country.
I've never been in there really good.
I was supposed to be one of those small
ones,
right?
Yeah.
It's a real small.
I think it's like less than 200 seats.
I think it's jammed though.
I joined three shows on saturday,
two shows on sunday.
I love it.
I love chicago.
Chicago's cool.
But the best.
There's something fantastic about that
town.
I mean this is a mess right now as far
as crimes,
especially with young urban kids like
the gang warfare,
that chicago.
Horrible,
horrible gang fighting and murders a
lot.
A lot of that going on.
Some pleasant.
Yeah.
There's a lot of that shit going on.
It's a,
it's kind of one of the highest murder
rates in the country.
Really?
Oh yeah.
When I was there,
I barely ever played there.
He never played there.
I barely ever do it with me just to do
with the theater fucking might ask you.
That was like a week ago.
I forgot how it will be.
All different material if you'd come out
there and I'm not going to appear of
that stuff.
Um,
there is,
um,
there's a type of person that comes from
the midwest.
They're like,
they're like grounded and you went in
the store.
Yeah.
This is sort of a genuine grounded
quality,
like a lot of hard work and people,
a lot of people that have worked on
farms,
a lot of people that have families that
worked on the farm.
People that came over here,
their relatives came over here a long
ass time ago.
You know what I saw there once though I
saw it was one of the early days.
I went there with you and there was
this.
They put us into like a vip area,
those night clubs and some girl was
flirting and then she came in and sat
with us.
I was like,
yeah,
sure,
come on in,
and then as soon as she went in,
some girl behind the rope bumped her.
She just gave her this look like,
excuse me,
you need to keep out of here.
This isn't my area right now.
She just took it over.
Was she kicked a girl out of.
It was so confused.
She just got invited to some vip area
that immediately started acting like she
was better than everyone else.
So the first time I saw that behavior,
oh,
I see where your shoes.
Somehow the queen,
all of a sudden,
yeah,
people can be county.
That's not good.
I definitely explained that the least.
You might be too hard to talk right now.
My tolerance went down in New York.
My most slow your roll.
Yeah.
The New York thing is a bummer.
Huh?
So it's such a horrible way to live.
They for folks who don't know.
Alright.
I mean I'm not saying this like a.
This is the way you have to live.
I'm just letting you know,
in los angeles it is unbelievably
ridiculously easy to procure a marijuana
just pulled over.
it's essentially legal.
It's essentially legal.
Yeah.
Um,
if you have a medical license,
it's legal.
If you have a medical license,
if you don't have a medical license,
it's decriminalized.
So,
uh,
that's one of the things that arnold did
when he left office.
So As long as you're not smoking weed
and drIving like an asshole,
it's,
it's pretty fucking legal.
You do it,
you're doing it in the privacy of your
own home.
So I'll give a shit.
They don't give a shit in my window
giving me a lecture about texting with a
half smoke bowl,
like in the middle,
leaning in for like two minutes.
They don't care then.
Okay.
They know what people are concerned
with.
Especially police officers.
There's people that are fucking
dangerous.
Yes.
They're concerned with.
If you see a guy texting,
that's dangerous.
You know if you.
If you see a guy in his van looks like
cheech and chong,
that guy's probably drove really fucking
slow.
As this smoke leaves is cracked window,
that guy is going to be a.
He's probably going to be really scared
of merge,
but other than that in Maryland I
couldn't figure out.
Even with my friend,
we're wanting to smoke pot,
but we couldn't do it at each other's
parents' house.
Just got in the car.
No other options,
but then you carson.
I was like,
wait,
that's the problem.
If you've got to make that choice,
you make that choice to smoke in your
car.
Your car is always going to smell like.
Wait,
no,
just for like 10 minutes.
Bullshit shit.
Unless you've closed doors right?
When you finished smoking pot,
smoking dogs come there a month later.
He smells like weed,
a weed in my car on the way to the
airport.
This time that was in there,
like in the center console for maybe a
year or two.
I was just.
I didn't try it yet.
I was on the way to the airport.
I always wonder if I know edibles lose
their potency.
They do.
Yeah.
They go away.
It goes away like almost entirely.
It gets to the point where they don't do
anything but they only have like a
certain time.
Mccormick explained it to me once.
I don't remember if tony,
somebody that was in the back of my
fridge for like three years.
Once you want it,
you can have it and how they and he was
like,
I'm high as fuck.
Wow.
Well I guess maybe the dried plants,
it's different than when you cook it.
It's like the cooking aspect of it I
think,
or the edible form.
Something about like top off too long
doesn't really like of what if like
let's say you have a thing of like that.
The red sauce,
not the structural cells,
but the ones with all the seeds in them.
You ever see those?
Oh,
okay.
Yeah,
I know what you're talking about on top
off that.
Just let it like oxygenate it goes away.
No,
no.
It's just observation.
Really?
Yeah.
Hm.
That's interesting.
I don't know.
You're the one that turned me onto that
fucking shit.
What is that stuff that you gave me that
bombs to bomb.
Oh,
so good.
Oh my god.
He gave me this hot sauce that it looks
like if you were like,
uh,
it even has like a nuclear warning sign
on it,
like a little nuclear sign on it and
it's such a small bottle.
You're like,
what did what,
what?
How horrific could this stuff possible?
It's such a small bottle,
like how are they so confident is
telling me that much hot sauce.
Is it just that one pepper that whatever
the ghost pepper pepper.
I don't know if it's ghost pepper.
It might be that casts become capsaicin.
Capsaicin.
yeah.
Well,
let's find out.
See the bomb d,
the habanero peppers.
That's it.
No,
that's not it.
That's a different one.
There's a death one,
the black one.
There's this little tiny death one,
whatever.
The little tiny death one is that one to
finally answer.
What is that?
Is it bob dropping in the middle of zed
it,
but literally three drops a plate of
spaghetti and marinara sauce.
Three drops.
Then mix up the whole thing.
Is that the same sauce?
It looks different.
I guess they have a bunch of different
flavors.
That's what it was.
A few different flavors.
Okay.
This is it that the bomb beyond
insanity.
That's it.
This is the one.
See this one right here?
Yeah,
that's it.
Yeah.
Well,
whatever.
Whatever the fuck.
The name of this stuff is.
I got cockY and really?
Yeah.
I put like a half a teaspoon of that
shit in and I,
uh,
I took your suggestions.
I think it was.
No,
it was either spaghetti or it was a
chicken noodle soup from jerry's famous
deli.
My suggestion,
what a.
Doubled it.
I took your suggestion and put it into
spaghetti.
You told him.
Forget it.
When I put it in noodles,
I'm actually,
I'm pretty sure that it was the chicken
noodle soup because I get that all the
time.
Um,
but holy fuck,
I was in agony.
I was like,
this is the most ridiculous hot sauce of
all time.
It's got a good flavor to it though.
It does.
But it was.
I went to war.
I went to war with wet body,
shit it out.
It says habanero pepper enhanced with
habanero infused flavor.
Create a sauce measured at 100,
19,700
scoville units of heat.
Wow.
That's a jalapeno pepper is $2,500.
That is insane.
One hundred 19,700
scoville units.
So a lot.
I didn't say anything on a plate of
spaghetti.
I took like a whole team one bite,
fought on the ground for awhile.
Thump the whole thing back into the
whole tub of spaghetti.
And then all that was hot.
I didn't think that it was.
Um,
I didn't think it was just to narrow.
It seems so strong.
I felt like it had to be more than when
they're really good.
Really good habanero sauce.
And you know,
real strong stuff,
but it was nothing like that.
That was so good.
Do you ever have liu kotecha?
That's my griddle.
That's my shit.
The mexicans know how to make the best
hot sauce period.
Dude there habanero sauce that you could
tuck.
It's delicious.
It's hot.
But it's also really delicious.
Like I put a lot of that shit in my eggs
and it's got a lot of heat,
but it's still so the taste is so good.
You get a lot of people don't understand
that.
It's a lot about the taste,
the taste.
It's a pain,
but it goes with the good taste.
Yeah.
You don't sound like an asshole.
I love.
Do you ever get challenged where you put
a bunch of hot sauce and someone will be
like,
drink this whole thing.
then during this whole thing of tabasco
in,
you're like,
I'm not trying to win it challenged.
Why come on?
It's like your dad,
if he catches you smoking a cigarette,
once you smoke the whole pack,
bitches want to try cigarettes.
YoU have to fucking stuffing my face
with a little pack.
You're about cvs.
What apple was cvs,
oh,
they're not going to sell cigarettes and
not going to sell tobacco products.
Weird
did it anyway.
We had a sell out and they sell alcohol
and it's supposed to be a place to get
medicine.
For the longest time I was blaming all
of these Philip Morris like,
oh,
they know it's addictive.
There's still fucking putting it out
there.
But then you're like,
well,
what about the people selling it?
They know to the stacks.
They're just making money off it.
They could easily do with the cbs is
doing
so weird.
Especially pharmacies.
Well,
it's weird man,
because there's part of me that says,
hey,
I want to be able to buy cigarettes.
If I was an idiot,
if I was an idiot and I decided to start
smoking cigarettes,
I'd want to be able to buy them.
I don't give a fuck if cvs cells,
um,
you know,
wants to keep selling them again,
if you don't want make it,
um,
illegal.
But some health place does not have to
sell but fucking agents of death,
that is kinda creepy that it's a cvs and
think about it that way.
They have a tequila,
they end the alcohol and then they have
medicine on the next side.
Just makes no.
I mentioned on twitter and all these
people like,
oh,
they still sell candy.
They still do this.
My gosh,
it's a good thing.
It gives people less like direct access,
easy access to a harmful product.
Yeah.
This is good.
It's almost like,
well,
they're just going to get all this,
all this business from the um,
uh,
insurance companies now.
And it's like,
yeah,
they should,
they should get rewarded that reward
when you do good thing.
It's nice when those people get
rewarded.
It's not,
doesn't make it bad.
The idea that you could just sell things
that you know are going to kill,
they're not held liable.
I mean,
it's not even something that gets you.
There's something about,
there's a willingness when you decide
you're going to drink,
you know,
like when you,
like when if we're at a comedy club,
like you want to do shots,
shots,
there's this thing that happens when you
decide that you're going to drink that
is beneficial.
There's some,
there's camaraderie in it,
there's like fun.
And you know,
there's,
there's happiness to it,
there's a warmth if you're doing it
right,
you know,
you can enjoy the experience of having a
couple of drinks.
But the experience of smoking cigarettes
is just death.
I mean that's all it is.
Nice when you're getting a good circle
of people.
Yeah.
but it's not changing your,
your fucking state.
I mean,
it might be giving you a little bit of a
stimulation,
right?
It gives you a stimulant sort of affect.
Right?
Yeah.
That's interesting.
Friendly
thing.
That's what hurt me the most is not
smoke when you see like phrase.
So like just in a circle dissolve.
I'm like,
I want to be part of that.
Right,
right.
Yeah.
There's a thing that people do,
like people like did that with cigars,
that I sit around cigars and smoke with
a bunch of guys now it's really weird
because all the comics are using these
things.
So you see circles of people using these
fake electronic who goes,
well,
those are better than.
Those are fucking better for you.
That shit is better for you than
cigarettes,
period.
This is great for me for like for chain
smoking or when I'm inside,
it's like chainsmokers thing I would do.
I wouldn't even think about it be like
working and I'd be smoking,
put it out.
I'm like,
wait,
where's my.
oh,
I already put out like I'm,
you know what I mean?
So that's good for like the inbetweens
and when I'm driving and traffic has
been like a two pack a day smoker for
years and years when he's already
telling about 120 days.
The.
yeah.
The good thing about that help people
quit.
The good thing about this is besides
like the blue cigarettes and like those
little disposable nicotine ones,
those like you have,
you don't get any kind of satisfaction
from,
oh really?
In this?
That one looks too much though.
It looks too big.
Like all attention to yourself,
the whole device.
It's a bunch of smoke.
that's topics not even straight on.
No,
no you,
it,
it's just too much attention.
It's just too big.
Why is it too much attention?
Because it's god.
It's like,
look at this thing I'm doing,
I'm doing something different.
Everyone look,
is that what it is or is it,
is there any,
um,
the ones that look the same size as,
as I get that.
AlrIght.
Gluten goes off.
You mean like a oil in their eggs?
Yeah,
the blue six.
Yeah.
Differences.
This battery lasts a long time and has a
lot of juice in it.
It looks like an electric toothbrush.
Yeah,
it looks like when those things that
they,
uh,
they put in your ear to look around.
Oh yeah.
Read out.
Also it tells you your temperature and
it also tells you how many hits you've
had.
And it also says like,
what your battery life.
that is a true.
Let me see that thing.
And what's really cool is that they had
these bars now in los angeles that are
huge bars,
mixology bars.
So you go in,
you're like,
yeah,
I want cotton candy,
but pez and they'll go,
okay.
And then some of those.
Yeah.
And it's like these,
it's almost going to a bar.
Okay.
All right.
You're,
you're wrong.
Was this thing's dope?
I do wear a fanny packs.
We really selling higher primate.
Got a beautiful one for boots,
higher primate logo on it with boots,
roots,
you know,
roots the company that makes bags and
make leather bags.
Yeah.
They made me one with a higher primate
logo on it.
I got it from dice.
Dice came in and he had a.
He had sweatpants on and these,
this fanny pack and I'll go,
that's a beautiful fanny pack.
I'm like,
where'd you get those?
The goal?
Yeah,
it's from root.
It's the best.
And he showed me the fatty,
so I got them.
I got the dice.
Clay,
a fanny pack that my.
My family,
my fanny pack is a dice clay inspired.
I've just ordered some sweatpants
online.
I'm waiting to get them and I'm just
going to start wearing sweatpants.
I know I'm going to wear track suits.
No,
no,
he's not.
I agree with this.
They are comfortable and not worried
about that.
Look,
they have this new sweatpants.
Do that look like pants.
Have you seen these things go out like
that.
That's ridiculous.
Could not go into pants.
You got to wear sweatpants.
You know that's you're full.
You can't put fucking racing stripes on
a cadillac.
That's just stupid.
that's dumb.
If you get.
What are you going to wear?
Sweat pants.
Their sweatpants.
Make them look like sweater and have a
crease in it makes it look like a
tuxedo.
I'm going to start wearing tracksuits.
Please don't do that.
I cannot sit with you.
If you do that,
you can.
You'll be fine.
these are fine.
I supported you through your cardigan
days.
Never sAid a word.
I never shit on your fucking terrible
dress habits.
I never did.
How dare you say that?
You wouldn't support me for athletic
wear.
That's just drooling.
Athletics.
I can see it.
I'm an athletic guy.
I like to move around.
It was breakout close.
It don't hold me down.
Cds or sweatpants,
but they look like regular pants.
Oh,
that's nice.
I would wear those.
I'd wear those.
Yeah.
I actually would love to wear those.
That's actually.
It seems like something that I was like,
sweatpants you're looking at right as
cock aren't.
You can't help it.
I looked at it,
I looked at it for a full three or four
seconds,
joe,
and he's going to be wearing cookie
monster sweater.
That's me.
Beautiful and be covered with cat hair.
Show you how much of a beta I am.
I'm all for the tracksuits.
I think that needs to make a comeback
because I hate wearing jews were so
concerned with what
kind of clothes we wear,
but people who were like really into
style,
they're always annoying.
Always annoying when they start talking
to you about,
this is a,
this is gucci,
this is and this is a.
This is a ralph lower end.
This artist's prints on with all.
There's all these older artists,
others get a little successful and they
have like sleeves,
but they're like,
oh,
I only wear these types of shoes.
Being into clothes,
there's nothing wrong with enjoying.
I think are closer artwork though,
don't get me wrong,
but this people that are like really
like obsessive really into style and
kind of snobbish about it.
That's like a weird thing to give a fuck
about.
You give a fuck that this guy has paint
on his pants,
like if you and I are hanging out and
you have pain on your pants,
I could give zero fucks.
Is that like a better thing?
Whatever.
You know.
I'm just saying if you choose to wear
type of shoe,
were you choose to where I can make fun
of portland.
You can wear anything you want to wear
anything you want everywhere,
but someone who's like into like rigid
style.
Oh,
that's out of style.
That's how style says.
Fucking who fucking who.
You tell me what the hell board decides
what's in style and not installed where?
Whatever the fuck you want.
If you want to wear some sweatpants,
where's fucking sweatpants and anyone
who cares is an idiot you.
You can look that guy's walking around
in sweatpants and why you give a fuck.
Why would anybody care even slightly?
If someone's walking around wearing
sweatpants in the office,
in the,
in the board room,
what do you give a fuck?
What you have to wear?
That weird stupid outfit that you wear
with these stiff
corners,
these sharp edges and a tie around your
neck,
enough and cuff links that are so
fucking stupid.
You have to stick some metal,
extraneous pieces in there and tighten
up the links because your scholar folds
over.
Get the fuck out of here.
That's what we are.
Shiny,
stupid,
hard,
soled shoes.
What do you have wood in your shoe?
Bottom of your shoe is would really.
There's wouldn't your shoe.
What is it?
Fucking 18.
12.
Are you living in Denmark?
You have clogs on you.
Fuckhead.
Ridiculous.
Why would you have leather?
Shiny leather on the bottom of your
toes?
They all slippery and stupid.
That is government at all.
What's with the tassels?
You fucking halfway.
You like tassels and the funnIer shoes.
Idiot man.
What is that?
Extra fancy fucking leather.
The leather tassel and silly and ancient
and dum de dum,
de dum.
Who cares how you dress?
You know I just saw several long in New
York.
I would put on flip flops,
shorts,
no shirt.
Just get high and walk around it.
Is that cool to walk around with no
shirt?
No,
it's not.
No.
I mean it's allowed,
but people go through it,
but it's not illegal.
What about women then?
Can women walk around topless?
I know that's been fought for right?
In columbus,
Ohio.
you can portland.
it can be.
You can be topless.
Yeah.
These tassels.
Oh my god,
man.
It's tasks on top of tassels.
You need iowasca.
If you were tassels and issues you need
iowasca like that take you away.
Have you ever done that stuff?
Iowasca still have not either.
It's a more prolonged version of a dmt
trip that apparently doesn't quite get
to that dmt flash level really,
but it gives you sort of this weird
spiritual insight thing that you don't
necessarily get with dmt.
That's the way it's been described to me
by my friends who have done it.
It's hard like when you try to relate
experiences,
everybody's is very different,
so like if you haven't personally
experienced it,
it's hard to put into context what
they're saying.
Like how They're describing something.
Yeah.
We don't have to put into words,
so one of these days I'll have to do it,
but um,
the dmt flash,
everybody that I've talked to where I've
tried to piece together what they say
about their experiences,
it's all seems like we're all talkinG
about a similar place,
but it's hard to.
It's so wacky that it's hard to put into
like any context on,
in the real world.
so the words that you use are all the
wrong words as they're talking about
talking about god and the voice of god.
He has no voice.
It's something like is no arm of god is
there's nothing that we can comprehend
if this is,
if it isn't,
you know,
when you,
when you do that,
if it isn't,
you actually communicating with
something.
If it's all happening inside your head
and it's all imaginary.
God damn your brain has some untapped
potential.
Oh yeah.
Probably if that's in there,
if that really is just our collective
minds in there or really is just the,
the,
the depth of the potential of human
thought and your ability to hallucinate
or imagined things are your imagination
in itself,
the very mechanics of your imagination,
creating all these crazy illusions and
if that is the case,
like,
wow,
you know what an incredible potential
the human mind has just on its own that
just we get to every now and again and
it puts on this bizarre show of this,
this godlike quality like this,
this perfect,
idealistic,
utopian,
loving thought process.
The hits you when you're on that stuff
like of course people think it's god.
I mean maybe it is god and maybe what
god is is human potential.
It's greatest heights.
This is what god really is.
Just a concept and maybe we're just
getting too much of it.
When you have a psychedelic experience,
it's too much.
Whatever the fuck you know that you're
tapping into.
That gives.
I've seen it once,
but I've never done it.
I watched them on.
No,
the other stuff.
The empty,
empty.
Yeah.
Well,
I'm sure we can make that happen.
If you were willing to sign a few pieces
of paper for the government to
participate in this study,
you should get in on the rick strassman
studies.
What's the.
He's doing it again.
What to do.
He's the guy that wrote that book,
dmt the spirit molecule.
He was the first guy that was able to,
um,
secure federal research.
Yeah.
He's got a license to be able to do it.
I don't know if they funded it.
They allowed him to do it,
but they allowed him to do intravenous
dmt.
A injection.
Some chippiness.
Yeah.
The book's called dmt,
the spirit molecule.
And it's a fantastic book.
It's really interesting.
He's a,
he's a scientist and he's a strassman
and say I would donate my Body to
science.
He's a brilliant,
brilliant guy,
but he's also like a really cool guy.
And uh,
he's,
he's really nice.
He's a really nice persOn.
And when you hear about his,
a relaying of these people's
experiences,
the way he set everything up and his,
his willingness to track this idea down
and try to see what it really is all
about is really courageous.
You know,
for a doctor to do that,
you can get in some weird.
We can some weird situations where
people think you're a kook,
But he's dealing with a real chemical so
they can't get funding to study
mushrooms for the low.
The maps is starting to break some
boundaries on that and they're starting
to,
uh,
to make some headway really,
you know?
Yeah.
There was a John Hopkins university
study and psilocybin maps is the
something,
multiple disciplinary psychedelic
studies.
I don't know what the actual acronym,
how it works,
but it's probably the number one group
as far as like really intelligently
debating and promoting psychedelics and
the study of psychedelics.
All brilliant,
brilliant guys.
You know,
we had rick doblin,
who's one of the guys from maps,
one of the head guys.
We had them on the podcast and the guy
couldn't have been cooler.
I told him I suburban friends that take
mushrooms.
She didn't.
She's about to turn 40 well burbs.
She was like,
oh no.
We're just like,
yeah,
that sounds like do it through with your
husband.
Tell to take mushrooms and listened to
that use youtube song.
Actually watch it,
watch it.
And when you can video the one fallon
from fallon.
Oh yeah,
yeah.
Do you think when you get through a
certain age though that it might be too
scary to recommend somebody,
you,
you don't have herpes and she said I'll
be scared.
I'm like,
yeah,
of course you'll be scared.
Yeah.
But I mean like when you get to a
certain age,
it kind of also have that like I'm going
to die.
No,
it's a big hit.
What kind of flavor?
This great mix of a little bit of a
fucking child.
Pina colada.
You're a black child.
I didn't get anything.
Yeah,
you have to hold the button the whole
time.
You kinda,
you can kinda like,
like puff on it almost.
That's kind of the way to do it.
Best puffing on it.
How'd you get the desk while symbol in
their sticker fit.
Perfect.
Oh my gosh.
That's hilarious.
But you know,
like when you're older you kind of have
like in the back of your head like,
oh,
you know what if I'm having a heart
attack because I'm 40,
you know,
like,
because I want to recommend it to
somebody that's never done it the same
way.
But I told them,
I'm like,
that's ridiculous notion.
She's never done anything like that.
But yeah,
totally.
You should let people do what they want
to do.
If they want to live their whole life
and never do mushrooms,
you should let them.
I'm not going to force them to do it.
She didn't even bring it up.
I shouldn't even bring it up.
Oh no.
Disagree.
Absolutely.
Bring it up.
You think you should offer it up?
Oh really?
Yeah.
Well I think if you want to fuck her,
you should know.
Even if I don't,
I did advise my male friends to try to
get them to do it.
Do you really?
Yeah.
I'm with me though.
I wonder if I'm gonna try to fuck girls
to mushrooms with them.
Really weird.
You freak out in front of her.
You ruined.
I can't.
So they don't feel like,
like held down?
No,
no way.
That's awesome.
Yeah.
I think,
uh,
anything you do,
whether it's mushrooms or smoked pot.
I was having a conversation with a buddy
of mine last night about a friend of
ours and we were talking about like how
this dude could benefit from weed.
This is why he does this because he
doesn't smoke smoke pot.
So he's not,
he's not,
he doesn't have that paranoid
introspective thing that you get when
you smoke weed.
We start really examining yourself.
Uncomfortable lights people.
A lot of people don't smoke weed who
need to lead the quality they're
lacking.
So they have like this hubris thinking,
oh,
they keep pushing forward without
considering how they come off to other
people.
They just pushing forward.
And this is hubris that will like,
come on man,
just smoke doesn't stop and think about
it for a second.
People get caught up.
Also,
you get caught up and going in a certain
direction.
Like,
like did you see wolf of wall street?
No.
No,
a good.
Yeah,
it's good.
Yeah.
I really enjoyed it.
It's really good.
You know,
a lot of people say that martin
scorsese,
like his movies are kind of like
formulaic.
Yeah.
But I say those people can go fuck
themselves because uh,
what he does is he wrote a column.
He knows how to do it,
man,
I should've.
I'm sorry.
So good with words for my next 1500
words that I don't need.
Here's a picture.
Boom.
He just knows how to make a movie that
like,
it's different.
Like he'll do things like,
like there's a part when leonardo
dicaprio,
like,
you know,
everyone's moving and talking and they
just stopped talking,
but there,
there's no sound coming out.
But he's walking towards the camera and
looking at you essentially completely
cut out the sound of all the other
people and he's talking to you.
It's like these weird little things that
he does,
like this is the chaos of the trading
room floor.
And as leonardo dicaprio walkthrough
through it,
it's,
there's no sound.
Just him talking.
He's explaining his life.
The world shifted.
The record goes saying something about
something.
He's just dope.
Martin scorsese,
he's just a master.
He's just,
he had his shot and I'm a taxi driver
where it's when you see a guy walking
towards the camera,
a character walk towards the camera,
and then you'd see another angle like
cut right from there to cameron moving
towards something and you're like,
that's the point of view of the guy we
just saw.
Right.
Um,
so then he started having a pan across
that view starts panning across the taxi
place all the way around and around,
and then it's that it puts the deniro in
the shot was supposed to be his point of
view and all of a sudden he's in it.
He just does stuff like that.
This shooting is just as craZy as this
character is.
Yeah,
yeah.
Yeah.
You,
that deeper shit gets you feeling loopy.
Yeah.
There's just a,
this such an art to filmmaking.
No,
I don't have any desire to ever do it,
but it seems like a lot of work.
Oh my god.
It seems like so much work,
but I appreciate the shit out of it.
You know,
I really,
really appreciate someone who's really
good at it.
Someone who just really knows how to
make a movie that you go to see go
fucking a as a good guy.
American hustle is a good guy.
That's pretty good.
That's a good fucking movie,
man.
That is a good fucking movie man.
Christian hail is such a bad mother
fucker and he's pretty good at either.
Damn.
He's good.
Yeah.
Do you ever see the machinist and those
women were fuckinG fantastic to the
chick from the hunger games?
Oh yeah.
God damn fantastic.
Prior what?
I'm moving.
bradley cooper was awesome.
You haven't seen it yet.
I don't see movies unless I have a
girlfriend.
I just never think about what you mean
ladies.
You hear that cry for help.
Don't let another seAson go by without,
without brian red band.
FInding a girlfriend.
I live a totally different
life.
When I'm in a relationship like a
relationship,
I don't do shit.
I don't watch tv.
I don't want you to movies.
What do you do?
Play with dogs.
You just don't do anything.
Furious.
Masturbation from the jump.
Alarm clock goes off and we begin the
race.
That's how many times you can masturbate
in the day.
What do you.
You get to?
Probably like three or four guys know
you could do more than that.
A day started right away.
About five or six.
For me,
I'd say you get this,
you can get to seven to 10 I think,
but by the end,
what the fuck is kind of madness?
It's mostly just liquid.
I wouldn't be afraid of that madness
filling my head with seeds.
What do you mean like back off?
Seven times in a day with the things
that I need to think of in order to come
after times five and six,
what are the madness?
The fucking craZy savage jeans that I
have to tap into my last load off or
slow to give yourself more room.
I don't want those.
I like smelling your wife's pillow.
I don't want those thoughts that are
already up from there.
I don't want those thoughts.
I don't want.
I don't want to hit comma number seven.
That's that's,
that's the person,
but you have to keep going.
I don't like that person fucking figured
out that I kind of thinking about dead
cats.
You go from It being central to being a
violent release of soldiers.
That's how you orgasm.
Thinking a bunch of angry release of
demon soldiers flying out of your take
on this boner pills make me masturbate a
lot more.
Really strike out.
And then you're like,
oh,
well know they just last week with his
bone and asked for like 24 to 48 hours.
Looked up like what happened?
Take that stuff a lot.
Nope.
You never even looked into it.
I want propecia postcard,
whatever it was.
I read a bunch of side effects and it
was like depression,
all stuff that maybe.
I don't know.
I think maybe it's stuff was caused by
that.
I think a hair shit.
Yeah.
I had a bad reaction to that stuff.
It killed my bone on bone arthritis in
there too.
Killed my boners and it also made me,
um,
uh,
it made me more tired when I would work
out.
I didn't have as much endurance when I
got off of it.
My boners came back with a vengeance and
it felt like I had more energy training
and I was like,
man,
I wonder if that's affecting me in an
extreme way.
Like everybody has like a different
stages.
The way it processes a testosterone to
dihydrotestosterone see that everybody
has a different bodies reaction.
So weird.
You know,
like some people are allergic to certain
types of antibiotics or they're allergic
to penicillin or they're allergic to,
you know,
people get weird rolls of the.
With your bodies is.
It might be that my body didn't react to
it very well,
but I know a,
I have a buddy who's on it.
There's no problems with it at all.
He's been taking that shit for like 10
years.
Most people don't.
Yeah.
For me it was a problem,
but I didn't realiZe it was a problem
until after I stopped taking it.
When it stopped,
like I ran out of it and all suddenly
take was like woken up from a coma to go
in bold.
Hello?
You.
Your head was.
You look great when you shaved your
head.
Oh,
I didn't go.
I did not like the shape that you don't
have to,
but I'm telling you,
you look great with a shaved head or
going to have shaved heads in five
years.
There's a reason why the monks did it.
It's and I don't give a fuck move.
I mean I was,
for me,
it was a matter of aesthetics.
My hair was getting so gross.
It was got down to the point where like,
you shouldn't keep getting haircuts if
every time you get your haircut,
your hair still looks like shit.
WhaT am I paying your shop all this shit
off.
But I would have done now that diet now
that I've done,
I would have done a long ass time ago.
It's the easiest way to deal with it.
Like you've got a round head.
Yeah,
it works.
Good head for,
for being bald,
but getting your hair cut is so
annoying.
Having to schedule that time out of your
day and sit down and listen to some
nonsense.
I had a cool hairdresser for a long
time,
my friend gabrielle up,
so she was a hairdresser from the news
radio days,
but yeah,
she's really cool.
Cool italian lady from New York,
so we've been friends for a long time,
so I used to actually enjoy.
She probably kept me from cutting my
hair off for a long time just because I
enjoyed hanging out with her.
Go to see her like once a month.
They're the coolest ones,
man.
On a shoot.
That the wardrobe stylist.
A wardrobe,
a hairstylist.
So the only.
She's funny.
She's a funny New York,
like a hard ass,
a cool lady.
The makeup people always hate me because
of your ego because you always had that
rule of like I never put makeup on like
on tv shows and stuff and so that twice
I've had to say,
no,
no makeup.
I don't do that.
They're like,
what are you talking about?
You have to know.
You don't have to try to get me.
The other day when I was doing fox
sports one,
I go,
nope guy,
we're just going to put a little powder.
I'm like,
yeah,
that's all right though.
This is what I look like.
This is exactly what it looked like.
pretended look different than I looked
this crazy.
Like get a smooth my skin out.
What are you going to do?
I let them do what they want to get a
light.
Me funny and soft.
Like I'm an angel.
What are you going to do it?
They'll fucking do up lighting.
This is look man.
No one's perfect.
This is what I look like.
What do you look like?
High fucking relax.
You don't have to put makeup on people.
She got mad.
She got upset.
Like,
look,
this is mY job.
If you don't get makeup doesn't stop
hiring.
You know what?
People are stIll gonna want makeup.
So there's nothing wrong with makeup.
I wore makeup everyday when I was on
newsradio.
Yeah.
they'd been make every type we filmed.
They put makeup on me.
They just want to do and I couldn't say
no.
Then you know who was there anything I
did to be a dick.
I was just totally replaceable.
I was totally replaceable.
I wasn't nobody on that show replay
actually replaced the guy who replaced
ray romano.
So they took.
Armando was booked for the pilot,
but they didn't shoot the pilot with ray
romano.
No.
This is what happened.
Ray romano was booked for the pilot and
he was working,
but they decided somewhere in the middle
of race thing.
I don't know if they weren't happy with
him or they decided to go a different
way with the character and he was
originally the last minute like we got
to switch.
Um,
you,
you're beginning when they're coming up
with ideas and it's throwing the ideas
around for a pilot.
It's not uncommon for them to change a
character.
They liked,
decide they need a different dynamic.
They have all these different dynamics
and ray was more of a laid back sort of
a dynamic.
That's who he is,
you know where I'm going to see him on
the show,
you know,
he's like a laid back sort of a guy and
I think they wanted someone who was a
little aggressive.
So when,
who was an idiot who's Like,
I'm a male idiot,
that was going to do aggressive stupid
shit.
That leaves room for funny.
So I got lucky.
I came along after ray was replaced by
another guy who just fill it in for the
guy.
He was in the pilot.
The other guy was in the pilot.
He didn't think he had a job full time
job.
I don't know what he thought.
I don't know.
I don't know if the car.
Yeah,
maybe if he was really good they would
have kept him or maybe if he was what
they were looking for,
they would have kept him.
So then they did.
Um,
did he knows.
The funny thing about the audition is
that the first stuff that they wrote,
it was,
it was really interesting because um,
it wasn't that funny.
It was like more like matter of factly
or was more like setting up a character.
It was like there was no jokes in them
were very subtle.
It was like a,
uh,
a behavior sort of a piece and a lot of
guys like totally like tried to overdo
it and try to make it like really funny.
It just wasn't really funny.
And they were saying they did that.
The writers did that because they wanted
to make sure that no one would try to
ham it up.
Whoa.
Really?
Like if it's funny,
it's funny,
you know,
like say it to make it funny like you
know how to say it to make it funny or
not,
but if it's not funny,
don't pretend it is.
You can't have everything.
Doesn't have to be a joke.
Like some things and not a joke and some
things are a joke just because you're
creating a character like that,
you know,
that character.
So when the character does like typical
things like that,
that character would,
it was like a joke of recognition.
Right.
You know,
so then the second time I came in for
the second one on the ground near bears,
his feet always go pick her up.
Yeah.
I wouldn't call it,
I'll just pick it up,
put it in my pocket,
let him go like,
oh my god,
I just.
Well you guys have like routines.
You go to things.
Yeah.
Based on what you know already.
But at the second time I went in for the
audition,
they wrote something really funny that
was like,
whoa,
this is hilarious.
It was really good stuff.
So then they had narrowed it down to a
group of people that they thought were
not going to ham it up.
And then they gave the smallest group to
the remaining groups shit to be funny
with.
Oh,
right.
So they were super.
I don't know,
I don't know those guys.
Oh,
there's just a couple of guys.
But I remember things I there.
Uh,
there's one thing that gives you
confidence.
It's to see other people falling apart.
Subtests who's just fall apart.
One of the guy who was auditioning,
one of the guys who is waiting to
audition,
who's totally fall apart or is visibly
sweaty,
like he was sweaty,
like it was sweat was dripping down his
head really going over the lines in this
like really weird,
like a frantic way.
Like he was like kind of mouthing the
lines while you're sitting there.
But it was like,
it was like he was falling apart.
He was like,
no shit.
Fuck.
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
There was something he was doing that
gave me massive confidence and I
remember thinking,
oh,
if I just got an audition with this guy,
is gonna fall apart,
one down,
I guess you know,
it's probably one of those guys that had
been in hollywood like,
look,
when you're coming out here and you try
and audition for shows,
it's totally a crapshoot.
You could get super lucky on the very
first show you get cast and all of a
sudden you're on television show.
It probably helps that you don't know if
it's earlier where you don't really know
the stakes.
Yeah,
maybe it does,
but it also helps if you just get lucky
and you are what they're looking for,
but you could also be here for 20 years
and never get cast and shit.
That's.
That's possible.
Especially if you have the wrong look or
the wrong,
you know,
whatever you do always used to say
everybody in this town through others,
ones away from being a bigger star.
Yup.
Three auditions away.
Yeah.
Everybody,
every single person.
I mean,
look,
there's some fucking really untalented
people on television right now that are
stars,
stars of reality shows.
I mean really untalented people.
Are you really gonna chew into the
microphone.
You motherfucker.
Rosanna is out here for what?
A week or gay and she got passed at the
comedy store and then she got a tv show
like quickly thereafter.
Was it?
Yeah,
she had a craZy ride.
She was in denver.
She started out in denver.
Oh yeah.
She got really good in denver a for now.
By the time she came.
Well,
you know what man,
there's a,
there's a kind of an attitude that a
denver people have.
There's like they're friendly folks,
but you know,
there's a,
there's a hard edge to that place.
I mean they're in the rocky mountains.
They have bears and shit there,
you know,
it's like,
it's a crazy place to live.
Could be living in colorado's a little
nutty.
So they tolerate a little more like
hardy.
Yes.
You know what I mean?
And so rosanne like coming out of there
and then going to the comedy store is
like,
she had already built up this app in
this cool,
smart,
hard edge town in denver is people
dealing with the fucking elements every
day.
And then from there she's in la and
there's no comics like her,
you know,
she's,
she's talked be housewife killing to ken
lang.
It's probably hard to follow.
Oh,
you could never follow where,
man.
Do you remember people that have a.
I mean,
dude,
if folks who weren't alive when roseanne
barr first hit,
she's like her voice ignored rate.
But then I gave it another shot and few
years later I was like,
oh,
this show's pretty good.
She's a great comic.
Yes.
Yeah.
Especially back in the day,
you know,
especially when she,
when she first made it,
she to me is one of the most influential
comedians ever.
Really?
Yup.
Because for women that had never been a
woman like her before,
she's the kinison version of a woman.
Never been a woman like that before.
She actually had 30 minutes.
So I don't know,
man.
She did more than one special.
I mean,
she didn't maintain that level of stand
up,
you know,
once she became super famous and the tv
show of the attitude of like,
no,
this is why I'm not trying to be
anything.
She was bad ass dude.
When she was before she got her
television show and she was just doing
stand up.
She was bad ass.
There was no women like her before.
She was a total new thing.
She was an overweight white woman who
didn't give a fuck,
didn't give a fuck.
And she had kids and she didn't give a
fuck.
You mitZi of black rose dead rose.
That's a message.
I don't know.
Massive following each other.
Roses are the rarest of all risks.
Mmm.
Like roses.
Well,
it's a nice thing to send then,
unless it's voodoo attached.
Oh,
maybe it is.
My notes from footie.
WhaT?
Roseanne believes.
A lot of wacky shit.
She's out there sometimes.
Oh dude,
she's so out there.
She's like,
she won't touch.
It's one of those really very rarely
will touch with.
Oh,
well congrats.
You're fucking.
I feel pretty good about it.
Don't get mad at me,
bro.
I didn't meet her.
she wouldn't shake my hand.
He introduced me to her in the fucking
office building one on this street.
Wow.
That's sad.
I'm sorry.
Sorry.
I was just thinking like that's not
acceptable to say I don't shake hands.
Just don't do that.
Well,
what about people that are like crazy a
add and worried about what diseases with
enough famous,
excessive compulsive.
They just die.
I don't know man.
I mean you can't do that at the plant,
right?
You can't.
No one's going to accept that.
Everybody's in the flintstones.
Fucking.
I don't shake hands.
What?
No way.
Yeah.
Why?
Why is that allowed?
Right?
Why it has to be like it's a movie.
A thing.
Yeah.
It's a fame thing.
Our cues.
Well,
I think we're,
I was saying,
I think we're uniquely fortunate in
being stand up comedians that you were
forced to look at ourselves all the time
and I think if you want to think about
someone who gets pushed into these weird
boxes of,
of power,
you the power,
that sort of unnatural,
you know,
power that really doesn't exist anywhere
in the,
the,
the natural world where someone is like
more famous than other people.
So everyone around them is terrified of
them.
And so they,
what they do is they just have these
situations where they have a show and
throw soda at the fucking guy who was
running the show or they were talking
about like one of those,
um,
grace under fire.
BreN butler apparently threw him in the
face of the dude who was doing grace
under fire.
Really?
Yeah.
He had like fuckiNg swore at him and
said some nasty shit to them.
And then they canceled the show.
Oh yeah.
She was like,
I'm too big for this total unnatural
behavior to have this one person like
brett butler,
repercussions and without thinking about
yourself all the time,
without examining it must be a weird,
weird.
What is his hecklers?
Seventy five percent of hecklers are
cute women.
CuTe too.
Above women trying to get some.
Try to get some arch feared,
dig.
No,
just trying to like.
They've never been told to shut up
because they're too pretty.
There's a little of that.
There's a little consultant you don't
know that like this has nothing to do
with you.
Be quiet while people get confused and
think that because you're talking,
they should be able to talk to ya.
Waiting,
man.
Yes.
Can't talk.
Can't just be talking now.
Now,
now,
now I don't agree with them.
I'm going to saY something.
I'm going to say something.
No,
iT's not cool.
Not calgary.
I had her.
She wrote letters to every one of the
clubs.
I was booked out for the next 15 weeks
saying what a horrible person I am and
how she didn't do anything for being
horrible.
she was talking all through the first
guy and then I started.
I was like,
stop,
stop.
I saw you talking about 30 straight
minutes.
You've got to be quiet.
You're just not gonna.
We're not gonna do that.
And then theY were like,
all right.
They did one more thing.
I told them to be quiet again and then I
heard it go next subject and I was like,
get out.
Just go get out of here front seats.
We got.
We got an extra ones.
I just had to do throughout my first
person.
I found your place to the other day for
same thing.
The girl talking the whole time,
that boyfriend would not shut her up to
the boyfriend's.
I'll just shut her up.
She just happened to be shadow girl up.
You either ask her to be quiet or you
asked her to leave with you or you leave
her there.
Her up man.
That shit never works.
Especially like a really mouthy woman
was really like,
that's what she likes to do.
People like some people like hold back
all week long and they liked to get
drunk and fight.
Get crazy.
Get fucking aggressive.
It ruined my whole entire set because
she was just fucking sitting there the
whole time and I'm just like,
alright,
couldn't take it anymore.
It happens all the time.
Yeah,
it's weird,
you know,
it's the enemy oF comedy sometimes,
but then sometimes it's fucking
hilarious.
Sometimes it turns out to be something
funny.
You know?
We also have the advantage that we were
comedy store comics and there was no
crowd control.
None.
Zero.
We like people would say like,
I would do like a show and some of the
hackle and it will go so well.
People would say.
Was that planned?
Like,
was that guy a plant?
no.
Where'd you come up with all that stuff?
Like when you,
when you started out at the comedy
store,
you go to war.
Not only is it not police,
even when you come off and it's been a
horrible heckler the whole time.
No one that goes to the door,
guy goes,
oh,
you should throw somebody out there.
Just moan about it in the back to
themselves.
Yeah.
And then the next idea after that deals
with it and nobody says something.
Yeah,
it's hilarious.
Have a to that place
was the worst.
I alwaYs thought that people were.
You throw him out if he was talking to
the mayor,
but not for me.
There's also an extra douchey ness to
that place because it's in hollywood.
It's a famous iconic building,
so you would get these people that were
like,
there's an extra level of douche that
you get from people that are like in
show business that are [inaudible] are
trying to make it in show business.
There's a lot of people that give
attempts at show business and they're
really insane and it doesn't go well for
them and so they'll,
they'll be at a comedy club and they'll
see someone doing something and they
decide and they're insane,
have so good.
Not only that,
this guy ain't shit and I'm better than
him.
I can be funnier than him.
Like I've heard people.
It was like,
you're a mattress salesman.
You don't do that anymore.
I've heard people that could be in a
comic or it could be an actor in their
mind,
but it's just this extra duty genus of
people that are out here.
You know what I mean?
It's like it's not an unchecked
juiciness that you don't find that often
in the east coast.
The different kinds of duchamp's yeah.
Unchecked.
What the fuck is wrong with you?
Yeah.
Nobody like,
they don't have friends that don't have
people to go shut the fuck up in boston
though.
It was different kind of drunk.
If it's out of control,
just savages that they're there.
They're just like that.
I've blocked out already to the
descendants of wild savages that came
with here on boats before there were
movies.
We just stop and think about that.
They didn't know what the fuck was over
here.
These people were craZy.
The genetics of the first irish that
came to America,
but maniacs who the boats or fuck with
that.
Hey,
we're thinking about going on a boat to
a place that we can't really describe
because any photos or anything because
they haven't invented cameras yet,
but it will take a few months.
We're going to take a few months and
hopefully we will die of starvation.
And uh,
by the time we get there,
I mean,
hopefully the savages one eat your
babies.
They won't shoot arrows into us.
Hopefully they will.
They will eat a lOt of your babies.
No,
hopefully they won't.
You like your babies.
You don't want them get eaten otherwise
you can't spread.
You see it across the country.
What's,
when did we make enemies with the
indians?
Why did they attack?
And it just like steal the women and
stuff.
Listen,
everybody that lands in a country and
this country is an attacker.
Yeah.
You know,
you might not think of yourself as an
attacker.
You think of yourself as a colonist,
but you're an attacker.
If you're running into people that were
already there,
you know,
and you can say,
well,
hey,
you know,
we,
they should make room for us to,
okay,
maybe.
But maybe they don't want to because
there's.
Yeah.
And if you show any aggression to them
and you taking food out of their
children are to get these things out of
here.
Yeah.
And then there was also the fucking
treaties that were broken and all the.
Here's some crimes,
smallpox blankets for you all.
Yeah.
All the horrific crimes that were
perpetrated on the american indian.
I mean,
god,
you starting to hear those stories and
think about it and he hears about the
slaughter and the fucking mass genocide
and the,
just the numbers.
Yeah.
You know what Australia,
they're respectful
of aboriginal people.
If one aboriginal kills another one,
the white people don't deal with it.
You guys saw in you to deal with us.
You know,
it freaked me out when they have their
own justice system.
Freaked me out when I was,
there was a,
they were telling me about,
um,
during the fifties,
I guess it was where they had this
concerted effort.
They decided to take aboriginal children
from their parents,
steal them and raise them in the white
world.
Oh.
Like to,
to help them to benefit them.
So,
so craZy and dark.
But the idea was that they were going to
try to civilize these people and the
only way to do it would be the fucking
kids.
Like that was a real plan that was
involved with that.
Yeah,
man.
They took their kids.
Oh wow.
They took their kids because they
believed that their culture was better.
So much better.
It's so good.
You don't think so.
That's so crazy.
That's so crazy that people could take
people's children.
Yeah.
It's so crazy.
And you know,
apparently like they have a lot of the
same issues that american indians have
with alcohol problems in their
communities.
Aboriginals.
Aborigines,
yeah.
The native americans.
I apparently it's a genetic issue with a
lot of them that they don't have long.
Yeah.
Their ancestors didn't develop the
tolerance and they weren't accustomed to
alcohol the way like europeans were.
So apparently aboriginal people in
Australia had a similar problem.
So a lot of them,
there's a lot of alcoholism,
a lot of real problems with.
I don't know if they ever had alcohol
before,
but they probably didn't have the shit
that we have.
Even if theY had their own alcohol,
if they didn't have wild Turkey,
they didn't.
They dIdn't ever have any crazy
tequilas.
They didn't have some shifts.
It might add some fermented berry juice
that of gets you high if you leave it
out and chase off the flies.
Yeah,
but they were so arrogant that they
thought it was okay to take their kids.
Wow.
That's sell a mean horrible.
Pulling a kid away from a mom.
Horrifying.
Terrifying.
The ugliest aspects of humanity.
Yeah.
I mean,
the thing I started thinking recently,
so I thought about Philip Morris,
the tobacco companies,
and you think of their evil people like
trying to addict you even though they
know it's already like bad for you,
but they're not evil people.
TheY're just people that had a job there
that are doing that stuff.
They're not.
These are all old men.
There's just people Who got a job and
now they're still doing that job even
though know it's terrible sort of.
Someone has to make the decision to sell
cigarettes.
Yeah,
and you could easily just say,
oh,
I'm not gonna.
Take this job.
Then the encountered from cigarettes are
going to be a thing of the past.
I think the shit that he's sucking on,
that kind of thing,
it's going to make much more sense for
people.
If that stops killing people,
why wouldn't they do it?
It's a nicotine distribution device.
Definitely getting people into smoking
these again now and then it's helping.
It's helping like
the tobacco farms find a way to make
money because they've all invested
heavily in it because new people were
actually getting hooked on justice,
smoking,
nicotine.
Now I've noticed
what is the actual health of those
friendships?
Those are outlawed in New York now.
Really?
Yup.
Indoors,
because they said I'm a secondhand
smoke,
but he builds vapor,
but they said they put.
The problem is they put on their
package.
I'm safer than smoking cigarettes and
then you have to prove that you can't
just say that you show me a study.
That is the problem.
You do have to prove that,
you know,
it's like some sort of like ses
carcinogen or something where it falls
into the same category as cigarettes
doesn't seem like that blue cigarettes
stuff.
It lingers.
Mill lingers more like smoke.
I don't smell it though.
You definitely smell like.
Because how I found out about this
actual one,
this girl was smoking it and it smelled
like strawberries and I just walked by
and like,
what was that strawberry snatcher vagina
and shit,
and then she showed it to me and I'm
like,
all right,
I'm lending that,
but it does smell,
but yeah.
And I can see if you don't like
strawberry and then you walk around the
library yet.
But people with perfume and
no,
there's nothing wrong with that smell.
You smell it.
I smell it when you just did it,
but it smells nice.
It's like a nice smell.
Smell like cigarettes.
Cigarettes are disgusting,
man.
You used to come into the car after you
smoke cigarettes.
Brian would like pretend he wasn't
smoking.
He wouldn't go stick to them in the
cold.
Oh,
when you come you'd come into the car
and we would all smell it.
Like,
oh dude,
that's nasty.
people don't like to hear that shit.
People that smoke cigarettes especially.
Oh yeah.
They don't like to hear what.
You can't smell it.
Okay,
fine.
I guess I made up the smell.
I just smelled so stinky,
stinky in the cold and the cold.
Come in,
stinky.
Fuck off a cigarette.
Smells stinky.
Fucking smell it.
It's gross.
It's bad for you to fucks.
Wait.
No that it's bad for you.
Don't do it.
Get it together.
These will be better for that.
It'll probably will take off probably
with a cigarette in 10 years.
We'll probably out there,
but this is the thing.
They say that nicotine is actually an
infect a,
an effective cognitive boost.
It gives you like a little.
That was one of the things that Steven
King said when Stephen King stop smoking
cigarettes.
He said he really felt it.
He really felt the difference in these
synapses firing his,
the way he described it and writing his
books and nicotine as sort of a
stimulating effect on,
on,
on thinking and creativity for a lot of
people.
But it's the tar,
the tobacco,
the kudzu.
It's.
Well no,
it's a lot of the chemicals.
There's,
there's like 590 chemicals that they add
to cigarettes on top of the tobacco
itself.
All approved bar,
lovely government,
but these insane chemicals are
essentially designed to change the
flavor and to make more addictive.
You know what to do with the nicotine.
They have a certain amount,
they'll shoot it up real high like all
of a sudden from five to seven and then
everyone has to smoke less cigarettes
because it's like all of a sudden I get
in too much,
so they always want to like half a
cigarette or whatever and they're
getting their fix of whatever they need
and then they
plummeted.
Once you get used to that,
they plummeted down,
like to.
Yeah,
and then you start smoking more because
he's not getting what you need.
Then they push it right back up to
average again.
Wait a minute,
they variant but on occasion in order to
get you fucking more addicted.
They do that.
Now that they already know it causes
death.
They're still trying to get you more
addicted.
Well,
I didn't know that they can do that.
So they can vary the amount of nicotine
that.
How do you know this is?
That's what a word on the street Is a
motherfucker.
That's what I've heard from smokers.
I think big jay told me that it's.
It's a dark business man,
that's for sure.
Especially if you've ever seen anybody
that's dying a cigarettes,
emphysema,
people that are dying of lung cancer.
I not.
I'm mike side of that though.
Really?
He got a stage four tumor.
That's when they found him dead and like
two weeks it wouldn't make any sense and
I'm going,
whoa.
Smoked a lot of cigarettes.
I smoke a lot of cigarettes.
Mike lacey from the comedy magic club
was a team made you cry that time brian,
who was telling you to stop smoking
cigarettes?
I was like crying because he gets to you
dude.
It's so nice.
Such a nice guy.
No,
we probably look at me.
Look at me.
We care about you.
We don't want you to tell you.
They want to know is legit.
Beautiful person.
Girl at the same day or something.
I don't know.
Maybe your cat hurt its foot shoving
cigarettes directly into your veins.
You were opening up veins.
Yeah,
I ripped.
I can't fucking in any comfortable.
You bad cry pretty easily.
I almost cried the other day and it's
just how many,
what I'm drinking.
I think sometimes maybe what you're
drinking when she cried.
Yeah.
If I drink too much Turkey,
that's why I need it in Turkey.
I start crying like it's just like
somebody that body's breaking down,
stuff like that,
or I think about something you can drink
that much.
Wild Turkey body's breaking down just
slowly dying.
It's getting poisoned.
It's moaning.
Like my,
my old cat,
he had fireball.
Fireball.
Have you had fire?
It's been a while.
What is it?
Have you had it?
That's like a cinnamony,
right?
What is it to.
It's the shot that we used a used to be
popular when I was in college and then
went away and they got near the time of
gold slog or an aftershock,
like all these really weird,
but then it kind of went away and it
came back and they repackage it and
everything.
NoW it's like everywhere you go
everyone's drinking fireball,
but it's my new drink.
Savages,
savages.
Each and every one of you.
Cinnamon whiskey.
I wanted to talk to you guys about this.
A jerry seinfeld.
Oh yeah,
pull this up brian.
Pull it up.
It's on gawker.
Gawker.com.
G a w k e r,
just pull up gawker.
It's like right on the front page.
It's who cares about diversity in
comedy?
Says jerry seinfeld.
Oh yeah,
that's a,
that's not what you want.
Just look up,
look up.
Uh,
just do a google search on the title
diversity.
Jerry seinfeld and he's getting just
gawker diversity journey.
Doing a public interview.
Yeah.
And people around.
I don't want to comment on it until we
actually pull the video up because I
would like you to hear it from him first
before we,
even before we even comment on it,
because it's,
it's a,
it's an important subject for guys like
ari and I,
you know,
as,
as comics,
there's some shit that they're trying to
attach to this here
of 22 episodes.
Yeah,
got fucked up.
I have noticed that most of the guests
are mostly white males.
Have 22 episodes that you can get into
that.
No,
but you take a look over here.
Peter,
what do you see?
Yeah,
a lOt of what's going on here.
But,
oh,
this really pisses me off,
but really pisses me off.
Well,
that's okay.
Um,
go ahead.
But you made a comment on the tina fey
episode that I thought was interesting
that I,
I'd like to get your thoughts on a
little bit more.
You said you were talking to her to that
and you said something about the female
comedians.
It's a struggle for them to balance
their feminine projections with their
comedic gold in this context of comedy,
not gender diverse.
I just want to know what you meant by
that.
Well,
I was kind of curious what it's like to
be a woman in comedy as opposed to a
man.
There was a little bit of a difference
and I thought that might be an
interesting thing to discuss from her
perspective.
She saw successful at it and I'm just
wondering how she looked at it,
if she even thought about it and she
kind of gave me the answer,
which is yeah,
you do have to think about that,
but you know,
it's just another thing to think about.
Okay.
All right,
fair enough.
Now you,
there were a lot of things about the
comedians of cars in the beginning of
the first 10 I did.
I think we're all white males and people
writing all about that,
which I,
part of the reason why I had people had
tweeted at me when I said I'm
interviewing with jerry seinfeld.
I'll ask him about their gender
diversity on this.
I mean,
it's,
people think it's the census or
something.
I may represent the,
the actual pie chart of,
of America.
Who cares?
It's just funnY.
Funny is,
is the,
is the world that I live in.
You're funny.
I'm interested.
You're not funny.
I'm not interested and I have no
interest in gender or race or anything
like that,
but everyone else is kind of with their
little calculating.
Is this the exact right mix?
You know?
Uh,
I,
I think that's a,
to me it's anti comedy.
It's comedy,
it's more about,
you know,
pc nonsense.
Then are you making us laugh or not?
Right,
right.
Yeah.
Well they went off on that so that See,
it shows that he's like racist.
Well,
I saw people,
uh,
I saw a video on don't even want to
bring it up.
I don't even Want to pull the video up
because I don't want to watch it again
because it was so annoying.
Uh,
people that were taking that and saying
that that's a problem.
They're taking that and he's not saying
all,
I don't care if he's saying I don't,
I only care about what's funny,
trying to make things funny and he's not
concerned about making them diverse.
It's like if you think about with
mustaches on your show,
because I wasn't even thinking about
that,
that's what he said.
And you should be able to do creatively
whatever you want,
especially when your goal is just make
stuff funny.
Like why should he have to.
I mean if you,
if I watch a show with all koreans in
it,
I don't get upset that there's no white
people say that.
Well,
you know what,
that's just because you're white and
you're privileged and there's an overall
problem maybe of not using enough black
people are not using enough people of
color,
but that's not each individual shoots
problem.
Well,
It's,
it's not the best thing about this world
that you know,
there's racism,
it's one of the worst things,
right?
It's not the best thing about our
culture that,
you know,
we aren't equally represented in the
media.
It's not the best thing when you have
to,
you know,
you have to factor in populations,
you have to factor in,
you know,
how long the,
these people who have been in the
business,
how long these people have been in the
business.
A lot of shit going on.
When you talk about putting a fucking
show on television,
a lot of people think that once someone
gets into a position where they have a
successful show,
then on top of having to create that
show,
they also have an obligation to be
diverse because they're representing
America and they're supposed to like
give opportunities to like a equal
percentage of the population.
For that story.
Storyteller show,
this is where it's a problem because no
know what you should be able to do what
you're not talking about.
Like sOme government position we're
talking about is a creative thing that
you're making.
You should,
if you are comfortable doing it only
with black people,
you should only deal with black people
if then,
because they're probably like,
well,
I asked like four or five girls.
None of them could do it,
so I did my part.
what am I suppose to get somebody worse?
Just because,
yeah,
it's ridiculous.
You should especially like that.
Like the storyteller type thing.
You should get whoever you think is
good.
It's your show things that you think are
interesting,
but I know you.
So I know if you find a woman who's a
gay black,
uh,
there's not that many black seven foot
tall woman and she's really funny.
You're fucking lover and you'll start
talking about our gracious.
If she's a five foot nine white girl,
you know who's really cute,
but she's really hilarious.
You'll say she's really hilarious.
I know you don't give a shit about
anything funny.
So just one of the reasons why I wanted
to play this when you're here because
it's like,
thIs is what you should be focused on,
but they're tricking him.
They're setup question.
It is a setup question because it's a.
It's a kind of a goofy,
you know what he's trying to do when
he's trying to make a good council.
He's also pretty much most of that show
is him in a car getting coffee with his
friend and look,
this clicks.
Yeah.
We'll have the people that hang out with
and there's not that many black comics
at the clubs.
There's nothIng wrong with it.
That's the point.
It's just who he is and who his friends
are.
Yeah.
He did a shoW with those four people,
so we're going to have them on.
We're going to force a black guy and
it's like it just have in this mostly
his friends and look what happens when
they had chris rock on.
They got pulled over,
so it's just.
Yeah,
at the end of their rope instead they
got pulled over.
He should be able to do whatever the
fuck you want.
It's his thing,
you know,
he shouldn't be able to do whatever he
wants,
but you know,
the idea that you should even debating
that he's got issues because what he
wants is different than when you.
Because it doesn't represent the exact
numbers,
so he had three out of 20.
If you have five out of 20,
would have been okay.
Nothing wrong with sex and the city.
There's nothing wrong with the show them
that is wrong.
No.
If you're a woman and you were in your
forties when that shit came out,
you would love it.
It's just wrong for ari shaffir,
but for them,
nothing wrong.
Women in entertainment,
if it's bunch of women doing shit for
women,
they should be able to cast whatever
women they want to cast.
It shouldn't be a man that steps up and
says,
hey,
my favorite use about left on
television,
saw it was a billboard of a girl.
Hold the gun up and another girl hold
another gun up and then another guy
behind her,
like in the force also and you're like,
what is that?
Lifetime television.
It's like scifi for women like tHis
could never exist.
Yeah.
What are you talking about?
You're hot and you're leaving the squad
and the guys behind you.
It's just accepting that role is like
psi phi for women.
It is.
Wouldn't it be awesome with the world
was like this?
Yeah,
they.
There was a few of those fucking silly
movies,
but that's okay for them,
man.
If that's what they want,
it's okay.
If that's what they want.
Black entertainment is so bad.
So bad.
What you need them is fucking garbage.
You mean like Tyler Perry?
is that what you trying to say?
Yes,
absolutely.
THat's one.
That's what all of it's so bad.
Have you ever seen like the cw,
the black shows which shows whatever
they are over the years,
but we showed up to the wayans brothers
to whatever with the wayans brothers.
It's just bad entertainment.
They're offering them.
THey never offer them anything of value.
You say them like there's some other
people.
Yeah.
They offer that group.
The blacks,
the blacks,
all their fucking black comedy movies.
Just like,
what is this soul plane?
It's just goofy.
Well,
with Robert Townsend.
Yeah.
remember he used to deal with shuffling.
He did some really cool,
funny movies that would happen to people
like that.
How many?
Like when?
It's really interesting because there's
like a bunch of known a white comedy
directors.
Judd apatow guys who produce phillips of
white,
top phillips,
one of those.
Yeah.
They're producing like white comedies,
hilarious white comedies.
You don't hear about a lot of black guys
that are doing that.
It's so true.
Yeah,
but aren't they white comedies or are
they just comedies?
Well,
they're not because craig robinson was
on a lot of them.
Yeah,
that's true.
That's true.
He was awesome and this is the end.
He was really good in that.
Fuck.
Yeah,
he was.
I liked the part of michael cera got
sabbath and somebody took my cell phone,
started ringing his backpack.
It's like,
oh,
that's really embarrassing.
That was a funny movie,
man.
When kenny powers came in,
that's when it became the most awesome
movie ever.
He's such a dickhead.
He started washing is good with
their fucking whatever water they had
remaining small amount of water,
but again,
I mean,
you should be able to make a show with
whoever you want to make a show.
It doesn't make you a racist.
Right?
It's irrelevant.
The terms you're talking about have
nothing to do with that world,
that world.
That's what he said.
It exists in funny,
that's it,
that's all that matters,
but the idea that you should have
affirmative action and comedy that you
should then that's essentially what
they're saying.
They're saying that you should have to
have x amount of women.
You should have to have x amount of
black people.
if you don't,
they're saying,
wait a minute,
do you have just a lot of white friends?
But then the problem is then you're
making female comedy worse.
You're makiNg it worse for advancing
people without merit.
Making it overall worse while you can.
Most certainly,
you know,
the other argument would be that he just
doesn't hang out in those cliques so he
doesn't know these funny women and it
would benefit everybody if he got to
know them and had them on.
I could see that argument.
Maybe if there was like a pool of talent
that you knew that was really fucking
crackling that you wanted to have on
your show,
but at the end of the day it's who he
wants to talk to.
Like when people say to me like,
why did you have a big foot expert on?
Because I want to fucking talk to him.
I don't know why do you have a
bowhunting expert on?
Because I want to talk to a bowhunting
expert.
Okay.
This is interesting.
You don't have to listen,
you know,
but if you want to,
uh,
I will do my best to try to make it
entertaining and I will try to ask the
questions that I have.
I will try to explore as objectively and
thoroughly.
But that's my perspective and my point
of view.
So I mean,
how,
I mean,
somebody asked me the other day like how
many gay people we had on,
I don't know,
like three or four or something like
that.
Like maybe melissa etheridge,
todd glass martindale.
Who else?
We had some other ones out.
Somebody.
Yeah.
Well whoever the fuck it was,
um,
you know,
and someone was like,
well why haven't you had more?
Whatever.
Who cares?
Like,
why,
why do I have to now I don't want to.
How about that?
Now you're bringing up.
I'm annoyed,
you know?
But then it's also like,
am I just not friends enough with black
people or gay people?
This man,
anybody.
I find interesting.
I'll talk to.
I give zero fuckS about what they look
like.
I don't care.
I don't care if someone's black or white
or fat or skinny.
If they're interesting.
They're interesting.
I don't care.
I really don't.
I don't care what your kind of music you
like.
I don't give a fuck.
It doesn't.
I'm not judgmental on that stuff.
please don't talk to anybody.
I'm sweatpants in it to jeff's son.
I'm into it.
I'm sweatpants in it with a jacket
jacket on,
fat fanny back with my higher primate
logo.
Have you seen the higher primates?
Fanny pack rat.
So sexy,
sexy.
Once you see it,
you'll unDerstand.
My passion was government eventually
will have purses,
but until then the higher primate fanny
pack the shaft on the of that sign.
Actually that beautiful leather.
Look at the front.
See that little
higher primate logo,
so it's.
Yeah,
it's a monkey with a chimp rather with a
light bulb.
I was sad like I got an idea.
First idea,
the first idea because that's the first
step.
A curious chimp.
We used to always look at these charts,
the comedy store to see who got what.
Rosa,
who's hire private was a few we didn't
know.
That's not my company.
My company's.
Well,
I can't tell you it shouldn't take it
online.
Well,
everybody keep it together.
But uh,
the um,
the higher primate fanny pack,
it's just the beginning from there.
I'm on my last launch,
a bunch of other get up.
She me off.
You see what natasha did when she had a
thing for new year's eve?
Yes,
yes.
Yeah.
People are mad at her and she made up.
There's no reason to get mad.
It's so dumb.
And she made the best apology you could
ever make.
It was perfect.
It was like,
sorry.
You misunderstood it.
Their old,
their teeth fall out when they're old.
That's the joke.
Well,
not only that,
she was like,
she was pretty clear that she was just
joking around,
you know,
it's pretty obvious that it was just
real.
Veterans are being mistreated as they
come home.
Now that's the issue.
You should worry about if you want to
honor the veterans.
It's a joke and it's not that people
were really upset.
Is it that people think that they have
the license to be upset and then they
can get you in trouble now what I was
trying to do,
they're trying to get you in trouble.
what I was just trying to change things.
They're trying to get you in trouble,
in trouble.
They can feel.
Yeah,
they can contact the network so you
should do something with this.
Like you don't have anybody in your
family that says something that dumb.
Occasionally they missed one.
You know they go for a little old
person.
JOy when vengeance and I deserved
vengeance.
She should be fired.
If an opposite of a drama is not any
good,
you can't fire anybody.
That's what I want to see as if it's not
such an innocuous joke.
If it actually is a borderline like rape
or murder or pedophile joke where it's
not completely nothing and it's not a
cute woman doing the non-apology.
I want to see how people get that or
people like chris rock or plus out
again,
tracy morgan and just do a one 80 and go
from like.
No,
you can say whatever he wants to.
Well,
all right.
You go too far.
So what happened?
Chris rock,
awkward.
TracY morgan to have that thing with the
case.
He said he went too faR.
it just totally flipped as well.
There's certain.
Wow.
There's certain things that you feel
like you can't fucking endorse.
Yeah.
That lack kind of gay bashing,
like saying that he would stab his,
his son if his son was gay.
People can endorse that.
I can endorse that,
but if you know tracy morgan forever,
it's what he does.
He says ridiculously outrageous shit
that he doesn't really mean and now
because it's popular,
we're going to go against it.
You caN't eat wants.
You know what he's doing.
Everybody knows what he's doing.
It's like a joke to pretend that he's
not saying something completely
outrageous,
that he absolutely doesn't matter how
old you are,
how old you want.
Oh,
you must be fast.
Fast.
My piece low.
Yeah.
He rubs his belly,
so we'll get pregnant who slap his belly
on that tv,
show someone getting pregnant tonight to
someone getting pregnant,
you know,
that's his whole thing was a real room
that he couldn't read a real legitimate
rumor that people are telling charlie
barnett couldn't read.
That's how he couldN't get on the
saturday night live.
Really?
Yeah.
Charlie barnett was.
Chris was shaped chappelle's teacher
that's mentor him and a lot of other
guys.
When I was in New York,
he was already not there anymore.
I don't know where he was.
He died,
died of aids,
I believe.
um,
but he was a,
like a guy who was dave chappelle.
He sort of taught dave chappelle had to
do,
um,
that those street side shows.
I think I might be talking to school,
but I have seen dave chappelle do a
street side show.
Dave chappelle in montreal.
It was pretty hilarious when he was
really young too,
is when I first met him.
I think he was probably like,
I first met him in New York and then I
saw him again up in montreal when he was
like,
maybe like 19 sit on the side.
He took his hat off,
put his hat on the ground and did a
comedy show and then pass the hat
around.
Wow.
And people put money in it.
It was before he was famous and he would
just do it at the drop of a hat.
Just do javelin notice.
Just when he was funny.
It was good.
He would kick cassius developed to get
the crowd.
Like he must've developed certain things
in order to get them to gather around.
I think he would just call them around
and you know,
he looks like a guy who would be fun to
listen to the talk so people slow down,
you know,
some,
some folks are in a hurry and some folks
aren't.
And the ones that aren't,
they circle them and then he'll do like
a little five minute comedy show and
then pass a hat around.
I saw him do it in montreal.
Well apparently charlie barnett used to
do that and he was like legendary out.
It was awesome.
He was awesome at like being hilarious
to a bunch of people,
like off the cuff,
he had material that he would do,
but they will also be off the cuff funny
and he would gather people around.
Then he would hand out of the hat,
pass out the hat,
you know,
and that's how he would make some money.
And uh,
he became famous,
like doing comedy,
did a lot of standup people,
loved him onstage and then he got an
audition for saturday night live and
apparently the word was that he got the
part but he couldn't read.
So since he couldn't read scripts,
they couldn't hire them.
That's tough.
The working environment without being
able to route.
And apparently he had a,
he had a problem with intravenous drugs
and he loved them.
Yeah.
He found out about them.
That's the problem,
you know,
and uh,
but he apparently was like a keep saying
apparently apparently or adjectives or
words.
He was like one of the pioneers of that
style of comedy.
Like,
yeah,
like natural talking.
Yeah.
Well,
not just natural talking,
but like knowing how to captivate a
group and get everybody settled down and
put out a hat.
Like that's a.
That's such a tough crowd that when you
go onto a stage at a comedy club must be
nothing.
Yeah.
It's like you're running up hill all
day.
Whenever we saw the third street
promenade people before we ever would
have thought of that to comedy here,
could I do it?
Yeah.
It's hard though.
I've never seen anybody do it besides
dave.
I've never seen anybody just do like
street comedy seems weird.
It does.
I see that goofy.
Like the dancers will do comedy in
between when they're going to make a
dance.
Well,
I don't think dave would do it today.
I mean,
I know he did do some shows in seattle
when remember when he wasn't doing
official shows anymore.
I did a show in seattle where it just
showed up and brought like a speaker and
started doing stand up in the park.
Yeah.
Wow.
Let's put it down his.
His career has been fucking fascinating.
It was a fascinating guy.
You ever heard?
I'm on the podcast.
I would definitelY,
but I've never run into him.
I need to run into him.
I haven't run into him since I've been
doing it.
He said I ran into him a couple times.
I got to get ahold of him.
He would be awesome to have on.
You know.
I bet he's a good dude,
man.
He's a funny fucking guy too.
He's a funny guy.
He's been.
He's been funny for a long
do.
When he came back from africa and did
that show in the main room?
I don't know if that was.
If that was after you stopped going
there before.
Have that on tape too.
Really?
In my car.
It was so packed and everybody was
there.
Fucking Bruce Willis was there.
Soundgarden was there.
The fire department showed up and just
asked if theY could sit on the steps to
block the pug and escape.
Wow.
Everybody.
That was the ticket.
Did you see kiss the other night was at
house of blues and there was like arnold
schwarzenegger was there.
Stallone was their families doing the
podcast.
Oh really?
Yeah,
dog.
The bounty hunter.
You got eddie bravo to come into.
Don't.
No,
I don't know if eddie can,
but I'm going to get an ace freely to.
Oh wow.
Awesome.
I met ace freely when I was like seven
years old,
how my uncle was a,
he was an artist and he worked for the
advertising agency that created the
album covers and the album art.
I was back when they had,
you know,
there were artwork for the album was you
would open up like especially like to
dislike kiss alive to have to uh,
records in it and it would open up.
THere's all these images and
advertising,
you know,
guys would put together these albums,
know they made the artwork.
So they hired artists,
graphic artists to create these things.
And ace really came into the office and
I was uh,
just staying.
I went to work with my uncle,
like he took me to work with them
because he was an artist at the time
too.
I was really into art and so he wanted
to see me to see like what his office is
like fucking case maybe I wanted to do
it someday and I just so happened to be.
He took me in a couple of times,
but it just so happened to be there the
day that ace freely arrived.
Was he wearing this makeup or no,
no makeup.
That's why I was so crazy because at the
time it was.
I'm like no one knew what they looked
like.
They would walk around with bandannas
over their face.
It was,
yeah,
it was a big thing like photographers,
we're constantly trying to catch them.
Oh wow.
Yeah.
They were trying to catch them out
because if they caught them they would
get the first photo of them.
There was a few calls like this where
you'd see you would take this much as
face.
You wouldn't see as total face you just
a little bit.
So you saw him.
Yeah.
So I saw him when I was like,
I think it was like seven or eight or
something like that.
It was crazy.
I couldn't believe it.
I was like,
starstruck.
Tell the rest of the classmates and have
them not believable.
Well,
my cousin had seen them a bunch.
My cousin,
I own a,
um,
she was uh,
like friends with them and they would go
play softball together and like she
would talk about it.
She's like,
it's the weirdest thing.
I played softball with gene simmons and
like you had no makeup on.
We were playing softball with kiss and
no one knows it's kits they have no
makeup on and you're like,
this is the nuttiest thing ever.
And my uncle Was like,
he's a really cool character,
very artistic character.
So hIs daughter was very cool as well.
She was really,
she's really smart and she,
you know,
so like her describing it was very,
it was like she was not,
she was totally taking into account the
bizarreness of it.
She's like some standing there and I'm
playing softball with kiss and asm got
this glove on.
I'm looking around and she's like,
what the soft with these guys didn't
have makeup on.
This is,
this is the most famous.
but I mean she was my age.
We were both like,
you know,
like oh,
they were huge.
Really?
Yeah.
they were gigantic.
I saw them in the nineties when I saw
them in the seventies when I was a
little kid.
My uncle took me to show and uh,
that's when he was working for the
company back then.
I was really young when they took me to
a kiss show.
That's weird.
I might've been,
I might've been like 10 or something
like that,
maybe 11 at the most.
I was 11,
but he took me to a kiss show.
Then I went to a couple and then I went
to two in a row with Kevin James and
yeah,
in the,
the,
uh,
the nineties,
a kiss when they made their comeback.
It was the nineties or the early 2000.
I think it might have been 90 days.
I don't think I was even on fear factor
yet.
And kevin was out here.
Kevin had won star search and search
sort of push.
Man.
Kevin is a bad motherfucker.
Norm mcdonald.
Kevin's one of the most underrated
standups ever.
Really?
He went.
He's.
Yes,
yes.
Listen to me.
That dude,
he could hit moments onstage.
He had some Bits on stage.
They were fucking murderers,
but he always wanted us to keep it clean
and family friendly and he wanted to
like,
you know,
make it so he didn't want to piss
anybody off.
He didn't want people to not be able to
go to his shows,
you know,
he,
he kept his act real clean,
especially once he had can't queens,
you know that he cleaned up even more.
He,
well he was just,
you know,
he would never do a bit that you would
do or I would do.
Never did.
Another one is our specialty.
I was one of the first hour specials
because we're just too big for a half
hour and it was just like,
let me tell you something.
I was with that dude when he was coming
up.
before you go to any of that shit,
that guy could kill me.
He was hilarious.
He was really funny.
He used to do this bit about getting
pissed because kevin is a sweet guy.
He's an awesome guy,
but if he gets pissed off,
he's got a fucking temper.
He doesn't do anythIng,
but he does get angry at shit.
He's not a violent guy,
but you could see I'm fucking crazy
about you.
So yeah.
Had this bit about his girlfriend.
He was like hitting the unlock button on
the door at the same time and she was
pulling the handle and they cancel each
other out and you have this bit where
they kept doing it again and do it and
it builds up and fucking hilarious bit
and he would go ape shit on stage and
scream and I don't even think he swore
back down and you might swear he like a
little bit like shit or something like
that.
Like every now and then.
But you know,
he was trying to do like a very specific
type of comedy.
You know,
a story about him in montreal or aspen
with sussman struck a deal.
He got where you're like,
come talk to my guy.
Couldn't see what he can get you.
Oh yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
That's an unfortunate story,
but I don't think we could repeat that
because it's very bad for someone's
business or whatever.
Yeah,
we,
we can't repeat numbers either,
but yeah,
he got lucky and got a good manager.
My manager knew exactly what to do.
They were trying.
He had other older manager that wasn't
given them such great advice and they
were about to get them to make a
terrible take this thing to a lot of
shitty things to them.
One of the things that said,
no one would ever believe this if you
never worked in hollywood,
but there was a guy that was working
with him before that actually told him
to not lose weight category.
Yep,
he dId.
The actual quote was,
kevin,
when you lose weight,
you're losing roles.
Wow.
He actually said that to him.
When you lose weight,
when you get healthy,
no one's going to like you.
When you get healthy,
it's not a.
It's not possible for you to be this
funny unless you're a fat fuck.
Okay,
so stay a fat fox so we can all make
money.
Kevin,
when you lose weight,
you're losing roles.
We're losing money.
Kevin.
People don't want you to know early,
but we can use you.
It's the worst thing ever because it
gave him a green light to eat.
Whatever the fuck you want.
Kevin,
when I first met him was like a pretty
stout character,
you know,
and he was even thinner and more stout
when he was in high school and he was
really into karate for awhile,
did a lot of karate,
really in good shape and when he's in
really good shape,
he was 200 pounds and that man just a
tank.
It was all pictures of Joyce Diaz.
We were like,
who's that?
He's a tank.
Yeah.
But when it.
When a guy tells you shit like that,
like you lose weight,
you're losing roles.
You're given a guy a green light to just
eat whatever the fuck you want,
you know,
that's rude.
They're just trying to make money.
They're just,
it just idiots.
People that want to tell you how you
should be,
you know,
you shouldn't be healthy.
There's kevin.
I don't need an iron anymore.
That's pretty cool.
and it's so hot down here.
I cannot take it anymore.
Although my role,
I have air conditioning,
which I love.
It's great because I grew up without air
conditioning.
It was the worst.
My dad was too cheap.
It was like we'll
do is bits because he probably wouldn't
like that because it starts two minute
comedy.
Yeah.
SO weird.
You probably would go,
god,
you fucking do my bed.
You know,
comedians are like,
take a chunk of their material and put
it on.
Like,
oh,
I hate that shit.
Don't fucking do that.
But he would kill me.
Man.
He was really funny.
He just,
you know,
decided to.
He got really into making the tv show.
I really enjoy the process of really
making a sitcom now.
He's good.
He's good at that shit.
He's good at comedic acting,
you know?
I just really wish you would really
chased comedy more.
Stand up guy was so funny,
man.
He used to kill me when we were kids
where like in our early twenties
together and we would do gigs together.
We did a lot of gigs together.
He was hilarious man.
He was hilarious dude.
And he was like real honest about his
insecurities and show people.
Some of them we started with are
actually still around.
Yeah.
A lot of them are still around eight it.
A lot of them have made it real in this.
Yeah,
like norton norton and I had been
friends since fuck since we were both
like 21 or something like that.
You know,
we're both like my open mic days.
Yeah.
Okay.
Well greg fitzsimmons is my oldest
friend ever.
greg fitzsimmons and I literally went on
stage like within a week of each other.
Wow.
We were friends in the dark,
dark days of open mic nights.
We were buddies back when we were
complete amateurs.
Neither one of them.
We were terrible.
We have nothing.
So to like be friends with your friends
now see him like I downloaded the past
six months where we're small.
Not so good for sure.
But I,
I downloaded his new comedy special.
He just has a comedy special is that's
put out that the one where he talks
about how,
how easy americans have it.
Yeah.
Oh,
it's fucking great.
Um,
but I listened to it on a,
on the way home from a gig and was
laughing my ass off.
It was really fucking funny,
you know,
it was really funny and it was so cool
to be able to drive home and listened
to,
you know,
that I started with and he's slaying and
even more cool for me for greg because
greg for a while was a.
Greg is a multiple time any emmy winning
writer.
OH yeah.
Was money writing.
Well,
he's like,
you know,
he's won emmys.
He's a really good writer.
You know,
he's got a good book as well,
but he decided to take some time off at
doing standup.
He didn't do standup for a long time.
It really didn't.
I mean maybe did it occasionally,
but he really didn't dive into it like
he's back doing now.
And then he,
after he did it,
every dove back into it,
then he put out this special and so it
was,
it was like extra cool driving around
listening to that special because I knew
what he did.
I knew how he worked.
I knew,
I knew that he got back into comedy and
I knew that he really loved it.
Again,
you know,
it's like a lot of our friends,
we talk about that,
like calvin and I had the same
conversation every week,
like he was just in some club,
but like he did a cap city and austin
and we're on the phone,
you know,
we're just both in our cars just
catching up and he goes,
he goes,
it's the greatest fucking job in the
world.
It's the greatest fucking job.
I don't want to do anything else.
He goes,
I do other things.
I don't want to do them.
He goes,
what I want to do is I want to do
comedy.
I want to tell jokes.
It's so fun when you watch them on
stage.
I've had a chance to do some shows with
him lately too,
and you could see him just really
enjoying this,
having done all these movies and all
these tv shows that he didn't really
necessarily enjoy because he thought he
was supposed to be an actor and then
seeing him just murdering with his own
silly goose style of comedy.
Because he's so silly,
you know,
really fucking great to see man.
Really great to see.
Really funny,
funny shit too man.
Like having,
knowing guys.
I've known calvin since [inaudible] 94
early.
So I've known greg since ada.
Greg's the longest running friends in
comedy,
but collin and I have been best friends.
It's like the moment we met,
you know,
I mean there's like,
there's like a core group.
I just went to New York.
No,
I met him out here.
I did.
I'm mad tv.
Oh,
he was on mad tv and I was the host of
mad tv.
He was on seventh heaven for like a
bunch of episodes.
Yeah,
he did fucking seventh.
Heaven and oz don't pull up videos of us
on mad tv.
I know what you're doing.
You were children back then,
but we became friends almost
immediately,
like we said,
like three or four sentences together
and we were playing and hanging out
together.
Yeah.
It's just a fun dude,
you know?
I knew.
He said it's hard to make fun friends,
but it's cool when you run into him and
you collect them,
you know,
was like,
oh,
I found a good one.
It's good friend,
and then you see that guy prosper.
You see that guy growing and developing
is like.
It's one of the Most depressing things
when you see a guy who used to do good,
like,
I don't want to say any names,
but guys that we know that had potentIal
and then they fell off and then they
stopped doing comedy altogether and
you're like,
my god.
We came up together.
Like that guy was just as good as me in
1998.
Like what the fuck?
Yeah,
they stopped,
they stopped doing comedy and they,
you know,
he got a job.
Like what job doing what?
Why did he see?
Oh my god,
why didn't you follow up?
scares everybody else too.
Like I said,
a possibility.
Yeah.
One of the guys we know stop people
don't know.
They don't understand and that's why
they get angry.
When I use the word civilian,
by the way people,
everyone who gets angry because I use
the word civilian comics,
go fuck yourself for real,
for real.
Go fucking stop your whining.
Stop your demand for respect.
Stop all of it up.
You know what we're talking about you
dummies.
We're talking aBout the dIfference
between someone who understands the
fucking hectic,
chaotic mental bore you go on in your
head when you're being a standup comic.
We're describing the mass of of this
life that you Will not understand if you
don't do it.
Just like if you're a Stock broker and
I'm not,
and you call me a civilian,
I'm not going to get offended.
I wouldn't get offended.
By the way,
if I was a fucking soldier either,
I wouldn't get offended.
You know what people are saying?
It's called a Figure of speech.
Don't be a can.
FInd some other shit to be a cut.
Find some other shit to be annoyed that
there's plenty of things that are real
that you can be annoyed at.
Don't be annoyed if somebody uses the
term sensibility.
That's silly.
You see that video of that comedian and
Tennessee that there was like a group in
the front row that were like wrestlers
and stuff like that.
Like these big guys start heckling and
then the guy gets on stage and racks and
right in the balls.
Rex who comments?
oh no,
here's the video.
Oh,
I don't want to see this man.
The guy is huge too.
It's a little cafe.
I don't even know wHere that is.
He hit him in the balls.
He gets on stage and then racks and
racks.
And why did you get the racks?
Oh,
he told them what it means.
Do you know the term
steak?
Shake my hand and be like,
did it?
I guess still in the room are so
delightful compared to this train wreck
over here.
Where did he start doing it?
Man.
Just wrote about the outbreak role play.
Role play gets catholic school girls.
Every time
we'll find it.
Then the heckler.
Why was he still in the room?
These clubs like tack the comic,
tell them to leave,
settle his bill and leave.
Guy comes on stage and taps you in the
balls.
It's over there,
just a little too comfortable hitting
each other.
You know,
when you hit each other for a living,
like wrestlers slap each other in the
face.
A regular person just not like that.
They don't want to deal with that shit
at all.
Like people wHo don't respect
professional wrestling.
Look,
you might not enjoy it as a form of
entertainment,
but you better respect like how hard it
is to do hyper camera.
This store,
the,
the those guys fucking.
They sacrificed every part of their bau,
weathered.
They're all broken up,
man.
That is a crazy fucking way.
or try to make a living.
He's throwing chairs at each other and
shit and jumping off the top rope and
fucking doing flips and landed on your
face.
Yeah,
that's some crazy shit,
man.
That is one of the most destructive jobs
in show business as far as like what it
does to your body laying on the ground.
OH my god.
Do you remember the brock lesnar one?
We did the shooting star press.
You know the.
He flew,
did a flip,
but he missed the flip and landed on his
fucking head.
Oh really?
Yeah.
He was trying to do a flip and like
pinot guy,
like he was going to do top rope and do
a flip and pinot guy,
but he missed.
It's just bam.
Right on his fucking head.
I hit slip.
oh,
that guy just need him in the balls.
I know.
Okay.
Just I don't want to watch this man.
That's fucked up.
Harsh.
Yeah.
You shouldn't let that guy on stage.
He definitely should have said,
what are you gonna do like what's up
with that fake bravado of having that
guy on stage and saying,
what are you going to do in this fucking
giant wrestler guy standing in front of
me,
but balls taunting him.
He shouldn't be on stage,
first of all.
Definitely for sure.
But you know the fucking shows
basically.
It's a weird position.
I always like,
oh,
what do you want me to walk away?
Well,
yeah,
you getting bullied by a giant wrestler
too.
I mean that guy was twice the size of
that guy.
It should mean why don't you go back and
sit down and nobody throws them out.
It's ridiculous.
You can't go onstage and need somebody
in the balls and then they don't throw
you out.
That's bad.
Why can't you get sued for that?
Like even like just this random
strangers kneed me in the balls.
That's not part of my job.
Yeah.
You should be able to sue for that.
The club for for sure.
You should be able to see the guy.
Yeah.
The guy for nina in the ball.
Well tammy Had that drink thrown on her
and she tried to press charges and the
sheriff was like,
nah,
it's just comedy.
Why?
She's like,
he threw a drink at my head.
He threw a glass at my head.
I want to press charges.
That's assault.
They didn't bring them in.
That's,
that's insane.
You can't throw a glass at somebody if
he hit her.
That's a fucking weapon.
It's just part of comedy.
It's like,
what?
Why?
Why is it part of comedy?
We don't agree to that fucking lazy cop.
That's what that is.
That's a guy that didn't want to fill
out some paperwork.
That was with tammy because the actual
assault didn't happen.
I don't know because it didn't actuallY
hit her or he's a local and she's not so
like I'm not going to arrest somebody.
HAve some traveling in la.
It wasn't here.
It was on the road somewhere.
Oh,
well it's like,
that doesn't make any sense.
Like where did this take place?
It must have been some fucking
hillbilly.
Yeah.
I don't know exactly.
Texas or somewhere.
A asheville making shit up.
You just making sure.
I don't know where it was.
Nowhere near each other.
Somewhere in Canada.
Something.
So I read back in Florida,
I don't know.
Something.
yeah man,
that's not cool.
But you know,
that's one of the problems with owning a
club.
You want a club,
you're serving people.
One of the most ridiculous drinks,
one of the most ridiculous drugs when it
comes to behavior,
like managing your behavior towards
lights.
You just give people like this drug that
makes them want to behave like a fucking
asshole,
like a good percentage of people want to
behave like an asshole on that,
on that drug.
And then you're selling that.
That's what you sell and you need them
to be around.
And then you got some guy who was on
stage talking mad shit about sucking
decks and shooting common to people and
people getting crazy.
Good,
crazy.
They're drunk and someone's talking
about sex and crazy.
Yeah.
they get nutty and they,
they just can't believe what they hear
and they want another drink.
Where's that fucking waitress?
I want to drag.
Yeah,
they heard somebody talking loud and
there's a lot of that.
We shut the fuck up.
LIke sometimes you hear that you guys
need to shut the fuck up and they hear
that like in the audience,
like people arguing and people or
somebody else tells them to be quiet
because they can't hear.
Last time we were at um,
for a duncan and I were at the hollywood
improv in Florida.
And like some people almost duked it
out.
Yeah.
Because one gRoup was talking,
the other group turned around.
They were like,
you shut the fuck up.
Like a guy like jumped up and he was
pointing at these big fucking giant fat
guy.
You shut the rob ford looking type
character.
He was screaming at people and they were
screaming back at him.
And it was like,
wow,
in the middle,
in the middle of the fucking,
you guys aRe all this
disruptive.
Please stop that.
Yeah.
He was getting super angry and loud
because the guy behind him was loud.
Like iT was more about him than it was
even about.
it wasn't like he,
even though there was like 300 people
there for the show.
Like I understand that this guy was
being a dick,
but him,
his yelling made it way crazier for
everybody else.
Like he wasn't concerned about that.
Like once the confrontation started,
it doesn't matter.
Sorry everybody.
But everybody.
Yeah.
Everybody else.
Fuck you.
Fucking superman gun into his latest
one.
Just destroying buildings.
Got into a fight and destroyed
buildings.
That's so stupid.
Why does he fight in the desert?
If you're superman,
you grabbed guys.
You bring them out in the desert and
kicked her out.
So it here.
You kick people's ass in the middle of
the city.
Fucking dummy.
You could fly around the world in a
second and you choose to duke it out in
the city.
You're an asshole.
Guilty connects case.
Send them to the side.
Say if I was a fucking judge and
superman came in and he told me smash
these buildings apart.
Be like,
what?
Why didn't you take him to the moon?
Duke it out up there.
You fucking asshole.
Oh yeah,
that's right.
I think he wants.
He can do anything.
Superman can fly to space.
He's fucking superman.
Yeah.
You can't see.
He lives in a different kind of planet.
Man.
Never likes to americans.
That reason.
I'm like,
he seemed indestructible.
Yeah,
totally likable.
Unless you get that kryptonite.
KryptOnite is right.
It's what it makes them weak.
It takes them out of character.
Can't make decisions for himself.
That is what it.
Eventually it's success.
Power way and he dies.
So there's times where you just know
you're making the wrong decision with a
woman or with kryptonite,
with a woman and you're just like,
oh,
why am I doing?
Even as you're doing it,
you're like,
why?
It's god because they have be up.
Well,
you know what it is,
man.
Your genes want to spread and you can't
help it.
And women who have beautiful bodies,
like a woman's body is the most
incredible backnet from.
And I sort of came a little bit.
I'll just wipe it off.
It'll be fun.
Let me just get my finger in there and
cleaned it out.
I would not have made that decision
yesterday.
Like this dinner.
What?
No,
I did not share.
I did it with a black girl.
Finally.
Bam.
Pete.
And then tell me.
Hold the story.
Talking to them about how.
I guess so I don't know.
Just so you know everybody.
My next storyteller shows in los
angeles,
February 27th at the improv.
Me,
mark,
marin,
ralphie may.
Louis cuts so far.
Wait.
Yeah,
$5.
It's nice show.
I liked that show.
I liked the one that you had with
natasha.
Bobby lee's the going is easy.
And you were all talking about the whole
thing.
It was a fun one.
Yeah.
Do you like it?
Yeah,
I loved it.
It's so funny.
I.
Bobby can't not be funny.
Yeah,
that was a really good one.
Look at.
This is not happening.
Go do a youtube search for that.
You'll find it.
But yeah,
that was a good one.
The eventually just lost control.
If they just like,
oh,
whatever,
keep going.
I liked her bobby lives and to we both
would you say,
no,
you're wrong in somebody else's.
You're wrong.
He'll go,
oh,
okay.
All righT.
It was really cool because I've heard
that story so many times,
but never actually
seen like a natasha around.
All of us brought up the water thing.
I can tell you were like,
oh,
I did do that.
But you asked about who was right,
who was wrong.
It was like,
it doesn't matter.
I'm just embarrassed about my behavior.
I don't care who else's behavior.
Yeah.
Because you dumped a water glass on her
heartbreak man.
It gets ya up.
San jose improv march,
middle of march and a against chicago
this weekend.
I love that place.
I was just staring and go across the
state that uh,
yeah.
Improv.
Go across the street.
There's a museum right there too.
Yeah.
been hosea and probe down the street
from joe's.
Joe's original joe jo.
Good.
Oh,
they have like a real wood grill for
steaks there.
Oh yeah.
they have like real wood coals.
They put lumped charcoal underneath the
steak.
It's a charcoal broiler.
Really boiler.
Yeah.
Yeah,
dude,
you could watch them if you get a seat
by the bar.
We went there once with two fighters.
We've been there a bunch of times.
John fitch and mike's wick.
That was a mix quick was telling us
about how we used to work for,
uh,
the United States government.
He was working in Russia and their
buildings were bugged.
The russians bugged the buildings with
incredibly sophisticated equipment that,
and he was like,
they were so far ahead of what we were
capable of.
He said they had bugs that were
operating on the power generated by the
movement of the building in the breeze.
What figured out a way to generate
enough power to keep the microphones
going and,
and transmitting,
transmitting like producing energy.
And they got it from the movement of the
fucking swaying of the building.
He was like,
they were so far ahead of us.
Why were they bugging his room?
There were bugging the whatever building
he was working at.
Government building he was working with.
people don't realize is that the,
the soviet union during the cold war,
like during the advancement of their,
their rocket program,
along with our rocket program,
they got the first fucking guy in orbit
man over.
I mean they were incredibly advanced.
They things.
one of the reasons we've made up the
moon landing.
Well,
I don't think we made up the moon
landing.
I've changed my position.
I,
yeah.
This is what I think.
I think
give me my hours back,
five years to figure it out and
figure it out.
Initially if I think if you watch that
fox show,
watch the fox show,
the moon landings,
it's very compelling.
It's very compelling.
It's a really interesting how it is
real.
What's saying it's not real.
Um,
but the odds of that being true,
it's so small.
It's like I don't know what haPpened,
but if I had a guest would happen.
I would say they went to the moon and I
wOuld say when you look at some of the
photos that look like they're staged and
the fact that all of them were centered
there very well could have been some
counterfeit photos.
They definitely did a little bit of that
back then in nasa,
there was a photo from gemini,
I believe it was gemini 15,
it was Michael Collins and they took a
photo of him and training with these
wires and this harness on and then they
blacked out all the wires and the
background and then use the same photo
and said that he was in space.
Really it was doing a spacewalk like
who's taking his picture that spacewalk
nobody.
It wasn't a real photo.
There was nobody out there with the
fucking cameras with photos,
so we didn't know that photo.
Just.
They didn't think that people are gonna
think that many steps ahead.
So I think there it's very possible that
they might have faked some things,
like some photographs might have been on
a soundstage or stuff there.
Yeah,
for publIcity and to make sure that they
got a record of john kerry show those
pictures of Syria above dead bodies and
it was from five years ago.
Dude,
my favorite quote,
those clinton's quote about it,
clinton talks about when he was a kid,
he was working for a carpenter and the
guy said that he didn't believe anything
on television that those television
fellers can put things on tv and make
you think it's real.
And he said,
back then I thought that guy was a quack
but or a crank.
But during my eight years in the white
house,
I saw things that made me think that
maybe he was ahead of his time.
Well,
clinton quote on the moon landing,
do you think they tell each president
like,
here's the catch you up on the moon or
do anything that I don't even tell them?
Why would they want to tell them?
Well,
if it really was fake,
which again,
I don't necessarily think it was.
I think it's more likely that there some
fuckery involved in some of the evidence
because you know,
they were trying to create things that
were used for publicity and there's
some,
some video that looks really fucking
hokey.
There's like,
there's this video of them jumping
around with.
they're on trampolines when they're on
the moon.
Yeah,
it's really weird.
It's really weird stuff because the,
the,
there's no consistency in the way they
move.
Like if you watch the earliest video
from apollo 11 when they're walking on
the moon,
you can watch their movement and then
watch the,
the later stuff.
It's like they move a little
differently.
Like they can do weird shit.
Like they can jump and fly through the
air,
you know,
later in the uh,
in the,
in the videos they got better at
whatever they were doing to get better
at walking into.
Well,
it's just weird.
So I think that it might very well be
that some of the footage that you look
at,
it's possible,
and I'm not suggesting that we didn't go
to the moon.
I know I haven't passed,
but what I'm suggesting is some of the
footage might be fake.
It's possible they used to do that kind
of stuff back then.
I know we don't like to think that,
but they did a lot of stuff,
but now they still do it now they still
fake things.
Now it's got good boards of martin
luther king with white women.
Sure.
MeanwHile,
martin luther king fucked a lot of white
women.
How about that?
How about he loved it?
Who wouldn't your mind?
Luther king.
Yeah,
I bet he did.
So he knew he was going to die.
Just a rampage.
Get the white posts.
What's this black girl like 5:00
PM or 2:30
AM.
What does that mean?
The color.
Oh,
like five per.
This is a starter.
Black.
okay.
She wasn't,
I mean for me to go in full bore.
That's kinda crazy,
right?
She was not from this country.
She was from like uh,
the uh,
england or lIke the or the or the.
I'm sitting anglosaxon.
Jamaica.
Yeah.
Like raised their.
Real white.
Real.
Not hip.
Hoppy at all.
Hip hop.
It was a very starter,
like just get in there.
Was she half black now?
I mean,
you know,
they're all black.
Did you notice that man?
Did the vagina seem any different to
you?
Any colors?
Any shapes?
Surprisingly similar to white posts.
It was pretty shocking actually.
How similarly shaped and feeling it was.
What's the same?
They're humans,
but then it got weird which she snored
and it was like a manly trouble after
that.
No,
no,
no.
Mainly way to sleep.
Watching your dick go into that pink
holdout with the contrast with the black
is such a coolest sight though.
Like if you have a darker one when he.
Because they are just bright pink inside
like pink starburst.
You have a darker one,
medIum rare.
He's not the kind of things that women
want to hear.
It's like a black and steak with the
medium rare.
Yeah,
exactly.
Inside.
Yeah.
So good for you.
Thanks.
I'm adding diversity to your.
Exactly.
Broadening my horizons.
I think a lot of people would salute you
for that.
I'm also dating chicks a little bit too.
Yeah,
tHat's weird.
That weird.
It's hard right now to go on like full
dates and like,
oh,
let's just try to explore you aS a
person instead of like you get bored,
try to get laid.
It just seems like fuck the
conversations you're having in my head.
I'm like,
come on,
let's just go back and fuck.
Wow.
I don't say that out loud.
That's what I think,
but that's what you think.
You don't really want to talk to them.
You just want to fuck them.
Yeah.
So I want to get to the point where I'm
like,
no,
let's enjoy a new human and fucking
enjoy them for a minute.
Trying to mature.
Right?
To,
uh,
to,
to find women that you actually like as
people and not just as sexual partners,
but if you get some just purely sexual
partners,
then you can do that.
Then you can afford to explore with a,
with a woman.
That's true.
Once your needs are met,
which are many biologic funding.
Yeah,
that's a weird thing where you supposed
to not be able to say that,
but a woman is allowed to say that if a
woman says that,
you know,
hey,
I take these men and I let them know,
look,
we're just here to.
I'm here to fuck.
Okay,
I'm busy.
I've got a career.
You can fuck me.
And then we'd done and you got to go
home.
You know,
it's not gonna argue with the guy will
be like,
okay,
god says,
I was like,
you fucking asshole.
Could you imagine if there was a hot
woman who ran a business or something
like that and whatever.
She makes fucking sculpture.
She say time,
but she needs to get laid.
So she says,
you listen,
here's the deal.
Okay,
I like you.
I think you're hot.
I want to fuck,
but I don't want you being my boyfriend.
I don't want you hanging around.
You can't sleep over and don't ever
fucking tell me what to do.
But if you want no strings attached,
you come over and fuck me,
suck your deck and
we'll have a good time.
And then when we're done you leave.
He'd be like,
okay,
I'll do that for you.
You'd be like,
yes,
I knew she was out there.
It's um,
I was having this discussion with one of
my wife's friends who happen to be gay
and they were talking about,
um,
the difference between two gay guys like
hooking up gay guys,
meeting and hooking up and a guy and a
girl meeting and hooking up the guy.
And a girl trying to figure out how much
again,
are we gonna have in this.
How much yann for possession.
Who's gonna?
Be in control here.
Setting it up.
It's a girl.
Is a girl going to tell you what to do
and answer your phone for you?
Or is she going to leave you alone?
Let you be you.
You gonna leave her alone.
You gotta.
Let her wear whatever she wants and not
get fucking weird.
Were there.
You know what's going to happen here?
Are you going to say what are you really
going to go out with that skirt you?
Really good?
Well done.
Skirt for real.
You're setting up my knees,
not your fucking knees.
It's not your knees,
your knees.
Okay,
I see your legs.
God.
Do we really need that much attention?
You know there's,
there's that,
there's that dude.
And then there's people that like,
are you a copy but you have fun.
Have a good time.
You know,
who are you going to be and who,
what?
What's she going to be happiest with
that early on?
Also finding someone who's like brings
out the best in you.
Like sometimes you could have
relationships that bring out the worst
in you.
You're like,
hey,
do you want to fight it initially
forward leaning forward.
Oh,
it's
so not necessarily for any of us to do.
It's just not,
you know,
any of us that are involved in
altercations,
like so much of it as it's both people's
responsibility.
You know,
there's a dance going on when two people
communicating with each other and a lot
of times we're shitty dance partner.
Yeah.
Sometimes I feel like telling people
that look at doesn't.
It's nobody's fault,
but you guys are never gonna work
because you just entered into this too
much.
You're just to fighting.
Some people like it,
man,
that's a,
that's a source of drawing their life.
They don't even realize that it's
completely subconscious,
but they liked to duke it out.
They lIke it,
they liked the fucking hate it.
I don't like it with anybody.
I don't like it with friends.
I don't like it with giRlfriends.
I don't like it with anyone in business.
I don't like with other comics.
I don't like it,
man.
It's nOt fun.
I would way rather be friendly with
everybody.
Yeah,
well it's way easier that way.
It is way easier.
It makes everybody feel nicer,
but there's moments man,
but you'll run into people.
You're like,
god dammit.
I got to fucking like defend my position
here.
I gotta like stay afloat here.
I gotta I gotta go to shut the fuck up
and leave me alone.
Like there's A moment where you have to
like say something or be assertive with
someone.
Just get them to fucking leave you own
it.
Can just do this.
People that just don't get it.
They will just fuck with you until the
end of time.
They're just so goofy and clunky.
They just don't get it.
I had an argument once at a party.
This guy was trying to tell me that the
un rapes children in africa rapists.
Those.
Yeah.
As he was telling me that they were
raped some for apples.
That's what he's saying,
but it was the dumbest conversation.
He raped him to other people.
Give them apples for like job well done.
Giving them apples to fuck them.
He Was saying it was like the rape them
for apples.
You saying it was great.
The guy was just such a douche bag.
He was um,
he was a country music guy who wound up
getting arrested for cocaine dealing.
He's like a singer and it's really
terrible country music band that my
friend knew.
Yeah.
And he was like that low pro rah rah
american guy,
but in the most idiotic way possible.
And uh,
you know,
he was,
they were talking about the United
States,
what they're doing over in Afghanistan
and this and that.
And He was just going on about the un
rape and people for apples.
And I was like,
what the fuck are you talking about?
Like what,
how can you,
first of all,
if you give someone an apple,
it's prostitution.
It's not rape.
Give them an app on your phone.
Yeah,
it's unfortunate,
but it's not the best prices in the
world.
Rape you with an app.
Unless you're fucking someone with an
apple,
you're not really raping them for apples
unless it's a mac book pro.
It's pretty good deal.
Yeah.
If you can get a mac book pro,
fuck you guys like really good plus one
techie,
I'll give you this or whatever it was.
It wasn't just that.
It was just the way this guy was just so
aggressive with me.
It was just like such a point and he put
his hands on me like on my shoulder and
said,
oh,
it's okay.
Like looking me in the eyes saying it's
okay.
I understand you just hate America.
I understand you're saying,
oh submissive.
It's just like,
dude,
get your fucking hands off me.
Like,
and that's when it turned ugly.
I was like,
you gotta get your fucking hands off me.
Don't touch me dude.
Don't touch me and talk to America.
Because I questioned it.
He had escalated it to not just that I
hate America,
but that he was going to like do some
weird shit to me.
I'm like,
hold onto me.
You know?
It was really gross.
That does push it up a level and
somebody touches you or like,
like you on the head.
It was a long time ago by the way.
It was a long time ago.
Who knows?
If I would've ever even entered into
that conversation today,
I don't think I would.
I think today I'm much more skillful at
the art of evading nonsense.
I would have known what it was.
I was the upside.
None.
I would have known,
but back then I would be like,
fuck,
this guy fucking touched me.
You know?
It was like I was ready to kill him.
I,
it was just,
it was the most ridiculous guy ever.
Like those people in your show,
you'll run into the man.
Oh,
some of the safety people yelling,
shut the fuck up.
It's like,
it's all unknown.
It's like you didn't have to say that.
Oh,
the people at the comedy show.
Yeah.
Well,
you know,
the only way to know that you shouldn't
go too far is to see the results of
going too far or other people when it
gets to those artists.
Like you could've just walked away and
greg was right.
Everybody is ready to fistfight.
Well,
he's very competitive too.
When I did a,
doug loves movies and san diego,
it was me and greg fitzsimmons and,
and he took it as a game and then like,
could he thought I wasn't taking it
serious and if you can tell immediately
like,
no man,
we're in a game,
right?
Yeah,
he plays good pool.
They kicked me out of my apartment
because let him stay at my apartment
while I was in Australia.
They're like,
no,
it's not so much As a friend of mine
who's a place to stay,
so I'm just
letting him stay there.
Like,
no,
it's not allowed.
I'm like,
I'm going to keep doing that because my
friend like,
I can do that.
And she left me a note if I get out how.
That's ridiculous.
Yeah.
It wasn't an official eviction.
It was just like,
we suggest you leave.
Why?
Because I don't know.
I think she had a really good hard on
for people subletting or something.
I don't get it.
People are weird with their
confrontations mean some of them are
necessary,
but there's guys like eddie gift.
It was a perfect example.
That motherfucker,
every time you talk to him,
he's got some new,
he's got somebody else getting so we're
out in the parking lot and I'm like,
fuck you and fuck you and you guys want
to go.
Let's go right now.
and I'm like,
what are you talking about?
Why did it get to their fighting in a
parking lot and the middle of the night?
Everyone,
everyone's drunk.
He hangs out with
people that are like that.
Also.
There's also this chris wild guy,
I don't know if you know him or not.
He's like fighting with tony hinchcliffe
right now on this show.
Like they're battling out of what?
What do you mean by battling?
Like they ads has,
has a show talking shit or whatever it's
called now and there's a guy that's
always on the show called eddie if and
I,
chris,
while tony was on the show also with
this guy,
didn't know him,
you know,
just thought it was a friend of his.
And then guess what happened is like the
wild guy who was like kind of mad that
he,
tony didn't know who he was or kind of
like upset or something,
and then they kind of went back and
forth on the show.
But now I guess he's just chris wild
won't let it drop and has been like
tweeting a things to tony and stuff and
just,
I don't know if,
you know,
chris wilder and I used to have a tv.
I dunno what the fuck happened.
I can't really comment.
I don't know what the specifics of it
were but.
But I'm on team.
Tony hinchcliffe always over there.
That's rosa parks on that.
So it's a parks yamaka.
Um,
I don't think that's a yamaka kid.
She's the one that lights can.
Jimi hendrix was like that.
As light as you're fucked,
you're fucked.
It's hard to tell.
In That photo I went a little darker.
The black and white photo.
So is the hendrix photos,
black and white photo.
That's toronto.
He got busted for heroine.
Son had hail when I went to visit his,
his childhood home in vancouver at a
small shrine to him.
Really?
Yeah.
Jeff ross.
A big focus on what they were near.
That's not to data at 27,
28 years old.
Was he 27 and 28,
27,
27 years old.
He's got a shrine.
You.
Where's your trying bitch?
I don't have a shrine.
How can we get in the shrine and.
Good question.
That's a good question.
That should be a goal.
A lot of people want to engage.
A specialist should have a fucking
strong and fierce shrine already.
The great was born here or the already
the great is born from the mediocrity of
his mother's pussy right here.
Just make my own stride.
the hospital,
whatever.
Right.
It like if you ever read someone's bio
on their website,
you know,
they wrote it themselves and makes you a
fucking up their lives in a part of like
near Washington dc where people have
historic houses things and he just made
one up.
I made up of historic house.
It was like a stop on the underground
railroad or something like that.
you just made it up.
Did he apply for it?
Like,
it made it a real?
Uh,
I don't know exactly how he did it.
If he wants the city,
I'm like,
this happened here.
So if we could get a plaque or if you
just bought a plaque and stuck it there.
Oh,
okay.
Probably mostly bought a prac.
Right.
It would be really hard to pass that
through city though.
Tell them like.
Yeah,
they'd be like,
we ain't even know unless you really
super.
Yeah.
It was like some writer stayed here when
he was visiting.
Well,
there's probably a bunch of places that
do kind of qualify for that.
Like for instance,
like Stephen King has a house in Maine,
in bangor,
Maine.
And like that house should be a
historical house in my setting up there.
Just that,
like that was his house for so long and
it's like he's got these wrought iron
gates that have these bats on them and
shit.
Really dope ass house and it's in the
middle of this town of bangor,
Maine.
And everybody knew about it and he's
such a legendary writer that that house,
to me,
It's like,
that's like an iconic house.
So you'd put like a historic.
Yeah,
make it,
make it a fucking museum for Stephen
King fans can come in and see.
This is the desk that he actually wrote.
You know,
some of his novels that I love those
little museums across the country.
I'll tell you man,
if they did that,
they would pay for that house a dozen
times over.
Just let people go and see.
Fuck.
Yeah,
I would,
I would pay if I was in boston and I
knew could fly up and just check out the
desk where Stephen King wrote the
shining.
Fuck you.
I would look at that thing I want.
I just want to be in the room.
ThIs is where he wrote cujo and he
didn't remember it.
Soak it a.
Yeah.
This is where you fit so much coke and
drank so much booze.
He didn't even remember writing.
Stephen king did dinner to coke.
Oh my god.
Did he do coke?
Stephen king was a maniac.
Became wIthout cigarettes to massive
amounts of coke and drink beer and he
would drink like 16,
17 beers at night and just write until
he blacked out and then fall asleep and
they'd get up in the morning,
coke it up and just do it again.
Yeah,
he was a maniac.
wow.
Joe frothing at the mouth.
He doesn't remember any of it.
It was all him.
He was cujo who knows.
I mean,
I'm sure there were some analogies in
there somewhere between a lot of his
demons and the demons he was
experiencing by being an addict,
but he was getting addicted to.
I heard his own writing or whatever the
book is.
Great.
It's great.
Yeah.
I've got two copies of it and realize
one.
Oh wow.
Yeah,
it's really good.
It's really good.
It's,
it's,
he's an,
he's a master to me,
you know,
and uh,
a master a of a specific type of genre
was him.
Well,
it's a specific type of entertainment
that I really enjoy,
like complete fantasy vampires and
demons and spaceships with aliens.
And I loved that shit.
I love stories.
Yeah.
I love all that stuff.
I'm a huge,
huge Stephen King fan to me.
He's like,
he made the World a cooler place.
he made the world a place with the
movie.
Carrie,
you know,
with the book carry with christine.
That movie about the haunted car.
That was a fucking great movie,
man.
He wrote that book too,
which is even better than the movie.
You know,
christine was.
A lot of them were.
Oh,
he was.
The books are too long.
There's too much detail.
Too much.
You would like to have seen it all in
the movie,
but it's impossible.
The movie's got to be two hours.
I got a lot of shitty acts.
A lot of those movies though,
like salem's lot.
Yeah,
a lot of life.
Let's just do this for 40 grand.
Yeah.
Well those I think was lot was for
television.
I think that was made for television.
Was it?
That was,
was it sam flatmates for television?
I think it was.
Um,
then there was the silver bullet movie,
the silly werewolf corey haim member.
But then he also wrote fucking stand by
me.
Yeah.
Which is so out of his genre.
Now he could write anything,
man,
he could write anything.
He's a bad motherfucker dude.
Then he followed those,
uh,
those,
a minor,
not minor league,
cub scout baseball players.
What are they called?
It's a little little leagues.
He followed one,
like started writing articles with them
and they went all the way to the little
league world series while he was
following them,
writing about them.
Oh,
I didn't like the bangor Maine team.
Went to the nationals or something like
that.
He was like writing their local paper
about them.
Yeah.
Just follow them along that season.
Crazy.
Yeah.
Well it must be awesome for those guys.
Well,
he can do whatever he wants.
He can do whatever he wants and he
didn't have to apologize to anything to
anybody.
Yeah.
He's an interesting cat.
Stephen king for sure.
And he's really like giving in the way
he communicates,
like his ideas have him on your podcast.
I would love to.
he's interesting in the way he
communicates a,
you know how he goes through his
process.
He's super honest about it and he's one
of the rare guys that doesn't have like
a setup like story in his head.
He like has these characters and he has
this idea that he starts with and they
just goes,
starts writing,
it just starts writing,
almost like goes into this crazy
transcend and,
and constructs this world and then you
get sucked into it and then you read it
after he's done with and you're like,
holy shit,
you know,
he just brings it out of nowhere.
It's not like,
like we had scott sigler on the podcast.
It was a really cool guy and a very,
very good writer as well,
but he has a totally different approach.
It's got sick,
was approach is he knows exactly where
he's going.
He knows where it's going to end,
he knows where this is going to happen
and get changed up.
He knows this and has to just sort of
fill it in and figure it out.
Flesh it out.
Yeah.
And you know,
make it to his liking.
but he,
he's very systematic about it and we
were talking about stephen king's
approach that he just lets it go and
that guy,
you know,
I just don't do it that way.
I couldn't do it that way.
But for him obviously it worked.
But for cyclers,
a great writer to be in his way works
too.
There's no right or wrong way to do it.
Do you write like that to you?
Like say I want to write a joke about
driving a car?
No,
I'll toss things over my head.
I'll write a note in my notebook and
then like when I looked to see what
jokes I should do on stage tonight or
whatever,
I'll keep passing that note.
I'm gonna keep thinking about it and
then when I'm driving or when I'm on the
subway,
all I keep thinking it over and then
I'll just like do it on stage.
So you don't actually sit in front of
the computer.
How come?
You know,
do you try that?
I've never,
I've tried it,
I've done it before but it's never
really stuck.
I just kinda think things out in my
head.
I just let my mind wander.
I think
you should write blogs.
You would have some fucking hilarious
blogs,
dude,
and it gives you.
The thing about writing blogs is it
gives you like an opportunity to spend a
lot of time thinking about a subject
because in the time that it takes you to
write it and type it out,
you have to figure a lot more.
You're thInking a lot more and you're
thinking a lot more in the containment
of a particular subject.
So you actually do the thinking.
Yes.
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
It's forcing you to focus on one
particular subject to and sometimes just
that extra focus is all you need to get
that extra path.
You take off that bit.
Like,
you know,
sometimes you find a bit like,
I don't know if it's this way for you,
but for me it is.
At least I'll have an initial direction.
And then along the way I realized that's
not the right direction.
The right direction is one of the other
taglines and then I'll go,
yeah,
totally,
totally turns it on its head.
I find that those take place more when I
sit down and write things like really
right thing.
Yeah.
Because I give myself more,
more paths,
like say if you're talking about,
um,
lava lamps,
whatever,
and you're going on a lava lamp path
when while you're on that path and
you're writing it out,
instead of just thinking about it in
your head,
when you're forced to actually mash
those keys and form a sentence in the
correct way,
like you're going to read it to
somebody,
you know.
Oh,
that [inaudible].
yeah,
that's pretty dope.
What's that?
It's a writing software program.
Has,
I can't see it.
Can't see it.
It's a corkboard with index cards on it,
but a virtual corkboard and You can put
your notes on those virtual corkboards
good.
Evernote sucks.
There's some.
Yeah,
every.
Well,
I like evernoTe because they don't lose
stuff for me to lose stuff.
Really.
I've looked at.
It's been written about it loose stuff
for you to really,
you know,
you've been.
It's been written about online,
you know?
Ooh,
that's not good.
Yeah.
Anyway,
yeah.
I think more people would benefit from
blogs.
That's why I've written some of my best
stuff.
So I'm,
I'm,
uh,
gonna start going back into blogs.
I'm going to commit to a one blog a
week.
Really?
Yeah.
And then what?
You won't mind doing material out of
your blogs?
Nope.
I don't mind doing that because it
becomes an idea like it's an idea and
the blog and then it becomes a bit full
thing.
well it's either that or you don't get
the blocks.
I think people like to read things and I
think that some of them are never going
to go to see my standup or friends will
get to see the germination.
And if You don't like it,
that's okay.
I get it.
I mean I've heard people complain about
subjects that we talk about on the
podcasts that eventually what's on your
mind.
The problem is that's what's on your
So I'm going to do with on stage what's
on my mind.
It's also the problem that some people
are just annoying concept,
like to complain about shit and they get
to talk to everybody gets to talk.
You know,
it's one of the beautiful things about
the internet and one of the annoying
things about the internet,
it,
even people that are not thoughtful,
that are all fucked up and really,
you know,
very hypercritical and annoying and not
rational about it.
They get to talk to,
you know,
there's a guy who was a,
he was a vIdeo game guy that just quit
social meeting,
quit his twitter now what's cliff epa.
It was another guy,
he,
he's like a famous for making youtube
videos and there was this thing that
they were going over his career and uh,
hIs,
his constant battling with people on
these social network sites.
And when people would say mean things
about him,
he couldn't help it.
he thought to respond or get involved in
these crazy fights.
And then he had started having his
employees handle his treater for him and
that relieved them of as a little bit of
a.
So then he got to a point where it's
like,
I'm,
I can't fucking do it anymore.
Like,
I'm going crazy.
I'm like real health problems and the
stress of this,
you know,
um,
when you start looking for that shit and
reading that shit and getting into that
shit,
it can fuck with your head man.
If you,
if you do something that people don't
like and they all start attacking you
for it,
attacking you as a human being and
trying to like hurt your feelings.
It's not just one.
There's like 20 of them in a day.
What was that about though?
What is,
what about,
what did those people doing that.
Why did you say that?
Oh,
because this guy did that.
He quit.
He quit as a social media to get away
from it.
Yeah.
I just couldn't take it anymore.
I mean he makes his living off his
youtube channel.
He's this huge youtube channel,
like people like millions and millions
of subscribers and he's got a huge,
huge twitter following.
Hundred thousand twitter people deleted
it all.
Yeah,
because he just couldn't take it
anymore.
I know it is his life,
but it's interesting like that,
that battle,
you know,
with the criticism and negative people
online,
like I released that I released that I
was worried,
but I released my album online with,
with commentary.
I put it on my podcast while we word
well because I was worried that someone
would say the only word.
It was like someone's going to say like,
oh,
this just lazy because he didn't want to
do another podcast episode this week and
the first comment was lazy motherfucker,
but that was the only one.
But It was like the first one.
I was like,
god damn it.
You can't listen to those people.
Those people are shitheads.
Yeah,
no,
you can't tell me that.
Somebody tells me like,
oh,
I saw this joke last time,
or whatever.
It's like,
it just bothers me.
Well,
do you need to let them know,
look,
I'm working on jokes and the only way to
work on jokes and you've got to do it
more than once.
A bit is never finished unless it's done
20,
30,
50,
depending on the bed.
It's got to be done.
A lot of times you have to do it onstage
and perform it and tweak it and move it
around and if you think that like,
you know,
you'd go to see me in this town,
then you go to see me in another town
and it's going to be a totally different
act a month later and some possible
crazy.
I need to work on that stuff.
Like a lot of my stuff that I've
released in the past,
I wish I'd worked on it more.
I wish I'd spent more time going over
it,
but that requires new people will come.
I go,
well,
it also requires you have to do it on
stage.
Know I had everlast on the podcast
yesterday.
We were talking about the difference
between writing a song and writing a
joke.
Like I've never made a joke without the
help of other people because every joke
I made,
it has to be done in front of an
audience and they let me know what's
working.
It's A combined effort.
It just is.
I can't.
I mean I'll write some good ideas that
will work.
The first time I get on stage,
but they get better when you do them in
front of an audience and you figure them
out and you gotta take chances.
You've got to do them this way and you
gotta move the punchlines changing.
Look at order real quick.
Let me examine each of these a bunch of
different ways.
You never know man.
Sometimes you nail one and it's just the
perfect way to say you can't believe you
used to say it another way before.
Pause,
right at some sock.
Man.
You know chris rock famously talks about
his,
one of his greatest bits of all time and
you know the bit that I love black
people and I hate niggers.
Remember that bit one of the.
That's one of the all time.
you certainly did,
but it's one of the all time classic
comedy bits.
It's just a brilliant bit.
Well,
he said that that been bombed.
Louis ck told me this.
He said that the bit bombed for like a
year.
Really couldn't get it to work.
Right.
And then finally he figured out how to
get it right.
If you could just figure it out how to
do it right,
but he believed in it.
He believed in the premise,
so he chased the premise down until it
got to a point where it was just a
weapon and then when by the time it was
on a special,
it's just flawless.
That bit,
that bit so classic.
It's a legendary but legendary,
but that's a perfect example of like
legacy book can't do that.
if you want to hear the same jokes every
week,
same with rather than wondering to new
jokes every show because you're never
going to get to that level.
It was really great doing going in New
York where do four,
five,
six spots a night and if you work on one
bit and you do want to go get that
feeling of like,
oh,
there's a little bit in the middle.
There wasn't enough laps,
but then usually I wait 24 hours before
talking about and I sort of forget this
time it's 40 minutes later I'm doing it
again.
I'm like,
oh,
it's still weak in the middle there.
So then on the subway I'm like,
I gotta write something and then you
don't still weak in the middle of the
next thing you do when you're like,
well that was okay,
maybe that'll work.
You try something else and by the end of
the night you'd like,
I've,
I've fixed this up a little bit.
[inaudible],
you know,
it was almost like a dilapidated house
and you're like,
I've done some work on it now.
Sometimes when I'm in a bit that's not
really working,
I try to think of myself like when I'm
writing,
especially I try to think of myself as
instead of making a bit,
instead of trying to turn it and figure
out a way to make a bit,
just figuring out a way to just express
what's going on and what you're talking
about,
what is actually going on at a bunch of
shit to it.
That's not necessarily the writing
aspect of it.
Like write a bunch of Shit out.
Talk about the whole thing,
read whatever the subject of the
building or whatever.
What emotions you were having.
Describe how embarrassed you fell.
Describe why you were embarrassed to add
a bunch of shit,
you know you're never going to say on
stage a bunch of shit,
like go way too far and then look at it
and go and just start cherry picking and
then go,
oh,
but this,
this makes sense.
If I can cut that out and go right to
this and you'll somEtimes you just give
yourself more by going too far back.
The teacher would tell us that like if
people weren't going to even close to
far enough,
that bloke was your cheat on me.
He was like,
you're not,
you're not going far enough.
Like I'm pretty upset.
Like it doesn't look like that.
And he would alwaYs go,
just do it like 10 times too much.
Just for argument's sake,
let me just see that.
And then people would do it.
He goes,
okay,
pull that back.
Like,
like three percent.
Like you're just barely over the line.
That's where you should be.
You got to take chances and people don't
want to take chances.
And that's one of the things that is the
hallmark of bad acting.
I don't really want to dive into and
become someone else.
They're still clinging onto who they
are.
What are you talking about?
You're not even going in there.
They don't even know how to be noticed.
Freddy would do that when he would
really do is dad getting exasperated.
He would lift his hand all the way up
over his head like at that,
and you'll see the new upper makers
trying something similar.
They're hammered comments about their
side.
They'd be like,
oh,
well,
you're doing that.
You just didn't have the guts to stick
with it to just go for it.
This is a commitment because it's so
foolish if you fail like that.
Oh yeah,
there was way more foolish.
Oh,
we've all done that.
We've over committed to bits and tried
to pump them up and they're just dumb
shit.
You know that feeling,
brian?
You know what I'm talking about.
When you get in the middle of a bit and
you're really working it and you're
like,
oh my god,
I can't even get out of this bit.
It's usually the dolphin one.
When people start going like women get
disgusted about it or something.
Yeah.
At the dolphin.
I'm sorry,
the stripper one.
Oh,
that's even more.
Yeah.
Well what are they going to do every.
It's not for everybody.
Some people like bluegrass succeeds that
stories like 10 minutes long.
Like once you start to realize a whole
crowd is not that intuitive,
you're like,
oh,
I really should've stopped.
Well,
I found a way out of it that lately.
Yeah,
that's sometimes important.
Part of like not doing well with a bit
too,
is that it shows other.
Yeah.
Well also I like doing it for crowd.
I'd like to,
in bits for crowds,
I'm mixed between either putting on the
best show or doing bits that I think
this crowd won't like to see if I can
make it work here.
You know what I mean?
It's a real dark joke and there's a real
conservative crowd.
I could do my more conservative jokes,
but it's sort of rather work on this in
front of these people work in this
really harsh thing in front of these
people.
That's why I like going to Australia and
Switzerland,
amsterdam doing shows and other
countries like I want to know what parts
of these really work in different
environments.
Wow.
You know,
a comedy on state has like a thursday
night,
like college night,
so it's all college students,
you know,
250 of them.
So it's like.
Yeah,
let me see how they relate to this.
Right.
College kids are a different thing man,
because when you do like colleges,
one of the things that you realized
almost immediately is how little
experience a lot of them have in life.
Like a lot of them are coming from their
parents houses,
protected environments of their whole
dorm to a dorm with a bunch of savage
hormonally charged.
Ten is just sticking things inside their
parties all day,
whether it's needles or dicks or just
she just fucking and doing drugs and
getting crazy.
I mean people are getting crazy.
You remember how much fucking you did
when you were in college?
Zero.
Oh no,
it barely won.
He didn't do any fucking.
Oh,
that's right.
You were a virgin religiously for
religious purposes.
But then I dropped the religion is still
was just waiting for the right girl,
the right girl to love kate hicks.
I saw that you added that to your phone.
Your email list is that if I said I had
to tell her revenue email address,
I said,
if I haven't talked to him all the time,
we're enemies.
Don't take this as a sign.
You just get in touch with me again
unless you go.
Do you know where she is now?
In baltimore somewhere?
Yeah.
Do your friends or facebook?
No,
she won't be friends with me on that
either.
She's doing.
She can't get the archduke anymore.
She's terrified.
She the one that got away crying.
It was like five that got away.
Thinking about the red.
Yeah.
Yeah,
there's.
I got away every time.
The one that always got away.
I mean,
I definitely got dumped.
I've definitely been dumped,
but when I got dumped,
I got away.
I realized after I go,
wow,
thank god,
but I was a maniac too.
Don't get me wrong.
They got away as well.
It's not like either one of us wasn't
good.
I love what you can both look back and
be like,
yeah,
what were you doing?
Wow,
got to be careful though,
so wrong for you.
Wrong for me.
You'll get into that situation where you
think you know,
like,
wow,
maybe we were meant together.
Now we've gone through our bullshit and
I try to do that once.
Right?
because you're just comfortable.
Girlfriend.
When I was a teenager we met when I was
25 and we went on a date in New York and
had a good time and went back and got a
little of that in there and I was like,
wow,
maybe she's the one.
Holy shit.
She's the one.
Yeah.
So much.
Two days it was a wreck.
Maybe she's the one he said I think
like,
well that's another thing,
one date when you're young and single
and you try to like hang out for a
weekend with someone that you barely
know and like a day in where you like,
will you shut the fuck up?
Like what kind of craziness are you
talking?
And you realize like what kind of
nonsense people talk amongst their
friends and then get stuck in the middle
of it squawking at you already.
Have You met anyone off of tinder yet?
What?
Girl?
Melbourne.
I hooked up with.
She's not supposed to tell that fucking
kiss and tell cock sucker.
Or was melbourne going to know many
people they know fucked are in
melbourne.
I'm tired.
No,
I like to know more than anything more
than.
Because I went on one date in New York
and we were like made out and that was
it.
And then another date we didn't do
anything but like it's nice to be able
to reject girls are kind of out of your
league just to be like,
nah,
no thanks.
Yeah.
Well you're just saying yes or no to all
these girls.
Are they putting their best pictures up?
You feel like your life has gone up.
Wow.
Because You're like,
why would I take this seven and a half
when I could tell.
Just took two nights.
And you don't have to get the match with
any of them.
What are we doing to humans?
We devaluing them with no numbers on a,
on an iphone app.
I don't know if it's setting us free.
Well,
I think it's definitely a vital norms
that aren't really us.
DEfinitely setting a lot of people free
from the,
uh,
the difficulty in getting laid.
I saw two hippos.
Fucking the zoo being simone and pizza.
Tinder did not meet on tinder.
It was the base level of it.
It's like that old joke you add with
the,
uh,
with the lions tigers though.
Like,
no.
oh,
I wonder if my pilot is going.
None of that.
Just fucking.
Yeah.
That's what tinder is like that you like
me,
I like you like each other looks.
Let's do this.
Well,
I think one of the things that's kept
people from being more sexually
liberated is that people cling when
there's a shortage on when it's
difficult to get sex.
People cling to each other when it's
difficult to find partners,
difficult to find lovers and people that
you enjoy being with.
It's hard to meet people when you find
people,
they get together and they get married
real early.
But when people get older,
instead of playing musical chairs,
just grabbing onto the first chair and
hang on and you get us something like a
tinder or one of those little dating
websites or the books.
Yeah,
you can just meet a bunch of new people
and then find who you actually like and
then he realized they're just meeting a
bunch of people too and everybody's just
meat and it's easy to hear.
To me,
it's like first day at dining hall of
the fucking college.
Hi,
how are you?
Yeah.
And if it becomes not hard to get a date
that that's limited limits.
A lot of obviously changed his life
really.
He said because he was the one thing is
worried about most of the rejection of
natural fearman,
but this takes that out.
They've already said,
hey,
I'm interested.
Wow,
that's interesting.
That's great.
Great idea.
That's a great application.
I just met this girl
on on tinder and she's like,
she's like,
ah.
I told her my name.
Eventually I was like,
I might said,
well online,
it's brian red band.
And she goes,
that's weird.
My last name is band and I'm like,
what?
That's crazy.
And then,
and then uh,
then she,
uh,
she had come to the comedy store with
Bobby Lee.
Bobby lee met his girl on tinder,
brought this girl with her and I was
like,
wait,
I remember I was like staring you down
the whole time.
And then I found a picture on comedy
store's website of her,
of the whole patio that night,
like they took a picture of you.
Right?
And I'm staring right at her and she's
staring right at me.
It's definitely working.
Her last name
band?
No,
isn't that weird?
Crazy.
Do it with her now.
I've even met her yet.
We're hurry.
Come on man.
How dare you?
It's hard for me to meet people often
wonder because it's a very weird
situation.
Even once you said the first move,
I was like,
hi,
I'm so we might want to.
We might want to talk to each other.
Yeah,
it gets tricky.
It gets real tricky.
You got to think about what you're
doing,
getting together.
It gets real tricky when you show up and
you're like,
there were about 30 pounds at weren't
represented in those photos.
What do you do that you Just enjoy the
date and then you get at some point
you're like,
you know what?
I don't want it to look sexy.
Whoa.
Ari shaffir.
That's why you got to do some research
Before you go.
You take a screenshot of it,
cut out the picture,
upload it to google image search and
I'll show you her face.
Ah,
god,
brian.
Too crafty.
She's like,
just
found out.
This girl that I met a.
She has a podcast on a podcast network.
I'm not.
I don't know if I should tell her not
because we've been talking back and
forth.
I was like,
it.
What the fuck?
This is something wrong with her having
a podcast.
Yeah.
I just don't like the network.
So was lumber party with allie and
Georgia.
Let all this shit go.
Don't,
don't tell people online who it is.
You fucking knucklehead and you want to
ruin your life already.
Elliot george,
you learn how to keep secrets.
You fuck.
I'm not going to.
Probably never meet this girl.
Oh,
but you might,
you might,
it might become besties.
I've is.
Yeah,
man,
you know,
I,
I really resent that idea that what
other podcasters have to,
uh,
be,
we have to be against each other.
We have to,
to them not even talking about your
situation,
but when the stitcher awards came out,
we won best overall podcast.
Congratulations.
But what I was shocked by was like one
of the other fucking podcast.
Some I've never even heard of them.
It might be the nicest guys ever,
but their,
uh,
their sound guy or something and
instigated some fucking hate campaign
against us.
Like,
yeah,
to tweet me and say a bunch of mean shit
to me.
It was like a swarm of it.
And I was like,
wow,
this is hilarious.
Like,
look,
guess what?
You know you can fucking light whatever
podcast you want.
You don't have to be mean to the people
that other people like,
like who gives a shit?
Like your podcast,
your podcast can't be that good if
that's the way you think.
If you really think that way,
your podcast has got to be filled with
some nonsense.
Like what David Cross hated larry the
cable guy.
David cross's starting that with
garbage.
Yeah.
That didn't work out so well.
That was a ridiculous thing.
Like,
like,
come on man.
You know what he's doing?
He's doing a character like the idea
that this character is like locals.
What do you care?
It's ruining the fabric of society
because it's already done.
Yeah.
That was the argument about larry.
The cable guy's racist.
Really?
Yeah.
That was a big part of it.
This zenith phobic fear of foreigners
towel head talk,
you know,
that kind of shit.
I don't know,
man.
Just other shit to be worried about in
this world.
You know that that weird thing where
people get mad at other people for Being
successful or get mad at other people
for winning an award or get mad at other
people for producing that you haven't
produced to tell it.
You want to piss the common golf.
Oddly telling me that he's your second
favorite comic book.
I'm still really good if all the
convenience is better.
Yeah.
That's so true.
Well,
we're all fucked up in some way,
you know,
or at least we come into it fucked up
and hopefully we balance out somewhere
along the trip going to piss off a girl.
Here's what you do.
He'd say,
color.
Say close your eyes and come outside
right now and then watch how
disappointed they'll get because women
think they just deserve free things.
Just assume you've got to have a
president that's not nice fear.
These are terrible ideas.
You've got to vet these out with me.
Call me up.
Next time you think about doing
something like that,
what are you going to do?
what?
What's the benefit of that?
I just got to laugh.
Ha ha.
You get nothing.
You get nothing but dick.
You want some dick?
You don't.
Somebody else does.
I get tender.
Look at my phone.
Fuck you.
I'm free.
Free dinners.
Where at every high schooler has one.
So what's that?
Every high school and I was one a 10,
but tinder,
I'm sure they do.
They're going on.
They're on.
They're on a goddamn rampage.
Kids today are fucking with an ease that
we've never experienced before.
That's why it's good that they have
that,
a hpv vaccination,
they can shoot that in them and then
they can shoot loads of
each other and not worry anyone under
26.
Right?
Something like that.
Anybody young,
uh,
they're to have sex should get that
vaccine.
Oh yeah,
shit's bad that he hpv.
But that vaccine apparently with some
folks this had given them adverse
reactions.
There's a bunch of,
what I don't know.
Some people,
you know,
it's like any other medication,
some people just don't know.
They just get sick.
Some people get sick from it.
These vaccinations,
a tricky,
you know,
shandra is um,
dad got lyme disease from a,
um,
from a lot they had a vaccination for
lyme disease,
but for a small percentage of the
population that have a particular gene
set up,
they would get lyme disease from the
vaccination.
Wow.
That's fucked up.
The poor guy got lyme disease from a
vaccination for lyme disease.
It wasn't a lot of people that got that,
but was enough that they pulled it from
the market.
What's going on in Venezuela right now?
Yup.
It's crazy,
right?
It's crazy.
Right?
Time.
Early in the world,
millions of people on the street
protesting against their government all
over the world.
[inaudible] put up some pictures.
The Ukraine also believe that they are
to Venezuela is not his people.
How dare you?
Well,
they're just tired of this.
A fucking really shitty setup that they
have and a lot of these countries quit
cheating us wrong what we want for once.
Yeah,
you.
You actually don't own us.
You don't have power over us.
We allow you,
we elect you to positions of control.
Elect you.
You don't.
You don't tell us what to do.
We tell you that you have power to do
things,
but the system is so corrupt though.
It's Like that.
You can't do apply any leaders in there.
It'll always be corrupted.
Not everyone man,
but most system will get mad.
I think will also,
I think people until today,
until this year,
people have been.
I mean,
until this age,
I should say,
the age of the internet,
people have been able to get away with
shit and not get in trouble with it and
not have the word spread across the
country with ronald reagan.
I'd have no recollection of that.
This is like the of it right now.
It's turned to this buyer versus a cost
versus citizens.
Yeah.
Oh my god.
That's terrifying.
This is a movie man.
Shots going off light,
but know what?
Otherwise,
wow.
Look at this shit.
This is crazy.
This is live right now.
Venezuela is a fucking.
The writing.
They are turning against our government.
Imagine if you were living in Venezuela
right now.
This is the apocalypse.
They have regular meetings on fire guys.
This is the chicago.
In 20 years,
everything's on fire and guns are going
off and this is the government trying to
keep control of its citizens because
they're [inaudible].
They're protested and said,
no,
no pro.
They outlaw protests,
protests.
You can't outlaw protests.
He fucks and I start getting violent
because I just want to say,
don't do this.
Yeah,
well they're.
They're living under a totalitarian,
dictator's block and twitter feed.
If You post pictures on twitter that
blocking a lot of them.
Yeah,
it's terrifying shit,
man.
You know what?
All these monarchs and all these kings
and all these people that run countries
are terrified of this kind of shit
happening.
All these prime ministers or whatever
their title is,
people in positions of power call them
whatever the fuck that was,
but you see that all these people are
terrified of losing this.
They're terrified of losing their
ability control to control these people
and they get used to that feeling of
power.
They feel like they deserve it the same
way we were talking about earlier,
like ridiculous.
Celebrities think that everyone is
supposed to kiss their ass because they
don't look at themselves.
These people don't look at themselves
either.
Just dominate these people.
People who support America going into
like Syria or something like that and
they're like,
well,
we got to do something,
and my thought is if there were dirty
dishes in the dish in the sink,
you don't send a spastic toddler in
there to watch it because they'll smash
a bunch of dishes and you're be like,
well,
we can't just leave the dishes dirty
like,
well,
we to send in somebody like that toddler
is the wrong guy to sit in.
America is proven to have just no,
there's no death,
but who else would you send in if you're
going to get rid of?
Literally not the ones we just spread
death to every country we go into.
Yeah,
but if you want to.
Okay,
look,
I'm not.
I don't buy the what's going on in
Syria.
I don't buy us that we need to invade
I think it's a very complicated,
gigantic mess,
but if you're going to say that someone
needed to invade,
Syria will tell you.
Would it be except us.
The only superpower in the.
We've only made more suffering and death
everywhere else we've gone.
We're getting better at it already.
Okay.
It takes like a joke.
It takes a lot of practice.
You gotta keep dominating worlds for a
long time before you get it right to
point.
You can be really nice while you're
doing it.
I'm doing a piece
already.
Should fear on twitter a r I,
s h a f,
f I r,
follow him and respect.
We will also be at the ice house
tomorrow night at 10:30
PM along with brian red band,
tony hinchcliffe,
duncan trussell and Justin Martin.
Dale.
Boom.
Schelok log.
And ladies from chicago this weekend.
Yeah,
go there to chicago this weekend.
Ari will be warming up for xannies and
xannies is a warmup for.
Oh the verizon theater in dallas,
Texas.
14.
So my goodness.
So much fun.
What are you doIng on April 3rd?
Okay,
what do you do in April 3rd?
I'm attempted with diego's boom son.
Um,
as miami bitch.
Let me just say I would reject that
anyway.
I hate miami.
How dare cities.
How dare you?
They're wonderful people and you love
them.
You creep there.
Your folks.
Cubans.
Jews just fucking with abandoned on
tinder.
Skinny ass fucking just chaos.
Fucking four.
18.
I'm in orlando,
Florida with joey coco diaz and then for
25 in baltimore,
Maryland.
ALso with the master Joe Diaz.
Alright.
So we will see you guys tomorrow with
campbell mclaren campbell mclaren is the
man who hired me for the very first ufc,
uh,
that I did,
which was ufc 12 in dothan,
Alabama in 1997.
And uh,
he was there for the very beginning.
We'll tell some great stories and he's
also got some new mma league that he's
putting together.
He's going to talk to us about that.
Thanks to our sponsors.
Thanks to naturebox.com.
Good food.
Yeah,
it's good.
It's yummy.
And they're sending me some gluten free
shit this week.
Oh,
get a handle on your hunger and your
health.
Go to naturebox.com/rogan.
That's naturebox.com/rogan.
Try it now for your first order.
Fifty percent off by going to
naturebox.com
slasH rogan.
Go there.
Enjoy the shit out of it.
You dirty freak.
I'm having a for 20 show at the comedy
store store 20.
Oh jesus.
Look at 4:00.
The comedy store for 20 show at for 20
ari shaffir.
I doubt we'd will be involved in that
show.
Wink,
wink.
But if you do get yourself in some
trouble and you need legal help,
legal zoom is not the place to go
through for that,
but it's a place to go with you for a
lot of other legal shit.
Legalzoom.com.
Use the code word rogan in the referral
box at checkout for more savings.
Legalzoom is not a law firm,
but they can connect you with a third
party attorney and provide you with self
help.
Services were also brought to you by
[inaudible] dot com o n n I t use the
code word rogan.
Save 10 percent of any and all
supplements.
Much respect you.
Dirty bitches will see tomorrow.