No bells and whistles.
We got snowed guests,
we're God's shit.
This is the hundredth episode and it
will go to 100 the way it began with no
form not knowing what the fuck we're
doing sitting in front of a laptop with
snow.
This stupid Karaoke Snell effect.
Yeah,
I listened to it today actually on the
way over here it's unlistenable there.
There is times where there was like 15
seconds,
20 seconds of dead air where we're just
fucking sitting there like looking at
things.
Yeah.
That wasn't really supposed to be on
iTunes.
We should've never let it go on iTunes.
Yeah,
what it is,
you know,
it was just,
we were just fucking around.
We just,
what did,
what started,
was it Anthony [inaudible] show?
I remember a while ago when Justin TV
came out,
we used to always be on the road in the
greenroom and I always tried to like set
up like a video,
like in the green room thing.
We did it a few times at Joey Diaz and
then Jody has got pissed and twisted my
finger.
I remember that he got mad cause you
didn't want the camera on anymore.
And he grabbed my hand and started
twisting my finger.
It was crazy.
Like he got really upset.
Joey.
I think Joey has to be funny all the
time and his eyes and when Joey's
backstage,
if he's just sitting there like,
what?
What do you want to do?
Well I'm not even hungry.
And now he doesn't want people to see
that,
you know,
he doesn't want people to see the normal
average everyday Joe.
He just wants Joey when he's on.
Right.
You know?
So yeah,
after that,
that,
that incident,
I was like,
all right,
I'm not doing this anymore.
And then we try to,
again,
Joey's a lot more sensitive than you
think he has.
Man.
You know,
Joey,
Joey said something to me.
I remember when I came down,
when I,
when we were headed to the show in
Portland and Joey got mad.
Yeah.
That was ridiculous.
That came out of nowhere too.
It was just me and him sitting there
waiting for you to come down.
And it's really weird.
I mean,
the bottom line was I had to take a
shit.
And sometimes who's that,
Amelia?
It's probably,
it's probably me.
You know when you have to tell you shit
sometimes you all the time it,
well sometimes like you're running out
the door.
I'm like,
God damn,
I think I got to go.
Let me just see if I can get it out real
quick.
And I was like,
Eh.
Oh my God.
Dammit.
I do have to take a shit,
but I,
I haven't had enough lettuce today.
I hate that.
That when you have to speed up a shit
that's the worst,
that's not cool at all.
That healthy.
The worst is when you thinking about not
taking a shit and then you do and you
go,
God,
I can't believe I was just going to walk
around for the next couple hours of that
inside of me or the girlfriend share
where you get a new girlfriend,
he can't shit in front of her or shit in
front of everybody.
You gotta deal with it.
Yeah.
I don't mind if they do it either.
It's life.
Yeah.
But it's just kind of stuck to you.
You just meet this girl.
You're trying to be like all sexy and
hot and your bathroom's right next to
your telemedicine has deal.
I'm going to go take a stinky shit.
Hope you can deal with it.
If you're not,
you don't get no more of this good deck.
That's where you gotta tell her,
let her know it's a commodity.
You didn't look through my camera by the
way that I left it.
I did not our God dammit that's not,
and if I did,
I wouldn't know what I mean.
I,
I did my first,
well not my first,
but my one or first or second,
it's a home movie sex movie.
And we were just like,
let's see what it looks like.
You like how you know?
Because it was,
it was a side profile and I noticed that
my gut just kind of sits on her ass when
I'm talking to her.
I've never noticed that before.
So now I'm like looking at 24 hour
fitness and shit like that.
But I left my rests on her ass like a
fanny pack.
Yeah,
it was crazy.
And I left it here though and
immediately I saw him like,
oh my God,
that video could easily have just gotten
out and that could have fucking,
that's how it happens.
It happens.
Yeah.
You fuck around and leave a phone
behind.
Exactly.
Yeah.
Jason Tebow has this thing with Sam Aaa.
Every time they leave their phone around
or somebody gets their phone in,
it's unlocked.
Take pictures of yeah.
Or put like black dicks and stuff like
that.
Like Jason Likes Black Dick and less,
uh,
last night,
Jason's did his mom though and was I
like Black Dick?
I did his mom.
What do you mean she left?
She was like,
Oh,
and look at these photos I took.
And so he did his mom's Facebook and put
like his mom left her phone behind.
Yeah.
So he took her phone and go on Facebook
and put pictures of black dude.
Yeah,
it's,
or I know he put black Dicks,
but he said something like,
I really like black muff or something
like that.
Whoa.
Really?
Yeah.
Here's his mom's pretty sweet though.
She's,
she's pretty sweet.
She,
she's,
she's a lesbian.
She just hangs out with the boys type
thing.
It was pretty sweet.
You saw like cart man,
his mom is pretty sweet.
I had one friend that had a mama who was
a lesbian growing up,
but he never admitted it.
Man took forever.
Took forever before he came clean.
Oh,
he knew about it and you just,
what he knew his mom was living with
this woman with a crew cut with,
with like big arms.
She had like,
she would wear Larry the cable guy
clothes.
Yeah.
She would wear like sleeveless shirts,
like sleeveless vest and shit.
Yeah.
And she had these like these big floppy
truck driver arms,
you know,
and she was,
she was a dyke and there's no getting
around it.
She was much was,
you know,
my friend did not want to come clean
though.
Why?
I so want to be normal,
man.
Everybody wants to be normal.
You remember Joey Diaz or stories about
wanting to be a white kid?
Yeah,
he's not white.
That's right.
Well he,
I mean that's kind of ridiculous.
That's called a slurp.
People go,
I hate him.
You make that slurping noise,
can't you turn your microphone up?
Just fucking deal with it,
man.
When I was listening to episode number
one in the car,
that was another thing that the mic
sucks so bad.
There was parts where things were
dropping and just blew your speakers out
like that.
So that's pretty annoying.
You know,
one thing I didn't know is a lot of
people,
you know,
say why you stitcher.
I had no idea.
So I talked to the president recently
when we were talking about the whole
incident and stuff like that.
The incidence,
the RSS incident,
we had a beer and now he said a lot of
things that I had no idea that stitcher
did.
And one thing was that stitcher
normalizes the whole audio.
So when there's big loud burst and stuff
like that,
which is what we should be doing,
we should be doing,
we actually used to do that.
Uh,
um,
but it made the audio too quiet because
if for some reason,
I don't know,
you don't,
I'm not an audio,
but it didn't work.
Right.
Yeah,
we need compression.
I heard that compression was actually
not the way to go though.
A lot of audio engineers that work at
radio stations here in La actually told
me that that's not the way to go is to
uh,
to use software post.
But who knows host.
Yeah.
But then you have to edit it.
You have to put it through posts before.
Well,
I think it's just a plugin in what the
program I use,
which is logic and it automatically just
does that.
Right.
But you have to run it through the
program and you can't do it live.
Right.
They're doing it live.
Yeah.
And I guess was written by saying there,
talking about the Adam Carolla show,
I have podcast envy.
I went to his setup.
It's so dope he's got,
I mean there's something cool about,
you and I are just chilling in my
office.
We always do it this way and it's either
in your office or in my office.
Right.
That's what we're doing.
There's something cool about that,
but his is set up is pretty fucking
sweet.
Yeah.
Except that you doing a radio show,
you actually got this one of the same
mix that you use as I guess Mark Marin
and him both use and we tried it out and
didn't sound as good.
Well ours is a lot louder,
but I think a part of that is the show
is a little more unstructured.
So there's people leaning back and
yelling and stuff like that.
It's not really any of that going on in
Marin show and there's not really any of
that going on the Kroll show,
you know,
I think for our purposes these are
better.
Do you listen to any podcasts besides,
you know,
or do you just kind of here and there?
Oh listen to this info.
I listened to psychedelic salon.
Psychedelic salon is kind of cool
because it's a podcast,
but really it's a bunch of old audio
recordings,
like old Terence Mckenna recordings or
you know,
stuff like that.
So I listened to that stuff.
But honestly I tried to listen to the
news or I listened to talk radio for two
reasons.
One,
you know,
to see if there's anybody that I agree
with and two,
to see if there's anybody that's just
completely out to lunch.
Like I listened at Patriot on Sirius
satellite radio.
The reason why we're listening to it,
it's just,
it's all fucking bananas.
It's all these crazy assholes that want
to Barrick gold and they're ready for
the whole thing to come tumbling down.
They got their guns ready and this will
bomb on what he's trying to do with
niche.
Eric Andre,
you know to those guys,
you don't fall for that shit.
They,
that doesn't get in the back of your
head like,
oh my God,
you're right.
We need to collect gold and no,
you don't.
You don't follow her.
Come on,
man.
I think if the shit hits the fan,
Gold's not what we're going to need.
We're going to make bullets and
gasoline.
That's what I think.
Bullets,
gasoline,
guns,
places to stay,
somewhere to go where there's no
radiation.
When the shit hits the fan,
there's so many human beings have
device,
so many ways to fuck each other up.
That if something ever really Keanna cap
and at this point in time where we
really went into like nuclear warfare,
man,
the golden going to help you dog
every time I'm away from La,
this is the reasonable,
one of the things that maybe we should
leave la someday because every time I'm
away from La,
like I was out of town this weekend when
I was away I was like,
now's a good time.
If Shit was to happen,
this would be a good time because I'm
kind of out of the crowd.
I could escape easier,
you know,
cause there's not a whole bunch of
traffic and soul vein and like I think I
have like a whole suitcase of shit.
I have my computers and stuff.
I think at a certain
point in time it becomes completely
unnecessary to be in such a large group
of people.
The only benefit of it is that because
there's so many people you're going to
get.
And especially because it's such a,
like a desired area.
You get a lot of fascinating people
here.
Yeah.
And like if you moved to Denver,
like what are you gonna do with the
podcast flight?
Freddy Lockhart out on a plane
I think
could do is there's three comedy clubs
in Denver.
There's two comedy works and there's one
a Improv.
I could talk to the people that are
coming in for that.
I can interview them.
Make it like a radio show kind of.
Yeah,
there's local comics.
There's a strong local comic scene in
Denver so I could always like have those
guys come on and we could do Skype too.
I did an Ariel Helwani,
his MMA show.
I did it yesterday and I did it through
Skype.
It's pretty bad ass man.
How did it sound?
It sounds he sounds great.
I use that stupid snow snowball
microphone.
The only thing that's kind of fucked
though is that you can't hear your own
voice.
Right.
I'm still waiting to set it up that you
could definitely,
you could use these mics as an example.
Yeah.
And if I had it set up like this,
like in like if I had it set up like
this in Colorado and you had it set up
like this in California and we just
skyped it together,
we could do a podcast,
it'd be pretty easy.
But then once I show you how sweet
Colorado as you're going to want to move
to yeah.
Yeah.
But there's not as many of your type of
girls out there.
Yeah.
You'd have to change your standards.
Yeah,
I think it,
yeah.
I don't know that I'm,
the Hippie is just this,
what's mostly there,
right?
Like people that were working out and
hippie.
Yes.
Boulder's a lot of that Boulder's hippie
and boulders.
People that don't really good shape.
Right.
No one wears makeup.
No one looks like a horror.
Yeah.
Shit.
And that's kind of a bummer.
But I have to get the girl pregnant or
something.
Not a lot of girls,
uh,
like the ones that you're around all the
time in California,
there's not a lot that's very rare for
the whole
world.
Yeah.
Well that's,
you know,
I go ups and downs,
my dating is not,
it's a,
it's like a stock market graph.
You know,
it's like,
I don't really look for what you saying,
but what I'm saying is living in Los
Angeles has given you access to these
girls.
Why leave that?
That's worth it.
That's what
they see.
Die With it.
Hard on,
you can find hot chicks and Colorado,
they're just not going to be quite so
needy.
Yeah.
It's fucked up.
You know?
Ever since I got in this relationship,
I already see my standup going away.
Just like how it was.
Does,
it's like,
Hey,
do you want to have sex and hang out
with this hot girl or do you want it to
stand up and hang out with four guys
that you barely know?
You got a tricky situation because if
you really want to do stand up,
you can't just do it fast.
And my shows are half ounce,
right.
So I'm making myself go at night,
but um,
you know,
have you been writing because when I'm,
I'm not writing as much either.
Yeah,
you're weak.
Weak.
He just given,
but it's easy to do,
man.
I did that when I was in high school.
Yeah.
I used to have a whole joke about it.
About how when I was in high school,
I played baseball.
I did all the,
until I started getting
lid and then I was like,
whatever would all that other stuff.
My parents were like,
what about baseball?
I'm like,
yeah,
found this new thing.
I think I like it more right now.
Like once you start having sex,
like,
like why?
Why am I playing baseball?
Yeah,
that Shit's boring.
Yeah.
I watch,
I watch.
Have you,
do you,
you don't have your first set on tape
too?
No,
no.
Yeah.
I'd watch it the other day at the awful.
It's horrible.
It sucks.
It's just,
just everything stuck.
Do you like the new ones though?
I like the new ones,
definitely.
It's definitely like before you could,
you could see the nervousness on stage
and I mean this was 2003
or whatever,
but I,
it was gross.
I can't even fucking imagine.
It's hard to watch my,
my sets from like last night,
like killed.
It's still weird.
You know,
it's hard even if you're killing,
but man,
if you're not killing,
it's painful.
So painful.
Uh,
stand up.
You got to figure out brown if you
really want to do it because if we
really want to do it,
there's only one way to do it.
You've got to go gang busters.
You gotta like put together an act.
You've got a rare opportunity man.
You're on the road with me all the time.
So you get to do these sets in front of
these giant crowds.
I guess I,
you have how I look at standup is more
as I enjoy doing it.
Kind of like,
I like doing it,
playing baseball,
you know,
I like bowling but I guess I'm not
looking as it in a career and I don't
think I ever want to do it as a career
wise.
I think.
I think if anything,
it's just a workout for this podcast.
Even,
you know,
make you more comfortable and more
comfortable and you know,
thinking of funny ideas and you're just
being creative,
you know?
Because if I'm not doing this,
then I'm painting.
If I have to be doing something and now,
right now it's just,
you just have so much in you,
you need to get out.
Yeah.
Shrooms.
Really Nice to reset that though.
You need to shoot him again soon,
man.
It's,
I certainly like the other day and it's,
it wasn't the best one,
but it definitely just opens up how you
look at everything.
So Risa,
yeah,
definitely.
Are we setting,
I do that every time I get in the tank.
Yeah.
It takes a big reset.
You need to try that.
But yeah.
Any,
any,
any opportunity that you have to just
fucking to step outside of the whole
thing and just relax and let's take a
look at this.
Let's assess this.
You know,
from an even position so many times in
life,
man,
you're just on momentum,
right.
You know,
every one step from the next.
It's like there's something pushing
behind you and you just keep moving.
Have you ever forgotten to tena forgot
to put take off a condom after second?
Like not no.
Like,
uh,
like sometimes you know,
like I'll have sex in like then,
you know when I call him and then I'll
take the condom,
throw away,
put a new condom on so I can continue
and did not come again.
But I forget I have that condom on.
You're getting way too personal,
but I know,
I know I'm trying,
I was trying to clean it up a little
but,
but I was swimming and then I went to go
piss and I'm sitting there going,
ah,
pain into the condom.
Yeah.
I didn't know the condoms or not and I
didn't hear the water.
And I'm like,
what?
Well,
I'd be the laziest motherfucker I've
ever met in my life.
But when you're so lazy you can even
take your condom off to be,
it's be bothered.
You never know the way down there.
Didn't know it was on there,
but
it's crazy how much pee comes out so
fast because it was like a full balloon
when I looked down.
And the first thing you do,
fuck does it stay on your desk?
I don't know.
It stayed on pretty,
I guess pushy.
Just dried or something.
I don't know.
But it's crazy.
Your first thing to do is like holy
shit.
And so I just like kind of like pulled
it off in the weight of the p dropped
into the toilet and just start spraying
out back out of the toilet and it would
piss everywhere.
Oh,
it's fucking,
that doesn't even make sense.
How does that condom stay on you while
you're pissing did it?
Didn't it didn't fall on a loop?
Did you use,
I didn't know.
I did use it.
I think I might've had some flush loop
around.
No,
I didn't know I was at the,
no I did.
So it's just whatever lube was on the
condom.
Yeah.
Wow.
That's fucked.
High Condom.
It was a tight condo.
That's ridiculous.
Go over your balls.
Huh?
That's uh,
that's an old joke.
A friend of mine,
Amir Golan.
Um,
fuck what?
I forget what his fake name was.
He used to have a fake name that he used
to use on stage,
I should call it.
I forgot what his name was,
but anyway,
he,
uh,
he had this joke about a,
the first,
I remember the first time I put on a
condom,
it was really tight.
I got back from the bathroom and the
girl was laughing at me.
I was like,
this is fucking painful.
Why you laughing?
She goes,
it doesn't have to go over your balls.
Fucking idiot.
He had a bunch of great jokes.
Here's another one.
Yeah,
my friend got his girlfriend pregnant.
They were having anal sex.
You know,
the baby looks like shit.
That's so stupid.
But um,
fuck.
Anyway,
you're so lazy.
You don't take off your coat.
God,
I wish rooming having sex and I feel
like incredibly lazy personnel.
Do you ever like look at some of the
shit that you say?
Um,
like lazy in general?
In Life?
Well,
yeah.
It was just like,
I always think I have some kind of like
if I ain't got my thyroid check but,
and it was fine,
but I always think that I always have
had some kind of like,
you know,
I'm always feel like I need speed.
Like I need something.
Like when I drink so much coffee,
it doesn't feel like it does.
It does anything.
Are you,
uh,
do you think you have add or something
like that?
No,
I wouldn't say do one of those fucking
buckle up Republican guy.
There is no way,
dude.
I would cry.
I was a kid.
They were just nutty,
nutty kids so that diseased now stop
coddling them now.
I probably think it's cause I just don't
work out.
I don't do shit like that.
That my body's just in fifth grader.
You need to slow the body.
Yeah.
You need to kick your body and the get
all this hump and should be doing
something for him.
Yeah,
absolutely.
That'd be firing up your fucking
testosterone bags.
Bang,
Bang.
Yeah,
no.
sure.
I don't know.
What were we talking about?
We're talking about you being lazy as
fuck.
Yeah.
I think it's either exercise or it's
probably some kind of deficiency of some
kind.
Probably that I,
I need like,
well,
I see,
I know that,
uh,
I know friends that are on that Adderall
shit.
Oh,
I needed it to concentrate and,
yeah.
Okay.
I guess,
but it's speed,
you know,
I can't think you're going to last very
long on speed.
I don't like what it feels
like.
I'll have a cup of coffee during the
podcast and a cup.
One Cup of coffee is fine,
but if I have two cups of coffee during
the podcast,
after the podcast is over,
I feel all amped up.
I feel like I don't feel shitty.
I don't feel that at all.
The only get like there's a lot of
energy in your system.
No,
it doesn't work.
But what I do notice is that I clinch
when I,
when,
when instead of feeling that energy,
I'll find myself like reading,
clenching my teeth really hard.
I don't know.
Out of nowhere,
I do it all the time.
I noticed on the way home yesterday
because I had two cups of coffee here
yesterday and it was,
I was driving and I'm like,
why am I clenching my teeth?
Like I don't know what it is.
Like it's like it's all going to my,
my jaw dude.
You've got to be one of the weirdest
motherfuckers have ever met.
I do it all the time.
If you,
if you look back at old use dreams,
you'll see like this line on my,
I do this and I bite my cheek.
And are you thinking about anything
where you're doing it?
Doing it?
I'm just like clenching.
You have this energy that you got to get
out.
Yeah and my mouth squeeze off around.
Wow.
Maybe you have some like unaddressed
energy issues.
You know,
maybe if you like started doing
something like like throwing the discus
or something like really physical you
maybe you would like feel much better.
I've been trying to Xbox at dance game
on connected.
It works pretty good
shit.
What are they going to have?
Some sort of a martial arts game where
like a robot does certain moves and you
can kick it,
you know,
get like moves forward and you can leg
kick and it moves forward.
Your Punch.
It doesn't have to do much this to be a
target.
I think this connect thing,
I don't know if you know what connect
is,
it's like that,
that Webcam thing that they put,
you put it on top of your TV and it
detects your body.
It works.
I don't know,
like I'm not,
I haven't played that much,
but the games I've played fucking bad
ass.
It's like a where you just hold up your
hand.
Like you can even do Netflix.
We're streaming through movies going
like this with your hand moving it left
or right your string through movies and
if you want to pick one you pull,
push your,
pull your hand out and grab it.
And it's kind of like a whatever
minority report or whatever.
But,
but they have games to where you don't
have any controllers anymore.
So how of,
how accurate is it?
How effective is it?
You know,
from what I understand,
it's not the best,
but I have never noticed it not being
accurate.
I think it's pretty accurate.
So I,
I've heard the long as you're not
playing like a first person shooter or
something where you'd have,
I think it's good enough for that.
I think it's really up for that.
I think it's really based on lighting
and clothing and w because like,
uh,
the girl I was with was wearing a dress
and it couldn't detect separate legs.
So it was kind of fucking up.
So she took off her dress and then it
worked perfect.
The,
it's a trick and wanted you to be a
whore.
That's right.
Well that's what I told her.
Cause you have a dress on it.
Too much clothes on.
God,
what are you doing over there?
That's crazy.
So now if you're using it as a first
person shooter,
how do you pull triggers?
Um,
see,
I don't know.
I haven't played a first person shooter,
but what I would imagine,
I don't know.
That'd be weird.
I don't know how they're going to do it.
We can't talk.
We can't talk about that one thing,
but uh,
there is a crazy first person shooter
that we can't talk about something now.
No one.
Not because I don't think it's known.
Somebody tell us this.
No,
that the,
the,
the video that I showed you that Kevin
Prayer it might've showed us.
Oh,
right,
right.
Yeah.
That's all.
Think Cognito,
I didn't know what the fuck you're
talking about.
Yeah,
because he got to think of a guy.
If you're doing a first person shooter,
you got,
you got to deal with two things.
One,
how do you simulate movement?
Like how do you go forward,
you know,
you're running,
how do you go on forward and how does
the machine know you're running back?
But because you're not moving forward
though,
I think it's good with your hands.
Like because with the dance game,
it was like you did like something like
that.
That means forward.
You go like this and you shake your hand
to the right.
That means you're shooting.
Well,
ideally what you want is like a giant
dome or a ball rather,
and you be inside that ball like a
hamster ball and that ball you have like
some sort of a three d helmet on like a
complete,
you know,
what is it?
Virtual reality,
complete virtual reality helmet on.
And then you would be walking around
with this ball.
You could walk in any direction,
you know,
it wouldn't feel totally real.
Like you would kind of be realizing that
you're on a ball and then you're stuck
in this,
you know,
in this thing.
But that would be,
I mean,
other than that,
how the fuck else could you simulate
movement unless you just did it inside,
like the virtual reality,
then I wouldn't even be virtual anymore.
You'd have to do it inside,
like,
uh,
put a program and then make,
make a program the exact parameters of
say an airplane hangar and then you have
an empty airplane hangar and they walk
around inside that hanger.
Yeah,
look,
it's all wired and you could do it that
way.
But then that kind of defeats the whole
purpose of virtual reality,
right?
The idea is that you're supposed to be
able to do it wherever you are.
Yeah.
Would you ever go to burning man?
No.
Why not?
Too many hippies.
I learned about hippies when I moved to
boulder.
I liked him in theory.
Yeah,
I liked him in theory,
I don't,
I don't like a lot of people that are
asking for money all the time.
I find that shouldn't be very annoying.
I don't like people playing shitty songs
and wanting a dollar.
Right.
You know,
for the most part that cool.
But you know,
there's just,
there's too much of that hippie movement
that wants people to help them.
You know?
And this is how I feel about that.
If I felt like everybody was on the ball
and everybody was doing their best,
and you know,
I'm a generous person and I think one of
the things about being generous is if
you have the opportunity to do so,
it feels really good to be generous,
especially if it doesn't affect you.
It's not like you're being generous in,
it's hurting you.
You know?
So I think it's,
it's important,
but in passing,
like say you're passing love to the left
and there's a big circle of people,
man,
the real promise was a lot of fucking
people that never keep passing the love.
They take it and then they walk away.
You know,
there's,
there's some people that are always
there for you.
There's some people and they're doing
their best and they're there.
They're living their life and you're
doing your best and you're living your
life and you're helping each other and
you,
hey man,
can I borrow your truck?
I've got to move.
Fuck yeah man.
Come on over it dude.
Anytime you got my shit,
you know,
we're friends.
You help me,
I help you.
We're all together.
But we all know those the few people
that don't contribute,
they always need something and they
don't contribute.
And my experience,
that's my experience with hippies.
That's my experience with,
of people that you know,
are like really into like socialist
ideals.
A lot of it is because they're fucking
lazy man.
They're fucking lazy and they don't work
that hard and they don't do their part
and they somehow or another field,
like the whole system's unfair man.
Which fuck yeah,
of course it is.
Of course it's unfair.
Of course it's corrupt.
Of course it's fucked up,
but that's not why you're a loser.
There's a lot of people that aren't
losers.
Most people are losers because they're
lazy as shit and they want to blame
other people for that and they want to
blame society and they want to blame.
Look,
society is completely fucked.
But guess what?
It's not like there's one person that
makes it.
Fuck the whole thing is it's fuck cause
it's on a foundation of bullshit.
It doesn't make any sense.
But knowing that you see what it is,
make your path,
make your path.
Figure out something that you can do to
feed yourself.
Okay?
Figuring out something you can do to put
a roof over your head.
If you just figure it out,
man,
fucking figure it out.
It doesn't mean you have to be a fucking
asshole.
To be successful doesn't mean you have
to be a part of the system,
man.
Now just dot.
Stop asking people for money.
Stop being a fucking Mooch.
Get your shit together.
Okay?
That's my problem with hippies.
My plan with hippies is part of the
whole idea of being a hippie as being
like really nice and being really
relaxed and sometimes life does not call
for that.
Sometimes life calls for you gotta get
off your fucking ass and make something
happen,
man.
Yeah.
You know,
there's a lot.
I had a friend who was his,
what?
His girlfriend was having a baby.
This was many,
many years ago and I had a fucking
scream at this guy.
This guy was unemployed and he,
he was like,
he couldn't get his shit together.
He couldn't make something happen.
He was trying to be a comedian for a
while that didn't work out,
and then he was trying to do some other
stuff.
You're trying to do some radio and a
budget and we have this conversation and
I'm like,
man,
you got to realize you're going to
become that fucking guy.
You're going to become that unbelievably
pathetic guy who can't feed his kids.
Right?
You got to fucking do something,
man.
You've got to make something happen.
And you know,
it's not,
hey,
you know,
we really need some food.
Do you think you could help us?
That's the hippie approach to go to
people and you've got to make your own
fucking way.
You've gotta make your own way.
And that was my problem with boulder.
And that would ultimately,
I'm sure it'd be my problem with
Portland,
and it's a bit of my problem with San
Francisco and it's not that I'm not a
kind person,
I'm a very kind person,
but I recognize the difference between
someone who's in need and someone who's
fucking lazy.
And there's a lot of people that just
weak.
They're weak is shit man.
And they have no philosophy to live
their life by,
they have no discipline that they've
developed over years of trying to
accomplish things to the point where
they have this sense of,
of personal sovereignty.
They can take care of themselves.
And I like occasionally everybody needs
help.
But if somebody will help you,
if they know that you're the type of
person that will help them and if you
know that you're the type of person that
does their best.
The what drives me nuts is when someone
wants help.
Like motherfucker,
you're not even helping yourself.
Like,
look what you're doing for yourself and
you want someone else to step in and
manage your fucking,
that's
ridiculous man.
That's,
that's,
that is the number one problem with the
whole idea of everyone together,
man.
The real problem is that everyone
doesn't do their fucking part.
Man.
That's the real problem.
There's a lot of lazy pitches in this
world.
The reason why I was asking about
burning man,
I,
I've often thought the same thing like
fuck hippies and you know,
cause I,
I been there,
done that.
I hate it.
I hated the people too.
That the lazy hip,
there's good heaviness.
There's legit hippies.
Right?
But I hung out with bad hippies.
They got bad,
you know,
so like everything else,
it's like MMA fans.
Well,
I have a lot of friends that are MMA
fans.
I have friends have graduated from
Harvard,
friends that are fucking,
I knows guys who were scientists.
I the guy who created a,
um,
a Beavis and butthead,
Mike Judge,
huge MMA fan.
I mean there's a lot of intelligent MMA
fans.
Yeah.
But then there's a lot of idiots.
But I was looking at these videos lately
cause the girl goes every year or
whatever.
And so there is some fucking cool shit
going on at burning man.
I'm sure.
And I guess you can rent these big Rvs,
you know,
and,
and that's the way to do.
It's the happier RV.
You don't live in a tent or whatever.
They have showers and stuff.
But,
uh,
there's this thing called,
I don't know if you ever heard of it.
It's uh,
they're called,
uh,
let's see,
where did they called?
Um,
her most shit.
It's at Zio tropes.
Have you heard of a zero trope?
Xeo trope is d.
I'm sorry.
Zoetrope Zooey Trope C.
What it is,
is it's like a carousel type thing,
like America round and each kind of,
you know,
a cup,
a couple of feet,
there's an like a drawn or there's some
kind of sculpture,
like it's like a monkey hanging from a a
vine.
And then the next one,
like,
you know,
three feet over isn't the same monkey,
but it's kinda changing a little,
you know,
so when it turns and you have a flashing
light that just flashes at a certain
rate,
it's like the monkeys are moving.
So it's in the middle of this desert and
there's like,
they have these statues of like people
diving down into the ground that just
melt into the ground.
They have like these monkey,
uh,
that are spinning a check this out right
here.
Here's,
here's the,
here's a monkey one.
I don't know if you can see this.
Uh,
here's a monkey.
Wow.
That is bad.
And it's fucking trippy.
So anyway,
so basically they've done is animation.
Animation.
Yeah.
And just like the old claymation models
they used to use for like King Kong and
Shit.
Yeah.
Or like a old flip book where you draw
on a flip book and he flipped it.
That's bad ass,
man.
I'm down with the artistic end of it,
you know,
I'm down with the,
the whole idea of a,
all these artists getting together and
doing cool shit.
I just think there'd be a lot of stinky
people.
I just wonder why I don't,
or maybe they have.
Why doesn't a collection of people like
yourself,
uh,
do a comedy show?
Why they're there?
Because that is huge,
you know,
I'd rather know perform there.
If I was going to go there,
I'd want to,
I just want to hang out,
have fun.
I got a foreign name magic performing
once the Woodstock of comedy,
psychedelic comedy,
there would be so much mushrooms and so
much everything else,
so much fun.
I would be too fucked up.
I would,
I wouldn't want to be talking on stage
through a microphone.
That's the last thing you want to do
when you're on shrooms.
Oh,
I mean,
yeah.
You just don't do shrooms that hour and
a half,
two hours.
Yeah.
I think if you're there,
you just want to experience it.
That's what I would want to do.
Yeah,
I'd perform enough,
man.
I performed plenty.
You know,
I think I,
Freddy Soto used to say this back in the
day,
you know,
people used to offer Freddy gigs at like
bars and stuff like that.
It's in,
it's like,
no thank you,
I appreciate it,
but I don't only do comedy clubs,
man,
that's it.
And that was his,
he just is like,
it's not worth it,
man.
You go to these bars and everyone's
talking and you can't do your act right.
Your rush it because you're trying to
get their attention.
And he was totally right.
You know,
he's totally right.
And that's Kinda how I am right now.
I only do shows I'll do,
here's my show I'm doing,
it's,
I'm at this theater,
come see me,
I'm at this comedy club.
Come in,
that's,
and then there's no problems.
There's no hassles.
It is what it is.
But if you're just doing a fucking look,
you're in a tent with some speakers and
you're on this stage and all these
people are all,
they're all fucked out of their minds
when you know,
why should they pay attention to you?
They shouldn't.
You would feel illegitimate standing
there asking them to,
if you knew that everyone in the crowd
was on mushrooms,
you would have nothing to say.
They look it.
Unless I'm on mushrooms to,
what am I going to tell you guys?
I'm not going to tell you shit,
man.
You're communicating with the ear,
the alien overlords right now.
You know these beings that have come on
asteroids,
their spores of infested this earth.
You're communicating with them through
eating them.
What?
I'm going to tell you some stupid Dick
Jokes.
Yeah,
but you're,
you're pretty pretty known for being a
psychic psychedelic speaker.
I mean,
you always do the marijuana shows here
in town and stuff like that for the same
reason to the same kind of people.
Yeah.
But the thing part of being into
psychedelics and understanding
psychedelics and I've had psychedelic
experiences,
it sort of negates any idea of you
wanting that sort of attention.
Right?
Like doing a show,
like when you're doing a show,
the,
the beautiful thing about a show is that
people enjoy and they have a good
fucking time that comes to your comedy
show,
but that's not what you want to do when
you're jazzed out of your head.
You know,
if you're on psychedelics,
you don't want to go see a comedy show,
you know,
I don't want to see anything structured
and I certainly don't want someone on
stage like forcing there.
Like there's a lot of things you say on
stage in a comedy show that's just to
get a laugh,
you know?
That's what it's there for.
It's there to spice up the show to have
more fun and those things will stand
out.
Like,
like fucking wet shits in your
underwear.
They just like,
oh,
what's this?
If you're on mushrooms,
every like jokey joke that you have,
which is below,
bring Doug Benson and some black lights
and somebody body.
It might be a good time.
Doug Benson would just be hugging girls'
high.
You can have a hug to come.
A hug.
Never been anybody who's hired more
consistently that Doug Benson.
Yeah.
Every now and then he'll send me a
tweet.
You're high right now or a text message
or high right now.
All right.
Yeah,
I know you are a motherfucker.
It's so funny because I never knew that
was real.
Like when I first,
when I first met Doug,
I thought the whole marijuana thing,
what's kind of like an act?
Kind of like an Andrew dice clay kind of
like,
yeah.
You know,
like he was doing it.
I mean he might smoke weed,
but I didn't think he was the the crazy
stoner in just after hanging out with
them that first night.
Oh fuck.
Yeah.
Immediately.
He's like,
every five minutes,
hey,
let's go back to your hotel room and
about someone in their joint.
Those guys like to go deep,
man,
this is there.
Some dudes who go real deep.
Those guys in involved in the medical
marijuana,
like those,
those look like normal and the toss guys
goes so deep.
We were not normal,
but um,
the cannabis cup,
that was the deepest that I've ever been
and there was an inn on Melrose in
Hollywood.
I was one of the judges and it was at a
a head shop and they'd close the head
shop down.
They papered up the window so no one
could see inside.
They put a doorman in the back,
lock the front,
and then they turned the whole thing
into this Cannabis Cup party.
Really fucking bold movement because
they did this shit in the middle of
Hollywood and the place was just filled
with weed.
I mean it was unbelievable and no one
stopped.
They just kept going deeper and deeper
and deeper until I left there and went
to get something to eat.
I'm was like,
I just,
no way I can drive home right now.
I just got to hang out for a few hours.
I had to hang out.
I mean,
most of the time when you're high
driving is not an issue because driving
is not any more complicated than
walking.
You know?
I mean you're,
you're,
as long as you're not smoking Endeca,
as long as you're not smoking some
dopey,
we'd,
you know,
you're,
if you're driving and you're high,
you know,
just be extra careful.
Watch what you're doing.
It doesn't affect your hand eye
coordination.
I mean I do Jujitsu on weed.
I kickbox and waiting is not a problem
but,
but I was so high that I was like,
no fucking way man.
I was just no way I'm going to drive
this thing and risk not being in control
of my senses.
I'm going to have a cup of coffee and
have some food and just fucking sit back
and read myself over a little bit,
go over my notes,
you know,
sit down for a bit before I drove home.
It was too,
it was too stupid cause like you get to
a certain point when when people were
like,
everybody's handing you cookies.
Here's a vaporizer bag.
Hit this,
Eh,
this is a new blank paper that are
developed,
hit that,
and everyone's passing joints left to
right.
It's like a never ending like a cyclone
of joints getting passed around.
It was fucking ridiculous.
But you get to this point where you're
not even high anymore.
It's not like you're high anymore.
It's like you're not there.
It's like you're,
you were in a room and you know the,
the room has one window and it's a
circular window and the room is like
four by four wide.
You can't even move.
I even toilet in it.
It's just you,
you,
and that room and that circular window
and that circular window is now how you
view the rest of the world.
You're looking out that window.
Go,
what the fuck is going on out there?
Because this is crazy.
I don't even know what's happening out
there.
That's what it's like.
It's like you're,
you're detached from the world.
You're so high,
you're detached,
you know?
But those things,
if anybody ever wanted like some sort of
argument against the cause,
right?
Because I don't go to one of those
cannabis cups bad.
The good thing is man,
everybody is friendly as fuck.
I've been to shit,
a hundred medical marijuana shows or,
or you know,
parties or parties at the playboy
mansion.
I've never seen so much as an argument.
Never seen a raised voice,
never seen a a push,
never seen anybody get crazy.
Not even girls,
you know.
I mean every time you go out some girl
would be saying talking shit to some
other girl everywhere in Vegas and La
Anyway.
So if you stay
around the night long enough and pay
attention,
you're gonna hear some girl yell at some
girl.
Right?
Yeah,
totally.
Definitely.
But not in,
in,
in this we chose,
we chose,
everybody's is so nice.
This is people.
If people really realize what it could
do for you,
you know,
so many people,
like I have a friend who's like super
organized and like he's like really
ambitious and he's,
he produced his television shows like a
real go getter.
Very nice guy.
And,
but he's so anal and it just fucking
wound up about shit.
He only wears black.
He won't wear anything other than black.
His whole like you open up as wardrobe,
it's black shirts.
And Blair,
when somebody does that or would they
only wear the white tee shirt like John
kept,
uh,
Cap Barela is that his name would do
that.
Where's the white tee shirt?
And uh,
you know,
like every day I was like his outfit.
So uniform.
When he goes to work,
does he wear it?
Like when he goes out and dates only
that one teacher that I don't know,
but there's definitely [inaudible]
amount of days.
What's up that vagina for me.
Yeah.
But like there is people like that that
like only wear certain things.
Like this dude isn't just in badly in
need of a joint.
I keep telling him,
I go,
dude,
just trust me man.
Just trust me.
Just try a little weed.
It'll help you relax.
Like you're a good guy.
He got a lot of good things going on.
He just needed a little fresh
perspective man.
And it's totally true.
You had a live proofing the other day on
that podcast,
98.
You remember?
It's like you just need some muck.
We immediately after smoking weed,
everything was great.
You know,
every podcast 98 Aka the disaster
disaster.
Brian Whittaker apparently is very upset
with the depictions of him from that
podcast tweeting mean things to you.
Yeah,
he started attacking me on Twitter just
like today.
It's like,
dude,
all right.
The thing I'm saying is I'm trying to
make sure that people that are at home
can listen to this podcast and
understand what's going on.
Instead of having a million people
talking at once.
It was no attack on you.
I understand what you're saying.
So for the people that don't know about
that podcast and it's not worth
listening to,
it wasn't a good one.
But,
um,
there was just,
he just had an issue where he didn't
know how to,
uh,
be on a podcast.
He didn't know that you can't talk while
other people are talking.
It wasn't,
you know,
he didn't have a chance to prepare.
It just got thrown into it.
You know,
he didn't even know he was going to be
doing it.
We've talked about him too much.
Yeah.
We have talked about he's a good dude.
He's just,
he's out there doing his thing and it's
taught out there for a pimp.
Yeah,
but at least it's easier when you work
at the Improv,
you know you get stage time.
Oh is that your dig your last dig at him
because he had a dig at you.
You get a lot of people that hate on you
man.
Of course.
I've always had that ever since I
started talking to you,
I haven't been getting haters.
You started talking to me.
Oh Man.
People don't want to respect the red
band.
Cause people well that whenever you do
something,
I mean if you do comedy,
people look at it and got it looks so
easy.
I can do that too.
And then you ain't even funny.
I could fucking do that.
But then the,
you know,
they look at you.
What does he know how to make edit some
videos or something.
Fucking I can do that too.
You know,
they just,
they look at someone who's in a nice
spot and what you think,
what the fuck?
Why isn't that in me?
I know it's hard to not jealous man.
There's some,
some ingrained shit.
I see what my kids,
it's really interesting,
the three year old and the one year old
I sometimes a three year old would get
upset at the one year old,
the one year old getting too much
attention.
She'll take things from her and stuff
and it's like they just,
it's just nature.
Nature wants you that you want to
collect all that love,
you know?
That's why people develop great
personalities.
They develop great personalities cause
they realized somewhere along the line,
you know,
with a rewards is that,
when you have a great personality,
the reward is people are always nice to
you.
You get all this nice energy that people
want to be around you.
That's the reason why great
personalities getting invented because
people become a horse for other people's
love.
You know?
I mean that's what really what it is.
I mean it's a,
it's a beautiful thing in both ways,
but really the root of it all is that
people really want positive attention.
So when you see like little jealousy and
like little kids and then you see
jealousy and like grown adults.
And I see like really petty shit and
haters and I love to go on like,
um,
those,
uh,
gossip blogs,
you know,
and just,
just to read,
I don't even know who these people are,
you know,
but someone will be someone from the
bachelor or someone from some,
I'd just like to read the comments.
It's just,
I don't even know what the fuck the
stories about.
I have the time,
the campaign,
his baby and you have mom and during
court,
whatever,
what's going on in the comments.
And I'd go down to the comments and it's
just,
yeah,
it is.
Hey evilness.
And it's ridiculous because when people,
the biggest thing is like if it wasn't
for Rogan,
this,
that,
this and that,
I'm like,
yeah,
if it wasn't for rogue and he saw my
work,
he liked what I did.
He hired talking about me.
Like I'm not even here.
I know it's,
but,
but what is like a company like NBC,
but like Jay Leno should,
you know,
people are managing it.
Like if it wasn't for NBC,
you would be nobody.
You know,
that's,
it's,
it's me getting Joe seeing my work and
then hiring me.
I got a job.
It's really simple.
Was an artist.
Hello.
He's an artist and he was creating
things that I thought were very
worthwhile and so I hired them.
It's a really simple,
pretty easy and you know,
and people that,
you know,
there's a weird dynamic and people like,
how are you guys friends?
You guys are so different.
Like you don't have to be the same as
your fucking friends,
man.
That's,
that's silly.
Right.
You know,
if everyone was the same then you know,
I'll be running around saying the same
shit and cock blocking each other.
This isn't a Paula Abdul opposites
attract.
Is that what you said?
I think
I heard forever.
Your girl the other day miss the music
on the podcast,
Joe.
Yeah,
I do too,
man.
We can't do that shit anymore.
The serious serious deal is signed
ladies.
Yeah,
it's all done.
I mean,
I haven't written my name on it because
they did just to do you.
Do you ever,
I'm just gonna.
I'm gonna so we're going to have it on
Sirius,
so it'll be 12 episodes.
We have to get ready,
we have to pull up music if we have
music on and we have to check him back
episodes.
We're going to send them 12 and then
we're going to go live episodes that
we've ever done.
Exit.
Not 12 but what's,
what's your five top five that you've
ever taught?
Five.
Well,
my number one favorite,
just just
uh,
just for sheer far out factors.
Always Dunkin Dunkins my favorite cause
just junk and just so fucking weird.
And like when he starts chanting
Buddhist mantras and talking to you
about the Bhagavad Gita and you know,
and he just,
he just gets me going,
man.
Dunkin and I,
he doesn't have these conversations he
says with anybody else either.
He's like,
he and he and I would have just this
weird chemistry when we get together.
It's all crazy talking to the other day
I called him up,
call him up yesterday because I said,
hey,
we're doing the 100th podcast today.
You know,
maybe you want to like walk in like
halfway in and sit down with us.
I was thinking like maybe that'd be cool
to have guests come over while we're
doing it.
And he goes,
Oh,
I'd love to become,
he's a middle of the show,
these putting together and he goes,
I did mushrooms last night,
man.
I was surrounded by Elvis.
They have so much to talk to you about.
Yeah,
I was scared to fucking grounded.
He said I was surrounded by Elvis.
He said I did more mushrooms than I've
ever done.
I was surrounded by El.
So Dunkin's going to be in the podcast
next week and he's going to tell us this
whole this whole thing.
And You [inaudible] you recently went
Truman up in
northern California,
north of Barbara.
Wouldn't the world be a better place if
people just did that if they had
retreats,
you know,
instead of going,
I mean even have these wine tasting
retreats.
How about right next to the wine tasting
or treats a mushroom tree,
they'd go there.
Everybody's going to be nice to you.
It's all soothing sounds and you know,
you're in a comfortable room and there's
the Sharman are all experience.
Everybody who works here is
professional.
You know,
you pay a couple hundred bucks a day or
whatever the hell you're doing and you
just blast off.
It's pretty amazing.
How much better wine taste when it's at
the vineyard.
I don't know why.
Cause it's all the same.
It's modeled,
you know?
Well the ones who offer the tours,
are they like really known?
Yeah.
Oh yeah.
These are like the big dog.
So you remember the names?
I don't remember anything.
I remember I don't buy,
I usually buy buy wine by the bottle.
Like,
like if it's got a cool bottle I'll buy
it.
Yeah,
there's kinds of wines I like,
like I like more Lowe's.
I like,
you know,
Shit like that.
But I just usually go by the bottle.
Like,
oh,
that's a crazy cat.
And on that,
you know?
Yeah.
I never used to go.
I,
if I was a on a date,
perhaps back in the day I would order a
glass of wine or a bottle of wine,
but I would never like order a glass of
wine while I was eating dinner.
But now I do all the time.
Yeah,
I do all the time.
Like I like a,
like a nice strong red wine with like a
steak.
It just tastes better.
It's like this little,
you know,
this is this thing that the flavor is
all combining.
And as I've gotten like a,
like Matt Lichtenberg,
my buddy is a huge one fanatic.
He's like,
he's a,
he's a wine geek.
I mean he has this crazy wine cellar and
his home with some insane amount of
money worth of wine in it and he's one
of those guys that can tell you why a
wine is good and what year it's good and
you know what,
what part of the country had comes from
and all that kind of shit.
And when,
when you're around a guy like that and
he,
they know so much about why,
then you start to sort of appreciate it.
Like,
oh,
okay,
this is some weird tasting art form.
It's like they're trying to create this
ultimate taste and it's a very specific
taste and if you're not,
it's a weird thing.
Like the whole idea of acquired taste.
I used to think that was so stupid.
Like why would you acquire a taste for
something like caviar?
The fucking stuff,
you know it's super expensive and it
really kind of tastes like shit when you
first take it.
Why wouldn't you just,
okay,
it's,
it tastes like shit forever and this is,
it is what it is.
I now have to worry about it anymore.
But no,
people get into it and then they start
getting more and more expensive tastes
and you're getting stuff that's
thousands and thousands of dollars.
She's salty fucking stupid fish eggs.
Well wine is kind of like that too.
And that like the first time you try
wine and I nearly a little kid or
something like who the fuck would get
into that?
But when you really like get a nice
peanut and war and a delicious steak and
you're cut into that stigma and then you
have a sip of the wine,
like Ah,
all the flavors together,
it takes a while to appreciate it.
But knowing someone who knows as much
about wine as I do,
I mean he tells me so much about,
you know,
like,
it's all about like how they put it in,
what kind of barrels they use,
store it and how they store it and how
long they store it and how long,
how long has it been bottled for.
And
it's pretty amazing.
One of the wineries I went to,
they did cheese pairings,
which is cool because you never,
you think,
okay,
they're going to mix this cheese with
this wine.
Yay.
It's going to just taste like if I still
use the word Faggot,
which I don't,
I might throw it out.
You're right there.
I'm know.
Be Honest.
I liked cheese.
You like you like wine?
I do.
It just sounds fruity.
Tooty yeah,
it does say,
oh,
I went to a cheese pairing,
a wine tasting.
Did you know how wet that pussy gets
when you're going to a wine and cheese
tasting?
That's the most ridiculous wet pussy
feel normal for the first time in their
life.
Normal.
Brian's a good guy.
He's not taking me to see poison in
concert.
That's right.
He's telling me to take you to motel six
so wine tasting in the middle of
Northern California.
He's an amazing guy.
Cool.
Do you know what,
but you went for the fun of it.
You didn't want,
it was more like,
Hey,
want to get away?
Not You.
No Internet,
no work.
I just don't like up there.
It's beautiful.
It's the crazy mountains.
There's a huge lake.
At one point,
I forget the name of it,
right north of Santa Barbara is this
humongous lake where it's just best
fishing.
I can know other families up there or is
it just,
there's my soul families.
I saw families,
but a lot of bed and breakfast is a lot
of Nice historic old hotels.
You know that,
that that you go in and there's just
like every room is unique.
That's what we stayed at this place
called Peterson.
At the end or the inn at Peterson.
Is this amazing Santa Ynez?
Yes.
Right next to Tom.
Like is he used to always rant and rave.
It's amazing.
There was ostrich farms where,
which is huge fields of ostriches
running around.
You can go there and you can get like
ostrich eggs and like hang out with
ostriches,
but they're were running around.
They look like dinosaurs.
They look like it's,
it's amazing,
man.
I highly recommend if you just want a
weekend out out of La,
take the kids,
go go to some farms.
It's,
it's pretty relaxing Jeff.
Ostriches or creepy as fuck man.
Yeah.
All birds are creepy as fuck.
Yeah,
and around about it.
About,
you know,
in my act a little bit about the mass
bird deaths that happened,
but how about how birds are really
dinosaurs that survived,
but they really are.
I mean that's,
that's the closest relative to the
dinosaur is the bird and an ostrich is a
fucking dinosaur.
It's a big ass weird looking dinosaur
with the tastes delicious.
You ever get the off Times Burger?
Fuddruckers wow.
Strong.
Yeah.
I'll buy you a coke.
You got to have it rare though.
Don't be a pussy.
You don't have to worry about mad cow
with those bitches.
Just get that shit rare fired up.
Fuck her up or I feel that that raw rare
ostrich meat.
So delicious man.
It's good stuff.
Would you go camping here in La tent
camping?
Shit,
when they go camping where I can drive
home.
The only time I would go camping is on
too far away to drive home.
And if I have guns on me,
I'm going hunting with Ricky Schroder
are you really?
Yeah,
we're going,
we're going to this ranch where you
could shoot bore and uh,
they even have bison at this ranch and
it's like you pay them for whatever you
shoot and then you'd go out into their
Dev,
this giant hunk of property out near
Riverside out near a San Diego that way.
And so I'm going,
oh,
that's cool man.
Yeah.
I've been wanting to go for a while.
I'm supposed to go hunting in October
with Randy couture,
natural Randy coture.
We're going for a TV show.
So,
uh,
before that I'm going to get some in
with Ricky.
That guy loves hunting,
man.
He got,
when I talked to him about his eyes lit
up and everything,
he wants to come back on the podcast.
I was going to say Ricky to me was one
of my favorites.
Uh,
I got some great stories are always that
out of nowhere.
People like the Ricky Schroder or even
Kim prayer.
I think it was one of my favorite ones
of all time.
Kevin was awesome.
Rick has got some interesting stuff
going on right now too,
man.
He just got some serious skin cancer
removed from his face.
Serious.
Yeah.
You gotta be people walking around
outside without sunscreen,
man.
Be fucking careful.
If you see some little mark on you,
man,
people die from weird skin.
You know little things when you're out
there getting burned,
you don't think it's a big deal.
And then you get melanoma.
He had a big chunk of his face removed.
Man,
he's got a big scar right on his temple.
Did you get checked a lot?
Yeah.
Well,
I don't,
I'm not at risk because I'm fairly dark
skin.
I get Tan pretty leads easily,
but I don't fuck around the sun man.
But he's,
Rick is Rick,
he's Pale.
He's like white,
like paper,
you know,
you gotta be careful as fuck and he's
always out in the sun.
He's like mister outdoorsy,
you know,
he's got this giant piece of property
and he's got property in Colorado.
Ricky Ricky Schroeder is an interesting
guy,
man.
He's a super outdoorsmen character.
He's always out there like chopping wood
and shit and getting things done.
You know,
he's like,
he looked like wishes he lives on a farm
or something like that.
I think growing up poor or rather
growing up super rich,
I mean growing up rich and famous from
the time it's early as he can remember,
he was a celebrity and he was rich.
So he's always had so much fucking money
that I think he likes driving around in
pickup trucks.
He likes like doing like manual labor
and shit like that.
But when you do that,
you've got to put your sunscreen on
homing,
especially California out here,
this fucking heat.
And the sun constantly beaten down on
you.
People get cancer,
you gotta be careful.
I have a bunch of moles.
I'm a very Molly motherfucker,
but uh,
my mom's had a few cutout and so yeah.
So I recently went and because there's
this one that I have on my back that
always is like crunchy,
you know,
it's kind of,
it's,
it's like it's a song.
Yeah,
it's not good.
It's not crunchy.
It just fuels like different than all
the other ones,
you know.
And sometimes you know,
if that was your problem,
they pull that out and all of sudden
point you get think clear and right and
start going to the gym.
I just,
that the mold was like a little vampire
just sucking the life out of you.
So I went there and she's like,
no,
that's fine.
It's normal.
And I'm like,
really?
That's why is it?
No,
that's just the kind it is or whatever.
And she,
then she showed me pictures.
Like if it ever,
it looks like this,
come back,
what's in you gotta say Annie Oakley
Style.
Look at your back with a mirror.
Exactly.
What the fuck is that about?
What is it?
What is it supposed to look like when
it's bad?
It's like,
it's like right around it.
It looks kind of like it.
When she showed me,
I was like,
Oh yeah,
yeah,
that looks bad.
You know?
Not this little,
no mold as a little flaky or whatever.
Yeah.
When are they going to fix that?
Molds can kill you.
Yeah.
Keep a good eye and your mole because it
might be a bomb.
How are you supposed to see that?
Especially if you go to in a weird
place,
like what if he died of a mold?
It was like right near your asshole who
looks in the Russell,
you know assholes.
Then in hotel rooms,
that's like girl's ass all.
You look at a girl's house,
so if you're banging her from behind,
what do you look at your own in a hotel
room,
because that's the only time when
there's good lighting and good mirrors.
I'll sit on the counter and just like
fucking sprayed open and go,
oh,
look at my butthole.
Really?
Once in a while you should check it out
and just to look at it.
I mean,
when's the last time you looked at your
butthole?
It's been a long time.
Exactly.
What have you opened it up and there was
this big purple signals from it.
If it's sending me signals saying
there's something wrong,
constant itching,
weird noises,
then I'll go check it out.
Like an itchy asshole.
Have you ever had an itchy household?
Like for like a couple of days it was
just nonstop UK,
but also a Dane Cook.
But that's weird how Dan Cook Louie Ck.
Very Common Joe.
That does happen.
I actually,
we've all had itchy assholes.
I was thinking about itchy assholes and
I was like,
oh wait.
Oh yeah,
that's right.
There's like 3000 jokes for I could she,
I suppose.
Yeah,
there's quite a few.
I mean the issue with Dane and Louis
obviously was that we really had done it
first.
Yeah.
But hold jokes are quite common.
If you,
uh,
if you think about a subject and it's a,
an obvious subject for a joke,
chances are someone's already done a
hundred jokes on it.
You know,
you know,
when I looked up the other day,
I was,
I'm writing this chapter in my book,
um,
and it has to do with porn.
And so why,
uh,
I was talking about the moment that I
realized that the Internet was taking
porn to a whole new level was the
moment,
I forget who it was,
it might've been,
Duncan sent me an email and the email
heading said home run.
And then I opened up the email and it
just said,
I love people in all capital letters and
a link.
So I clicked the link and it opens up,
it's Bella,
Donna on all fours with a baseball bat
stuffed in her asshole.
I mean it's stuffed in there and fat and
first,
which I didn't even think was possible
and I remember doubled face palming like
the home alone kid and going,
this bitch is just taking shit to
another level.
She stuffed at baseball and then I
thought about it or is she taking it to
another level?
And I went and did a Google search and
there's 2,000,800 hits
for baseball bat in the ass.
Yeah,
it's,
it's normal and you know,
it's normal shit.
No,
you know,
when she,
uh,
when she did that,
she,
uh,
used to tweet about that where she was
stretching it out for like a whole week.
Like I got a big anal scene,
you know.
And so she had like all these butt plugs
and she just spent the week getting
ready for doing shit like that.
You know,
she doesn't do porn anymore.
I heard,
I heard she retired.
Well she had that really sad interview.
I don't remember what it was for,
whether it was Nightline or one of those
shows,
but you know,
when they,
they,
you know,
they made her feel bad about it and you
know,
and they asked her,
you know,
what happened to you?
How did you become this porn star?
And they kind of like go over her past
and shit like that.
And then at the end she was like,
you know,
I'm done.
I'm not doing this anymore.
And then they found out afterward that
she had done some more movies after that
after she said that it was weird.
It was like,
you know,
you kind of wanted to root for her to
get out of it and then she's still in it
and it's like,
you know,
fucking not everybody can be a ballet
instructor.
Okay?
Some,
some people are going to be porn stars
and by the time they're that age where
they're gonna be porn stars,
man,
the least of their problems,
it's fucking on film.
That's the least of their problems is
that baseball in their ass,
that's the least of their problems.
The big problem is what?
What have you become that you're letting
someone put a baseball bat and your ass
what has happened to you to get you to
this point?
It's not the bad itself.
That's not the real issue.
It's who,
who,
who are you?
Like what kind of a strange person are
you that you,
you know,
you've got your ass hole up in the air
and there's a giant log in it,
a big fucking bat.
And then there's 2,800,000 hits of that.
Yeah.
But didn't you also think about if that
only is bad?
If you look,
if you think it is bad,
you know,
like if,
I don't think that's good for anybody.
If it's like,
Hey,
I could put it.
Yeah,
I know,
but it's like,
Hey,
I can put baseball bat and my ass that
equals $20,000.
Okay.
Do you think they get paid that much?
Because I don't think they do.
No,
I don't think they do either.
It's a couple of grand if they're lucky
and I think that might have been during
the Hay day.
Yeah.
You know,
I think nowadays I don't,
you know,
those,
those girls were getting like half
million dollar vivid deals.
You remember,
I remember hanging out with Gemma
Jamison's husband and he was a producer
and he was giving me the whole skinny on
how much money there is in the porn
industry.
And this dude,
you know,
he had all the numbers and I was like,
dad is incredible.
Like there was so much money.
And then the net came along,
the Internet just robbed them all,
sucked it all away.
And now,
I mean,
how the fuck do you make money?
No.
Doing porn I think.
I think there's definitely still money
there.
It's more of you just have to do more.
Like I know a lot of these girls they'll
do like,
you know,
like a spanking video and make 500 then
they'll,
you know,
do another video later that day where
it's just them masturbating and they get
a thousand you know,
so it's like,
then you think of it that way.
It's like all right,
you just made $2,000 today and is it for
a website?
Is that what it spends?
Most of these are websites,
you know,
fetters websites or you know,
exchanging content.
And I think that the,
the,
the weirdest thing about knowing all
these porn stars,
I think the saddest thing is not even
what,
how they got into it or that they do it.
Cause I don't have a problem with it.
Is that their future?
Because a lot of them don't have
it.
An idea once that one.
Yeah,
they're like fighters.
I mean is that where you go to,
you know,
like a truck stop and that really older
woman then you're just like,
wow,
she used to be a playboy bunny,
you know,
look this,
this avenue,
this Internet avenue has opened up the
door to the point where there's way,
way,
way more porn stars than there ever were
back in the day.
You know.
And porn is so much more available.
When I was a kid,
there was the way you got porn was
magazines.
When I was a kid,
VHS has came out while I was in high
school.
I remember we got one,
it was like a big deal at our house,
you know.
And uh,
my dad had a couple of my step father,
a couple of porns laying around the
house too and got to watch those too.
And I was like,
what the hell is this?
You know,
to go from like,
it never existed.
Or every now and then you saw a magazine
and the weird thing about those
magazines where they had rules so you
would buy a porn magazine,
but there was rules and one of the rules
was the man couldn't have a hard on.
They still have those roles really?
Yeah,
like word,
they can't show insertion and you know
in certain magazines and magazines they
can.
Yeah.
But back then it was all magazines.
Back then there was no magazines that
showed hard ons and I think,
I mean none that you could find and it
was like,
you know,
you'd asked the guy at the counter if
you were bold,
you know the,
the bookstore,
but you didn't really want to ask them
like,
hey,
how come nobody's Dicks hard?
What's going on here?
You know,
you don't really bring it up to him.
But there was always like these weird
poses where there would be in like,
not just one but like 20 different
poses.
And in each one of them,
the girls like moaning,
like she's an XC and the dude doesn't
have a hard on.
Again,
every one of them.
It's like,
what is the message that the trend is
send you?
You know,
what is the message that they're trying
to send you?
Is it that this is just how the universe
works and that women that are way hotter
than you could ever possibly imagine?
We'll always wind up with gay guys and
you're going to be alone by yourself,
jerking off on to pictures of them.
I mean,
is that what it is?
What is the message?
Why can't they have hard ons?
They're naked and they're there and then
the,
the surreality of it all comes into play
because you see all these 20 different
scenes like this pitch is not giving up
in every scene.
She's super enthusiastic.
She seems nonjudgmental.
This guy can't get it up and she's doing
everything for him.
She's posing,
she's got her ass up in the air.
She's lying on her back with her legs
spread,
sucking on her fingers.
She's letting him pick her up and he's
holding her by the hand and his dick
still limp.
It's still limp and this bitch is just
therefore him the whole way.
She's like soup somewhat.
Eventually he's going to get a hard on.
I know it.
I just keep posing for him until she's
in all these weird poses and never loses
interest.
Never has the,
you know,
it should be like at least the 18th or
19th posts.
She should be like,
what the fuck?
Like what's going on?
Like why do you have my legs split
spread and you know you're laying your
limp dick on my pelvis.
Right.
You know,
like,
like a drowning victim just pulled the
shore and it was just like slop.
I mean,
that's what it's like.
He's got his limp Dick and he's laying
it on her pelvis.
Like who is that for?
Like W W who,
who doesn't want hard dicks?
Like who was,
who was there?
It was like,
this is where it says why we draw the
line.
You'll want to get all naked and crazy
and pretend you're fucking so,
if you had to look at a dick who was
either hard or lamp,
you would pick hard all the time.
If I had to look at a dick.
It depends.
If competing off,
the last thing you want to do is be
beating off to a dude with a limp Dick.
So you would rather have a hard dick.
Can't even imagine that.
That would feel good.
You'd feel like that the guy would be
embarrassed and that it feels pointless
and she's,
she doesn't feel good because he's not
even excited.
And so there's a lot of like weird
chicken on there.
At least if the guy has an erection
while he's feeling good,
it feels good.
And Elise,
she's happy that she can give him an
erection.
It's a much more positive experience.
Is it harder for you if the tick is
black or white?
I can't really relate to black decks.
See,
I always like,
I can relate to a black dick if it's
big,
but,
and then a little tiny micro white dick.
I'd rather have hard black Dick fucking
a girl because for some reason to me
that's more naughtier or something like
that.
Take that big black Dick,
you know?
Really?
Yeah.
Really.
So you find yourself saying that as
you're doing the stroking moment,
why whisper it
for real?
That makes you,
it makes it more naughty deal.
Yeah.
It just seems like you're,
Oh,
you're getting fucked for realsies.
I remember some girls for real,
some girl came to the comedy store one
night and she,
uh,
gave us the rules of,
of being a porn star.
She was with,
I think she was with Ron Jeremy,
and she was like,
you know,
rule number one is don't fuck black guys
until they pay you.
You have to,
you can't do it right away.
Don't fuck them until they pay you.
Rule number two is no angel for a long
time.
You've got to keep it.
Keep it to yourself.
I'm like,
you have strategies on what you'll hold
back when you do a porn.
Oh yeah,
honey,
it's a business.
Oh yeah,
honey,
it's a business.
Wow.
Yeah.
I think they strategize when to give up
for the black deck.
You can't just right away start fucking
black guys.
Hey,
hey,
hey.
Settle into that.
A little,
like some girls,
like,
like Jenna Jameson never fucked a black
guy.
Well that's a big thing.
Important.
Once you go black,
you're actually considered different.
Thrilling.
If you did.
It's like a weird,
so why do girls,
why did any girls do black guys?
Just,
I mean,
for their career.
Why do they do that?
Uh,
maybe,
I don't know.
I just easy.
Yeah,
they're just,
they just want to fuck black guys,
I guess.
Yeah.
Maybe.
Maybe they don't care.
Maybe they're there for equal rights.
I guess a lot of the porn buyers are
southern and stuff like that.
And once you fuck a black line,
I don't want that stupid slut.
Please.
There's a disproportionate amount of all
interracial porn sold in the deep South
said no.
I used to do a whole junk about that.
That's right.
It's true story.
It's a true statistic.
Disproportionate amount.
So then it's not black guys buying him
that stuff.
It's,
it's,
it's scared white guys don't where
[inaudible] oh man.
Okay.
I believe what he's doing,
or nude or,
oh,
I'll stop looking at me in the eyes.
Stop,
bitch.
Ooh.
Yeah.
I think that,
um,
that whole black white thing,
eventually it's going to go away.
I think we're all going to be like one
strange shade of gray.
You know,
when Moca one something Mexican,
we're going to be Mexican.
We're going to imagine this.
It's not the black white thing can't
last.
It only lasted back when people couldn't
move to other places.
When you were stuck in China and
everybody else was in China,
what are you fed off the same gene pool
and you produce Chinese people,
you know,
but once the Africans got to,
the northern Africa and Egypt and things
started getting weird and they took
over,
you know,
Cairo and then they move into other
places and then the Moore's hit Sicily
and then all these fucking,
the Spaniards come over on boats and
fuck the American Indians.
And then eventually,
eventually we are going to be a world
culture.
I just don't see how you can keep people
from interbreeding for the next
millennia.
I just don't see it happen.
I think in the next thousand years we're
all going to be one shade.
You know,
they think that's what happened when the
end of the you,
the,
the talls got assimilated into the
population.
They used to think they went extinct,
but now they think they sort of went
extinct because women wouldn't fuck
them.
But men would fuck the women.
Men,
human men would fuck neanderthal women
and make babies with them.
But Nanda tall men were like,
what the fuck?
Nothing.
They just got on the outs.
Hmm.
That wouldn't be weird.
What would that one final specie look
like?
Yeah.
Both the end of the road,
once you make Jesus,
well it's got probably going to look
like aliens,
you know?
I mean you look at the gray alien,
the model alien,
this big,
big head and you know,
sexless body and you know,
and no muscle tone.
And that's probably the next stage.
I mean,
if you look at monkeys and then you look
at us and what is the difference?
Well,
are our heads,
aren't the monkeys have smaller heads or
heads are bigger,
our muscles aren't as big,
were softer.
We're,
we're not.
We last longer.
We have,
you know,
nutrition and information and all that
stuff,
but physically were far weaker than the
chimps,
you know,
and then,
well then they're going to be more weak
than us with bigger heads.
They're heads are going to be bigger.
They're going to be more,
uh,
more smooth and less muscular insinuate
because they're not going to need that.
They're never going to be in combat and
never going to be fighting for their
life against other bodies and try to
take down animals to eat them.
They're moved way,
way,
way past that shit.
That's,
I mean,
the,
the human alien connection,
you know,
for a lot of people,
they believe that what they're alien
image represents,
whether it's real or imagined.
What it represents is humans from the
future and that the eventual
metamorphosis of the human animal,
the morphing,
the evolving will ultimately lead to
something like that.
We,
we look at inherently all our issues.
Well,
first of all with sexual issues,
we have emotional issues.
We have,
you know,
anger issues.
We have all these things,
well,
the,
all the depictions of the aliens,
they've gone completely passed all that
shit.
You eliminate all your,
your sexual issues.
If you can reproduce,
you know,
outside of a,
uh,
a male female environment.
If you're able to reproduce completely
in,
in laboratories or in,
you know,
petri dishes or whatever the fuck
they're doing.
You know,
if,
if we,
if the human animal moves past
reproduction in a natural way,
I mean,
that might be,
what if they found out that babies were
a hundred percent smarter and they live
twice as long and they were,
you know,
five times more resistant to diseases.
If you raise them in a test tube,
if everybody raised them outside of the
womb and some new machine that someone
created,
well,
everyone would want that.
Why would you want your kid to be
stupid?
Because you want to carry it around
inside you.
You selfish cunt,
put the baby in the machine,
right?
That's what they would do.
And that's inevitable.
They're going to eventually come up with
something like that.
The human body can only do so much.
You know,
the human body there are already
figuring out artificial parts.
They already devised artificial hearts.
They've come up with artificial leaves
that make photosynthesis.
They're going to have artificial wounds,
official electricity,
you know,
it's artificial trees going to be able
to make electricity.
Yeah,
we're going to be able to make
electricity.
The solar power.
And it does.
Another thing that I got from
transcendent man that uh,
the w the Ray Kurzwell documentary that
I watched,
fucking awesome shit man,
but he talks about the upcoming advances
in solar power.
Solar power is going to be the Shim.
It's going to be driving cars,
man,
they're going to have solar powered cars
or the next 20,
30 years.
It's,
it's all,
it all eventually is moving us towards
the aliens man.
I mean they really might be the ideas
of,
I don't believe,
I don't believe they exist or that they
don't exist.
I don't believe that,
you know,
people were really seeing flying saucers
and I don't believe that everything that
people see is a government spacecraft
there.
It's very possible.
That could be something from another
dimension or something from another
world or something from some,
some even even Hokey,
ridiculous cliche description from like
a 1950 Scifi movie.
I'm not discounting the possibility of
that,
but I've looked at all these different
people that all their stories and all
their d,
it doesn't jive.
It doesn't jive to me.
I have a,
an awesome bullshit detector.
I'm,
I'm currently reading this John Mac book
and John Mack was a,
actually a professor at Harvard who a
start.
He had started doing posts,
um,
uh,
past life,
a hypnotic regression shit with people,
uh,
you know,
hypnotic regression,
not,
not past life,
but in the,
in their past like abduction stuff.
Cause he,
he was dealing with all these different
people that had a very,
very similar,
um,
experiences where they were abducted,
you know,
repeatedly over many times in their
life.
But I'm looking at the,
the,
the work and I'm reading this stuff and
I'm like,
God,
this is so embarrassing.
It's like squirrely work.
It's like this guy has,
he's gone.
He's made a conclusion in his mind
already.
And what he's doing in his work is not
like he's not exploring all the
possibilities.
He's kind of like pushing towards this
conclusion.
And the,
the latest one that I'm reading is like,
it's so sloppy cause he's telling all
these stories about all these people and
all the,
there are depictions of their
experiences.
How about you tell me how crazy that
person isn't a one to 10 tell me,
ask me what do they,
what do they think about astrology?
What do they think about Tarot cards?
You know,
what do they think about crystals or
mind reading?
What do they think about the loch ness
monster?
I want to know a lot of other shit about
these people.
I don't want to know about what their
experience was like.
You know,
first when I was eight,
you know,
it was alone in a cabin.
I knew something was there with me.
I saw the dark eyes in the corner of the
room really were yon lithium.
We you crazy.
Are you crazy at all?
Was anyone else in your family crazy?
Because there's a lot of crazy
motherfuckers out there and they tell
some crazy stories and all you need to
know about this whole Ufo abduction
experience.
The one most important point is that it
all happens at night.
Well,
when the fuck are you dreaming?
When the fuck do you have the most
realistic,
bizarre dreams?
The other night I had some crazy fucking
dream.
I was on a dragon.
I was reading from these scrolls that
the words would light up on fire as you
read them.
So you could only read it once.
I mean,
this is bizarre.
Yes,
cool ass dream,
but it was a fucking dream.
All right.
It was really obvious to me what I woke
up like,
wow,
what a crazy ass dream.
Well,
what?
What is a dream?
What a dream is.
As your mind reaches a certain state in
rem sleep or rapid eye movement takes
place and all sorts of crazy chemicals,
psychedelic chemicals start being
produced by your body and they all pass
the blood brain barrier and you have all
these nutty fucking experiences and you
and your cousin Mikey,
and you're on sleds and you're running
from God,
Zillow.
Like what is that?
Is that real sleds?
Should we investigate whether there's
sleds in space and whether Godzilla is
real?
No,
no,
no.
You should say,
when did this happen?
Oh,
I was sleeping.
you were dreaming,
right?
Yeah,
probably.
When were you abducted by aliens?
While I was in bed.
Do you think you were dreaming?
No,
it was so real.
Oh,
okay.
Let's write a book on how real it was.
And you gotta you gotta say no go real
well.
A lot of them,
the,
the interviews that they do with them
are so telling they're,
they're really fascinating and not
necessarily that the people are stupid
and it's not,
and not even necessarily that they're,
they're,
they're lying.
Cause a lot of them,
I don't think our line,
I think what a lot of them are is first
of all,
people live some boring ass fucking
shitty lives.
They're boring as fuck and if something
happens and all of a sudden that's
something gives your life meaning like,
oh my God,
it instead of it being some sleep
paralysis thing where your,
your brain has his indogenous dump of
psychedelic chemicals that are natural
in the,
in the brain anyway,
instead of that being the case like,
no,
I've been visited and I have information
that I have to give to the people of the
world.
Well,
you know,
if you have a natural psychedelic
experience or if you have a real
psychedelic experience where you take a
drug and you know you're planning it out
and either one is going to give you a
very similar experience and that
experience is what you're doing is
totally wrong.
Everybody's fucked up.
You need to get your shit together.
How about an analysis of yourself and
analysis of life on the planet and let's
look at this.
Other than the way we're looking at it
right now because this obviously isn't
working.
This is the theme to every mushroom trip
to theme,
to every acid trip to theme to every
time you eat a pot Brownie,
you want to reconstruct the whole thing
and put it back together in a way that's
rational and that makes sense.
You know,
and this,
this,
this experience of these people are
having,
when they're,
the aliens are telling them,
well we need to get your shit together.
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
You're high dude.
You're high.
You're at,
you're tripping.
You're seeing things in a closet.
It's that simple.
There's no evidence,
man.
There's no,
all these people that are tall.
I've got a nick on my shin.
Look,
this is where they pulled out the
implant.
Get the fuck Outta here.
Crazy.
Do you really think that aliens are
going to leave like little scars on you
and going to be pulling you,
pinched yourself,
you crazy fuck you pinch yourself and
made your own scar.
You Daddy Bitch to mention that there's
so much technology now that that people
probably do kind of like prank.
He Shit,
you know,
like I got these like helicopters that
looked like,
you know,
that you control helicopters and stuff
like that and well there's also
government stuff that guy in um,
Philadelphia the other day.
Thank you.
Whoever you are.
Some guy came to the show and handed me
a handed the manager a book and the book
got to me and it's all patents on
Aircrafts that the government has like
us patents for experimental aircraft.
Oh,
very cool.
It's fucking nuts man.
There's this crazy looking cling on look
in ships and Ufo looking things.
It's not,
it's not a book.
He just put it together.
Yeah,
he put it together.
It was pretty dope.
That's pretty sweet.
Yeah.
And so,
you know,
I mean you just look at the things that
the government has and has admitted to
designing and creating.
I mean this is like a fucking a giant
amount of a man.
When we were doing fear factor,
we were out at Edwards Air Force Base
near Edwards Air Force Base.
I think it was Edwards.
It's out like near um,
we were in Palmdale,
whatever the air force bases out there.
It's a big one.
And um,
I think it's Edwards and they were
flying stealth bombers and dude,
that is some crazy shit.
This was the beginning of the Iraq war.
It's like 2002 and they fly those things
overhead,
dude.
You swear to God,
you swear to God,
you're in star wars man.
You swear to God.
You're like,
that is,
that is some shit from the desktop.
When you watch something fly overhead,
they don't make much noise and they look
like fucking alien.
Spacecrafts it's dope.
I have you look at them like Danny's a
fucking stealth bomber.
You can't see that thing with radar,
man.
That's,
that's something designed to sneak up on
you and fuck you from the sky and you
can't even see it common.
And it's black like the sky.
So like you look up,
you see just blackness and it's black
too.
You're fucked.
Shit's bad ass.
Yeah,
it's,
you know,
it's all who designed for killing a few.
Who Do you want on the podcasts in the
future?
What is your dream people to get on?
I know,
isn't Adam Carolla coming and I'm coming
next week.
He's going to be here on the 26th.
Adam Cro will be there so that it what
is out of seven days from today.
So I'm like,
yeah,
yeah.
Adam's going to be on.
And you know what man,
the,
my dream has already been,
uh,
not just reached but surpassed.
I,
when we first started doing this,
when you and I first started doing this
in episode one,
we were just fucking around man.
And we're just sitting in front of the
computer and we just thought it'd be fun
to have like some little kind of silly
show that we would do for like people
that were on the message board and
that's mostly what it was.
And people on Twitter,
you know,
but now it's become like a radio show.
Now it's become this a,
this a way to tell people about shows
that we never had before.
You know,
it used to be you would go on a radio
show and you know,
you would hope that some of the people
that are listening where your fans or
hope that you could say something funny
enough to convince them,
you know on the radio in the,
it's in the morning,
you're fucking half away.
Give random people listening.
It's random people listening and who
knows if you're ever going to jive with
the um,
the Djs,
like there's a radio station in Houston
that apparently is still mad at me for
being on their radio show back in,
I guess it was like fear factor days,
like 2002 or 2003.
And they apparently still talk shit
about me.
They had me on and I remember they
wanted me and I was probably tired and
if I came off rude,
I didn't mean to,
but they wanted me to eat some stuff.
The first of all they wanted me to eat
some big hamburger they had and I'm
like,
no,
no thank you.
Like I kind of like,
I watch what I eat and also in the
morning I have hypothyroidism.
So I take a thyroid medication and when
I take it,
I can't eat anything for like an hour.
And so I was on this radio show and
they're trying to get me to eat this
stupid thing that they made an easy bake
oven.
I was there.
I actually filmed that digital people
are mad at me.
Are you still that there's still talk
shit about me.
Like I'm the worst person they've ever
had on their show.
And I didn't even know that.
I didn't even know they had an issue
until I left.
And apparently they were talking about
me when I wasn't there when I was there.
They were nice as pie to me.
But then when I left they started
talking like what?
The guy was so rude.
They had a gag and I wasn't into their
gag and I didn't know it was stupid
shit.
This is stupid.
And you know what?
They're not comedians,
man.
And they're,
maybe they're not on my,
my vibe [inaudible] on my frequency.
They're on their own frequency and they
thought it'd be fun.
They thought it'd be cool if I played
along,
but I didn't want to eat their thing and
they didn't adjust.
They didn't adjust.
So then I'm like,
why the fuck am I doing this?
And then it's like,
look,
when you,
when you do radio stations,
there's a lot of different kinds of
radio DJ's.
Some of them are really cool and easy to
do and easy to do their shows and other
ones,
they want more attention than you and
they're a little squirrely and they
don't like the fact that you're on TV
and they're on the radio and they get to
be cunty.
You know,
they get to be weird and they're looking
for something to be wrong with you.
So you're,
if you're coming from some fucking
television show and you won't eat their
stupid easy bake oven thing,
you become an asshole instead of,
if that was me and I had a guest on
like,
come on,
easy,
easy bake oven and he won't do it.
Oh,
I'd be like,
why don't what kind of an idiot am I
getting this gotta eat something.
This is all I have planned for this
fucking thing.
I can be asking him a million
interesting questions like we be talking
about all kinds of crazy stuff,
but instead I'm pissed that he won't eat
my fucking tuna casserole out of a
fucking easy bake oven.
So these people apparently are still
upset at me.
Well,
you used to,
it used to have to deal with those kinds
of people in the past.
Now I don't have,
that doesn't mean anything anymore.
Every show that I do now,
I do nothing for no press.
I mean I did Preston and Steve.
I called up,
uh,
for Philly,
but it was after the shows are already
sold out.
But I did it because I like them because
they're cool guys.
But like when we do these shows,
now we have our own radio station.
We have our own,
our own ability to promote the shows.
Probably more listeners than ever then
compared to that radio station that
hates you.
Yeah,
well that,
and it's all 100% your fans,
those are,
I hate that word.
Oh,
100% people who your work,
right?
So they already are enjoying what you
do.
They already enjoy your podcasts.
They,
they're already there for you.
They like you,
you know,
and so they want to come to the shows as
opposed to,
you know,
doing a radio show and trying to get
people out there to listen and like you.
And that's why people like those people,
these mediocre folks in Houston,
that's why they,
they,
you know,
they have like this,
that's why they have power.
They're their only power was that
they're the ones who get to talk on this
radio show when you mind would it,
they're not even,
they have no talent.
There's nothing going on there.
They're just talking people.
They're just dumb dumbs that are,
and then they play music.
They sorta hijack your attention span
for a few minutes while you wait for the
next cool song to start planning.
And they're just sitting there and
reading your Wikipedia page most of the
times,
if it's still Joe Rogan,
I heard that to be a problem for me.
It's just don't,
you know,
I just,
I don't know why they're still upset at
me because apparently this is some
recent interview.
Oh really?
I didn't even know about,
I don't even know who they are.
I don't even know where the station is.
I don't care if it's there.
Look,
if it's all these years and you're still
upset that I wouldn't eat your thing
that's on you.
That's on you.
100% I didn't do anything to,
I didn't break your window.
Didn't like your bathroom on fire,
you know?
If I just didn't eat your thing,
that's on you.
It's,
the whole world is filled with different
kinds of people,
men,
and if you try to make everybody happy,
you will fucking go crazy.
I know when I've been a douchebag and my
past,
I know when I've done things where I
could have made this go smoother,
I could have just,
this wasn't one of those things.
This is just stupidity and I didn't want
to deal with stupidity.
You're going to Texas soon,
aren't you?
Like August or something like that?
I want to go back to,
yeah,
I'm going to Houston.
I think August,
August.
I can't wait.
That'll be fun.
Yeah,
I'm doing that September again in the
Austin too.
Oh really?
Yeah.
That's always a good time.
And plus now,
um,
it looks like I'm recording the special
in June.
So,
uh,
if that happens then um,
I'll have,
uh,
I'll have to have all new shit by the
time September rolls around.
So I've got a lot of work to do.
Right.
That's exciting man.
I've been writing a lot lately man,
cause I'm trying to finish this book.
I've been writing like crazy man writing
is so fucking satisfying.
It might be one of my favorite things to
do.
I love the idea that you just sit in
front of that computer and these ideas
just start dancing in your head.
There's Ted dancing,
you know,
they start arranging themselves on paper
and then sometimes like when a,
when an idea will come out and then
another idea,
we'll follow it and I'll like a step
back,
a step back and look and I'm like,
wow,
it's this crazy thing that just like
happened through me.
You know,
this crazy idea that you know,
just happened through me.
And then it all like puts itself onto
paper and then the next thing you know
there's a hundred pages and actually,
you know,
there's 200 pages.
It's like wow,
it's,
it's such a fascinating process,
man.
The creative process of actually sitting
down and writing.
It's amazing,
man.
I tried last night,
I was going to write just for like an
hour and then get in the tank.
But once,
sometimes every now and then you tap
into a vein and you've got to stay
there.
You can't go anywhere,
you know?
And I just had one idea that I needed to
write down before I went into the tank.
And as I was writing that idea down,
something about writing,
like say if you're thinking about a
word,
like if you're writing the word
experience,
it takes longer to write that word than
it is to think of the concept of
experience.
So it allows you to deeply consider
everything that you're saying.
And then oftentimes like when you're
writing,
I can seem so much smarter writing than
I ever could.
Just talking.
You think?
Yeah.
You definitely,
I mean you talk very like smart.
Yeah.
But I'm wasted.
I,
but I'm way smarter writing that I am
talking cause you can consider
everything much more.
You know,
you get a chance to look at it.
you,
you really get to know someone.
Like,
and that's another beautiful thing about
this podcast.
You get to know someone when you're
talking to them for a long time.
You get to know like how their brain
works.
You know like you could write things
out.
Like that's what that was used to drive
me crazy about presidential speeches and
shit like that.
That they have people writing them for
them.
That is so fucked up.
It's his time.
Right.
Cause they have to give it like a speech
like every fucking day almost.
Can you just speak from the heart?
Yeah.
But,
but there's probably things they have to
just touch on their property.
Not like writers.
Like this is what you have to say.
It's more of like taking your ideas and
making an his speech for him.
Cause I,
I mean they literally have to do like
probably two or three speeches a day.
If you looked at Obama's like really?
Does he do two or three of them?
They're always going to,
colleges are talking here with
representatives,
you know,
they're always doing speeches.
If you looked at his schedule,
like there's that one time where they
followed him around for a week or I
forget what program did it and it was
just like his schedule is pretty much
from when you wake up,
uh,
just going from one place to another,
giving a speech,
giving a speech.
Oh right.
Your own speech speeches,
bitch.
I think he does actually.
And one of his most famous speeches is
one that he wrote,
one of them,
the ones when he was running for office.
He's,
he's a smart guy and he's a very good
speech writer.
But the whole idea of having a speech
written out for you by a bunch of other
people's kind of offensive to me it's
like,
what the fuck are you doing?
Being the leader.
If you've got all these people telling
you exactly what to say and you know
you're following all these charts and
graphs and this is what the people want,
and so let's give them this and this is
sort of in the middle and we'll lower
the expectations,
expectations with that,
and then they'll hit them.
We'll hit them with this to make them
happy.
It's just,
it's like so obvious that were being
played,
you know?
That's what drives me nuts about speech,
writing,
about the idea of it.
So this was like,
they're not even trying to pretend that
they're not playing.
You didn't even try to pretend that this
guy wrote the shit himself.
You know,
he's just up there reading off a fucking
teleprompter and you're just going you
and nothing changes.
Yeah.
I couldn't never do that.
I could never do speeches or anything
like that.
You could,
if you wanted to give speeches on
podcasting or speeches on something that
you know a lot about,
like if you want to give speeches on how
to be a good video editor,
you could do that.
You could easily do like a seminar in
video editing.
You know,
if you ever wanted to like if people
like we're anti your internet videos and
you could come up with a bunch of bolts
and points of things that you need to
consider.
Like,
Hey,
brevity,
you know,
there's,
you want to make it under 10 minutes.
You want this,
you want that,
you know,
this is my best video and this is why.
And the good thing about this video is
it starts off in one point,
then it goes back in time,
then it brings you forward again.
You know,
and then you can,
you could,
you know,
you could easily do something like that.
Anything that you're in too,
man,
you could teach other people how to do
it.
Did you hear that flip video is no more
what Cisco bought flipped video and they
asked him,
they killed it.
I always thought for some reason flipped
video was very successful and a big
moneymaker.
Seems like everybody's got flip videos.
See a lot of them had it.
And when Norton was at,
uh,
Austin,
he taped all this.
That's what that shit,
yeah,
they killed it for some reason.
Is it?
What is it so good?
Is it a big deal?
Well,
I mean it's,
it's just kind of weird that,
that,
that they did that,
you know,
you would have never found out about
that 20 years ago.
Yeah.
It would just,
it would,
unless you were reading the technology
page of the New York Times,
you know,
how the fuck would you have ever known?
You know,
now you get like an email alert from CNN
to tell you that flip video has been
eaten up by Cisco.
Yeah.
You know?
You know who Scott Adams is the guy who
created Dilbert.
Uh Huh.
He got busted going online defending
himself under a fake name.
Or You sir?
Yeah,
I sound like the week of shit ever.
How did he get busted?
I don't know.
No,
he got busted and then he,
um,
he like wrote something about it,
admitting it and uh,
it's,
this is what he wrote a according to
wise and fair Denisons of the Internet.
This after he's been busted according to
the wise and fair denizens of the
Internet,
this behavior is proved that I am a thin
skin troll asshole Dick fame whore
egomaniac Douche nozzle,
misogynist.
That list might sound bad to you,
but keep in mind that I was starting
from a pretty low base.
So I think my reputation is trending up.
That's pretty funny.
Wow.
Yeah,
it's in the Osi weekly if you guys want
to read it.
It's kind of interesting cause they're,
you know,
they're like,
wow,
this is what he did.
Was he logged online.
Um,
and he,
he did a under the name planned chaos
and he pretended to be the only person
in the world who doesn't hate him
because I guess he's been getting in
trouble lately.
I don't remember what it was.
I don't,
I don't remember what exactly he said.
He's,
he said some things that people thought
were a questionable and so,
uh,
people were shitting all over him.
I met him.
He was on a,
an episode of News Radio.
Yeah.
That goes to show you a how old Tilbert
is Dover.
It's been around forever.
Man,
I never got into Dilbert.
Wrote was terrible.
Those,
those cartoons are like the lowest
expectation ever for humor and for
entertainment value.
It's amazing that they can make so much
money.
Like I used to read Doonesbury and I
remember Doonesbury this smart one,
man,
it was really smart.
The only time to me it was even remotely
interesting was when they had a Raul
Raul Duke.
It was the hunter s Thompson character
who would come in with guns and start
shooting shit up.
And you know,
it was like hunters Thompson's,
um,
uh,
they kind of like,
he has his character,
Raul Duke from,
um,
fear and loathing in Las Vegas.
You know,
he like the,
not the novel is sort of based very
loosely
on him and his,
uh,
his friend Oscar and the crazy shit they
did when they were on drugs and Vegas.
Right.
And this,
this guy from Doonesbury just sort of
co-opted that character sort of stole
it,
stole his intellectual property and
started using it as characters inside of
his,
uh,
Doonesbury comic.
I thought that was kind of cool.
Like those kind of funny that he did
that it was kind of,
those were fun.
But other than that,
like most of it was like really like
nothing.
It's like the jokes were like,
Ooh,
uh,
give a read like Marma Duke or something
like that.
How was that shit still even a possible
your Bailey's still around?
Yeah,
I think so.
I think,
I don't know.
I don't fucking know who would cry if
the cartoons section.
I remember when I was a kid though,
I used to like the cartoons I used to
like far side that was fucking brilliant
shit.
And then they just Kinda,
you know,
Kinda went away when I was at Garfield
guy growing up,
obviously.
So Garfield in far side where my to
Calvin and Hobbes pretty.
So you do like our duties?
I do.
I mean,
but,
but then you get those ones like
whatever that fucking Kathy.
Oh yeah.
Fucking,
there's some that don't make any sense
and you have to wonder how those people
keep their jobs.
Is it like some sort of a government job
where you can't get fired or that prince
valiant or whatever that one that was
like,
remember that one?
What was that one where it's like all
medieval knights and I always tried to
get into that one but I could never
fucking do it.
Oh,
they're the worst man.
They're the worst there.
Is there.
Is there anything worse than fucking
stupid cartoons because there's no lower
standard.
You know,
like if you ever like read a cartoon and
laughed now like Holy Shit,
that's Pharcyde definitely.
Really?
Yeah,
first sides.
You never read any of the first.
I never got into it,
man.
It's,
I think like standup comics.
Some cartoons are so bad,
they like turn you off to other
cartoons.
Like I've talked to people that have
been to like shitty comedy shows like,
man,
I'm not really in a live comedy,
right?
Like,
well,
you're not in a lab company.
Okay,
what are you talking about?
Have you ever gone to Saint Louis C k?
Okay,
go see Louis C K and then tell me if
you're in the lab comedy,
because you might not be into some
Douche bags at the chuckle hut,
you know that are telling nonsense
jokes,
but go to see Chris Rock.
Go to see Dave Chappelle.
What does he a real comic.
You're going to love comedy,
man.
Don't get crazy.
You go see Joey Diaz and if you don't
laugh,
you don't have a fucking pulse.
All right?
There's something wrong with you.
You're not.
You're not enjoying that.
Joe.
Joey destroyed all weekend in,
in Philadelphia.
He's so fun to have around,
man.
No one makes me laugh more than that
guy.
He's so fucking fun to have around.
But as we were saying before,
he gets wired,
he gets angry at you.
I'm just reading these facts that I,
that were on digg.com today if facts
about masturbation and it's going
through that,
that male Kangaroos have been known to
give them stuff,
blow jobs and female porcupines have
been witnessed using wooden sticks as
deal dose.
What he imagined wanting to animal
checkoffs.
Did dinosaurs have Dick's?
Right?
Right.
Yeah.
I was thinking,
imagine how big that Dick is and then
like if a dinosaur fucking calm,
like how much come that would be?
How are you 12 no,
I was just thinking about it the other
day when the dinosaur come didn't have
dinosaur decks.
How big would the load be if a dinosaur
come?
Yeah,
and here's another fact.
30% of suicides by males age of 12
through 20 are attributed to our auto
erotic fiction.
No.
What is that on Wikipedia,
man,
I don't know to,
Oh,
here's a flush [inaudible] 12 to 20
that's silly.
That's insane.
You know,
here's a fucking interesting statistic.
That's real.
70% of all pornography gets washed
during nine to five hours.
Really?
Yep.
12% of a,
a porno film is watched at a hotel room
on average.
Only 12.
That makes sense.
But 70% being,
uh,
during the internet or downloaded from
the Internet while you're at work,
nine to five.
Totally.
How many people are watching this
podcast or listening to this podcast at
work?
How many of you were masturbating while
listening to two people right now and
only one's hard?
One of them was crying,
struggling,
trying to make shit happen.
There's too much porn.
I think at this point it's almost like
it's too easy to beat off,
you know?
It's all,
it's all out there.
It's,
it's,
it's almost like unavoidable.
Like you used to be hard as hell to get
some pornography.
When I was a kid,
like we were talking about earlier,
like about magazines,
man,
that was what you got magazines,
man.
You had to go to a liquor store and ask
for the back shelf.
And you know,
nowadays,
man,
it's so fucking easy to get pornography
nowadays.
You could just specialize on one
particular type of pornography.
Yeah,
you could be like a Weirdo foot guy.
You only want foot jobs,
girls jacking guys off of their feet and
you could fucking stack monitors to the
top of your room like a,
like a,
a movie screen,
50 feet high and every one of them has
got a different video of a girl,
Jurgen,
a guy off with their feet.
You would die of old age before you
watched all of them.
There's this,
there's this a shit that I was reading
about where guys who,
uh,
go to graveyards after they bury
somebody.
Um,
like recently,
like,
like they go,
they would like the next day after they
bury somebody and they'd dig 'em up and
fuck them.
Oh God.
Like they check the obituaries and find
like a young team,
you know.
Oh,
and where was this happening?
Uh,
it was on the Internet.
I read it.
Of course people are doing it in the,
there was a,
an old Kinison bit,
people doing it and a morticians office
and the mortuary that,
you know,
remember that bit.
I could see that happening.
Dude.
That bit is what got me into Kennison
really.
I've told this story before,
but in the interest of brevity,
a girl that I was working with did the
bit for me cause he was telling me how
funny he was and she was lying on her
stomach in the parking lot on it.
Oh you mean live keeps fucking you in
the ass even after your dad never ends.
And I remember thinking like,
wow,
what does this guy like?
This guy must be the funniest guy ever.
And then I got ahold of is a HBO special
and I got a chance to see it.
That's what that was probably the one
moment when I was 19 years old,
but girl on her stomach
and the parking lot telling me that Joe,
that was one of the,
the one moments,
one of the few moments in my life were a
spark went off in my head like wow,
maybe I should do that.
Maybe I should be a fucking comedian.
You know when I was 19 I had no idea
what the hell was going to happen in my
future.
I didn't know what what I was going to
do,
but I was already starting to think like
maybe,
you know,
maybe I have to find something.
You know,
maybe it's not martial arts.
I have to find like something else to
do.
Like maybe it was this,
this fucking guy's on his stomach,
you know,
pretend to get fucked in the ass like,
but there was nothing like that back
then,
man.
But I think his joke was based on a true
story.
It was in la,
so some people got arrested for paying
the morticians to spend a few hours
undisturbed with the freshest male
corpses.
Oh God.
Yeah.
I think if I was a mortician,
and I think if you get a hot chick that
there'd be some times you're sitting in
this basement by yourself,
you'd be like,
I'm definitely going to touch this
video's online.
There's photos online of guys fucking
dead bodies.
Fuck it.
There's a voting photo online of a guy
with this where,
I don't know if it's still up.
This was years ago.
This was in the late nineties,
early two thousands and there was a
whole sequence of photos from start to
finish of this woman up being on the
slab.
She's clearly dead,
you know,
and then you know him putting his penis
inside of her and yeah.
And it's like,
whoa dude.
You know,
he didn't just take these photos of
someone's daughter and someone's sister,
someone's wife.
He fucked her and took pictures of it
and then put it online.
You know,
some fucking crazy shit man.
I wonder how many people who get into
um,
like what the,
what the number is,
how many people get into being a
mortician or being how many of them in
the sex?
Yeah.
Fucking around with bodies.
I'm sure it's very high,
man.
I'm never surprised at the things I
hear.
And I think if you were in to fucking
dead bodies,
that would be the number one thing to
do.
I bet.
How good is the meat and the dead body
as it is it,
I'm sure it's,
I'm sure it's juicy.
It's here.
I know what I'm saying.
I mean,
get mowed persons rigor mortis set in.
Do they,
can they fix that too?
They is there a way that they can have
remorse,
not knots in like what happens when they
embalm them?
Don't they pump out all the,
what is Rigor Mortis?
What does that come from?
Do you know what it comes from?
I think that's when you die.
The body just difference up.
But I don't think it's,
I think it took me a squirrel off the
road.
I think it's an immediate,
oh,
you get to meet,
I think it's a case.
It takes a few hours.
Yeah.
So maybe if you get the person right
after they died,
they'd be still pliable.
Yeah,
but don't you like when you die you'll
also,
you just automatically piss and shit
yourself and all that crap.
Just cleaned them up,
man.
If you're going to fuck a dead body,
you can't have high standards.
So I just
kind of have to warm him up.
Maybe get some lamps are heated blanket
and let them sit in there for awhile or
something like that.
Put them in a warm tub,
not warm enough to cook them or how,
you know,
the cool thing is that you could just
pretty much fucking rip skin if you
like,
wanted to fuck that ass really hard.
You know,
you just never have to worry about are
getting hurt.
Right?
Yeah,
that's true.
I guess you could think it that way.
She's a gagger going right through the
back of your throat.
Something about disrespecting dead
bodies.
It's particularly offensive,
particularly unsavory.
You know,
the idea of disrespecting someone's
body,
their vessel while they're gone.
You know,
it's so like,
it's so inhuman,
you know,
there's something about it that's like,
it's very creepy,
right?
One of the creepiest things that an
eating it,
eating someone's body after they're
dead.
I was listening to,
um,
Casey case.
Um,
there were,
uh,
he's still around.
I don't know if he's still around.
They had them on the radio though he
might be dead,
but they had a,
he was there playing a once from the
1970s I was in Philly and Philly has
this one bad ass radio station and I
tweeted it out.
I don't remember the name of it.
It's like w o o g l,
e,
g,
O l.
And it was all like one badass song.
It would be like pink Floyd and then it
would be Michael Jackson and then it
would be like,
uh,
you know Sam Cooke.
I mean it was like some serious fucking
jams one after the other knows how this
pool hall that we were playing at.
And uh,
they were,
they played like repeats of like the
countdown show and I forgot like Casey
Kasem with the cow and he would,
uh,
you just pull that out.
Never.
First Time I've ever done that too.
That was awesome.
Here we go.
This,
this request comes down on outcome.
Hey Scooby,
come over here.
[inaudible] some with the countdown.
I can't even do I have,
if I heard him,
I can do it.
Really?
Can we do?
Oh yeah,
I didn't know that.
Yeah,
so weeks.
Um,
but he was,
the,
one of the songs apparently was about
cannibalism and I don't know the song,
but it was about some people that,
it was like the Donner party.
It was about like,
you know some people that,
you know,
the Donner Party story,
they were headed to the west coast and
they got stuck in the mountains of
Colorado and they ran out of food and
they,
some people die and they ate the dead
bodies to stay alive.
Right.
Parker made a film about it.
Did it really?
The musical.
What's a cannibal?
The musical when his first movie he made
in college with Matt Stone,
it's fucking brilliant.
That's really funny cause they're from
Colorado too.
Yeah,
I fucking love it.
It's,
it's a brilliant movie.
Cannibal.
The musical.
Yeah.
Okay.
I'll have each of your Amazon that shit.
But Casey Casen was going off,
Casey Kasem about this.
Sometimes you have to make decisions and
it was like,
the decision was like,
we,
we like stop playing.
We're like,
what the fuck is it?
It's like you have to make a decision
between eating the body or dying
yourself.
And we were like,
what the fuck?
Wow.
What,
what a weird,
you know,
top 40 or whatever the fuck it was.
Or,
you know,
a song is,
I mean,
I think it was a request,
you know,
I only like tuned into it halfway while
he was saying it,
but you know,
it was one of the weird thing.
This next song deals with cannibalism
and it was like what?
Like how many times in history of people
had to eat?
People stay alive.
There's only like a few recorded
instances,
right?
There's a soccer team that crashed in a
plane crash and they made that movie
about them.
Remember their spoon?
Yeah.
They're spooning that guy's ass out.
Oh yeah.
Eight is the frozen asked meet with a
spoon.
That was a freaky ass movie man when
that that airplane broke apart.
Yeah.
Tubes made out of metal aren't really
meant to fly through the fucking sky.
Yeah.
You know,
I was thinking the other day is what
happened to all those lots of people.
You notice how like all these actors
from loss were so high in their career
and now do you see any of them?
They burnt off and he didn't want to
have anything to do with them.
Jack was pissing me off.
Man.
I know after a while,
man,
he really annoyed the shit out of me,
man.
He drove me nuts.
He was so phoning it in at the end when
they're all standing around that tub and
someone comes back to life like this
mother fucker is just phoning it in man.
Yeah,
he drove me.
It drove me nuts cause he wasn't
appreciating his fucking,
his,
his part.
He was,
he started off that series as a winner.
Jack was the fucking hero.
He was the man,
you know,
he was a doctor,
he was handsome.
All the girls loved him.
And by the end he was a junkie and a
loser.
And you know what they did was,
I guarantee you that guy's annoying.
A guarantee.
That actor is annoying and they're like,
the fuck this guy.
Like,
well let's just start making them a
douchebag and start slowly like making a
more and more annoying.
Fuck yeah,
they must have done that.
Cause how if he was so cool,
everybody else sort of like kept their,
their thing or became more cool as the
show went on.
You know,
like the really hot girl with no ass.
What's her name?
The really pretty one with the dark hair
with a fucking beautiful case.
Kate.
She sorta became cooler as time went on.
We got her shit together,
you know,
raise that girl's baby,
she had a like a lot of good positive
attributes.
John Locke became like mysterious and
sort of magical and sort of figured out
the world.
Jack just became a junkie.
Just became a fucking loser man.
Yeah,
he just slowly,
the reason for that,
if you saw the last episode,
last episode can suck my Dick.
I mean ain't fucking with that man.
I think this much and you have some
freedom and walking away for it,
man.
You watched so much of it that you might
as well see what happens.
There's some freedom and just saying,
no,
you don't have me anymore.
You fucks.
You can't.
You can't own me bitch.
I'm not your whore.
All right,
I'm not tuning in every week to watch
your stupid commercials.
Just so you can trick me with your silly
storyline.
I don't even watch TV anymore,
it seems like,
but once you start fucking throwing in
like time travel and shit like they did
and now we're in 1970.
All right.
You don't even know what happened.
You're fucked so you can do anything.
You want your fucks.
There's a reason why.
Yeah,
I can tell you as it is,
they can switch.
You like to know.
Nope.
I don't want to know that.
You want me to know and then I don't
want to know.
I love that there's freedom in that man.
All right.
He was a girl the whole time.
He was a girl.
Oh good,
good.
He seemed like a girl.
He was,
Kate seemed like he was on his period
for 10 years.
Fucking Twat.
Jesus.
Um,
anything else before we,
before we get going,
there were some questions on the Rogan
board that I'm perusing through and some
of them we've actually already answered
and um,
some of them,
here's just like one,
what are your thoughts on listener
supporting the fod cat,
the podcast financially,
if it's not necessary?
The podcast,
as I said,
is a great method for me to promote
shows and promote all the other stuff
that we do and we get sponsorships.
The more you guys listen,
the more we get sponsors.
I mean we just have this flashlight
right now,
but that's mostly because we're going to
be moving to serious very soon both.
Obviously we will still be live and free
on the Internet.
It's still be on iTunes for free.
It's still be available for download on
the website for free,
but it will also be on Sirius satellite
satellite radio,
just so more people can listen to it and
just,
you know,
I like serious.
I have it in my car.
It's,
it's an awesome service and I think it's
just another avenue for us to get heard
and you know,
we're not even getting paid for it.
The same thing as like stitcher and all
that.
I'm,
I'm for all of those things and the more
of these things that we do,
the more it,
you know,
it it like,
I've never had this many people come to
my shows.
I've never had,
I mean this is obviously,
this is a good thing,
you know,
it's obvious that there's a benefit for
me in that and the promotional aspect of
it and is a benefit in people that they
get this free entertainment man.
And it's a benefit for us too,
you know,
over the course of the year.
So that we've been doing this.
One of the coolest things that it really
made me appreciate it.
I was bummed out when I had to come back
here from Colorado.
You know,
I,
I have this idea of raising my kids in a
place where it's a little more calm,
there's less people,
there's less of the pressures of
Hollywood,
the,
there's sort of the bullshit materialism
of,
of this area,
this part of the country.
It's a silly part of the country.
There's a lot of cool people here,
but it's also a very silly part of the
country.
So I was bummed out,
man,
when the dog got eaten by the mountain
line and when Mrs Rogan got pregnant,
we had to come back.
I mean,
it was,
to me it was like,
fuck,
I was gone.
I made it out of this place.
I was,
I had escaped and now I'm back again.
But what really like made me appreciate
this place was this podcast and was
having all these cool people come over
all the time.
Having Ari over,
having eddy over,
having Joe,
we over Evan,
Bert Kreischer and Russell Peters and
Tom Green.
And I'm like,
you know,
I sit back and I go,
God,
this is so much fucking fun.
You know,
somehow or another we have like a real
legit national radio show and not even
national man worldwide because we had a
fuck load of podcast fans in Australia
that's on the other side of the fucking
planet.
And when,
when I asked them about the podcast,
they went nuts.
So it's,
it's,
it's a worldwide sort of a thing,
man.
And you know,
and
who the fuck knew when we did this that
it would be what it is now?
Who knew that every week would be in
the,
you know,
the top five of iTunes?
Who the fuck we had never,
I had no idea.
It was completely by chance.
And slowly along the line it's morphed
and slowly along the line it's evolved
and slowly along the line it's become,
you know,
like something,
it's,
it is itself,
you know what I mean?
Like now we don't think about how to do
it.
Like we came over here,
like Brian came over here today and we
didn't even have to talk about when we
talked about just normal shit like we
always do,
but this is our hundredth episode.
Man was a big deal,
but we're like,
but we should do it.
We were like,
wow,
we should do it together.
Yeah.
It's just sue,
you and me for the hundredth.
And then that was the,
all the thing we had to talk about.
It's like it is its own thing,
you know,
it is,
it's got its own life to it now and all
the people that send me emails,
man and all the Twitter messages and all
the people that I meet in the comedy
clubs,
I appreciate the fuck out of that.
I think it is.
One of my biggest accomplishments in my
career is this podcast and that that
message board and both of those things
and that the,
the,
the whole,
the whole Internet group,
but bringing all these cool people
together and the,
the positive energy that I get from all
of these people at shows and the
positive reactions that I get so many
people coming up to me and telling me
that this podcast helps them think
differently.
It changes the way they look at life.
It changes the way they view their
friends.
Change the way that you view how they
interact with other people.
You know,
I couldn't be happier man.
I couldn't be happier that we did this
and this wouldn't have happened if I
didn't give in and,
and come back from Colorado.
If I decided to stay in Colorado,
we would have never have done this.
You know?
What about the idea of getting like a
female sidekick?
A,
I'll take a whole,
a whole robbing Chris Rogan's not really
down with that.
Yeah.
Oh,
did you hear that he slept as coffee
again?
Then the fuck filled it out.
Load for you.
Yeah.
If you hear suburban man,
that's me.
Blame me.
Um,
yeah.
You Know Adam Carolla had a really funny
girl on his show.
He had Theresa Strasser for Awhile and
she was really funny and now he's got
this new chick and a lot of people on
the Rogan board didn't like her.
But I thought she was funny.
She made me laugh.
The crazy thing about that is they
ought,
he had auditioned a few girls like
Esther little Esther went there.
Oh that's how this girl got it.
Yeah.
And I guess,
but what's crazy is like if you go to
his website and look at all the comments
per episode,
every single one of the girls that he
did like all hate,
like his,
his audience hates so bad girl on any
girl that's on his show.
I feel so bad.
Or Brody Stevens,
those.
So the girls and Brody,
who was the new girl?
Uh,
you know,
I think her name is like,
uh,
Jesse or something like that or no,
no,
I'm looking for,
I'm going to look at it right now cause
I feel rude that we're talking about our
own.
Nothing in her name.
Yeah.
That's gotta be cool to have Adam
Carolla on.
He's going to be on this,
this,
uh,
next week.
Next Tuesday.
Yeah.
In your formula,
uh,
that you've been working with on,
on it.com o n n I.
T.
A cause it's almost done.
It's on its way.
I was reading the,
did you read the case study?
That,
that's pretty interesting.
Yeah.
A lot of people,
look,
I've been taking five HTP and I've had
some pretty powerful results.
I feel like it makes a sentences form
easier.
I feel like there's more circulation to
my brain or something,
and then I don't know what it is.
But five HTP has given me a,
a very tangible benefit.
And there's some other stuff that I took
that gave me some good benefits as well.
But what we did with Chris did with this
new tropic formula at school,
like Alpha brainwave,
nootropic formula is going to call it.
What we did was take all of the best
nootropics,
which are nutrients for the brain and
condensed them into a,
into,
I think it's like two pills and it's all
these people.
The case studies had some really
positive experiences with it.
Yeah,
I'm excited.
It's all legit stuff.
It's all stuff that people have reported
actually helps brain function.
We're going to combine it into one thing
and I think nutrition and you know,
mental nutrition and physical nutrition,
all of it is one of the most underlooked
keys to happiness for people.
You know,
I mean we have a friend that got on
antidepressants and this motherfucker
eats Cheetos every night.
It never works out.
And I was like,
Yo Dude,
you know,
if you took care of that body,
I guarantee you you would feel a little
bit better.
I mean you,
you,
yeah.
I mean,
I'm not saying you don't have an issue
that maybe needs to be corrected
chemically cause I'm not,
I'm not inside your head,
but I know for a fact my own brain,
if I didn't work out,
I would not be nearly as happy.
I would have all this extra pent up shit
and you got to get that out man.
And you've got to treat this fucking
vehicle.
Good.
Give this vehicle vitamins,
van.
I drink fresh squeezed juices every
morning.
Every morning when I'm at home I squeeze
a,
I get ginger and raw garlic and carrots
and celery and I blended all together
and you feel so fucking good.
It's great getting all those raw
nutrients in your body and your body.
You know,
two people that I know,
I have a lot of friends who are very,
very smart,
but they almost think that there's
something vain and trivial and foolish
about taking care of your body.
You know,
they smoked cigarettes or they,
they,
they eat shitty food and you know,
and they never exercise.
They never had to take care of
themselves.
Like,
man,
you're missing out on a big chunk of
life.
It's annoying.
It's annoying to have to go to the gym.
That's why it's good to learn a martial
art or it's good to like to pick up a
sport or racquetball or something where
you're forced to move around.
You know where it's fun.
It's part of the whole game.
But find some way,
find some way to take care of your
fucking Bonnie fines on fucking away
man.
Take some fucking vitamins.
Even if it's just multivitamins and fish
oil,
even if it's just that,
that will make a fucking difference.
And so many people don't,
man,
so many people just ride it out and they
just hope it all was going to
can stay together.
I switched my five HTP two Chris's
brand,
which is called Ron or rollover are,
can't remember which one it is.
It's the blue bottle.
Yeah.
And uh,
it's,
it's great to,
that's 175 milligrams I think it was.
And you feel a difference after taking a
photo shoot?
I've been taking it for over a month and
that in the reservoir patrol I think are
two of the best things I've take.
I take,
I take fish oil in a multi,
multi vitamin everyday,
but I think those two are the things
that I've noticed the biggest from.
How much do you think cigarettes fuck
with you owe a lot.
Definitely.
Yeah.
Does it bother you
doing that?
That you're poisoning yourself with
cigarettes?
Cause I've seen you before,
dude.
There's,
there's Times that I've seen you when
you were smoking a lot.
When you take on,
like you have a great quality to your,
he's,
it's almost like I'm serious man.
And you,
when you quit,
you,
you know,
what is that great?
You know what that is?
Is I have a great beard.
No,
and if I,
if,
if shave it,
it's great for the first three days.
No Man.
I mean,
um,
I mean like your eyes,
like around your eyes.
Like you,
there's something about smoking.
So I'm thinking about a lot of that
cigarette smoke in your system where
like your whole system looks like,
you know,
it looks like your whole system is being
poisoned slowly.
Well it is.
Why don't you fucking quit crazy bitch.
Hi.
Well you won't know what makes you say
you're going to quit waiting for the
first stroke.
The best part.
Is that what it can do?
And you going to go Vegan?
All my grandfather.
Your grandfather had a stroke?
Yeah.
From smoking.
Really?
Yeah.
Oh look at you live in smart and it was
like 65 oh,
so you feel like you've got a few years?
Yeah.
Okay.
Well what isn't there like a a point of
no return?
Like where you've done so much damage
that you can never heal yourself up?
No.
I mean well to a point if you get cancer
obviously,
but I mean there's a chart.
I think like after a year you're pretty
much back to normal,
your religion,
your lung capacity and all that stuff.
There's actually a thing where like if
you quit the first week,
that first day,
what keeps you from quitting?
Quitting?
I mean you've taken those nicotine
patches.
Can you just jam knows?
Yeah,
I mean it's just doing it.
I mean,
seriously smoking.
You see,
I wish you could tell I the,
the,
the addiction.
I wish I could too because Marin's
complaining about it all the time.
He's always on his Twitter talking about
they're putting nicotine patches on
shit.
It's always going to be there like that
voice in the back of your head.
Even if you quit,
it's still there.
Joey's in denial.
Joey likes to pretend he's not smoking.
You know me dog.
I don't need that shit.
While every time before a show he's
bummed cigarettes off.
Yeah,
right.
Yeah.
I always have to buy two packs every
time I'm hanging out with him.
Helium gave me some cigars.
Helium was the shit.
I fucking love it there.
Yeah,
to helium's we did this month Portland
and filling Baltimore fucking awesome.
For those folks that are interested in
the Massey Hall and Toronto Show,
the only tickets that are left are like
single tickets.
But you know,
man,
if you want to go to separate seats,
sitting separate seats or you know,
get people to move or something,
who the fuck knows?
But I just go and have fun and it's
going to be chaos.
And I'm doing it with Sam Tripoli.
But other than that,
it's sold out.
And for the June 11th,
I think it's,
what is the date,
by the way?
Same Aaa got a Fohawk Nolan on now.
Really Silly Bastard Sam Tripoli's
awesome.
And uh,
he'll,
he'll be opening for me.
And um,
I said June,
he's so excited about it too.
He's like,
I'll never play a bigger show than this
ever.
He,
he,
he's,
he's gone crazy.
And by the way,
San Francisco is May 12th through the
May 14th.
And that's at Cobb's comedy club.
Yep.
June 10th is the Vancouver date.
And uh,
April 29th is the Toronto Date in April
29th,
I said there's only a few tickets left.
And then the other thing is cobb's in
San Francisco.
Yeah.
It's already selling very fast at 12th
through the 14th because slow death.
Scott,
who's going there?
Uh,
yeah,
probably whoever's around,
you know,
if Joey and I can do it though,
you know how we do it.
It's like always getting a of a headline
gigs now,
which is very nice.
Yeah.
Always headline and all over the place
he's doing,
I'm doing comedy competitions.
He's doing or um,
you know,
um,
comedy festivals.
He says got back from Atlanta and he
goes,
uh,
it goes,
rulers though.
Something.
I was like,
why does this feel so weird?
And then someone said,
because you're the most famous comic
here,
it's like,
oh,
I'm not comfortable with that.
And I go,
you're not comfortable with that because
that's responsibility.
You feel like responsible for like the
young pucks,
you know,
like,
is that what it feels like?
He's a,
yeah,
that is what it is.
Like I go,
you shy away from every responsibility
possible.
Even being like the most famous
comedian,
like,
Oh,
don't look to me,
I don't know nothing.
And I'm like,
I'm getting Outta here.
And he just runs away teach.
It should be so much bigger.
I mean,
I was talking to Mary Carey when we had
her on the podcast and he was talking,
she was talking about how she saw you in
Ra.
She's just like,
it's I,
what's that guy saying?
Ari Shaffir.
He was so fucking hilarious.
I'm like,
wow,
you knew his name offhand.
Well,
we talked to her for like five hours on
the plane too,
but yeah,
that she did remember his name.
Yeah.
Wayne,
look,
it's,
it's tea.
It's tough these days for a comic to get
notoriety just for their standup.
You know,
you have to,
you have to get on something where
people see you.
There's just so much entertainment
value.
You know,
you have to have a comedy central
special,
you have to have something and an Ra is
at a bit of a disadvantage just like
Joey is and that they're both roost,
ruthlessly dirty,
you know,
which is really hilarious,
but it's hard to clean that shit up for,
you know,
a seven minute spot at live at Gotham or
something like that.
You know,
it was always hard for me to,
when I,
when I first started out to clean it up
for like a 10 minute set or seven
minutes,
seven minutes,
that's our hard in the first place.
Cause it's like just getting a joke out.
It's like fuck you know,
you,
when you want to do a set,
you want to open up,
get their,
get their respect,
get some laughs and then slowly settle
into your view of things.
But you can't do that in 10 minutes,
man.
In 10 minutes you got to slam him with
some shit and then just get the fuck out
of there.
And you know that that's something that
Ari hasn't done yet.
He hasn't really,
really knocked one out of the park and
they've got a half an hour comedy
central special and then got an hour's
comedy central special.
And he doesn't do enough updating on his
website either.
He's,
I mean,
you know,
I was,
look,
I've had a website since 1998 and
there's thousands of blog entries,
you know,
I mean I,
and I'm a busy guy.
You've got to write things,
you've got to give people things like
Twitter,
look,
I write a lot of shit on Twitter is
like,
hey,
the podcast is about to start.
Or Hey,
you know,
I'm about to do this Gig,
or hey,
you know,
come see me here.
But a lot of the rest of it is just me
writing things that I think certain
think are funny and interesting or some
link that Sony sent me.
That's interesting.
I'm retweeting it and I want it
entertaining.
You know,
I want to make sure it's entertaining
and because it's a part of that whole
system of,
of,
of promoting yourself,
of getting yourself out there or being
of being able to work and Ari hasn't
really embraced that.
You know,
he embraced the Twitter better a little
bit.
He writes funny tweets every now and
then,
but he needs to be like real proactive
of like his website.
It's not,
he's got a wife and kids and a job and
an excuse to not be doing all this
stuff,
you know?
But at least he's doing his podcast on
your desk squad network and it's the
skeptic tank.
If you're looking for that's the army
calls it and it's really good.
And uh,
I've been on it.
Um,
may have,
Miller has been on it.
He had with Steve on his,
I know that was,
I was,
I may have,
if they're under desk squats is go on
iTunes and subscribe to test squad has
met res.
It has Sam Tripoli's podcast,
Tom Sigora who was on yesterday.
They're all grouped into one podcast.
And think about that man.
You would have never thought that you'd
be doing something like that.
Yeah,
I mean how crazy.
You know what's weird is the whole thing
is that when I was in middle school,
you had to or something like that.
High school freshman in high school you
had a shadow of the day job where you
pick what you wanted to be when you grew
up and you shadowed them for a day.
And so I shadowed air radio station
because I wanted to be a radio DJ and I
shattered the morning zoo and a Wnci in
97.9.
It was the day buster Douglas One and
they have buster Douglas on the,
on the radio station.
I think I've talked about this before
but time,
but it was crazy cause we actually,
Doug was knocked out Tyson.
Yeah.
And we were,
we were actually in Columbus,
Ohio like when we did your DVD special
and we are on that radio show and the
guy was still working as a Dj and I was
like,
you know what,
you were the guy that I,
when I was a kid that I hung out with
this guy all day,
took me to breakfast,
took me to lunch and now,
now look at this.
And it's like I'm an adult and you're
still here.
Yeah,
no,
it's uh,
it's,
it's interesting what,
what podcasting has become,
you know,
um,
Ariel Helwani,
uh,
and I,
I did his podcast yesterday and I did it
through Skype,
which is pretty bad ass.
I did a video of portion of it through
Skype and a,
I just use the microphone and listen to
the headsets and I'm like,
this is crazy.
And we're doing it in real time and it
sounds awesome.
Yeah,
it sounded really clear.
Sounded Great.
Yeah.
Cool.
You know,
you can,
uh,
it's a different world,
man.
We live in a different world and we got
lucky.
We snuck in right on the ground floor,
you know,
totally never expected that.
I remember all these other people were
doing podcasts at the time because I did
Adam Carolla's podcast way before I even
moved to Colorado.
You know,
I had done it,
you know,
and it's still hadn't done my own.
What's podcasts in general?
It's weird how they used to be popular
like four years ago.
Like when I first came out and the iPods
first came out and they were,
or whatever,
it was a huge or for,
oh no.
Huge,
huge ones back then.
I remember like Kevin Rose and all those
guys from tech TV had no bills.
He,
the guy started dig.
Yeah.
Same Guy.
Kevin Rose.
Yeah.
Crazy bastards.
All him.
He's got some ideas.
Well now he's not with dig anymore and
everyone's pissed because they,
he pretty much,
he digs,
supposedly gone to shit since he left.
And then one's mad at him.
Like I said,
well that's a,
that's what I've heard.
I haven't been following still.
I use dig all the time.
I liked did good.
digg.com if you've never been is uh,
an excellent portal for interesting
stories.
Yeah.
There's always like,
I will scroll through the first four or
five pages and uh,
every time I do it,
you know,
there's always something interesting
that pops up.
That's where I got that Dilbert story.
And you know,
there's always Charlie Sheen asking for
custody of his twins.
Oh,
that's the fucking perfect thing to
happen right now at the end of the
podcast for this God damn phone to ring
because I never turned it off.
Malibu,
California.
All Right,
sorry ladies,
gentlemen for that sort of an inside
joke on this podcast and I'm a retard.
I never turned my fucking phone off.
The real problem is I'm always usually
on the phone right up until the time we
start.
And then there's a,
there's a bunch of them and their
cordless,
you know,
so they're all floating around.
I never know where the fuck they are.
And I usually just pull the plug out of
the wall.
I did it yesterday but actually plugged
it back in right before the show,
the show today,
cause I had to make a call.
You don't give a fuck.
And I wouldn't either.
The point is a,
we've done this for a hundred episodes
now.
Give me some knuckles.
We'd had a good time.
Red Band.
And I have uh,
we've,
uh,
more than,
surpassed our expectations.
I never had any going into it.
I don't think you did either.
Never thought it would be like this.
I thought this was actually going to
last a month.
I thought like you'd get sick of it in a
month.
And that's the craziest thing about
that,
that you still,
I,
you know,
you still do it,
you know?
Yeah,
I thought for sure.
I'm pretty good at
doing things.
Once I get,
once I get started,
I'm pretty good at sticking to him,
you know?
But it's uh,
the one I realized it was crazy when I
realized like weird things was happening
was when I asked the crowd in Boston,
I did the Wilbur theater packed,
sold out and I go,
how many in Eddie Bravo was there?
And I yelled out to Eddie Cause I had my
10th planet Jiu Jitsu shirt on and I was
like,
Chad planted in the house and then I,
and I yelled out how many guys listen to
the podcast?
And they went fucking crazy.
It was like 90% of the crowd.
And I was like,
Whoa,
really,
really?
And then I realized that I'm like
somewhere along the route,
maybe that's why these crowds have been
cooler lately.
Like over the last like six months,
the crowds have gotten noticeably cooler
and they were always cool.
There were always cool.
There was always a huge percentage of
cool people,
but there was always people that didn't
know what I was up to and they're just,
you know,
the fear factor or UFC or whatever.
Jamie Kennedy wasn't in town,
so they wanted to see me.
I know what I mean.
It's like they don't know what they're
doing and just wander in there.
But now it's,
uh,
it's a completely changed,
like in Philly,
the whole crowd,
it's all podcast fans because they find
out about the show long before everybody
else.
That show was sold out a month before we
were ever there,
you know?
I mean,
that's,
that's never happened to me before.
If the best case scenario was like the
last time I was in Philly,
which is like a year ago,
we sold it all out just before I got
there.
But this was sold out like way before
that,
you know,
so it's,
it's,
yeah,
I did an extra show.
You did more.
Shut the fuck up.
God Damn it.
Who is this again?
Same thing.
Hung up on me.
I'm don't give a fuck about them.
That's how I roll.
All Right Ladies and gentlemen.
Um,
at that note,
I apologize for the phone.
This won't happen after episode 100.
I'm going to,
I'm going to have that shit straightened
out.
I'm going to fix it.
Um,
we will be back next week.
As we said,
a Adam Corolla is on,
on Tuesday.
And,
um,
I think we're probably gonna do one
either Wednesday or Thursday.
I Dunno who Duncan trussell's coming in
next week too.
Yeah.
Joey wants to come on next week too.
We don't,
we should have in Joey.
We haven't had that Combo it together a
while.
It's a good combo.
That's a good Combo,
ladies and gentlemen.
It's been an awesome 100 episodes.
We,
uh,
have enjoyed the fuck out of it.
We thank you very much.
Everybody that enjoyed it.
We're,
we're,
we're so happy that you did.
And,
uh,
I appreciate all the twitters.
I appreciate all the Facebook messages.
I appreciate everything.
Thank you very,
very much.
You guys are the coolest motherfuckers
on the planet.
Thank you to the flashlight for
sponsoring the podcast.
If you go to Joe Rogan dot.
Neck,
there's a fleshlight link on the right
hand side.
If you click it and enter in the code
name Rogan,
you would get 50 no,
15 15% off the number one sex toy from
men,
and you can shoot loads and it feels
awesome.
Alright,
that's it folks.
Thank you very much.
We'll see you soon.
Love you bitches.
[inaudible].