[inaudible] four,
three,
two,
one.
Jeffrey.
Hey.
Thanks for being here man.
I appreciate it.
It's my pleasure and honor and uh,
on the day were bill cosby goes to the
pokey,
crazy,
sad story that a sad for some people,
happy for others.
Sad that he's only going away for,
I wonder if that's a death sentence for
a man at his age.
Essentially it is,
right?
He's like 81 or something like that.
It'd be weird if justice took into
account like your health status and
awarding.
Right.
I think they have done that though.
Didn't they do that with that guy who
was speaker Hassard who was speaker of
the house who was convicted for
molesting a large number of boys when he
was a wrestling coach.
Oh yeah.
Do you remember that man?
Yeah.
15 months.
Imagine they might,
I mean that's,
that's pure insanity in a wheelchair and
he was cool.
Yeah.
It could have been.
Well,
there's,
there's no way.
If he was a 25 year old able bodied man
who had done the exact same thing,
he would have gone to jail for 15 months
for a admitting to Molesta a large
number of kids who are under his care.
When he was,
he was a wrestling coach,
right?
Yeah.
Oh,
here's the guy in the movie was made of,
no,
no.
A different guy now is that,
that was dupont.
Dupont was not a child molester.
He was just a psychopath who,
uh,
hired a wrestlers to come live with him
and wrestle with them.
Yeah,
I remember that.
Yeah.
I know one of them,
the,
one of the main guy in the movie,
they,
uh,
the,
the two brothers,
Dave and Mark Schultz,
fantastic.
Uh,
wrestlers who were completely
misrepresented in the movie.
They made him out to be like,
involved this weird gay relationship
with him and doing cocaine and all,
they added all sorts of shit to that
movie.
Very weird.
How they do that.
Screenwriters,
you've got to dramatize it.
I guess it's sentence wasn't for child
abuse.
Why?
That's why it was that.
It says that says the judge said it
would have been higher,
he would have gotten more if the
statutes didn't run out.
The limitation for accident in 1960s and
seventies ran out to the judge,
noted the punishment for such a
conviction would have been far worse.
I think he actually got convicted for
big transactions keeping stuff secret.
Oh Wow.
Yeah.
I had to pay fines.
Statutes of limitations.
Yeah.
So we were talking about bill cosby that
a psychology professors and experts were
obviously stating that he had some sort
of problem.
I mean,
it's weird because the media will,
um,
have a certain narrative they want to
promote and they'll sort of find,
the psychologist will say the thing that
fits that.
Yeah.
So I think most clinical psychologists
would say,
I've never talked to the guy,
I'm not going entire to diagnose him
from a distance.
I have no idea what his condition is or
what his issue is.
But then there's the handful who are
willing to kind of stick their necks out
and say something.
And Man,
it's embarrassing to be a psych
professor for that reason because
you're,
you're always kind of being represented
publicly by the people who are kind of
being least professional about those
kinds of diagnoses.
That is a real problem today,
isn't it?
Like in,
in terms of,
uh,
identity politics and this,
this inclination to draw conclusions and
to lean towards one side or the other
instead of just looking at the actual
situation objectively.
And if you're not talking to him,
I mean,
I'm assuming bill cosby's a terrible
piece of shit as a human being.
That's what I'm assuming.
But you're looking at all this,
but I've never talked to the man.
I don't know what kind of crazy shit
he's got going on in his head.
But if all these women are telling the
truth and seems super unlikely that
they're all lying.
Yeah,
I mean wizard and it like zero for 50 of
them,
right.
With the same story.
Yeah.
He's got a deep dark streak,
that's for sure.
Um,
I mean,
the weird thing is,
so a lot of people who are successful
have a little bit of that dark streak
that have a little bit of that
sociopathy.
Like they can kind of step back from
normal human relations and they can
either turn it into,
you know,
abuse and exploitation like cosby did or
they can kind of civilized themselves,
right?
And they can harness that to do
something that's good and,
and where they're kind of using their
ability to take a different viewpoint on
things to,
um,
analyze human behavior or invent things
or,
you know,
propose new policies or whatever.
And um,
so I think that kind of dark streak,
you know,
if you have it,
you have to recognize it and kind of
tame it and work with it.
And the people who do,
I think can often do great things for
society and the people who don't end up
in jail.
Well,
this is one of the reasons why I wanted
to bring this up to you as an
evolutionary psych professor,
looking at the human mind in looking at
behavior patterns and what's clearly
some sort of,
I I hesitate to call crime and
addiction,
but it seems like an addictive pattern
that he has,
that there's a compulsion to doing this
to people,
that it's not as simple as he wants
women to have sex with them.
They don't want to have sex with them.
So he drugs them.
I don't think it's that simple.
I think there's some getting away with
it thing.
There's gotta be some,
he's better than everyone thing because
he's,
you know,
he's royalty in the t in terms of like
Hollywood,
in terms of show business,
in terms of standup comedy,
he's always been treated as royalty.
I mean,
he's been allowed to essentially
criticize anyone who wants.
He's rarely is there a rebuttal to the,
the things that he and
you know,
he's been criticizing the black
community for its use of bad words and
for its use of sexually explicit
language and,
and depictions.
And meanwhile the entire time he's
raping people.
I mean it's fucking
amazing.
I think one thing that might happen is
if you've got this public image as being
like squeaky clean family values and
you've got the burden of kind of being a
moral exemplar like that,
you know,
just like um,
televangelists right?
Or anybody who has a big religious
following,
like the pressure to be good all the
time I think can kind of tip people into
this.
The thrill of transgression I imagine
could be quite,
quite kind of addictive and I think
that's a real danger.
And I think that's that kind of
hypocrisy is why we should be really
careful about kind of idolizing anybody
to that degree kind of morally and
putting that burden on them.
Yeah,
I mean,
I could only imagine like being an
evangelist,
being someone who,
who preached about the word of God,
but meanwhile having this weird hooker
thing like,
uh,
do you remember what was his name?
Ted?
He ran a giant church and I believe it
was Colorado.
And the entire time.
I used to have a bit about them the
entire time we smoke in math and having
sex with gay prostitutes and all the
while he's going on about,
it's always the guys who go on about how
awful gay people are.
They're secretly gay.
It's so common.
There's a little research on that.
I mean it's not definitive,
but it looks like a lot of Ted haggerty
like film haggard,
cause a lot of people,
well a lot of guys who are pretty like
outspokenly homophobic and like you put
them in a sex research situation and see
what actually rouses them.
You show them straight or gay porn.
Right?
And you'll have a plethysmograph and
you,
you sensed it.
What's the graph?
What does it is my graph?
What does that sense is blood flow in
the penis?
Oh boy.
I need one of those.
Just have it in the background of every
podcast.
But when you come and do the podcast,
you had to put these electrodes on your
penis and then we were just going to
talk about Japanese vomit porn and
tentacles.
Well,
the playthrough graphs don't lie because
I'm still not the heart.
The heart lies.
Not those put his,
my graphs.
So yeah,
the,
the people who are often,
you know,
most hostile to something,
you have some,
some little issue inside that is
creating some conflict.
Yeah,
I mean normally makes sense.
They,
they,
the conflicted dots of the human being
who has this ideal of who they'd like to
project and what they'd like people to
think they are.
Meanwhile has this thing below the
surface that is literally everything
they despise and everything they rally
against.
And that is their,
their true nature.
Yeah.
God,
it's gotta be the office feeling.
I mean,
I've known several who were closeted
gay men and it's,
it's an awful existence.
They just live in this perpetual state
of just adjuncts and unease.
And meanwhile,
God,
if this,
think for the most part,
especially if you live in an urban
environment and most part people don't
give a shit anymore,
there's a almost a self imposed prison.
And the people that do give a shit,
they're the real problem.
You know,
the,
the people who are not gay,
who really care if someone's gay,
unless they're trying to do a cause
behind you.
Like why do you care?
Yeah.
Look,
if somebody wants to be in the closet
about their sexuality,
like they want to be discreet for
professional reasons or because
investors would panic or whatever,
like that's totally cool.
But I think,
and it's so hard to be authentic to
yourself.
Like it's okay to sort of acknowledge I
have this sexuality or these
predilections and,
and it's up to me to kind of harness
them and deal with them and manage them.
And if you want to do that privately,
that's,
that's cool.
We should have that freedom.
Yes.
But if you don't work out those little
demons and if you can't acknowledge
what's authentic,
I think that's where you get these
problems.
Like the cosby case.
Yeah.
And I believe there's a difference
between discretion,
not wanting to discuss your sexuality
and out and out hypocrisy there.
These are completely different thing.
It's one thing,
like you said,
like say if a guy's a ceo of some major
corporation and he happens to be gay and
he's just not interested in all the
political nonsense and all the social
nonsense it goes along with discussing
that.
Yeah.
He's like,
I'm just going to keep it discreet.
That makes sense.
Like why should he have to,
but if he lies to his friends,
you know,
like,
or if he goes on the attack and media
ass that is,
yes.
That is damnation in hell fire.
We are so strange.
Um,
as,
as a race and I have talked many times
about how bizarre it is that we've
become really comfortable with seeing
people have sex like on phones and you
know,
I pads and laptops.
I mean it is such a massive part of
Internet consumption.
Yeah.
But yet so dirty and so forbidden.
If someone comes in the room and you're
watching,
you slam the laptop shut in disgust,
total embarrassment.
It's really weird.
Yeah.
Well it's weird on so many levels.
Like I don't do research on whatever,
the psychology of porn,
but I know people who do.
And the fact that you can study it and
everyone watches it,
but you can't even show clips at a
scientific conference.
Wow.
Of what people are watching is kind of
bizarre.
A second thing that's bizarre is if
you'd asked people seven years ago,
you know,
in the 50s or whatever,
what do you think will happen if there's
unlimited free online pornography that
has every possible genre of humans,
of all sexes interacting with each
other,
including cartoon dragons and whatever
they would go,
civilization will have fallen.
Like it would be chaos.
It that sounds post-apocalyptic.
And,
and yet we're living in that era and
people are still driving their kids to
school and seeing like morally
judgmental about politics and our
ability to carp compartmentalize is kind
of all inspiring actually.
Yeah,
it really is.
Um,
but it's also our ability to adjust to
the times.
It's kind of awe inspiring to you think
about the different,
like I've often talked about,
uh,
when I was in high school is I was in
high school in 1981 my freshman year of
high school.
And that was literally around the time
that vh one tape was introduced into
modern America.
Is that what was the,
what was the exact year vh one?
Tapes were invented.
We got them in my house,
I think in an 82 like maybe I was a
sophomore,
which is right when you're about the
horniest and uh,
that's,
that's when porn made it into people's
houses.
And you had to go through those beads in
the video store.
Do you get to the porn section?
And everybody was like everybody but had
blinders on and nobody looked at anybody
else and it was just terrifying.
And you know,
you saw your name are there in the late
fees?
Like should I bring it back today?
Oh man,
if he paid,
I'll just keep it,
keep it bucks.
Three bucks.
If he just stole it costs 30 steel.
It just,
so you don't have to look,
look the guy in the face and in the 70s,
seventies really,
and her home use in the 70s on the Wiki
it says,
yeah,
seventies and early eighties.
Okay,
well maybe it was late seventies or
something like that.
My house,
we got it around 1980 I want to say 82
ish,
but it changed the world and it changed
it in a real sneaky way where nobody saw
it coming.
But the difference between the access to
sex to the looking at sex from 1960 to
1980 20 years,
which is,
you know,
in terms of historically is a very short
period of time at any other time other
than today.
Today it's a massive change.
Or if,
if you had to anticipate what it would
be like in 2038,
he'd be like,
Oh God,
you know,
all of you on mucks inventions have come
to fruition.
We'll be living in tunnels underground
and the surface of the earth would be
190 degrees and there'll be no more
water.
And
yeah,
people always overestimate how much it's
going to change in the next 20 years
compared to the last 20.
Yeah.
Um,
but you know,
if you'd asked a bunch of,
let's say psychology researchers who
study like marriages and longterm
relationships,
ask them in 1980 what's going to happen
when you have unlimited vhs porn?
Some of them might've said that'll save
American marriages.
How many do you think would go with
that?
All the hippies.
I think a lot of folks would have,
well that's the way you can get your
sexual variety needs mat and a kind of
virtual fake way.
And so that'll reduce the pressure for
like infidelities and other folks would
have said,
oh my God,
it will remind people what they're
missing.
And so it'll,
it'll nuke marriages.
The divorce rate will go to 80%
but then there's the third option,
which is the sort of the cosby ask thing
is that the addiction that there's,
there's,
and maybe I can ask you about this,
like what is it about things,
whether it is gambling or you know,
whatever video games,
there are things that people get
obsessed with and those things become
almost a part of who they are.
It takes over their minds so much.
Like if you had a pie chart of the human
brain with some folks,
there's a giant chunk.
This just porn.
It's like 40% of the brain's porn.
Yeah.
Like what happens?
What is,
what is it about the mind that makes one
obsessed,
whether it's with gambling or whatever,
whatever,
the vice,
whatever the,
the thing that makes you
dick did.
Well,
I mean,
one,
one issue is people differ in their,
their conscientiousness,
right?
Their degree of self control and their
ability to kind of resist temptations
and keep their eyes on the target.
Like career,
family,
kids,
you know,
do the right stuff.
Um,
other people like I just can't control
myself in any domain of life,
whatever it is,
video games,
porn,
um,
doing my homework,
whatever.
But I think we also have to cut people
some slack because remember now if
you're a teenager and you're really into
video games,
call of duty,
whatever it is,
there are literally thousands of people
designing that game to be as addictive
as possible and Beta testing it and
refining it and,
and you know,
doing the level design.
So it gives you just the right
reinforcers at the right pace.
And of course we're not going to be very
good at resisting that because the power
of capitalism and tech and innovation to
kind of exploit our brains is,
is pretty awesome.
Am I being naive or are they just trying
to be entertaining?
I mean,
I'm just trying to make an amazing game
that's totally immersive and sucks you
in.
Or are they really thinking,
Hey,
this Jeffrey Miller guy,
I want to get him fucked up on
battlefield earth now.
That was the John Travolta movie,
right?
That that did not succeed.
Okay,
let's just say unreal tournament.
I want to get him fucked up on unreal
tournament and get him completely
addicted to this.
They're just maximizing sales and profit
and what are they doing it consciously
or are they just trying to make the best
possible game that's so entertaining and
then it just as a side effect,
it becomes a addictive,
I think it's s
well,
okay.
If you're running a video game company
that the folks actually doing the
programming,
right?
Character design level design and
whatever,
they want it to be awesome.
They want it to just pick the best game
ever.
That is just so fun to play,
but the management knows we have to sell
it.
We have to make it compelling,
we have to make people excited about the
next version and,
and you know,
the add ons.
So I think there's kind of like a super
ego and ed issue going on even within
companies,
whether the designers just want it to be
cool and management just once a viable
commercial product.
But
doesn't that just come with something?
That's cool.
I mean,
I'm,
I'm just playing devil's advocate here
because I'm not exactly sure how.
I'm friends with a few guys who make
video games.
Uh,
Cliffy B who,
uh,
worked for epic games,
who makes a,
he showed us unreal way back in the day,
even before Jamie worked here.
We get to see them making unreal
tournament,
like as it was be made.
And,
uh,
I went to the aid offices when they were
working on quake three,
which are just these amazing games.
And it seemed to me,
and again,
I could be naive,
but it seemed to me that all they were
doing it was just trying to make awesome
shit that they like.
Yeah.
And then it became addictive just cause
it was so good.
I think that's most of that.
Um,
yeah,
I mean this summer,
like my girlfriend and I were each
doing,
working on our next book proposals and
we each got a little bit addicted to age
of empires hd,
which is like back in the day,
20 years ago.
And it's really fun because we learned a
lot about each other,
just watching each other play.
Like we had such different strategies
and in terms of like what you build,
what you prioritize,
how you deal with enemies.
Like it,
it's an amazing kind of personality test
[inaudible] its own right.
Um,
and we each got a little bit addicted
temporarily and in our own way.
And I don't think that's an intention of
the designers.
It's just if you make anything awesome,
whether it's music,
whether it's standup comedy or sex,
whether it's sex,
whether it's long form TV drama,
um,
like Ozark,
then people want that.
You know,
it works.
It's,
it's brain candy.
Yeah.
I saw you quote you,
you posted about Ozark after I posted
about how amazing it is.
I'm completely wrapped up in this second
season.
So incredible.
But you were saying how they always make
the kids bratty.
Yeah.
You don't have kids Dhea.
I'll have a daughter.
You do 22.
Oh,
okay.
I didn't think she was bratty at all.
I think she kept it remarkably together
for a teenager who's parents are
murderers and drug dealers spoil alert.
I thought it was,
I think she's Jimmy and she needs some
time alone where they need to talk to
her.
I mean,
you can't just let her go through life
hanging out with some kid who lives in a
trailer smoking weed and steel and
books.
You got it.
I kind of warmed up to it after,
like I'd watch the first couple of
episodes and she seemed kind of Bratty
the daughter.
And really and that,
and then,
and then be amazing.
My kids.
Awesome.
And,
and I don't know why all kids aren't
like her,
so,
um,
but I think screenwriters get lazy about
this stuff.
They think,
well,
if there's a family you need marital
conflict and you need parent offspring
conflict and you need secrets and lies
and,
but I think the way they're handling it
is amazing because the kid doesn't have
that kind of conflict.
The kid has,
like,
in my opinion,
uh,
a typical sort of a relationship with
his father where he admires his father
and his father's abilities and,
you know,
and he seems to be,
it's,
I just think that shows fucking great.
It's just so well read a written rather.
It just,
so it's so twisted and there's so much
going on.
So many different levels.
It's like I get anxiety,
I start sweating and I feel like I'm
buried body.
Well,
I love that you don't really know what's
going to happen and legitimate.
Like it's,
you know,
game of thrones,
you had that thing where any character
could die at any time.
Yeah.
And that's what that was one of the
major things that people watching.
Um,
and I think with really good TV drama,
you get that kind of engagement where
it's,
it's like real life.
Like,
you know,
the series will continue but you don't
know any particular character.
Well,
but
we didn't have that for most of culture.
That's what's really interesting.
It was through most of mass media
fiction that you saw on television in
the movies,
the good guy one.
Yeah.
You know,
and it was real predictable and there
was always like a little bit of drama.
Like he might lose,
he might lose.
Oh,
he wins occasionally.
You had something crazy like Thelma and
louise driving off the cliff and you're
like,
whoa,
whoa.
There's off themselves.
That's the end of the movie.
And he would leave the movie theater
like,
Holy Shit,
what a gangster move.
You know,
there was a few movies like that,
but for the most part,
yeah.
Well starting in like the golden age of
cinema in the 70s the counterculture
cinema,
you sometimes got those really profound
surprise endings.
But one thing that made an example,
the hustler vanishing point.
Oh,
okay.
That was the one with the challenger.
The guy had the challenger.
Yeah.
It's like I forgot to suicide by storm.
I remember the car.
Awesome car.
But I mean,
one thing that makes me optimistic about
America is that the same adults who are
being completely insane to each other
about politics on twitter,
whatever are watching this really
sophisticated,
you know,
emotionally insightful netflix stuff.
Yeah.
And I can't connect those,
those two things.
It's like when people aren't talking
about certain issues to capable of,
you know,
really in appreciating really insightful
drama that's about the subtleties of
human relationships and moral ambiguous
situations.
And then they go into the voting booth
or get on twitter and,
and it's like there's black and there's
white and that's it.
And,
and,
and I hate those people and I love these
people and I can't connect the dots
between,
you know,
the entertainment media that we
appreciate versus the kind of ideologies
that we over simplify.
Yeah.
I think twitter and I think,
well twitter in particular,
but blogs as well.
I think it is a horrible way to
communicate when you are saying
something that's in dispute,
you know,
because you're not challenged.
And I think there's also,
whether it's 140 characters or 280
characters,
I just think this limited way of writing
in text without talking to someone,
without being in front of them and
communicating with them and the
subtleties of human interaction and
social cues and recognizing people's
feelings.
And it just,
it's a piss poor way of getting your
thoughts out.
And it's very non human.
You know,
it's,
it's very,
um,
it's,
it,
it tends to gravitate towards cruelty
because there's no consequences for
saying cruel things.
It's almost like you're throwing a bomb
over a wall and you don't know who's
over there.
You know,
like you don't,
you're,
you're not there seeing it.
You're not,
there's something about that that I just
think is alien to the human condition.
And I think it's,
it's having a real effect on our
civilization and our culture and how we
communicate with each other.
And I think it's galvanizing the,
the polar opposites and it's making
people go towards these extreme left and
extreme rights,
especially people that are easily led or
maybe not so thoughtful about,
you know,
the objective way that they're
interpreting these events and not,
not being introspective and not looking
at themselves with a critical eye and
just engaging in this sort of back and
forth tribal shit with people that I
just think is a,
it's so strange to watch and
particularly with when you read
something and it's really well written,
like you could tell this is an
intelligent person that's written a
bunch of nonsense and called people
outright and Nazis.
And what's the most recent one?
Um,
that box voc speaks about the radical,
what is it?
This is a new,
the radical,
right.
The reactionary,
right?
Oh yes.
That's it.
The reactionary,
right.
This is the new one.
We have a new one now.
It's new.
It's only like a couple of weeks old.
The reactionary,
right.
It's a baby.
Yeah.
It's time to,
I mean the weird thing is people do have
a hunger for this more primal engaged
kind of long form discussion,
which is why podcasts like this are
really popular.
My people are willing to listen to,
you know,
to reasonably smart people talking for
an hour three about cool topics because
that's the natural condition.
You know,
imagine our ancestors a hundred thousand
years ago around the campfire having a
discussion about some fraud issue.
Well,
they would talk it through until it was
more or less resolved or unless they at
least identified,
here's the things we can agree on and
here's the things we can agree to
disagree on both twitter,
it's,
it's just the exact opposite.
It's not sitting around the campfire,
it's,
it's lobbing these hand grenades over
the,
and it's an infinite number of hand
grenades.
Like say if you have 30,000
followers or something,
God,
that's 30,000
people that might be lobbing hand
grenades and then they might retweet to
a bunch of other people and oh Jesus.
Then kier comes some,
you know,
especially if it's on some hot button
topic that they would like to chime in
on.
You know,
this,
this is strange.
Yeah.
Well I think,
you know,
the human social psychology is,
it's very hard to reach any agreement
without a certain amount of back and
forth,
preferably face to face in person with
as much time as you need.
Yeah.
And this is why things like,
um,
the sort of time limited presidential
debates drive me nuts.
I would love to just have 50,
60 hours of candidates.
Sure.
Talking it through and people can tune
in and just here,
okay,
here,
here's six hours about foreign policy.
Let's see what they really,
and then voters could have an informed
choice.
Imagine candidates actually learning
something from each other,
right.
And being open and honest about that.
Instead they have to pretend that
they're,
their ideas are rock solid and
completely well thought out and rigid
and impossible to evolve.
This is it.
They've got it and you're wrong.
And more what my opponent wants is some
something terrible for America.
And God,
we've,
when we've seen this hustle so many
times and yet it's the same hustle every
four years.
Yeah.
I hope we get to a future where people
are allowed to be epistemically humble.
Like here's what I don't know and I
don't know a lot about most things.
Even if politicians or scientists or
media figures,
we're able to take that attitude.
Yeah.
And just,
it kind of gets back to the hypocrisy
point,
right?
Everybody inwardly knows about most
topics.
I know virtually nothing or I've heard a
few things third hand that I can kind of
regurgitate at a party.
Yeah.
But we're all kind of expected to have
an informed view about everything.
And this is something I try to model for
my students.
Like if they ask a question and I really
don't know the answer,
I try to make a point of saying,
I don't know,
let's look it up.
That's awesome.
That's so important.
The idea that you should know everything
about everything is preposterous.
Yeah.
And you know,
if your 20 year old underground,
you don't know what the typical 50 year
old knows,
you might think,
Oh,
they've probably mastered most of the
wisdom and the world already.
Or he might think,
no.
Uh,
the,
there's like gigabytes of stuff and they
can't possibly know at all.
There's such a spectrum to the average
person that has a like a very intensive
job.
Like say if you're involved in
something,
a computer coding,
electronics,
something that's 10,
12 hours a day,
you're engrossed,
you don't have a lot of time to focus on
other areas.
You don't really have a lot of time to
expand your understanding of whether
it's biology,
mathematics,
whatever it is.
It doesn't apply to what you do for a
living.
Really have very little time.
So this,
this notion that you,
like people are embarrassed about things
they don't know.
And I think that's really unfortunate.
It's,
it's,
it's one of the main stumbling points
when it comes to like open and honest
discourse.
There's not,
you're not dumb if you don't know some
things,
you know,
you just don't know some things and you
just,
no way,
you know,
everything.
Yeah.
I think that's a great point.
A lot of people have these cognitively
demanding jobs and that's not just white
collar workers.
I mean a lot of manual trades.
Um,
you've got to think about what you're
doing and it,
it's hard mental labor and then you get
home and you have dinner and you have
the kids and their homework and your
family life.
And what are you going to do?
By the time you finally have some alone
time at whatever 9:00
PM are you gonna,
you know,
turn on the nature channel and watch a
really hardcore David attenborough,
you know,
animal behavior documentary or you're
going to be like,
oh,
just rewatch,
you know,
um,
unbranded or whatever.
Yeah.
I mean,
people want escape at that point.
Yeah.
It's,
there's not enough time in the day.
One of the most beautiful things about
podcasts,
it was completely unexpected for me,
is that it gives me this very unusual
opportunity to sit down and talk to
somebody without any interruptions for
three hours,
which I could never ask someone to do in
real life.
And why it never came up before.
Like even to have dinner.
If you and I went out to dinner,
we'd be talking in,
you know,
maybe someone else would be with us,
different conversations to be eating all
this amazing.
Did you try that?
Oh,
this is good.
Yeah,
what do you have to blah,
blah,
blah.
This is like little simple
conversations.
It's fun and everything,
but it's not completely locked in like
this with the headphones on through a
microphone.
The knowledge that other people are
listening and that these,
these subjects that you're discussing,
you're allowing these ideas to play
themselves out and you're,
you're sort of moving them around and
asking questions and you're looking at
them from different angles.
And,
and to have that liberty and freedom to
do that is a very rare thing.
And for people that get to listen.
And I,
I enjoy Sam Harris's podcast in
particular radio labs,
one of my favorite,
but one of the th there's so many good
ones out there,
but what's really good about them is
that you get a chance to listen to
discourse uninterrupted and uncensored
undirected.
And this is something that I think is
sorely missing from the rest of our
culture.
And it's one of the reasons why these
things have caught on so well.
Yeah.
I mean if you respect the ideas that
you're talking about,
you should be willing to give time yes.
And attention.
Yeah.
And let them kind of breathe,
like opening a bottle of wine and just
letting it do the aeration thing before
you pour it.
And
it's funny how much of a thirst there is
for that.
I mean,
if you'd asked me 10 years ago,
would anybody ever spend three hours
listening to a podcast,
I would have said,
no,
there's just this,
there's one way out acceleration of
culture that's going to be faster and
faster and nobody will watch more than a
92nd clip on youtube.
It's,
that'll be it.
Yeah.
And instead it's the opposite way.
I think people have a yearning for a
more relaxed pace of dialogue that is
actually a break from the frenetic pace
of their work life.
Right.
Yeah.
Um,
I think even like leaning towards things
that are like tech reviews,
things along those lines,
those are getting longer and longer when
people are just,
I mean,
there was never a television show where
someone would discuss cell phones in
depth with no interruption for over an
hour.
That's very common now where,
where someone will go over all the
different details of a phone and let you
know,
like,
here,
here's what's new about the galaxy note
nine and,
and the,
the gift fucking hundreds of thousands
of views.
Like clearly someone's missed something.
Yeah.
I mean,
even on Youtube,
like you can get 25 minute reviews of
like an ar 15 accessory.
Yeah.
Not just like the rifle,
but like the red dot scope or whatever.
And um,
or you,
I'm sure there long but wanting reviews
or whatever.
Oh yeah.
There's a lot.
Yeah.
I've seen them all.
And I,
I mean,
I think that's just a more natural pace
of,
uh,
human human discourse because no bear in
mind,
like a hundred thousand years ago,
sitting around the fire with a bunch of
people,
no smartphones,
no video,
no TV,
no movies,
no recorded music.
The entertainment is each other and it's
not rushed.
It's like the sun,
the sun went down.
None of us are going to sleep for four
hours.
Um,
what do we do?
Entertain each other with jokes.
No,
I mean,
break out the Ukulele.
They wouldn't have done standup comedy,
but there would have done sit down
comedy.
Well,
somebody's probably stood up.
Yeah.
You know,
held court told some good stories,
you know,
I mean,
a good story is always valued.
Good storyteller.
This is what my anthropologist
colleagues tell me is,
you know,
your status,
if you're in a tribal society,
a small scale society is heavily
dependent on not just how good a hunter
you are,
how many kids you have.
It's how entertaining are you in the
evenings.
Sure.
And the people who are just break the
monotony or just gold there,
their treasured.
Yeah.
They give you fuel to give you energy.
Like when you're around someone who's
really hilarious to telling great
stories,
he like everyone around it was like,
ah,
you get fired up by it.
Yeah,
yeah.
Um,
it's,
I don't,
I mean I have a rosy view of the future.
I'm very optimistic and I think that all
the chaos that we're going through right
now politically and socially in
particular,
this is,
I feel like this is just an adolescent
period of communication that we are
experiencing this,
this open flood.
Like we've opened up the,
the barriers for communication.
Anybody can communicate now and it's
just k and it's going to take a while
before the discourse levels out and
you've got a lot of loud noises on,
on all sides.
And there's a lot of people fighting for
power and fighting,
fighting for virtue,
fighting for,
you know,
whatever Social Brownie points they get
by pointing out their position being
correct and your position being foolish
and silly.
And this is the future and this is done.
And it's,
there's a,
there's this cruel aspect to it,
which is interesting.
Like when if someone missed steps and
someone says something that they regret
and then they delete it,
there's this cancel culture,
get rid of 'em off with his head because
people realize the immediacy of all this
and there was terrified of it happening
to them.
So it's like they're just throwing rocks
at whoever might be the accused.
It's fascinating to watch,
you know,
I mean we're going to need a whole new
set of social norms where people just
calm the fuck down about this stuff.
And I think it's kind of analogist like
one of my favorite books about kind of
social history is called dog,
the bourgeois virtues by Deidre
mccloskey and economic historian.
And she points out when you switch from
like the Middle Ages where everyone's a
peasant to this urbanized commercial
culture where people are mostly um,
traders and they have little shops and
whatever they needed to learn how to
interact with strangers to provide value
for money and they needed a whole new
set of virtues that had to do with
reliability and thinking,
what am I making,
what goods or services in my providing
that actually are useful?
And it took,
you know,
a couple of generations for people to
enter that kind of capitalist mode of
what can I do that's helpful to others
that can support my family.
And I think now we have a cultural shift
where we realize,
given social media,
how do we cope with the fact that
everybody virtue signals,
everybody sometimes says things that
are,
that are mean and stupid and everyone's
fallible and anything you say will be on
a permanent record basically.
Um,
how do we cope with that?
You know,
we're,
we're used to a sort of public culture
where everything is very polished and
edited and curated and,
and that time has gone.
So we need a new set of kind of social
and moral norms that cut each other a
lot more slack,
I think.
Yeah,
I would agree with you and I would say
that the inclination towards tightness
and communication and understanding
should be rewarded and that we,
we,
we need to reward that.
And I don't want to say ostracized
people that are inclined to go towards
this cancel culture idea,
but we need to let people be aware of
it.
You know,
we were talking before the podcast that
I have like all these emails that I
can't catch up on because I was gone.
I was in the mountains for six days with
no cell phone service at all.
I felt better when I was there.
I just did.
I feel like there's a certain amount of
anxiety that comes with being connected
to all these people all the time and
constantly checking your mentions and
constantly looking at Google news to
find out what chaos is coming our way.
And it's just,
I just don't think that that's healthy
and I don't think,
I think I do my very best to mitigate
the negative effects of it,
but my very best is not good.
So don't think we're doing a great job
because when it's taken away from me,
and I've had this happen twice over the
last few months,
um,
I was in Lanai,
this small island off of why one of the
Hawaiian islands and I broke my phone
and it took a few days for them to send
me a new one and I was like,
God,
why do I feel so good?
I feel so present and it feels so
healthy.
And then this last past week,
the same thing,
no cell phone service for all these
days.
And so I just felt better.
I think there's a funny thing even that
it happened with burning man culture
where like when it got started in the
early nineties it was let's all come
together and have this excitement of
interacting more.
And now since burning man is one of the
few places where you don't get cell
phone service and you can't really be
online,
it's like,
Oh man,
this is such a relief because we
literally can't stay connected.
And the community we're in is only
70,000
people instead of 331
it was almost boulder that's almost
boulder,
Colorado.
I think boulder's a little bit over 100
so 70,000
is,
that's a fucking big city of freaks.
It's
city,
but it feels intimate compared to
twitter.
Ooh,
right.
Yeah,
for sure.
Yeah.
I,
I'm fascinated by burning man.
I
can't go because hippies will drive me
crazy and there's too much dust.
Yeah.
But I love the idea and I'm up fully
support.
If there was like a fun do,
you could write a check like to support
burning man.
I supported as a project,
as an idea.
I don't necessarily want to go there
until they got it really polished and
worked out.
But I think what the idea behind it is
fascinating.
It's the people saying,
I don't like this.
I don't like where this is going.
I think there's a lot of people that
would like to do something different.
Let's just try it out for a week.
Let's just everybody,
let's agree,
we'll get together through these days
and let's,
let's just fucking dance and we'll have
glow sticks and where pastries and get
fucking crazy and do ecstasy.
And a lot of people were like,
fuck yeah,
let's do it.
And then this thing happens and this
thing is only a few years old.
I mean it really is.
What,
a decade and a half.
How many years have they been doing it?
The night?
The first burning man.
It was like the late eighties but it was
just like a couple dozen people and now
it gradually grew and it really became a
pretty solidified subculture by probably
the late nineties and no leadership.
Well there is guy behind it.
There's behind the scenes leadership of
course.
I mean that's another fascinating thing
is depending on the political lenses
that you wear when you go there,
it's either like a libertarian paradise
or it's a communist paradise.
Mm.
Or it's pantonium self organization of
some sort.
Um,
but there's,
there certainly are people who are kind
of coordinating it.
It's just they're not,
well there's tickets now you have two
tickets.
It's hard to get,
it's hard to get tickets.
It's even hard to get a parking pass.
But this is my point.
Like why would they want to limit this
thing?
Like who,
who is like a bit coin thing.
Like you're arbitrarily limiting the
amount of bitcoin or deciding there's
only a certain number and they're doing
this with humans are just saying,
well I can't really go over 70,000
is just,
it's not going to work.
But what if they did?
What if they just opened up the
floodgates and said,
anybody who wants to come to burning man
and,
and get get fucking crazy.
Just come on down.
How many things,
how many things would come?
Um,
half million pool boy.
But it would be chaos,
right?
Cause it would like who supplies the
porter potties and the emergency medical
services and the therapists for people
having bad trips.
Mm.
Um,
like you need some infrastructure and
then,
you know,
Nevada state police have to kind of make
sure there's not like murderers and
stuff,
but do they come around?
Oh yeah.
The wander around.
They police how fast you drive and they
must be so annoyed.
Like what did they have been dealing
with up until Bernie man fucking
nothing.
No,
just a little bit of mass hearing.
Their cow got loose.
Someone blew up a trailer
cause they got their mixture wrong.
But yeah,
it's,
it's fascinating in terms of,
um,
how quickly it went from not being a
thing at all to being its own subculture
with its own mooch.
They'll moral norms and dress styles and
systems of virtue signaling and um,
yeah,
sort of political expectations about
what beliefs are the right ones to have,
even though it didn't start out
political at all.
Well,
whenever you get freaky you go left
wing.
Like if you get freedom and freaky and
drugs,
it's left wing period.
Right?
I mean there's no real,
I mean unless it's some eyes wide shut
type shit.
We were wearing masks and everybody's
got a
right.
Yeah.
You don't typically hear people like,
well I went to burning man,
I dropped acid and,
and I realized like Mormon monogamy has
really the proper way to live.
Yeah.
They're nice people though.
They might be right.
Yeah.
Mormons are the nicest called of all
time there.
They are.
Some of the nicest folks.
I know.
If I had to say if like there's one
religion or I had to say like what are,
what are the,
what are your expectations of
friendliness and niceness?
Like wait,
where's,
where's the highest expectation?
For me,
it's Mormons.
That's one religion.
Like I think it's nonsense.
I think Joseph Smith was a little con
man,
1820 when he found golden tablets that
contain the loss work of Jesus and only
he could read him cause you had a magic
rock and all that crazy shit.
It is absolutely ridiculous.
But the end result is a bunch of really
nice folks.
Like they have a wonderful community.
They're really nice to each other.
Once they got rid of all that polygamy
shit,
you know,
once they got rid of the 90 wives and
dressing up like a pilgrim,
they,
they became like a really nice community
of people.
They're like generally really friendly.
So my Granddad,
who was a business school professor,
um,
back in the forties,
he moved his,
his little family to Salt Lake City and
they live there for a while and he was
really inspired by the kind of family
values.
And I think that was one reason he sort
of went on to have 12 kids of his own.
And not that he turned mormon,
but he thought they're onto something in
terms of how seriously they take,
um,
the future,
both on earth and in the afterlife.
They believe in the afterlife,
don't they get a plan and have their own
when they die?
Right.
Well,
this is something I loved about the TV
series,
the expanse.
I don't know if you've seen it.
We keep hearing about it and I haven't
gotten into it yet.
It's just too many damn shows.
They're awesome to watch these days.
But as soon as I'm done with Ozark,
I'm gonna jump in.
What I loved about it is it's maybe a
couple of hundred years in the future.
And so we've colonized Mars and the
asteroid belt and there's one group of
people who are building the first ship
to
the distant star system and who's doing
it?
The Mormons of course.
And I thought,
of course,
of course it's going to be a religion
that has a farsighted approach and
that's kind of pro natalist and that's
all about family values and like
increasing their numbers and,
and yeah,
of course it's going to be that.
I'm not
okay.
What's the social justice warriors
putting together and star ship?
Yeah.
Did you ever see the um,
um,
the Osman family photograph from one of
their albums,
the early albums where they all got
their own planet because they think that
when you die you get your own planet.
And so the album was based on that
concept and like if you open up the
album,
it's like,
Oh,
here's a fun planet.
Donnie.
Look,
Murray's got her own little asteroid
belt.
Yeah.
Third,
they're totally locked and loaded to do
the uh,
the interstellar colonization.
It's strange though.
I mean it's true.
It's strange the blinders that people go
on that people put on and that they
would put those blinders on.
Like it's almost like if you just can
go,
hey look,
let's just all admit Joseph Smith was
full of shit,
but we got a good thing going on here
folks.
We're all real nice to each other and
that seems to be some real positive
energy involved and believing in this
higher power and this greater good and
this overwhelming sense of community
that we all have.
And they have a sense of humor about it,
like the way they reacted to the South
Park guys doing book of Mormon.
It's fantastic.
It's like fair enough.
They took that Hillary page ad in the
playbook.
I mean that,
that and that is a brutal musical in
terms of like the way they're depicted
buffoons believing in nonsense,
trying to recruit these indigenous
people.
It's kind of,
I mean it's ruthless and hilarious at
the same time and they're like,
wonderful.
If you want to find out more about being
a mormon here,
come,
come to our website.
Come check it out.
Thank you.
I think having that humility and that
sense of humor about what you're doing,
I wish we saw more of that in like
academia because there's a lot of fields
that are very bad and don't do good
work,
but that are terribly,
terribly serious about it.
Like what gender studies or dare you,
social psychology,
gender studies.
I posted something on instagram
yesterday.
Um,
I was at a bookstore and there is a
feminist baby.
A book says feminist baby finds her
voice and it's a baby screaming into a
bull horn.
Look at this picture,
baby screaming into a bull horn and,
and I said that the lines between parody
and reality have never been blurrier and
some people laugh,
but a lot of people call me a piece of
shit and I
is one of the rare times I dove into the
comments just to take a little look,
see into the gates of hell,
but look,
that's fucking parody folks.
Why is the baby screaming into a bull
horn?
What voice does she have?
Did what?
What oppression is she rallying against
at three months old?
Is she screaming about the patriarchy
when she can't even fucking talk yet and
he hears more parody?
Why she fat and ugly?
What kind of baby is that?
Baby looks like a thumb.
She doesn't even have a chin.
This is chaos.
It's not even a real baby.
It's like an m and m with legs.
It's crazy.
Look,
she got fucked up hair and they've
already gendered her.
They put a bow on her,
which is really fucked up to do to a
baby.
You've decided that she's a girl.
How dare you?
You piece of shit.
You transphobic asshole
and the [inaudible] is a little bit
over.
Yeah,
she's got horror makeup on.
She dressed up like a fuck clown already
as a baby.
Fucked up hair.
Child abuse,
big nutty eyes.
It's crazy.
Finds her voice.
She found her voice.
Fantastic.
She can't talk yet.
That's a baby.
What we should all listen to the baby.
Give the baby a bull horn.
Let's all gather round.
I got poop.
What does the baby,
what is it baby saying?
She finds her voice.
Look,
it's parody even at the book is
wonderful.
I don't know that it's not.
Maybe it's a great book.
Maybe it's fun.
Maybe it's a silly book that's parody
that fuck.
That would be a goddamn character on
south park.
A baby feminist with a bow that screams
at the top of her lungs.
What does this free the nipple.
Hmm.
Oh,
like right now I'm hungry.
I get it.
Yeah.
Oh,
is that from the book?
That's from the book.
I guess feminist baby,
maybe it's a great book.
I think it's satire,
but it's what I do.
I mean,
here's the thing,
like if you're in a field where you
can't tell whether something is from it
or it's city Oracle,
right,
then you need to lighten up about your
field.
Yes.
And just gender studies in particular.
Well yeah,
in particular,
but um,
but what is it about it that leans
itself towards foolishness?
I think it's very hard to do good work
in a field where you have to everyday
systematically denying common sense and,
and deny the evidence of your own eyes
and ears about what's right in front of
you.
Like how sex differences work.
I think that creates a habit of
interacting with the world in a way that
says what I study is going to beat
completely divorced from every aspect of
day to day life and everybody else I
encounter who's not in my field.
Because if,
if you allow any crosstalk between like,
yeah,
you're sort of blank slate,
gender ideology and the real world,
the ideology crumbles so you can,
you can only maintain it behind this
wall of,
of insulation and that's a terrible
position to be in.
I don't envy the people who,
who live their lives that way.
It all grows inside the walled gardens
of academia and outside of that it's
these,
you know,
you get Internet groups from people that
sort of were indoctrinated into these
ideas in,
in college or,
and it's also,
I think in some ways there's a,
a leveling of the playing field that a
lot of these ideologies present some
people where they,
they go,
no,
you're not a freak.
You're okay.
You know this,
there was some silly article on fat
acceptance the other day and it was
talking and they,
then they got proposed,
which is fine.
I accept people who drink except I've
except all kinds of unhealthy choices.
But let's don't lie to me,
just
don't lie about the physical reality of
what you've done to your body.
If you reach 400 pounds,
that's not,
that's not healthy.
You're saying it's healthy.
You're saying it's okay.
No,
you're just not dead yet.
If you lost 200 pounds,
you would feel wonderful.
That would be healthier.
Like if you smoke every day and you're
like,
look,
no,
cancer smoking is healthy.
No,
no,
you're just,
your body is dealing with it.
Your body's processing it.
It won't be able to forever.
That is exactly what's going on.
If you're morbidly obese and for you to
pretend any differently and to just go
on about this fat acceptance movement
and you know,
the big beautiful this and that and
like,
no,
you're obese.
You've eaten too much food.
If you see a fat guy,
how come he doesn't get the same sort of
treatment?
If you see a morbidly obese man in his
underwear,
no one's saying he's beautiful because
he's disgusting and he's fat and he's
lazy and he's,
he's addicted to food.
We all know it.
But if it's a woman,
we're so inclined to like acts such as
the care.
Let her go.
She's fine,
you're wonderful,
you're beautiful,
you're amazing.
Like kid give her her space,
we treat them as if they're incapable of
recognizing the absolute reality of
their physical being.
I think it's important,
you know,
to address both the kind of individual
choice level and also the kind of
systemic level like the food industry
and what is being promoted and what the
federal government promoted for ages.
And,
um,
it was this terrible situation where you
could have followed exactly what the FDA
recommended and it would have been bad
for you for decades.
And because of lobbying and because of
the powers that be and an influence.
And I think that's the level to
criticize,
right?
If you have a systemic problem like
promotion of tobacco products and you
want to say for alternative,
um,
then yeah,
you got to address the tobacco industry.
We have this bizarre situation for
example,
um,
where like a lot of people in my
department work on alcoholism treatment
research.
How do you get people to drink less or
they work on how do you get people to
stop taking opiates?
How do you deal with opiate addiction?
And if you make a suggestion like,
oh,
here's some awesome new research showing
that if people switch from opiates to
cannabis,
it like dramatically lowers the risk of
death.
Or if they switch from alcohol to
cannabis,
it,
it has all these health benefits
relatively to like being an alcoholic,
but it's kind of considered to bu to
raise that and a lot of medicine and
psychology and so forth.
Well it's like,
oh,
you're,
you're giving into people being self
indulgent.
If you say,
they said they should switch from one
thing to another in a kind of harm
reduction mode,
almost like Methadone type solution.
Yeah.
And a lot of them come out of a kind of
12 step program mentality where it's
like you have a disease.
If you ever do anything that is bad for
you,
then you've relapsed and that's feeding
your disease.
I think that's idiotic.
And that's not the evidence shows,
that's not the way to treat any of these
physical addictions.
But,
um,
something like cannabis as an
alternative is it's totally marginalized
in academia.
Like you really can't talk about it as a
valid alternative where people could
come home and they can drink or they
could come home and they could get high
and maybe getting high for a lot of
people might be better.
It's is that changing though?
I haven't seen any evidence that it's
changing,
at least within academia really.
I would think that that would be one of
the first places where it does change
because the influence of the
pharmaceutical industry isn't so deeply
entwined in the system itself.
It's not like pharmaceutical industry.
People are dropping off pamphlets on
talking points when you're giving
lectures.
Well,
here's the problem.
Who gives you the research funding to
look into this?
Right?
National Institute of Alcohol and
alcoholism or National Institute of Drug
Abuse.
If you do a grant proposal that says
here's an alternative that might work,
they will shut it down because the
federal government does not.
Those agencies don't want to blow back
of some senators saying,
how dare you fund this research that
says this is a valid alternative.
Yeah.
So everyone who works in these areas is
kind of locked into a system
of,
of grant funding that subject to kind
um,
political censorship by the funding
agencies.
Do you remember those?
A talking dog commercials of about 10
years ago where there was a girl,
she comes home from school and the dog's
like,
Lindsey really wish you wouldn't smoke
putt.
He not the same when you do.
And I miss my friend and the girl
sitting there stoned out of her mind,
her dogs talking to her dog runs away.
It turns out that the organization that
funded those commercials was funded by
tobacco,
alcohol and pharmaceutical companies.
Yeah.
Like they're drug dealers who are
against drugs.
It's literally like hookers doing a
commercial against strippers.
That's literally what it's like.
And we just accepted this and it was all
over television.
It was everywhere you look,
it became parody and he became
preposterous.
It was like,
this is your brain on drugs.
You remember the eggs and everybody's
like,
I'm hungry.
I mean a meat million comedians had
jokes on that.
Give me the Munchies,
man,
this is just insanity that this is
allowed to take place is that drugs that
kill enormous numbers of people are
allowed to demonize drugs that kill no
one ever in the history of use.
If you looked at that rationally,
if you were something from some other
planet that was studying the human race
and you saw the way we program people
and the way we spend enormous sums of
money to project a certain idea and get
it into people's heads through these
very influential short,
memorable videos,
you'd be like,
this is a culture and a civilization.
Uh,
uh,
an org,
an organism that is matt.
This is madness.
Yeah.
I often asked myself,
how is this going to look in 50 or a
hundred years to whatever my,
my great grandkids or future people who
stumble upon my books or this podcast or
whatever.
And I think if this would make zero
sense and would it be totally
embarrassing both intellectually and
ethically,
then don't take it seriously and this
particular issue,
I think it's really important for
citizens to understand how much of
science is constrained by what can be
funded by the federal government and
that we are not actually supported to do
certain kinds of research that might be
really helpful to people.
It's the same thing with sex research,
right?
It is virtually impossible to get
federal funding to do any kind of sex
research in America these days.
So what do you do?
You write a grant to do something else
and then you kind of do this x research
on the side using like some of the
resources.
Um,
I don't do this,
but everybody I know does sex research
does it,
is it because they're concerned that the
image of funding sex research versus
funding,
whether it's obesity or hunger,
poverty,
whatever it is,
these are,
there's not enough resources to go
around.
Why would you spend any money studying
this?
You must be
pervert.
It's partly that,
but it's,
it's partly,
you know,
the individuals in Washington who
administer these grants don't want the
political flack.
If some politician discovers,
oh,
you're,
you're doing funding on,
on like how women can have more orgasms.
Outrageous.
Right.
And it's like,
that sounds like one of the most cost
effective ways to increase human
happiness I've ever heard of.
Right.
But people are embarrassed of or glare
embarrassed about it.
Embarrassing of all sex.
Yeah.
Um,
marital therapy,
research you can do,
like if you want to research,
how do you make a monogamous
relationship less full of stress and
argument,
you can get some money to do that.
But even there,
like the kind of suggestions you could
make are quite restricted in terms of
what,
what kind of therapy you're allowed to,
to research or talk about.
So I,
yeah,
I wish citizens understood this because
their tax dollars are not being
allocated in the best way to deliver the
benefits in their real lives to their
families and their relationships that
they,
that they could do.
So to bring it all back to obesity.
What,
what I would like,
and I bet I could say the same about
you,
is we'd like to take some of these sort
of influential videos that we've seen
done that demonize innocuous drugs like
marijuana and put those on sugar.
Put those on how upbeat people are
addicted to sugar.
People are addicted to so many things
that are causing obesity.
So many things that are causing us to
have this epidemic of,
you know what I mean?
If you go to Disneyland,
it's one of the saddest things in the
world.
You see how many people are on scooters
because they've eaten themselves out of
their ability to be mobile on their own.
They're just overflowing out of the,
off the side of these scooters.
It's,
it's very depressing and then you see
them,
what they're eating,
they're drinking slushies and you know,
eating fucking nonsense.
And this,
this is a,
and again it's another addiction and in
the availability of it is so,
I mean,
imagine if you were a heroin addict and
everywhere you went has heroin.
That's what it's like to be a sugar
addict.
If you're a sugar addict,
every store you go into is filled with
your drug every
seven 11 right when you go to pay for
your gas or whatever you're doing,
it's filled with your drug right there
in front of you,
your drugs everywhere.
And you know,
if,
if you want to do something alternative,
like I've been involved in the Paleo
Movement for a few years and like my
girlfriend's Vegan and if you want to
find good Paleo or Vegan food,
it's like getting a little easier.
But it's not mainstream enough that
there's like a whole island walmart
devoted to it and this is a shitty I'll,
yeah,
so I don't know,
the,
the food system is a pretty hard nut to
crack because there's an awful lot of
money at stake and the profit margins on
junk food are very,
very high and it's also,
it's very difficult to keep things on
the shelf.
Things go,
I mean if you have real fresh food,
it goes bad very quickly.
It's natural.
That's what it's supposed to do.
And Good luck keeping a supermarket
open.
If you could only keep your vegetables
for a couple of days.
Now if there was like long life Kale,
I'd be pretty sad about that.
But that would be sad.
Like some sort of artificial turf type
Kale and stuff goes bad quick,
you know,
it gets funky.
Yeah.
Um,
but I,
I'm kind of excited about new
developments like clean meat,
lunch meat.
I am too,
because I think like ethically that'll
be awesome and we'll see what kind of
monsters they make out of that.
Yeah.
It's going to be strange to see headless
meat slabs,
no central nervous system.
Just grow and,
and trying to figure out how do they get
it to have like a muscle consistency,
like a philemon yawn or something.
I mean,
you gotta realize an animal like
different cuts of meat have a different
texture to them because there's
different muscle density because the
animals use their body.
I think you'll have to electrically
stimulate the muscles issue.
So it kind of has to twitch and it's
weird,
but,
and people go,
Oh God,
what did have nerves?
That's disgusting.
People would make the argument then that
it could feel somehow or another in some
neighboring dimension.
It'll have like fake fake nerves.
What I'm excited about is you could
potentially have meat that's not just
from like the top three species.
You know,
we could eat meat from people's pigs and
chicken.
Well,
you can eat people,
Jeffrey.
Well,
one of my edgier tweets was like
celebrities will start selling pieces of
themselves that can turn into like a
Ryan gosling stake.
If you don't want,
encourage that bro.
Trust me,
Brian,
don't go down that road.
You're too delicious.
Yeah,
man.
I don't know about all that.
I don't think we should encourage
because what if people are delicious?
That could be a real problem.
I think the lab grown people always be
cheaper than like,
I don't know about that.
Yeah,
I bet.
Could buy someone real cheap and some
sort of third world country.
Yeah.
For food.
You know,
there was a terrible,
not terrible in a bad way,
but in terms of its revelations a,
there's a documentary piece from vice on
Liberia.
And one of the things about it was that
they were selling human meat and that,
uh,
this guy recognized it because he had
eaten humans before.
And so when there was a stand that was
selling meat on the side of the road and
he turned them in for selling human meat
and the reason why he knew his cause he
had eaten people.
I'm like,
okay,
when's the next flight out of here?
What the Fuck Cube?
Imagine.
I mean,
if you gave me a piece of lamb and he
didn't tell me what it was,
I'd be like,
hmm.
Not sure.
Do you,
how many people you have to eat before
you absolutely know that somethings
people like,
fuck man,
I had a lot of lamp chops,
would not bet 100% on my ability to
distinguished a lamb chop from say of a
veal chop or a venison chop.
But all of this stuff is going to create
some real moral quandaries.
Like there'll be this,
uh,
what Jonathan Haidt calls moral
dumbfounding where you go,
Yuck.
That is disgusting.
Why?
I Dunno.
It just is.
Yeah.
I can't give you a reason.
Well,
robot brothels,
this is one of the more recent
discussions,
the ethical implications of robot
brothels and there's a robot brothel
that's scheduled to be open.
Where is that in Germany.
Is that where it does?
I believe,
I believe it is.
And there's all these people were up.
Where's this Texas Holla powerful Texas,
Texas.
Dex Is,
you could probably fuck a tiger if
you've got enough money.
Countries,
first robot sex brothel set to open in
Texas prompts backlash.
See,
I wonder if that's real or one of they
just like a hey put out a fucking press
conference to tell them we're going to
open up a robot brothel.
Let's let them go crazy.
Is Ron White?
He did it.
Ron.
When Ron White from his,
from his off from the desk of Rod White
it Austin,
Texas.
He said this email,
60 bucks for a half hour.
Oh,
that's cheap.
How long does it take to get off with a
robot?
What did you lose your concentration set
locations by 2020 is there a snooze
button?
2020 so 18 months.
Yeah,
but see what you don't want to show up
late.
Right?
You don't want to be there at the end of
the day.
A bunch of unmotivated people cleaning
out those fuck holes.
Oh well of this was actually at the
forefront of the lap dance club
revolution in the late 80 [inaudible]
the revolution there was a revolution.
Well,
yeah,
from from old stripper style clubs.
The lap dance where they actually
touched you in.
That actually started in the,
in Texas.
So either this is a show room where
customers can test and rent dolls before
deciding to purchase one.
Ooh.
He imagine,
you know how like,
uh,
they have certain cars that had been,
you know,
on the lot for a while and like,
are you thinking about buying an m for
Mike Cologne?
Take the
sucker for a spin.
Well,
y'all should read the essay.
My girlfriend Diana Fleischmann wrote
about sex bots,
which got her a little bit of notoriety
a few months ago.
What was her take on?
It?
Did it would be really good on balance
because there's a lot of guys who,
um,
need,
like a sexual release and if it kind of
takes them away from doing some like
exploiter to bill cosby style behavior
into just doing something like this,
which is kind of weird and gross but
innocuous,
like it's not hurting anybody,
um,
that,
that would be a net win.
Do you make that connection because
that,
that's a,
that's a tricky connection,
right?
Because most people who think of rape,
they don't think of it as an act of
arousal or sex or intimacy rather.
It's a thing of power at some sort of a
creepy,
sociopathic,
psychopathic behavior trait.
I know that's a standard view in gender
feminism,
but I don't think it's well supported by
the evidence.
Um,
for example,
there's a big problem with rape in
India,
right?
And Porn as far as I understand,
is illegal in India now accessible
though?
Or is it that you don't,
I don't think it's even like,
I think it's pretty hard to access porn
websites from India,
but I think if you legalized porn there,
I predict the rate of sexual abuse would
drop.
Willing.
Yeah,
I really do.
Boy,
that would be a weird sort of
experiment.
But the thing about robots and sex is
they're going to get so good that it's
going to be like a person and then we're
going to be in this weird x Mokena sort
of situation where,
um,
how would you feel?
Like,
what if you were dancing around with
that really hot Japanese girl,
an x Mokena she starts taking off your
clothes.
Like what do we do here?
Like she feels warm.
She's beautiful.
She smells good like this.
My,
all my senses are telling me this is a
person and she's a good listener.
Yeah,
she's pretty,
she doesn't Nag you.
She doesn't give a whole Nag.
You owe you man.
He man's planning.
No,
not yet.
That's my favorite.
If you're correct and you have a penis,
you're a mansplainer.
Gotta be real careful about your
information,
the way you distribute it to two ladies
these days.
It used to be close to words being
patronizing and you've got this to do it
well.
It also could be called being correct.
Yeah.
If sometimes you correct it just
happened to be [inaudible] explaining
true things as a crime.
Well,
when it comes to gender studies,
we circle back to this,
this,
um,
denial of reality.
And we know that there's,
there's this sort of really broad
spectrum of sexuality in terms of male,
female,
in terms of,
you know,
in terms of the,
the obvious,
you know,
the rock on one side and Kate Upton on
the other,
right.
You know,
these Super Uber female,
Uber,
males.
And then there's all these,
like,
who's the guy who was in the hobbit
illogical?
It's that guy he started in this sort of
weird space in between the two of those
people,
right?
And draw in this hobby.
Well,
he's not really androgynous,
but in terms of like,
you compare him to,
you know,
fill in the blank,
Herschel Walker,
it's not that manly,
you know?
And then there's,
there's women that don't feel
represented by these standard views of
female sexuality as well.
But this just speak to the variability
of the human genome and it just,
it just DNA in general.
There's different people that breed with
different people in different shapes
come out until we figured out how to
manipulate those shapes,
which seems to be right around the
corner with the robot fuck dolls.
It seems like they're both gonna arrive
probably at the same time where you're
going to be able to choose from,
you know,
having sex with a robot or having sex
with the hulk.
Like there's going to be real
possibilities that everyone's going to
look like thor.
I mean,
this seems like this is not too far
away.
One,
two,
three generations maybe,
possibly inside of our lifetime will
have mastered the human form to the
point where the world's going to be
preposterous and it's going to be like
the Star Wars Cantina scene everywhere
you go,
oh yeah,
well this is what happens whenever you
have a biological innovation that opens
up new possibilities in terms of the
evolution of bodies or behaviors.
As you get this adaptive radiation,
this explosion of possibilities like the
Cambrian explosion,
right?
530 million years ago,
animals finally figured out how do you
program a multicellular body with a
nervous system and as soon as they got
that boom,
you've got all this,
these bizarre new forms,
and then you get,
you know,
dinosaurs and mammals in us.
I think once we can program the human
genome and you have parents who are
like,
I want,
I want to select for kids who were like
really tall and really religious,
right?
And other parents are like,
I want cute little hobbit babies who are
like hardcore atheist with furry feet
and then you'll,
you'll get a divergence.
Imagine if your parents decided to make
you a Hobbit,
like they could have done anything they
want.
Remember like the first early adopters,
I imagine it's going to be about fetal
transformation,
about taking something that's in the
womb and manipulating it,
and then as it emerges and evolves and
grows,
then you're gonna see what it is.
If you fucking parents were just
gigantic Jrr tolkien fans and you have
heard furry feet and two feet tall,
you're like,
what the fuck mom?
Like you asshole.
I just wanted a hobbit.
I did want to pay me like who's either a
hobbit or a cave troll,
so you should call your boss.
Yeah,
that's entirely possible.
I think the,
I think the sex bots will come a lot
quicker.
Yeah.
I think we're going away.
What do we look like?
What do we look like right now in terms
of sex bots?
What are we looking at?
Let's say state of the art type?
Google state of the art sex robot
started talking to and see what they
have there in Texas.
I think they look pretty good,
but they're not.
They're not good at.
We're good at like language or
conversation with eye contact or
handjobs movement or whatever,
but I think there will be this tipping
point where they can do conversation.
That's good enough.
Right.
It doesn't have to be quite as smart as
an actual lover,
but it can be a hell of a lot nicer than
an actual lover.
It can have better memory for all your
preferences and your desires and your
and like it will also be more trainable
in terms of it'll kind of register.
Oh the last time I asked this question
like you didn't respond much,
but this other question you talked for
five minutes.
I'll ask more of that.
Mm.
Right.
This is all very problematic behavior
discussing here Jeffrey.
Well like your tone,
trainable.
Well my girlfriends,
sometimes people are nice when you're
nice to them.
Jeffrey,
how about you?
Be Nice.
First set of expecting this fucking
robot to just take care of your Dick and
balls and just be nice to you all the
time and remember all the stuff you
like.
What about it?
He would develop into total narcissist,
sociopath with robots that we could just
get to do whatever we want.
We bring them to the mall on a leash.
Well,
so there are two different ways I could
go.
Right,
right.
On the one hand,
like if there's a woman I'm interested
in let's say,
and she has access to a male sex bot
who's like really funny cause it's like
it's a little neural network has learned
like all of your standup routines or um,
how to,
how to riff on today's news and,
and it's a great listener and it
remembers everything about her
backstory.
I can either be like,
I can't compete with that.
I'll have to dis it.
I'll have to say you're not allowed to
see him anymore or all have to level up
and be better.
Yes.
Well like,
like humans and I,
I hope people will level up and I'm well
yeah.
And we'll get to see,
we'll learn from the people don't level
up like how they fall apart.
I present you with an even more
disturbing scenario.
Okay.
Some people will be like,
you know that Jeffrey Miller is a
handsome guy.
I like to fuck them all the time and
they gonna make a version of you and
bring it around the mall with a leash on
and you're going to be going to the
apple store and a version of you.
It was going to be kicked and come with
a dog collar on standing right next to
you
while you're buying a new Mac book.
And you're like,
what the fuck?
And it's going to be totally legit cause
you don't look at,
Oh whoa.
That's what it looked like.
Swappable face.
Let me see what it looks like though.
This is just,
this is,
this is like when you're looking at one
of them digital renderings of a house
they haven't built yet.
Let's see what we got here.
Pouch.
Are they warm?
Whoa.
The all these closeups or creeped me
out.
Come on.
Get Ai.
It's Howard Stern.
Hey,
leave this.
Oh that's creepy.
They haven't passed the uncanny valley.
Clearly that,
yeah,
it was hairy chest.
What the fuck?
Oh,
it's a guy.
Robot video.
A long video.
Yeah.
I mean people will do like celebrity,
deep fake sex bots on,
there will be people wandering around
with their Jordan Peterson Sax bought on
a leash and the store will have you seen
the porn where they do face swaps.
That's,
that's getting really good.
They're really good at that.
Now this is another social revolution
we're going to have to brace for as an
Arrow when you can do a credible porn
fake of any celebrity or any citizen.
Yeah,
just based on like sampling their
facebook photos or do you know who kyle
done again is hilarious.
Standup comedian who has the funniest
instagram page of all time and his
instagram page is about 80% of him doing
face swap videos of the Kardashians and
president trump and Kanye west and with
it just so fucking ridiculous because
you know that they're fake because it's
real obvious that they fake,
but it's essentially like a new art
form.
If you think of like sketch comedy and
here play one forum,
see what we got here.
This is a good one.
Yeah.
Big Job.
What I do know when I was at your tiny
White House,
I put a recorder in the chat.
Yeah,
yeah,
she'd be,
yeah.
Holy Shit.
Another day.
Yeah,
the bathroom,
the House we had,
oh by God,
she's got the weirdest ass,
but also sorta terrific.
Esoteric a been a spell speller.
Chair.
Hello.
Some information here.
Okay.
She had a bell a little bit about an
hour and a half ago.
That's what we had tech,
but totally datcher that she's on her
period.
Light flow day,
maybe day three.
God,
yeah.
Yeah.
That dead chicken by buddy lilly.
He's realistic though.
Died.
We just tried to open up this shit.
Paid bottle.
Just celebrate by retruded coby.
So this kind of stuff,
but see what I love about this is it's
so obvious.
You know,
it's,
this is essentially,
I mean most he has them out of the
little sketches that he does on his
instagram page,
but most of his stuff is this face
thing,
which is,
I mean,
relatively new technology.
When one was face swap invented less
than a decade ago or so on your phone.
Yeah,
that good.
Pretty soon,
just a few years,
and it's become this new form of comedy,
of sketch comedy,
you know,
and and with a guy like him,
he was such a good impressionist,
you know,
but this is crude and obvious and how
long is it going to be before someone
can actually,
I mean they already have that machine
that a lot of the technology that allows
you to take,
especially someone like me who's talked
for countless hours,
you take your voice,
you take all of the recordings that I've
ever done,
this more than a thousand podcasts.
You throw them into this machine and you
basically have all my various
inflections,
anger,
sadness,
laughter or giddiness,
perplexed,
all the different words that I have in
my vernacular,
and you put them all into this thing and
you can kind of morph it around.
It's photoshop for voice,
so you have the video where you can face
swap and manipulate people's images and
it's getting better and federal at the
time.
Then you have photoshop for voice.
You can essentially make movies with
people where they just do whatever you
want them to do.
Yeah.
It'll be pretty soon,
totally impossible to tell a fake audio
recording from real and yeah.
And then fake video from real.
And what do we do then?
It means we can't really trust digital
records of people in the same way.
Um,
it also means you can,
I don't know,
it might be good.
I mean,
it means you can digitally sample
anybody who's a good communicator and
they can do an unlimited number of,
I mean,
you could have David Attenborough,
you know,
natural history videos forever,
even after he's dead.
Right.
But he could also be doing Nazi
propaganda videos as well.
Yeah.
That's what's really weird.
You could essentially,
it would be up to the user.
Yeah.
So someone like kyle done again,
but an evil version could take David
attenborough and,
you know,
yeah.
You can do whatever you want.
Well,
almost like what we're saying about
communication that you,
this open floodgate of communication.
We're learning how to manage all the
implications of this.
It's really recent.
Yeah.
And I think with,
um,
human relationships,
you know,
we'll have to figure out kind of
ethically
once,
let's say once somebody can make like a
deep fake video porn of their ex lover.
Right.
And then the wife wife catches them
watching it.
Right.
Okay.
Or,
um,
you know,
the wife buys a sex Bot and it's like
keeps it at work.
Okay.
Like
she didn't come home from work
exhausted,
all busted
up and like,
I just want to watch ozark.
I don't want to hear anyone talk to you.
One of her shoes broken fucking
happened.
Yeah.
Is that cheating?
Some people think that,
I mean,
some people think looking at porn is
cheating.
There's that argument.
I mean there's,
people have standards vary varying
levels of standards
and they don't negotiate it.
They don't talk about it.
This is something my friend David Ley
points out in his book,
um,
ethical porn for decks,
which is about responsible porn
viewership for men.
Hmm.
That,
like if you're in a relationship with a
woman and you're a straight guy,
you need to have the talk about what is
your girlfriend.
Consider cheating in terms of porn
watching.
Most guys don't have the guts to have
that conversation.
Most women don't either.
And then
there is it the guts or you don't want
to open up that door.
It just keep it on the sneak tip.
She can't complain and then no one knows
nothing.
And then we're all good.
Everybody finds out yes and mile and you
go to the movies and y'all hold hands
Jeffrey and everything's fine and he
keeps push the secrets to the grave.
Shut down into the why you're watching
that Romcom you think of someone with a
ball gag tied up in a basement covered
in baby oil,
right?
Yeah.
Some people into a happy place.
I'll have to go there.
You got to go there all day sometimes.
Yeah.
So the people have to talk about this
stuff like that,
like grownups.
And as the technology keeps advancing,
right and becomes more and more,
you know,
the line between like
porn and real life gets fuzzier.
And fuzzier right with robots and
virtual reality is going to be very
strange.
I think that probably what's going to
happen is there's going to be some sort
of a merger between virtual reality and
robots like that would be like the,
the real ultimate brothel.
So you wouldn't be as confused by the
uncanny valley because there's so much
closer in a visual sense of replicating
that.
I'm sure you've seen like some of the
more recent video games like God of war
and a bunch of these like really high
end games.
The graphics are so intense,
especially in the um,
you know,
the little scenes that they do,
whether they're there,
have promo clips and stuff.
He looked at it like,
is this real end game video that I'm
looking at these,
this is insane.
It looks like I'm watching a movie.
Yeah.
That this in combination like some sort
of real four k age d virtual reality in
combination with a sex robot is probably
where people are going to go.
Yeah,
I think so.
Um,
and then the other question is like what
happens with that technology in terms of
education and college and how people
acquire skills and knowledge and
insight?
Um,
it's really,
really hard to imagine that people still
think in 15 years.
Okay.
Going to a physical classroom and
sitting,
you know,
listening to the average community
college like adjunct professor talking
about human sexuality or gender feminism
or political science that they'll think
that's a state of the art.
That's the way we should do that.
And,
and then what happens?
I mean it seems kind of unlikely that
university is,
as we know them,
will keep existing in anything close to
their current form.
And yet no one's talking about this.
Um,
uh,
like I wouldn't be that surprised if
half the universities in America go
bankrupt within 15,
20 years.
So do you think that people are going to
be getting their education and some sort
of an online form,
some sort of virtual classroom form or
some maybe new,
not yet created version,
some new virtual reality form that's a
lot more interactive?
I don't think it will be just watching
videos and then taking quizzes.
Have you paid attention to what Elon
Musk has been saying about as neuro
link?
A bit.
Yeah.
What do you think about what you've
heard so far?
I think it will be very,
very hard technically to do that.
Um,
but what,
what do you know about it?
Um,
if you could explain it to people that
don't know what we're talking about,
if I understand correctly,
having watched like you interview Ilan,
et Cetera.
Um,
he's just concerned that the bandwidth
that connects the brain to the world or
the brain to the Internet is quite
narrow.
Like you can get a lot of information
quickly through your eyes and ears,
but your speed of like typing and
controlling things is,
we're speaking is,
is kind of limited.
So I think there's a push to kind of
open up that that bandwidth and the
speed of communication between the human
brain and digital reality and other
people,
if they figured out a way to do that,
it's a total game changer.
Um,
in terms of how people interact with not
just social media but in general with
each other.
I mean it means basically you have a
global telepathy system if you want and
then everything changes because it means
the ease with which one part of my brain
communicates with another part isn't
that much higher than the ease with
which that part communicates with
somebody else's other brain part.
What I've been thinking about is some
sort of universal language in that if
that's,
if they bridge the gap between cultures
and civilizations and w the way people
communicate and doing so do it through
some sort of a digital interface and
instead of like very simple characters
that equal words that you put into your
linguistic disc dictionary and you have
an understanding of what this person's
talking about.
Instead of that you get like real clear
concepts,
maybe even like an Emoji form or
hieroglyphic form or some sort of form
where we figure out over x amount of
years how to communicate through agreed
upon imagery or agreed upon data in some
sort of a way that it lets people
express emotions and perhaps even more
engrossing and more complicated than the
actual language that we're enjoying
right now.
Yeah,
it'll,
it'll be amazing.
I mean the evolutionary backstory to
this,
right,
as you basically have the whole history
of life on earth,
you know,
before humans invent language where
animal communication is pretty
primitive.
Like all you really have at the most
complicated as like nightingale's
producing complicated bird song to track
mates.
That's about as much as you get.
What about like chimps that have certain
sounds for tigers and other sounds for
eagles
that have like a maximum of maybe a
dozen different sounds.
Um,
but with human language it compared to
that,
it really is suddenly like having
telepathy where you can communicate so
much,
so quickly,
so efficiently and yet,
um,
you know,
of neuro link works,
it would be as far in advance of
language as languages of kind of animal
signaling.
Whoa.
And it's hard.
It's hard to imagine what that world
looks like because
yeah.
You know,
imagine a form of twitter where it's not
just through your,
you know,
your thumbs on a key pad,
but it's a direct brain interface.
And then when people,
it's not just saying something mean or
stupid,
it's even thinking something meaner,
stupid that could immediately get
posted.
And once you kind of start sharing your
whole subconscious with people through
neurolink,
then well,
you know,
we'll have to level up with some new
social norms about what,
what that means and sort of how much
radical honesty we can take from each
other.
That seems to be where the future is.
The complete desolving of all boundaries
between people and information people
and their lives and that some sort of a,
uh,
a way of recording your actual
experiences or letting people share them
in real time.
Like imagine if people decided to let
people through some virtual reality
scenario put on headsets and experience.
You are having sex with your girlfriend.
You say,
hey,
we're going to fuck on periscope.
Come on,
join in.
And everybody just puts on their neuro
link and their augmented reality headset
and they put on their haptic feedback
suit,
which is,
you know,
now and you know,
like iphone 10 level,
you know,
you'd go back to iphone once,
piece of shit,
haptic feedback,
10,
it's going to be incredible.
It's going to be silky smooth.
It's going to feel like real touch and
they're going to be able to have sex
along with you.
You can have a digital orgy.
Yeah.
I think that's coming within 50 years.
Maybe earlier.
That's a very conservative guess.
Yeah.
100% is come up there.
There it is.
Jesus Christ.
Jamie,
there's a haptic feedback system looking
around in there.
What is this?
It?
Oh this couple sexy as fuck to take your
clothes off folks.
Why are you wearing these goofy outfits?
Pretend you superheroes.
What do you,
uh,
what are these things for?
Climate control systems,
biometric systems,
motion capture and avatar system.
Boy,
we're fucked.
Jeffrey Vr,
ar and Mr.
So this is all happening while we're
chit chatting about it,
these people have already engineered it
and society is going to be totally
blindsided by this.
Yeah,
cause everybody thinks,
oh well I saw it on Black Mirror but I
know that it's not even my like so I
don't have to worry about it and
minoration yet,
cause it's only science fiction.
Like
you said,
something on Sam Harris has show that
gave me a little bit of hope that turned
out to not be true.
Okay.
He sits up that you were talking about
asteroids about our ability to recognize
asteroids and,
and stop the impact.
Nope.
According to Neil degrasse Tyson,
we need at least 10 years.
We need to know that they're 10 years,
they're going to hit in 10 years and
then maybe we could do something that's
not comforting,
isn't it?
Well.
Okay,
here's the thing.
It would be really good to invest at
least a few tens of billions of dollars
in doing that for sure as insurance,
but like the probability of a
significant asteroid impact within the
next century is pretty low.
If I understand it correctly.
I think he's just guesswork.
Does motherfuckers just whizz by all the
time?
Yeah,
it's the probability of us getting hit
eventually is 100%
yeah,
it'll happen probably in a few million
years,
but,
but why do you say that?
Is that to make yourself feel better?
I'll be long gone.
It'll be my great quick,
quick,
quick.
Great.
Great,
great.
Great grandchildren have to worry about
that.
Well,
you got to play the odds,
right?
I mean we could,
we,
we could be exterminated by a gamma ray
burst from like a Supernova at any time
with zero with no warning.
But it's pretty unlikely.
And it hasn't happened before in the
history of life on earth.
Right.
But it happens constantly.
All throughout the universe.
There was a documentary I watched once
the freak me the fuck out.
It was all about hyper Novas and they
were talking about when they first
started discovering them that they were
really actually concerned that there was
a war going on in space.
And then they,
they recognize that all these explosions
were happening all day long and they
thought there was a war going on in the
cosmos,
which is really fascinating because I
think this is like when they just got,
I want to say it as a sixties and they
discovered this.
Does that make sense?
In a way,
it's kind of surprising that we haven't
seen evidence of that happening already.
Right.
I mean,
when,
when I wrote my piece about the Fermi
Paradox,
which is why don't we have evidence of
aliens already?
My solution was basically,
well,
most species that are intelligent,
that invent technology get wrapped up in
video games and virtual reality and sex
technology and it just distracts them
and they kind of dropped the ball on
staying alive and exploring anything.
And,
um,
I think it's still quite likely that
that happens to most intelligent species
that they just kind of disappear up
their own buttholes
yeah.
Or they create some sort of an
artificial life form that's far more
advanced than anything that it's
biological and has no desire,
need or,
uh,
no instincts to reproduce.
And if you,
if we see,
I mean,
I've,
I've said this to many times that I
think that we are essentially some sort
of a,
some sort of,
uh,
electronic caterpillar that gives birth
to a technological butterfly.
And we're making a coon right now.
We don't know what we're doing.
And we're about to create artificial
life.
And then we're doing it through our
intense desire for innovation.
Constantly want newer,
better things,
whether it's televisions and cars or
phones were never like that.
This one's perfect.
Let's just stop here.
Never.
The desire is always towards every,
you know,
fill in the time period.
We want a new version,
a better version with improvements.
And we keep getting those.
And this is what fuels in many ways,
it fuels our desire for me.
Materialism,
materialism.
IMBA is embodied by technological
innovation.
I mean what you're always wanting when
you get past jewels,
you always want the newest,
greatest innovations.
Yeah.
I think at a certain point humanity's
going to have to bite the bullet and say
we should plan which innovations come
first,
what happens next.
And we might even have to have like
regulation or social taboos that say we
really shouldn't go down that path until
we do this other thing first.
That makes us ready to do that thing in
a safer,
more rational,
more ethical.
Yeah.
But that's the big word,
right?
Rational like we're not really rational
and competition,
especially when it's a dealing with
different countries that have different
human rights laws and standards of
behavior and thinking,
well this is a problem with regulating
like artificial intelligence is how'd
you get China to play ball?
That was going to say China,
I didn't want to seem racist.
Well they're going to do it.
And Russia too.
I mean I'm already doing it.
China's a threat because they are smart
and organized and future oriented and
they can do long term planning and
technologically they're incredibly
advanced.
I mean,
so,
so far advanced.
So we're,
or this government rather it's trying to
keep the best phones from China,
from getting to America.
Yeah.
I mean Huawei probably has some pretty
close links to the Chinese millage.
It does,
right?
Yeah.
It does.
To the Chinese government.
Communist dictatorship.
Yeah.
And of course it's a lovely system if
Huawei phones how backdoors it allowed
the Chinese to learn a lot about
Americans and our culture and our
communication.
And that's the concern.
Um,
it's,
that's actually more of a concern to me
than like,
um,
military spying in the strict sense.
Cause I think China has so many people
working on cyber warfare that we
probably don't even have any idea what
their capabilities are.
But I think if they have insight into
like,
here's the American psyche and here's
how their political thinking works,
it will be quite a bit easier to kind of
manipulate,
um,
in terms of our geopolitics because we
don't have anything analogists I think,
where like,
is the Pentagon trying to figure out how
could we nudge Chinese social media use?
You don't think they know our interests.
I'd be surprised if they're doing it
well.
Well,
what's fascinating is Google's take on
China is that they're willing to censor
video or internet searches because they
feel like if they don't try to just
going to copy their technology and do it
anyway,
and so this way,
at least they're in there.
I'm like,
boy,
that's a sketchy way of sort of
absolving yourself.
Yeah.
Of any bad feelings about censorship.
You're,
you're contributing to censorship.
Government issued censorship.
Yeah,
because you want to control the market
and we're going,
oh yeah,
well,
you know,
I can't Google Tiananmen Square.
You literally can't Google Tiananmen
Square.
It seems like there's a huge difference
between China's authoritarian regime and
the American political system,
but I think they're not quite as
different as a lot of folks think.
Like if you talk to Chinese academics
about like what can you research and
what can you not research,
like they have different constraints
than Americans do.
But on at the pragmatic level,
there are certain topics that they can
address that we can't and vice versa.
So it's not like there's just one
dimension of freedom and we're better
than them on,
on every aspect of it.
And I,
again,
I think American citizens have no idea
how restricted American scientists are
and kind of what we're allowed to study.
Oh,
we're going to talk about loud too,
or what you can get grants and approval
for.
And is that the same thing as allowed to
effectively it's the same thing because
you,
if you don't have any funding,
you're not going to,
there's no study.
You can't do science without money.
Right.
Um,
and in fact,
like if I was starting my career again
at this point,
I wouldn't go into academia.
If I wanted to understand human
behavior,
I would go work for facebook or Google
because they have much more data about
human behavior than I could ever get as
a scientist.
Are they doing that?
I'm sure they're doing it,
but we don't know what they're finding
because they don't publish journal
papers.
It's all,
it's all commercial secrets.
So what I'm sure that like facebook
understands a lot more about social
psychology then social psychology does
at this point.
Really?
Yeah.
How could they not?
They have like 1.2
billion people interacting socially
regularly and they data mine to hell out
of that for commercial purposes.
Right.
But are they publishing things?
Are they sharing this information?
Don't turn it all.
I'm sure it's all internal.
But internally,
do you think they're publishing things?
Yeah,
I dunno.
That's the thing.
Yeah.
Um,
it's just a little bit alarming when
this state of the art in understanding
behavior isn't public.
That is alarming.
And then Mark Zuckerberg might be a
robot to,
right.
Everybody's worried about that might be
a Spec spot.
We've,
we played many times a video of him
drinking water.
I don't know,
Dude.
He drinks water like that creepy little
fuck.
It's a just kidding mark.
Don't delete my account.
Um,
I think that we're,
we're looking at in terms of like Google
and facebook and twitter and even
youtube,
we're looking at these enormous
organizations that I don't think they
had any idea what they were going to be.
You know?
And I,
I really particularly feel that way
about twitter.
When twitter first started out,
do you remember how it used to be like
you would use like you're at like at
Miller is enjoying a cup of coffee.
Yeah.
You,
you would talk about yourself in the
third person.
It was really weird,
you know,
uh,
at Jamie Vernon is going to the movies.
Okay.
And that's how people talked the early
days of [inaudible] and then people
realize what the fuck am I doing?
You had,
that's sort of the reason it developed
it because there was no group tech
texting back then in 2007 or six when it
started.
So it was developed for group texting so
you could share what you were doing with
a group of your friends.
Was that what it was for?
They opened it so that more people could
follow if you wanted to.
And then celebrities jumped on and then
it,
and they,
like,
they started adding the ability people
just started doing at Joe Rogan.
So they'd added the ability to,
to click that and share it and tag it.
Yeah.
So weird.
And then you think about it now,
now it's a vehicle for the president to
threaten other countries
and it is the,
it's the global public forum and
particularly in America,
it is that the public square where
everyone shares ideas and,
well,
it's a less verbose version of facebook.
The problem with facebook is you just
can write too much.
I can't keep up with you,
bro.
And I like the really,
really ridiculous people who just
paragraph after paragraph of run on
sentences with no,
no editing at all.
Like ugh.
Yeah,
it's a lot about,
here's a very long story about my most
recent emotional trauma or I dunno if
anybody ever is like having a breakup or
divorce on facebook.
You're like,
Oh man,
now I'm going to have to listen.
Stop for a few months.
Yeah.
And then they reach out hoping some
people say it's going to be okay,
mark,
everything's fine.
Life moves on.
You're going to forget about her
eventually.
It's just,
and people keep going back to who's,
who's left a comment.
Yeah,
yeah.
Maybe she liked it.
Maybe she's changed her mind,
but it,
it,
I mean it is very kind of funny and
interesting that nobody predicted 15
years ago exactly how humans would make
use of this new technology.
Yeah.
Like nobody in psychology was talking
about,
oh,
twitter is going to radically transform
the way that science operates.
For example,
news of like failed replications will be
spread within three days to everybody in
a field.
And anybody who does scientific
misconduct will be suddenly like pushed
out within a week or a new result will
be shared globally within 24 hours.
Nobody was thinking about that.
So there's like signs,
twitter,
politics,
entertainment,
twitter,
and they've all kind of changed the game
and their respective fields.
Um,
and we didn't understand human nature
well enough to predict how people
actually use the stuff.
Yeah.
We did.
Just didn't see it coming either.
Okay.
I mean,
no one ever would.
I remember when Ashton Kutcher was in
some sort of a race with someone else,
I want to say to get to a million
followers,
wasn't it like a million?
Yeah.
And everybody thought that's crazy.
He's going to have a million followers.
I don't even think he's on twitter
anymore.
He's not.
But his account is hilarious.
It's like a production company now or
something.
Yeah.
And gave it to system fucking too
dangerous.
And now what?
Katy Perry has like 120 minutes.
Yeah.
Something insane.
Probably more.
And then you've got to go to her
instagram,
which is probably even bigger than that.
It was racing CNN and Brittany Spears.
Oh Wow.
Okay.
Here's the article for a million.
Look at that twitter race to a million,
what years at 2009.
Wow.
Twitter raise to a million followers can
cut your beat.
CNN and spears.
That's hilarious.
No one even knew what it meant back
then.
So I mean with the virtual reality work
or the neuro link,
right.
We're going to have those things.
We'll probably have a beginner impact on
culture and society.
Even then twitter did.
Yeah.
And still people are kind of just
sleepwalking into that,
that world sleepwalking with a few
hesitant observers on the outside
warning,
like almost like standing back,
like watching someone play with
fireworks.
Like,
okay,
Hey,
um,
do you know what's going to happen when
you light that garbage can on fire?
It's filled with dynamite
and the legal issues or privacy issues
that the impact on relationships.
Yeah.
Um,
is okay,
so like we train a lot of PHD's in
clinical psychology in my department and
a lot of them are going to deal with
people and their relationships and their
marriages and the conflicts and
arguments and whatever.
Are we training them for a future world
where they're going to have to deal with
sex bots and virtual reality and new
forms of social media and new kinds of
basically telepathy that are foreign
advance of human language.
No or not.
But that's,
that's the world that they're going to
spend their professional lives in.
Isn't it similar in some ways?
I mean,
Jamie,
you could speak to this,
you were trained as an audio engineer
and now everything's like all the
software that was available when you
were learning is just useless now.
Honestly,
it wasn't even youtube when I went to
school.
So a lot of the,
uh,
if anyone has questions now you can
learn almost everything.
I learned in the Year of program I had
in a week if you need it to,
you just don't get the hands on
application and touched on this stuff.
But
yeah,
but people that went to school for video
editing and all the other different
systems
detailed,
detailed from anyone you want to watch
now almost because they even had like
the master class,
you could learn screenwriting from Aaron
Sorkin.
It learn directing from Hawaii.
Yeah.
Ron Howard or whatever it is.
You didn't have that 10 years ago.
Yeah.
And then in terms of financial,
I mean the,
the amount of financial strain that
getting the traditional education puts
on people and they get out of school and
they're saddled with this debt that is
also,
you can't even absolve it if you declare
bankruptcy,
which is kind of hilarious when you
think of the dirty shit that banks do
and Wall Street does and all the risks
they take and all the chaos that they
have created from their shitty decisions
that have affected the entire economy
and they're absolved.
But yet some kid who wanted to get a
gender studies degree and now as a
quarter million dollars,
some fucking halfassed Michigan
University.
I think it's unconscionable.
Yeah,
it's terrible.
I mean,
I feel really morally conflicted about
working in an industry that I think is
pretty exploitative and a lot of ways.
Yeah,
I was going to ask you about that.
Like what,
what's the stance that you take?
I mean if,
if a kid comes to you and says,
you know,
I don't know what to do here.
I mean generally the stance I take,
so in,
in a way I'm,
I'm lucky because I work at a large
state public university and tuition is
really pretty.
Do you want to say which one it is that
people at University of New Mexico,
um,
and it's great.
We serve 40,000
students and we charge very,
very little tuition money compared to
most places because it state subsidized
and if you keep up a certain grade point
average,
it's about as close to free as you can,
you can get in America.
So I don't feel like we're as
economically exploitative as if I was
like teaching at Middlebury college or
Yale or whatever.
But still,
um,
you know,
of undergrads come to me and they go,
what,
what should I learn?
What should I major in?
What classes should I take?
The only real advice I can give is like
take stuff that's going to be useful in
your life,
your personal life,
no matter what career you do.
Mm.
So you should take my human sexuality
class cause you'll probably be a sexual
being for the rest of your life and
you'll be in relationships of some sort
or another.
You should learn about,
um,
politics.
You should learn about the history of
civilization.
You should learn about animal behavior
and biology and all that stuff.
But don't expect that.
Like you can major in pharmacy and then
get a job as a pharmacist that makes a
hundred k out of the gate because that
might be automated.
Don't assume you can go to law school
and you'll make bank like your dad did.
Because a lot of that like,
um,
document discovery is being automated.
Don't assume you're going to be a
surgeon because that might be
roboticized.
So I just say you should try to get a
classical liberal arts education that,
that equips you as a citizen and as a
person and as a,
um,
an ethical being a and that's the future
proof way to do it.
And even then,
there's a distinct possibility that this
education or a superior version of it
will be available through some new
unfound or soon to be discovered form.
Yeah.
And just expect that you will,
if you stay curious throughout your
life,
you'll be able to learn about as much,
you know,
in every four to six years going forward
as you learned in this four to six years
of college.
That's right.
What's interesting is that no one really
thinks of a university education as
being something that equips you for
life,
that your,
your learning so that you can just,
you're,
you're just educating yourself and to
sort of make your mind more available
possibilities and options and
causes and effects.
And just,
just for your own edification that
that's,
this is not a consideration.
People think I need a career.
Uh,
I don't want to go to this college for
four years.
When I get out,
I want to kick ass job cause I want to
buy Alexis or whatever it is.
My favorite students,
honestly,
are the mature students.
It's the vets about a couple of tours in
Iraq or Afghanistan and come back to
college and they have life experience
and they're like here because they
really want to learn,
not because the parents think it's the
right thing to do.
Or even in my human sexuality class,
I get,
uh,
grandparents in their sixties and
seventies sometimes.
Really?
Yeah.
Grand Pan.
They're great because they've actually
had like 50 or marriages,
so they know a little something about,
wow,
you know,
psychology and it's not for their
career.
It's not for the status.
It's because they really want to be
there and they want to learn.
Well,
I would also imagine they're not as
filled with angst as an eight
18 year old first escape from the family
nest and is not understanding what to do
with their freedom and
so many distractions.
They're there just to educate,
educate themselves.
Yeah,
they're there.
They're less neurotic.
They're more confident.
Um,
they call me out on my bullshit
sometimes today.
Oh yeah.
Like,
like what bullshit.
Um,
well,
the horrifying thing now of if you're
teaching a class is you can make a
factual claim and any student can check
it on,
on while I'm talking while you're
talking.
And of course the 20 year old won't
raise their hand and go,
that's wrong.
Put the grandmas will grandma's well,
yeah.
Hilarious.
So yet you have to,
what do you even call that on?
Okay.
So there was a book back in 99 called,
uh,
I think the technology of orgasm that
made the claim that vibrators were first
invented in the Victorian era,
the late 18 hundreds to help doctors
bring their female patients to orgasm to
cure quote hysteria.
And for 20 years that was sort of
accepted as,
oh yeah,
that's a good historical analysis of
that situation.
And then that got totally debunked in
the last few months by other historians.
Look,
the last few months I've been telling
people that forever.
I know I
kai had to,
and what's the reality?
They didn't really,
doctor,
you didn't finger back.
There's no evidence at all that that was
going on.
I would think that that would be a thing
that Gal's wouldn't want to let go.
If there was a place we could go or the
doctor definitely knew how to work it.
You give you an orgasm,
there'd be a line around the block,
frustrated ladies,
you would,
you would think it would have left it
there in print.
I would not just that,
why would it stop?
Why would the doctor say,
you know what,
this business is just too goddamn
lucrative and my hands are tired.
Closing up shop.
I got carpal tunnel.
I can't even type anymore.
Yeah.
And the women are like,
yeah,
how would that go away?
So it was no evidence of who invented
that.
I can't remember the name of the author
of that.
Um,
it even got made into a movie hysteria.
Right?
The job nobody wanted.
Is that a book?
Oh yeah.
There we go about it from the New York
Times based off the book.
Or this might actually be from the book.
And what year is this?
I don't,
this might be the book.
I don't know.
Yeah,
I think that's it.
It,
so is this like sorta like that killer's
sperm theory that people still to this
day recite,
even though there's no evidence
whatsoever that's prime as any other
function other than impregnating and
egg?
Yeah.
There's a lot of kind of urban myths.
That's a big one though.
There was a whole book written about,
about different kinds of berm.
Yeah.
Sperm wars attacks Berm.
That would kill other sperm
Baker and bellis back in the early
nineties and those guys are assholes.
It was a beautiful theory,
but like nobody could replicate it and
it just didn't work.
Oh,
I thought it was a little pac man's
sperm of their attack.
Another sperm.
Right.
They called it what?
Kamikaze sperm.
Is that what they call it?
Yeah,
the sperm that allegedly were
specialized to,
yeah.
I remember someone brought that up to me
and I,
I,
uh,
I read it and I went,
oh boy,
I don't know about that.
How smaller
sperm.
So there's not a lot of room in there
for other functions.
Like how are they even getting those
other sperm and killing them?
Like,
what's,
what are they using?
They have acid,
like the alien.
What are they doing?
They rotten little ied.
Yeah.
What are they doing?
Yeah,
they have an acrosome reaction.
Like there is a tiny little warhead that
like helps her get into the egg a
warhead.
Well it's some enzymes that are pretty
good at that kind penetrating yeah.
Digesting their way in.
But yeah,
that's an example of urban myth,
um,
published urban myth published.
I mean at the time it was plausible but
it kinda got debunked fairly quickly.
So it was this sort of just a
sensational sort of an article that
someone wrote or the book that they did,
they just say,
hey,
let's just fake this in order to sell a
lot of books and get people excited
about our work.
I don't think they faked it.
I think they may,
they slightly old oversold it,
but they,
like,
they did have some proper journal paper
publications that were peer reviewed and
that made sense at the time.
And like I used to teach that stuff
cause I believe that.
Oh yeah.
How'd you teach it?
Like,
what,
what was the,
what was the conventional way of
describing this conventional story was
people think we evolved to be in
monogamous,
long term pair bonds,
but here's some evidence that humans do
extra pair copulations that they
sometimes go outside the relationship.
If that happens,
then there's occasional sperm
competition where a woman mates with
more than one guy during one ovulatory
cycle.
So that potentially ejaculates from two
different guys could be in a
reproductive track competing to
fertilize same ag.
If that happens,
the sperm would be under selection to be
good at being fast,
fighting off the other sperm,
um,
making the reproductive tract more
hostile to any guy who comes after you,
et Cetera,
et cetera.
So it was kind of like a way of
challenging the assumption of monogamous
mating and pointing out women have this
sexual freedom and agency that was not
fully recognized.
And the result is men have to compete
more,
like not just physically,
uh,
not just for status speeding and even at
this kind of biochemical level.
And it all made sense,
right?
We could have been that species,
but as it turned out,
um,
the rates of extra pair copulation or
infidelity or actually pretty low and a
lot of societies like it's not like 20%
of kids are sired by some guy other than
their dad.
It's like mostly well under two or 3%.
Right.
But we're talking about now.
Yeah.
But in,
in comparison to when all of this stuff
evolved,
we could be talking about humans of 50,
60,000
years ago.
Yeah.
Which is a totally different ballgame.
It is different.
And if,
if we'd been a species with like a lot
of sperm competition,
then our testicles would be as big as
chimp testicles.
Right.
That's what's interesting,
right.
That when it comes,
there's a direct correlation between the
number of promiscuous females in the
size of the testicles of the male.
Yeah.
Which is why girls have little tiny
dicks.
Yeah.
Cause they're just dominating.
Well I,
I wouldn't,
I wouldn't try to do some other alpha
bad idea.
I mean crazy that something grew to be
so strong,
so powerful with giant fangs and it only
eats like stalks of grass.
And Broccoli and shit.
Yeah.
So there's,
there's a lot of these little things in
psychology,
these little urban myths that get,
you know,
learn by professors and Grad school and
never really tested and then passed on.
And now that whole house of cards has
been tumbling down the last couple of
years where like almost everything that
was taught in a social psychology course
now turns out to be kind of bullshit and
not like what other examples?
Um,
the idea that you can use a implicit
association test or iat to sort of
register how sexist or racist somebody
is.
Right.
That was a big exciting thing that
social psychologist thought that they'd
discovered that you can give someone
this kind of computer test that measures
word associations and that kind of
determine like how secretly sexist are
you.
And that turned into a whole industry of
giving these tests,
everybody in corporations to sort of
assess,
you know,
are you secretly sexist and it,
and to sort of wag fingers at them and
say,
see,
you scored positive on this test,
that means you really are secretly
sexist and therefore you need training.
Mm.
Um,
and that's the industry and this is what
happened with starbucks,
right?
A few months ago when they had that
issue with the black guys and the
starbucks and starbucks didn't handle
that well,
and then there is public blow back and
starbucks went,
okay,
we're going to do implicit association
training for all of our staff
nationwide.
And all of us in psychology.
We're like,
wait,
but you,
you guys know that was all debunked like
a couple of years ago.
It's all nonsense.
No,
they're just concerned about the optics
in order to make their stock go up.
Right?
Oh yeah.
Yeah.
So it's,
it's a pr move,
but,
but it's not science based.
It's not science based on,
and anybody who's a savvy consumer will
be able to like Google this stuff and
see,
oh,
it's,
it's nonsense.
But implicit bias training is still
being used.
Right.
And so,
and it's all horse shit.
Yeah.
So what is the method like,
say if you ran a corporation and,
uh,
like,
hey everybody,
Jeffery's going to come in and teach us
how not to be racist.
You might be racist,
not even know it.
And Jeffrey's going to show you how,
I don't really know what they do in
implicit bias training.
I know that they typically will give
everybody one of these implicit
association tests that purports to show
that you have issues and you do have
hidden bias.
Like what would be like a question on
one of these tests?
It's like associations.
It's basically d are you faster to
associate this stigmatized group with
this negative word than you are to
associate them with a positive word?
And you can measure reaction time.
Oh boy.
So lever in your hand or by you're
pushing,
you're pushing,
you're seeing words flash on screens and
you're pushing buttons.
And the,
the subtle differences in reaction speed
to like the good versus the bad
associations are supposed to map like
your attitude towards the group in
question.
And it's a,
it's a reliable a fact.
The problem is it doesn't actually
predict real sexist behavior in real
life or racist behavior.
So,
so how did it get past the initial
stages to the point what was
implemented?
Um,
social psychology has just a very
politically correct,
virtually everybody in it is pretty far
left.
And if you're conservative or centrist,
you pretty quickly get driven out of it.
Really?
Oh yeah.
So Centra,
Steven,
um,
well we have pretty good data now unlike
like political affiliations of people in
different fields and in psychology it's
at least like 10 or 15 to one liberal to
conservative.
Why do you think that is?
Is that more of the indoctrination of
the walled garden of academia?
I think it's partly that,
but I think it's also like there is
pretty overt hostility to,
um,
centrist conservatives,
libertarians where you just kind of get
these signals.
Like if you start Grad school that,
um,
whatever you asked all others,
other students,
Hey,
do you want to go to the shooting range
or do you want to go hunting?
Or let's talk about politics.
And if you're on the wrong side of
what's considered normal,
then you're made to feel pretty
uncomfortable.
And you'll probably just,
you know,
leave Grad school and go,
uh,
the hell with that.
I'm going to be a lawyer,
entrepreneur.
Um,
whatever.
So just the hostility forces people out.
It's as a tribal environment.
Yeah.
What was the source of that?
I mean,
it seems like if you're going to do real
social experimental work,
if you're really going to try to
understand human behavior,
it's really gotta be done objectively to
really get the actual raw data to really
be able to do scientific work where
you're explaining things and trying to
gauge cause and effect and origins of
thought and behavior patterns.
You'd have to do it really objectively
the same way you would do mathematics.
You'd have to really look at it
cautiously and get your data points in
order and,
and,
and if you're doing real good work,
you would think that there would be more
of an inclination to do good work,
then it would be to a ps whatever tribe
you belong to too.
He would hope so.
But,
um,
take political psychology,
for example,
where the whole point is to understand
how people think about politics and
moral issues.
There's a huge liberal bias and
political psychology and you would think
they would have corrected that and said,
you know what,
it's that maybe we're missing something
by not like we have a conference of 500
people and there's not a single
libertarian here or whatever.
And they never self corrected like that.
Um,
they just assumed,
well,
we're all well intentioned and we're all
smart so we're going to be able to,
to check our own biases and they
completely failed to do that.
So you have all these measures of like
political attitudes invented by leftists
that kind of demonize conservatives or,
or centrists as basically being mentally
ill or,
or stupid or,
or whatever.
Where do you fit on the political
spectrum?
I'm kind of a centrist libertarian with
like a complicated patchwork of views.
Like I,
I'd be considered extremely far left on
certain things and pretty far right on,
on other things like what far right and
what?
Um,
I'm pro gun rights.
I'm pretty cautious about immigration,
um,
on pro economic freedom.
Um,
I don't want a big,
expensive state that has high tax
burdens and,
um,
in,
in complicated ways,
kind of profoundly values and pro
natalist and like,
I think longterm relationships are good,
not necessarily conventional ones,
but I'm pretty concerned about society
figuring out a way to make it possible
for ordinary folks to have longterm
relationships and raise families.
Isn't it fascinating that that's a right
wing thing?
Wouldn't you think that something that
would encourage families like the
universal,
it wouldn't be tribal.
I mean,
you would think that something that
would encourage longterm relationships
and monogamous pair bonding and people
getting together and working out long
term solutions to keep a family
together,
that'd be,
uh,
that'd be good for everybody you would
think.
I mean,
that seems like a left wing thing too.
So the left is very concerned about
environmental sustainability.
Right?
Right.
But they're not that concerned about
kind of what you could call the
civilizational sustainability or family
sustainability.
And I don't totally understand why,
but you tend to get the right thinking,
um,
how's this going to affect my great
grandkids or allow me to have any,
and the left is more like how's this
gonna Affect Harp seals and polar bail
bears in a hundred days and one should
sort of imply the other but
okay.
Hence being a centrist
[inaudible].
Yeah,
that's being a centrist and like
it's a weird thing like when you try to
reach a conclusion about a particular
political issue based on what you think
is think of the facts and the evidence
in the good arguments and then you do
that for each issue separately.
Right.
Rather than doing kind of tribal
affiliation signaling,
it's very,
very confusing to people because they're
like how can you be like pro cannabis
legalization if you're also pro guns or
how can you be like open to polyamory if
you're also concerned about long term
family stability or whatever.
I was like,
that's just cause of the issues I looked
into.
That's the end dies.
I ended up supporting.
Does this go back to what we were
talking about earlier,
that most people really don't have the
time to form these opinions or become
informed on these opinions and instead
they just sort of adopt a pattern of
behavior that seems to be the tribe that
they most affiliate with.
So this this way are,
there's a conglomeration of opinions.
I'm just going to accept these opinions.
Yeah,
absolutely.
It's so strange that we have to very
clear sides this left,
right?
I mean,
we even have it represented by blue and
red.
I mean this goes back to,
uh,
the Korean version of the Yin Yang,
you know,
and um,
the Korean flag,
they have that Yin Yang,
but it's instead of white and black,
it's red and blue.
I mean that,
that is what it is.
It's these,
these opposites that work together in
harmony.
It's,
well,
our society,
it's,
well,
I mean we,
it seems to be some sort of a natural
system that we gravitate towards.
Yeah.
And people police it.
It's not like everyone just sort of
chooses one side or the other and then,
and then they go,
well I guess it makes sense that if you
believe the laughed about issue a should
also believe the left about issues b c
through z.
If you deviate,
you got punished for it.
Well people use the term we to like
we've got to win the house.
I've heard that,
you know,
we've got to win the Senate.
What,
who's we?
Yeah.
Are we running bob?
Like what are we doing?
But people,
it's,
it's basically like the raiders.
We got to get to the superbowl.
I mean it is very tribal but I mean it's
weird because when,
if you're in a literal tribe,
you have your territory and your
resources and your,
your mates that you're defending and the
other tribe on the other side of the
hill has their territory resources,
mates and kids and you actually,
there is a little bit of a zero sum
conflict.
But if you're all in the same effing
country together,
yeah.
And you're all paying taxes to the same
authority and you're all partaking in
the same economy and you're all
wrestling in the same public sphere of,
of the Netflix that you watch and the
twitter we are engaged with.
It's,
it should be more positive sum than
that.
Well,
this is why I wanted to ask you this.
As an evolutionary psychologist,
does this,
and you know,
you're,
you're obviously far more aware of this
and the average person,
does this just go back to the way the
human brain developed when we were
living in small tribes and that there's
this inherent need for an us versus them
mentality that keeps us moving?
Yeah,
I think so.
Um,
you know,
the people who have thought the most
deeply about this,
like I'm a big fan of Jonathan Heights'
work and the righteous mind and the way
he kind of analyzes this stuff.
Um,
I think it will be quite hard to escape
the tribal thinking,
but we have,
we have escaped it with respect to a lot
of issues,
right?
Where we really did,
did reach a moral common ground.
Like we all kind of Said,
Oh shit,
slavery was bad.
Women should be able to vote.
MMM.
We should try to reduce the risk of
nuclear war.
Right.
So on some really big issues,
we have succeeded pretty well.
And kind of setting aside the,
the,
the tribalism,
I think the problem now is there's just
so many issues that are coming at us so
fast that we don't have time to reach
that.
Yeah.
Social equilibrium on,
on and off of them quickly enough.
Well,
this is what fascinates me by augmented
reality and things like neuro link,
something that's going to accentuate
the,
the ability and the power of the human
mind,
where we're going to be able to take
into consideration all of these things.
Um,
in a much like with Elan's term,
we'll have more bandwidth to work on
them.
Yeah.
It just,
I think the more I think about it,
I think that this just quagmire of
civilization.
There's so many different things that
were conflicted about that really.
A lot of it boils down to a lack of
time,
lack of time,
and a lack of also training in how to
think.
One of the things that's most disturbing
about education,
particularly lower education,
is that no one ever tells you how to
think.
They give you information,
but they don't tell you.
Now here's the tricks your brain is
playing on you.
Like this is why you think certain ways.
This is if you're lucky,
if you're really lucky,
someone teaches you about discipline,
they teach you about resistance and
about apathy in about about a
procrastination and all these different
games that your mind will play on you.
And just that alone will give you the
ability to work through things and get
more stuff done.
But very rarely does that even get
discussed.
So most of the time you're just getting
boring information stuffed into your
fucking face and you barely pay
attention to it enough to pass the test.
And as soon as the test is over,
you forget everything you learned.
I learned
because he really didn't learn it.
You just memorize it.
And I wouldn't take that long to learn
sort of the top dozen rationality hawks
that like the rationalist community or
the effective altruism community are
very,
very good at using and teaching.
Like just the idea of steel manning an
argument where you develop the ability
to state the strongest possible version
of your opponent's argument in a way
that they would go.
You've said that even better than I
could say.
Awesome.
That means you really understand me even
if you disagree with it.
That's a good term to steel man as
opposed to a straw man.
Yeah.
And if we just taught,
you know,
kids in high school how to do that,
um,
I think that would go long way towards
being able to have these,
these tribal dialogues.
Um,
or just that being able to think
quantitatively about political and
policy issues.
Like how many people are affected,
how are they affected,
how much would it cost to fix?
How do we know what the best way to do
it is?
Um,
rather than just diving straight for the
emotional argument.
I think that would help a lot.
But is it really in anyone's vested
interest to teach that and do the
current stock of members of the public
school teachers unions really have the
ability or interest to teach that.
Right.
It almost seems like something they're
going to have to learn online and to
augment their traditional education.
Yeah.
So ideally you'd have like a virtual
reality system where a kid could go into
it and argue about some issue like gun
rights or abortion or immigration and
some ai would sort of argue against them
or picking out their arguments or go
convince me of your position.
Right.
And somehow or another make it
interesting.
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
Make it fun.
Like they,
whatever make it,
uh,
you know,
make it,
you're arguing with rick and Morty,
right.
That is a,
one of the big issues with learning
things is making things fun,
making things somehow or another,
a enthralling and captivating something,
something that you actually want to
absorb.
And it's one of the great arguments
about video games.
And um,
one of the more interesting things about
the previous generations,
sort of a dismissal of video games,
is that the dismissal was at one point
in time,
oh,
you're just wasting your time.
And now that,
that dismissal doesn't necessarily hold
water,
because just like professional golfers,
professional video game players now make
enormous sums of money.
So it's gotten to this place where,
oh no,
this is a viable career and perhaps you
should even be taking your kid to
coaching and learning strategy and
learning all these,
you know,
various applications that allow you to
get better at these things that,
cause there's a real career in this and
mean.
Try telling that to your GRANDPA,
Hey,
I'm going to play.
Um,
what's the,
what's the game they played for the most
money today?
Fortnite.
Fortnite right?
Yes.
The big one that you're going to wait,
I want to be a professional fortnight
player.
They would say,
get the fuck Outta here.
But you know,
I'm going to be a professional golfer.
How good are you,
Johnny?
You know,
I'm an underpart,
eh?
Yeah,
I want to be the next tiger woods.
Well,
in my cohort,
a lot of other academics I've talked to
like,
Hey,
did you play Sid Meier civilization a
lot in Grad school or postdoc and yeah.
And we all go,
yeah,
most of our understanding about the
history of technology and like world
affairs and economics comes from playing
that game.
Really?
Yeah.
I never played it.
How does it work?
Is it a one of those role playing games?
He started out in like the dark ages and
you progress through like Bronze Age,
Iron Age,
you invent railroads and then eventually
you like colonize Alpha Centauri and you
playing against the computer or it's the
human's turn based strategy game against
the computer.
Um,
but you kind of learn the whole
technology tree and what everything's
called and what followed what and God I
Hope said Meyer got it right more or
less,
but it was a much more compelling way to
learn all that than like taking whatever
European history ap.
Right.
I would imagine that's incredibly
immersive.
Like how,
how could they do something like that?
Oh,
the new discovery mode turns on
assassin's creed origins is doing
interactive history lessons.
It's like ancient Egypt I believe is
what they do here.
And it's like deep detail,
really creation of it.
You go through it and they take for this
mode,
they kind of take all the the shoot and
that's shooting but stabbing and killing
the people and just walk you through
ancient and Egypt.
Cairo you get to see people die.
Not In this mode.
Maybe they did.
They might show some stuff of what not,
but so that you can either have it
graphic or non graphic cause that's the
idea.
Yeah.
Then they can show you through the map,
take you to play a video of this.
Can I watch this?
I think so.
I need to see this.
I'll look it up like okay.
Yeah.
I mean that would be the best way to
teach people.
Things do make some sort of interactive
environment,
especially virtual where you could go
there and experience it.
And,
and I mean,
I don't know if you've messed around
with any of the htc vive things.
Oh is this year?
So yeah,
it's just like a tour of the full screen
with this.
Hello Mrs.
This is part of the game but this is not
the actual game.
This is like a mode they did to teach
kids cause they had all of this
technology available.
So they said,
you know what,
just get a narrator,
add some audio clips,
making a mode.
Wow world.
And they even have it the way it was
originally built.
The Great Pyramid with the limestone
still attached for the most part.
This is a 20 minute videos.
This is like,
this is real deep detailed man.
He's like the best Graham Hancock,
you know,
explanation you could get,
but you're the guy there and you're in a
third person position.
You probably could go first person too,
I'm sure.
Wow.
This is just this particular part.
They're going to keep doing this as
well.
This assassin's creed has gone through
all sorts of different modes of history
through the renaissance,
Rome,
Spain,
all sorts of different areas.
And now that they sort of turn this on,
it's gonna ramp up probably.
Well that to me like a really
good idea in terms of getting kids
excited about learning things,
having some sort of an interactive game.
Yeah.
Just game a game of every topic.
Everything up really high quality way.
Yeah.
And I think the tricky thing with um,
you know,
education is the kind of tech that we
use is several steps behind the state of
the art in Hollywood.
Special effects or documentaries or
this,
this kind of game.
So the students are kind of disappointed
when they come to class.
Right?
Right.
And it's like college is really
expensive and it's really retro grade in
terms of the tech quality.
So why,
why are we here?
Um,
we should be on the forefront,
right.
It should be possible to go to your
State University and see awesome
gamified interactive stuff that you
don't have access to at home.
But everything is changing so fast.
And in order for the curriculum to keep
up with modern technology,
it would have to revamp every year.
Well,
I mean,
a lot of the content we teach is pretty
old actually.
Like the key ideas and evolutionary
biology.
Many of them go back 50 or a hundred
years.
Um,
key ideas in animal behavior or
paleontology or,
um,
anthropology.
It's not like those get updated that
fast.
It's just the way you can present them.
Technically
we're,
we're not competitive.
Yeah.
And that's embarrassing.
Is there a way to change that or is
that,
that seems almost insurmountable without
a complete overhaul.
The system,
I think you need a totally different
kind of university and credential that's
backed by a significant amount of
capital and that's technology,
technological,
innovative,
and it's very on pc in terms of what it
teaches and how it teaches.
Do you think that's possible that would
come along and compete with the
standard?
Yes.
Yeah.
I think it's inevitable that that will
happen and then that's probably going to
be what bankrupts and I think it's going
to eat our lunch.
Yeah.
What do you,
how do you feel about that though?
As a person who makes their living?
Do,
I mean,
I'll see you write books and I'd be
happy to jump ship and go do that.
What did you oh yeah.
Good for you.
If I could like teach hundreds of
thousands or millions of people rather
than write 200 at a time.
Well that's essentially what Jordan
Peterson is doing.
Yeah,
exactly.
But he's not doing it through a virtual
thing.
He's doing it through video lectures and
then physical lectures.
It's really fascinating to see the
reaction to him.
And now to Sam Harris is doing this as
well,
but not the videos,
but he's definitely doing the uh,
the live sort of performances.
And
No,
who would've ever thought there would be
a place where public intellectuals would
go and 5,000
people would sell out like that and go
to see them?
Like they would go to see fucking Kevin
Hart or something.
It's crazy.
Yeah.
Well,
you know,
when
Kenzie first started doing a sec surveys
and he would go around the country
giving lectures,
like he filled up a 4,000
person stadium and in UC Berkeley,
just presenting the first real data on
human sexuality back in late forties,
I think.
Wow.
And so there was why,
because there's a real hunger for that
because it was something the students
couldn't get anywhere else.
And the same was true back in the 18
hundreds when you had famous authors
touring America,
like Mark Twain or um,
many people think is the founder of
standup comedy.
Yeah,
yeah.
Right.
And they would use humor like Jordan
Peterson,
Sam Harris,
you,
um,
and they would speak in the register of
the people,
not pretentious academic jargon.
Sam is surprisingly funny.
I told that we had dinner recently and
we were talking and I said,
dude,
you're really funny.
Like those,
those little side notes and asides you
throw out little funny quips like this
is like standup comedy type stuff.
When someone will say something like,
like even with you though,
you guys were talking about polyamory
and there was he through some sort of a
joke?
Like how's that working out?
Yeah,
no,
it's a very dry humor,
which I love.
Yeah.
Um,
so funny guy,
but that makes it more palatable.
Spoonful of sugar helps the medicine go
down.
You know,
this fascinating technology in terms of
video games is going to help you absorb
information about ancient Egypt.
And humor is going to help just make the
time go by better and make the whole
experience less flat.
Yeah.
So I think,
I think that's a future and I think
within 10 years,
um,
a lot of young people are just going to
realize if I can actually learn more
from some alternative system,
some franchise of really good gamified
instruction plus great presenters who
have a sense of humor and are smart and,
and kind of like Hetero docs and,
and edgy,
they're going to flock to that.
The main thing is that business,
that franchise would have to provide a
credential that actually separates them
from people who don't have it and that
predicts performance in companies or in
the future.
Right.
Cause that's the main function of the
university right now is it?
It's this credential signaling system.
And if somebody figures out a way to
make it so that like if you've got a
degree from this,
okay,
whatever Sam Harris University,
that that is really a better predictor
of doing well in a job or a marriage.
Right.
Then a Yale degree,
then suddenly the whole business model
changes for universities.
Well,
what's really fascinating when you think
about the history of education is that
our ideas about these gigantic
institutions,
whether it's Yale or Harvard,
is that they've been long established
and long proven and bolt.
No,
I mean a few hundred years in terms of
people being alive.
That ain't shit.
You know,
you go back before that you're,
this is really,
you only have a certain amount of years
where these things were even a real
thing.
Yeah.
And I mean the idea that you have a
teaching institution that's also a major
research institution really only goes
back to post World War II.
Like before World War II,
Harvard was basically an elite finishing
school.
It wasn't a research power.
So that whole system that we think of as
being ancient as actually just less than
a hundred several decades.
Yeah.
Wow.
Okay.
Yeah.
Um,
I think you're probably right.
I think the new things can eat the
lunch.
Yeah.
Well that's,
it's almost like they're setting
themselves up.
I mean with some of the more ridiculous
and preposterous protests that go on
where there they are just trying to
silence discussion.
And even with people like Christina Hoff
summers who's very reasonable and calls
herself a factual feminist and they want
to call her a Nazi,
it's like there's no,
there's no wiggle room.
You are a one or a zero,
you are black or white,
you are evil or good.
And that's it.
And this inclination towards Silencing
People d platforming,
screaming them down,
halting them and getting them out and
who decides who decides who's correct
and rock?
Well,
the only way for people to get an
accurate assessment of who's giving the
right information is to have a debate,
but to have a real debate,
like a real debate where people are
allowed to express themselves without
people in the audience shaking jars of
coins and bull horns and all the
nonsense and setting off fire alarms and
all these things that these children,
and I call them children because they're
behaving like children are celebrating.
You know,
I'm sure you're aware of what happened
at Evergreen and now evergreens,
uh,
Evergreen State University where Bret
Weinstein had,
you know,
his horrible experience with,
if you don't know the story,
I'll give you the brief synopsis.
The,
they had a day of absence where it used
to be that people of color would stay
home so that you would miss them.
And then he decided to turn around and
make white people stay home,
make them,
force them.
If you didn't do it,
you're a racist.
He said,
that's crazy.
Like you guys are being racist.
And they shouted him down and they shut
the school down and he won a half a
million dollars in a lawsuit.
Uh,
and thou,
the schools,
most recent enrollment from the freshman
class was only 300 people,
which is crazy.
Yeah.
I'm noticing the parents noticed,
the students notice and universities are
so complacent.
They think,
oh,
we can,
we can do any amount of this.
Yeah.
And the customers will still come and
they're,
they're wrong.
As soon as there's a viable alternative
where somebody can get a credential that
means something and it's cheaper and
better and they learn more and it's more
engaging that hole it universities
acting stupid about that and,
and you know,
denying free speech and denying real
debate.
That's the existential threat to them.
That's what's going to blindside them.
That's what's going to kill their
tuition.
It's stunning how little resistance
there is to it.
Yeah.
That you,
the everyone knows that the only way to
find out whose ideas are more,
more well thought out,
more valid,
more factual.
The only way to find that out is to have
people discuss things together.
Yeah.
And T for you to be able to make an
assessment based on the facts,
do it in real time and based on who was
who farms a more compelling argument,
who's more reasonable,
who's,
who's taught,
who's addressing all the flaws and the
problems with both sides of this and
coming up with a reasonable conclusion.
The only way to do that as discourse.
We all know that and we've known that
forever,
but,
but somehow or another in higher
universities in higher education
centers,
this is where they're shutting this
stuff down and they want to,
you know,
whatever,
whether it's Ben Shapiro is speaking or
whoever it is,
it's speaking,
they want to scream at them,
they want to yell,
they want to break windows,
they want to co you know,
column racists or whatever they want to
call them.
Stunning.
I mean,
the way I think of it is like standup
comedy.
I love and,
and you know,
you do and the stuff you can say when
you're on stage doing standup comedy
university should be at least that open.
Like I should be able to lecture in a
way that goes even a little bit edgier
than most standup comedy could go
politically,
intellectually,
ideologically challenged the thoughts,
challenged their thoughts.
So universities should be like the inner
sanctum of intellectual freedom compared
to which everything else is more
restrained.
And we're kind of the opposite.
Like,
I know a few academics who go,
who actually are like amateur standup
comedians and it's so liberating to them
to be able to get up on a stage and say
what they really think.
Dev Use fake names.
Um,
no,
but they're kind of protected by like
the social norms of comedy,
right?
Like,
you know,
you're not supposed to really take it
very seriously.
Um,
but we're,
we're so far from that and you know,
in physics it doesn't matter that much
because it's not like there's any
aspects of quantum mechanics that are
that intellectually edgy,
but man and psychology and the social
sciences and behavioral sciences and in
political science it's really important
to be able to be provocative and
authentic and,
and we can't in America at the moment,
well,
which is really what's going to set up
whatever's coming next.
It's going to offer some sort of a new
new pathway,
new avenue that's not restricted.
Yeah.
Much like what you're seeing with a
podcasts and blogs and all in,
in comparison to,
or youtube videos in comparison to what
you're getting on regular network
television mean it was network
television.
And then cable was the more edgy
alternative,
and then there was pay cable like Hbo,
like,
Oh my God,
I saw breasts and then that got nuttier
and nuttier and,
but then it became Netflix,
which is a total nother level,
and then the internet is the wild west
and they want you to go back to NBC in
the 1970s and you're like,
ah,
no,
I'm not going to do it.
No,
not going to pretend,
but university seemed to be stuck.
Yeah.
I think universities are like NBC Circa
1975 right,
where they're like,
oh,
this cable stuff that's not really gonna
matter,
and then,
oh,
this internet and that,
but the Netflix of education is coming
and it's,
it's going to be incredibly disruptive
and I hope that the academic friends and
colleagues I have who are good and an
open minded art ready to jump ship
because ultimately they're educators,
whatever form it is that what their
career is.
Is there an educator,
just like Kyle Dunnigan is a comedian,
he takes on a new form with this new
technology and he becomes a comedian
using face swapping technology that
these educators are going to recognize
that the,
the landscape has changed and there's
gotta be some sort of a new way of
distributing information.
Yeah,
I could have good academics or like just
ordinary humans with their curiosity
turned up to 11 and who have a passion
for discovering new ideas and then
sharing them with people.
And we don't really care how we do that.
We will do it through lectures or
writing books or writing articles or
podcasts,
whatever works the best.
Have you thought about starting a
podcast?
Well,
you know,
I did a podcast with Tucker Max a couple
of years ago,
the maiden grounds where it was sort of
related to our mate book that was dating
advice for young single guys.
Um,
but it wasn't realized.
It wasn't really,
well,
it was figure out what women
authentically actually one and then try
to transform yourself in that direction.
So you're a better boyfriend.
What do they want?
A women want guys who are uh,
well informed and know about the world
and ambitious and capable capability is
the main thing,
like competency just in as many domains
as possible.
Um,
they want guys who were in like
reasonably good physical shape and good
mental health and um,
who can strike the right balance between
being kind of Nice and agreeable and
kind,
but also being dominant and assertive
and um,
kind of high status.
And if that's too much to ask,
you become a male feminist,
just grovel,
just bend of the knee,
bend the knee.
So
yeah.
And you know,
when I teach human sexuality,
I kind of emphasize this to students
that there's a lot you can do to make
yourself more attractive to whoever you
want to attract it.
You don't,
it's not all limited by what traits
you're born with.
Well,
it's fascinating is the difference in
what a man is attracted to versus what's
a woman's attracted to.
And this is something that we just don't
like to admit.
Yeah.
There's a great deal of difference when
it comes to heterosexuals at least.
Yeah.
I mean there's a lot of difference when
it comes to short term mating,
like what men want if it's a one night
stand versus what women want.
And if you look at long term mating,
like who people choose for marriage,
there's actually quite a bit of
convergence there.
Like everybody wants someone who's
mentally healthy and reliable and smart
and kind and would make like would pick
the kids up on time from school.
Yes,
et cetera.
And funny,
funny is really important.
Bret Weinstein,
um,
talked about the difference between a
woman who is beautiful versus a woman
who's hot.
And what hot does is it gives you the
opportunity to spread your genes with
very little responsibility.
So a one night stand for,
I'm a girl who's hot.
You don't have to mate.
You don't have to like court her,
get her to love you,
show your virtue,
earn her respect.
Now he just bang her in the park like
that.
That's hot versus someone who's
beautiful,
who you really go out of your way to
maybe even be a better person so that
you could attract that person.
Yeah.
If you fall in love with someone,
you want to be a better person for them.
But it's fascinating that there are
these two choices.
And I never really thought about it
until he brought it up.
But,
but they're essentially ways to
distribute your DNA.
There's pathways.
One of them is through longterm bonding
and you want a stable,
reliable woman who has a lot of self
respect,
who chooses you.
It makes you feel good,
she choose you and the other one's a
freak.
Yeah.
But the fact that all different kinds of
people exist with all different mating
strategies shows put each of those
strategies historically and
evolutionarily has worked like it's been
a valid strategy.
Yeah.
Cause there wouldn't be like promiscuous
men or women if that hadn't been
something that worked.
Sure.
Right.
There also wouldn't be longterm pair
bonded,
you know,
family people if that hadn't worked.
So I think it's silly when people are
sort of dissing each other's mating
strategies as if,
well there's one proper way.
And then all the other ways it sort of
degenerate or reactionary or
whatever.
Well the other mating strategies
produced fucked up kids.
I mean,
you know the,
the hot one when you're not going to see
the kid,
you can develop a mess of a child.
And those are the ones they used to sell
cars,
right?
I mean,
but each fucked up by what standards.
So,
well there's dots,
the question father around,
you know,
you have daddy issues.
I think a lot of that is just a way of
kind of shaming these,
these other mating strategies.
Cause you mean,
well of course you get a little bit of
circular logic.
For example,
where you say this mating strategy,
for example,
let's say a high degree of promiscuity,
you say that's bad.
Why?
Because it leads to offspring who in
turn act promiscuous and then you call
it the cycle of abuse or daddy issues or
whatever.
But it's not a promiscuous thing.
Or is it just a longing for both a
father and a mother and a loneliness and
a vulnerability that seems to come with
being a,
the offspring of a single mother.
Most people agree that that's not the
ideal situation,
but it does produce unique people,
which is really interesting.
Like all,
most,
all of my really cool friends came from
a fucked up,
broken childhood,
which I don't know what to think about
that because I want my children to be
comforted and healthy and never worried
about the future,
but all my friends that grew up in
chaotic environments where everyone was
poor and fucked up and there's crime and
violence and nonsense and chaos.
Those are the interesting ones.
Their parents are drug addicts.
Those are the cool ones too.
It's,
it's such a,
as a parent,
yeah.
I mean,
so like as a scientist,
you've got to look at the whole spectrum
of mating and parenting behavior and go,
particularly as an evolutionary
psychologist,
you can say,
I might have a moralistic reaction to
that.
I might go,
that's bad,
but you know what?
If it actually,
if what we consider bad is actually the
way most of the other 4,000
species of mammals do it,
then who,
who were really the weird families
anyway,
right?
Most mammo families,
the dads aren't involved.
It's single moms raising offspring by
themselves under harsh conditions and
they,
they're not doing pair bonds.
Right?
Hardly any mammals do pair bonds apart
from like gibbons and few prosimians,
like really small primates.
Okay.
I,
I'm just very hesitant to kind of
moralize it and,
but it isn't really fair or even
accurate to compare ourselves to things
that only lived to be like 10 I mean
we're,
we're talking about enormously
complicated emotions,
far more so because of communication and
societal norms and eh,
you know,
the comparison.
Yeah.
There's so much more involved being a
person.
Okay.
It's just like,
if you look back historically right
there,
premarital sex is to be demonized.
Right?
And folks used to say,
well,
oh my God,
you had,
you had one or two lovers before you
settled on with your husband,
that's terrible.
And you could produce statistical
correlations to say,
oh look,
premarital sex is correlated with being
lower class or criminal or drug use or
whatever.
I'm like,
that's all true.
But then society moved in a direction
that said premarital sex is okay.
But wasn't that really because of birth
control?
Because a woman's once,
once a woman had an ability to control
her reproductive system and say,
you know,
I can hit,
just have sex for pleasure and
enjoyment.
Yeah.
Because before it was the consequences
are so grave.
Especially in poverty.
Yeah.
Like now there's another mouth to feed
and now I can't work because I have to
take care of the babies.
Oh,
right.
Okay.
Yeah.
So the technology of contraception made
a big difference.
Um,
it used to be thought,
okay,
if you're,
if you're gay or lesbian,
that is morally degenerate and terrible
and invalid and you can't possibly have
a longterm relationship or a family or
whatever.
And then we kind of changed that pretty
dramatically in the last 20,
30 years.
So I just,
you know,
as a sex researcher,
I want people to
be quite cautious about saying that
lifestyle is wrong and degenerate and
unhealthy and this other lifestyle is
better because in the era of sex bots,
right.
In virtual reality,
deep fakes and whatever,
who knows what's going to happen.
Well,
if you read sex at dawn,
yeah.
Did you like it?
I had very mixed feelings about it.
What was the negative?
Um,
I don't think it's an accurate
description of pre history,
prehistoric meeting.
Um,
I think pair bonds,
Ron,
really deep and human evolution,
but I think as a sort of ethical ideal,
um,
polyamory is,
is okay and it works for some people
some of the time.
And this is something that you've
discussed a lot.
Polyamory.
Um,
I really only kind of came out publicly
as being interested in it on the Sam
Harris' show a few months ago,
but I'm,
I'm thinking about writing a book on it
next and um,
it's a very popular thing.
I mean the number of people who are in
open relationships or poly relationships
is larger than the number of people who
are gay or lesbian.
Certain really?
Oh,
for sure.
Yeah.
What's the number of people in gay or
lesbian relationships?
Number of people who are gay or lesbian
at the population level is like two to
5% depending on the surveys in
polyamorous relationships.
Um,
probably five to 15% at the moment.
And it's even higher among people under
35 or so.
So this is a new thing.
It's relatively new.
And is this just an acceptance of the
instincts that people have to be
nonmonogamous the acceptance of the,
that,
that jealousy is holding people back
from experiencing different things?
Like,
yeah,
I think it's only in the 90s that you,
you got a coherent subculture that said
if you're not going to be monogamous,
here's the honest,
ethical,
open way to do it.
And it kind of developed a bunch of
social norms about how you manage these
relationships in a way that's different
from cheating or different from swingers
or different from prostitute,
hippie love communes or,
or prostitutes.
And I mean this is a longer discussion
than we have time for probably today.
But,
um,
as a researcher it's a fascinating
culture because it's people who are
trying to find ways to kind of hack
their jealousy and manage it better.
Yeah.
Um,
and it's also a new method of social
networking,
right?
Where you're not drawing a sharp line
between who you are sexually connected
to and who you're socially connected to.
Um,
so people who were in depaul a tend to
have sort of sexual friendship,
professional networks that are much
broader than done.
A lot of people tend to have.
And I,
I think that's actually a little bit
more similar to what Christopher Ryan
was talking about with sex at dawn
[inaudible].
Like I think in most prehistoric tribes,
anybody who wasn't a close relative who
was sort of mating age,
you probably would have had sex with
like sooner or later at least once,
even if you both had a sort of stable,
um,
paramont
and this is probably an incredibly
controversial subject at the academic
level.
Well,
when I taught my course on polyamory and
open sexuality last year,
it got a little bit of controversy.
You say that with smile in the
department.
Um,
well there was concern about what
happens if,
you know,
you get complaints from
legislators.
Ah,
there it goes again.
Funding,
yeah,
money.
But yeah.
Um,
there's a lot of cool research on it.
There was a lot of interesting
psychological issues.
Plus if your students,
probably a good way to find the freaks.
It was,
they were wonderful,
wonderful freaks.
I mean those wrong,
great in a freak,
great students and open minded and you
know,
we talked about the pros and the cons.
It's like this stuff is really hard to
do for this and this and this reason and
people really only succeed at it if they
have certain kinds of traits and
abilities and communication skills.
And if they don't,
they crash and burn and doesn't work.
So it wasn't just an advocacy class,
it was also like here's the pros and
cons,
but also as a social trend,
this is a big deal.
And if you're going into one of the
caring professions like medicine,
nursing,
social work,
clinical psych,
you damn well better know about this
because a lot of people do it.
And if you're giving advice to a couple
and they're in an open relationship and
you don't even understand what that
means or how it works,
you're going to give bad advice.
And that's to me kind of professional
malpractice.
Hmm.
It's also sort of in some ways,
an ongoing experiment in terms of how,
you know,
how people bond with each other,
how people form communities.
Yeah.
And this is in particular with in
today's climate,
in today's society with the,
you know,
the ability to distribute this
information and discuss these things in
groups and yeah,
it's a different world in terms of just
collecting data and it and comparing
experiences.
Yeah.
It's a work in progress.
I mean,
I think nobody who is polyamorous or in
an open relationship can pretend that,
yeah,
we really know how to make this work
very well and here's the best practices
and here's the,
all the,
the hacks and,
and anybody can do it.
No,
we're absolutely not.
At that point.
It's also brave to talk about because it
immediately puts you into this potential
pervert place.
Yeah.
Like,
you know,
you talk about sex with more than like
more than one person.
Well,
wait,
what are you doing?
What are you doing,
Jeffrey?
Yeah.
What are you doing?
I know you're wrecking your reputation.
You have to having sex.
I know it's super stigmatized.
Yeah.
But like compared to what?
Compared to be an evolutionary
psychologist in the first place,
who does intelligence research or
compared to teaching human sexuality or
compared to doing just as a human and
civilization doing a book with Tucker
Max.
I mean,
that's tricky,
right?
Um,
but I think we,
we have a professional responsibility,
you know,
if you're a behavioral scientist to
understand what are people doing out
there,
um,
what is working and what isn't and how
do you make it work better.
And the people who ignore it,
I think it's kind of like if you were
like a psychologist in the early
seventies,
right?
When the gay and lesbian rights movement
of starting,
if you'd sort of said,
Oh God,
I hope that'll blow over like that.
That doesn't deserve research.
We,
we,
uh,
we should keep it as a mental disorder.
And you know,
the,
the Dsm,
right,
I feel like is sort of at the same place
where,
um,
yeah,
there are reactionaries who go that
that's just gross and disgusting.
Just like people in the early seventies
would have said,
homosexuality is gross and disgusting.
Well,
it's still,
it's,
it's brave to discuss right now.
I mean,
it may very well be like,
you know,
when you're talking about the gay and
lesbian rights revolution of the 1970s,
it may be 40 years from now,
it's just like that.
Like,
oh,
they're this and this.
Is that normal?
No,
who cares?
But in today's Day and age,
it's a tread carefully.
Right?
Well,
somebody's got to research it and talk
about it.
Yeah.
And um,
I think like people should read sex at
dawn Bicros,
Christopher Orion.
But that shouldn't be the final word
about human evolution and polyamory.
What's another good book on it?
I mean,
the ethical slut is a good kind of,
that sounds like a restaurant.
I mean,
it's kind of the Poly Bible.
Is it really the ethical slut?
I love it.
It's a,
it's a,
that um,
dossie eat,
uh,
what's her name?
Eaten,
I think,
I
can't remember.
She's got a coauthor.
It's slot.
It's been right now I know it was a poly
Bible for 20.
Everybody buys that book just,
just to have it on your shelf.
I have,
that book sells a billion copies.
It's done pretty well at there.
It is.
The ethical slut.
Yeah.
Dossie Easton and Janet Hardy.
What a great name for a book.
I'm sad that I never came up with that.
It's a good title,
but I don't think there's a good book.
Yeah.
That's actually savvy about evolutionary
psychology and human sexuality and
polyamory and how it's all going to play
out in the next 10 years or so.
And this is why you were kind of
planning,
writing it yourself.
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
Well,
I hope you do,
man.
Thanks.
And thanks for coming here.
It's a lot of fun.
It's been a pleasure.
We had,
we talked for three hours.
Can you believe that?
Oh my God.
Yeah.
We did time warp in this room.
Time flew.
Thank you Jeffrey.
Really appreciate it.
Welcome.
Uh,
tell people how to find you on twitter.
I'm primal.
Poly,
P R,
I m a L P O,
l y.
And I'm sorry,
Jeffrey Miller and primal poly.com.
Okay.
Thank you,
sir.
[inaudible].