All right,
we're live,
dude.
That's it.
We're going.
Boom.
It's moving.
Just like that.
It's amazing.
It's amazing to have young man like your
show.
You know,
it's one of the few shows where you take
over,
like it's a real problem whenever you
got a show that's iconic and top gear is
iconic as fuck.
Oh sure.
I mean it's the iconic car show and then
they did an Australian version.
They've done other.
How many versions is,
are there now?
Australia was first.
There was a German one really German
when they did something with them once
and then that kind of killed them.
There was,
there's us,
we're still a thing.
There was a top gear Korea for like five
minutes,
which may or may not be going on there.
The ones that drop that Apache
helicopter,
uh,
in the desert,
everybody was fine.
What was the same?
There was a new,
there's like a Zl one camaro chasing,
getting chased by an Apache helicopter,
which is something we did in our first
season and the same helicopter pilot and
copilot got too close to the.
The blades got too close and caught it
and it dropped him.
They walked away,
the helicopters toast.
But then when you hear it,
you start,
there are certain things that happen and
you start to look back at your life and
go like,
does that mean I could've also almost
died when we did that?
Like 20 minutes from my house season one
before?
Totally.
Definitely.
So luckily that didn't happen.
Apache helicopters are fucking
expensive.
Yes.
The government had all these helicopters
laying around that they couldn't do
anything with.
And uh,
the guy that,
that flute with us was a guy named skip
lamb and he and a bunch of other pilots
like,
hey,
we could do stuff with TV,
with movies,
whatever.
So they started this little group and
the government gave them a bunch of
these surplus helicopters that they
weren't doing anything with.
So they exist and they can do different
films and movies and it's cool for these
guys because they get to use the skills
that they had and get to do something
cool with them.
But again,
it's a real helicopter.
Like it's a bad bitch helicopter that
millions to be to be one of those work.
Jamie,
find out what one of those fuckers are
worth.
We had a,
not those,
but we had a bunch of helicopters that
we used on fear factor and a lot of
times they were really close to each
other.
It have to fly staggered where the
blades of one,
we're just above the blades of the other
and they're connected.
Both of them connected by ropes to
something that they're picking up like a
bus or some shit on fucking stupid.
$52 million.
Jesus fucking Christ.
Wow.
Oh my God.
I kind don't feel like there's any of
those on Amazon is what my gut tells me.
There might be Ebay for sure.
603% more expensive than the average for
its class.
Were you ever close enough when they
were doing that and you can feel like
the wash from them?
I assume you've been in a helicopter.
One of my least favorite things in life.
I've only been in all honestly.
I never flew in a helicopter the entire
time we did for your factor.
We,
we,
we shot for six fucking years.
Helicopters every other week.
I never got on one good for you because
I couldn't.
It was part like I would have to be
insured
due to the helicopter.
Right.
But uh,
I've been on.
I'm on vacation.
I've done that.
I'm the Big Island in Hawaii.
Oh yeah,
the volcanoes you've ever done that I've
known,
I've been there once.
It was lovely to.
It's,
it's like literally take it,
takes my breath away just thinking about
it because it's the earth bleeding out
into the surface.
Middle of nowhere going into the water
and creating the island.
You watched the island be created like
it's every day.
It's like a couple more inches gets
added to the big island and you could
actually literally watch it happen and
that's that.
That's it.
Like next level stuff.
Meanwhile,
the whole time I'm in there,
I'm thinking like this bitch is going to
go down and he takes off or when it
lands is the worst part for you because
you can feel when you feel that when
push up against the blade and it's like,
are we're going to go?
Are we thinking about that?
That's for me,
the pants crapping factor that makes it
not fun.
I've owned a lot of shit boxes and I'm
sure you're aware of things breaking
like you're on the highway,
but if a wheel falls off,
you and I can pull over exactly if a or
drops off we make the news.
It's not my favorite.
Yeah,
I think there's a way they can kind of
like.
Bill Burr just started flying
helicopters.
He has his fucking hilarious bit about
it on his last Netflix special about
flying helicopters,
but he said that they're not nearly as
bad to crash as people think they are.
There's a way you learn how to bring
them down.
I'll pass on that man.
I will and I have for you.
I would probably,
if he ever invite you up then I just
tell him I'll just meet you there man.
I'll go.
I'll just drive.
I'll go for the story.
I was in high school.
Buddy of mine was taking flight lessons
when I was in high school.
I had a buddy one and his parents were,
who was a wild guys family was his dad
was a poacher.
He's dead like a out here illegally.
There's a lot of weird shit in their
family and they were teaching him at a
very young age how to fly planes.
I don't know what the fuck they're going
to do with the plane,
but he came from a very sketchy family.
But uh,
we're gonna like fucking 15.
We were in a plane and I'm like
[inaudible],
well you shouldn't be flying shit.
But we were flying in a little single
engine plane.
Man,
one of those little,
one of my best friends flies for Delta
and I,
I tell him,
you know,
you travel a lot,
you get it.
But like if I hear his name broadcast
over the PA,
I'm probably going to get off the plane
because I've been drunk with them enough
times that it's just,
I'm,
I dig that he's in charge of so many
people's lives.
I just don't know for their.
Did you see the picture of the plane
that ran into a bird?
A commercial jet plane slammed into a
bird in a caved in the entire front of
the plane.
No,
you didn't say that's awesome though.
Assuming everyone's okay.
Everyone lived because it hit it
perfect.
But if you hit the wing,
I mean you look at what it did to the
front of the planet,
like give it hit,
hit,
you know,
six
feet to the left,
six feet to the right,
whatever you look like people might have
died or if it landed the through the
windshield and it killed the pilot.
I mean you've gotta if you're hitting
like a Canadian ghosts,
like one of those bright fucking giant
geese vineyard trying to land in the
Hudson.
Yeah.
It's like that story.
So there's this place in Georgia near me
where we shot the same place with the
helicopter and they are the people that
go and recover airplanes.
Look at it.
There's the impact.
Holy Cow,
right?
Just boom.
Soft spot right in there.
So when the plane went down the Hudson,
these redneck dudes from Griffin,
Georgia were sent up there to get the
plane that's floating in the water,
right?
Insurance companies pay them to go and
recover these planes and they have to
basically cut them up,
get them on a,
on a train or a flat bed or whatever.
And so for Christmas,
one of our executive producer for top
gear,
he was like showing me,
Oh,
here's some stuff I got from Ronnie and
my buddies back in Georgia.
And it was a tiny bottle of Jack Daniels
that looked like it had mold growing on
the outside.
And it was one of the bottles that was
in the plane that went down on the
Hudson and these guys were covered it.
And that was his Christmas keepsake to
his friends.
That's funny.
Wow.
That's probably worth money things.
So then on Ebay and there's like,
there's this cool like [inaudible]
looking and I was like,
oh,
that looks neat.
What?
Like,
uh,
I landed that.
And the guy was like,
oh no,
that plane hit the water and the Panama
City,
that guy died.
You couldn't have a more trite like
business unless maybe you're an
undertaker.
I don't,
I don't know.
Maybe a funeral service director,
I'm not sure.
But you have to basically go pick up
crap after bill burr and his friends
learn how to roll a helicopter that's
going down safely.
Didn't Patrick swayze crashed drunk?
Wasn't uh,
something that happened?
I believe Patrick swayze before he died
was boozing it up,
flying around with his cancer.
He's not so happy with just going for
it.
Just getting hammered and flying around.
I mean,
he had cancer for quite a while and uh,
was flying planes.
I think he crashed one of them.
I'm pretty sure he crashed one of them
and walked away until it's hardcore.
And was it a Harrison Ford that just
landed one on a,
on a golf course?
Yeah,
he crashed,
landed somewhere.
Harrison Ford.
He apparently,
he got pretty banged up like that was a,
that was a real crush swayze.
Suspected drunk flying was in 2000
skews.
Me.
Yeah.
Three men are facing misdemeanor charges
in connection with Patrick swayze
emergency landing.
Earlier this month,
the men are accused of failing to tell
authorities about how they allegedly
held the act to remove alcoholic
beverages from his crashed plane.
He was doing it,
man.
He's fucking dirty dancing guy.
Come on,
he's roadhouse.
Let them,
you know,
it's weird that like Patrick swayze
would wear stuff in those movies that
like if our friends war,
we'd kind of make fun of Patrick swayze
ways.
You're like,
that guy can dance.
Only because he didn't know him.
If you got to know him after awhile,
you start mocking them if hanging around
with him.
You met Patrick swayze and he was like
dancing.
You'd be like,
Hey,
that's pretty cool.
And then like five minutes later I'd be
like,
uh,
do you do sports or just fucking dance
around you play golf?
Or like what?
What is,
uh,
do you have friends?
Do you hang around with like on a
Tuesday?
You know,
Mckell Baryshnikov or some shit like
there.
There's roadhouse.
Roadhouse wouldn't move.
It wasn't a man playing the guitar.
I'm the blind guy.
Yeah.
That guy was really good.
He was really good.
Whatever happened to that dude got
killed.
Yeah.
Dive.
I think it was in a car wreck.
He wasn't driving.
I'm sure as you know,
that's not a joke against and I just got
asked the same question.
That was a really good musician.
He was great.
That's right.
He was in and I forgot it was in it.
And that.
Sam,
Jeff,
he leaf healy.
Thank you.
How did he die?
Find it for us.
This is the.
Can I get somebody like that that just
goes with going places,
right?
So it's more fun with someone else.
You can continue your thought.
That's the benefit when you're have,
when you have a podcast.
Died of cancer.
Underwent surgery to remove metastic
tissue from both lungs.
And that's what in Alabama,
that's what we call a car wreck.
So my bad,
I got.
I categorized that wrong.
Well,
we were talking before the podcast and
we were talking about muscle cars and
we're talking about mustangs and Mustang
people being weird like that.
You're not the only one who's ever said
that to me.
I haven't experienced this except in
high school when I was in high school,
my um,
auto shop teacher was a mustang fanatic.
Okay.
The guy was nuts.
Sure.
And he had all these old shitty mustangs
and he'd like to put back together again
and they were all like,
fucking heat that students do the Bondo
on them.
They're all,
you know,
look at them sideways.
It was like looking at a fucking ski
slope.
Right.
They're just completely fucked up.
But he was weird and he just,
he didn't look like any other cars.
He's like,
I like mustangs just hardcore,
just all he wanted and he even like,
he didn't even like the cool ones,
like,
you know,
shitty hubcaps and like he never,
he never like did them up nice.
And where they look like something,
I would want muscle cars,
but in his mind they were,
they were the jam.
Yeah.
It was a mustang or nothing.
That was his thing,
and to quantify it a tiny bit,
you told me that you were kind of
thinking about building a car and it's
maybe a Chevelle or maybe a mustang.
I think there's lots of.
If you look at the car world,
man,
there's,
there's so many different pockets of
people and this stuff that they like and
I.
I was never a big mustang guy.
I dig them.
I get why people love them,
but like let's pick the Fox body,
right?
That's the 79 to 93 and they made a few
changes in their.
Like they had the tops and a few death.
Those cars were desk.
They're just ship there in vanilla ice
is a number one song.
Write doom,
doom,
doom with a rag top down below.
And I did that,
but that's what that car was like.
To me.
It's a great representation of sort of
like a redneck mullet,
late eighties,
early nineties kind of style.
Well,
I on my show,
lost and transmission,
we had to take one.
I've found it in my buddy's junkyard.
I needed an engine and transmission and
try to make this AMC Eagle.
Cool,
right?
I couldn't keep the car all wheel drive.
It was like a jacked up ugly four by
four.
I couldn't keep it all wheel drive and
have any amount of power.
So I said,
all right,
let's make it rear wheel drive.
Let's make it something cool.
So I had to basically sacrifice this Fox
body and do people came out of the
woodwork.
I don't know how active you are on so I
know you are,
but like sometimes when people try to
get mad at you on facebook,
it's so much funnier to read and you're
like,
this goes so pissed.
He forgot that English is a language
because it's just a hail of words and
like he tried to call this one fox body
rare and I made fun of him and then
other people saw it.
Not like in a mean way,
I just poked back,
but like there's no fox body that's
rare.
Those pictures back up again and let's
all agree that these should all be put
in a pile and nuked awful,
disgusting cars.
The worst representation of American
muscle cars that have ever been built.
Look at that girl in the hood.
Even.
She's not enthusiastic.
She's like this.
I hate my boyfriend.
Chaz Chaz.
He's an asshole.
He makes them get on top of his car and
you know,
that's.
That's like an Lx.
Five point on my might have been a four
cylinder.
I don't know.
I'll look at the girl with the pink one.
Oh yeah.
You totally want to buy her some boone's
farm.
Look at you girl.
I like how they redid the back lights.
They got crafted the fucking lights.
All Teza style.
It supposed to be a muscle car and they
had four lug wheels.
It was a disgusting car.
My friend,
my buddy Kevin,
Jason had one when we were kids.
He had A.
I'm not saying you can't make on cool.
Oh yeah.
I mean they're kind of cool.
They're kind of cool.
It's cool,
but they're not cool compared to the 60s
mustangs and the not cool compared to
the new ones.
The new ones are fucking bad.
They're dope.
Right?
And really they got,
they got better than what was the next
one.
So in 95 or would it not to be a total
dork?
I know codes and stuff,
I said,
but shouldn't they got cooler,
right?
They did.
They got better.
They got,
they were kind of decent.
And then in the two thousands,
like I had a 2010 shelby gt,
500.
That's bad.
That's a bad ass car.
It was a vicious car.
But it was,
you know,
live rear axle.
The handling properties weren't the
best,
but it wasn't about that.
That car was about.
It could go sideways anytime you want
her to know anybody around.
No hit it.
I would just go sideways around corners.
I mean it was so easy,
right?
Just anytime you wanted to just give it
a little juice and it would just kick
out the back for you.
And there's only really only a handful
of cars that you feel like when you see
someone on the road in,
you know,
sometimes people,
it's not that they're messing with you,
they're just not bright enough to know
how to be a good driver.
That's one of those cars you would
always see a dude in a mustang just be
like,
I've had enough of your crap.
I'm out,
I'm going to drop the hammer and I go.
So like I always liked that about him,
but there's just certain cars that
people that love them are sometimes
just.
They turned me off of the car,
like I always wanted a he 46 m,
three BMW.
Right.
That to me it's just such a great car
out of the box,
but then when I would meet a lot of the
people that would own them,
I would decide.
I don't think I really went wrong.
One.
I've heard that about Porsche's.
Do people have always said that about
porsches?
Magnus Walker is changing that for me.
Yes,
he is that guy.
How could you not love magnus?
First off,
he's just as bad ass dude that just
likes what he likes.
Well,
he's also so enthusiastic about it.
That's contagious.
Yeah,
he loves those like 60 to 73 and now
he's.
He.
He's in some turbos now.
Some older turbo models.
Sure.
Although he loves his [inaudible] 30
now.
A bunch of those.
Yeah,
and I think your buddies at shark works.
Took him a newer one,
like a 14,
that he got to go beat around on it and
suddenly he was like,
maybe the new ones aren't so bad.
Well he knows now.
Well he had never experienced anything
like the GT two.
So what Alex did,
Alex,
my buddy from shark works,
took a gt two from,
I want to say it's 2010 maybe somewhere
around there.
And um,
he made it 800 horsepower and it is the
fucking scariest car I've ever driven in
my life.
I mean,
it's fucking terrifying.
Like my gt three has 518 horsepower that
has almost 300 more horsepower.
It's somewhere in the eight.
It's a mind bogglingly fast.
It's a fucking time machine.
And he lead magnets,
drive it,
and he said to do with it whatever you
would do if it was your own car.
So Magnus had it fucking painted,
right?
Yeah.
But that's how cool Alex is.
And that's how cool magnets,
they just,
they're both fanatics so they just have
this understanding with each other.
So this is what he did to it.
You can see it there.
He painted.
I think it's ugly as fuck.
Go.
Come on with testing.
I love the golden wheels on there.
First wheels not aren't bad,
but the orange and the bumpers like why
it has that very like German dtm kind of
look to it like shit.
It looks like dog shit.
It's a great card since it's such a
beautiful design though.
It doesn't need fucking gray stripes in
the hood and Orange Burger.
But whatever.
Something my car.
But the bottom line is driving it
though.
What a goddamn experience.
Yeah,
it's terrifying.
We took it up.
Um,
Angel's crest.
Oh yeah.
That area.
And you can't drive it up.
It's too fast.
It,
every corner comes to quick.
And that's one of those cars.
That is,
when the power comes on,
it is,
doesn't matter how they've tuned at your
foot is not a machine.
You're foot is like,
hey,
let's do this.
All the sudden you think,
oh,
maybe I'll shoot off this hill,
or is this because you can't.
It's hard to drive that car in control
no matter who you are.
Well,
I had never really thought.
I never been in a car that had too much
power before where I drove it.
I've always been like,
whoa,
this is fast.
Like the shelby gt 500.
It was like 550 horsepower.
Pretty light car.
I'm like,
God damn,
this thing is fast,
ridiculously fast.
The GT three super fast,
but that is in a different category.
So it's mind boggling how much power it
has and when it kicks in,
just pinned you to the child.
It Ah,
ah.
Your heart starts racing like I'm going
to die.
This kid,
this kid,
this is,
this is physics.
You're like,
I get a James Dean.
Sinking feeling brother on a highway
apparently is even scarier.
They were saying on the highway,
you just don't feel compelled to let off
the gas.
And so you look down and you go in 170
miles an hour on the [inaudible] and
you're like,
what the fuck am I doing last season?
Top gear we went to,
we went to Germany,
we drove on the nurburgring.
Have you ever been in that ring?
Is like being inside of a of a video
game for folks who aren't car geeks.
The Nuremberg ring is the track that
everyone talks about when talking about
lap times.
Like if you have a car that can do seven
minutes and 30 seconds or below on the
nurburgring you've got a mother fucker.
It's car motherfucker.
What?
The record is just under seven minutes
right now.
So it,
it's for the 12 minute course,
right?
It's 14 if you run the whole thing.
But the 12 minute courses is like just
under seven for some unbelievably fast
thing.
When,
when we went there,
they tanner's got a friend over there,
right?
And Faust,
[inaudible] spouse.
Who's The you?
Adam for our,
uh,
and tanner.
Yes.
Of top gear.
Do Dude.
Gosh,
he loves you,
you guys.
It's,
it's like,
I love that comedy.
It's like one gigantic,
a fraternity and sorority that everyone
likes everyone,
unless you're that one.
A whole does a few of them.
We could go into that for guys that
needed to be killed.
Exactly.
Climate in the body of those shitty old
mustangs and newcomb from orbit.
But tanner tanner's got a friend who is
friends with the owner,
the people that just bought it.
So they closed the nurburgring for us
with God for three hours.
We had to track all to ourselves.
Wow,
dude,
that's the most insane thing I've ever
done in my life.
And I was in a 2014 carerra ass for us.
So it's a non turbo all wheel drive and
it's a little over 300 horsepower,
right?
It's about four.
I think it maybe you're right,
it's about four horsepower.
You could kill yourself on that track.
And uh,
you go maybe on a bicycle on a,
on a good downhill.
Every turn is a blind turn.
Every hill is a blind hill.
I hit one 82 on the back stretch.
And then like on the way there we were,
we were trying to hit the rev limiter on
the Autobahn because people know how to
drive on the interstate there.
It's the most amazing thing.
They get on the right hand lane and they
stay there until they need to use the
left.
And then they just like California.
Unless I'm like any work
before you use the word everywhere I've
lived,
California's still worse when it comes
to getting out of that left lane.
Nobody respects it.
Literally was slow down.
I'm going fast enough.
Yeah.
I'm just going to patrol this on my own
horn.
Yeah,
I've always lived in California.
I don't know anything about tomorrow
rounds because they kind of designed the
roads out here for a bunch of cars.
Right?
There's no.
Like when I first came here,
one of the first things that I did,
I drove down to was a place called hard
times billiards in bellflower,
California.
It's like a legendary pool hall and I
drove down there and I,
you have to take four or five,
get down there.
I was like,
look at this fucking road.
It's like seven lanes on each side.
I'm like,
this is insane.
And Massachusetts where I grew up,
there's nothing like that.
Right?
They didn't exist.
There were like horse and buggy roads
and someone can put hard pavement over
here.
You know,
potholes everywhere.
Yeah.
The road down here.
It's.
This is like the best car culture in the
world and the worst driving conditions
for car people.
Certainly for traffic.
It's on dude.
I don't know.
3:00
AM.
You guys can have traffic.
Yup.
In the middle of nowhere.
That bumper to bumper for no real
reason.
The real reason is people.
Fuck.
And they made babies and then they move
out here because they want to be famous.
I mean,
don't.
You're wrong if you go nowhere,
if you go south.
I mean there are some great roads to
drive here.
Yeah.
But you,
it'll take you six hours to go five
miles to find them.
Right.
I'm just,
I'm so nervous going anywhere here.
I was five minutes away and just
crapping my pants about if I could get
here on time or not.
Uh,
yeah.
It's it's nerve wracking place if you
want to be punctual,
but that dude run.
Let's lose it.
Let's go to the nurburgring.
What was your time?
Did you.
How fast did you get around it?
Did whatever.
I think I was under 10 minutes from my
first slap.
That's pretty God damn good.
And they said that's first time seeing
the track.
That's great.
You should feel really good about that.
You lose it at any point in time or just
get close to the edge.
The carousel is the coolest feeling I've
ever had because you dip in and it's it.
There's graffiti everywhere,
right?
Because they have these huge parties out
there around the races and so you're
seeing all this stuff in the car just
dips in and you're hauling ass as hard
as you can and then it just shoots you
right out the other side and you keep
going and you're like,
I just did it.
So the carousel is like a site,
like you're almost going sideways like a
bank.
Yes.
It's just steep bank to just kind of
pops in out of nowhere and you just get
any kind of.
Just ride it.
There it is right there.
It's so.
It's so amazing.
And the whole time I kept thinking,
what am I doing here?
Like how did this happen?
How did this goofball kid from Atlanta
end up on this show?
And they handed me a car and the keys to
the nerve,
greg to a German porsche,
modern German Porsche.
It was,
it was insane.
And they do the coolest part about that
road in that track on days when there
aren't races,
it's a toll road so you can pay $30 and
go take a lap.
Really?
So there are guys like you and I who
were there who either showed up with a
[inaudible],
rented one,
whatever.
Right?
So they're going out and having fun.
You still have to use your blinker and
you can only pass on the left,
which is hilarious to me.
But there's also like grandmothers and
families in tourists on the track at the
same time.
So you're just going to do it.
But people really going.
And so we're standing there,
we had just wrapped up and I was like,
let's see if we got five minutes,
I just want to watch some cars.
You see this mini cooper come hauling
ass around.
Right.
And this dude's just carving and there's
a guy in a f four 30,
he's like,
I can keep up with this son of a bitch.
And he punted that for 30 into the wall
on one side and then drug it down past
us now because it's a toll road,
they have to do an accident
investigation.
The money's gone.
The mini coopers checked out.
It's not.
He didn't have anything to do with it,
but he,
I think he still felt bad.
So everybody that was on the track at
that point has to exit and this team
shows up and they do like an accident
investigation because that guy's
insurance would still be good on the
track at that moment because it was a
toll road.
That's hilarious.
So how fast can you go?
I had one 83 and there's no Schema.
No,
you could just go.
And I was not the fastest car we had.
What kind of fucking insurance that they
have underneath crazy.
It's because you've heard of friends
that are like,
oh,
I took this new car to the track and
then I had to pay the tow truck guy to
drop it on the side of the four.
Oh,
five.
So I can call the insurance company.
Tell them I don't know what happened.
I was sitting here,
so I guess it just works out better,
but you can rent a racecar.
They're either like a Peugeot or they
have all these like little kind of
import smaller race cars you can rent.
It says like rent a racecar.
Just go for it.
Well if you get a Nissan Gtr,
they have a.
They have a speed limiter on it until
you get to race courses and the GPS
recognizes that you're at a race course.
That's awesome.
And it lets you just go fucking crazy.
Have you have you journal on such a
great car for the money?
Did one.
Did you?
Yes,
I rented one in Austin,
Texas.
If you go to um,
ah,
it hurts.
I think it's hurting.
Hertz has some pretty ridiculous cars
that you could share and if you wanna if
you wanna pay,
they'll let you run a GTR.
I was like,
whew.
So the whole weekend I was like,
I was riding a ride everywhere.
Just what I mean.
It's.
I mean,
for the supercar world,
it's such a bargain.
That car.
I mean it's,
they're getting more expensive now.
There is somewhere around a hundred
grand now.
They were like seven and nine I think
was when they first came out.
Yeah,
and it was like fully loaded.
Now they keep adding a little bit,
a little bit more.
They're a little bit over a hundred now,
but the way they handle is like it
defies physics.
It doesn't feel like the gt three
handles amazing,
but it makes sense that car does not
make sense because there's all sorts of
electronics going on.
It's four wheel drive.
It's three.
It's very heavy.
It's probably like eight or 900 pounds
heavier than my gt three.
About 3,900
pounds or something like that.
I think.
I think it's a fairly heavy car and
that's like part their strategy in
some sort of strange way,
but it fucking works.
That is an ungodly fast ride and it's
just hop in and go kart.
Tanner doesn't like it because it takes
so much.
He feels like a way from a driver at
that skill level,
but you and I are in fact not tanner
foust.
I don't feel like I.
I feel that same way,
but one of my favorite episodes of your
show was when he was racing with a
motorcycle around all these industrial
box core zero six
down in Long Beach.
It
was nuts is when you can watch someone
drift and entire cloverleaf onramp.
Yeah,
and I think the city of Long Beach try
to get mad at US afterwards.
Really saw all the stripes that we had
done.
And you're like,
no,
no.
You gave us permission.
Sorry.
They were mad because it was rubber on
the road.
That looks cool.
That's what I say.
Pussies.
I don't know what their deal is.
Died.
Yeah.
Fucking was a drift drift bike.
Right.
And he only had like three degrees of of
slip on it.
Still bad.
It is right here for the record.
But you just see how good a driver
tanner is in this video,
especially with those shitty dog shits.
God is fighting core vets.
Who the fuck allowed that?
That was such a glaring error on their
part to make this incredible car.
I mean ridiculously fast car.
And then give it these dog shit seats to
terrible.
I had a CEO sick for about five minutes.
So you.
It was awesome.
It was not.
Again,
I'm not a corvette guy.
Like you wouldn't,
you wouldn't see me get out of the car
and think that guy has got a vet because
I don't have like a gold chain not
wearing jean shorts.
Nowhere she.
Right.
Or George shorts,
if you will,
for their very popular thing.
Were they aware?
Do they do they do.
And I,
it was atomic orange.
I got it from my friend Kevin,
uh,
in Chicago.
Give me a killer deal on it.
And it was one of those cars at once.
You drove.
Once you got in that [inaudible] it was
a [inaudible],
atomic orange.
Everything about core vets change
because that.
I mean it's the same as that car.
It's just such.
It's a mean ass car so fast,
so fast,
so fun and really well balanced to where
those cars are shockingly well balanced.
It's just because it's plastic and
American sheets and the seats are dog
shit.
You just think like,
well this is a fucking terrible car,
but it's not if you.
If they just.
If someone,
if you took it somewhere and just had
some really good bucket seats installed
the ride experience and then the
steering wheel's dog shit to the
cavaliers.
Yeah.
That was always my beef.
You could get the same radio in the
corvette that you could in the last 10.
Now it's just not how that's supposed to
work.
No,
but they did fix that.
Yeah.
I mean the c seven c six zero six and a
GTR had an illegitimate child and that's
what they.
That's what they spit out.
He even made it better than anybody
anticipated.
Like the new [inaudible] is a
motherfucker a car.
I mean it a really incredible,
incredible car and that's just them
listening.
You know what?
You got to appreciate goodness.
They listened and they even engineered
it like way better than the other ones.
I mean the new corvette,
c seven corvette is a marvelous car.
It's a marvel of engineering.
It really is.
I mean,
it doesn't.
There's not a car under a half a million
dollars even compares to it,
you know,
when to get that zero six and they
finally.
They are.
Let's do it.
Yeah.
They finally figured it out.
The seats are perfect.
Like everything's great in it.
Tanner's good drivers.
I just went,
man.
Every time we would go out and do stuff
and people would say like,
why are you letting tanner beat you?
Just smiling,
talking.
I don't know if you noticed I was trying
my ass off.
I've actually not trying to let him beat
me.
I think people don't truly understand
the amount of skill and knowledge that's
involved in driving a car like that or
when he took that,
um,
the GT two around downtown La at nine,
it was that they closed down some
sections of downtown La and he had a
really recent model,
gt two,
which is just a stupendously fast car
and he was driving it during the day,
but it was too hot because it's turbo
charged and it just didn't really help.
So she was getting crazy.
Yeah.
So he took it.
They mean it was pretty fast,
I'm sure still.
Oh yeah.
But not fast enough and that's like his,
you know,
that's his dream car right there.
He's got a nine,
nine,
six,
six turbo.
Yeah.
He bought it from.
Somebody had built it up.
It had like seven and change hundred
horsepower at the wheels and the guy put
a really stiff clutch in their thought.
He had ruined the car.
Tanner bought it,
drove it home from,
I think he got an Arizona Change,
a clutch.
Took it and I think it's called bb buys
a place.
He took it and change a clutch,
did a bunch of little tuning on it,
so it's six and change it.
The wheels now and that sucker is so
stupid fast and just absolute screamer
will look how much better that looks.
Disgusting.
Magnus Walker.
Paint job.
That's the same car you're looking at
the same car,
but that car looks bitching like some
freak carbon makes everything better.
The carbon fiber hoods.
Pretty wicked.
It's just,
it's an amazing car.
I had a gt,
I'm a 19,
96 rather turbo,
just like his,
those same ones,
the nine,
nine,
six turbo.
But mine was a hunk of Shit.
Mine broke down five times and almost
queered me off of A.
I don't know if that's it.
Can you say about that?
I mean gay.
I was like,
ah.
It's too weird.
They just break too much.
I mean,
queer as an odd.
I wouldn't say queer it off.
I don't even know.
I said that.
I think I've ever said that before,
but I'm just butter coffees.
What it is.
It's in my blood.
But um,
the,
the car broke down five times,
like catastrophic failures,
like twice the shift,
linkage blue where the clutch,
like I go to put in the clutch and I
moved,
move the gear and there's just nothing
that the gear shifter just spinning
around in a circle,
nothing connected to it.
One time it blew at a red light and a,
it stuck in second gear.
So I just rubbed it really high and I
pulled out in second gear.
I drove to the porsche dealership in
second gear and that was the second time
they,
it.
So I was like,
what
the fuck?
What's happening?
Then they replace the engine once the
engine.
They didn't know what the fuck was.
It was making weird noises and like
we're going to replace the entire
engine.
Like okay,
great,
good.
Whatever.
Fucking year old car replaced the
engine,
that's this whole thing to the ground.
And then they um,
then the gas gauge broke on the highway.
I had half a tank of gas,
but I did not have a half tank.
And in the left lane on the [inaudible],
near the Hollywood bowl,
the motherfucker ran out of gas of man.
That's the worst.
Yeah,
it was his year.
There you are on the side of the road
and everyone knows you.
Huh?
Well,
I can't tell you a little secret.
There was a.
I saw a good looking food truck about
two minutes from here.
Yeah.
Uh,
we're getting a little lunch for him.
I was like,
oh,
it's swinging there.
And I caught just enough of the curb
with the tire that when the tire came
off of it,
the noise was so loud that I was like,
okay,
get back in.
Let's go.
We can stop here.
I bought a car from Toyota racing,
loaned me Alexis RCF,
beautiful car.
I'm not getting out at that point
because then I'm that guy who I just
don't.
You just don't need more of that in your
life.
Turns out cars don't.
Especially if they're like,
you're that guy from top gear.
Hey,
you just fucked up that car,
man.
I saw you hit that curb.
What happened?
There's nothing you can do about it.
If you can hit a fucking curb every now
and again,
here he is in downtown La,
going sideways around these regular
streets that gt two,
so say in the tunnels,
you people don't appreciate it.
Like what it takes to drive like that.
They don't really have to know when to
come in,
when to go out,
where the turn is when they hit the gas.
There's like so much knowledge and
experience that goes into driving a car
like that and the consequences or death.
There's not a lot of gray area.
Yeah.
This isn't a real game.
You're getting good at.
You're driving a fucking 600 horsepower
car.
The waist,
a little bit over 3000 pounds.
Have you ever gone in and either watched
her done any drifting?
No.
Oh my gosh.
You love the most.
It's just vehicular shenanigans in one
place.
Right.
And that's why like I can trip but my
transition suck.
Right.
Minefield.
Like I stole a car.
Where's tanner?
Like you could hold a cup of coffee and
never move it because he's just so good.
Smooth me in.
It's like when they come down to long
beach or Irwindale Fan,
I think that it's early and I was going
to be a mall now or something.
But yeah,
finally they,
they,
they fought that for years.
But watching what those guys in formula
drift can do is.
I mean it's the stuff we did in parking
lots in high school.
Right.
But now it's a sport and they're so
good.
I did a lot of that in high school
because we had snow.
So yeah,
are drifting with snow creative.
Like I learned how to drive from driving
in snow because that's when the asset
kicks out.
It's like that's the skills you need.
It's really the same skills.
It's why we pray for snow in the south.
It snow like five times in my life and I
bought some of the cars from top gear so
I don't know.
We built a four by four school bus was
jacked up on 44 is with a snowplow.
I don't know if you ever saw it.
It had a flame thrower on the roof.
Well,
I knew they were going to crush it and
cut it up because they couldn't sell it
to the public.
Let me buy it.
I'll take it home.
Shifted home to Georgia.
So got it tagged taking my daughters to
school.
We drive it around for Halloween.
Do you really still has a snow plow on
the front and as you can imagine like it
snowed once and like the last 10 years
in Georgia.
And we made the news because everybody
got on the interstate at the exact same
time.
So it melts the snow.
The fire blaster turns out there was a
Celica under their toys.
So yeah,
we left a note.
It will be fine.
It was in Maine.
That was in Caribou,
Maine at the old,
uh,
the air force base.
It's right there.
So there's Canada is just on the other
side of that shot and this is one of
those places where,
um,
I think they call it a minute men where
you had to be able to get from like
where you were sleeping to an airplane
in 60 seconds in case like Cold War.
Right?
So there's all these tunnels underneath
where we were shooting and we had to
have all sorts of clearance would be out
there.
It was awesome.
Whoa.
And then I bought the bus much as they
sold that to for a I,
I got,
I got a very good deal.
I got it costs more to ship at home.
It was a lot to ship it.
I'm not going to lie because you have to
put on a low boy cause no truck that
delivers cars can get through,
you know,
have like 13 or 14 clearance getting
across the country.
So when it's already at like 12 feet.
Right.
You have kind of a problem.
Did you think about driving it for about
five seconds?
I mean 44 super show offers.
I can't imagine what the mileage would
be like.
Two.
Yeah,
two months ago and there's 197,000
miles on it.
And Tanner drove and didn't kill it.
It now says the magic school bus on the
side.
I put a stereo in there.
It's really fun.
But we gassed it up,
got it ready for it to snow in January.
And we didn't even get rain at my house.
It was just,
it's so defeating year,
dude.
Snow driving is.
I mean,
that's just some of the best out there.
Parking lots and snow.
That's what dreams are made up.
Yeah.
That's where I learned how to drive in
snow in the parking lot.
It's just,
it's the best.
Yeah.
Because it's so gentle the way you're
going sideways.
It's like,
it doesn't feel like when you go in
sideways on concrete,
it feels very violent.
Right?
On paved surfaces.
But if you go in the snow,
it's like woo.
Wish I could remember a this girlfriend
that I had back in Boston,
um,
I took the car that I had to a parking
lot once and for like an hour,
all we did was like gun it.
And then I'd slam on the e brake.
I turned the wheel and slam on the
break.
We'd spin around in circles.
We were just laughing and laughing.
It was fun.
And that's really,
that's the car,
the car's fine.
That's basically drifting is because you
think about the beauty of your car takes
on concrete when you do that.
The other friction and everything that's
rubbing but on snow and you just,
you just glad there are ice driving
schools.
Tamar,
todd [inaudible] in Colorado for years.
So again,
one of the reasons he's so good at what
he does,
but it's basically like a little road
course they have and they wait for it to
snow and then they put a little water on
it and ice it over and you take BMW's
out there and learn how to handle a car
in the ice.
Like what a great idea is a great idea.
And apparently it really translates.
Sure.
One of the things I w I almost got a
motorcycle a long time ago,
but I saw a bunch of people crashed.
I saw two crashes and a friend of mine
saw somebody get hit,
some guy who was at a red light and
somebody was texting him this dude and
he went flying through the air and I was
like,
that's it.
Fuck that.
And my two friends that got hurt,
they got hurt pretty bad.
Um,
but I was thinking about getting one.
And my friend said,
who wrote all his life?
He said,
get a dirt bike,
said,
get a dirt bike and learn how to drive
in the dirt because when you,
when you have that loose surface,
you get used to the ass kicking out on
you and it becomes normal because it's
natural.
You don't panic.
So I think it's the same thing with snow
and ice and totally probably directly
translates driving on the ice.
I think so because it's,
again,
it's all of that,
you know,
it's the overseer,
the uninsured,
all of those things that you would feel
in a smooth,
safe environment you would feel you
would feel they're all.
He's drifting.
Yeah.
That's a,
that's a closely to each other.
That's Turk up front from the back.
Know who these people are.
Yeah.
Dude,
I love this.
This is my mama right here.
This is my son.
So he's from.
He lives up in New Hampshire.
Freddy's from Sweden I think,
but both of those cars.
So those start out Frederick Houseboat,
that's a front wheel drive sign,
TC converted to rear wheel drive.
It's got a turbo four cylinder and
they're Turks.
Car Is A.
has a turbo super swapping it gigantic
turbo.
It's a a really seriously.
I just love it.
It's just the most fun you can have in a
car,
but it's just going sideways.
It's basically these guys,
what they do is they have these clipping
points,
right,
and they try to get as close to the
clipping point is they can.
It has to do with their speed of entry,
the angle,
the car right,
and they've got this huge e-brake that
they've got the breaks or is big for the
rear wheels as they are for the front
because they've got a clutch,
kick it pulling on a lever right block,
you know that can block Mustang video,
which is amazing.
That four wheel drive Mustang call that.
Yes,
the Hunington guys,
but that's a funny name for that.
The Unicorn a yes that that Mustang is
such a bad memory jammer,
but you know what?
What those guys do in that precision.
Look at that fucking thing.
It's so calm and so the e brake is a big
part of being able to do that and right
the way they bring the car around.
So especially in drifting,
those guys have to get as close to each
others they can write while still
keeping the line,
trying to get as close to these
different like clipping points as they
can.
So he's slamming on the e brake,
right to make these turns and the way
these guys have to to use the clutch at
the same time they're using the e brake
to get it to slide without killing
everything.
And then they get back on a guy like
Vaughn gitten jr who drifts a Mustang.
He is full throttle the whole time in
module eight just with the clutch.
And that's like next level stuff that I
can't.
I can only do seven things at one time.
I can't have a 12th.
So one watching him go out there.
Tanner has A.
Tamar,
took a VW Passat,
convert it's rear wheel drive and use
that ls seven from zero six.
It's no,
it's basically like the Chevy,
a cookbook,
American Jewry,
and then they tune.
He's gotten nine nine to the wheels that
the chambers newpark wait a minute.
Nine the wheels.
And what kind of car is.
It looks like a Volkswagen Passat,
so on the outside it's a fucking shitty
Volkswagen community car in the inside
it has 900 horsepower to the wheels.
It's bad ass.
The most ridiculous thing I've ever
heard in my life.
I just wish Volkswagen would build
something like a little bit like that.
It would make them much cooler.
Now let me ask you this.
[inaudible] Mustang.
People are so weird that that can block
video.
What did they think about that car?
Because he took,
was it 65 or 65 or 66 and they basically
had to stretch it and make it kind of
fit and they turn into a four wheel
drive.
Did everybody freak out?
They lose the fucking power.
That car made the cover a hot rod
magazine,
so it transcended like people like me
that love import cars and in horsepower
it was like,
no,
this,
I'm just going to trump everyone with
this ridiculous car.
So I think that's one of those ones that
can also can kind of get away with stuff
like that because he's Ken can block and
he kinda just like,
you have to dig that.
He can do what he wants to do because he
made it work.
But yeah,
that's,
that's tanner sought what a ridiculous
human being 900 Horsepower v eight
Volkswagen bug sot that's an ela.
So.
So He's,
he's a,
he's racing in Daytona this weekend.
He does that global rally cross series,
which is a lot of funds basically him
and Ken Block and about 10 other people
wrecking the crap out of each other.
There's not a single person out there
that knows how to pass besides tanner
that gets them.
It's really fun to watch,
but it's just,
it's insanity.
These cars are so I just don't
understand why.
Like why would you do that to an ugly
car?
Like,
I mean why wouldn't he do that to a car
that's like a really cool car.
Like why do this?
He's sponsored by sponsored by
Volkswagen.
So he races their stuff in GRC and then
did some world rallycross stuff with
him.
But the coolest part is that he
convinced them to let him do it.
Like that's what I love.
Yeah.
Because I have.
So I have a scion xb at home,
like the little box that the same people
that built that car.
Papadakis racing built this one and my
Johan used to own it.
It's converted a rear wheel drive.
The back of the car thinks it's a mark
for supra,
like complete sub frame,
just like the car.
And then it has a two jz super swap in
there with a six speed.
And Yo had a line lock put in.
If you look up,
uh,
if you look up Dta Xb,
you would find that.
But papadakis racing Stefan postdoc
right away.
Super Guy like coolest nerd you'll ever
meet.
He's like the,
just,
he's like the doctor,
you know,
he's like the mad scientist up there,
but this has a line lock so you can step
on the brakes and hold the button and it
holds the front brakes.
Right?
So then you rev it up,
drop the clutch.
And it's a smoke show.
Adam have cy on that.
Looks like a front wheel drive car.
That's hilarious.
That's really fun stuff out there.
If you make it to Atlanta,
you got to come drive it.
It's really fun.
I get it.
But the cars are ugly.
That's what I don't understand.
Taking these ugly cars and turn them
into these amazing driving vehicles like
wouldn't you want to invest that same
amount of energy and is something that
looks great now?
Well that's a fair point.
I hadn't really thought about it from
that.
For me,
when I saw this car I in and I was like,
oh well that's,
that's it.
Because for me,
I've got three daughters,
right?
So I can't,
like I can't have [inaudible] because
that's a date night card.
Right.
Beyond that I can't afford one.
But let's pretend for a second I could
afford it.
And I love it.
I still can't have one because I just
don't need just a car for me and my
wife.
Like I want my girls to be able to come
with me.
So that's Cya.
They can ride with me.
I can have three car seats in there.
God go thousand miles there.
They're tiny bit embarrassed by it
because it's really.
It sounds great.
It had magnaflow do nice custom exhaust
when I was here.
Right.
It's got a great growl to it,
but when the boost starts to build,
it's got this huge single turbo.
I mean it's.
It'll pay you back in your sheets for I
think it's like four 25 to the rear
wheels and a car's very light,
maybe 3000 pounds.
They cut a lot of stuff out.
Things safety wise,
the best fucking bread,
but it's a lunchbox drove around a
lunchbox with wheels,
but it's got air conditioning because I
wanted my wife to ride in it with me.
So when a bought it out here,
I took it to my friends at tr,
Dionne Hill,
the Guy Chuck.
I said,
can you see,
okay,
it looks like there's a vintage vintage
era as this company that makes like old
hot rod kits.
Right?
So there was a control panel for vintage
air thing in there.
And I said,
can you check and see like if we could
make it.
And have air conditioning.
He looked,
he's like,
yeah,
just going to bolt up a supra ac
compressor and charge it.
You'll be fine for 20 horse at four,
25 horsepower.
The thing that looks like insane,
like vintage air.
So important because they made those old
hot rods livable because if you drove in
one of those old hot rods,
most of them didn't have any AC.
And if they did,
it was a joke.
Yeah,
it was not.
It was like the swamp cooler of what you
put underneath.
But my wife will actually ride in stuff
with me.
That makes a big difference as you
understand.
I do understand that.
Makes.
That definitely makes a big difference.
What were you doing before you were
hosting top gear?
So they found me and found you.
I felt like I would say so I was uh,
you know,
when a man and a woman,
when they find each other,
they found me,
believe it or not,
from,
from Youtube,
from a clip that somebody had loaded up
that I was traveling with a the speed
channel.
I started with them in,
Oh,
five from a craigslist ad.
Love craigslist,
I'm,
I'm the number one craigslist fan.
Uh,
I found this add on there that just
national motorsports company was looking
for a marketing guy that could be an MC.
And so I sent all my stuff in and it was
one of those terrible interviews.
I'm not going to get this job.
And then two weeks later like,
hey,
go down to Daytona.
So you got the Gig.
So I go down to Daytona and I,
I like kind of knew a little bit about
Nascar,
you know,
knew Petey and Wallace Earnhardt I know
much else besides that.
Went to school for marketing.
So all of a sudden I want to be around
cars.
That was always my plan.
So it started as a Dj for this big speed
stage.
It would go to all the races.
So I was out here at Fontana twice a
year.
I said all the other races and that I
kept begging him to let me do something
on TV.
And they finally let me a year later.
And then I think a year after that,
oh,
seven,
uh,
John Schneider from the Dukes of hazzard
came to Atlanta Motor speedway to be the
Grand Marshall.
And they said,
hey,
would you do this little piece with this
guy?
Um,
he does kind of lighter side of racing.
Yeah,
just do something.
We found a general lead to borrow and we
shot this whole piece riding around in
the generally in the whole time I refuse
to call him John.
I would only refer to him as Bo.
And I kept being like,
so Bo,
I'm daisy is not your real cousin.
Right?
He was like,
no,
that's a,
that's an actress Katherine Bach.
Like,
but so like,
if she was not your real cousin,
like you guys ever,
you know,
go to dinner or see a movie or.
And so he starts out,
he's like,
yeah,
we're good friends.
Really enjoyed it.
And so some a race fan who,
I don't know who loaded that clip onto
youtube illegally,
this Guy John Heseltine,
who is our executive producer,
saw it in A.
I don't know if he was here still in the
UK at that point.
And he was like,
this kid might be funny.
He was looking at everybody who had been
on TV for cars and like the last 10
years.
And so this re,
the craziest part about my life is that
this person who I don't know who loaded
this video up is the person that like I
feel like is the reason I got to talk
here.
Because you ever find that person?
No,
I don't know who it is because the video
got kicked off because it was
copywritten.
Well,
I guarantee you that person is going to
find out that they got you.
That somehow through the grapevine I
want to take them to a race.
I want to say I don't want to do
something.
Like I didn't have an agent.
I was in the phone book like I was just
a kid trying to hustle and try to figure
out how am I going to make this TV thing
works.
Great Story.
Thanks man.
That's amazing.
I love craigslist.
Yeah,
I guess you should.
They.
That's what I mean.
It's a little.
Craigslist is like a little bit filthy
dirty,
but human beings
all about where everything's.
Everything's got a little bit turns on.
It brings us a little bit of poop.
This is a little bit.
Yeah.
Well,
there's a lot of weird,
you know,
men seeking women seeking men seeking,
seeking,
seeking that out will be honest.
That.
What is it,
um,
missed connections.
What's that?
That is this section of craigslist where
it's like,
Hey,
saw you in the coffee shop.
You ordered the Latte.
I had the muffin that some of the best
reading.
If you're bored or if you're a person
that reads a lot when you're taking a
dump,
that's,
that is joy.
It's like people who've seen too many
tom hanks movies and believe that they
just missed out on the one they saw her
older,
that pumpkin spice lattes,
pumpkin spice lattes.
I knew it was her and I just,
I didn't have the courage,
but now I do and I need a finer.
You honestly,
you're going to have to look at these
because some of them are so we forget
that because you probably don't spend
time with like my friends are just
pretty normal people.
I don't spend time with people that are
genuinely just out of their mind crazy
and that's an entire section for those
people.
We had a guy like that on fear factor
once and he met a girl at a cod,
believe it was at a concert and spoke to
her briefly and wanted to win fear
factor because he knew that she was the
one and he needed to find her again and
he'd spent some insane amount of time
and money going around the city and
where he met her putting up flyers and
say put up all these flyers and you
know,
all those people that contacted him that
weren't,
that girl,
you know,
that were fucking with him.
And he was like super determined.
But he had done it for like a couple of
years and they thought it was funny when
we first talked about having this guy on
the show.
Like he's got a great story.
Good story.
So I heard the story I go to imagine
that was your fucking sister.
Imagine if that was your daughter.
I imagine that was your girlfriend.
That's not a great story.
He's nuts and you know,
who knows like where he's going to take
it.
Right.
You know,
who knows if he's murder,
suicidal,
you know,
it's in.
What if she just.
What if he said to her like,
Hey,
can I get a Napkin?
Sure.
What if that was the entire conversation
was a very brief conversation.
I forget the nature of the conversation,
but it was extremely brief,
but I remember being really creeped out
by him really creeped out.
Like when we had him on the show,
because there was a lot,
there was a lot of decision making that
went into getting on those shows that I
didn't agree with.
A lot of people made it onto the show
that I was like,
fucking really,
you want to put this guy on tv?
Are you out of your mind?
This is a crazy person.
Like there was a guy that I almost got
into a fist fight with,
like I had to restrain him and it was
the same thing.
It was a guy he beat his girlfriend up
on one one TV show.
He threw her to the ground on a TV show
and attack some fucking guy on vh one
and then got in my face and I was like,
Jesus fucking Christ.
And I said to them like,
why are you putting these crazy fucks
that,
you know,
are crazy Fox on TV?
Like,
do you understand that this is like,
you're responsible,
this is not a smart thing to do.
What did the producers say to that?
Um,
they didn't give a fuck,
right?
They're trying to,
they're trying to make money and the way
to make money is to have crazy people on
tv and that's it.
You know,
in my point of view was like,
I had hosted,
you know,
and these people were kind of dangerous
and you know,
you're on rooftops with him and shit in
downtown La.
So that's a 30 fucking stories,
right?
There's a lot of weird shit that could
happen on those rooftops,
you know,
someone could push somebody,
somebody could jump,
and we had some like really nutty fucks
that made it on that show,
but that guy that got the guy almost got
in a fight with that guy that was trying
to find that girl they stood out like
cheese is Christ because I looked in his
eyes while I was talking to them and
there was nobody there.
It was just this missed of consciousness
who's like a child in a man's body who
thought he was in a movie and thought,
you know,
that he's just gonna keep going until he
finds the ratio and as the show went on,
you know,
a couple of days in and hanging out with
this guy,
you got deeper and deeper into who he
really is and he's creepier and creepier
and weirder and weirder.
And then even the producers,
by the third day it was like,
we made a mistake.
We shouldn't have this guy on the show.
We're like,
we only hope that it doesn't ever right
by bad.
We only hope we never find that girl,
you know,
can I,
can I ask,
because I was such a big fan.
What,
what was Newsradio lack?
Because when I watched that show and
saw,
I mean,
what an amazing group of people you got
to work with like that.
When you look back on that time,
like how does that rank?
Because you've done some really cool
stuff.
Turns out for sure.
It,
it fucked me up at queered me off of
sitcoms forever.
Really?
I never do another [inaudible] because
it will never be that good because it
was so.
It was just so lucky and I had gotten to
do a show before that for Fox.
That was terrible.
It was called hardballs a baseball set
comp.
Okay.
And it wasn't hard.
It wasn't horrible because of the
creators.
It was one of those situations were
really funny.
Guys who wrote with married with
children,
they wrote off for the simpsons.
They created a show and then the show
became,
once it went on television,
they took it away from them and then
they brought in some hacks and it just
became.
It was grow,
so that got canceled really quick
because I went from that to news radio,
which was the total opposite.
Sure.
The guy running the show at genius,
the writers were fantastic that the
scripts were insanely funny and the
people were so talented and I had no
acting experience.
I had taken a few acting lessons because
they forced me into taking it.
When the game me this big development
deal,
no way.
It was all based on stand up and all of
a sudden the mountain Hollywood and I'm
totally feel like a fraud.
I totally feel like I don't belong and
I'm on the greatest outcome of all time.
It was.
It was madness,
but it was.
It was one of the greatest things about
it was that it never got any
recognition,
so no one ever got a big head because it
never.
No one ever got famous from it.
It was just.
We barely survived every year and the
one year that I thought that we weren't
going to get canceled was the year we
got canceled because it was.
I was like,
well,
they didn't cancel us after Phil Hartman
got murdered.
Right.
We're probably not going to get
canceled.
Right.
But then it just didn't work.
It just didn't work with Jon Lovitz.
It's not that it does love,
it isn't funny.
It's just,
it was,
it was fucked.
It was just,
he was dead.
It was the whole thing was just,
you know,
even though there was andy,
Dick was still on the show and Vicky
Lewis and Maura tierney was still
amazing and Dave Foley is still.
It was like having filled dead was
always going to be a part of what was
wrong.
It just didn't work.
It was just,
it was
time was such a,
you know,
it was,
um,
it really interesting landscape for tv
because there weren't a ton.
There's also like,
if we look back at that time,
I don't remember a lot of other shows
that I really liked and could sit there
because it was such a good ensemble of
so many people that brought different
things.
Whereas normally there's like there's
Alpha male and then there's two other
sort of people.
I felt like that was a fantastic mix of
people.
It was a group.
It was a very weird.
None of us were all outliers.
We're all Weirdos.
Like even phil was a Weirdo de
[inaudible],
as weird as it gets.
Dick's the weirdest human that's ever
walked the face of the planet.
I was weird.
I didn't belong.
No one belonged.
You know,
we all had some weird bond because of
that though.
We all felt like we didn't fit in.
And so like when we would do,
like we'd have guests stars,
it would be like real actors.
We'd be like,
what's this methodology that he's doing?
We would have guest stars and they would
like talk after talk like industry talk,
just a way that actors talk.
They pick up this,
uh,
this sort of acquired vernacular.
And one of the things that I say when
they meet someone,
they say,
Hey,
nice to meet Ya.
Like you did.
And I do normal stuff.
They say,
good to see you because they're hoping
that they didn't meet you and forget you
because they don't give a fuck about
you.
There are so constantly they're
concentrating on themselves wholly and
exclusively,
so to mitigate that,
what they do is they say,
good to see you,
and so it becomes this thing that they
all say.
So when you meet someone they say,
good to see you and they're an actor,
fucking run.
They've adopted this actor think shirts
and they would read like the,
what I would call the devil's rag,
like the Hollywood reporter.
They would read that shit and get angry.
God,
how does he have a show?
how does she have a show?
And they like that shit would happen.
Like when we have guest stars that we
would like.
So it was a weird combination of a bunch
of people that were just Weirdos.
They were just,
they didn't,
they didn't fit the mold of standard sit
calm and no one went on to do a sitcom
since none of them.
I didn't think about that.
No one did.
I'm Vicky did one for a little bit that
didn't work out.
I'm Stephen Root,
went on to do amazing work and office
space and he was in um,
he was fantastic in that fucking hbo.
What does that,
uh,
the uh,
Hbo Documentary of the HBO show.
What the fuck is his show with,
um,
about liquor,
about bootleg liquor sales.
Boardwalk Empire.
Yeah,
boardwalk empire.
He was amazing in that.
I mean,
he's just a fucking brilliant actor.
He was the one guy that wasn't himself
on the show to like,
like what they would do is they take the
wackiest shit about like Andy and
exaggerated wackiest shit about me and
exaggerated.
But Stephen Root,
like if you met him,
he's nothing like Jimmy James.
Jimmy James says this wacky character
that he developed,
but he's just a brilliant,
brilliant actor,
you know,
just to the bone.
I was listening to you one day and you
were talking about the difference and I
can't,
I'm sorry,
I can't remember if it was stand up that
I was watching you or or the podcast,
but you're talking about the difference
between a comedians and actors and how
essentially the actors have to get up
every day and pretend to be someone
else.
I never really like.
They don't know who they are.
Whereas comedians like know who they are
and they.
That's what they talk about,
but even in my limited experience in
that town I don't like.
I don't really like it.
I don't ever have to wake up and wonder
who to be.
I can't imagine what that's truly liked
to to dive into someone so much that you
essentially get paid to lose yourself
each time and then you have to move on
and do it again.
Like that's a lot harder.
Will think that Steven Brute,
who's the one guy who did that on the
show is he doesn't have any problems
knowing who he is.
He's a really nice guy.
Super easy to like.
You get to know him.
He's like very warm and friendly,
easy going guy and he just loves the
craft of creating a character like it's.
He has the most pure intention other
than any actor person I've ever met,
like his,
his love is really of creating,
you know that Steve Buscemi character
that you remember from that movie that
you know,
that Russell Crowe character,
they like fucking nailed it,
you know,
like that.
He just loves nailing a character.
He's just a master actor.
He's just a master at that and there's a
difference between those people and the
people that just want to be famous and
they want to be famous as an actor.
So there's,
there's a lot of weirdness in that
craft.
There's a,
there's a giant percentage of the people
that want to do it are massively damaged
people,
which is why they feel like they should
be famous.
It's like they got fucked over when they
were children or when they were,
you know,
adolescents or whatever the fuck
happened to them.
That led them to have this insatiable
desire to be thought of as special.
And once they get it,
that's when they become maniacs.
Like everybody's heard the story of the
person who's got their own [inaudible].
Then they become maniacs.
I mean I've,
I've met them,
I've seen them,
you know,
I've talked to them.
I had Roseanne on and she was telling me
about how fucking crazy she went.
When she got sick on,
she was like,
I was fucking crazy.
Completely crazy.
Like she'll,
she'll tell you.
And she was a great standup comic in my
opinion.
Like one of the top 10 greatest of all
time,
like Roseanne's in my,
as far as like revolutionary influential
stand ups I think for,
for time,
like she's
a top 10 and she was in,
she went crazy.
She,
they all go crazy.
It's like she seems totally chill now
though.
Yeah.
That's just perspective over time or
what.
But I think it's that she got rid of Tom
Arnold that helped mom.
Guy Is,
he is crazy.
Every cycle.
You know why he married her?
Get the fuck out of here.
That's ridiculous.
Just me,
like,
I feel like that's one of those guys,
if you watched like 12 hours of just his
life,
you'd be like,
Shit.
Yeah,
it's crazy.
I met him.
I did the best damn sport show when he
was on.
He's a nice guy.
Yeah.
But you know,
he took his shot.
He had to do what he had to do,
married Roseanne,
did what he had to do and then it didn't
work out.
It's weird,
man.
Some days my wife will be like,
Hey,
can we um,
can we hang this painting?
And I'm like,
ah,
probably like the kids going to bed
early.
Like it's a different negotiation I
think when you're married.
But like his was like,
you might have to marry Rosanne bar to
have a career.
That's just,
I'm saying she's lovely.
That's just a different kind of
negotiation for the record.
That was,
yeah,
he sold his soul.
I know what you're saying.
Thank you.
Did.
Yeah,
like I want to say that you,
like,
you will trade sex for hanging up the
painting.
Sure.
You'll make this house and I get it.
I get it.
That's a good move.
But that's like everybody wins.
It's like nobody got hurt there and you
love.
Everybody was happy.
He sold us all,
but he,
but he got out of it.
He's alive.
You get a refund on your soul,
like what do you think happens at that
point?
Or do you feel like it's going to be
misses Roseanne?
Dom on the devil,
he has a very steep price based on
everything.
Big,
big number out here,
man.
I mean,
she's a super talented woman,
but she was 300 pounds and you know,
he did what he had to do.
What do you think?
Um,
what was,
what was her husband on that show?
John?
Uh,
John Goodman?
Yeah.
Amazing.
One of those guys that I watch,
I can't from from big Dan Teeg in
brother where art thou to just anything
he does.
He's almost people.
I want you to go ski that fucking
character from the bigger basket.
It wasn't even.
You're not even Jewish man.
I don't turn on the TV.
Turn on the stove and I sure as Shit
fucking roll.
And he would pull out when someone
violate bowling rules by the only one
that gives a shit about the rules.
What a great fucking character is.
Just.
He's amazing man.
By three o'clock with Nail Polish.
Like what?
How do you channel?
I'm finishing my coffee.
There was a conviction of that being
that crazy.
He just created a.
well,
first of all,
Coen brothers movies are my ultimate
favorite movie.
Like when I saw Donald Trump was running
for president the other day,
I say we live in a Coen brothers movie.
It's official.
Seriously,
because like his fucking Slob,
this is goofy Slob is going to run his
ego just pouring out of his ears.
He ever met him.
No.
Weird dude.
And I'm sure we met him.
We did something on top care where
you're trying to convince him to like
pick one of these cars that,
that we had each pick for a celebrity.
We found out like halfway through,
it's for Donald Trump.
And he basically was like,
uh,
this guy looks gay.
He's looking at tanner was like,
I think this car,
you look gay.
So the car's probably for gay person at
whatever tailored to.
I don't remember what kind of car he had
picked the teams.
Like what did you tell Donald Trump to
make fun of me that I look like I'm in.
That's just what he does.
He just went for it and then he was
like,
Adam,
I'll take your.
Was it trying to be funny?
I think he was,
but he's one of those people that I
don't think he can hear other people.
I think maybe he can read lips a tiny
bit,
but like he walks into the room and all
you do is you look at his hair,
man,
you can't.
There is nothing an asteroid hit the
earth next door and you'd still be like,
man,
what's going on up there to that?
Like how do you get up every day?
And you say,
yeah,
this is the look weirds me out.
Here's you and him weirds me out is.
It's not like he's going bald,
is he?
I don't think so.
I think he's just,
he just moves it around in some weird
way or doesn't want to cut it or it's a
signature look,
but it seems like there's too much hair
up there for him to be going bald.
It's just I ain't been there in real
life.
So what do you remember the hair spray
that had looked like hair follicles?
I don't know if it's like that's in
there.
It's not a,
it's not a rug.
It's in the book.
It's just,
you can't take your eyes off of it.
I just don't understand.
I mean,
he can't think it looks good dudes.
So in a weird,
because New York doesn't actually like
him that much,
but like some.
Right.
But you like him?
He's a Dick.
He puts his face on everything,
but he's like,
he's so aggressive with his,
like stickiness.
Like I remember he had this feud with,
with the,
um,
with the fuck's her name.
Who was it with?
God Damn it.
Oh,
with Rosie O'donnell,
that's who it was.
His,
his feud with Rosie O'donnell and he was
on know TV's like Rosie is a losers.
Basically.
She's a loser.
Right,
okay.
Let's think about who's listening to
this.
You're talking about a multi millionaire
movie star world famous comedian and
you're talking in a camera's on you and
it's broadcasting to the rest of the
world and you're saying this
multimillionaire world famous comedian
is in fact the loser.
What are we?
Right?
What the fuck am I?
What am I?
If she's a loser,
like what standards do you have and how
do you feel about yourself?
Right?
You know,
like this is just nonsense.
He,
that guy needs mushrooms in his life in
a bad way,
is to get in a tent in the middle of the
desert and eat a giant bag of mushrooms
and really find out how the rest of the
world sees him.
Sweat it out.
Oculus,
I think he needs to go to a sears and
pick out a washer and dryer like a
Thursday night.
Like I think he may be normal person.
Maybe just feel like what life is kind
of like.
But I like those.
Those are the kind of people that I see
in like his wife,
um,
malaria,
some of them,
whatever her name is,
Larry,
I'm.
That's one of those girls that I would
look at her and then look at him and
think,
there's no way you guys have ever had a
conversation right now.
You look at her,
you look at him and you go,
do you know Tom Arnold?
Is He did what you're doing.
He did it with a woman.
Right?
I see what you're doing.
I get you.
It's all right.
Hey,
look,
it's better that than working at
Wendy's.
If these are your odds.
It's true.
What do you want to do?
Do you get trump's dick or get a lot of
money?
Do you get the free frosties?
Donald?
I've,
I gotta give you that,
but your wacky hair,
if you're into that,
it's because you're in a what?
Tens?
Yeah.
Who's into that?
Who's in the hutches mouth shut.
I was thinking.
I was really thinking for her.
Like if you're really into.
Oh,
she's not into that.
I don't know.
She's probably pilled up.
She'd probably just stays on a steady
oxycontin drip throughout the entire
day,
just just stays mellow and weird looking
at a gelatinous facial thing he's got
going on too.
Was really the shoulder rolls into his
neck colors.
Really interesting here too.
I'm telling you,
I meet him.
I hope not necessarily that you meet
them,
but just that you're in in your life.
You end up in the same room and just
test my theory.
I honestly,
I couldn't look away the moment if I did
meet him.
The moment he gets Dickie,
I will grab your fucking hair.
I'm just telling you right now and I
will find out what's going on.
So you might want to shut the fuck up.
What are you going to do?
Beat me up.
Call security.
I better get your hair before security
gets here.
I Bet I get to your fucking hair,
dude.
Don't get ticket with me just to lead in
the later stages of my life or whatever
where I'm at.
I don't have any patience for people
like that.
Just don't have any desire.
I get it.
Like,
uh,
you know,
that's the reason why he's so
successful.
I mean,
you don't get to be a super fucking
billionaire.
Real estate mogul has his name on every
building dot trump towers.
Right?
You don't get that unless you have that
sort of an attitude.
So I guess I understand.
Stay there history,
put us up there once for the upfronts.
And uh,
I opened the little like mini bar and
his face was on the vodka for me.
I was like,
this feels like too much,
bro.
I feel like you've got to draw a line
somewhere or you just go for it.
Just go for it.
If you just keep going like the further
and deeper you go into the crazy ego,
swimming pool becomes like warmer water
because it gets better.
Is that the more he can be like the Walt
Disney of total douchebag,
real estate moguls,
is that.
It was,
it felt like Disney world.
I couldn't escape his face.
He's got steaks,
trump steaks.
Look above that job.
I think those are made from a manatees
in endangered species.
Polar bear stakes.
Yeah.
Right,
right.
When they get sad about the fucking
icebergs melting,
they shoot him in the fucking head and
cut them up,
drag them down in New York and he's ever
had a hot dog cart.
Yeah,
I'm sure he has.
I mean a,
uh,
like all bullshit aside.
Like you gotta he went fairly bankrupt
and then built it right back up again.
Good for him.
I mean he really did.
He hit a point in our lifetime where he
like basically was worth what we're
worth,
you know,
so it went down to almost nothing and
then he just shot right back up to being
that guy again.
There was like one week where he
thought,
can I,
can I go to the grocery store?
Do I need to wait a couple days before I
go?
And then he's like,
okay,
you want me to be a millionaire?
Then he,
I think never stop being a millionaire I
think,
but it got down to like a million.
But he might have had a lot of debt to.
I forget what the entire story was,
but it was,
there was a store that I've read in one
of those magazines,
esquire in New York or something like
that and they were essentially saying
that what he's doing right now is
pretending that he's rich and then if
you look at like the amount of debt that
he had,
but he knew how to get rich.
I like that knows what the fuck he's
doing.
You just.
And I always wonder like,
do you like to be a Michael Jordan?
Don't you have to be kind of crazy,
you know,
truly that Goddamn damn good at
basketball and to be that fucking deal
making son of a bitch,
don't you have to be a real asshole.
I think you,
I think you have to trade in like,
okay,
look,
he claimed his network was 9 billion.
We figure is close to 4 billion
[inaudible] billion to be exact,
but this is,
this is recently now,
right?
This is yesterday.
Yeah,
but this is like,
look,
even if he's worth 4 billion or knight,
who gives a fuck?
He's a goddamn billionaire.
You know,
he wasn't a while ago at one point in
time,
I want to say like maybe 15 years ago,
maybe 20,
something like that.
He had hit a,
like a really a really bad spot and
there was a,
an issue with him,
like opening up golf courses,
look some golf course in Scotland and
this one guy was fighting it and this
one guy,
like he had land that was outside of the
golf course and they wanted to buy him
out and he wouldn't sell and it became
this huge issue.
Who are,
you know,
Donald Trump's like,
this guy's a loser.
He wants to show me his property.
And the guy's like,
I don't give a fuck about him.
This is my house man fucking stone.
But it was,
it was a fascinating thing.
It's like this,
this insane pursuit of just ungodly
wealth and that's what he does.
That's his thing and now he's going to
run for president.
It's a weird man.
I'm all about keeping the lights on,
but sometimes you watch those people
that don't.
They don't know what you know.
There has to be this good balance of
work.
Hustle and drive in enjoyment,
like if you're just doing stuff all the
time and you can't find anything good
out of life,
you should probably just check up a
little bit.
Maybe he does find good out of life.
They asked me to be on that celebrity
apprentice thing.
I thought about it for a second,
but I would have been great man.
I'm not into that man.
I just,
I don't like those shows.
I don't,
I don't like those fake scenarios work,
any of that just didn't seem appealing
to me and it wasn't a fuck load of
money.
It wasn't enough money where I was like,
hmm.
But it also,
I don't,
I don't enjoy those kinds of.
Would dance with the stars or you have
no fucking chance.
Not a chance in hell.
That's hard.
By the way.
I did a part in that movie.
Zookeeper and I had to learn how to
dance.
Me and Leslie Bibb,
we,
uh,
we did this,
this dance scene where we had,
I had to learn how to dance for fucking
weeks,
had to take dance lessons.
I was like,
that's awesome.
You know,
and they were like,
you should totally do dancing with the
stars.
Like fuck you dude.
No chance.
And now it's not even dancing with the
stars.
It's like dancing with the,
used to be stars like a long time ago.
The Internet sensations,
dancing with the people.
You kind of know who they are.
Like dancing with the people who someone
out there knows that the bachelor guy
was just all there.
I don't know.
I don't have a nice.
Whereas um,
he was from Iowa that,
those,
those are the people that are.
I'm proud.
Like when I go to the supermarket and I
see us weekly and I look at the cover,
what I love is want to look at the
cover.
I don't know anybody.
My good.
I don't know who the fuck are these
people?
You know?
Dominic is mad a debra,
debra,
who's dominate,
right?
Talking about good.
I'm glad.
I don't know.
I'm glad I'm out of that cultural loop.
It's strange,
man.
I'm not sure why.
I'm sure you're thinking about this all
the time.
I'm just not sure why people care about
some of the people that we do that it's
not really that we care.
It's that they broadcast people.
This is what I've thought about this
long and hard for a long time when you
have something like television and it's
something that is a,
just a natural thing that people come
home,
they turn it on and they sit there and
they badge.
I have children too and uh,
you know,
like if I want my kids to chill for a
second and just like sit down,
like if I need to do something,
look,
daddy has to make a business call.
So I'm going to put on one episode of a
show.
What show do you want to watch?
And then they'll sit down.
They fucking Zombie out,
right for that 20 minutes or 20 minutes,
whatever.
The shows on their jaws open up and they
sit there.
I want a drink.
Okay,
get a drink,
here's your drink,
here's a chip.
You want some chips?
Okay,
here's your snack cheese stick.
I'll be right over here if you need me.
And I know they're not going anywhere,
right,
but there's something that happens when
people watch tv,
they just lock in.
Well if you get used to that thing being
on while you'll watch almost anything.
And that's how keeping up with the
Kardashians,
it's still on the air because people sit
down there and they watch.
They just sit there.
I was getting to buy this for us,
but then I couldn't find it and I was
like,
oh my God,
this is sun knowing and I'm watching it,
watching it.
I'll be in a hotel
room when it comes on and if they edit
it quick enough where it's like one
scene to the next scene,
one scene,
the next scene.
They're like,
I'm watching a little ping pong match
with my eyeballs.
For whatever reason I lock in.
I know their names,
I know their.
I know their names.
I know the why.
If I look at the poor Bruce Jenner
bastard before it became a woman,
I know about all those people for no
reason.
There's not a goddamn thing they've ever
said.
I've been.
It's been interesting to me.
This is not a content thing.
It's not a quality thing.
It's not a.
They have these.
If they're engaging,
they're these amazing points.
They're very unique individuals.
Now.
There's none of that.
There's none of that like because the
show I really love,
it's called life below zero.
Ever seen that show?
No,
I feel like I've heard of that.
So all these crazy fucks that live north
of the arctic circle,
above subsistence living.
This one woman that we had on the show
named Sue Akins and she lives 200
fucking miles plus above the arctic
circle in this place where you're not
allowed to have permanent structure.
So she has tents that she built up there
and like these,
these,
these covered,
you know,
circular tents.
It snows like a fuck.
There's wolves everywhere.
She was attacked by a grizzly bear.
Okay.
Broken her hip bone in your skull,
broke her leg.
She went back,
shot the bear and ate it.
Okay.
That's a person I'm interested in
seeing.
You know what I mean?
Pitches gangster as fuck.
She lives crazy.
She's crazy,
but she's awesome.
She's a really.
It's really unique.
Like when I had her on the show,
sitting and talking to her because she's
so personable.
You had her here.
Yeah,
so she knows there are other places in
the world she could live.
She likes it up there.
She really does.
I think people like weird shit.
Some people like living in Florida,
they like it.
They like Florida,
you know?
They just decide like I'm staying here.
Like it.
She loves it up there.
She loves the solitude.
She loves the fact that she has to rely
on ourself and she.
But she's,
she's a unique human.
She has a very unique perspective.
She's very intelligent and very.
She's very strong and independent and so
that's the person that I want to hear
talk.
Sure.
She's just unique.
Don't get any of that from,
oh,
we went there and oh my God,
this is so annoying.
The air conditioning was not working
properly and those are not my favorite
shoes and they hate you watching
nonsense.
But as long as that nonsense is on
television,
certain amount of people will watch
nonsense.
Nonsense in the environment of dating.
He's like always exciting to people like
who's hooking up with who is he going to
be with her or was he going to be there,
she going to feel rejected or is he
going to feel rejected or is she going
to reject him,
but then he rejects her.
God,
it's amazing.
There's suffering.
There's panic.
People are freaking out right now
because it came out that I guess whoever
the current Bachelorette is might have
slept with a bunch of the guys.
I've been telling sex with a man.
I've been telling my wife years.
I was like,
you know everybody on that show,
so can often.
She's like,
no,
it's not.
It's not like that.
One of our,
one of our directors on top gray sky,
gary was was one of the directors for
the first couple of seasons.
There's a vault with footage every.
There's a camera everywhere and we feed
these people tons of alcohol and hardly
any food.
There's.
There's video of everybody humping like
there's just a whole closet full of
weird videos of these people hooking up.
Find Out who Caitlin sleeps with and the
surprising motivation.
Click that fucking tab.
You shut that tab off.
I don't want to ever see that again.
You keep that out of my life.
Jamie.
You may have to clear out the Google
history just to.
Just to jumble clear your history.
Jamie.
That's what.
This is enough.
I can't do it.
I won't.
I miss the days of of you remember the
real world and MTV like people's first
started sort of look at like,
Oh,
I guess that people just sit around and
drink all day.
They might get into fights about
something that's seemingly important.
Well,
just as a bit of history,
the guy who produced the real word world
was the producer fear factor.
Might not know that.
Yeah.
Mac units.
Great Guy,
and he saw some.
He was the guy that forced the people in
there drinking.
Come on a fear factor.
Was it from donkey?
Sure.
It was his idea.
He laughs at me when I told him he
shouldn't do it.
I'm like,
you shouldn't have people drink.
Come.
He's laughing.
Why not?
They're going to do it.
Don't do it.
Don't fucking do it.
And I didn't watch a ton of the show
because I was just against like,
why would you eat exactly horse's anus?
I'm going to be honest with you.
I didn't watch it either.
I watched it maybe three times,
entire fucking hundred and 48 episodes.
I enjoyed some of the,
like the,
the physical things that people don't
have to feel like I get why those were
cool.
And I don't know what like Lake y'all
used for some stuff.
Stay at mostly boy,
that sucker looked,
had looked cold and it looked rough some
days.
How cold does it get?
Were living in California?
Two shits down.
It must have been 60 degrees in their
water was like 75 degrees.
You've seen one snake on a stranger.
I just felt like this is not for me man.
Well I get so used to like fucked up
things and vomit and like,
like it just,
I'm just so used to it.
Um,
so like just unfazed.
One time my wife,
um,
she went to the gym and she had wheat
grass juice right off the gym.
She threw up in her car.
She just couldn't help.
But she was on the highway and she threw
up in her console.
She's like,
oh my God,
I can't even clean it all.
Throw up again.
I will clean it.
I didn't give a shit no big deal.
Just going in there to throw up to me
was nothing I saw throw up every day.
I mean,
literally every day I was at work is
either someone throwing up or someone
thinking they were going to throw up
once a week for sure.
I saw three or four people throw up
every week.
It was really like preparing,
preparing you for being a parent to sort
of.
Yeah,
the diverse hit or anything else.
Like,
Oh,
let's get in there.
Well,
you know what,
that was one thing that really was
shocking to me was,
um,
that it wasn't gross at all.
Like when it's your shit and you're
cleaning out a diaper and you're wiping
and cleaning or it's not gross at all,
you just feel like,
oh,
this poor little thing.
I got to help her.
I got to help her out.
And your uncle,
it's your uncle at a wedding and you're
like,
this guy's got a problem.
Exactly.
This weirdo drunk bastard.
Shit crap.
Again.
Fucking savage.
How old?
How old are your kids?
The little ones are seven and five.
Seven to five.
And that means you've seen like doc
mcstuffins,
doc mcstuffins.
I watch all the time to call her doctor
stuffings.
It drives my girl's crazy.
Well,
you know what they think is funny now.
They like to watch shows that they
already know in other languages and just
laugh and laugh.
Yeah,
they're like bubble guppies in French.
That's the latest plays in the car
singing to apiece because you have
daughters to people at home.
I'm like,
yeah,
not fantastic.
People listening clear like Jamie over
there.
No Kid,
no girlfriend.
Look at him.
He's like,
you should get some kids,
man.
It is a ride.
We have a dog,
do we?
But the beauty is when kids say things
that you,
you know aren't wrong,
but you're not sure how to help them
understand that publicly.
Sometimes they're incorrect.
We stopped on the.
We drove back from Chicago last week.
We stopped in a in a town called Arcola,
I think it was in Illinois,
might have been Indiana.
It's something with an eye.
It's the home of the guy that created a
raggedy ann and Andy Doll and it just so
happens there was a parade in Andy
Parade and kids here.
There's a parade and it's.
It's like catnip to children.
They just go,
oh my God,
we have to see this parade and we're
just trying to get them out of the car
to stretch it looks.
Here we go.
Okay,
great.
We'll see the parade.
Big woman comes up on a golf cart and
she tells this high school girl,
okay,
plugging the speakers and this girl gets
out with a boombox,
like a disk man and two,
three inch speakers and she plugs it in
with an orange extension cord.
And my wife turned to me and she says,
is,
do you think that's the music?
I said,
honey,
just got this.
This is an exit off the interstate.
Let's look this up.
And then suddenly realize the parade has
begun.
My uh,
our four year old male,
he is on my shoulders,
LCR,
seven year old standing at my wife's
holding the baby and so they start in
the first group is about six women
dresses,
Ragaini in and then one weird dude
wearing striped socks and I don't know
how to tell you this man,
but I just felt like saying,
hey dude,
you're not going to dress up like it
just stand over here with the other 12
of us watching this parade,
which is all of a hundred yards long.
That actually,
that that's way too.
It's like 30 yards long.
So the six,
the six women go buy it.
Then there's about five high school
girls dresses,
raggedy Ann.
They walk by and then there's the eight
girls from the local high school,
flat core.
That's the entire parade.
It takes maybe a minute and a half.
And then lc,
the seven year old said,
is that a real loud chemo?
And all of town is there.
And then millie,
the four year old says that's the worst
parade ever seen.
She's not wrong.
How to tell her like,
ah,
you sit there and you're like,
all right,
how do you do this?
And I said,
millie,
debt wasn't very sweet.
Very honest.
Let's just go get some food.
Let's get out of here.
And I know they tried.
But like sometimes when kids say stuff
you just don't know how else to be like
you're not wrong.
But socially we shouldn't say that out
loud.
Well they need to experience that
though.
They need to know that not everything is
the Disneyland parade.
Right.
Not Everything is Snow White and the
cast of frozen and all the jazz that you
see a Disneyland like sometimes,
like sometimes in the middle of the
country it's dog shit.
It's just a terrible fucking parade.
It's a terrible,
terrible raggedy and prey drive from La
to Vegas.
Yeah.
Oh yeah.
You know those.
There's all this weird towns that you
stop off along the way if you adventure
still and just a great town in
comparison to some of the really odd
ones.
Well there was one that was about an
hour or so outside of Vegas.
I was with a couple buddies were driving
down to go as long time ago to go see
some kickboxing event,
k one event that was in Vegas.
And so we said,
well let's just stop over here and go
get,
grab something to drink or something
like that.
So we pulled into this town and they had
a wild west show and I was like,
oh,
we are going to see this fucking wild
too.
So we got out and they had like a fake
gun fight in the whole thing and like
there's these like shitty fake houses
that were like,
you know those movies.
Yeah,
you have the front and there's nothing
behind it.
Like Saloon Bank,
you know,
we got out and they had this whole act
and all we could talk about for like the
whole weekend was that fucking Shitty
wild west show that we stopped off just
randomly,
completely randomly pull off the road,
drove a mile,
pulled in,
paid our money,
got out of our car,
smoked some weed,
got in and went to see this ridiculous
wild west show.
That was the highlight of our weekend.
Not at the time,
but became the highlight of our week and
all weekend.
We're just making fun of this fucking
wild west show that we saw and their
total commitment.
Right.
That's the part like when you see it and
there's like Wyatt earp walks out.
It's not a guy who's kind of wider
pitch.
This son of a bitch believes he is
wider.
He grew that mustache curly at the poor
bastards.
They just made it kind of like the
people that believe in doing the
reenactments.
Oh yeah.
I know how this could end the best
reenactments or reenactments where you
know it's a lie in the first place,
like a reenactment of like the time you
saw big foot this fucking show on the
sci fi network.
When I was on,
when my show was on Joe Rogan questions,
everything was on the network.
They had this supernatural show that
should've just been called the liars our
because it was all just a bunch of liars
and one of them was these people that
said that they were trapped in a house
in Maine while werewolves were outside
and they just going over this whole
thing and they're like talking about.
And then they had like the reenactments
of them,
like looking out the window and then
like they're trapped.
The werewolves not know that glass is
super fucking easy to break your know.
So you're looking out windows.
The werewolves,
they're,
you're protected inside this fucking
house when he's killing machines.
Yeah.
Well,
because they can't figure out how to
break the glass and get it.
The meeting.
Delicious portions inside.
Right?
Fuck out of here.
That's not how that works for the
center.
The werewolves,
they're little like there's one in your
lobby,
but genuinely frightened me.
You think it's going to stop and like
use the doorbell?
No.
Well that's a rubber one.
It's really easy,
so it doesn't weigh that much.
Smack it wiggles.
If that was a werewolf,
it's going through your window.
It's gonna tear apart.
Everybody in the room,
but it's just those reenactments,
you know,
they're,
they're cheesy in the first place,
but when it's a lie,
when you know it's a long time and those
are the best.
Do you like those guys?
They watching that show cracks me up.
Some of them are nice and some of them
really believe,
but why did you to just look at each
other with that funny look,
because we've had a bunch of those guys
on that.
Nothing goes hundred guys,
but bigfoot hunter guys.
We've had a few of those on the show.
Ones that make the sasquatch call.
Oh yeah,
we had that guy.
That guy's a bad shouting nonsense.
Not only that,
no one has ever recorded a sasquatch
where you know,
it's like if you do a coyote sound,
you know what a coyote sounds like.
Right?
He can hear coyotes,
they have recordings.
You don't know what a fucking pig foot
sounds like.
No guessing because it's made up because
it's not a real thing.
They just yell out into the Holler,
yell out in the Canyon.
How about those dudes and back?
The guys in Alabama a couple years ago
that they said they had one in the deep
freezer.
That guy had already hooked something
just a few years before that.
It.
Yeah.
He had hosted a few years before that.
He said,
well,
that one was fake,
but this one's.
This one's real.
This time through.
Yeah,
we've got them for normal witness.
Season three is just the Werewolf one.
Oh,
please play some of this fucking stupid
shit.
Look,
it says Joe Rogan questions.
Everything in the corner.
You.
These people were reenacting is this.
This is what the inside of the house
would have looked like this.
This is the reenactment account.
Froze.
I had this weird recurrent dreams plan
at the same time,
had a weird dream as a kid that I saw a
lumberjack outside my house.
He was in a red and black flannel,
like,
uh,
the one big he used to wear and he had
red eyes and I up to Alabama.
I would see him outside the house and I
thought like,
that dude could get in.
Right.
But it was just a dream.
Yeah.
I didn't believe he was actually outside
there.
Scroll back to that guy talking about
how the thing was outside while Joe
hurted,
not just froze,
was he drunk,
dropped his keys,
look like,
and I and
I felt very vulnerable.
Do you have to have a mustache to have a
really crazy story or is that sometimes
just an added bonus?
Listen to this.
Yeah.
Paranormal witness season three.
That means they had two other seasons of
the shitty show.
I like.
He sees it.
Rachel,
he was right there.
I was on my dodge Ram and that's when I
realized I had soiled and pants.
This thing was breathing.
I thought he was going to come in.
This is the worst recreation of all
time.
Honest question.
Is it possible this guy had glaucoma and
it just the neighbor had a black lab.
It's possible.
This guy's been sniffing paint.
Three years old and he's got three brain
cells inside his head.
They're bouncing around off the walls.
He's an idiot.
He can't even pronounce sentences.
Just amazing.
Now he's going down.
Did they recreated this?
They actually made a show around an
obvious lie and recreated.
It makes feel bad.
He left his keys out there.
I wonder if they're still there.
Well,
one of the things when I first started
doing the sci fi show,
they were worried that the show is going
to be just totally debunking things,
and I said,
no,
I'm going to approach everything with a
complete open mind.
I just want to find out what what.
What are these alien implants that
people keep saying that they find in
their bodies?
What are,
you know,
what our crop circles,
what are all these things?
The problem is once you start looking at
it,
you realize you're dealing with the same
type of human being over and over and
over again.
You're dealing with these really
socially awkward,
delusional,
bad liars,
right?
And that's a whole industry.
There's a whole industry of making shows
around the stories of these socially
awkward,
bad liars.
Like I met one guy within three minutes
of meeting them,
and I'm not exaggerating,
he told me that he saw big foot,
that he saw a bulletproof wolf that
appeared out of mist and that he knew a
spot where he could regularly some in
Ufos.
They would come and these,
these orbs would show up and they would
start moving around you.
And we were looking at each other.
It was like,
I can't believe we drove out to talk to
this fucking a long shot.
Is he by any chance unemployed?
This guy actually ran his own bar.
He's got his own place job though,
like all his time would be taken up by
believing nonsense.
He might've lived in Florida or
somewhere like,
just get away with shit.
I love that.
Florida is your go to like,
what's the craziest place that this
country has?
Florida.
That's everybody's craziest places in
the south.
It really is.
It's the best.
That's like,
we're like,
uh,
whatever happened to him.
Moved to Florida.
Well,
I had a,
my friend Jim Florentine on the podcast
the other day,
a stand up comic.
Love Him and he uh,
he moved to Florida when he was a kid,
he said because when he went there on
vacation,
everybody got off.
He was like,
Shit will just.
He goes,
oh,
let's just move down here because you
realize like in Florida,
like girls would just fuck.
Like things were crazy.
This totally different kind of human
being that you're interacting with.
I love it.
That was his reasoning.
That's exactly what is brilliant.
It appear.
But if you live in New Jersey,
it's hard to get laid,
you know,
if you're a young guy coming up in New
Jersey,
it's fucking to grind.
Is it?
Yeah.
It's a grind because all the big hair
and like it's just a lot of work.
So they're not that fun.
You ever watched real housewives of New
Jersey?
Once when I was getting it,
it's based on real humans drills.
Those are real human beings.
This is the one lady who literally,
her fucking hair starts an inch above
her eyebrows,
like shit her,
she has her eyebrows and then an
insulator her,
she's a monkey.
She's essentially some kind of monkey
and they let this lady live with people
and uh,
she wound up,
uh,
she's in jail now for like,
yeah,
it didn't work out to her husband.
Her husband's in eight.
He looked at her husband and he looks
like a gorilla,
like someone shaved down a gorilla,
big fat Italian gorilla.
And that's Jersey.
Do you know what I almost miss is a,
what was the MTV show?
Jersey shore that watching that train
wreck happen was you have to admit like
when that dude,
the situation was like,
like I'm a,
I've got a Lamborghini,
not for those.
That was one of those moments where you
thought,
kids,
I can't wait to tell you about this one
day.
Stay on the air.
That's what's confusing.
Great question.
Somehow Pauly d like,
I don't know what he seems very
charming.
I'm like,
I want to not like them,
but I kind of do because he's just fist
pumping,
like chance.
Like I think he's just a dude that just
knows what he loves.
Right?
Yeah.
But snookie seems everyone else seems
bananas.
Jesse,
the video,
the one where snuck,
he got punched in the face.
It was hard to watch.
Man was harder.
I've been,
I've been in,
I've been in one fight in my life and it
was with one of my best friends in sixth
grade.
My Buddy Richard Davis punched me
repeatedly in the face.
Why?
I was,
we're mad about something.
Right.
And it was like,
I'll meet you after school.
Well,
I was like trying to like tackle him and
trying to.
I don't know what.
I don't know what I was doing.
I'd never been in a fight before.
My face was so swollen.
I told my mom that I had had an accident
on my bicycle because I didn't want to
tell her like,
yeah,
my friend Richard from up the street
beat the crap out of me.
Did you enrich your stay friends?
We're friends now.
Great Guy.
Like that was a time when you could just
get in a fight,
right?
It's fucked up.
How easy that guy punched her.
Like he just like,
you fucking bitch.
Boom.
Just punched her in the face.
Like there wasn't no like worry that she
was going to hit him.
She didn't have a knife,
she wasn't threatening him.
It wasn't like self defense.
It was just like he decided he didn't
want her talking to anymore.
So he just knock it right in the face.
Your hat flew off.
Don't don't play that back.
Please go from the beginning though.
Here we go.
This guy was a school teacher to watch.
No,
boom.
Yeah.
And He.
Did he lose his job?
Of course he did.
I think he actually had some MMA fights.
No,
he didn't.
Yeah,
he just punched her right in.
The face isn't by the way that the human
body scraper.
Good friends.
I know,
but like what is it that made you get
into.
Where did that come into your life?
Where did see 1997 when I first started
working for them,
I did the post fight interviews in 1997.
Was it something like that?
Had you seen it and kind of dug it and
told him and those guys,
Hey,
was the for Dana.
Really?
Yeah.
I worked at the UFC before Dana.
I didn't realize that I quit and then
Dana hired me.
Okay.
I did it back during the dark ages when
I was banned from cable.
Right.
And it was like,
it was in the video store,
in the faces of death aisle where you
see it.
Remember those?
I didn't watch them.
I just remember seeing him.
Well,
that's where you would find the UFC
video.
So it was just,
it was a freak show.
And uh,
I,
my,
most of my life I'd been involved in
martial arts from Tom was a little kid.
Sure.
So for me it was like that show a or
that event was like the first time they
had figured out a way to get different
styles to compete against each other.
And for me as a martial artist,
it was entirely fascinating because I
had always wondered like,
what would happen if a karate guy fought
a judo guy or what have you?
So the UFC was the first time someone
has ever done it and put it together.
So it was a huge,
huge fan of it.
And um,
they needed someone to do their
interviews just the after the fight
interviews and they literally didn't
give me any instruction,
no advice,
nothing.
They put a microphone in my hand and
they said,
okay,
we're going to come to you in three
minutes.
Talk about the fights.
This is a live on pay per view.
I mean,
no one had briefed me when I say no one
to give me any advice.
I mean,
they hadn't said a fucking thing to me,
right?
They turn the camera on me and they
said,
okay,
you're live.
And I then I was like,
this is an amazing event.
Ba Ba ba Ba ba.
We got this guy who's going to fight
that guy and the implications are blah
blah blah blah blah blah blah blah.
And he's just got to train in Jujitsu.
And then that's it.
It's a fantastic event.
I can't wait back to you guys.
And I did it.
And I was like,
what the fuck am I doing?
Like who?
Let me do this,
right?
Like this is ridiculous.
Like the post fight interviews.
No,
no advice.
No one told me how to do it,
not just set me in.
Their fight was over.
I had to come up with the questions I
would ask him.
It was very bizarre,
very bizarre,
very,
very strange gig.
And I did it for about two years and it
was like all little puddle up hopper
planes flying into weird casinos in the
south.
That was the only places where they
allowed them to have it.
And uh,
I quit.
It was just too much,
just too weird.
And so I stopped for a couple years in
the UFC,
got purchased by [inaudible] when Dana
came into it for the brothers and uh,
I just became a fan and I was hanging
out with Dana and Dana and I became
friends and we would go to dinner and I
would just start saying,
well,
why don't you have this kind of fight
that guy?
Like,
what about this?
You ever see this guy find Japan?
Like,
do you know about this guy?
Do you know about that?
And I just started talking to him about
all this different cities,
like,
do you want to do commentary?
I was like,
wow man,
I don't want to work,
I just want to come and drink fights and
have a good time.
And back then no one was watching it
either.
It was like,
it wasn't like someone was asking me to
do the UFC today.
Right.
It was like the UFC then was doing porn.
That's literally what it was like.
Like you want to fuck on film.
Like oh I don't know that much money is
involved,
you know,
they're going to be alcohol.
You'd have to be like,
you know,
to be involved.
And it was like detrimental for your
career.
But she was on news radio.
I was doing the UFC.
Really?
Yeah.
They were flying me these weird places
like I started in 97.
So yeah,
the news radio started in [inaudible]
94,
so Nandini 94 95.
So it was like two,
three years in that I was doing that and
they were like,
what the fuck are you doing?
Like they were thinking about your
weekend.
They were thinking it was bad for my
career because like w filming would be
over on Friday,
you know,
we'd be done filming.
I'd get on a fucking plane and I'd fly
to Alabama and watched dudes get punched
in the head.
Right.
What else do you work with?
Like in Santa Barbara for the weekend
they were doing at fucking plays.
You're in Montgomery at the civic
center.
They'd go to some musical that nobody
really enjoyed.
Like you had to pretend that everybody
enjoyed and I would come back and talk
about,
you know,
some crazy event.
Somebody's got to teeth kicked into the
third row.
It was a,
it was very strange.
I got to,
I got to do the Toyota pro celebrity
race.
But cain Velasquez,
cain.
Cain is like a gentle giant right guy.
Total sweetheart.
Total teddy bear.
But he could rip your house down like he
is.
He's visually to me,
he's like,
wreck it Ralph.
He could just come in and take out an
interstate and I don't know what it is
about like being around them,
but the first couple of days I was like,
hey guys,
nice to see you.
Don't kill me by like the end of the
second week.
I was like,
what's up?
You want to just go,
just take care of this circuit.
I don't know why.
I started talking crap to constantly and
there was one time,
I don't know if he actually touched me
or he just got real close and I did.
I shut down.
I was like,
Oh God,
I just want sort of limp,
like he's going to grab your neck or
settlement.
Why?
I did that.
Every time I see him now I'll still
like,
what's,
hey man.
Did you see the fight this weekend?
No.
Was it just nuts?
It was rough.
Yeah.
He got beat up.
I got beat up and then he got strangled.
So watching a guy like Cain,
uh,
who has been,
except from one fight,
he got knocked out by junior dos Santos
in the first round,
the one fight.
But he went into that fight with a torn
knee ligament,
like he was pretty busted up going into
that fight and um,
he got caught with a huge punch from a
real devastating knockout puncher.
Go Santos.
So that fight,
that loss was a tough loss,
but there was a lot of reasons behind it
kind of made sense.
Then he came back and dominated junior
and the rematch and you know,
he's like,
in my opinion,
he's like one of the all time,
all time greats.
But to see him fight,
fabrizio over doing for preschool for
Dylan was fucking him up.
And fabricio is like one of the best
Jujitsu artist ever to compete in MMA.
Multiple time world champion.
And a cane was actually forced into
taking fabrizio down and he took for
heel into the ground and for resale
economy a team and tap them out.
No Way.
It was crazy.
Well,
they fought in Mexico City down there
training for,
for.
I don't know why.
I mean,
it seemed like it was in the middle of
nowhere in Mexico training.
He was only there for two weeks.
Really?
And yeah,
somebody,
um,
I don't know where it was,
but somebody put it up on my message
board that there's some sort of a
formula of like altitude like that if
you competed altitude,
you have to be there for x amount of
days depending upon how high the
altitude is.
There's x amount of days you have to be
there in order to acclimate for Mexico
City.
It's like 26 days.
Oh Wow.
And can only got there two weeks before.
So he had not acclimated at all and he
just wasn't ready yet.
And the altitude is ruthless.
75 to 7,800
feet above sea level.
And people don't know.
Like I,
I've gotten altitude sickness on top
gear before.
It's,
it's ridiculous,
man.
You just can't.
Your body just doesn't know how to
function.
It's like wearing the tightest belt on
every part of your body.
It's just weird what it does.
It's real bad to just see.
I put a picture on Instagram,
I don't know if you saw it,
but there's an instagram picture that I
put up that I took while we were
landing.
This is real.
That's how bad the pollution is all in
that same Mexico City,
Mexico City that's landing in Mexico,
so you see it on the big screen and I
mean I was like,
holy fucking shit.
That is it,
and as soon as I got down there,
I could smell it.
You smell it in the air and you get a
headache right away because there's no
fucking air because you're at 7,500
feet above sea level and whatever air
that you have is filled with car
exhausts and no traffic lights are a
joke.
No one stops.
It's not even a suggestion.
It's just like they.
They fought a government gig street
somewhere and read right through.
Nobody was paying attention.
Everything's gridlock.
When you hit rush hour,
everything's gridlock.
There's no non gridlock.
You know?
Sometimes you get la gridlock.
Some selfish asshole decides that even
though the light is turned red,
he's still going to make that left turn
right and he gets blocked and people
honk and he's like,
just looking ahead.
Lucky doesn't notice you in Mexico.
That's just what they do.
There's just too many people and it's
not even their fault.
It's just that it's just out of control.
Just too many people I saw people pull
out into intersections and it's like a
kamikaze maneuver.
The traffic's going and they just go.
They just pull out and you have to slam
on the breaks.
They just decide no one's going to let
you in.
Right?
You just have to make.
You just have to make your way.
Just go for it.
And so like traffic was going and this
guy's like creeping in front of car and
you see people hitting the brakes.
Then he would recognize that a little
bit of an opening,
so you're going to be gone it a car
length ahead and like fuck.
And watching it was giving me a
headache.
I was like,
this is crazy.
A crazy way to live and there's like 40
million people or something like that.
It's much larger than La,
much larger,
much larger.
2000 feet above Denver and polluted as
fuck.
It's madness.
How's the food?
Great.
The people are great too.
That's the interesting thing.
They're very,
very nice.
They're super,
super friendly.
I get it to just easy going,
even though they're in a giant ass city.
It's not like a New York thing,
like sometimes in New York.
I love New York.
I love the vibe of it.
I love the fact there's so many great
restaurants.
It's so much stuff to do.
It's like this is a crazy pack,
a packet of energy,
but the abrasive nature of some of the
people,
it really gets to me like totally like
the Tsa in New York.
You go to Kennedy airport.
It's like some of the rudest fucking
people I've ever met at a,
at an airport there or just in the
world.
They just happened to be at the airport
at that.
It's like it's.
It's just that attitude.
I think it's because there's so many
human beings jammed into this place that
people like,
they lose an appreciation for each
other.
Yeah.
Which you know,
if you grew up in a small town or if you
have ever been to a small town,
the one thing that people love that
people look at you and they say hi when
you walked on the street and wave,
kind of appreciate.
Yes,
there's not.
We're not overwhelming each other.
I think in cities like New York,
there's just too many God damn people
smushed in next to each other and in la
too.
That's why everybody gets so angry on
the road.
Sure world,
we're overwhelming each other and we're
not valuable.
There's too many of us just New York
with with more cars that people can
drive versus taxis,
but when you're in New York,
I'm always astounded that it seems like
everyone is simultaneously upset that
they're there,
but they will tell you it is the
greatest city in the world.
Yeah,
but they're all like,
this place sucks.
Really?
Yeah.
But I love it.
God never leave.
Well,
the dumbest fucking people in the world
are the ones that are they.
They act like there's something special
because they're from New York.
Like,
Hey,
listen,
I'm from New York.
I could handle myself,
you know,
like of like,
well,
you know how to fight because you were
from a spot,
right?
Like really?
Is that what you're telling me?
You wrote a small bus hooked to other
buses.
They called a subway,
so suddenly I'm from New York so I can
handle myself.
You know how it is,
right?
I'm from New York.
No,
I don't know.
I don't know what you're saying.
I thought we were trying to run a rental
car.
It's really.
That doesn't apply here.
Okay.
Your toughness and grown up in New York.
They're from nom nom.
I did my time overseas within the Bronx
in New York.
I live in a city,
big city in a box.
You know,
we,
we're looking at real estate the other
day just as a goof and there was a,
a tiny ass shitty little apartment on
the west side.
Uh,
and it was $500,000.
I was like,
this is offensive,
right?
It's one bedroom,
shitty little apartment.
Didn't even say how many square feet it
was because it looked like it was less
than a thousand square feet and it's
half of a million dollars.
Like think about how many years it would
take the average person working every
fucking day,
all day long,
eight hours
a day plus commuting.
Right.
And then tax is taken out of it to
scrape up enough money to buy this shit
back house.
It's basically impossible.
It's basically the weird thing is like
we're.
When we were shooting lost in
transmission,
there was two different producers that
bought houses in Atlanta where we live
not to live there,
but to buy them and then rent them out
because they can at least make a little
money and grow some equity in something
there.
Because out here,
like if people don't know to the
dumpiest house,
you can find out here is still like a
million plus unless you want to live in
Palmdale and smoke crack every day.
Which if you're watching from Palmdale
and you smoke crack,
I'm not singling you out.
I'm just making a suggestion.
I have a friend who just moved to
Palmdale.
Gosh,
is it for dogs?
Just for pit bulls and she needed to
leave some space.
She needed a place that accepted her
dogs and that wasn't very much money.
She doesn't make a lot of money.
She moved to Palmdale is awful.
It's so far out there.
If you.
If you could move to the surface of the
sun.
That's what living in Palm Dale is like.
It's the hottest place on earth and Afro
Man is from there because I feel like he
should know that side is not to go beat
up some woman on stage.
Oh No.
Oh Gosh.
I'm sorry.
Yeah,
righty.
Like he fucking crack some woman on
stage.
He was on stage.
She came up behind him and he punched
her in the face and dropped her.
Did you ever see that?
Didn't.
I'm not.
I don't wanna make it sound like I'm a
fan of Afro Man.
I just know that he's from Palmdale.
We filmed almost every car scene from
fear factor in Palmdale.
I like willow springs or somewhere like
that.
Just closed down some side roads.
There's some side roads out in the
desert is nothing but Joshua trees,
coyotes and shit and,
and we had these giant,
you know,
10 mile stretches row that they allow us
to close down.
Nobody gives a fuck right there.
Just go for it.
This is the video video.
You're showing second video of a chicken
and punched in the face.
Hit people.
It says you're so sweet and gentle.
I try to be nice man.
Shit goes wrong sometimes,
but yeah,
some woman got behind them and she was
like just drunk and being silly at a
show and just thought it was cute
clothes on stage with him and he punched
her in the face and knocked her out
cold.
She fell back and cracked her head.
I mean it was fucked up.
I was on stage and in New Hampshire at a
Nascar race once and I was telling
people like,
all right,
thanks for coming up to the show.
Have a great night.
And all of a sudden I turned and there
was a woman right here.
And I'm not saying like I've never had a
stock or anything like that.
Thank goodness.
But I don't know if you've ever had
people precariously I was standing on
like an eight foot tall platform,
I don't know where she came from and no
one saw her and then she was just there
in my face and a little bit drunk and
definitely from New Hampshire.
I don't know if you've had those
moments.
It's a real fight or flight moment where
you're like,
why are you,
why are you right here in my face and
you're drunk and she knew my name and
then you're like,
I'm just going to go.
This feels
weird.
It's weird that someone would not think
that you would freak out by sneaking
behind your glasses in real limited
peripheral.
So it's not like you can sneak up on me
in the room that we're in.
My wife will sometimes stare at me in
the car to see how long it takes me to
notice and then she'll give up because
I'm not going to see you over there.
I can't.
I'm not going to notice.
Little tough game with me.
Yeah,
there's a lot of Weirdos out there.
That's the thing is you never know when
you hear about that guy that shot
Darrell dimebag on stage,
you know like you never know.
There's.
You might be in the wrong place,
wrong time,
so I can understand that.
He'd be freaked out.
This woman was onstage,
but a cursory glance at her would let
you understand,
oh,
there's no reason to give this woman a
concussion.
She's just a crazy drunk lady.
You don't need to fucking molly whopper
in the face.
Jesus Christ certainly am.
I bet they had security there too.
Like you could've,
could've probably had another plan of
action.
They did have security shoot a never
gotten onstage a fair point.
I mean the security got high because
they were listening to a song because I
got high.
Like that song is basically like I was
going to do all the things I need to do,
like pay the rent,
pay the bills.
I was going to do some stuff and then it
got high.
Maybe he got hot,
maybe security got high.
I don't know.
Anything could have happened.
It's just saturation,
speculation.
It feels like a Monday morning
quarterback here.
Riff raff happens.
Insecurity is onstage.
Is Fan gets tackled.
Oh Jesus Christ.
All right,
let's get.
Let's get with God.
Let's just through that guy in the
crowd.
Riff raff.
The white rapper.
Let's give him some credit for making it
on Worldstar hip hop.
Is he white?
He is all you've seen.
Is that a woman that tackles what's?
Show that again,
because that's the power.
Double that.
This dude lens is quite impressive to
watch.
The guy taps some.
Look at this blue.
Oh Gosh.
That guy probably died.
Throws him in the crowd to look.
He's trash.
Like don't they have any liability
whatsoever to for fucking a 300 pound
giant human being.
So riff Raff.
I've.
I've never heard of this fellow before,
but gosh,
he has dreadlocks.
Is he related to the woman from spokane?
That was the head of the Naacp to apps.
How crazy is that to me?
Did you ever see the movie soul man?
That was our babies.
You know what I love about this super
progressive.
People are starting to take her side.
The tide has turned and they're starting
to say that race is just a social
construct and I've been reading all
these articles about how she ran circles
around Matt Lauer on the today show.
All these like super progressive left
wing.
People who are pro transgender are now
starting to accept Trans Racial.
They're not fucking around.
I never saw that coming.
She is running with it.
She's running with it.
I love it.
And one of the things that she said is I
as black,
so she's been lying about her dad like
this.
The guy she hangs out with,
she calls him her dad,
he's black.
I just pretended to real dad.
Her parents are from Montana or white as
fuck.
They're white as fuck,
but she has.
She checked on her college application.
Right?
What's amazing about,
apparently she went to Howard University
and sued Howard University because sued
for discrimination because she was
white,
so she's in the lawsuit.
She's saying that she's white.
She's like,
well,
then I identified as white,
but I identify as black now.
Wow.
We live in crazy times.
Donald Trump's gonna be president.
No one's black.
No one's white,
you whatever the fuck you want to be.
You can be anything you want.
We live in fantasy land America.
He paid $50 to cheer for him.
A president.
No,
really?
Is that true that he offered actors $50
each year from him?
Hey,
you can't say he's not a businessman.
There's a video of him pulling his hair
back to reveal that he has a real hair.
No way you could see.
I love that.
Your fans are that.
Yeah,
there are two dude throwing the ball for
you,
so someone must have challenged him on
his hair and he.
So he pulls his hair back.
Look,
see he's got fucking hair.
He just likes.
He just,
he basically just moved his bangs,
which shows,
but he showed his look.
He showed his hairline and he does his
hair.
It just has a wacky fucking thing with
AOL.
Got Don king thing going on.
That's fucking hair,
man.
Okay,
that's weird.
There's a lot of hairspray in there and
it's obviously thinning,
but you know,
there's nothing wrong for the record.
There's nothing wrong with losing your
hair.
You're talking to a bald guy.
It looks great on you.
Thank you very much.
I've always said if I lose it,
I want to look like a clown.
I might go like just diet,
but I think when you get to be the guy
like a don king or a guy like a Donald
Trump,
that's sort of his look like.
They commit to that and then they start
thinking that that's their lucky look
that you kind of have to have your hair
sticking straight up in the air or
nobody's going to know it's don king.
Don King all sudden had cornrows.
Everybody's like,
get the fuck Outta here man.
You can't have cornrows.
You're don king.
Your shit supposed to stick out like a
troll doll.
I interviewed him.
He said,
oh,
it's amazing.
I did it for the UFC.
It was fucking amazing.
I do some stuff.
He doesn't let you talk.
First of all,
he doesn't answer any questions.
You asked him a question.
The the pontification upon the universal
connection that we all share.
Like most of like I would ask him a
question and he would bring in to
women's rights.
Who would go to well,
like he's like,
oh,
let's go to,
let's not.
Yeah,
it was like a women's rights and gay
rights and,
and uh,
it was really strange.
It was very strange.
It was like he just talks and they
change his subjects in mid sentence and
keeps going and going and going.
So like you'll ask him a question and
you sit there for 10 minutes.
Like I said,
I couldn't imagine being a fucking
fighter who has some issues with my
contract to come into your office and
um,
I probably have a hard time talking
already.
Right?
I mean,
not,
not everybody's as eloquent as that
fucking guy.
You sit in his office,
you know,
maybe you're a regular dude who just
doesn't know how to phrase shit that
good.
He sit in his office,
he asked them a question and he goes on
his fucking 10 minute diatribe about,
you know,
Rosa Parks and women's rights and,
minorities and the white man.
And it just keeps going.
He just keeps going on and on and on.
And I was like,
you would,
you would confuse the fuck into people.
And I brought it up to them,
I kind of called them on it.
I was like,
you're baffling.
Baffling speaker.
It was weird though,
just knowing that first of all,
across the guy from the guy who killed a
couple people.
Yeah.
One of the worst stomped the guy to
death for a gambling debt.
And uh,
one of them I think he got off on the
other one he did some time for like,
one of them was like manslaughter and
the other one was like justifiable
homicide or some point that she.
Yeah,
that's,
that's a real stuff.
CLEVELAND,
right?
Isn't he from Cleveland,
Ohio in the fucking house.
Yeah.
Don King is a but,
but an interesting guy nonetheless.
Fascinating to talk to.
Covered in diamonds by the way.
Covered.
Yeah.
Diamond Star of David and cross covering
both sides just in case.
Just in case.
And uh,
he told me that late diamonds are a
girl's best friend.
That's why.
Whereas diamonds,
diamonds and rings diamonds on his
chains,
like you find yourself when you're on
tour.
A lot of times when you make it back to
a hotel room late on Saturday night,
that lock up is the only show on
television that just great
it block out some of those shows and
when I travel,
especially going to nascar races,
I don't know why they're always on
Saturday night and I feel like what if
like what if these dudes were like one
wrong car on the interstate away from
just being like a normal person.
Then just snapped.
Now I'm watching them in a federal pen,
like those two.
Okay.
So the two dudes that got out,
you're hearing about that.
The do's escaped from New York.
I learned late yesterday that the reason
that chick helped them was because they
told her they were gonna kill her
husband.
She wanted her husband,
dad.
So that's why she was helping them get
out because they said they would go kill
her husband.
Okay.
And then my next thought is or where
they hooking up with her because I
assume they have to.
There's gotta be some sort of weird love
triangle.
Right?
Well,
apparently the younger guy,
the word is he had a giant hog.
How does that come out?
Well,
everyone's going to want to know,
do you look at the girl?
She's quite the ugly duckling and uh,
you know,
you figure well,
she's inside the prison.
She probably gets to talk to these guys.
Probably lonely.
You know,
they make friends slowly but surely the
guy works his way in shows is giant hog.
Suddenly she wants her husband dead.
Let me ask you question.
Okay.
Just,
just two guys talking.
Okay.
You ever heard,
hey,
there's a prison break.
And your first thought is,
I wonder how big this guy is downstairs.
There's never been.
When a woman's involved though,
if the woman helped him get out,
you're like,
well,
what did he have to offer?
Can fucking giant snake?
Maybe it was a great dancer.
Maybe we knew a lot about poetry.
And you look at her and she's just sad
and unkempt
and neglected.
All of the above.
Just her whole body's just a tragedy.
You know,
John Mayer flaring bodies in Wonderland
about her.
It is kind of a wonderland.
Wonder how the heart keeps beating.
She doesn't climb to the top of the
fucking tower where they shoot prisoners
and jump off face first into the
basketball court.
Yeah.
What keeps you going,
honey?
Well,
I was hoping this guy shoot my husband
and give me some giant Dick.
What's amazing that they haven't caught
them yet.
Right?
And that they're still out there.
What are those guys doing?
Probably they're learning French and
walking into Canada.
Yeah,
that's what I would do if I was in
upstate New York.
I would think the best way like Canada,
if you go to Lubbock,
um,
they're,
they're very divorced from American
culture and a lot of ways in a very
strange way.
Like Toronto's not like Toronto,
like we understand that their mayors a
crackhead,
they know all about our presidents.
You know,
like we,
we,
when I go to Toronto it seems like I'm
in America.
The people are nicer,
you know,
it's very similar to America,
but Montreal is not.
Montreal is a very international
feeling.
City and the outside of Montreal,
Quebec,
like that whole area,
the French speaking area,
they have completely different stars.
They have singers that you've never
heard of that are huge,
that play stadiums.
They have comedians that a lot of them
would steal like English jokes and they
would translate them into,
into French and they would go on tour
throughout the French speaking areas and
do their comedy routines and they have
like a whole different world.
They speak French,
they like a lot of them exclusively
speak French and a lot of the areas like
you have to have French on the signs of
the buildings.
Like you know when you go to Montreal,
like everything's in French.
Like even Kentucky Fried Chicken,
they don't have KFC.
It's Pfc.
it's pooled a fried chicken,
you know,
it's probably not do well.
There's no way you'd learn French,
you know,
they're lovely people.
I mean I guess if I had broken out of
prison,
yeah,
I would think that that would be the
move though.
You go up there,
you learn French and a French on tape,
but you think they have Rosetta stone
when you've escaped from prison.
I bet you could learn in prison and I
bet if the guy was learning French,
they would say,
motherfucker is probably learning,
so you're going to escape to Quebec.
He's talking to his new girlfriend who
hates her husband.
He's like,
hey,
why don't you Rosetta stone me some
fringe me and Tommy will get out.
I'll take care of your husband.
Little Walkman or something.
We'll meet in in French speaking Canada.
How much could you really learn from one
of those Rosetta stone thing?
So I mean to really learn a language.
It seems like it's a long process.
I don't think.
It doesn't seem that way.
Do you know anything you want to speak
and I know a tiny bit of Spanish took
two years dose on Ios.
I took two years of Italian.
I don't know a word of it anymore.
Not sitting there.
That's a nice language though.
I just don't understand it at all.
I didn't pay attention.
I've had trouble with this language that
we're speaking clearly enough,
enough hurdles.
They're speaking to English.
I'm the tra.
Wow.
That would be a mess if I talked to you
and didn't talk about the Jeremy
Clarkson tragedy.
Oh sure.
Because,
uh,
the real top gear,
original top gear rather.
I'm in England,
which was a Jeremy Clarkson,
Richard May.
And I'm James Madison,
James,
Richard Hamill,
Hammond,
they call the hamster.
Yeah.
Sweet.
Hilarious folks there.
Nice work together.
And that's a tough act to follow,
right?
I mean it's a long running show that
went on for decades,
the most popular international show I
think,
isn't it?
Yeah.
And they said it was the most viewed
show in the world.
Um,
when you looked at CBS Sunday morning,
did an awesome kind of a no 60 minutes.
I'm sorry,
60 minutes was talking about it based on
downloads,
both legal and illegal.
And then how many shows how many
countries does show airs in like our top
gear USA or something like a hundred
countries.
There isn't like 170.
Um,
so yeah,
it's a big huge.
Can you kind of hinted to it before
about like,
you know,
it's a big act to follow.
We knew when we got ours that we
couldn't pretend to be the three of
those.
We were never gonna do that.
We're going to have to be our three
guys.
Um,
and we knew that there's like,
there's this like kind of core group,
we call them UK fan boys and they got
really upset that we were doing an
American version because they felt like
they were the only ones that knew about
the UK show,
not realizing how many people around the
world saw it.
They felt like,
I've got this special like Unicorn.
No one knows about.
I'm super awesome.
Well,
it turns out we were just taking the
kind of foundation of it and it's three
people in cars,
right?
So we're going to go do our own thing.
We,
we started with some of the same
fundamental ideas,
did everything different.
We didn't like our producers would come
up with crazy things for us to do,
but we didn't know about them.
Like we just went and they wanted to
watch us squirm and go have fun.
But what's happening now is a announced
a today.
I think Chris,
is it Chris Evans?
The guy's name,
who I guess is like a morning host or
their show or dj or something,
a popular guy is going to be the new
host of top gear UK,
which would,
they will relaunch and kind of re.
I'm not saying they'll reformat.
I assume he's going to have two people
with him,
sort of a rebirth.
So James May is not going to be on
anymore.
Correct?
Correct.
I think
the two of them said we will stand with
Clarkson and this is our group.
This is what top gear is to us.
So when everything went down,
um,
and I've never met Clarkson,
I've only met Hammon and uh,
he and I are pals.
Really great guy.
Uh,
I think it's one of those things where
he had gotten in so much trouble before
over the things he had said,
which is also like,
it's weird because that's the same
reason people watch him.
Yeah.
You know,
it's like when comedians get in trouble
for being funny.
You're right.
But that's what you wanted.
So I'm not making any kind of excuse for
that,
but I think it's a real bummer what
happened.
And you know,
everybody has bad days,
but when he flipped out,
flipped out on this producer,
who's a great guy,
I've met him before.
Ah,
apparently they'd had like a long day
and there were some sort of dispute,
excuse me,
about dinner or whether something should
be cold.
There was cold cuts instead of like a
hot steak or something.
I wasn't there and no one talks about it
in our lab group.
Everyone's very sensitive because I
didn't know whether overnight that would
screw up our show because it worldwide
brand is,
it's very important to,
to everybody.
That's a part of it.
And so I think,
I think he just had a real bad evening
and he took it out on somebody and that
cost him his job.
And so did he beat the guy up?
Is that what he did?
I think so.
I think he punched him.
I don't know if he beat him up and seem
like when you watch that show and you
watch that guy,
he's like this fun loving.
Right.
Hilarious dude.
I just have a hard time seeing him
beating somebody up.
Yeah,
I don't.
I don't know.
I mean,
I just read the same stuff everybody
else did that.
There were some sort of verbal
altercation and then a physical
altercation.
I don't know what that means.
I know it's a bummer for everybody that
was involved because it's certainly not
something that.
I mean he obviously was very upset in
the shame that happen as well as a
producer.
Everybody else.
It just wasn't one of those things that
happens sometimes and you realize it
sucks for every single person involved I
think because all the things he had been
in trouble for four before that.
What are the retarded or they not
understand what's going on and there's a
reason why the show is popular and it's
because that guy is a very unique and
bizarre character.
That is the main reason that shows
popular is Jeremy Clarkson in Richard
Hammond is grade and James May is great,
but on their own they're starving to
death.
Let's be honest.
It's a.
it's a.
it's an Altima.
I'm rude.
It's,
it's a.
it's a group.
It is an ensemble,
but Jeremy Clarkson is the funny one.
Just like the heart and so like he,
he wrote a ton of the different,
you know,
because he from the journalist side,
right.
So much about the stuff that they do and
a porsche people hate him.
There's a lot of people from the
manufacturers that don't like and which
is funny because sometimes people
wouldn't want to loan us cars because
things that they had done will the
Chrysler,
remember they had those three cars,
they drove costs in America.
Chrysler didn't want to give them raw
challenger so they bought one.
So the black friend was a producer that
had to pay for it,
pay them back.
And then.
So yeah,
like that's hilarious.
Things like that that would happen.
Richard Hanna was actually very funny.
I'm just fucking around saying that they
would both starve to death.
They're good together,
but they're better with him like as a
threesome.
So are they going to try to launch a new
show?
The three of them together?
So what I heard they have to.
Yeah,
I know the name is not important.
Right.
And so right now they're doing a,
they would go and do these kinds of live
show events.
I've never done one here.
They wanted to do on with us and them
kind of a combo thing.
And then we never,
nobody really moved on it.
But they were in [inaudible].
Ken Block was helping them out in South
Africa this week.
They did like six shows and they're
calling it like a Clarkson Hammond may
live or something because they can't use
the name.
Oh,
that's hilarious.
Gear live.
Right.
So I hope they'll keep doing something
fun together.
They're funny guys.
Yeah,
they're great together.
Hammons got a sweet Mustang.
We've seen some.
He's got some killer toys.
He's a helicopter guy too.
He lives in a castle.
I'm sure.
How much money they make off that show.
I think they did pretty well.
Maybe they got just a hair more than we
have.
Says the guy with two other jobs.
Uh,
yeah,
they,
he lives way out far somewhere,
which I think is also why he has a
helicopter.
But Hayman's got a bunch of kids.
Shows that he produces.
Really?
Yeah.
So he's got like kind of his other thing
and I don't,
I don't know what may does the rest of
the time when they're not makes you two
videos,
a lot of youtube videos and being
unemployed and cooking,
which are funny.
But they'll and recorder.
Yeah,
like really talented musician
apparently.
But those guys,
it's we got to do when they were
launching our show over there,
we got to go to this like a British,
I'm kind of television thing where they
put us up and,
and they had this party like top gear
USA.
So they tried to make the most American
themed evening they could.
So there's glass coke bottles on every
table.
Uh,
in Jack Daniel's.
And then the girls,
they had girls in like daisy dukes with
cowboy boots and American flag Bandana.
Amazon.
And they had like a holster with Jack
Daniels and shot glasses.
That's hilarious.
That was a fun time.
Fun Time.
Tanner I think was single at the time
and I'm a pretty good wing man because
my wife loves me so I can just be an
idiot publicly and not worry about it.
So the whole time I was like,
you guys know that's,
that's tanner foust over there.
You know,
he's got a couple couple gold medals
from x games.
I don't know if they have it all here.
Yeah,
well it's like a casio g shock.
They dipped in gold chrome.
That's not true.
I don't,
I don't know that for sure.
But I have experience in taking over a
show that was a big love show because I
took over the man show for a couple
years.
I hope we got tortured like right out of
look.
Rightly so.
In a lot of ways it was kind of a
disaster.
The show wasn't what we wanted it to be.
Fun.
Funny.
We got fucked over because we came in
under false pretenses.
They Kinda told us that they were going
to make this wild show,
you know,
have nudity,
will blurt out,
swear will beep it out.
We want to get sued.
We're crazy.
And then right when we started doing it,
Janet Jackson pulled her nipple out.
Oh,
this the superbowl.
Jt?
Yeah.
Slipped.
The plan says not amazing that that
generated this.
Still to this day
just hurts my brain that everybody got
so upset that they saw nipple on
television.
Right.
I quite enjoyed the show,
but just doesn't make any sense.
Like it was a man's nipple.
No one would care.
But it's Janet Jackson's nipple.
She's how man.
Like,
it's still just the nipple live in tyler
showed his nipple on that.
Probably every time they did a halftime
show.
So what's the big deal?
Yeah,
I mean it's because it's a female.
It's a sexual thing.
Poor Justin timberlake.
Heck,
I didn't even know that was gonna happen
y'all.
I was like,
he pulled it.
He pulled the nipple a pulled her
closer.
He knew what the fuck is going on here.
But how weird is it that a nipple is
like for a woman?
It's like super taboo for a dude is
nothing.
No problem in that strange.
He,
uh,
my friend Ari Shaffir lives in New York
City during the summertime and he takes
his shirt off every day of the week,
just walks down the street with his
shirt off because they have laws in New
York.
You're allowed to do that.
But because they have laws like that,
they have,
they can't sexually discriminated,
so women are allowed to take their
shirts off too,
so women could walk down the street
topless and occasionally they do.
And there's like this naked cowgirl,
you know,
have that naked cowboy.
I was him for Halloween one year.
I was.
It was tough.
It was tough costume.
It was cold that year were built
slightly differently.
He's a hands on me and the naked cowboy
built fella.
He's a strong businessman to.
It makes a lot of money off the shit.
Let's do him.
He's suing this woman because she was
doing the exact same act.
She was the naked cowboy.
She's topless.
There is the naked cow girl.
Good for her.
This is a different one I think.
I think there's more than one naked
cowboy for her,
but she has to have [inaudible] that
they deal because in Manhattan like you
don't.
I'm pretty sure the law is that a woman
can walk down the street naked or
whether top out rather.
You can't have your vagina out,
but you could have your nipples out
because man can just want to.
We're,
we're,
we're fucking so strange.
Great law though.
Good for them.
You know,
be quality.
Yeah,
topless.
All around.
I say go for it.
Why not?
It's just nipples.
Like if it wasn't,
it was something that the whole idea of
clothes,
it's just preposterous.
You don't want to wear them.
I don't give a fuck as long as you don't
rub your Dick on anybody or get weird,
who cares?
You know?
Suns out,
guns out.
You're fucking.
Your kid freaks out.
You gotta explain to them.
You get some talking to that little guy.
Say,
hey look buddy,
this is a.
Some people are freaks.
They like weird shit and they want you
to look at their Dick.
Okay.
You don't have to look at it.
They're not going to force you it.
Sometimes your parents are going to take
you to the worst raggedy Ann and Andy
Parade you'll ever see and you need to
not shout that afterwards.
Exactly.
Some checks and balances.
Sometimes shit gets weird.
Also,
big foot's not real and that is not
black.
She's white,
but she identifies as black,
so he's just wearing a lot man.
He used to be a man he wanted to Cathal
on in the Olympics and he had children
and then decided to use a woman.
So now we have to call Caitlin.
Hey,
smoke them if you've got them.
It's an interesting thing when you have
to win,
when you have to make sure everybody
knows,
look,
everybody's got a right to be happy,
but everybody does not have a right to
be completely out of their mind.
Crazy.
Somewhere we will find that line.
I say,
you do have a right to be completely out
of your mind.
Crazy as long as it doesn't interfere
with someone else's happiness.
Like say if your neighbor and you're
completely out of your mind crazy and
you're like sticking fireworks up your
ass and doing cartwheels,
but you live in a dry area and you could
potentially start fires,
right?
Then.
This is all logical,
fantastic analogy.
Your,
your craziness is interfering with
people's health and safety.
So,
uh,
I would say that guy know that guy
can't,
he can't be that crazy.
That's too crazy like that.
The guy with fireworks up was totally
cool.
Listen,
is this a,
is this a burn sensitive area?
Not Cool Pal.
This is California.
We have a drought going on right now.
Man is really interesting.
They're paying people in California to
take out their lawns and putting what
they call hardscape.
They give you money and you put like
rocks and Cactus in grass.
You can vacuum.
Yeah,
I've seen that.
The plastic turf.
I've drove down the street the other day
and there was a sign up from work for a
company that does again,
are they calling it hardscape as though
they're calling it like tax rebates and
whatnot for it too?
I think they actually give you money.
I think that they find out about that
because uh,
me and you're interested,
you know,
I'm thinking about.
No,
you've had enough of grass and bushes.
Well,
you know what,
I fucking passed by A.
Was it pepperdine?
Whatever.
The ones in Malibu is nice.
That is a God damn enormous lawn
watering for Jesus.
It's a big religious college roll down
that hill before it's fun for top gear.
No,
I think it was just for fun with my
family.
That was shooting a commercial for a lot
of fucking water to use on that gun.
Nice grass.
If they're listening,
so Kudos will not be taxed.
You cannot be taxed a not being taxed on
that rebate,
which can range as much as $3,000.
So you get a free three grand.
No saying they just won't tax you on the
three grand.
Is that what you said?
Like no,
because you get a rebate,
you get a rebate,
you get money and then you can't be
taxed on the money.
I think was when he started,
right?
Rebates received by homeowners replacing
their lungs with drought tolerant
landscaping would not be counted as
income,
so it doesn't say exactly how much
should probably,
depending on how much land have
insights.
That makes sense,
but the thing that's fucked his golf
courses,
I mean that that is.
I get that.
You like to play golf.
I like to play pool.
I understand I get get addictions,
but your addiction is using up a lot of
fucking water and apparently in some
Middle Eastern countries they play a
version of Golf on oiled sand sand and
they put some sort of oil on the sand
and the way the ball reacts is very
similar to the way a ball would react on
grass.
See if you could find that.
Someone was just.
Explain that to me the other day.
I never bothered looking it up.
I just said it sounds like a great idea.
Well,
except allow those assholes,
like those divots,
those big chunks of grass that go flying
through the air and then what?
Yeah,
he didn't want this.
Is this it?
Okay.
Just disgusting.
Be a tough place to where a lot of white
colors.
Weird.
Well,
where do golf bluestones what does that
say?
Grassland Greens used motor oil to make
putting possible.
Huh?
Whoa.
There's no.
I've been to a lot of tracks that will
use a motor oil from all the tractors
and stuff to put it on top of gravel to
basically like keep dust down.
So it's like that idea magnified.
I guess,
yeah,
I think that just they're putting right.
Is that what they're doing?
It's a tough gig.
Tough gig right there,
but I'm not that good at golf.
I'm never played it.
Really?
Yeah.
Never.
Best part golf carts.
Yes.
That's really like my dad,
when he would go play golf,
I would always go with him as a kid
because I was like,
yeah,
can I drive the golf cart?
And then when there's no water like
waterhole,
then I would take his own ball finder
and just swim with a little stick and
try to get as many balls as I could.
I have a friend of mine who has a ranch
in California and uh,
he has golf course and just drive golf
carts around and when she lets us little
kids take the golf cart.
So.
And one of his daughters like
[inaudible],
she was driving us around his fucking
golf cart ranch where the town I live
in.
You can have golf carts.
Really?
Yeah.
You must have lived in a little tiny
place.
I do.
That's cool.
I grew up in this town called peach tree
city in Georgia.
It's south of Atlanta,
it's built on five golf courses and the
idea was that you could get to any of
these little miniature neighborhoods on
a golf cart.
So there's a hundred miles a golf cart
path there.
So if we're at my house and you want to
go to dinner,
like we can just get on the golf cart,
it's a little bit like the movie the
Truman show,
like he definitely feel like there's a
bubble over it,
but it's also a golf cart.
So it's really fun.
That was kind of cool.
Huh?
And you can soup them up.
I built a golf cart on my new show,
but it's a 69 Subaru three 60 van,
a microcar.
And I built it on a golf cart chassis.
This just got 20 horsepower,
single cylinder engine.
The thing about golf golf courses is
pesticides.
And uh,
I knew a dude who got bone cancer and a
lot of people in his neighborhood got
bone cancer because the water from the
pesticides are in the wells and uh,
like a lot of people in his
neighborhood.
All cancer.
Yeah.
Pesticides or there's just the term
pesticide past like it's just poison.
Just call it what the fuck it is.
Why are you calling it pesticides?
You're poisoning bugs.
Bugs are tough,
mean roaches are going to be half to the
fucking nuclear bombs go off and you're
killing them with some chemicals and you
leave that shit in the grass and it gets
through the ground,
seeps into the water and then people
drink the water and they get sick as
fuck.
Pesticides.
They're just.
That's a creepy thing.
That seems pretty obvious to us then
that pretty God damn obvious and yet we
just go.
But the people that live in the golf
course or near the golf course,
they didn't even think about it.
They just let it seep into the well
water because it looks real pretty.
Yeah.
The only way to keep it pretty.
You gotta keep killing bugs.
Keep slit after,
right?
It's key.
Policing them.
Spraying.
It's brutal.
Yeah.
I'm one of the pesticides.
I was,
I'm listening to his radio lab podcast.
I'm the way they,
um,
figured out how to use poison gas in the
concentration camps.
They used Zyklon B and zipline a was
originally developed as a pesticide and
so they,
they use this gas zipline,
a had a particular aroma to it to alert
anyone that was near it or handling it.
It was very dangerous,
so the,
the Nazis re engineered Zyklon a and
turn it into a Ziploc bag and took out
the smell and you started using it as
gas and the concentration camps designed
a by a Jew,
not only that,
a Jew who was one of the first guys to
figure or the guy figured out how to
pull the nitrogen out of the air like
they,
like I'm a big majority of the particles
in the air apparently or nitrogen and
nitrogen is very difficult to get w for
fertilizer and stuff.
It's very difficult to acquire but
necessary in order to grow plants.
And so this guy hopper Fritz hopper
figured out how to pull it out of the
air and uh,
use it for fertilizer.
And apparently that method that he
developed in 19,
19 fucking [inaudible] or some shit like
that during World War One.
That method is still being used today.
And like half of the food that people
eat in the world is fertilized from this
method.
Same Guy Develop Zyklon b or cycle on a.
At least I feel like if they ever need
to go in front of Congress and talk
about the legalization of marijuana,
I think we could take a video clip of
that last 45 seconds of you telling me
that story and then like people would be
like,
well,
he can remember all that and he smokes
weed.
We should probably just let it go.
That's great.
That's the kind of podcasts that you
relax and listen to.
Shit that I listen to.
Yeah.
Why love stuff.
That history.
Podcasts.
I love those.
I just thought I'd love.
I'm fascinating information.
I don't have any information that makes
me go.
What the fuck,
right.
Anything like that.
You know,
pot does not fuck with your memory.
It fucks with your memory about shit you
were just talking about.
I don't mean that's what you just laid
down was brilliant.
But what's interesting in the way that
the guy also was one of the first people
that use gas and warfare and he uses
like,
I think it was a chlorine gas.
He used it on the,
uh,
English and the Canadians,
I think it was English and the Canadians
that they used it on,
but he was being,
he was,
he,
they thought the United States was
addressing him as a war criminal the
same time they
were using his fertilization methods.
I Kid,
right?
Like he was a very,
very complex guy,
was a very complex guy.
Like he wasn't a good guy,
but he wasn't,
I mean,
he was like,
he was brilliant in a lot of ways.
The radiolab podcast when anyone's
interested,
it's called the bad show.
And it is about,
um,
a lot of people that did a lot of really
awful things.
And it's,
he's just one of the many stories.
Um,
but I've been on this world war one kick
lately.
Sure.
Because of Dan Carlin.
He's got this podcast called hardcore
history and um,
he has his whole world war one series
that's going on right now.
And just put the final,
I think it's the final episode out.
It's fucking amazing.
It's just so crazy that world war one
was just for me,
a war that I never really thought about
and if really looked into it and I've
just been really getting into it lately
because of these podcasts.
But.
So yeah,
it doesn't really fuck with your memory.
I just meant that was what you lay down
and uh,
the,
the um,
there's a lot of layers to them and I
just thought that was,
I was just sitting here thinking,
that's really impressive.
Inhibited you asked me about something
about 10 minutes ago,
but what the fuck we're talking,
but what was it?
Or just 10 seconds ago we were just
talking about whatever,
whatever.
I got to turn into my dad and I just
can't remember things.
Really.
Yeah.
My Dad will,
will,
like the,
my friend that's a pilot.
Martin,
my dad has met Martin.
I met because he's introducing himself
each time is a new time,
30 times.
And I'm like that.
That's smart.
And it's nice to meet you.
Yeah.
The teacher right now,
he's a pilot.
He's always been a pilot.
If your dad ever meets Martin and says,
good to see you,
then I'll know my dad's an actor.
Yeah.
Need some fucking Alpha brain song.
I've got to get some of this stuff.
This is this cognitive enhancing
supplements.
Really good for memory.
I was in double blind placebo testing.
I wasn't kidding when I said I really.
I really enjoyed like watching you on
instagram and the stuff that you're
into.
Like I dig because you don't.
You're very honest about who you are.
She don't like you don't split hairs
about like,
yeah,
this stuff is cool.
I want to learn more about it.
And you'll ask people like you have
genuine interest in feedback and stuff
like that.
That's what I did because there's so
many people that are like that.
They wouldn't want to say like,
I had a coca cola classic at lunch today
because someone's going to tell him
there's corn syrup in there.
Right.
Where you live in that kind of like a
weird thing,
but.
Well if you really feel that way,
I feel like you shouldn't have classic.
Right.
You know,
just do what you want to do and if you
have,
if there's any repercussions,
this is probably something you shouldn't
have done in the first place and you
should learn from them.
I think so many people go through life
like trying to project something instead
of just being who they are and working
on what the negative aspects of whoever
they have designed themselves to be said
of working on that.
They just put up this fucking fake
facade that's too labor intensive.
I have no desire to do that.
I don't pretend you're someone who
you're not.
Seems to me like a Glock goddamn effort.
Lot of work.
And
for what would you get out of it?
Like look at Charlie Sheen.
Okay.
That guy's a junkie.
He's a junkie and he loves horse and
everybody knows it and they love them.
It's not like some fucking secret,
but it's because he's like,
hey,
I like to smoke rocks.
And uh,
I pay girls to suck my Dick Goodnight.
I love him.
He's so refreshing.
Sawdust.
Isn't that amazing that a guy can be on
a a network fucking television show,
like a squeaky clean cbs show like two,
two and a half men,
and do these interviews about doing
smoking rocks and paying girls to leave.
You don't pay them to have sex with you.
Pay Him to leave.
And everybody's like,
yes,
I love them.
Hashtag winning,
right?
Hashtag tiger blood sugar blood.
I saw that all over the,
the,
the Internet when that all went down.
Any,
you know,
look did the reality of who he was.
He was not pretty.
I mean it looks like he's a hundred
years old.
His fucking face has fallen off.
He looks really bad.
Like there's,
there's some,
some of the videos that he did like
right after he got kicked off that show
and he did like these weird podcast
style videos where he's like staring
into the camera and the people behind
him,
he looks like he's just sweaty death.
Right.
You know,
it was fucking mine.
Still.
People love the fact that he was being
who he really is.
I think so much of what you see,
like when you see Tom Cruise jumping on
oprah winfrey's couch saying how much
she's in love.
I'm in love,
I'm in love and all the women in the
audience and everybody else
like bullshitting me,
you're bullshitting me,
but I'm used to being bullshitted so I
just deal with it.
Right?
Like the bachelor,
you're peeing on my back and telling me
it's raining.
Tom Cruise.
I'm used to it.
Now I'm going to put up with it,
but only because top gun was a great
movie.
Exactly like we're shocked at.
That girl fucked a bunch of handsome
guys that she got drunk with.
Whoever.
That girl is good for you,
young lady.
I hope you got your rocks off.
I hope you sucked.
A lot of delicious dicks and how gail
time like flinstone style
flinstone style.
Just different world back then you could
say again,
it had nothing to do.
It's totally different.
Now.
The thing that I'm still puzzled by
right now is that I got.
I put up a picture on instagram about
like a picture with some friends or
whatever and the amount of people that
will go out of their way to say nasty
stuff to strangers.
Yeah.
I'll put a picture up of of friends that
I'm hanging with and someone will go
after someone in the picture and I'm
like,
[inaudible],
how much is your life suck that you need
to go attack a stranger?
Virtually.
It's just not.
It seems to me the internet,
once they.
They fall into several categories,
but the most egregious or youtube and
instagram.
Yeah,
like twitter.
At least.
My twitter feed is surprisingly polite
and nice and genuine and kind friendly
it.
I mean people was talking about the
negative people that deal with the
Internet.
I deal with Nice people.
99.9%
of the time.
It's almost all nice people.
Occasionally a Twat will sneak through
the to the net and find their way into
my twitter feed,
but then you just block them and then
you're done with it.
Yeah,
but instagram,
good luck trying to block those fucking
monsters and they all have.
If you go to their accounts,
they're all locked right there.
Like I feel like if you're going to be
critical,
my pictures let me be critical of years.
There's a couple of times I always think
because for me it's not that different
from like being in middle school and
people like this cannot go shockey.
I was a little weird middle school too,
like that not much has changed.
The world was in middle school as well.
It's just more accepting of us.
I come from the exact same person but
good for you.
It's like lunch room bullying,
but on this virtual level,
so I guess what I would stand up for
myself then so sometimes I watch people
and I don't get a lot anymore,
but like when when they said I was on
top gear or when I started being on tv
for Nascar than you would see those
people come out of the woodwork and even
still like I did these funny videos for
Nascar on NBC with like Danica Patrick
and Kevin Hart,
all these people and someone will be
like,
you suck,
you're fat,
you're stupid.
And that's fine.
I'm not.
I don't mind,
but I will.
I would say 95% of the time I at least
like to know if it's something funny
then I'll laugh and just move on.
But if it's something to where like they
they really want to go after you a lot,
I'll be like,
okay,
let me just at least look at your
profile and if I can tell they don't
know any better,
you just block them.
Unum wrong.
But if I feel like they know better,
every once in awhile I'll just lean back
a tiny bit and this guy one day when
after me about something stupid and he
told me how stupid I was and fat and
ugly and I shouldn't have a job in
whatever.
I looked at his picture,
his profile on twitter and it was a
picture with him and his daughter like
going canoeing and so all I said was,
hey man,
I hope no one ever says to your daughter
at school what you just said to me
because I know that'll feel bad for you
to hear that.
And He,
you would've thought I cussed his
mother.
He came after me so hardcore at that.
How dare you look at my picture and how
dare you try to dare you make me public
is public.
We're all public.
If you're on the Internet,
you fuck your public.
Like I wasn't being mean.
I'm just being honest.
Like,
hey,
how about golden rule?
This sucker,
like don't say mean stuff to people.
If you don't want them to say it back to
you.
Like fascinated people have said mean
shit to me and I retweet them.
That's it.
Just retained them and like you pick
your friends.
I mean,
no,
no.
All I did was retweet what you put out
there.
This is you and I let everyone know this
is you.
This is you.
This is shared,
you know,
shared.
You know that's not being a bully.
Do I have a bigger platform?
You?
Of course I do.
Fuck face.
That's how you know who I am.
I don't know who you are.
That's simple logic.
It's like,
don't stick your hand the cage if you
don't want to get bit because that's
what's going to happen.
I'm going to retweet you and then
everyone is going to all these other
people that are bored looking for some
asshole to shit
on.
Right?
They get home at Tartar taking shit from
their boss.
Their fucking wife is an asshole.
They're kids suck and they're happy to
climb up your ass and plant bombs.
They're happy.
I'll give you an earful.
Exactly,
but I think it's because of the same
reasons why people were bullying people
in middle school where you don't see
nearly as much when you become an adult.
I think it's because it's a new thing,
Sharon.
I think that the cyber communication is.
It's untested.
We have to figure it out.
We don't know what the fuck we're doing.
All the normal shit involved in
communication,
like social cues and knowing first of
all,
someone accepting you as a person who
want to have a conversation with.
There's a lot of these people that
you're communicating with online that
you would never accept as communication
partners in real life.
Right?
You would meet them.
They'd be gross.
He'd be like Mike a dick and he just
like stopped talking to him.
He right or stop visiting his place of
business or or whatever,
but because they can just get to you
without any,
you don't have to accept them.
You don't have to choose them to pick
you because you pick your friends.
If you're a wise person and you'll have
a better life if you do that.
If you don't pick your friends,
you just let let anybody in your life.
You develop a series of fucking
incurable disasters over and over and
over again that you never really recover
from and you live your life based on the
momentum of a bunch of assholes who
aren't thinking straight then that's a
lot of people.
I have friends like that,
but live their life like that.
It's just one disaster after another
fucking disaster and if you get caught
up in the hurricane that is their life,
they'll drag you into the cyclone.
You'll get fucking tossed out into the
ocean somewhere or you.
You choose.
But in the online world,
you don't get to choose.
So if you're out there and what they're
doing by blocking you,
they think my wildest get him and he
can't even me back and so they put their
little fucking locked profile on
instagram and it's just guaranteed
they're a coward.
Like anybody who has a locked profile to
talk shit.
I don't.
I just block them immediately.
I don't even think twice.
I don't speak to them if they think like
they like there's a rider in Nascar,
the blocked me and I was laughing,
right?
Yeah.
And,
and it,
it was just one of those things where
for some reason this guy decided the day
I showed up,
he hated me,
but I laughed because I thought that
means you thought I wanted to know what
you thought,
but I never wanted to know what you
thought because I didn't care then and I
didn't care now.
But the fact that he went to that
effort,
it made me giggle.
Like same thing with if some stranger
says you're stupid and then blocked me,
I'm so sorry.
You must have thought I was going to
want to learn more about you after you
insulted me.
What provider could seriously get to
know you and not take care of Greg Carr?
That's choosing to me.
They're very friendly guy.
Like why?
Why did he decide that you're a dick?
Great question.
What was his criticism?
What he say?
What's his name,
by the way?
No,
please find out.
There's this one guy,
this one guy who was a nascar rider.
Too many of the other way.
There's a bunch.
It's a.
It is a great guy.
Honestly.
It's great,
right?
With crayons,
Napkins?
Not Anymore.
They.
I think most of them have a brother
typewriter.
I think his brother is that right?
This one dude would go on like serious
and say terrible things about me.
How much he disliked me,
but then it was really nice to me at the
track and he did a bunch of shows.
Big Boy,
and I'll say this.
My boy,
like a fat guy was sloppy.
He was big size load.
Every motherfucker he's gone,
he's dead.
He died of a heart attack.
It's poor fat.
Had a.
He had a windbreaker that he would take
when he went to eat chili dogs.
Whoa.
And that was kind of when I found that
out.
So when I worked with is like,
you know,
he puts on like a tarp,
the chili dogs.
I was like,
I can't,
I got to leave.
This guy knows his stuff is a lot worse
than anything I got going on in my life.
If you need a tarp for Chile though,
either he really loves clothes or knows
he's a slob.
And just gave in,
I think it was the second,
it was a lot of self loathing is
involved in people being mean to people
because they want you to feel the way
they feel a little bit.
You know,
they want to reach out.
Like I've had communication with people
online like really mean to people.
And then you go and look at their
twitter feed and like you'll find some
like suicidal shit in there.
You'll find you some miserable.
Yeah,
there's a lot of that.
There's a lot of people out there that
are hurting.
I think the model of life that the
majority of people are living in civil
as well as in civilization.
The civil civilized world,
when you're involving offices and jobs
that you don't really want and places
that you don't really want to go to,
but you have to like what you're doing
for a living.
You enjoy your.
Obviously you have a real passion for
cars and totally great time.
That's the ideal life for everybody.
That's what everybody really wants,
but there's not a lot of people get to
be you.
Sure.
Small amount of people that get to be
you just it's.
It's like a.
not even a one.
You know?
People talk about the one percenters
isn't even the 1% that are doing what
they want to do.
Do you think Donald Trump is doing,
he wants to do that for fucking goofy
Prek wants to be president.
He wants to.
He wants to be loved.
He was paying people to cheer at his
presidential announcement.
He's just an ego.
He's just a big ego.
You know that's not.
He just got on that path and that's the
path that he's using to try to validate
himself,
but if you are not living a life that
you enjoy,
you're going to have this fucking
feeling all the time of God dammit,
like,
why can't I be on top gear?
Or why can't I do this?
Or why can't I be the fucking UFC
commentator?
Or why can't I be the president?
Or why can't I do this and what about?
And that's,
that's a lot of people,
man,
it's all day is fuck,
this guy is fucking core vet and fuck
that guy in his Ferrari and fuck this
guy in his big house and fuck him and
his hot wife and fucking with his
fucking kids that don't suck.
No,
it's true.
It's hard and most of us,
we're the victims of Shitty childhoods
and people who had kids that didn't know
what the fuck they were doing and they
pray.
It's like,
it's like imagine getting programmed.
Imagine if you had a program,
a computer program,
right?
And your computer was programmed by
someone like me who doesn't know Jack
Shit about computers.
I know how to type my name in the
fucking,
you know,
my password and how to get my gmail,
but I don't know what's going on
underneath the surface as well.
I don't know.
So I'm an idiot.
You know,
if I had to program my own computer,
it'd be a disaster.
It would be crashing every five.
That's a human being.
It's essentially like a gigantic
biological computer.
What's your most complex?
When we know and they're being
engineered and program by morons,
millions and millions of morons.
They're raising kids and fucking them up
and then it's our job as the kids who
got fucked up to sort of decipher what
the fuck are parents did wrong to us are
and try to make it through life with as
much happiness as we possibly can to our
heart stops beating and that's a complex
puzzle and everybody makes it through
and figures that fucking thing out.
That's it.
Those are the people on instagram with
locked accounts and those are the people
that eat chili dogs with wind breakers
on and smile to your face and Shit on
you and your fucking computer or on
Sirius satellite radio or whatever they
do.
It's just,
it's hard.
It's hard to be nice,
man.
It's hard.
It's hard to let yourself forget about
liking other people,
especially liking other people that are
successful.
Host in top gear.
That handsome tanner foust and that
beautiful Adam Ferrara.
I mean,
I will say this.
I think you know,
like if,
if,
if your life sucks,
if it's now or you want,
you know,
you,
we've all been there,
but like I think a lot of people forget
sometimes that you can change that.
Like we,
the reality that we're flying through
this gigantic marble in space.
It will kind of blow your mind,
but the fact that you can wake up every
day and do what you want to do or not do
what you want to do,
like that's pretty awesome.
Like I these things,
the fact that we're sitting here,
this didn't happen by accident.
You know,
and I think sometimes people forget that
like if there's something out there that
you want,
you're going to have to physically do
something about it,
you know,
and that's the one thing that when
people come after me that I,
I,
I love having fun.
Like I want to make people's day better.
That for me it was like I was either
going to try to go back to school and be
some sort of teacher,
like a high school counselor because
columbine and stuff like that breaks my
heart like I can't believe that
happened.
And it's because those kids didn't have
the parents that I did when they got
made fun of the parents weren't there to
say,
you're fine.
There's nothing wrong with you.
There's something wrong with those
people that they don't have enough
confidence in who they are,
that they're going to take it out on
everybody else.
And so I thought,
well,
I'm either going to do that or I'm going
to try and get on TV and make as many
people smile as I can,
but it's because I wanted to do
something about it like that.
I just sometimes it breaks my heart that
there are people that aren't willing to
push and say I want something better.
I think a lot of people feel trapped in
their existence because they sort of
live their life on momentum and they got
kind of stuck in this trap.
They're in high school and then they go
to college and they get student loans
and they somehow get out and they don't
have a job.
They're trying to find a job and then
they take whatever job they can get and
they still have debt and then they have
a family and then they have mouths to
feed and they feel fucking trapped and
was super frustrated so they see a guy
like you who's putting a 900 horsepower
engine Osi on and running around like a
fucking crazy person on television and
they get mad because you look at your
sweet guy,
have a big smile on your face.
You look like you're having a great
time.
And for people who are not having a good
time,
one of the most punishing things is
watching someone live their life better.
It's like,
like we were talking about drifting,
like how good tanner is a driving a
fucking car when he drifts.
He's like,
he's an artist,
right?
It's like he's moving like a ballet
dancer total if you,
if I was drifting.
I'm sure I do it way.
I don't even know how to drift.
Okay.
Let's,
let's pretend I did.
I took some drifting lessons today.
Sure.
I know how to drive,
but I guarantee uh,
I've looked like a clunk.
Clunky fuck fuckhead in comparison to
him.
I'm not doing as good a job and the
drifting or driving or doing anything or
bowling or fucking playing darts.
It's like life.
So he's going to be people that are
better at it than you.
Okay.
And you could either learn what are they
doing differently and try to apply that
to your own life or you can just shit on
them.
No,
you easier to shit.
It's a lot easier to.
Shouldn't have tried to learn.
So it's a lot easier to shit on them.
And sometimes you shitting on people and
you're correct.
You know,
sometimes you shitting on people and you
know,
you,
you realize you are watching some
bloated ego or some ridiculous version
of a pop singer that record companies
are trying to stuff down your face and
you know it's Horseshit,
right?
You're correct.
And comparing them to,
you know,
whatever,
fill in the blank,
Lou Reed or Mick Jagger or whatever the
fuck it is that you really appreciate.
You're correct,
but a lot of times it's just pitching.
A lot of times you're just trying to
figure out why you're not happy.
You know,
you're seeing someone on television or
in movies or just on the cover of a
magazine and you're,
you're angry because it's not you
because for whatever reason,
you got down a bad path and you got
stuck in this fucking shitty existence
that seems to have no exit door.
You don't know what to do.
So you lock up that instagram account.
You Start Shit graphing on strangers.
Fucking Shitty fucking dad.
Just farting in your fucking office
chair and sniffing your own farts and
keeping typing and horrible people out
there.
I don't mean to make you think that I
have a ton of those.
They're just have them look.
The better you do,
the more you're going to have snow.
There's no getting around it,
but I think it's a temporary stop.
I really do.
I think we're about maybe a decade or
two away from no one ever having secrets
ever from everyone understanding
everyone's motivation,
being able to read people's minds.
I think we're.
We're getting closer and closer to each
other in some ridiculous way through
technology and that's what's going on
with these people that you would've
never chosen to communicate with.
Reach out and fuck with you.
You know,
whether it's through twitter or facebook
or what have you.
I think that we're going to come to a
point in time where,
and not too far away from now what we're
going to share thoughts and some sort of
a weird way that's not going to be as
simple as like reading something on
Reddit or you know,
facebook or instagram.
It's going to be way more complex.
It's going to be.
We're going to have you seen that thing
that they did where they did an
experiment where they,
um,
they hooked these people up to some sort
of a brain detecting device,
implanted electrodes on their head and
they,
they sent words through the Internet,
across the world.
Like instantaneously these people on the
other side of the world receive these
words and knew what the person was
saying,
like brain to brain communication.
You haven't seen that?
I have not.
And that's crazy.
It's not,
man,
I,
I'm not.
I don't totally understand how they did
it.
I think they can only do it with crude
words right now.
Like,
yes,
no,
you know,
you suck like those kinds of thoughts
because I think they,
you identify in your head what that word
means and you commit to that thought and
then they can transmit that thought
pull,
pull up that study.
Because I don't understand it
binary.
I think it turn that word into a binary
code of some kind of transmitted that
one zero on offs to you.
And then you know what?
There was only a couple of things they
had in it,
so they knew what it was because of the
binary.
It's our hello or something like that.
Shower.
Hello or goodbye.
We'll do.
Did they just play the flight of the
conchords song about the Binary Solo?
Do you think that's what it is?
Oh Man,
I love those guys.
New Zealand's are my favorite.
New Zealand is a nice gentle people.
It's a sweet spot,
but they're trying to getting fucked
over over there.
Stole all his money and they're trying
to import or export them to the United
States,
deport them rather.
That's a weird situation.
Honda Mega upload situation because a,
he didn't,
you know,
he's never even been to America and
they're trying to bring them to America
for some alleged crimes against these
alleged movie companies where people
were uploading videos.
It's very,
very complex,
but it's also like I would like to know
like what percentage of that site was
being used for that and what percentage
of it was being used for people just
uploading things.
I don't totally understand how he was.
Were people paying like a subscription
fee?
I don't know either.
Sometimes when people make a lot of
money,
you're like,
well,
how did that just happen?
Okay.
A company in Barcelona called star lab
described transmitting short words like
chow and coded as binary digits between
the brains of individuals on different
continents,
both sides.
Both studies use a similar setup.
This the sender of the war in Iraq,
electro and cephalgia graphic cap that
captured electrical signal generated by
his cortext while he thought about
moving his hands or feet.
These signals were then sent over the
Internet to a computer that translated
them into jolts delivered to a recipient
recipients brain using a magnetic coil.
In Star labs case,
the recipient perceived a flash of light
in the University of Washington case.
The magnetic poles caused an involuntary
twitch of the wrist over a touchpad to
shoot a rocket into a computer game.
Whoa.
See where we're getting to this weird
place in technology and the the.
The ability that we have to manipulate
technology,
but the ability to manipulate matter and
information that's going to make haters
online.
It's gonna be.
It's gonna be ridiculous.
This is a temporary pitstop like an
adolescent stage and the communication
that we're enjoying and it's what it is,
is if you look back at watch game of
thrones,
send a raven the only typical fucking
rave and tie a message through his leg,
you know,
that was like the only way you get a
message to somebody that is ridiculous
now and I think these ideas of texts and
tweets and all that stuff,
it will be ridiculous in the future
because we'll just have something that's
far more satisfying.
Far more direct.
You'll understand sarcasm,
you're gonna.
Understand when someone's fucking.
You ever get a text from someone you
know,
like,
are you fucking with me as this of
really mad at me?
Are you fucking with me?
Right?
And then you have to say,
are you fucking with me?
And they're like,
totally,
totally no,
not serious or just joking around and
sometimes they are serious,
but they're pretending they're not
serious.
You're going to be able to feel that
right now you're saying that we could
wake up one day and I'll be like,
I'll be thinking we should get coffee
and you'll be thinking that.
That sounds great.
You show up at your house with coffee
even.
How about butter conversation
nootropics,
nootropics.
That was close with his memory.
Is that it?
Oh yeah.
From shawnee.
Parker.
Kligerman soon.
Something with those whose a bunch of
different nootropics that'll help with
memory.
But,
uh,
we've done two double blind placebo
controlled tests on it with the Boston
Institute of Memory,
Boston Center for memory.
And um,
they showed.
Can you not remember the name of the
center?
Um,
that we've got work left to do.
It's not important to me.
For me,
I use like names.
I don't remember people's names.
Mike Baab.
Tim.
It's not important.
It's like that,
that dude,
you know,
like,
love that.
But when something's important to me,
I've never fucking forget it.
Right?
Like,
like what I do like UFC commentary and I
started talking about past fights.
I don't have notes.
Those aren't just from my head.
I just remember fights.
Good for you.
You remember?
I've probably called like 1500
professional fights at least and I just
remember it was just Rolodex.
It's in there.
I don't remember all of them.
Sometimes I have to research or go back,
but I remember most of them,
most of the big ones,
most the ones by the memories of weird
thing,
man,
you know,
I went to this thing the other day.
My daughter had this,
a dance recital and uh,
she had been to the same place two years
before and I'd only been there once and
as I was walking there I was like,
where do I go?
Oh yeah,
I'll go over here.
Like all of a sudden my brain went,
Yay,
let me pull those files up.
Right.
You gotta go over here.
And I was like,
thinking as I was walking I was like,
how weird is this that my brain is just
pulling these files up now?
Because if it wasn't for this recital
that I had to go do,
I would never remember shit.
But for whatever reason your brain can
like reach back and find those files and
pull them out when necessary.
For now it'll keep them for like,
it's like sort of like tweets.
Someone sends you a direct message in
twitter,
twitter cleans those out after six
months or something.
Like you don't need this anymore.
Trying to save.
So this was an important.
Kicked this out of here.
You know,
I think that's also going to be one of
the things that gets resolved with a
technology.
I think the way we memorize things now,
it's like really crude and it doesn't
work that good.
I think they're going to,
we're going to be able to record things
that you see directly to some sort of
medium,
like whether it's a SD card or whatever
the fuck it is.
And you're going to be able to share
experiences with someone else.
You're going to be.
Your wife was like,
hey,
how was work today?
Like,
well why don't you fucking live it
bitch?
You put the card in her.
Yeah.
And she's like,
oh my God,
I just jumped a fucking school bus over
the top of a bridge and flames were
shooting out of it.
Yeah,
that's what I did at work today.
pretty good.
Pretty good day.
Were cutting.
That's going to be crazy.
Yeah.
We're gonna put,
you know,
the roots really bumming me out.
And what's going to bum me out as an
automotive enthusiast as you are as
well.
Is He self driving cars?
So strange,
isn't it?
Well it isn't.
It isn't.
I think we need it because I think a lot
of assholes drive like shit.
But man,
it's going to be a bummer when you can't
just go for a ride up the fucking
angel's crest highway and just blah
blah.
Just just have fun.
Just go drive and you know,
roll the window down and feel it just.
Or is it possible it will make driving
for people like us even better because.
No,
in three minutes.
Okay.
No one else.
Like if,
if all the people that suck at driving
in autonomous cars in,
we're just in the left lane in fast
cars,
won't that be better?
Yeah.
Maybe if you have to like,
you know,
like every tanner foust guy is allowed
to drive whatever the fuck you want.
Right.
Because he has such tense,
right?
Because like my 53 plymouth,
you can't,
there's no way you could make a computer
big enough to drive that thing yourself.
Do you think we'll ever get to a point
where you're not allowed to drive those
cars?
So I get some weird laws in California,
like one of the reasons why people like
older cars because you don't have to
smog them.
Hell yes.
But look at Mexico City,
that fucking picture that I showed you
today,
that's what happens when you let people
not small their cars or you have too
many cars and we don't want that.
So
like where do you draw the line?
I mean there's only a certain amount of
19,
69 Chevelle that are available in the
world,
you know?
And you've got to find one of those in
order to have a 19,
69 Chevelle.
That's it.
They don't make them anymore.
Totally.
And if you want to build a new 19,
69 Chevelle,
well guess what,
bitch,
that's gotta get smog.
That's not going to be the same.
But I think that,
you know,
there's good and there's bad,
it's not clean.
It seems like if you've been drinking,
it's a genius idea,
right?
Just drop me off at home parking garage.
That sounds awesome.
But imagine if you were in that self
driving car and you're safe and sound
and some Dick Wad in a fucking Mustang
is going who?
And again in right on the corner,
just doing a standard burned out at the
stoplight.
Boom.
He smashes into you.
You know?
Then you're like,
well,
everybody should be in these fucking
driverless cars.
God Damn it.
Didn't crash.
One of those Google cars though.
There's been some confirmation that the
Google cars,
they've actually crashed.
So they're not.
They're not perfect yet.
They're not.
But they've probably crashed a lot less
than the people that work for Google.
Right?
To Shay.
Now see that?
That's a stat.
I don't want to wonder.
Hmm.
Out.
Just because you're good with a laptop
doesn't mean you're good with the camry.
Dude,
I had a great time talking to you,
but once you're having me,
thanks for being on.
We got to do this again.
That was great.
What's funny is I was like,
how long are some of these?
This was three hours flew by man.
Thanks for having.
Thanks for being on,
man.
I really appreciate it.
And I enjoy your show.
And when can people watch?
It's on the history channel.
Yeah.
So we just ran our season of lost in
translation,
so we'll go back to work.
It looks like into the summer on top
gear.
They'll take a little while to make and
then hopefully we'll do more.
I'm lost in translation and,
and see me every weekend on NBC a
starting in July for all our nascar
covered.
And what is your twitter handle is at
rutledge would rut leg.
Beautiful.
All Right Ladies and gentlemen,
we'll be back tomorrow with hypnotist
vinny shoreman demand that uh,
Joe Schilling was telling me about.
Is he going to hit and ties me?
I'm going to tell you if this shit works
so you guys much love.
Thanks buddy.
Appreciate it.
Mm.
Yeah.