Two one. Boom. All right. We're live.
Thank you very much for doing this, man.
I really appreciate it.
I've been absorbing your information and
listening to you talk for quite a while
now. So it's a, it's great
to actually meet you. Thanks
for having me. My pleasure.
My pleasure.
You are one of the rare guys that is a,
you're a big investor. You are, um,
you're deep in the tech world,
but yet you seem to have a very balanced
perspective in terms of how to live
life as opposed to not just be entirely
focused on success and financial success
and tech investing,
but rather how to live your life in
a happy way. That's, uh, it's, uh,
that's not balance.
Yeah. You know, I think the
reason why people like, uh,
hearing me is because like,
if it's like if you go to a
circus and you see a bear, right?
That's kind of interesting, but not
that much. If you see a Unicycle,
that's interesting, but you see a bear
on a Unicycle, that's really interesting.
So when you combine things, you're not
supposed to combine. I get interested.
It's like Bruce Lee, right? And striking
thoughts, philosophy plus martial arts.
And I think it's because at some level,
all humans are broad.
We're all multivariate.
But we get summarized in pithy ways
in our lives and at some deep level,
we know that's not true,
right?
Every human basically is capable of
every experience and every thought, uh,
you know, your UFC, comedian,
commentator, podcasts here,
but you're also more than that. You're
also father a lover, you know, a thinker,
et cetera. So I like the model
of life that the ancients had,
the Greeks, the Romans, right, where you
would start out and when you're young,
you're just like going to school,
then you're going to war,
then you're running a business,
then you're supposed to serve
in the Senate or the government,
then you become a philosopher.
This sort of,
this arc to life where you
try your hand at everything.
And uh, as one of my friends is a
specialization is for insects, right?
So everyone should just
be able to do everything.
And so I don't believe in this model
anymore of trying to focus your life down
on one thing. You've got one life,
just do everything you're going to do.
Yeah,
I couldn't agree more.
And I think that sometimes people find
certain success in whatever the endeavor
is and then they think that that is their
niche and they stick with it and they
never change.
And they almost out of fear.
Well it's, it's hard
because there's a, you know,
there's analogy around mountain climbing.
Like if you find a mountain and you start
climbing and you spend your whole life
climbing it and you get say two thirds
of the way and then you see the peak is
like way up there, but you're
two thirds of the way. Yeah.
But is still really high up.
But not to go the rest of the way.
You're going to have to go back down to
the bottom and look for another path.
Nobody wants to do that.
People don't want to start over.
And it's the nature of later in life
that you just don't have the time.
So it's very painful to go back
down and look for a new path.
But that may be the best thing to do.
And that's why when you look at
the greatest artists and creators,
they have this ability to start over
that nobody else does. Like Elon will,
you know,
be called an idiot and start over doing
something brand new that he supposedly
is not qualified for or when Madonna or
Paul Simon are you to come out with a
new album.
Their existing fans usually hate it
because they've adopted a completely new
style that they've learned somewhere
else and a lot of times they'll just miss
completely.
So you have to be willing to be a fool
and kind of have that beginner's mind and
go back to the beginning to start over.
If you're not doing that,
you're just getting older.
Yeah, I mean I don't even know
if it's willing to be a fool.
It's just to me that the most exciting
thing is to try and get better at
something and to learn things.
I mean it's,
it's really exciting when you just have
incremental progress in something that
you're completely new to.
Yeah.
I live for the Aha moment,
that moment when you connect two things
together that you hadn't connected
together before and it fits nicely in
solidly and it kind of helps form a steel
framework of understanding in your mind
that you can then hang other ideas off
of.
That's what I live for.
That curiosity fulfilled and it's what
little children do to, you know, my,
my little son is always asking
why, why, why, why, why,
and I always try and answer him
and half the Times I realized,
actually I don't really understand why.
I just have a memorized answer for you,
but that's not really understanding.
Yeah. Those are weird
conversations, right? When you're,
you're talking to your
kids and you say, look, uh,
the reality is I don't know a lot of
things. Yes. I've just memorize a lot of,
yeah. And there's certain things
that you just can't know. Yeah.
You realized that you know,
you have,
you have answers for a few things
that you've thought through.
Then you sort of have coverups like,
like trap doors. Like don't go here.
This is just a cover up.
I don't really know the answer to what
the meaning of life is or how we got here.
And then you've got a whole bunch of
memorize stuff because a lot of your, uh,
a lot of intelligence these days, just
the external brain pack of civilization.
I know it's out there and are,
the answers are out there and I'll have
to look them up and I've memorized some
of them and I kind of understand how
money works in the Federal Reserve prints
it and what this government thing is,
but not really.
Right. Um, so not good enough to
teach it in university. Yeah. Uh,
I think people do that with almost
everything in life these days.
In terms of like have a, like
a, a one page of one sheet,
like a brief summary of what
the explanation for what
this very complex subject
might be. Tldr, right? Yes.
Give me the don't give you
the lecture. Gave me the book.
Don't give me the book. Give me the blog
posts. Don't give me the blog posts.
Give me the tweet. Don't give me the
tweet. I just, I already know. Yeah.
I got really fascinated by the way
you read because I thought there was
something wrong with me by doing that.
But you,
you don't really just
read a book to completion.
You read and then you pick something
else up and you just kind of go based on
your whims,
whatever you're interested in.
Raised by my mom,
I was raised by a single mom in New
York and she used the local library as a
daycare center because it was
a very tough neighborhood.
And so she would basically say,
when you get back from school,
go straight to the library and don't come
out until I pick you up late at night.
So I used to basically live in
the library and I read everything.
I read every magazine I read
every pictograph or what
every book or every map.
I just ran out of stuff to read.
I just read everything.
So I got over this idea of that reading
a large number of books or reading a
book to completion as a vanity
metric because it really,
when people are putting
a photos on Twitter,
Instagram of looking at my pile of books
that I'm reading, it's a show off thing.
It's a signaling thing.
Yeah sure.
And the reality is I would rather read
the best hundred books over and over
again until I absorbed them rather than
read all the books. Yeah. Cause your,
your brain has find that information,
uh, and find its space. Uh,
you get enough advice. It
all cancels to zero. Um,
there's a lot of nonsense
and books out there too.
So I don't read any
more to complete books.
I read to satisfy my genuine intellectual
curiosity. And it can be anything.
It could be nonsense. It could
be history, it could be fiction,
it could be science, it could be Psi Phi
these days. It's mostly Scifi philosophy,
science cause that's just
what I'm interested in.
But I will read for understanding.
So a really good book I will flip through.
I won't actually read it consecutive in
order and I won't even just even finish
it.
I'm looking for ideas,
things that I don't understand and when
I find something really interesting,
I'll reflect on it, I'll research it. Uh,
and then when I'm bored of it I'll
drop it or I'll flip to another book.
Thanks to electronic books.
I've got 50,
70 books open at any time and my kindle
or I books and I'm just bouncing around
between them.
Uh,
it's also a little bit of a defense
mechanism to how in modern society we get
too much information too quickly and
sort attention spans are very low.
So you get Twitter, you get
Instagram, you get Facebook,
you just used to being bombarded with
information so you can take that to you.
You can view that as a negative and
be like, I have no attention span.
Or You could view that as a positive.
I multitask really well and
I can dig really fast. I can,
if I find a thread that's interesting,
I can follow through five social networks
through the web, through the libraries,
through the books, and I can really get
to the bottom of this thing very quickly.
It's like the library of Alexandria
that I can research at my disposal.
So I no longer track books, read
or even care about books. Read.
It's about understanding concepts.
Yeah. You brought up two awesome points.
First of all, the social media aspect of,
of books and basically anything,
it's like,
it's such a weird way to display
your life cause it's, you know,
you're displaying the best aspects of
your life and some sort of a glass case,
you know,
just,
it's an unrealistic version of your
life that you cultivate and you curate
and I'm, I'm as guilty of that as
anybody. Everybody's guilty of it.
I'm guilty of it too.
Yeah. You know what I mean? I
pose with my dog every time I run.
Yeah.
We're always signally rather
than really looking at yourself,
you're looking at how other
people look at you like this one,
remove mental image,
and it's kind of a disease because social
media is making celebrities of all of
us and celebrities and the most
miserable people in the world, right?
Because they're this strong
self image that gets built up.
It gets built up by compliments.
Every time somebody pays you or me,
a compliment and we're like,
oh, well thank you. Right?
Then that builds up an image of who
we are and then one idiot comes along,
one out of 10,
one out of a hundred,
and they can easily tear it down because
it doesn't take many insults to cancel
out a lot of compliments.
And now you're carrying around this big
weighty self image and it's just very
easy to be attacked and because you're,
you're famous or you're well known,
people want to attack you. So,
uh, being a celebrity is no good.
It's actually a problem.
Like one of my tweets is,
and these are all reminders to myself,
is you want to be rich and anonymous,
not poor and famous, right? There's
benefits to it of course, of course.
But we wouldn't do it.
Unusual problems that you don't get
trained for and you really will not
understand unless you experience it.
You know,
it goes having this conversation with
my wife, we were talking about um,
people that just come up to you and
they don't care what you're doing.
They don't care if I'm with my daughter,
if I'm holding her,
if I'm feeding her for, you know, we're
in the middle of an intense conversation,
she's crying,
she could be crying and some bro,
we'll come over and just
immediately have to take a picture,
doesn't care his needs,
supersede the daughter.
And my wife was saying
that before she knew me,
she used to think that that's just
part of the price of being famous.
That people, people like you, that's
just part of the price, be famous.
And now when it interrupts
her life and you know,
interrupts the children and interrupts
friends and you know, she now she's like,
this is annoying. Like this
is not, this is not healthy.
This is not a smart way to,
to interact with people and that
people have this weird challenged,
this weird thing that if you're,
if he become famous,
there's this weird challenge where
people just want to come to you,
especially today,
because if they can get a photo of you,
then that boost their social
media profile. Like, Hey,
I'm sitting here with evolve.
Look at this.
Anonymity is a privilege. Uh, on the
other hand is self inflicted. I mean,
we brought it on ourselves. We don't
think we knew what it was though we did,
but we carry on. So it tells us we
are getting something out of it.
So there are times when some of the
approached me in public and I'm a little
resentful and then other times
they're just like, actually,
I'm really grateful that you know,
I've worked for this, I got this right.
This is the payoff. Just embrace
it. Smile, Grin and bear.
It meets someone of a different,
yeah,
sort of celebrity too, right?
You're a, you're a hero
amongst investors and amongst
tomorrow among young male Geeks,
which is just some of my favorite people.
Right.
But that's not the kind of celebrity
I think most people set out to get,
especially the most guys. Right, right,
right. You want the cute females? Yeah.
I look at my brief little youtube clips.
I'd have a tiny little podcasts
going now and it's like 95% male. Oh,
I'm sure. Yeah. This
is very highly 18 to 35, right? Yeah. We,
what are we, what is the numbers and said,
yeah, it's in the nineties.
Yeah. Um, you, you did that one.
You do that one very small
podcasts where you just have small,
like three or four minute clip.
Yeah. So what it was, I
did a tweet storm, uh,
called how to get rich without getting
lucky and it got pretty popular in
Twitter. Uh, and uh, it's
really about wealth creation.
I just used the click baity title and
it's trying to basically lay out timeless
principles of wealth creation
that if you absorb them,
you become the kind of
person who can create wealth,
create business, make money.
Uh, and my theory behind that is like,
there are three things everybody wants.
There's actually more than three. But
let's see, let's just start with three.
The three basics.
Everybody wants to be wealthy,
everybody wants to be happy
and everybody wants to be fit.
And I know there's a lot of which
she was signaling that goes on,
like we don't want to money.
And you know,
I don't care about being happy and
happiness is for stupid people,
but let's face it, like you want
to be rich and happy and healthy.
That's the TRIFECTA.
Now of course you also want to
internally calm state of mind.
You want a loving household. So there
are other things that come into it,
but those three I think they can
actually be taught right? And a fitness.
I'm not going to teach. There are a
lot of people who you've had on here,
including yourself,
who know a heck of a lot more about
fitness and health than I do. Um,
but I was born poor and miserable and uh,
I'm now pretty well,
often very happy. Uh, and I
don't, and I worked at those.
And so I've learned a few things.
There's some principles.
And so I try to lay them out,
but in a timeless manner where you
can kind of figure it out yourself.
Because at the end of the day,
I can't really teach anything.
I can only inspire you and maybe give you
a few hooks so you can remember things
when they happen or put it,
put a name to them.
So this podcast actually ended
up explaining this tweet storm.
So there's a tweet storm was like
36, 38 tweets, got very famous,
got translated dozens of languages.
Um,
and these were principles that I came up
with for myself when I was really young,
around 13, 14. Uh,
and I've been carrying them in my head
for 30 years and I'd been sort of living
them. And over time I just
realized like sadly or fortunately,
the thing that I got really good at was
looking at businesses and figuring out
the point of maximum leverage to actually
create wealth and capture some of that
and do it in a very longterm kind of way.
Not, not the, you know, banker crashed,
the economy get bailed out kind of way.
But you know,
build businesses and help people
and provide value kind of way,
especially when applied to modern
technology and leverage in this age of
infinite leverage that we live in a,
so the podcast is just explaining each
tweet. So these are little three, four,
five minutes snippets. I don't like
to say the same thing twice. Uh,
I don't like to explain
in detail. Uh, I just,
I feel like if you have something original
and interesting to say should say it,
otherwise it's probably been said better.
So that podcast tries to be information
dense. It tries to be very concise,
it tries to be high impact
and tries to be timeless. Uh,
and it has all the information.
I think you need the principles that if
you absorb these and you work hard over
10 years, you get what you want. Um,
so I've got the one on wealth creation.
I'm going to attempt to do one on
happiness is a big word, but you know,
happiness and inner peace
and calm and all that.
Because what you want is you don't want
to be the guy who succeeds in life while
being high strung,
high stress and unhappy and leaving
a trail of emotional wreckage,
whether you and your loved ones,
which is more common than not.
Yeah. Because you got to focus and it's
very hard to be great at everything.
You want to be the guy or the Gal
who gets there calmly, you know,
quietly without struggle.
Uh,
you want to be the person who the
e when there's a crisis going on,
you want to be the calmest,
coolest cucumber in the room who still
also figures out the correct answer.
Hmm. If you can be, you were in,
one of the things that you were saying
is that you feel like happiness is
something that you can learn and then
you can teach yourself to be happy,
even just by adopting the mindset that
you are happy person and proclaiming that
to your friends. And so you've sort
of developed a social contract.
I'm a happy person and the law,
I have to live up to that.
Yeah. I've got hundreds of
techniques, but develop that one. Oh,
well, there's this, uh, there's
social consistency, right?
Humans have a need to be highly
consistent with their past pronouncements.
So the way I started my first
tech company was I was in a,
in working inside of a larger organization
and I told everybody that I was going
to go start a company. I was like, I hate
this place. I'm going to do my own thing.
I'm going to be a successful entrepreneur.
Six months past, nine months pass.
Then people start saying,
you're still here.
I thought you were going to go start
a company or when you're lying, right?
That was the implication. So
we kind of know this, right?
Social contracts are very powerful. Like
if you want to give up drinking, right?
And you're not serious about it,
you'll say, I'm going to cut back.
I'm going to have only one drink a night.
I'm going to only drink on weekends.
You tell yourself, but if you're
serious, you'll announce it on Facebook.
You'll tell all your friends, you'll tell
your wife, you'll say, I'm done drinking.
I'm throwing everything out of the house.
You'll never see me drinking again.
When you say that you know you're serious.
So I think a lot of these are choices
that we make and happiness is just one of
those choices. Uh, and
this is unpopular to say,
cause there are people who are
actually depressed, you know,
chemically or what have you.
And there are people who don't believe
that it's possible because then it
creates a responsibility on
them. It says, oh, now if I'm,
you're saying if I'm not happy,
that's my fault. Not saying that,
but I'm saying that just like fitness
can be a choice. Health can be a choice.
And nutrition can be a choice. Working
hard and making money can be a choice.
Happiness is also a choice. If you're
so smart, how come you aren't happy?
How come you haven't figured that out?
That's my challenge to all the people who
think they're so smart and so capable.
If you're so smart and capable,
why can't you change this?
Hmm. There are a bunch of people though
that actually take pleasure in being
miserable there.
There's something about the pursuit
of excellence and have success that
supersedes
all other pursuits that in in their eyes,
it is.
It is that the peak, the pinnacle,
the most important thing.
It's not a trade off.
I would argue that now when I say happy,
happy is one of those words that means
of zillion different things, right?
It's like love, right? What
does that mean? Right? I love
cheese. Yeah. Before that,
a little bit more tightly, right? So
let's go back to desire, right?
This is old, old Buddhist wisdom.
I'm not saying anything original,
but desire to me as a contract that you
make with yourself to be unhappy until
you get what you want. Okay? And
I keep that in front of mine.
So when I'm unhappy about something,
I look for what is the underlying desire
that I have that's not being fulfilled.
It's okay to have desires.
You're a biological creature.
Can you put on this earth? You have to
do something. You have to have desires.
You have a mission, but don't have too
many. Don't pick them up unconsciously.
Don't pick them up randomly. Don't have
thousands of them. My coffee's too cold.
It doesn't taste quite right.
I'm not sitting perfectly,
oh, I wish it would warm.
Or uh, you know, oh my dog pooped in the
lawn. I didn't like that. Whatever it is,
pick your one overwhelming desire.
It's okay to suffer over that one,
but on all the others,
you want to let them go so you can be
calm and peaceful and relaxed and then
you'll perform a better job.
Most people,
when you're unhappy
like a depressed person,
it's not that they have very clear calm
mind. They're too busy in their mind.
The sense of self is too strong.
They're sitting indoors all the time,
their minds working, working, working.
They're thinking too much. Well,
if you want to be a high
performance athlete,
how good of an athlete are you going
to be if you're always having epileptic
seizures?
If you're always like twitching and
running around and like jumping in your,
your, your limbs are flailing
out of control the same way.
If you want to be effective in
business, you need a clear, calm, cool,
collected mind.
Warren Buffet Plays Bridge all day
long and goes for walks on the side.
He doesn't sit around like constantly
loading his brain with nonstop information
and, and, and getting worked
up about every little thing.
We live in an age of infinite leverage.
What I mean by that is that your actions
can be multiplied a thousand fold
either at broadcasting,
at a podcast or by investing capital
or by having people work for you or by
writing code.
So because of that,
the impacts of good decision making are
much higher than they used to be because
now you can influence
thousands or millions of people
through your decisions or
your code.
So a clear mind leads to better
judgment leads to better outcome.
So a happy,
calm,
peaceful person will make better
decisions and have better outcomes.
So if you want to operate
at peak performance,
you have to learn how to tame your mind,
just like you have to learn how to attain
your body. I love what you're saying.
Um, Warren Buffet might not be the
best example because he drinks like,
I think six coca is a day and eats
mostly Mcdonald's and he's still alive
somehow. So that shows you
that low stress is more shit.
Like how old is he? I mean, he's a fairly
old man, Charlie, I think in his nineties.
Right? Yeah. It's made it really far.
I wonder what Warren's doing, you know,
I mean just he's got it. No,
that's bad for him, but if
it's terrible, doesn't care.
He doesn't care. I think he's just a
little stress. Stress is a big key. Right.
So he's just enjoys that Coca
Cola and that's probably,
maybe there is a trade off,
right?
Like maybe him and join that
junk food and that coke just ah,
that the pleasing of the mind is maybe
better than him just eating wheat grass
shots and, and be pillar
salads and just being, yeah,
just super worked up about everything.
It's like if you need your glass of
red wine and de stress and calm down,
that's probably better than you
flying off the rails. Right, right.
And I think that that's applicable not
just in business but in probably any
pursuit.
And I like what you're saying about allow
that one thing to be your obsession,
but everything else, you know, learn
how to learn, how to let things go.
Pick your battles.
And we'd like to think that we'd
like to view the world as linear,
which is I'm going to put
an eight hours of work,
I'm going to get back eight hours of
output, right? Doesn't work that way.
The guy running the corner grocery store
is working just as hard or harder than
you and me. How much output is he
getting? What you do, who you do it with,
how you do it. Way more important
than how hard you work. Right?
Outputs are non linear based on the
quality of the work that you've put in the
right way. That work is
like a lion. You don't,
you and I are not like cows were
not meant to graze all day. Right?
We're meant to hunt like lions were
closer to carnivores in are omnivorous
development than we are to herbivores.
Um, we don't tell vegans. Yeah, sorry.
Look, I wish all that stuff
worked. I don't want to eat meat.
This future generations will look back
at us as worse than slavers. You know,
because the Holocaust,
we're committing with the animals,
but they'll have artificial meets that
taste in or healthier is better than the
real thing. So allegedly,
allegedly, but so as a,
as a modern knowledge worker athlete,
as an intellectual athlete,
you want to function like an athlete,
which means you train hard,
then you sprint, then you
rest, then you reassessed,
you get your feedback loop, then you
train some more than you sprint again,
then you rest.
Then you reassess this idea that you're
going to have linear output just by
cranking everyday at the same amount
of time saying that's that's machines.
You know machines should be working
nine to five humans are not meant work.
Nine o'clock are not meant to work nine
to five. No, I agree whole heartedly.
But that's for people that
are working for someone,
there's not really that option. So
that's unfortunately the, the rub, right?
That that's kind of where
my tweet storm starts,
which is first of all the first thing.
If you're going to make money is that
you're not going to get rich renting at
your time. Even lawyers and doctors who
are charging three, four, $500 an hour,
they're not getting rich because their
lifestyle is slowly ramping up along with
their income and they're
not saving enough. Uh,
they just don't have
that ability to retire.
So the first thing you have to do is
you have to own a piece of a business.
You need to have equity either
as an owner and an investor,
shareholder or a brand that you're
building that accrues to you to gain your
financial freedom.
Yeah,
and I was really fascinated by another
thing that you were bringing up about
working for yourself that
you feel in the future,
whether it's 50 or 100 years from now,
virtually everyone is going
to be working for themselves.
And I believe the way you put it is that
the information age is going to reverse
the industrial age.
Yeah.
If you go back to a hunter
gatherer times how we evolved,
we basically work for
ourselves. We communicated and
cooperative within tribes,
but each hunter,
each category stood on their own and then
combine their resources for the family
unit. But there was no
boss hierarchy, hierarchy,
hierarchy where you're like the third
middle manager down in the farming age.
We became a little bit more
hierarchical as we had to run farms,
but even those were still
mostly family farms.
It's industrial work with factories that
sort of created this model of thousands
of people working together on one thing
and having bosses and schedules and
times to show up. The reality is if you
have to go, I don't care how rich you are,
I don't care whether you're like a top
Wall Street banker, if you have to go,
if somebody has to tell you,
if somebody can tell you when to be at
work and what to wear and how to behave,
you're not a free person.
You're not actually rich.
So we're in this model now where we think
it's all about employment and jobs and
intrinsic in that is that I
have to work for somebody else,
but the information age
is breaking that down.
So Ronald Coase is an economist
who has this coast theater.
I'm very famous Theorem,
but it basically just talks about
why is a company the size that it is.
Why is the company one person instead of
10 people instead of a hundred instead
of a thousand?
And it has to do with the internal
transaction costs versus the external
transaction costs. Let's say
I want to do something, uh,
let's say I'm building a house and I
need someone to come in and provide the
lumber. I'm a developer, right?
Do I want that to be part of my company
or do I want that to be an external
provider?
A lot of it just depends on how hard it
is to do that transaction with someone
externally versus internally.
If it's too hard to keep doing the
contract every time externally,
I'll bring that in house.
If it's easy to do externally
and it's a one off kind of thing,
I'd rather keep it out of the house.
Well,
information is making it easier and easier
to do these transactions externally.
It's becoming much easier to
communicate with people. GIG economy.
I can send you small amounts of money.
I can hire you through an APP,
I can rate you afterwards,
so we're seeing an atomization of the
firm we're seeing the optimal size of the
firm is shrinking.
It's most obvious in silicon valley.
Tons and tons of startups constantly
coming up and shaving off little pieces of
businesses from large companies
and turning them into huge markets.
So what looked like the
small little vacation rental
market on craigslist is now
suddenly blown up into airbnb.
One example, that's one example,
but what I think we're going to see is
whether it's 10 2050 a hundred years from
now,
high quality work will be available.
We're not talking when
I'm driving an Uber,
we talking about super high quality
work will be available in a gig fashion
where you'll wake up in the morning,
your phone will buzz and you'll have
five different jobs from people who have
worked with in the past or
had been referred to you.
It's kind of like how Hollywood already
works a little bit with how they're
organized for a project. You decide
where to take the project or not,
the contract is right there in the spot.
You get paid a certain amount and you
get rated every day or every week you get
the my delivered and then
when you're done working,
you turn it off and you go to Tahiti
or wherever you want to spend the next
three months.
And I think the smart people have already
started figuring out that the Internet
enables this and they're starting to
work more and more remotely on their own
schedule,
on their own time and their own place
with their own friends in their own way.
And that's actually how we
are the most productive.
So the information revolution by
making easier to communicate, connect,
and cooperate is allowing us to
go back to working for ourselves.
And that is my ultimate dream. Even when
I run a company and I have employees,
I always tell those people,
hey,
I'm going to help you start
your company when you're ready.
Because I think that's the
highest calling. Maybe not
everybody will get there,
but it would be fine if
we were even working at 10
person company or a 20 person
company is way better than working
in a thousand person company,
a 10,000 person company.
So this idea that we're all factory like
cogs in a machine who are specialized
in have to do things by rote memorization
or instruction is going to go away.
And we're going to go back to being
small groups of creative bands of
individuals setting out to do missions.
And when those missions are done,
we collect our money,
we get rated,
and then we arrest and reassess
until we ready for the next sprint.
Has there ever been a study done on
happiness as it regards to the size of
companies? Not that I'm aware of,
but to me it's obvious. It's just
yes, the smaller the company,
the happier you're going to be.
The more human year relations are,
the less you have rules to operate under,
the more flexible, the more creative,
the more you'll be treated like a human.
Just because you were able
to do multiple things.
Yeah. Um, this brings me to what is a,
a subject that keeps getting brought up
nowadays is universal basic income with
the oncoming apocalypse of automation
is this is how it's being portrayed by
Andrew Yang,
who's running for president.
I sat down and talked to them about it's
very compelling and he's a very smart
guy and he's an entrepreneur himself.
And when he starts talking
about automation and how
it's going to just eliminate
massive amounts of jobs and leave
people stranded, what do you,
when I know you're a guy that thinks about
the future and I'm going to take this
unpopular point of view on this, I think
it's a non solution to a non problem.
Mm.
Ooh.
And I mean that in the sense
that automation has been
happening since the dawn
of time. Mainly electricity came along
that put a lot of people out of work,
did it right. A lot of people carrying
buckets of water and you know,
lighting lamps and all
those kinds of things.
And this was the concern with
factories as well, or apps, everything.
Literally every single thing that comes
in the printing press. Absolutely.
And what it does is it frees
people up for new creative work.
So the question is not is
going to eliminate jobs.
There is no finite number of jobs.
We're not like sitting around dividing
up the same jobs that were around since
the stone age.
So obviously in new jobs are being
created and they're usually better jobs,
more creative jobs.
So the question is,
how quickly is this transition going to
happen and what kinds of jobs will be
eliminated and what kinds of jobs
will be created. It's impossible.
Looking forward to predict what
kinds of jobs will be created.
If I told you 10 years ago that podcast
it was going to be a job or that, uh,
you know,
playing video games is going to be a
job or commentating and video games,
it's going to be a job you would
have laughed me out of the room.
Those are nonsense jobs.
But yet here we are.
So society will always create new jobs.
Civilization creates new jobs,
but it's impossible to predict what
those jobs are. So the question is,
how quickly is that transition happening?
All the reality is,
even though everybody keeps talking
about this automation apocalypse,
where did record low unemployment?
Explain that.
Where does the transition Donald Trump,
that's how it, all I'm saying is it's,
it's, it's, I don't see it in the numbers.
I don't see it actually happening.
The question is how quickly
can you retrain people? So
it's an education problem.
The problem with the UBI,
there's a couple of problems that ubi.
One is you're creating a straight,
you creating a slippery slide
transfer straight into socialism,
right?
The moment people can start
voting themselves money
combined with a democracy,
it's just a matter of time before
the bottom 51 votes themselves.
Everything in the top 49 and it just,
it,
and by the slippery slope
fallacy is not a philosophy.
And I know people like saying that, but
they haven't thought it through. Um,
but the moment you start having a
direct transfer mechanism like that in a
democracy,
you're basically doing it with capitalism,
which is the engine of economic growth.
You're also forcing the entrepreneurs
out or telling them not to come here. Uh,
the estimate I saw for 15 k a year,
a basic income for everybody will
be three quarters of current GDP.
And of course GDP was shrinking responses.
All the entrepreneurs fled.
So you would essentially
bankrupt the country. Uh,
another issue with Uva is that
people who are down on their luck,
they're not looking for handouts.
It's not just about money,
it's also about status.
It's about meaning.
And the moment I started giving
money to you and put you on the Dole,
I have lowered your status.
I've made you a second class citizen.
So I have to give you meaning and meaning
comes through education and capability
I have.
You have to teach a man to fish,
not to basically throw your writing
leftover carcasses that haven't say here,
eat the scraps. So it doesn't
solve the meaning problem.
And lastly, it's nonsense.
The hand 15 k out to everybody
you want to means test people.
There's no reason to
give it to you and me.
So you end up back towards the welfare
system where you do have to figure out
who needs it and who doesn't.
So I think the better route is that
we actually establish a set of basic
substance services that you have to have
and we provide those in abundance to
technology based automation. So
get basic housing, get basic food,
get basic transportation, get
high, high speed Internet access,
get a phone in your pocket.
Those are the kinds of things
you want to give people. Um,
and finally,
in terms of the rate of automation,
I think we can educate
people very quickly.
One of the myths that we have today
is that adults can't be reeducated.
We view education as this
thing where you go to school,
you come out when you're out of college
and you're done. No more education.
Well that's wrong.
You have all these great online boot
camps and coding schools coming up.
They're ones that are even
pay you to go there. Now. Um,
you can educate people and mass and
you can educate them into creative
professions. People who are talking
about Ai, automating programming.
I've never really written serious code.
Coding is thinking it's
automated structure.
Thinking an AI that can program as well
or better than humans is an AI that just
took over the world. That's end game.
That's the end of the human species. Uh,
and I can give you arguments why I
don't think that's coming either. Um,
people who are thinking,
and I know I take the opposite side from
some very famous people in this debate,
but we're nowhere near close to
General Ai, not in our lifetimes.
You don't have to worry about it. Even in
our lifetimes really. It's so overblown.
Uh, it's a, it's another,
it's a combination of
Cassandra complex. You know,
it's fun to talk about the end of the
world. Um, combined with a god complex,
like people who have lost religion.
So they were looking for meaning
and some kind of end of history. Um,
the reason why I don't think AI is coming
anytime soon is because a lot of the
advances and so so-called AI
today or what we call narrow AI,
they really pattern recognition,
machine learning to figure out like,
what is that object on the screen or
how do you find the signal and all that
noise. There's nothing approaching
what we call creative thinking, uh,
to actually model general intelligence.
You run into all kinds of problems. First.
We don't know how the brain works at all.
Number two,
we've never even modeled a paramecium
or an Amoeba, let alone the human brain.
Number three,
there's this assumption that all of the
computation is going at the cellular
level, at the neuron level, whereas
nature is very parsimonious.
It uses everything at his disposal.
There's a lot of machinery inside the
cell that is doing calculations that is
intelligent, that isn't accounted
for. And the best estimates,
I would take 50 years of Moore's law
before we can simulate what's going on
inside a cell near perfectly and probably
a hundred years before we can build a
brain that can simulate inside the cells.
So putting it at saying that,
I'm just going to model neuron is on or
off and then use that to build the human
brain is overly simplistic.
Furthermore, I would pause it.
There's no such thing
as general intelligence.
Every intelligence is contextual within
the context of the environment that it's
in. So you have devolved
an environment around it.
So I think a lot of people
who are peddling general AI,
the burden of proof is on them.
I haven't seen anything that would lead
me to indicate we're approaching general
AI.
Instead we're solving deterministic,
closed set finite problems
using large amounts of data,
but it's not sexy to talk about it.
If you,
you're talking about mirroring the actual
abilities of cells or are you talking
about recreating the actual mechanism?
Like what?
What is going on inside
cells and biological organisms that we
just don't know how intelligence works.
We don't know.
No idea.
So most of the AI approaches basically
say we're going to try and model how the
brain works,
but then model at the neuron level,
which is saying this neurons
on that neurons off, they're
combining their signal,
but I'm saying in the neuron is a
cell inside the cell there's all this
machinery going on that's operating
the neuron that is also part of the
intelligence apparatus. You can't just
ignore that and abstract that out.
You have to model it down to
the inside the cell level.
It's also a part of the
biological organism itself.
Exactly and it has all
these needs that you know,
the biological organism has to have
food and rest and it's actually,
it's a balance going on.
But when you eliminate all that,
when there is none of that,
and it's just calculations and we get to
a point where it's just this thing that
we've created,
whether you call it a computer where it
doesn't have to be a moving thing even,
but a thing that you've
created that stores virtually
all the information that's
available in the world,
star stores,
all of the patterns of all the thinking
of all the great people that have ever
lived,
all the writers,
all the people that have ever published
anything on the people that have ever
spoken, any words, stores,
all of their points,
all of their counterpoints,
other contradictions,
applies logic and reason and some
sort of sense of the future and starts
improving upon these patterns and then
starts acting on its own based on the
information that's been provided with,
well first you would have to actually
simulate a structure of the human brain
that can hold all that information.
You're basically talking about tens of
thousands of brains worth of information,
right? We can't even build one brain
the next decade or two or three. Well,
in terms of an actual physical brain,
yes,
but what about something that recreates
the abilities of a brain then?
Like I said,
nature is parsimonious.
So we've got this three pound wetware
objects that can hold all this data.
Nature has been very efficient in
evolving kind of how we get there.
I just don't think computers are
anywhere close to that. Like that.
It can hold that amount of data with
that complexity with like the holographic
structure of the brain working recall
in many, many different ways. Uh,
and then I don't think you can evolve
a creature to be intelligent outside of
the boundaries of feedback in a
real medium. Like if you evolve,
if you raised the human being a concrete
cell with no input from the outside,
they wouldn't have any
feedback from the real world.
They wouldn't evolve properly.
So I think just dumping information into,
into a thing isn't enough.
It has to have an environment to
operate and to get feedback from.
It needs to have context, but isn't
that biological? I mean, what if you,
if you have just the,
all the information that people have
accumulated and the lessons that people
have learned and you programmed
that into the computer. Like if,
if we can take a computer that
can beat someone at chess, the,
the real question was,
well,
can we make some sort of an artificial
intelligence that could beat someone a go,
which is far more complex than chess.
They figured out how to do that too,
and that was a giant shock,
right? These are still manmade,
very closed bounded games.
They're, they're not,
they're not on the road to
the unbounded game of life.
They are completely artificial.
But this didn't go well.
Didn't that give you like
a little bit of a pause?
A little bit go is not go or
league of legends or Fort Night.
They're not completely deterministic,
but they're still very artificial
and very bounded games.
Being good at go doesn't mean that you
can then suddenly figure out how to write
great poetry, right? The creativity
for sure is something that's,
creativity is the last frontier.
So I do believe that automation over a
long enough period of time or replace
every non creative job or every,
not creative work,
but that's great news. That means that
all of our basic needs are taken care of.
And what remains for us is to be creative,
which is really what every human wants.
Yeah. When, what are you doing right now?
This is the creative job. Sure. Um, that,
that brings us back to the idea of
meaning and universal basic income. Uh,
I think the idea of giving someone
$15,000 a year doesn't necessarily cause
whatever, whatever one would worry
about is people being on the Dole.
You would have a bunch of listless
people out there with no meaning in life.
But the idea is that $15,000 a year,
and I'm not necessarily sure
I agree with this, I'm not,
I'm not even endorsing this,
but that $15,000 a year,
we just provide you with the
necessities to get by in life.
It would give you food. They
would give you shelter. Well,
that's not gonna stop at 15
because the moment people are like,
I'm getting 15 or like,
then people will demand more Bernie
Sanders and beyond the, I'm 16, 17, 18,
19 these companies are too big. Yeah.
That could, it doesn't, it doesn't stop.
It just,
it just goes all the way to bankruptcy.
And the concern is a slide to
socialism. It's obvious. I mean, heck,
if I was on, if I was not working
and I was getting my 15 year,
I would happily voted for the
guy who would give me 20 or 25.
It's just common sense.
What do you say to the people that don't
believe that there is such a thing of
ethical as ethical or
compassionate capitalism?
And then there's many people today
that are espousing Marxism and they're
espousing some sort of a socialist society
where they believed that capitalism
is screwed people over and,
uh,
eliminated the middle class and they're
absolutely problems with capitalism.
I think monopolies are a
problem. I think that, uh,
crony capitalism is a problem
with the government, you know,
kind of gets in bed with them
and sort of forces things. Uh,
I think the bankers have really,
you know,
rape society and the rest of us
are suffering literally. Yeah.
They have essentially taken huge risks
where they prioritize the gains and the
socialize the losses.
So when it fails,
they basically get bailed out
and bankrupt everybody else. Uh,
so the capitalism has
gotten a really bad name.
Let's talk about as free exchange.
Free
markets,
free markets and free exchange are
intrinsic to humans from when the first
person started a fire and somebody
came along with a deer and said, hey,
if I cooked my dear in your fire,
I'll share some of it with you. Right?
So specialization of labor, we trade
that's built into the human species.
Basic math comes from accounting, keeping
track of debts and credits and so on.
We need to be able to
engage in free trade.
The correct criticism of capitalism
is when it does not provide equal
opportunity. And so we should always
strive to provide equal opportunity.
But people confuse that
with equal outcome.
When you have equal outcome that can
only be enforced through violence because
different people,
free people make different choices
and when they make different choices,
they have different outcomes.
If you don't let them suffer
the consequences of bad
choices or reap the rewards
from good choices, then you are forcibly
redistributing through violence.
It's interesting that there isn't.
There are no socialist working socialist
examples that exist without violence.
You basically need someone to
show up with a gun and say, okay,
you're not allowed to do that.
You hand this over to that person.
So one of the reasons why this podcast
is because I believe everybody can be
wealthy. Everybody. It's not a zero
sum game. It is a positive sum game.
You create something brand new,
you exchange with me for
something brand new I've created,
there's higher utility for both of us.
The some of the value created is positive.
It's not like status where
it's like you're higher up.
I'm lower down your presidents.
I must be vice president.
You're a plus one I'm a minus one.
It has to cancel the zero.
We should all be all for playing positive,
some ethical games.
The problem is because of these looters
who have ruined capitalism's name,
that then you get socialists coming in
and saying, burn the whole system down.
You burn the whole system down.
We end up like Venezuela or the
former Soviet Union, you know,
you don't want to be a fail socialist
states with Mac to teens hunting cats on
the streets to eat. Right.
That's literally what happens
in some of these places.
Uh, so I think it's very important not
to destroy the engine of progress that
brought us here. Yeah. The idea that
socialism just hasn't worked yet,
that it needs to the, we just need to
do it right. If we do it right, we can.
If you ever hundred a hundred
million dead and yeah.
Well let's keep trying all over the world.
Yeah.
And every single time it's implemented.
Have you ever had a conversation with
someone who's a socialist? Were we,
many times some of my better
friends are socialists. Really?
We really get into
that. Yeah. What is the,
I mean there's anyone have a
compelling perspective at all.
I think really socialism comes
from the heart, right? Y'All.
We all want to be socialist.
Capitalism comes from the head because
they're always cheaters in any system.
And there's incentives in any system.
So when you're young, if you're,
if you're not a socialist, you
have no heart. When you're older,
if you're not a capitalist,
you have no head, right?
You haven't thought it through.
So I understand where it comes from.
I always like Nassim Taleb framing on
this where he said, with my family,
I'm a communist with my close friends,
I'm a socialist. Uh, you know,
at my state level politics, I'm a Democrat
at, you know, higher levels. I'm a,
I'm a Republican. And that the federal
level and the Libertarian, right?
So basically the larger
the group of people,
you have mass together who have different
interests, the less trust there is,
the more cheating there is, the better
the incentives have to be aligned,
the better the system has to work.
The more you are towards capitalism,
the smaller the group you're in,
you're in a Kibitz you and you're a,
and you're in your house, you
in your tribe. By all means,
be a socialist with my aunts,
with my brother,
with my cousins and my uncles and
my mom. But family, I'm a socialist.
That's the right way to live. A
loving, happy, integrated life.
But when you're dealing with strangers,
I mean you want to be a real socialist.
Great. Open all your doors
and windows tomorrow please.
Everybody come take what you want.
See how that works out.
Yeah. Um, this idea of income inequality,
that always strikes me as a very,
it's a deceptive term.
Income inequality.
Well, let's flip it around. It
comes from outcome inequality. Yeah.
And the outcome inequalities there because
you made different choices. Now again,
going back, if it was because he
didn't have the same opportunities,
that's a problem.
So society should always
try to give people equal
opportunities. So for example,
instead of basic income,
what if we had a retraining program
built into our basic social fabric,
which said that every four years or
every six years or whatever it is,
maybe it's every 10.
You can take one year out and we'll
pay for you to go retrain completely.
And you can go into any profession you
like that has some earning power and
output,
uh,
hopefully a creative longterm profession
and you can reeducate yourself.
That would be much better for society on
all levels. Then basically just saying,
now you're going to be the
Dole for the rest of your life.
MMM.
Yeah.
Just you'd have to lead that horse
to water and then make them drink.
It requires people to put in some
effort. Yes. We can all just sit around.
It's just not well, that's my
perspective on income inequality.
There's always effort, inequality,
and thought inequality.
There's just certain
people that are obsessed.
And if those people become successful,
it doesn't mean they stole from you.
It just means that they put in the amount
of energy and effort that is required
to reach where they're at.
And there's a lot of Richard's signaling
that goes on now where people say, well,
it's cause you're privileged. You know
what the greatest privileges you're alive,
85% of humanities dead.
So how privileged are you then?
You're living in the first world. Then
you're, you know, you have four limbs,
et cetera.
So you can take that argument all the way.
It's kind of a nonsense discussion.
Well,
it's a very weird progressive argument
and it as it pertains to a race is always
a weird one, right? Because
white privilege to me is,
although you could look at what
they're saying on paper, like yes,
yeah, I'm sure there's more black
people that are harassed by the police.
I'm sure there was more black people who
are treated suspiciously by shop owners
in the light. But the problem isn't
the people who aren't treated poorly.
The problem is the people
who treat the people poorly.
The problem is racism.
The problem is not people that didn't ask
to be born white or whatever they are,
and they don't get harassed that,
so this idea of white privilege or
male privilege or whatever it is,
that's not the problem.
You're,
you're just looking at someone who's
not a victim of this particular problem
that you're highlighting,
but you're not looking at the
perpetrators of the problem.
You're making people perpetrators by
simply existing and having less melanin in
their skin or having their answer
assessors come from that's
just racism by another.
It's another sneaky way being racist
and then they say you can't be racist.
It's not racist because you're white.
That's right. That is this hilarious.
If you can't be racist
against white people,
that one as a variation of the whole
still while I hit you argument, you know,
stop struggling while I'm hitting you,
but it's just so silly.
You've just completely
change what racism means.
What's hilarious is it mostly the people
who are yelling racist and not the
minorities? What I look on my Twitter
or my social media or on my news,
it's white on white violence,
virtue signal.
It's white on white violence was
mostly going on is it's elitist whites,
blue state whites, college educated
whites beating up on high school,
educated whites,
blue collar.
It's a white collar versus blue collar
war that's going on and the rest of us
are just kind of watching like,
oh, that's kind of interesting.
Well it's also a side effect of
the ability to broadcast, right?
Like everyone with a Twitter handle
has the ability to broadcast.
Everyone with a Facebook page has the
ability to pontificate and have these long
rambling,
these huge statements that people put
out when you read them. It's like,
how much time did you put in this and
what the fuck do you put that much time of
your kids or your job or your job or your
life or your future planning for your,
you know, how much do you work out
a day? I mean you just, these some,
I've read some people's Facebook posts.
I'm like,
this is a preposterous amount of effort
that you put in the saying virtually
nothing.
Let's see. Humans are being creative.
It's the Ai do that. Well that's true.
It is create. It's, it's okay.
Creative in a very odd way,
right?
Cause it's creative and that they're
trying to elicit a response from people in
there trying to raise their, their
social value or raise their position,
the social
totem pole.
It's signaling and it's easy signaling
because of the kind of thing that
everybody has to agree with you on it
because nobody wants to be seen as a
horrible person.
And it's a very hard to make the nuanced
arguments against than it is to just
kind of go along.
Right. Well it's also, it's, some of
it is so cliche that it seems like,
I know one guy who poses
as a woman on on Twitter,
but he does it just obviously,
what is the name?
Tatiana Mcgrath
graph? Yes. Yeah. Used to
be Godfrey Elwick. Yes. Oh,
is that the same guy thing?
So yeah. That's hilarious. Yeah, I
did not. They killed his account.
They can't get the same one for that
hundred percent sure for pretending to be
trans racial. That's
right. They didn't leave.
He basically says all the crazy
stuff that people on the left say,
but he says the craziest yes. And kind
of just shows how it's okay to say it.
Like I think I saw a tweet from recently
just said or her that it's not okay to
be white. Yes. And then some people agree,
but it's,
it's so close to what they say.
It's so close that it's like the most
artful form of subtle parody because if
you replace in half of these things that
you replaced the word white with black
or Asian, what's the Lynch mob
descended on you? Yeah. It's,
it's a strange time in that respect
that there's a famous old saying,
if you want to see who rules over you
see who you are not allowed to criticize.
Mm, excellent. Yeah, that
is a, that's so true, right?
Yeah. That's so true. I wonder where
this is going. I really do. I'm,
I wonder because this is,
it seems like this new found ability
to broadcast that we have with,
whether you have a youtube page or
whether you have a Twitter or whatever,
you're doing,
this new found ability to spread whatever
you're trying to say to so many people
with very little understanding
on the most part,
from what it's actually a
great thing overall. Yeah.
It means that any human can broadcast
to any other human on the planet at any
time. So, for example,
if you know a totalitarian dictator
where to come to power and someone was
beating up,
you know,
had fascist beating up an old women like
that would get broadcast out instantly
there would be an instant outrage, hue
and cry rallying. So in that sense,
it helps bring attention
to the plight of anybody.
But right now we're going through the
phase where we have this new found power
to assemble mops and people
don't know how to deal with that.
So it becomes very easy to set up
a mob and have it attack somebody.
Take all the context out.
Like even this conversation,
I'm sure people will take out snippets
to put him on social media and try and
get somebody's outraged. Of course.
Uh, and so you have to learn how it,
first of all, society just has to get
over to this idea of outrage. Like to me,
like outreach people are the people
who get easily outrage of the stupidest
people on social media. Those are
the people I block instantly. Uh,
it's just kind of very low level thinking,
right? These are the foot's off the,
these are the foot soldiers in the mob.
Eventually society just
has to get over it.
They have to understand that these are
all snippets being taken out of context.
These are doctored video clips.
These are just someone who's trying to
get outraged over something. Eventually,
there'll also be anti mob
tactics. Like for example, if,
if I go to someone's Twitter feed and
all it is, it's full of political,
political, ranting, raving
conspiracy theories.
Do I want to work with this person
doing associate with this person?
Do want to be friends with this person?
Their mind is just cluttered with junk.
I don't necessarily blame them.
I think that the human brain is not
designed to absorb all of the world's
breaking news.
24 seven emergencies injected straight
into your skull with clickbait headline
news. If you pay attention to that
stuff, even if you're well meaning,
even if your sound of mind and body,
it will eventually drive you insane.
This is goes to clockwork
orange where he's, you know,
has his eyes opened up this
forced to watch the news.
But I think that's what's happening right
now because these are addictive, right?
Twitter, Facebook, Instagram,
these are weaponized.
You have social statisticians
and scientists and
researchers and people in lab
coats.
Literally best minds of our generation
and figuring out how to addict you to the
news and if you fall for it,
if you get addicted,
you're brain will get destroyed.
And I think this is the modern struggle,
like the modern struggle. So the ancient
struggle used to be the tribal struggle.
You had your tribe of friends and family,
you had your religion,
you had your country, you had
your loyalty, their nationality,
at least you had meaning and support.
But now you would struggle against other
tribes. Modern life, we're so free.
Everything's become atomized. We stand
alone. You live in your apartment alone,
you live in your house alone and
your parents don't live nearby.
Your friends don't live nearby.
You don't have any tribal meaning.
You don't believe in religion anymore.
You don't believe in country anymore.
It's fine. You've got a
lot of freedoms, fantastic.
But now when they come to attack you,
you're alone and you can't resist.
So how do they attack you?
It's all well meaning I don't fault
capitalism, I love capitalism.
But look at how it happens.
Social Media,
they've massaged all the
mechanisms to addict you,
like a Skinner pigeon or a rat who's
just going to click, click, click, click,
click camp,
put the phone down,
the food they've taken
sugar and the weaponized it,
they've put it into all these different
forms and varieties that you can't
resist eating drugs,
right?
They've taken pharmaceuticals and
plants and they've synthesize them.
They've grown them in such a way
that you can't, you get addicted,
you can't put them down point,
right? If you're a young male,
you want to around the internet,
it'll like SAP away your libido and
you're not going out in real life society
anymore.
Cause you've got this
incredibly stimulating stuff
coming at you video games,
another way to Dick People.
So you have this,
you have entire large factories of
people that are working to addict you to
these things and you stand alone.
So the modern struggle as an individual
is learning how to resist these things
in the first place.
Drawing your own boundaries and
there's no one there to help you.
Oof. That's terrifying. I mean, it is,
if we do road that needs to be
navigated by young people that are,
there's no map, there's no
guidebook on how to handle this.
Our generation is the
transition generation.
I think our kids will know how to handle
it better cause they'll grow up with,
I hope,
I hope.
I hope too,
because you're seeing some ridiculous
behavior from people today that's so
common. I mean, I don't know if
you've been paying attention to this,
but there was a guy who,
he made a, uh, a video of,
it turns out it wasn't even
him that made the video.
At least that's not what he said.
But it was a video where he sort
of doctored Nancy Polosi talking.
It made it look like she was drunk.
And then a bunch of people
retweeted it and like, oh my
God, look, she's drunk. And,
and so one of the online
publications, uh, uh,
some website tracked him down
and doxed him and turned out he's just
a day labor who is an African American
Trump fan.
And thought it would be funny to do that.
And it turns out that he didn't even,
at least according to him,
he actually just put it
up on his Facebook page.
What's even more disturbing is Facebook
gave up his information to this website.
Right. For what? Cause he made something
funny that made people seem drunk.
There's a million of those about me.
I mean,
you could find them mean I think Facebook
and Twitter and a bunch of these other
social media platforms are committing
slow motion suicide through these kinds of
activities.
That was a stunning one though,
that they would give up this guy who's a
labor because he made a parody video or
he made someone look foolish with editing.
Well,
you now have basically the media views
it as their job to go after individuals
they don't like. Yeah. I used media
with air quotes in that regard. Yes.
I don't think this is something that
the New York Times would have done us
anything responsible, but the media is
getting more and more desperate, right?
Because what happened
was before the Internet,
you could have two local newspapers in
every town and you could have two local
news stations,
TV stations in every town.
And then CNN came along and
started commoditizing the
news 24, seven broadcast,
and then the internet came along.
And that was the final nail in the coffin.
Because what the Internet did was it said,
actually,
if there's a fact that's news,
you can distribute that immediately.
It can go on Twitter,
it can go on Facebook.
It gets reprinted and Google
news a thousand times, you know,
you go on Google News, you're like, okay,
what's the piece of news? Which source?
And 3000 other articles. Too many, right?
So news has become commoditized.
So the entire news media has shifted
into peddling opinions and entertainment.
And so now they've become a variation
between like cheerleaders, shock troops,
enforcers, uh, you know, talking
heads. So these are now tribal,
these are not propaganda
machines signaling for their
tribes. It's a right wing.
One is left wing one, right? There's
the alt right, there's a control left.
And the two of them were just fighting
it out using their various media organs
in memes. So basically when you see one
of these news organizations, doxing,
an individual that's like a tank running
over a soldier, that's what's going on.
It's just a war. And so there's
no, there's no such thing anymore.
Less than neutral media commentator.
The,
the illusion of objectivity
that journalism had is lost.
There is no longer one guy,
like a Walter Cronkite that
everyone's going to listen to.
It's now the shock troops fighting wars
with each other. How does this play out?
Have you thought about it? Yeah, a little
bit. Uh, so what the Internet does,
a lot of this is internet driven.
What the internet does is the Internet
creates one giant aggregator or two for
everything. One taxi dispatcher, one
ecommerce store, one search engine,
one uh, you know, one social
media site for friends and family,
one for business,
et cetera.
So the Internet is this giant aggregator
where it creates one big hedge Amman
for everything.
And it creates an atomized long tail of
millions and millions of individuals.
What it gets rid of is the medium, medium
size ones in the middle. So for example,
you might've had like seven
Hollywood studios. What's
Origami? Netflix. You had a,
you know, like, uh,
10 large ecommerce players had commerce
players from Walmart to Costco to,
you know, Kmart and whatever. Nope,
not just going to be Amazon and
a ton of small individual brands.
So that's the world that
we're headed towards.
One Hedge Amman and
millions of individuals.
So we're ends up longterm is media
will be a few gigantic outlets.
You know, it could be the New York Times,
it could be Facebook, a few like that.
And there's going to be just a really
long tail of millions of independent
people. So this idea of who is a
journalist and who's not, you know,
is a Sandra journalists are
not everyone's a journalist.
That's the world that we're headed
towards. I do think that extreme power,
the most powerful people in the world
today, and this is not well known,
but the most powerful people in the world
today are the people who are writing
the algorithms for Twitter and
Facebook and Instagram because they're
controlling the spread of information.
They're literally rewriting people's
brains. They're programming the culture,
and they're doing it very subtly like
Google. I believe that, you know,
one of their execs got up
in front of Congress and the
Congressmen asked him, uh,
you know, do you manipulate
search results? And he said, no,
we do not manipulate search
results. Really, that's your job.
That is literally all Google does.
Google has one job,
which is to manipulate search results
to pull them out of the noise and rank
them properly. And the, the
precise algorithms of how
they do that is very hidden,
very complex, but influences the
hearts and minds of everybody,
including all the voters. Now, if Google,
Facebook and Twitter had been smart about
this, they would not have picked sides.
They would have said,
we're publishers,
whatever it goes through our pipes goes
through our pipes. If it's illegal,
we'll take it down, give us a court
order. Otherwise we don't touch it.
It's like the phone company.
If I call you up and I say something
horrible to you on the phone,
the phone company doesn't get in trouble.
But the moment they
started taking stuff down,
that wasn't illegal
because somebody screen,
they basically lost the right to be viewed
as a carrier and now all of a sudden
they've taken on liability. So they're
sliding down the slippery slope into ruin,
sloping to ruin where the left wants him
to take down the right, the right ones.
And I take down the left and now they
have no more friends. They have no allies.
Traditionally the libertarian leaning
Republicans and Democrats would have stood
up in principle for the common carriers,
but now they won't.
So my guess is as soon as Congress,
and this is, this day is coming,
if not already here,
it might even been here today actually
because you saw something related in the
news.
The day is coming.
When the politicians realize that these
social media platforms are picking the
next president,
the next congressman,
they are literally picking and
they have the power to pick.
So they will be controlled by
the government. In what way?
How do you think they're
going to be controlled?
We think they're going to have to adhere
to strict principles of freedom of
speech. Now, no,
unfortunately is headed the
opposite direction, right? Yeah.
I wish it was freedom of speech.
Uh,
much more likely they're going to
be in the short to medium term.
They're going to be hauled
in for hearings. Uh, they're
going to be pressured,
massively do this,
don't do that.
My concern about that is the
hearings that I saw with Zuckerberg,
those people were completely incompetent.
They are and seem to understand them.
They don't, but they're just applying
pressure. They just trying to scare him.
So he'll do what they want.
And what do they want them to do?
They want them to basically suppress
the other side. So if you're right wing,
you want to suppress the
left wing for left doing.
You want to suppress the right wing.
And if you just see where these companies
are headquartered in Silicon Valley,
um, all the sensors, and
that's really what they are.
There are sensors working inside
these companies that are just called,
they're called by different
names obviously, right?
Doublespeak you call it the department
defense wants the Department of war.
So in this case,
the Department of safety and trust,
when really it's the
department of censorship,
the sensors are inside Silicon Valley.
So it's going to reflect
Silicon Valley's politics,
which is extremely progressive.
Left ring. And if you're not that,
you really have no place.
There's, that's right.
Try being a conservative and open
conservative at Google. Good Lord.
Now you get lynched. Yeah,
that's crazy. I mean,
I don't think that there was ever a thing
like that that was so influential and
so politically, ideologically
one sided. Yeah. There's a,
there's a little saying on the Internet
thing. It's called conquest law,
that any organization that's
not explicitly left right
wing eventually becomes
left wing.
And I don't know why that's true,
but it does seem to me to be true.
What's a,
it's a fascinating battle that's going
on right now. I mean, it really is.
And conservatives in,
in as far as social media is concerned
that they're just getting chopped off at
the Hams left and right. Yeah. What
will eventually happen is that, uh,
whenever you suppress speech,
the organism metastasizes,
then it has to start
turning towards other means.
If you're unlucky goes towards violence,
uh,
if you're lucky they find other outlets.
Uh,
I think what will happen is we will
start creating decentralized media that's
not owned by any single entity that
can't be suppressed or shutdown.
That will then start spreading
these various things and
that will take the place
of Twitter or Facebook or whatever, but
it's going to take 10 years, 20 years.
It's not overnight. Well, uh, you know,
Twitter took 10 years to get to the
point where it's at this mess right now.
But it was so interesting too to have
Jack Dorsey in to talk to him about where
it's going, where you thinks is
going on in his own principles,
which he believes that it's a fundamental
right and he believes that freedom of
speech is something that we all should
have and that these platforms should
essentially be like,
like utilities,
like the electric company I think is
correct and he has the right vision.
It's just he's in an organization
where the other individuals in the
organization feel differently,
very differently.
So the organization itself
can get hijacked and his
timeline for changing things,
it's like it's decades. I mean, I don't,
I shouldn't say decades.
I mean I was like,
when do you think that something where
there was a park that was one idea of
having an uncensored Twitter, like
one Twitter, that's the wild west.
Like you can have regular Twitter or
you could try wild west Twitter like,
well that that already existed
and that were called Gab. Yeah.
Such as APP isn't even wild west Twitter
they did when when people, docs people,
they remove things like
that. Yeah. I mean,
I think there's certainly lines around
violence and reality that you don't want
to cross. But yes, gab is closer
to free speech platform. Uh,
but it's still not decentralized.
It can still get shut down.
I can still get taken out. It's also
suppressed heavily. Yes. So there,
and the people on there right
now are extremely right wing,
so it's not a pleasant place
for someone like me to hang out.
So that people that have been kicked off
of something. That's right. That's right.
Try going over there and being moderate.
Try going over there and there's no
room for you. Yeah, unfortunately,
because I don't identify as any
party here, any creed, you know,
it doesn't work for me.
Does that a problem in silicon valley
when you don't identify as anything? Do,
do you get pressure? It totally. It
used to be okay. It's not okay anymore.
When was it? Okay. 10 years
ago I would say it was okay.
And then you start seeing a shift.
Yeah. And now you have to pick sides,
otherwise you'll automatically
the enemy real. Yeah.
Struggle sessions and all that.
Okay. God struggle sessions.
I'm exaggerating for effect,
but it definitely has that
oppressive feeling to it.
Right. And you also have to be
politically outspoken. It can't,
it can't be something that you
just stay neutral about. Right.
It's like when a Tim Ferriss,
I think at some point put out a tweet
about how you can't just say anything
anymore and you know,
people are being suppressed and a whole
bunch of people who allowed them from
Silicon Valley pilot and said,
what is it that you can't say?
What are you afraid to say? You can
say whatever you want him. Go ahead.
What are you afraid of? Like baiting.
Yeah. Yeah. What was he trying to say?
Wow.
We have to put them in that box.
One is someone who was thinking
about saying something he
shouldn't have said it.
Exactly. Now we know one great tweet
us was, you know, the left one,
the culture wars and other just driving
around shooting the survivors. Wow.
That's hilarious. Yeah. I wonder,
uh, I wonder who as has one,
the cultural war,
the certainly a battle that's
been one in terms of like control,
social media control,
social media is absolutely laughable,
but this is unfortunate for conservatives,
but technology is a force
that also pushes left.
So if you look all
throughout human history,
like the left essentially grows and
grows and grows, right? Why is that?
Why is it an extra believe that
as some commentators have said,
Leviathan slouches left, right? For
the Leviathan is the government,
why does it smell?
She left?
And I think a lot of that has
been because of technology.
Technology has made it so that it
makes more like industrial revolution
technology. We all band together,
awards awarded the state, right?
Contraception is a technology
that kind of helps lean leftward.
It takes away from the family unit.
Abortion is a technology, right?
It wasn't possible thousands of years ago.
Um,
so technology actually
empowers the individual.
The individual means that you have
the breakdown of family structure and
religion and all that.
And I'm not necessarily opposed to that,
but it does mean that there's
a leftward shift to it.
Now we're getting a small
set of technologies that
actually can take you more,
right word,
uh,
encryption as an example
because the encryption makes
it easier to have privacy.
It makes it easier to have money that
is outside of the state. Um, guns,
three d printing of guns and example of
a technology that is more of a rightward
shift. Um, but generally
technology leads the world left.
Yeah.
It's also usually highly educated people
that are involved in technology in the
first place. And I think when you
look at universities in particular,
they tend to lean left
in this country as well.
Well, universities, uh, what happened
with the university is very interesting.
Universities first one, you know,
became the arbitrators of, uh,
data, intellectual ism, and
know what's right and wrong.
So that the time period when it was like,
should we be doing that or not? Well,
let's look at the university.
What do they have to say?
What are the smartest people, the
professors that think tanks have to say?
And the universities got this,
this credibility from the hard sciences.
So they got this from a,
you know,
physics and math and computer science
and chemistry because these deliver real
things. The Manhattan project,
the microprocessor, the
space vehicles and so on,
the electric car.
So they gained this mantle of authority
and legitimacy from the hard sciences.
So then come the social
sciences kind of sneaking.
Then you get economy economics and
microeconomics is a real discipline,
real science, real math behind it, logic
reason. And then you get macro economics,
which can be politicized
a little bit more voodoo.
And then you get social studies and then
you get gender studies and then you get
blah blah blah blah blah,
blah, blah, blah blah.
And so what happened is that because we
took scientists to be the high priests
of our new world, science itself has
gotten corrupted and the social sciences,
and you can tell they're
fake scientist because they,
the word science tacked on at the end
have come in and hijack the universities
and become the new think tanks.
And so essentially what you see going
on today in the universities is a war
between the social sciences
in the physical sciences.
And the crossover point is biology,
right?
Where you can see like the whole gender
is a social construct movement is
attacking biology and
evolutionary biology. Um, just
like in the social sphere,
they're coming after the comedians.
Right.
But you can see the struggle going on
in the universities and I would say the
physical sciences are
essentially losing that war.
What can be done? Or is it just
something that has to play out? Is it,
do we have to realize the consequences
of the foolishness and the good news of
the physical sciences have a
reality on their side? Yeah.
But it's not even, I mean, in
many ways it's not respected.
Yeah. But at the end of the day, you're,
your aircraft still has to fly. Uh,
you know, you're a microprocessor
still has to compute.
So there's only so far they can, they can
take it. Uh, but I do see, for example,
in biology,
a lot of biologists are facing this
difficult thing where they have to say
things that they know are not
true to keep their job. Like, Oh,
you had Bret Weinstein on here. Right. So
that's a, that's a clear example. So it,
there's just the crossover line of what
is acceptable and what's not is entering
into biology and biology will
probably suffer the most. Um,
synthetic biology for
example. Uh, will, you know,
a lot of this will end up in
China, um, because it won't be,
you won't be able to map facts
and reality and actions together.
You won't be able to get grants.
He won't be able to get the
adulation of your peers. Um, I don't,
I don't know enough here's
the nom and shaky territory,
but it's just my sense that that
crossover battleground right now as an
evolutionary biology economics lost.
Well,
it certainly in terms of gender
in the, that, that sort of,
that seems to be one of the
major battlegrounds. Yeah.
I mean, it's also going to happen if
we have a blank slate theory, you know,
are we nature or are we an immature?
Um,
it's kind of a socially
unacceptable to say that, you know,
a lot of it is in nature and
not nurture or vice versa.
Depending on which side you're on.
Those kinds of discussions get corrupted.
They do get corrupted.
Yeah.
It's really unfortunate because that's
an unbelievably important thing to
understand.
Like what makes a person a sociopath?
What makes a person a super
successful person, a winner. Right?
But what makes a person a drug addict?
What, what are, what are these factors?
You can't have a reasonable conversation
about climate science anymore. Right?
It's not a science, it's all
politicized. You can't even bring it up.
Everyone's got their
minds made up already.
Well,
it's,
what's uncomfortable to me is people
have their minds made up and they don't
even have it.
Yeah. Well, on most of these topics,
people are talking past each other anyway
and talking about different things.
Like when you get into, uh, you know,
when you, when you get into gun control,
for example,
right?
One side is talking about the right to
bear arms in case I to radical ruler king
tried to take over the
country the other time.
The other side is talking about
school shootings and you know,
protecting people in their homes,
right from crime.
So they're just talking about
two different things, right? Uh,
and it's just not politically acceptable
to even talk about the same thing.
Or when you get to immigration, the
Wright is talking about, uh, you know,
uh, the, the,
the left is like bundling together
illegal immigration and legal immigration
into one thing, right?
Whereas in the, on the right,
sometimes you got racist siting in there
so it doesn't help their cause. Right?
They're talking about
two different things.
If they were talking about the same thing,
which is how many immigrants should
we let into the country and you know,
what are the criteria for that?
That would be a very different
conversation than no immigrants are.
Everybody comes in. And then
also on the left, you know,
you had this benefit that everybody who's
currently coming in illegally is going
to vote for the left because of
where they're coming from and their
socioeconomic circumstances.
Um,
to me the test of any good system is
you build a system handed over to your
enemies to run for the next decade.
So for example,
if you want a censorship
on Twitter or Facebook,
you should build that system and then
hand it over to the other side to run.
So if you're a left winger
who is promoting a censorship,
let somebody else running. Same with
immigration. If you immigration system,
build the system then handed over to the
other side to run in there. So, you know,
it's a good system.
There's no room for nuance when you're
dealing with these political battle
grounds, when, when you're
dealing with right versus left.
And one side has a clearly established
stance that you're supposed to take.
Like gun control is a great example
of that, right? There's no room for,
what about mental health?
What about the fact that so many of these
people are on psych medication, right?
What, why is that not being discussed?
You're running one of the greatest, uh,
mental health experiments in history when
we're building great buddy up in Sris
and maybe you get 30 million people
Sris maybe like 29.9 million are a lot
happier and then you have a fraction
that commit suicide or detonate. Yeah.
You're basically trading the mean for the
variants. You have blow up risk. Yeah.
There's no room for nuance, which is
why I stay out of politics. Largely.
Do they drag you in though?
Sometimes. I always try.
I mean even conversations conversation
you get to get dragged in,
but I'm sure there's
going to be some people.
Here's the thing about politics because
there we have a first past the post
system. What that means is that whoever
wins 51% of the vote in this country,
he gets a lot of the power,
right?
It's not like proportional representation
where the Greens have 10% and you know
libertarians of 3% or whatever.
It's just like you're all Democrat
in power now are all Republican.
Because of that, to win, you have to pick
one of these two sides, right? You have,
you have to choose. You can't just, you
can't just, you can't just basically say,
I'm going to be, uh, you
know, nuanced about it.
You can't vote for third party to
throwing away your vote, right?
I have a friend who's tried to fix that.
He started this thing called a good party
where like, you kickstart your vote.
So you combine all your votes,
you hold them in reserve,
and then when you have enough to win,
then you vote that person in power, right?
You don't, you don't throw away your
boat. But outside of those hacks,
we're never going to get a third
party get elected. So because of that,
all of your beliefs have to neatly
fit into the Democrat bundle,
other Republican bundle. And so
when you get into that tribe, uh,
if you signal outside of that tree,
out of that bundle, you get attacked.
So it's literally,
it's making you into an unclear thinker.
It's making you into a muddle thinker.
If all of your beliefs line
up into one political party,
you're not a clear thinker.
If all your beliefs are the same
as your neighbors and your friends,
you're not a clear thinker.
You're literally just your beliefs.
They're socialized,
they're taken from other people.
So if you want to be a clear thinker,
you cannot pay attention to politics.
It will destroy your ability to think.
But what dread
most of modern life,
all our diseases are
diseases of abundance, not
diseases of scarcity, right?
All Times I may have starved. Uh, I'm,
you know, all times if I've got sugar,
that was a wonderful thing. I should've
eaten all the sugar to get my hands on.
If I got an a piece of news or gossip
that was interesting data that would have
helped my life and move me forward.
Um,
if I had gotten some brief
amount of entertainment,
whether through video games or magazines
or whatever, that would have been good.
Now it's all diseases, abundance.
We are overexposed to everything.
So the way to survive in modern
society is to be an ascetic.
It is to retreat from society. There's
too much society everywhere you go,
society and your phone, society in
your pocket, society in your ears,
you're being socialized right
now by listening to this podcast.
We're socializing.
You were programming you.
Everyone's trying to program everybody.
The only solution is to turn it off.
The only solution is to turn it off
and concentrate on your breathing.
Meditation. Yeah, I, yes, it works.
It's, it's been a lifesaver for me. Oh,
I do it and I do it whenever
I get like spare time.
I was at the doctor's
office this morning and uh,
I knew it was going to be 20 minutes,
so I just sat there with my eyes closed
for 20 minutes and I meditated. You know,
when I was growing up, there was this
statement, I think it was pascal. He said,
you know,
all of man's problems arise because he
cannot sit by himself in a room for 30
minutes alone. And it's very true.
I always needed to be stimulated.
And when the iPhone came along, boredom
was dead. I would never be bored again.
If I'm standing in line, I'm on my
iPhone and I thought it was great.
And when I was a kid I used to try
and over clock my brain be like,
how many thoughts can I think at once?
The answer is only one.
But I would try to like think
multiple thoughts at once.
And I was proud of that as proud
that my brain was always running.
This engine was always
moving and it's a disease.
It's actually the road to misery.
And now that I'm older,
I realize that you actually want to again,
rest your mind.
You want to learn how to
settle into your mind.
And now I look forward to solitary
confinement. You leave me alone for a day,
it'll be like the happiest
day I've had in a while.
And that is a super power that
I think everybody can attain.
The superpower of learning to be
alone and enjoying it. Yeah. Yeah.
Well I think it's critical and I,
and I do think that this, this,
these times where you
just think about things,
just be alone and think about
things are so rare these days.
And I think during those rare times is
when you really get to understand what
you actually believe or don't
believe. Yeah. It's, it's funny,
when I first started meditating, it was
really hard, right? Cause everybody,
I think a lot of people who are
listening to the broadcast ever heard of
meditation that has a good reps.
Everybody tries it, they struggle,
they kind of give it up. It's one of
those things that everybody says they do,
but nobody actually does. Right.
It's like not eating sugar. Right.
Everyone talks about how, yeah, I
don't need sugar with like, yeah,
then then the dessert tray rolls around
and everyone's going for the cookies.
Yup. Right? Yup. So it's become
one of those things and in fact,
it's not even become a signaling
thing where it's like, oh,
how much did you meditate? I
meditated this much. Right. You know,
there are people now wearing
headbands saying with tweety,
birds Chirp and then when they're
in deep meditation, I don't know,
I don't know how they make it work,
but they'll be like,
I got a lot of trips today. How many
trips did you get? Oh right. Oh,
you're a meditation technique
is wrong when it's right,
but really all it is is the
art of doing nothing. Okay.
And it's important because I think
when we, when we grow up, right,
it's all this stuff happening to you
in your life and some of it you're
processing some of ear absorbing and
some of it you should probably think a
little bit more about and work through,
but you don't, you don't have time.
So it gets buried in you and it's all
of these preferences and judgments and
unresolved situations and issues
and it's like your email inbox,
it's just piling up email after email
after email that's not answered going back
10 2030 40 years.
And then when you sit down to meditate,
those emails start coming back at
you. Hey, what about this issue?
What about that issue? Have you
solved this? Did you think about that?
Your regrets there,
you have issues there and that gets scary.
People don't want to do that. Like it's
not working. I can't clear my mind.
I better get up and not do this. But
really what's happening is it's, it's,
it's self therapy.
It's just that instead of paying a
therapist to sit there and listen to you,
you're listening to yourself
and you just have to sit there.
As those emails go through one by one,
you work through each of them until you
get to the magical inbox zero and there
comes a day when you sit down,
you realize the only thing is you're
thinking about or things that happen
yesterday because you've
processed everything else.
Not necessarily when resolve that,
but at least listen to yourself and
that's when meditation starts and I think
it's a,
it's a very powerful thing that everybody
should experience and that's when you
arrive upon the art of doing nothing.
Well,
I think it's even a problem that most
people are getting their meditation from
an APP. I will not use an APP. It's key.
I mean Sam Harris was a very good
meditation. Now I should say that,
but you should be able to
just do it and many people,
it is literally the art of doing nothing.
So all the initiative for meditation
is just sit down, close your eyes,
comfortable position, whatever happens,
happens. If you think you think,
if you don't think you don't think,
don't put effort into it,
don't put effort against it all you need.
Do you concentrate on your breath or do
you have a specific nothing, nothing.
Now you just said, he just said, I
think about my breath. That's all I do.
I just to try to only concentrate
on breathing. I used to do that,
but at some level,
all the concentration,
every meditation technique is
leading you to the same thing,
which is just witnessing and concentration
is a technique to still your mind
enough that you can then drop
the object of concentration.
So you could also just try
going straight to the end game.
The problem with what I'm talking about,
which is not focusing on your breath,
is you will have to listen to your mind
for a long time. It's not going to work.
Let's do at least an hour a
day and preferably at least
60 days before you kind
of worked through a lot of issues,
so it will be held for awhile,
but when you come out the other side,
it's great.
You get rid of the chatter or when the
chatter comes, it's in the background,
it's dimmer, it's smaller. You've heard
it before. You see the patterns. Uh,
it's more recent. It's something
you need to resolve any way.
And you will get moments of
actual silence. What is your,
what's your ultimate
state when you meditate?
Like is there a state where
you've achieved rarely if ever,
where you just, you, you are,
you're in bliss or you're in
harmony or urine enlightenment.
Like whether it's kind of,
it's kind of indescribable, uh,
because when you're really
meditating, you're not there.
When there's no thoughts,
there's no experience, there's nothing,
there's just nothing. Uh, so it's,
it's hard to describe, but
I would say that, uh, it's
like, uh, you can definitely,
every psychedelic state that
people encounter in using
so called plant medicines
can be arrived at just
through pure meditation.
And I've definitely hit
some of those states.
You've hit some transcendent psychedelic
states where you're anticipating the
whole deal. Had trippy visuals. I've
had the kind of the lights and colors.
I've had been the so called downloads.
I've had the realizations,
I've had the bliss, I've had the light
of the colors, but not every time. No,
it's really an in fact I would say that,
that that's uh,
that's also like an experience
that you can start craving,
which will then actually take you out
of meditation. Um, where you really, I,
and I'm not enlightened or anything
close to it, so not even the Ballpark,
but my own experience and this is just
personal experience is the place where I
ended up the most. That is
really the one that I, I,
I want to be at his peace.
Just peace. Peace, happy.
Yeah. Peace. To me,
peace is happiness at rest and
happiness is kind of piece in motion.
You can convert peace to
happiness anytime you want,
but pieces what you want most of the time.
That's interesting.
You can convert peace to
happiness and time you want. Yeah.
If you're a peaceful person,
anything you do will be happy activity.
And by the way,
being on social media,
engaging in politics will not bring you
peace. There's nothing less peaceful.
Right.
And today's Day and age,
the way we think you get peace is by
resolving all their external problems.
But there's unlimited external problems.
So the only way to actually get pieces
on the inside by giving up this idea of
problems, who thinks you can get piece
by resolving external problems other than
politicians, everybody. That's what
everybody is struggling to do. Right?
Why are you trying to make money to solve
all your money problems while you're
trying to win it politics?
Cause then you'll be at peace
because your people will have one.
It's a daunting task to
get your shit together.
It's easier to change yourself and
to change the world. That's true.
And the best way to change the world is
to change yourself. Exactly. It's all,
yeah, it's all these people who
are shouting on social media.
The best way is just to actually live
the life that you want other people to
live.
Uh,
like I went down to New Zealand and
there's this guy that I met with and uh,
you know,
everyone's on social media shouting
about environmentalism and conserve and
sustain. And I go to this guy's house
and he was doing a very quietly,
very gently,
he was doing a two week long,
a zero waste experiment where
he was throwing out nothing.
So every package that he opened he would
keep and he would like clean it up so
he could keep his Amazon boxes. You'd
keep the look and handed him a tea bag.
If he opened a tea bag he has to figure
out how to compost the tea inside,
how to make the tea itself useful,
how to make the tea bag like a little
storage item so there was no trash.
He was literally living with zero trash
waste and he was doing it and it was
really inspirational.
Meeting people like him made me far more
environmentally conscious than you know
any amount of people yelling at
me on social media ever will.
How long did he do that for? I
think it was two weeks. It was hard.
What the fuck are you
going to do with tea bags?
He had quite the collection was
filling them with little things. Yeah.
Sounds like you're crazy hoarder,
like a hoarder person stacks a tea bags
in his house for a pretty impressive guy.
Yeah, that's a strange way to go
about things. I, I appreciated that.
I mean look,
it is entirely possible to
somehow or another engineer,
all of our cups and all of our things
and all are about to be biodegradable.
If you know the struggle with the modern
environmental movement is that they
identify the correct problem,
which is finite earth
spaceship. This is all we got.
Don't ruin it. But they don't have the
solution. So what they say is no growth,
no growth,
no growth on.
The problem is you got 3 billion Indian
and Chinese who aren't going to stay in
poverty. They're going to grow
whether you like it or not.
So you can yell at them,
you can scream at them,
you can yell at us and scream at us.
But that's not going to happen.
So the only way out unfortunately
is again, through technology,
which is you have to
build green technology.
And I give Musk a lot of credit for being
one of the few people who's out there
trying to do that.
So you build things that are biodegradable
and good for you and healthier and
everybody wants to be healthier
in Chinese, want to be healthier.
India's want to be healthier, they
want to be cleaner. If you say,
I can clean up your rivers,
I can clean up your forests,
I can have your children not get sick
with cholera and diphtheria, typhoid,
I can cure your diseases. That can
help make your immune system stronger.
I can give you clean drinking water.
Like that is what causes people
to become environmentalists,
not shouting and screaming at them that
they shouldn't grow and they should stop
pumping things into the sky. And you
know, they have no concept of that.
They're just trying to get out of poverty.
So I think the modern environmental
movement identifies the correct problem,
but then doesn't come up with the right
set of solutions that are appealing to
people. People are not going
to give up economic growth.
They're going to have to get
rich first. That's, yeah,
that's a very good point. But how do
you do, how do, how do you do both?
You lower the price of cre,
clean technologies massively.
So you basically make clean technologies
cost competitive through subsidy
technologies.
Innovation.
Ideally you can subsidize in the short
to medium term until the innovation curve
is crossed. I mean, like Tesla doesn't
have any patents, right? Right.
Or they freely give away their patents.
That's an example of how you can do it.
Um, so you know, someone, if you want
to get rid of plastic straws, yeah,
you can do it here and there. You can
get San Francisco to ban plastic straws,
but China's not going to
blend banned plastic straws.
Not until you build a paper Straw that
is, you know, same cost, good durability,
and then you in, and then you educate and
Chinese like, Hey, this is petroleum. Uh,
you know, this plastic that you're doing
this patrolling. This is bad for you.
Here's the chemical composition.
Here's the things that are going in
your bloodstream. And they want healthy,
happy kids also. So they going to
have their kids use paper straws.
Maybe straws aren't the best
example, but you can, you know,
this is true with fossil fuels, for
example, that's probably the best one.
Or replacing a lot of plastics
with glass and paper and so on.
Yeah, there's a new technology that was
just Rhonda Patrick cut in on her Twitter
today about they're,
they're able to convert plastic waste
into fuel and that there's companies that
are actively trying to do that now.
So then in that way,
plastic waste will become valuable,
right?
And then it'll become a commodity and
it becomes something that people are
resource.
Now there's certain problem
this doesn't solve, this doesn't solve
carbon, this doesn't solve deforestation,
you know, so there you kind of have to
step in with other means. So for example,
you look at the Amazon,
right?
Everyone's complaining about the
Amazon being deforested. Well,
you're not the poor Brazilian
farmer, right? Right. So you're,
you're sitting here in your
comfortable chair, like social media,
hammering away at, you know, the evil
Brazilians for deforesting, the Amazon.
But the Amazon has incredible resources.
If we really care about it,
we should turn it into an
incredible tourist park.
And put your money where your mouth is,
start doing ecotourism and the Amazon
started paying for it and then maybe take
the future rights for all
the pharmaceuticals that
are going to come out of all
the incredible plants there and start
selling those off so that people,
so that maybe give the pharmaceutical
companies and incentive to preserve the
biodiversity in the Amazon. Say, Hey,
if you buy this patch of the Amazon,
you consider that and you can serve it
whatever plant medicines that come out of
there that you can then license,
you get the patent for 20
years or 30 years or whatever.
So I think there are solutions where we
as the first world who have money can
put our money where our mouth is and go
and rescue these kinds of properties.
That's a very interesting solution.
But I could see immediate pushback
from people that don't think the
pharmaceutical companies should have
the rights to this natural plant or the,
or the government does it and then the
government gets the patents and the
government,
we'll auction off the patents later or
they'll worse or the license them or
whatever it is. Right.
The often like just this,
the often the problem is there
is no really good solution.
There's a bunch of solutions that
also have drawbacks. That's life.
Yes. That's the trade offs
as being humans. Very messy.
Yeah.
It's a constraint environment.
Obviously I skew more towards a private
property capitalist type solutions
because even though they're not perfect,
they had been proven to actually work.
Right. When something is your
property, you take care of it, right.
You're not gonna, you're not going
to crap all over your own house. Um,
but it should probably be temporary
property, not permanent property.
You see a lot of countries in
the world and not doing this,
no foreign ownership of land thing,
for example.
Or Mexico has no private
ownership of beaches. Right.
So you can draw the
line at certain points.
[inaudible] yeah.
Do you enjoy doing this kind of thing
where you break things down and give your
perspective on things and try to
illuminate certain complex objects?
I'm not,
I'm not trying to eliminate so much as
you know, talking to you.
I learn as much as I say,
and I learned it from myself because
I'm being forced to articulate it.
I can sit around and think my
thoughts all day, but it's a lot of,
it's going to be nonsense.
It's not, I'm going to,
cause there are gaps in thinking where
you make leaps because you're kind to
yourself that you don't
realize you're making.
But when you're forced to write it down,
and this is why I tweet or when
you have to talk to somebody,
you have to complete those gaps
and make it a proper logical chain.
And the mistake that I made
when I was young was, you know,
I always want to seem like the smartest
kid in the room. Uh, you know, like,
just like you probably want to seem like
the funniest kid in the room where the
toughest kid in the room, right?
We're all losers starting out.
We want to be winners.
So we picked the thing we're good
at and we doubled down on it.
So I always want to be the smartest
kid in the room. So what did I do?
I read a lot of books,
I memorize a lot of things and then
whatever I hadn't memorized as pre
pre-google I made it up.
So that sounded good.
Pre-Google after Google fact checking
started and I had to get better, right?
So Google improve me that
way. A lot of people. Exactly.
So now what I realize is that the
biggest mistake was memorization,
right?
Because when you're actually trying to
live your life in Congress with reality,
you, you want to have a deep understanding
of what you do and why you do it.
And so it's much more important to know
the basics really well there is to know
the advanced.
Knowing Calculus wouldn't help you today.
It doesn't help you in business,
doesn't help you in most things.
But knowing arithmetic,
really what will help you really,
whether it's at the corner grocery store
counting change to figuring out the
value of your podcast business,
to figuring out how to do the
probability math on you know,
some action that you want to take.
So understanding basic mathematics cold
is way more important than memorizing
calculus concepts. And the problem is, and
this is true of, I think all reasoning,
it's much better to know the
basics from the ground up.
Solid Foundation of
understanding of steel frame,
of understanding that it is
to just have a scaffolding.
We just memorizing advanced concepts.
This is why there are a lot of people I'm
sure that you listen to who are really
smart. They use a lot of jargon and
you can't quite follow their reasoning.
You don't know how they're putting
things together and you're this deep down
suspicion. They don't even really
understand, right? So if you look at the,
the the most powerful thinkers,
especially the ones where
money or life is on the line,
they have to understand the basics
really, really well. Richard Fineman,
the famous physicist,
was able to,
he had this piece in one of his lectures
where he takes you from counting
numbers on your hand all
the way to calculus in four
pages of texts that orally
but written down it's four pages of text
and it's a complete unbroken logical
chain that takes you through
geometry, trigonometry, precalculus,
analytic geometry, graphs,
everything, all the way to calculus.
He understood numbers at a core level.
He didn't have to memorize anything.
When you're memorizing, it's an
indication that you don't understand.
You should be able to read, derive
anything on the spot. And if you can't,
you don't know it.
So do you apply that to things other than
mathematics and everything? Everything.
Everything. You don't even make
attempt to memorize things.
Just make an attempt to understand them.
You can't help but memorize things.
But if you can't,
and this is where Twitter is great
for me as I try to understand,
and then I tried to write it down in
such a way that I could remember it.
Just the basic hook that'll point
towards the deeper understanding.
And I'm forced to explain it to people
and that's how I know I understand
something.
So this is what I meant originally.
We talked about reading a good book.
I'll read one page in the night and
then I'd spend the rest of the night
thinking about it.
Or I'm chasing down references and
Wikipedia or weird blog posts trying to
understand it. Um, you
know, so for example,
there was a, I was dealing
with, this is a few months back,
I was dealing with a question of
stupid topic, but the meaning of life,
right? Let's see. How could that be stupid
though? Well, it's trite, it's trite.
You're not supposed to think about it.
It's something you ask your
parents when you're young,
they tell you don't worry about it. Are
they still get the job? Exactly. Good job.
You fricking hippie. Or here's God. God
is the meaning of life, right? Yeah.
And so I was just trying
to resolve for myself.
Like what could the answer be right?
Not what is the answer,
but what could the answer be?
And so at a core level,
I was forced to kind of hunting down
all these weird little things and really
understand for myself, and
it's gotta be personal, right?
But as they established for myself
what it could and could not be,
and that gave me some level of peace.
So now I don't have to keep asking that
question of what is the meaning of why,
uh,
I mean you,
you sh I think the question is
more interesting than the answer.
Everyone should explore this on their own,
but let me just explore a few
parts with you, right? Okay.
So first is if I gave you an answer,
if I said the meaning of life is to
please God. Well, which God, okay.
Judeo Christian God. Well, okay,
why that one? Why this thing?
The problem is it's a why question.
You can keep asking why forever, right?
Any answer I give you, you'll just ask
why again? Why again, again, that's right.
And you end up in a place
called a grip as trilemma. Okay.
This is a philosophical exercise,
but I kind of thought it through.
Then Google around and there's a thing
called a grip as trilemma and a grip was
trauma says that any
questioning like this,
why will always end in
one of three places. Okay?
First is infinite regress,
right? Why? Because of this,
why that and just keep going forever.
The second is circular reasoning. Well,
a why a cause? It'd be, well, why beat
because of a fight to get trapped in that.
Or the third is an axiom and
the most popular axiom is God,
but it could be anything cause of math
because the science, because the big bang,
because the simulation,
right? These are all axioms.
These are all just stopping points.
Saying simulation we're in a simulation
or saying is the big bang is just
another way of saying God.
It's just God's a dirty word.
So we don't use it as much anymore.
But same thing.
So you end up in one of these
three dead ends essentially. Right?
So there is no answer. Uh,
the real answer is because
what is the meaning of life? Yeah. You get
to make up your own answers. The beauty.
If there was a single answer,
we would not be free.
We will be trapped because then we
would all have to live to that answer.
Then we'd be bored like robots,
each one competing with each other to
fulfill that single more than the others.
Back to signaling like I'm
better at it than you are.
But luckily there is no answer.
So you just do whatever you want.
The meaning of life.
It's funny that that w w that's the
basis of all existential angst that you
don't, you don't know why you're here and
you have this feeling that it could be
meaning less. It is. I mean if you,
when you start pondering the,
the multiverse, the universe,
the galaxies, solar system,
the planet, the organism,
the cells inside the organism,
the bacteria, the parasites,
the symbiotic relationship we have to
our environment. And you start going,
Jesus Christ, what am I? Just a little
piece of this thing? It's like, well,
the answers to all the great questions
are paradoxes. Yeah. So for example,
you're asking like, do I matter? That's
like really the question you asked, right?
Well, how do I matter in this
infinite universe? Well, you know,
on the one hand you're separate.
No two points are the same.
Every point is every two points
are infinitely different.
You're completely separated. No one
will have your thoughts, your emotions,
your feelings, your experience. So
your life as a single player game.
You're trapped inside your head and you're
just aware of a bunch of things going
on. And that's it. On the other hand,
I cannot say the word Joe Rogan
without invoking the entire universe.
Joe Rogue alien comes along,
says, what's that Joe Rogan?
What's Joe Rogan Rogan's a human.
What's a human bipedal ape?
What's an ape on the earth?
What's the Earth Planet?
What's a planet solar system where
it was the carbon made inside starts,
right and says,
I have to create the entire universe
to just say the words Joe Rogan.
So in that sense, you're connected
to everything. It's inseparable.
So the answer to that question of
do I matter is I am nothing and I am
everything. And you'll find this
with all the great questions.
The answers are all paradoxes,
which is why at some level it's sort of
pointless to pursue them to find a trite
answer like I'm giving,
but the act of pursuing them is actually
really useful because then it gives you
certain intrinsic understanding in
your life that brings a level of peace.
I feel like there's with many people,
this stress of this question is
also accentuated by unhappy lives.
It's unsexy accentuated by
unhappy choices, by being trapped.
There's a big difference
between not knowing what the
meaning of life is and God,
I gotta get the fuck out of this job. I
have to, I can't live my life this way.
What's the meaning of life?
If this is my life,
which is why I always start
with let's get you rich first.
That's why very practical
about it, because look, you
know, Buddha was a prince,
okay? He started out really rich and
then he got to go off in the woods.
In the old days, what happened was
if you want it to be peaceful inside,
you would become a monk. You
would renounce everything.
You'd become an aesthetic.
You would give everything up. You renounce
women, men, you'd renounce children,
you do announce money, you renounce
politics, science, technology, everything.
And you would go out in
the woods by yourself,
you to give everything
up to be free inside.
Well today we have this
wonderful invention called
money or you can just store
stuff up in her bank account. Okay?
And you can basically save, you can,
you can work really hard,
you can do great things for society and
society will give you money for giving
it things that it wants and
it doesn't know how to get.
And then you can save that up and you can
live well below your means and you can
find a certain freedom in that and that
will give you the time and the energy to
pursue your own internal
peace and happiness.
So I believe the solution to making
everybody happy is to give them what they
want.
Let's get them all rich,
let's get them all fit and healthy and
then let's get them all happy is are
those things even possible? Can
absolutely. Everyone can be written,
everyone can be recovery.
Here's my thought exercise for now.
It seems like we're in an infomercial.
Everyone can be really not selling any my
home, this is my Rolls Royce. Yeah, so,
so that's a good point.
So everything that I've ever created
on this topic of how to make money,
I will never charge a dollar
for because that would ruin it.
That would show that I'm just another
huckster who's trying to get rich off of
you.
There are no get rich quick schemes.
That's just somebody else trying to
get rich off of you. Right. So it's,
so to me it's more of a philosophical
contribution where for it to have meeting
and to be legit, I can't charge
you anything for it. But yes,
everybody can be rich. And let me
give you a thought exercise. Okay.
Imagine if tomorrow we could wave a
wand and everybody was trained as a
scientist or an engineer. Everybody,
even if you weren't very good,
you had enough understanding of computer.
Did you write some code and you can build
some hardware and don't tell me people
can't do it because they can. That's
just the attorney of soft expectations.
That's just you looking down on
somebody else, they can do it.
They just have to be educated. Now,
if they're educated all as hardware,
software engineers, scientists,
biologists, technicians, hard sciences,
not the social sciences.
We would all be done within five years.
Robots would be doing everything from
cleaning toilets to cooking food to flying
airplanes and driving Uber's
and what would we be doing?
We would be doing all creative jobs to
entertain each other and researching
science and technology.
We will have wonderful lives.
So it is really just a question
of education. Nothing else.
Is this a scale issue though?
I mean you're talking about it as if
this would work with 300 million people,
it will work with 10 billion people.
It will work.
This space fairing race with 100 trillion
people. Just we have the resources,
we have the ability. The
Universe is infinite resources.
You build it, you know,
have you heard of a Dyson sphere?
You know,
you pull the Dyson sphere on a star and
you gather all its energy like that.
There's so much energy out there.
One asteroids got all the
minerals that we need. One son,
one solar system has got all the power
we will need for a long, long time. Uh,
you know, we can extract it of
nuclear fusion. You know, we're,
we're not that far from those
kinds of technologies working. Uh,
it's just a question of
gut and, uh, you know,
an interest like we should be building
nuclear fusion test plants on the moon.
The moon should be littered with
F. It's no downside, right? Yeah.
If you could,
how would that work?
Is send a bunch of people up there
to work on. The problem with robots,
the problem with fishing nuclear
fission is that, you know,
nature creates energy through
nuclear energy, right?
Like the sun creates energy,
nuclear energy. Now for
transmission reviews, photons,
because photons don't interact.
And so photons are great for
information transmission,
but they're actually not great for
energy transmission for energy creation.
You want nuclear to work. And the problem
is because nuclear energy, you know,
we built it with a bomb.
We have dirty nukes,
all those kinds of problems with
Fukushima, three mile island, Chernobyl,
we don't innovate anymore. Nukes. Imagine
if when the first steam engine blew up,
we said,
oh no more steam engines for awhile,
or very carefully regulated
billion dollars a regulation.
You can't innovate that way.
When the first airplane crashed,
we said no more innovation in airplanes.
Right?
So we need a way to iterate on nuclear
efficient and eventually fusion and get
them working safely, cleanly,
passive, say failure,
etc. If we're going to find our way out
of the energy trap and the best place to
do that is someplace
like on the moon or Mars,
do you think that it's
actually a possibility that
they could get nuclear power
to the point where it's not a detriment?
Because when everyone's worried
about is a meltdown, right? Yeah.
And we do have these old plants that
are running, that are running on this.
This is 50 year old technology.
It's crazy cause they,
there's no ability to shut them
off, right? Very old technology.
They do now have gen four nuclear
reactors that are passive, fail safe.
So in other words, when they fail, they
fail until you pull the plug on them.
They fell into a state where there's
no leakage, there's no problem.
There are default is a positive
outcome as opposed to the current ones,
the old ones where if you
unplug them like, and these,
even these gen four or just gen
four, they're not gen five, gen 80,
gen hundred where we are microprocessors.
Right?
And that should be something that people
are working towards. I hope so. I mean,
in an ideal world we would do that.
The problem is if you have nuclear energy
on the moon, how do you get at home?
Right?
So what you actually got to do is you've
got to read it on the moon and you're
using it there maybe to
launch more satellites,
more rockets further out into the solar
system. And that's the initial use case.
Um, but then eventually the technology
gets so good you can bring it home.
Now I want to go back to this idea of
getting people rich that somehow or
another that's going to make people
happy. How do you stop that? The,
the natural progression that people
have of, you know, Oh, you know,
I have got a nice Chevrolet.
Yeah, but I really want to BMW.
I've got a nice BMW, but now I want a
Mercedes. I have mercy. I want to for Ron.
Yeah.
How do you stop that
material possession trap?
Because you can't at some level.
But I think most smart people over time
realize that possessions don't make them
happy.
It's just you have to go through that
and you have to buy your stupid car to
realize that it doesn't attract attractive
girls that actually just attracts
other dudes who are like, Hey, I
like that car, man. Right? Like,
like you have some expensive out there,
some fancy cards.
Tell me how you know how much
that attracts women versus
men. Well, I'm married.
Those are for me. I just
enjoy machines. Yeah.
So let me their toys. That's a particular
thing where you enjoy machines.
But I think as you get older,
you just realize that there's no
happiness in material possessions. Now,
lack of material possessions
can make you very unhappy.
So being poor can make you unhappy. But
being rich is not gonna make you happy.
And what happens.
Unfortunately,
a lot of people struggle through their
whole lives to make money. They make some,
they were exhausted and then they're like,
well now why am I not happy?
I guess I'm just not a happy person
and smart people aren't happy.
That's like a great little way to, people
feel better about it. They say, well,
if you're smart, you're not happy.
Right? Whereas I positively, other way,
if you're smart, you should be
able to figure out how to be happy.
Otherwise you're not that smart.
Yeah.
That is an offensive statement that
if you're smart, you're not happy.
I've heard that before and I just do not
understand the logic of that other than
self justifying. I understand where it
comes from. It comes from if you're smart,
it's usually cause you thought things
through and you are very busy mind and so
busy mind can often rob you have peace
of mind because when the piece that we
seek is not peace of mind,
it's piece from mind. Right?
So if you look at all the crazy
activities you do to be happy, right?
Whether it's like trying to get laid
and have an orgasm or extreme sports or
looking at something beautiful
or taking a psychedelic.
You're trying to get out of your own mind.
You're trying to get your monkey mind
to stop chattering at you for a moment.
You're trying to get peace from the mind
and there are other better ways to do
that. Most of the ways we try to get
peace from mind, our indirect, um,
whereas if you understand things,
if you see things properly,
you will naturally slowly
develop piece from mind.
Sorry if I went on a tangent
there. No, it's a good tangent.
It's a good tangent because I think
oftentimes the pursuit is what's thrilling
to people and the possibility that one
day they'll be able to rest and that
they'll reach this goal.
That's the fundamental delusion that there
is something out there that will make
me happy and fulfilled forever.
Yeah. Golden years there
is, it's called death. Oh,
I'll take care of everything. That's the
great leveler. But when people look at,
particularly social media was bring it
back to that. When you see someone who,
you know, you see them posed in
front of their mansion there,
beautiful car and they're leaning against
it with their designer clothes on,
they're expensive. Watch
you. Ah, I want that.
That's what I want.
What you really want is freedom.
You want freedom from your money problems.
And I think that's okay. So people,
once someone can solve their
money problems either by
lowering their lifestyle
or by making enough
money, uh, and you know,
essentially what you want to get everybody
to the retirement but not retirement
and the,
I'm 65 years old sitting in a nursing
home collecting a check retirement,
different definition.
Retirement is when you stop sacrificing
today for some imaginary tomorrow.
Mm.
Okay.
Today is complete in an of itself.
You're retired and so how
do you get there? Well,
one is you can have so much money saved
up that just your passive income off of
that without your having to lift
a finger coverage, your burn rate,
keep your burn rate low,
right?
A second is you just drive your burn
rate down to zero. You become a monk.
A third is you're doing something
you love, you enjoy it so much.
It's not about the money.
So there are multiple ways to that path.
But the most common is people just say,
I need to make more money.
And the kind of wealth creation that I
talk about is about creating timeless
principles and adapting yourselves that
making money won't be an issue and you
can do it by doing what you love,
right?
Like we get into this model of
I must work for other people,
work my way up the ladder.
Uh,
I must like do what that
person is doing to make money.
But really today in society,
you get rewarded for creative work,
for creating something brand new that
society didn't even know yet that it
wanted, that doesn't know how
to get other than through you.
So the most powerful moneymakers
are actually individual brands.
People like yourself or elan or
Kanye or Oprah or Trump, right?
These are individual brands, eponymous
name brands who themselves are leveraged.
Like you're leveraged.
You have podcasts,
media going out to everybody that's
leveraged the podcast work for you and you
sleep.
They have knowledge that nobody else has,
which is your knowledge is the
knowledge of being Joe Rogan. I mean,
who else is a UFC fighter
and a commentator and a
podcaster and a comedian and
you know,
interested in all these things and knows
all these people can't replace you. Um,
so we have to pay you what you're worth.
And was I never fought in UFC though.
Oh you did? Okay. Sorry. Um, or you
know, your, whatever you're, you're,
you're involved in that whole scene. You
just have a unique set of skill sets. Um,
so because of this unique,
what I call a specific knowledge,
because of the accountability
that you have with your name,
because the leverage that you have through
your media, your money making machine,
you're, I'm sure at this point I
could make you start over tomorrow,
wipe out your bank card.
You'd be rich again, no time.
Because you have all the skillsets.
So once people have those
skill sets and the beauty is,
the way you've done it is you
don't have any competition.
There's no substitution. If Joe Rogan
were to disappear off the air tomorrow,
it's not like random podcasts and number
12 with step in and fill that thing. No,
it's just gone.
So the way to get out of that competition
trap is actually to be authentic.
The way to retire is actually to find
the thing that you know how to do better
than anybody. And you know how to do that
better name because you love to do it.
No one can compete with
you if you love to do it.
Be Authentic and then figure out how to
map that to what society actually wants.
Apply some leverage,
put your name on it so you take the risks,
but you gain the rewards,
have ownership and equity in what
you do and then just crank it out.
I think people have to be very careful
to not get trapped along the way with
things that you can afford
with your current lifestyle,
like the way you're living
in the way you're earning,
but they're also imprisoning you and the
fact that you are now to have to work
this
40 hour week job in order to get
this thing that you can afford,
but now you are saddled down to this job.
You've no, you're not saving, you're not,
you're not putting things in a,
in a good place and you're
working for these things.
Working for things as rewards is a real
trap that a lot of people fall into.
It's the biggest one. Let's see,
until I've also says that, uh,
you're under two great addictions,
heroin in a monthly salary
and that's why you can't get rich
renting out your time because you know,
when you start charging
more and more for your time,
it's a slow upgrade loop and then you
upgrade your house at the same time you
have in your car at the same time
you move in the neighborhood.
You really also have to get
used to ignoring your peers
or upgrading or changing
the definition of your peers.
There are a lot of,
a lot of people here who are poor here,
but there'll be rich if they
were living in Thailand and Bali,
and if they have the luxury
of a remotely doable job,
they may want to be living
there and saving up money.
But the ignoring the peers is an issue
because the keeping up with the Jones,
this is a real phenomenon. Yeah.
And makes the world go around. Yeah.
And then there's this other
thing that people have to avoid,
even allowing their mind to think when
they're hearing what you're saying and
all this logical,
fantastic advice.
There's these six dirty words
that's easy for you to say.
Yeah. That is a terrible trap. And look,
I grew up as a first generation
immigrant in Jamaica, Queens, uh,
with zero money, single mom, two kids
working day and night, go to school.
Uh, you know, I washed dishes. Uh,
I was [inaudible] catering jobs,
I was mowing lawns. I was working since
the age of 11 on and off here and there,
um, didn't have 2 cents to
rub together, you know, uh,
I had to borrow $400 to go to college,
like literally a short $400 to 400.
I had to find $400. I didn't have it.
Uh, you know, got rejected from a
job at Dunkin donuts. So like, okay.
It's not to say that it's easy, it's not
easy. It's actually really fricking hard.
It is the hardest thing you will do. But
it's also the rewarding thing. You know,
look at the kids who are born
rich, no meetings, their lives,
you're terrible place. Yeah, you're real.
You're real resume is just a
cataloging of all your suffering.
If I were to ask you to describe
your real life to yourself,
when you look back on your deathbed,
you're going to go back and say,
what are the interesting things I've done?
And it's all going to be around the
sacrifices that you've made in the hard
things that you did. Anything you were
given, doesn't matter. You know, you,
you have your four limbs, you have
your brain, you have your head,
you have your skin yet.
So that's all from granted.
So you have to do hard things anyway
to create your own meaning in life. Um,
making money as a fine one. Yes. Struggle.
It is hard. I'm not gonna say it's easy.
It's a really hard, but the tools
are all available. It's all there.
There's also this,
these traps that people sort of establish
in their own mind of giving themselves
excuses or giving themselves
in unsurmountable obstacles,
insurmountable d paths,
terrain mentality. Yeah.
It's somebody else's fault. That's my skin
color's fault. It's the system's fault.
Yeah. Those people are
sinking. I feel bad for them.
I want to shake them out of it and
say, actually, you can get out of it.
You just have to stop thinking.
It's everybody else. I'll
do the perspective. Yeah.
It's so difficult for people to do.
It's one of the most difficult things for
people to do is to change the way they
approach approach reality itself.
At the end of the day.
I do think even despite
what I said earlier, life is
really a single player game.
It's all going on in your head.
You know,
whatever you think you believe
will very much shape your reality,
both from what risks you take
and what actions you perform,
but also just everyday
experience of reality.
If you're walking down the street and
you're judging everyone, you're like,
I don't like that person because their
skin color. I don't like that. Oh, she's,
she's not attractive. That guy's
fat. This person's a loser. Oh,
who put this in my way? You
know, the more you judge,
the more you're gonna separate yourself
and you'll feel good for an instant
because you'll feel good about yourself.
I'm better than that,
but then you're going to feel lonely
and then you just gonna see negativity
everywhere. The world just reflects
your own feelings back at you.
Reality is neutral.
Reality has no judgements to a tree.
There's no concept of right or wrong
or good or bad, right? You're born,
you have a whole set of
sensory experiences and
stimulations and lights and
colors and sounds.
And then you die.
And how you choose to interpret that
is up to you. You do have that choice.
So this is what I meant,
that happiness is a choice.
If you believe it's the choice,
then you can start working on it.
And I can't tell you how to find it
because it's their own conditionings that
are making you unhappy.
So you have to uncondition yourself.
It's just like I can't fix
your eating habits for,
you can give some general guidelines,
but you got to go through the heart
habit forming of how to eat right.
But you have to believe it's possible
and it is absolutely possible.
I was miserable.
I'm happy as a clam and it's not just
the money I got there before the money.
You got happy before
the money? Mostly. Yeah.
How did you get happy before the money?
I started getting older. You know,
I just realized like life is
short. I'm going to die again.
Try it. Right. Try It, try
anyways. Yeah. Well, Confucius
had a great saying that, uh,
you know,
every man has two lives and the second
starts when he realizes he has just one.
Ah,
and I read that it was one of those
book dropping lines. You know,
it's like Mike drop.
Confucius had a lot of microbes.
Confucius was a bad motherfucker. He was,
that's a crazy one. That was a great one.
Um, or another one is next
time you get sick, you know,
cause everybody gets
sick every now and then.
It's like a happy person
once 10,000 things, a sick
person just once. One thing,
right? So it's your, it's your unlimited
desires that are clouding your piece,
your happiness have desires.
You are biological creature that stands
up and says, I can do something. I move,
I resist,
I live.
But just be very careful of your desires.
This is the oldest most trade wisdom.
Desire is suffering. That's
what it means, right?
Every desire you have is an
access where you will suffer.
So just don't focus on more
than one desire to time.
The Universe is rigged in such a way
that if you just want one thing and you
focus on that, you'll get it. But
everything else you gotta let go.
Did you make a gradual shift to
happiness or was it a radical change?
It's ongoing. It's gradual. Everyday.
You're happier today than you were
a month ago. Yeah. Allegedly. Yeah.
Yeah.
I'm very happy these days deliriously,
so it's actually a hard for me to hang
out with normal people. Really. Yeah.
So you,
you've made a significant shift over
the period of like how many years?
Eight years. Eight years, yeah. Wow.
And is this something that you've pursued
through certain books or is it just
like you,
you've made an understanding or gained
an understanding in your own mind and
then started pursuing it based on,
I don't understand that.
Yeah, it's very, very
personal. Uh, it's basically,
you have to decide it's a priority. And
then I tried every hack I possibly could.
I used to, you know, I tried all the,
I tried meditation, I tried witnessing,
uh, you know, I even tried an Ssri
just to see what it would feel like.
How did it feel? Uh, it was, it turned
me from a pessimist or an optimist,
but I didn't like the physical
side effects and all that.
I want to be in a drug
for sustained basis.
So I dropped it and I felt it
turn you into an optimist. Yes.
At the time I used to be
a pessimist. Yeah. Um,
I started doing things like I would
start looking at the, uh, you know,
in every moment and
everything that happens,
you can look on the bright
side of something. Right.
And so I used to do that forcibly and
then I trained it until it became second
nature. So for example, like a
friend of my wife's was over and she,
when we were dating and
she took all these photos,
she took like hundreds of photos
and then she sends them all to us.
And my immediate reaction was like,
why are you dumping hundreds
of photos on my phone?
I don't need a hundreds of photos,
have some judgment.
That was my immediate reaction. And then
I could say actually how nice of her,
she sent me hundreds of photos I could
pick. The one that I like, right?
There are two ways of
seeing almost everything.
There are a few things that
are like high suffering.
So you can't do that other than just
saying, well, this is a teacher, right?
But I slowly worked through every negative
judgment that I had until I saw the
positive and not second nature to me.
I also realized that like what you
want is you want to clear minds.
You want to let go of thoughts,
happy thoughts disappeared.
I had automatically very easy to let
go of them. Negative thoughts linger.
So we interpret the neck, the positive and
everything. Very quickly. You let it go,
right? You let it go much faster. Um,
simple hacks. Get more sunlight, right?
Learn to smile more,
learn to hug more.
These things actually released
serotonin and reverse.
They aren't just outward
signals of being happy.
They're actually feedback loops to being
happy. Um, spend more time in nature.
You know, these are obvious. Watch your
mind. Watch your mind all day long.
Watch what it does, not judge it and not
try to control it. But you can meditate.
24 seven meditation is not
a sit down close your eyes,
activity meditation is just
basically watching your own thoughts.
Like you would watch anything
else in the outside world and say,
why am I having that?
Does that serve me anymore?
Is that conditioning from when I
was 10 years old? Like for example,
getting ready for this podcast. You
got Ready? I didn't but good. I did,
but I did. But I did.
But you couldn't help it.
And what happened was the few days leading
up to this, my mind was just running.
And normally my mind is pretty calm
and it was just running and running and
running. And every thought I would have,
I would imagine me saying it to you,
my brain couldn't help but rehearse what
it's doing is just rehearsing all the
time to talk to you. And then I
was even rehearsing, rehearse,
telling you about the rehearsal,
right?
So it was all playing all these Meta games
and I was just like, shut up, stop it.
What is going on? And it took me
a while to figure out, oh yeah,
you know what it is.
When I was a kid in queens and I had no
money and I had nothing and I need to
save myself. The way I got out was
by sounding smart, not being smart,
sounding smart.
That was the skill I perfected.
So I am hardwired to always rehearse
things so I will sound smart.
It's a disease that keeps me from
being happy so but when you see that,
when you realize that when you understand
something then it naturally calms you
down. So after that I stop rehearsing
as much, but it's still a train habit.
That is
really interesting point that you want
to sound smart that that many people do
that and especially young
people and it's you.
You see someone who is smart or someone
who appears smart, they say smart things.
You kind of want to sound smart.
I want people to think about me the
same way I think about that person,
that that is my disease. That is my
feeling is what clutters my mind. I,
the the thing I have to
ask myself now is if I can,
would I still be interested in learning
this thing if I couldn't ever tell
anybody about it? Uh, that's
how I know it's a real,
that's how I know it's something
I actually want to know.
Common thing though, I know I
suffered from that when I was young.
The desire to sound smart,
that's very, very common.
All of us start out.
You know, every, everything.
You're the winner now in your life. You
were to you. It's because you are a loser.
At some point, if you had gotten all
the girls, if you had all the money,
if you had everything you want,
you're a good looking.
And in junior high or high school,
uh,
you wouldn't have done anything with your
life and you would have peaked early.
It's like the Bruce Springsteen
glory days song, right?
You would have married your
high school sweetheart.
You'd be living in your home town.
You know,
you'd be a manager at
the local Mcdonald's,
whatever that first dream job you had.
Thank God we didn't all get what we
wanted when we were young. Right. Right.
Or we would be trapped in that.
So you have to be able to break
out of where you came from.
I don't know where I was going.
That is interesting too about
people who peaked too early. Yeah.
Or maybe those people that peak too
early can do the Ilan Mustang and just
abandon it and start something
new and then learn the,
the joys of sucking at something.
Yeah, and actually the, in
our professions, especially
when you're high visibility,
the problem with Peking is
that you then get drowned in,
in death of a thousand cuts. People
have expectations of you. Hey Joe,
can you come to my event? Hey Joe,
can you look at my business plan?
Hey Joe can give me advice on this.
Can you talk to my friend?
Can you come in as podcast?
You're just being assaulted all the
time with inbound opportunities.
So you have no time to
start over with anything.
So you have to ruthlessly
ruthlessly disappoint everybody.
Eliminate and clear your schedule,
drop all the meetings,
not even respond to the emails.
The only way you're gonna be
able to start over with anything.
Yeah,
and I,
we've talked about this and I'd love
your approach to meetings that if they're
not life or death,
I'm the same way.
I avoided a good one recently,
and this was someone that
was just tracking me down
as a high profile person in
a big organization. And I'm like,
can we just talk on the phone?
And then we talked on the phone list.
There was nothing to say.
It was just they wanted to
get me in the office and
yeah,
meeting hardly be phone calls.
Phone calls should be emails and
emails should just be texting. Right.
Many of them, right. With meetings.
I mean, I, I despise meetings.
I used to own the domain. I don't do
coffee.com I eventually had to go,
but I used to respond from the violet.
I don't do coffee, you know? Oh,
that's hilarious. It was a little
bit of a jerk move, but it really,
what it comes from is when I was young,
one of my principals was I
knew I had to make money.
It was my overwhelming desire. And, uh,
one of the things I did was I said, okay,
I'm never going to be worth more
than what I think I'm worth. Okay.
No one's gonna pay me more than what
I think I'm worth. So what am I worth?
So I picked an hourly rate for
myself that I was worth. And I said,
I'm never going to squander
my time for less than this.
So if originally is 500 bucks an hour,
then I upgrade the 5,000 bucks an hour.
And you know, it's ludicrous. But pick an
aspirational hourly rate, aspirational.
It has to be a little ludicrous.
And then what I would do is
if I have to return something,
I'm standing in line to return
something and it's below my hourly rate,
I'll throw it away if I have
to, if I, or give it away.
If I have to do some tasks and I can
hire somebody to do it for less than my
hourly rate,
I would hire them.
And so I just became
extremely jealous of my time.
Which doesn't mean you
can't have fun rest leisure,
spending time with your
friends and family. That's
all great. Don't count that.
But if you're doing anything
you don't want to do,
which is the definition of work,
it's a set of things that you have to
do that you don't want to do if you're
working it better be for your hourly
rate otherwise don't do the work.
And so once it came out of that,
then I just realized the cost of meetings,
a costume meetings is so high,
especially given all the people who are
in their right, one person's talking,
seven people listening, you're
literally just dying an hour at a time.
So you have to just drop
nonurgent meetings or figure
how to be more efficient
with them if you're going
to do anything great.
The extreme example is business travel.
Getting on a plane to fly halfway
around the world for one meeting,
which never amounts to anything.
And then like wasting your whole
little life there and then flying back.
So about five years ago I resolved.
I am never going to travel for business.
Wow.
And I haven't traveled for business since.
I only travel if the travel
experience will be so entertaining,
enjoy us because I have friends or it's
a place I want to see or whatever that
it will be complete in and of itself
because I know that whatever the business
meeting it came from is,
is never worth it. Wow.
And actually that principle
applies larger than just travel.
It applies to life in general.
The this,
one of the secrets to happiness is to
really embrace what you're doing in that
moment. That's trite. But where that,
where that comes from is saying,
I only want to do actions that are
complete in and of themselves. Right.
If I'm looking for some ulterior
motive down the line is not going to
materialize and, and if you think
it is, maybe even if it does,
it'll be very short lived.
Anything you want in your life,
whether it was a car or whether
it was a girl over those money.
When you got it a year later,
you're back to zero.
Your brain had had dynamically adapted
to it and you're looking for the next
thing.
That's a great statement.
Had dauntingly adapted.
That's that is what happens to people
and you get accustomed to whatever it is.
I realized that when I
first got a new apartment,
it was a nice apartment and after awhile
I got used to it. I was like, oh, okay.
Yeah, so just an apartment. It was just
where I live. I'm used to, it's nice,
but I'm used to it.
Yeah. We all go through this
learning. It's it's, you know,
it's riding the Ferris wheel of life.
It's like you get at the bottom,
you're like, oh, I want to get the top.
This is so exciting. You divide it up,
you get a little dopamine rush
and get a little serotonin.
Then you ride it back down is that
wears off. Then you need another high.
Then you write it back up and
you write it back down. In fact,
the more high as you get, the harder it
gets to go around the wheel. More board.
You get it in,
the harder it goes to go back up.
So what lights your fire in now?
Like what,
what gets you motivated
to do things and to act?
Art. Art. This is art. Oh,
okay. Art Is this creativity.
It's just anything that's
done for its own sake.
So what are the things that
are done for their own sake?
There's nothing beyond uh, loving
somebody. Uh, creating something,
playing art. To me,
creating businesses play.
I create businesses early stage cause
it's fun cause I, I mean to the product,
even when I invest, it's because I liked
the people. I like hanging out with them.
I learned from them. And I think
the product is really cool. Um,
so these days I will pass on all kinds
of great investments because I'm like,
I just, the product's not interesting.
It's boring. I'm not gonna learn anything.
That's a beautiful luxury. It is a luxury
part and learning. Yeah, it is a luxury.
These are not 100% or zero things,
right?
You can in your life start moving more
and more towards that goal. It's a goal.
When when I was younger,
I used to be so desperate to make money
that I would've done anything. Right.
If you'd shown up and said,
hey,
I got a sewage trucking business and
you're going to go into that. I was like,
great, let's do it. I'm
going to make money.
Thank God no one gave me that opportunity.
I'm glad that it went down the
road of technology and science,
which I genuinely enjoy. Uh, and
so I got to combine my vocation,
my avocation.
I mean, what are you doing?
You're playing, you're
having fun, you're doing art.
You're not, you're not working. No.
That's what I always say when people say
work hard. I'm like Sarda. No, not really.
I'm always working,
but it looks like work to them,
but it feels like play to me and that's
how I know no one can compete with me on
it because I'm just playing 16 hours a
day and if they want to compete with me
and they're going to work,
they're going to lose because they're
not going to do it 16 hours a day,
seven days a week. Well, listen, man,
there are some gems of wisdom
in this conversation in the,
I hope people pull things out of this
and apply them to their own life,
and I'm certainly going to
listen to you again and,
and try to apply some of this to my own
life stuff that I'm not already applying,
but I really appreciate your time and
I really appreciate you coming in here.
Thanks for having me.
And please tell people you do small little
podcast is just the Navarro podcast,
right? Yeah. Best way to find me is
on Twitter, actually just at Nepal.
Then I have a website at Nav dot.
A L I have a youtube channel novel,
and I have a podcast in the wall. That's
it. Well, thank you very much. Thank you.
Really appreciate it.
Thank you. Bye everybody.
Bye Bye.
[inaudible].