Hello Freak bitches while there's this
thing,
uh,
speaking of guys who are in the business
of doing heroic acts,
there's a,
you've heard of the firemen fantasy.
I mean the fact that women find guys
bought fireman to be very attractive.
And it actually turns out that there was
a study that was done that actually
shows this to be the case.
And I discussed this in one of my
articles on psychology today.
Uh,
if you have a guy approach women either
wearing a fireman suit or not,
uh,
his chances of getting her phone number
increases quite substantially.
Really if he is wearing a fireman.
So how do they know this?
Did they do a study where they did they
have the same guy?
Not where the firemen with the same
approach and the same,
same word,
same script,
same everything.
One version.
It's called the field experiment.
In one version.
You,
you approach women at a cafe wearing the
stuff and another version,
he's the guy who actually did that
research is a French psychologist.
His name is Nico [inaudible] and I've
actually covered a few of his studies on
my website.
Uh,
my most read article ever over maybe
three,
400,000 readers is one of his studies
where I was simply,
because we're going to talk about the
blowback issue now and here again,
it was a study where he looked at the
likelihood of women being picked up as
hitchhikers as a function of their
breasts size.
So he actually had the same woman and
they,
you know,
artificially manipulated her breast size
and on different days she would stand
there.
And,
and of course it turned out that men
were much more likely to pick up the
woman if she had the same woman that she
had bigger rest side.
So I just summarize that study,
put it up,
and then I remember I'd gone on
vacation,
came back from vacation,
found out that I had completely gone
viral,
but I had a million hate mail,
not just from readers but from fellow
psychology today,
bloggers who were arguing that I was,
you know,
peddling pornography because I had a
picture as the teaser image for that
article.
I had a photo of a woman sitting in a
passenger seat would big with large
breasts.
Well,
it seemed appropriate for the topic
given that that's what the topic of the
study was.
But by putting that image,
I was objectifying women.
I was treating them as mere sex objects.
And so even though I had nothing to do
with the study and I was simply
summarizing somebody else's work,
I was a horrifying pornographic peddler.
Isn't it funny that just a photograph of
a woman with large breasts is considered
pornographic?
Now,
listen to this.
So then I've also written articles on
psychology today where I talk about all
kinds of issues dealing with penis size.
You know,
so do women want a guy with a bigger
penis?
Are they more likely to have orgasms?
She's got a bigger penis.
Uh,
if you're in a gay relationship,
man,
uh,
are you likely to be top or bottom as a
function of your penis size?
That study has been done by science.
And so for those articles,
I put sexy images of men.
So then I wrote to each of those people
who had written the hate man.
I said,
well,
in all fairness,
you now have to write an equally hateful
thing.
Because I am also sexually exploiting
men's bodies.
Of course they went away and never came
back.
We have the,
I think this is one of the coolest times
ever to be alive.
I really do and I think that one of the
reasons why it's one of the coolest
times ever to be alive is because it's
just so chaotic and it's so strange and
no one can do anything about it.
No one can stop it.
Now they're going to try and net
neutrality and they're gonna try to put
the brakes here and charge people for
that and you're gonna,
you're in trouble and you're on a list
and I'm going to watch you.
What do you try to be anonymous?
You fucker.
I want to know where you are.
We were,
we were talking about this right before
the show,
like all that shit that's coming out,
like all the corruption and anger and
government and competence.
I'm starting to believe that it has to
be there because that's what wakes us up
to.
We don't need so many agencies.
We don't need like so many wars and so
much bullshit.
Let's just decide things for ourselves.
And of course we need some laws.
We need some police,
we need some roads.
And that's really it.
Thank you very much.
You know,
like have a nice day.
We don't need you archiving fucking baby
photos.
Yeah.
That's what we've gone over the line.
And so you're seeing the people realize
that people realize that banks are
ineffective ingredients.
People realize that the old media is
dying out and they don't give a shit
about their viewers.
So they're just moving over to better
stuff.
And it's happening across the board in
pretty much every industry even.
Um,
I had,
uh,
this woman,
Tiffany van goalie on my show recently.
He was another podcast host and she was
talking to me about how all these
grocery stores now have an organic
section and that's taking off.
And so you're seeing like this,
we have new standards.
Like that's,
I think what's happening is that we have
higher standards than we used to.
And so across the board is better stuff.
Yeah.
There's no doubt that things are getting
more complex and harder to control
because no doubt,
and there's no doubt that these old
systems,
whether it's like afternoon,
when you watch the news,
it's six or five or whatever the fuck it
is.
It seems like you're watching a parody,
right?
The anchorman is becoming more and more,
I mean,
when you,
when you watch,
if you try to watch like the La news
tried to watch any of those channels,
local news at five o'clock it's like
these people were aliens,
right?
I think these things,
we're not supposed to exist forever and
that's why to us it seems so kind of
silly.
It's like it's supposed to be dying out.
That's like the,
it's the new season.
New stuff's going to come out.
It's kind of like fashion,
right?
Like every year it's going to be
something different.
That's the way it works.
Now.
It's a corporate media and
centralization,
top down type stuff is dying out and I'm
sure it'll continue to exist in a bunch
of different forms,
but that idea is getting weaker and
weaker.
[inaudible]
okay.