Hmm,
the countdown?
Sure.
So you were just two.
One.
Hello?
Peter Schiff.
Hello Joe.
You just what we're going to,
we're going to ask.
You just did a whole other show before
this one.
I did three hours.
No,
two hours.
Oh,
alright.
So it's not hard.
Oh,
okay.
Well the comedian,
those are the easy ones.
Oh,
all right.
It's just basically talking to a friend.
Okay.
Well I'm a friend.
You are a friend.
That's right.
Yeah.
I remember when I first saw you when you
were doing that octopus is occupied Wall
Street thing anymore.
Did they give up?
They stop occupying?
Yeah,
they did.
But you know,
we just.
Maybe you saw that on my youtube
channel.
I know we just reposting the occupy Wall
Street video.
I never actually had it on my channel.
Oh really?
But because it was originally done by
reason this about five years ago or so,
five,
six years ago and so reason tv did it
and so I let them promote it on their
site.
I didn't copy it and they got millions
and millions of views and there was some
other sites that that that went with it.
It was asking a one percenter,
right?
Wasn't that what you called it?
Well,
I was down there with a sign that said I
am the one percent.
Let's talk,
and I went into Zucotti Park and the
only reason I stopped that if you the
long,
the long one,
the long version is just under two
hours,
which is on my youtube channel now,
but the other reason we stopped is
because we ran out a ca,
a candidate batteries,
batteries in the camera.
The camera died,
but I could have kept talking and we
were losing the light.
You can see by the end,
you know it's getting dark.
It's getting darker.
Swatching them get frustrated with you,
but not having the words nor the
knowledge to compete with what you were
saying was very entertaining,
like agree with you or disagree with
you.
It was just hilarious watching someone
so completely outmatched or a group of
people,
so completely outmatched trying to
debate economics with you and trying to
understand the way business works,
except they didn't even realize they
were out match.
They thought they were smarter than me,
but you know,
the,
the main reason I went there was not so
much to try to convince the people there
that they were wrong and that,
you know,
capitalism was,
the solution,
not the source of their problems and
that they should be protesting
Washington,
the Federal Reserve or Congress.
It was for the people that I knew that
would watch it on the internet and I
still get emails even now at least I
don't think a week goes by where
somebody from somewhere in the world
doesn't send me an email about that.
And I know another website,
I forget the name of it,
re posted it about a year ago and they
got a couple of million views on it.
Just posting it again.
So a lot of people have watched it and I
get comments from people saying,
this is what changed me.
I was socialist,
very left wing.
I watched this and that was the
epiphany.
That was the moment,
and then I did more research and I
learned more and now thanks to you,
I'm a total libertarian or free market
capitalist and so it's served its
purpose.
Yeah,
well it was enlightening.
It was good.
It's good to see people that are so
involved in something that they'll go
and they'll protest will hang out in the
park,
but they can't articulate their feelings
or their thoughts in a well reasoned
debate.
They really don't have the facts,
but yet they're dedicating their entire
life to protesting something.
It's really interesting that people will
spend so much energy and effort on
something that they're really not even
educated.
Yeah,
and it's a lot easier just to talk about
something just emotionally instead of
actually taking the time to learn about
economics and to understand,
you know,
the source of the problems because
anybody could just blame it on some rich
person who's hoarding money and
discriminating.
They loved doing that and then just say,
oh,
this solution,
see if you blame the problems on some
rich person.
Well,
the solution is easy,
just take his money,
right,
have the government come in and,
and redistribute the wealth,
which is another word for steel.
Take money from somebody who earned it
and give it to somebody who didn't,
but if you actually take a little bit of
time and use your head instead of your,
your,
your heart,
your feelings,
uh,
you'll learn that you know,
that the source of the problems is
government interference in the economy
and that the protest should be directed
at government,
at their regulations and their subsidies
and their taxes and all the things that
government does to stifle economic
growth and deny opportunities to people.
I think that would be a really funny
documentary if you could do like a
documentary on the last occupier,
like the last person to occupy Wall
Street because they had to be like
stragglers,
right?
Eventually must have gotten to the point
where there was like 30 people left,
20 people left that one guy,
no,
fuck these people man.
They started occupying different areas,
right?
Because it caught on and it was all over
the world.
They were occupying here and occupying
there and they were setting up camps.
Right?
They're essentially living there.
Yeah.
And um,
who knows what else they were doing
there,
but um,
but now the occupy a movement kind of
morphed into the Bernie Sanders
Movement,
right?
Because that's where all those guys are
now.
They were volunteering for the sanders
campaign and socialism is really kind of
going mainstream now because they put
the word Democrat in front of it as if
somehow that changes the meeting.
Right.
I'm not a socialist.
I'm a democratic socialist.
Meaning I want to vote for socialism as
opposed to just have an armed
revolution.
But the end is still the same.
Right.
It's still a socialism and it doesn't
work.
Yeah.
I was watching an interview with Tucker
Carlson and some guidance,
a professor at Harvard and he said,
I'll give you the last word you guys
said socialism is gonna win.
I made the piece on like,
what is that?
What does that even mean?
Like socialism is going to win.
What is it?
What does that mean?
What is socialism?
But it could win at the polls.
That's the problem.
It's very intoxicating to people who
don't know any better,
and the interesting thing people,
they have too much money.
The interesting thing about socialism is
that no matter how many times it fails,
people expect it to succeed,
right?
That's the definition of insanity,
Doing something over and over again and
expecting a different result.
Well,
the Socialists always expect a
different result from doing something
that has never succeeded in
pass.
So socialism by definition is one thing,
but by the emotional reaction that
people have is kind of another thing.
The emotional reaction is there's rich
people that are a real problem.
They're hoarding their greedy.
I'm not concerned with money.
I want.
I'm concerned with people and community
and feelings and health and welfare and
education and all of that money.
We should take it from those rich people
and we should funnel it into education
and community.
And they say all these words that make
people feel good.
Like,
yeah,
we're not about money either.
It's all about feeling good.
That's what the liberals are about.
It's about feeling that they're better
than everybody else because they're,
you know,
they're,
they're higher up on this moral pedestal
because they don't care about money,
they just care about,
you know,
people and you know,
but when you talk about rich people,
they don't hoard money.
I mean,
the way you get rich is not by hoarding.
The way you get rich is by trying to
figure out what problems people have
that you can solve,
right?
Whether it's inventing something that
makes their lives better or providing a
service that makes their lives better
because the customers are in charge
individuals,
right?
That that's what's gonna.
Allocate wealth.
It's if,
if somebody is better than somebody else
at satisfying the desires that people
have,
right?
If,
if I can come up with something that you
like,
that you want to buy that's cheaper and
better than what somebody else has come
up with,
then you're going to buy from me.
And so the person who ends up with the
most money is the person who's satisfied
the most desires,
the most needs in the most efficient way
possible.
And that's what's benefiting society.
I mean,
it's great to have charity and I'm all
for private charity,
but if you look at the wealthiest men in
history,
even though they've been incredible
philanthropists and they've given away a
lot of money,
they helped a lot more people,
a massing their fortunes than gifting
away what they made.
It was the businesses that they created,
the,
the products that they invented,
the services that they provided,
and the employment,
right?
That was all a function of they're
creating their wealth.
That's what did a lot more to help
society than simply giving away some of
the money that they earned.
Have you ever had a debate with a
democratic socialist?
Well,
I mean,
most Democrats are socialists.
They just don't know it or they don't
want to admit it,
and a lot of people don't even
understand what socialism is because you
know,
you'll have the left.
I'll always consider somebody like even
Donald Trump,
they'll say,
oh,
he's a fascist.
Right?
They don't even realize that fascism is
part of socialism.
Socialism is a broad concept that
includes things like Communism and
fascism.
So if you're a communist,
you are a socialist.
But by,
but it doesn't mean that if you're a
socialist or communist because you could
be the fastest,
you could be for a lot of things,
but fascism is a form of socialism where
the government doesn't just steal all
the property,
like the communists want to nationalize
everything and take legal ownership of
the means of production.
Right?
The government just owns all the capital
under,
under fascism,
but government is a little bit smarter.
They,
they realize that people will work
harder if they think they're working for
themselves.
So the fastest doesn't want to
nationalize businesses,
they just want to control it through
regulation and taxes.
And that's pretty much what the
Democrats want to do.
They want to control everything by
taxing it heavily and regulating it.
And those,
that's an important aspect of fascist.
I mean a lot of people associate fascism
with racism just because the Nazis were
racist,
but you don't have to be racist.
I mean,
fascism started in Italy and that there
wasn't any racism there.
And if you go back to the Nazi party,
it's the National Socialist Party of
Germany.
That's what the Nazis are.
It's socialist.
So fascism is a form of social and
that's why the communists and the
fascists,
you know,
are you so much because they're really,
they're fighting over the same turf.
It's which brand of socialism is better,
fascism or communism,
but they're not at opposite ends of the
political spectrum.
They're on the same end.
So do you think
people are frustrated with the current
system and so they see someone like
Bernie Sanders come along that offers
this radical change of pace.
He saying,
you know,
we need to end income inequality and
redistribute wealth and all these
different things and it just sparks a,
an emotional reaction in people that
they know that the current system,
the way it's in place,
especially the way it was under Obama,
they didn't like how things were that in
like how things were under Bush.
They think we need someone who's not a
career politician or someone who has got
a radical new approach.
Oh look at this Bernie Sanders guy.
He wants to do some stuff with money.
Let's vote for him.
Yeah,
look,
people are grasping for straws when
they're looking for a solution that
that's why trump is president.
I mean,
a lot of people think that trump's
election maybe shows that the UK,
the US electorate has moved,
right?
Right.
That were more republican or more free
market,
but that's not what that election was
about.
It was about the fact that we had a
lousy economy and trump was honest about
that too.
The voters,
trump told people that the numbers are
phony.
Don't believe these unemployment
numbers,
four or five percent.
It's a lie.
It's fraud,
it's fiction.
And he was right because the way they
calculated today,
they don't calculate that.
Millions and millions of people who I've
given up looking for work,
right?
They don't count the people who just
have a part time job and they're still
looking for a full time job.
So the real unemployment number is much,
much higher.
And,
and trump talked about that and,
and he called out,
you know,
all the politicians from both sides,
right?
Not just the Democrats to Republicans.
And he said,
look,
I'm going to clean house.
I'm not a politician.
Vote for me,
right?
I'm going to make America great again.
I'm going to drain the swamp,
you know,
and he appealed to people's,
uh,
you know,
their,
their fears about immigrants.
I'm going to build this wall as if the
reason that things are bad is because we
have too many immigrants taking away the
jobs.
And so people decided,
you know,
what the hell,
let me,
let me give this guy a trance because
things are.
The media is lying to me.
Wall Street's lined to me.
And so,
you know,
trump,
trump won.
But unfortunately now trump is part of
the establishment and now all of a
sudden the fake economic numbers are
legit.
Now every time there was an unemployment
number out,
he tweets about how it's the lowest it's
ever been.
So I think that when we get this next
recession,
which is going to happen while trump is
president during,
during this first term,
which I think will be the only term,
but when all the why do you think those
two things?
Well,
because I think the economy is going to
fall into a severe recession.
What makes you say the well a,
you know,
it's,
we're overdue,
right?
I mean,
you don't normally have an expansion
that lasts as long as this one.
I think that we're,
uh,
we're the second longest in history and
I,
if we go for another year,
it will be the longest expansion in
history.
Two thousand eight is when it started to
turn around to the end is kind of the
end of 2009 years in exactly what is a
usual expansion and compression
out of five,
six years.
So,
so this one is long,
but it also,
this one required more government
stimulus than any other,
you know,
recovery.
And I don't think we actually recovered.
I think the government simply injected a
bunch of cheap money into the economy
and exacerbated the real problems.
But you know,
reflated the bubbles in the stock market
and the housing market.
But you know,
everybody talks about how the economy is
doing so great,
but it's really not much better than it
was under Obama.
If it's any better at all.
And we GDP growth for trump's first year
in office.
Last year was two point three percent,
I mean,
nothing great.
First quarter was two percent,
this quarter might be a better than
three,
maybe,
maybe not,
but I mean,
I think it's going to be the second
quarter will probably be the best
quarter of the year.
Maybe we're probably going to go
downhill,
but you know,
last year was I think the weakest year
of job growth since 2011.
So people want to talk about how great
everything is,
but it's more a function of people are
hoping things are going to turn around.
There's a lot of optimism now that
things are going to get better.
But I think that the people who are so
optimistic,
a lot of them are going to be
disappointed because we're,
we're going to end up with is a weaker
economy.
The only thing that's really
strengthening is inflation.
Inflation is going to pick up.
So the cost of living is really going to
be rising as the economy is falling into
recession.
So we get stagflation,
uh,
which is probably the worst possible
economic scenario.
And you know,
I think that the,
uh,
the left and even the Fed is going to be
able to blame it on trump because trump
has come in and claim credit for this
great economy that he believes we have
and he's claimed credit for the record
in the stock market,
but he's basically put his name on a
bubble and when it pops,
you know,
it's going to be hard for him to try to
blame the next recession on Obama when
he's already said,
hey,
this is my economy.
I created it.
And so people are going to be
disappointed and they're going to vote,
I think for a,
another person whose promises change and
unfortunately that's going to come from
the left.
So you think this is going to
happen in the next three years?
Well,
yeah,
I mean,
one is what is the bubble?
What do you think is going to cause it
to crash commercial real estate?
Is it credit?
What is it?
Well,
I mean,
commercial real estate is expensive
being it's in a bubble,
but that,
you know,
that's not going to cause it.
I mean going gonna come out of the
bubble.
I think we would already be in a pretty
severe recession now,
had it not been for trump winning had
hillary won.
I think we'd already be there.
But I think that makes you say that.
Well,
we got a lot of false optimism as a
result of,
of trump.
And we did get the tax cuts and the tax
cuts,
you know,
just like any kind of artificial drug,
you can inject yourself and,
and get a little bit of a phony high.
Because remember the tax cuts were paid
for with debt.
We didn't shrink government,
right?
If you,
if you make government smaller,
that's great.
Then you can cut taxes because now
government doesn't need as much money
and you can,
you know,
you can relieve the taxpayer of the
burden of paying for it and that's
great.
But if you just cut taxes but you don't
cut government spending.
And of course what the trump
administration did was,
was even worse,
they increased government spending.
We increased welfare spending,
we increased warfare spending.
Uh,
and so spending is more,
but they reduced their tax revenue so
the deficits are just exploding out of
control and those deficits are going to
do more damage to the economy.
Then the tax cuts were benefit,
except you get the benefit first,
maybe for the first year and then you
start to deal with the pain after that.
And so I think that's going to set in a,
you know,
long before the end of trump's term.
So you think that this is what is
causing the economy to be in a really,
at least a two to look like.
It's in a really healthy state right
now.
Well,
some of the numbers,
right?
Some of the numbers look better,
but beneath the surface,
again,
it's not improving,
just like,
just like it wasn't improving under
Obama.
That's what laid the foundation for
trump's victory was because obama and
everybody kept talking about how great
the recovery was,
but the average voter knew that that was
all a bunch of nonsense because he
wasn't living in that reality.
So if you were the financial advisor to
the president,
what would you tell him?
How would you,
what would you do to try to keep the
economy moving in the same direction?
Is it possible to ward off any kind of a
crash?
Right.
And we don't want to keep it moving in
the same direction.
I mean it's in the same direction it was
going in before trump came in and that's
towards the edge of a cliff.
I mean,
so what we do,
we need is an about face and trump is
not doing that.
I mean about face.
So like for the people that are
listening to this that don't understand,
like they're saying,
okay,
your comedy is supposed to be doing
well.
A black unemployment is the lowest it's
ever been on.
Unemployment is down.
All these jobs have been created.
Yeah.
Well remember again,
the unemployment rate is mainly down
because so many people that are
unemployed are no longer counted as part
of the statistics.
So you know that that's.
If you look at the labor force
participation rate near record,
low mean certainly for men it's the
lowest and spending in the history of
the republic,
but.
And look at the workers to population.
So fewer and fewer people are actually
working and more and more of the people
who aren't working are not included in
the unemployment statistics.
So if you backed all those people in
right,
able bodied people who don't have jobs
but should be working,
then the unemployment rate is much,
much higher so that that doesn't really
paint a good picture.
And then,
you know,
you look at the fact that so many
Americans are unqualified,
right?
There's a lot of jobs out there that go
unfilled because American workers aren't
qualified to fill those positions
because,
you know,
we,
we take a lot of our kids and we keep
them in high school until they're 18,
19 years old.
Many of these kids should drop out of
high school and learn a trade.
I mean,
a lot of people,
you know,
they don't have the aptitude for
academics.
There's no point in just being in high
school.
A lot of times they're glorified daycare
centers,
but they should be out learning trades.
And of course we make it harder for
employers to train people on the job
with occupational licensing laws and
minimum wage laws.
So we destroy a lot of the opportunities
for younger kids to get skills and then
the ones that we send the college,
they waste their time,
you know,
majoring in liberal arts.
So they spend four or five,
six years in college learning nothing of
any real value in the market.
They accumulate a massive amount of debt
in the process.
And so,
you know,
we have a labor force that's highly
educated and that they've got a bunch of
degrees,
maybe they didn't learn anything but
they got a piece of paper,
but then what they have is a lot of
debt.
And so we don't have a lot of people
qualified to do a lot of the things that
need to be done.
So what would you tell the president if
you were,
if you said,
look,
Peter Schiff,
uh,
I don't know shit about the economy.
You obviously do help me out.
How do I stop this bubble?
Well,
first of all,
you can't stop it.
You got to let it deflate.
But the question is how does it deflate?
And then what do you propose as the
solution?
See,
the problem that trump already made was
when he first got elected,
he should not have changed his
perspective.
He shouldn't have said,
hey,
everything is great right now.
He's planning on running at his next
campaign is keep America great.
Right?
When trump ran for office,
he said America was an economic
wasteland,
that it was a disaster.
He's been president for a little over a
year.
All of a sudden it's the greatest
economy in the history of the country,
which is not even close to being true,
but if he's gonna,
try to run for reelection on,
I've already made America great and now
we just want to keep it great.
That's not going to resonate.
So what he should have done from day one
is leveled with the American public.
Again,
this is how bad the problem is and this
is what it's gonna take to solve it
because there's a lot of,
you know,
I'm a pain short term pain that we're
going to need to go through in order to
come to the other side in order to get
rid of all these problems.
Right now,
look at the trait,
right?
Trump is making a big deal about the
trade deficits and he's launching,
terrorist is going to have this trade
that he's convinced that we could win.
And this is very misguided.
The trade deficits are not the problem.
They are the consequence of the problem.
The problem is that we have bad monetary
policy,
bad fiscal policy,
too much regulation.
That's why we have a trade deficit
because American industry is not
productive enough.
We don't save enough.
We don't make the right capital
investment.
That's because interest rates have been
kept too low.
You know,
our tax code,
uh,
favors debt,
you know,
and we have a lot of regulations that
make American businesses less
competitive.
And so the result is that we import a
lot of products rather than making them
ourselves.
And it's not because the other countries
aren't fair or because they have
terrorists.
Terrorists are very low around the
world.
I mean,
there's tariffs are not the problem.
And so if trump is simply going to erect
tariffs,
all that's going to do is tax the
American public because the American
public has to pay the terrorists
whenever they buy imported products.
So this is not going to,
I'm going to turn the economy around,
but you know,
trump is right.
He points out that,
well,
you know,
at one point in time America ran on
terrace,
which is true during the 19th century,
the government,
you know,
raised money pro predominately by
tariffs,
but we didn't have an income tax,
you know.
And so this is the irony of it,
the reason we have an income tax today
is because the populist politicians of
the day told the American voter,
if we can tax the rich with an income
tax,
then we can get rid of terrorists that
the average person is paying.
So the average person understood that
terrorists cost them money and the
politicians said,
let's get rid of these tariffs and let's
just tax the rich.
And the income tax that was originally
proposed really was attacks on the very
rich.
I mean even doctors and lawyers didn't
pay it.
I mean,
you had to be super rich before you pay
the tax.
And then it was like,
you know,
one percent to four percent.
So it was a small tax and it wasn't
taken from your paycheck,
right?
I mean,
first of all,
if.
Yeah,
if you've got a paycheck,
he didn't pay the tax,
but we didn't have withholding until
1943.
That was part of the victory tax to pay
for the Second World War.
But Americans were told let's tax the
rich and you won't have to pay
terrorists anymore.
Well,
it was the minute that you know,
the government got the nose under the
tent,
right?
All of a sudden now the income tax
effects everybody,
right?
People pay a lot more in income taxes
today than they used to pay and
terrorists.
But now,
now the president wants to bring the
towers back on top of the income tax.
I mean,
if trump wants to repeal the income tax
and get rid of it entirely and then have
some terrorists,
I'd be okay with that.
But you can't do that unless you
dramatically shrink the size of
government,
which is the most important thing to
trump needs to do.
But what he's not doing,
he has to make the military smaller.
Not Bigger.
I mean,
he's talking about a space force.
I mean we can't even afford the air
force navy marines that we got now.
We will be going to make money for space
force,
but we have to cut everything.
We got to cut entitlements,
right?
He's think we should be the first people
to have a space for us.
What are the Russians come up with a
space for us and no one's going to come
out of luck.
What are,
what are you going?
What did he do?
Is space for it so we can.
Who are going to fight in space?
Maybe we fight the Russians is space
for.
Why would we fight them in space?
Their doubt earth?
Well,
maybe they want to fight in space.
It's more novel.
Yeah.
I don't think.
I don't think anybody wants to fight,
right?
Want to be protected,
Yeah.
I,
I think we got that covered.
I think we've got a pretty good sized
military.
I don't think anyone's going to mess
with us.
The problem is our economy.
So when you say let the bubble crash,
like what,
what would that entail?
Well,
basically the problem,
the basic problems with the US economy,
and this is because of monetary policy,
fiscal policy is we don't save anything,
right?
And because we don't save enough,
we don't invest enough.
We don't produce enough.
We don't make enough real things,
right?
I mean when trump wants to say that
foreigners are taking advantage of us by
running these huge trade surpluses,
he's got it backwards.
We're taking advantage of them.
They like the Chinese are sending us all
these products that they worked hard to
produce and they had to use real
resources,
land,
labor capital to make these products and
they send them here and what do we give
them?
We give them ious,
we give him a piece of paper and they
buy our treasury bonds.
So in the short run,
Americans are just putting everything on
a credit card,
right?
We're living a higher standard of living
because we can consume what we didn't
make.
But when you do that,
you become poorer.
See,
America used to be the richest creditor
nation in the world,
right?
The world owed us a lot of money.
Today we're the world's biggest debtor
nation.
How did we go from being the biggest
creditor to the biggest debtor?
It was trade deficits.
Every year we keep borrowing money to
consume and what this has done is this
has turned to rich Davidson into a poor
nation,
but we just don't live like a
coordination yet because we're still
borrowing.
Yeah,
and you can be a rich individual yet
maintain a rich lifestyle on debt,
but eventually you know that's going to
catch up with you and then your
lifestyle is going to come crashing down
and this is what's going to happen,
but what we should do instead of having
a crisis imposed on us globally with a
crisis and the dollar and a crisis and
our bond market,
we should do it ourselves.
We should set these forces in motion
ourselves.
So what we have to do is shrink
government,
right?
We have to cut a lot of government
spending,
get rid a lot of government agencies and
departments to get government out of the
way so we can lower taxes legitimately.
And then we have to allow the Federal
Reserve to let the market set interest
rates.
Interest rates have to be much higher
than they are now.
Right?
That because that's going to encourage
people to save.
If interest rates are high,
you'll put your money in the bank to
earn that high rate of interest.
When money goes into a bank,
it can get loaned out to businesses.
Right now,
all that money is going to government or
it's in the corporate bond market where
it's not growing the economy or the
money is being used to finance stock buy
backs.
We need money on main street financing,
capital formation,
uh,
entrepreneurship,
you know,
new businesses,
new jobs.
So we get higher interest rates will get
that.
And we need people to stop buying things
they can't afford.
You know,
you buy something,
if you have the money to pay for it,
you don't just put it on a credit card,
but if and if credit card interest rates
went up and if credit was contracted so
that credit card companies were not
giving out as much credit,
they're giving out a lot of credit now
because the government is misdirecting
it,
but if we slow down our consumption,
we increased our savings and investment,
then the economy can actually grow,
but if interest rates go up,
asset prices have to come down.
The stock market has to come down a lot.
Real estate prices have to come down a
lot.
Now that means people are going to lose
money.
They're not going to be happy about
that.
Yeah.
This sounds counterintuitive to
everything that I've always heard about
how to boost up the economy.
The idea would be that spending and
people buying things,
it's great for the economy.
We need more of that.
No,
that's
put the cart before the horse.
You can't buy something that doesn't
exist.
Something has to be produced before it
can be consumed.
So it's the production that drives the
economic trade,
not consumption.
See,
right now we're just consuming what the
Chinese produce,
right?
But,
but the consumption doesn't mean
anything unless you produce something
first.
So you drive an economy by creating
supply.
It's supply that creates demand.
If you just try to create demand without
the supply,
it's just inflation.
It's weird too that we keep hearing
things about Chinese telecommunications
companies like Walway in particular.
They're always telling you to not buy
their stuff.
That wasn't there.
There was something about something in
the paper today about Walway.
It was about,
uh,
I think another country saying no to
these,
uh,
I guess Walway in particular is the
third largest cell phone manufacturer in
the world and they have a close tie with
the communist government and they
believe that there's,
there might be some shenanigans going on
with them,
their electronics.
I don't know.
I mean,
I'm not familiar with that.
I know that the,
the,
there's,
there's constant talk about trying to,
Oh,
you know,
just don't buy a certain product
the way they were actually the State
Department told people to stop buying
them,
but they have a national security threat
or something or something along the
lines of I'm a third party spying the
concerns,
what does it say here,
Australia to band while away from five g
rollout amid security concerns,
but us had an issue and I think the US
issue was slightly different.
US was um,
who was the State Department that was
saying for security concerns to not.
Yeah.
I don't know.
But I,
you know,
whenever they talk,
look,
they're talking about these,
the,
the auto terrorists from and they say
it's national security as if somehow my
buying a foreign car is somehow
jeopardizing.
What is the national.
I don't know.
I mean even the Canadians have called
trump out on it.
So what do you mean we,
you know,
we fought as allies in every single war.
How are you saying that you have to put
tariffs on Canadian?
So why is,
why is trump doing this?
Look again,
he's going after
the symptom.
Trade deficits are the consequences of a
problem.
Most politicians ignored the trade
deficits,
right?
At least Donald trump is putting them on
the spotlight and saying,
look,
this is a problem.
It is a problem,
but not for the reason that trump
believes in the short run in the here
and now the trade deficits benefit
America.
Because the world is subsidizing our
standard of living.
We're getting to buy things that we
otherwise wouldn't be able to have.
I mean,
without these trade deficits,
we wouldn't have all these consumer
goods on all these shelves.
I mean,
people would not be able to buys them.
Prices would be much higher if we had to
make stuff ourselves by having the
Chinese make it,
you know,
it's a lot cheaper and plus,
it's great for the,
our environment because we don't have to
pollute our own air because the
factories are over there.
Uh,
but he's so he's right that it's a
problem.
But in that it's a reflection of the
fact that the economy is inefficient and
that's what needs to be addressed.
It's like,
you know,
we have cancer,
but you just can't put bandaids on the
blemishes or something to cover it up.
You got to actually get to the source of
those blemishes,
which is the the Federal Reserve and
their bad monetary policy and our
government policy or our fiscal policy
or regulatory policy.
We need to have that type of change and
then the trade deficits will go away,
but if we simply tried to put tariffs
on,
it's just going to make our own problems
worse.
All that's going to do is make prices
higher.
Is this going to mean that Americans are
gonna have to spend more money buying
stuff and it also actually undermines a
lot of American businesses that export
into countries that are retaliating and
also a lot of us businesses,
a import components and then they
assemble the components here,
but now those important parts are going
to be more expensive and so their net
exports are more expensive and so they
become less efficient.
The people that are supporting trump,
that people that are happy with the way
things are going have have said that him
lowering taxes for corporations
encourages growth and encourages it.
It gets more jobs and there's more
economic activity.
Does that make sense?
Well look,
if we eliminate taxes,
yeah,
that'd be great.
I mean the lower taxes are the better
it's going to be,
but not if you borrow the money to pay
for the tax cuts.
So the idea is if the government now has
to go into the market and borrow money
that it no longer collects and taxes,
that's going to have an impact on the
economy,
that's going to further deplete our
savings pool.
That's going to put real upward pressure
on interest rates and obviously the Fed
is trying to counteract that.
But you know what they did with the tax
code though,
they dramatically complicated it.
I mean there's a lot of.
There's a lot more complexity in the
code now than there was before.
Not like it wasn't complex before.
So initially they talked about
simplifying the code.
They didn't do that.
They,
they,
they made the,
the,
the code a lot more complex and they
certainly,
you know,
they lowered,
they raised lower taxes for some people,
but they raise taxes for other people.
Me,
depending on what state you're in,
there are a of people now that are going
to
pay higher taxes.
What?
See what people are doing.
Well,
people in California are you gotTa,
you know,
you got a 13 percent income tax in
California that's no longer deductible
on your state income tax,
on your federal income tax.
So that's it.
That's a new thing.
Well,
yeah,
I mean,
up until this year you could deduct your
state income tax from your federal
income tax.
So you did the effective tax rate was,
you know,
maybe 40 percent less because it was
just money you would've sent to
Washington.
So instead you send it to Sacramento.
But basically the state tax rates are
almost double now what they were last
year,
uh,
in the,
the way it impacts the payer.
So there's a big increase in state taxes
for individuals.
You didn't,
you didn't know that?
No.
Yeah.
You know,
you gotta you know you're going to move
to Puerto Rico with me.
I know,
but I hear you guys don't have any
power.
Well,
we got power now.
Now many months.
Did it take?
What?
Don't I have generator?
Yeah,
but you're the only one.
You're like guards outside making sure
nobody steals your water.
No,
it's not.
It's,
you know.
In fact we were laughing about it,
but you know,
I was on your show a year ago,
right?
We talked,
we talked a lot about Puerto Rico.
It was post trump.
Trump.
Trump was.
Trump had won but it was before Maria,
but.
And so I was on the show and we were
talking about Puerto Rico and we also
talked about cryptocurrencies and
bitcoin and stuff like that.
But since then hundreds and hundreds of
crypto guys have moved to Puerto Rico.
I met some of my neighbors.
Now are these crypto millionaires?
They're living on the beach.
They,
they,
they weren't there a year ago.
They're there now.
They're,
they,
they call it a poor topia.
They all want to come there because
there's no capital gains tax.
But I got to,
you know,
kind of credit you because I think a lot
of these guys didn't know about it until
they heard about it on this podcast and
they said,
wait a minute,
there's no taxes down there in Puerto
Rico and now they're all there and they
moved there just in time for the
hurricane.
No,
they moved after the hurricane.
I moved before the hurricane is moving
after the hurricane,
a better move.
Financially,
it's probably cheaper land easier now
know I can't even tell.
Some of the real estate has actually
gone up.
Um,
yeah.
And like the real estate that was
untouched,
you know,
I mean my community a weathered the
storm pretty well,
so maybe it made it more desirable.
Really Widens your community.
You do so well.
Just,
I mean it's got,
it's,
you know,
even though I'm on the beach,
the elevation is,
is very high so we didn't get any
flooding and I guess the construction is
much better there.
You know,
the houses are built better so they
didn't know.
They didn't withstand the damage and the
community got up and up and running a
lot quicker.
So how long were you without power?
Oh,
there was.
Well,
officially there was probably no power
for a couple months,
but I have a,
you know,
my condo has power just as a big
generator and so we had,
we had condo power there right away,
but the house that I,
I ended up buying a house there too,
right before the hurricane and I didn't
have the generator put in yet so the
house didn't have power for months and
months,
which just exasperate,
I
had some damage to the house and then
the fact that there is no power made it
worse because it got very humid in
there.
But I've since purchased a generator and
I've got it all installed and so I'm
ready for the next,
for the next hurricane.
But you know,
I,
I got those funny,
funny they'd before the hurricane.
There was a lot of controversy from this
podcast from my,
um,
my,
uh,
my talk about Puerto Rico because I
mentioned on,
on the show that I had moved some
employees to Puerto Rico.
I have three single guys that used to
live out in southern California and they
all moved out to Puerto Rico because I
moved my business there.
This was in 2013.
I moved my asset management company.
You're Pacific asset management,
moved it to,
uh,
to Puerto Rico.
And so these guys moved out.
They're single guys that I mentioned
that they were having a good time there.
A lot of very beautiful women in Puerto
Rico,
you know,
um,
I mentioned I think five Ms Dot Universe
has been from Puerto Rico,
which is,
which is a lot for a small place.
And I said that know they have a good
time there because the labor force
participation rate in Puerto Rico is
terrible.
I mean hardly anybody has a job,
maybe,
maybe a third of the people who should
be working or working.
And that's,
you know.
again because of the socialism down
there,
the welfare state that's there and it,
you know,
and the minimum wage in Puerto Rico is
effectively like,
you know,
it's the medium wage,
it's like having a $15,
$17 an hour minimum wage year.
So it destroys a lot of employment
opportunity,
dying island.
So I mentioned that,
you know,
if they,
they have a good time down there because
there's a lot of women and if you're a
guy and you got a job,
I mean,
you know,
you could write your own ticket,
that's a big plus to have a job because
women want to date guys with jobs.
And,
and this was controversial,
you know,
you wouldn't think it would be,
but all of a sudden all these big guys
down there in Puerto Rico,
they'll probably say something again
because obviously they watch your
podcast.
But,
but um,
couple of really big guys were calling
me out saying that I'm insulting Puerto
Rican women.
Like,
you know,
I'm calling them whores or something
because I said that they want to date
guys with jobs.
Well,
why
doesn't every woman want a data guy with
a job?
Yes.
It's not just Puerto Rican into running
around going,
I don't want to go with a job.
No,
exactly.
Of course a girl wants a god that has a
job.
I mean,
every girl.
Yeah,
I mean probably one of the main reasons
we get jobs is to get girls.
Oh yeah.
I mean,
you know,
and you know,
generally the more attractive the woman
you know,
the more the better your job's going to
have to be to attract her.
Yeah.
There's a,
there's a term for that high pergamum
like women tend to gravitate towards men
with higher social status status and
higher.
Well first of all,
if you want a guy to take you out on a
date,
if he doesn't have a job,
where's he going to take you?
There you go.
I mean,
you know,
so I mean it's not.
I didn't think it was a controversial
statement is I think that point just
making much ado about nothing these days
and they can write a blog and then you
talk about what they wrote because you
were upset that them being upset at you
on the podcast and talking about it
again.
So you're feeding it.
No,
but I'm correcting it.
I mean,
I just want to say that it's not just,
you know,
there's nothing wrong with a woman
wanting a guide that,
that has a good job and not only that
it's favorable.
Well,
yeah.
but it's not only just because he can
take her on a date.
I mean,
when a woman is on a date with a guy,
I mean everybody is a potential husband
and you've got to bring something to the
table.
You know,
you gotta you know,
you gotTa,
you gotTa have ambition,
you've got to be a go getter.
You gotTa,
you know,
you just get me living in your parent's
basement.
What does that mean?
You got to get a job right to get the
money.
So then when you get some money,
you get the power to get the whipping.
How are they saying?
What was the protest that I was
insulting Puerto Rican women by saying
they want a man with a job,
like they're just all gold diggers or
something and I,
you know,
I didn't say that guy,
it was just,
they only,
they only wanted money.
But look,
I mean,
having a job is a key thing.
God,
we don't care.
The guys don't care as much what the
woman does.
But women,
I mean that's a big thing.
Most nothing.
They don't care at all.
If she's hot,
if it takes a lot of money and the
girl's hot.
Yeah.
I mean,
look here,
she got nice to read.
If a guy was going to set up a guy right
with a friend,
the first thing that guy's going to say
ask is what does she look like?
Yeah,
right.
That's the first question.
Is She nice?
Right?
If a woman is going to tell a girlfriend
about a guy,
what's the first question?
Probably what it looks like first know
what is he doing?
I guarantee it's what is he doing?
What does he do for a living?
I think first it's what he looks like.
Second is what is he not know?
I think what he looks like his lower
down on.
I think it's what does he do for a
living?
Is He.
Does he have a nice personalities?
They have a good sense of humor I think.
I think.
How does he look?
Is a little bit lower down on a woman's
totem pole.
Have to pass it.
How hot she is.
Well maybe.
Yeah.
It depends on how good she's doing in
the marketplace.
Yeah,
but I mean,
but all this.
I mean it's almost,
it was almost part of the whole
political correctness thing of it like
or the me too.
Like you can't,
you,
you can't say something.
Anything that you say is going to be
spun like this is,
this is against women because I'm
stating something that's very obvious,
right?
That,
that,
that so can't state obvious anymore.
No,
no,
no.
I mean it.
It's all like look like you can.
Because I think these outrage peddlers
that make these articles and write these
blogs,
who the fuck is agreeing with them?
I just,
I just don't buy it.
I think what they're doing is they're
striking a chord and a,
a few malcontents go along with it.
But you read those things and you think
like,
wow,
there's some validity to this because
it's in x publication.
So I got a comment on this.
They're,
they're misrepresenting what I said,
but they're outraged merchants.
Yeah.
And everybody wants to act like you
can't say something that's offensive to
anybody.
Like if somebody gets offended then you
know,
like,
you know,
this,
what was this,
you know,
this one of these contestants,
I read this story,
but one of the contestants on the
Bachelorette,
I'm apparently on his instagram page.
He liked some jokes that,
um,
that,
you know,
maybe off color a little bit offensive
jokes that right wing.
Somebody on the.
I had posted on their instagram page and
it was like a big deal to take that as
whole instagram page.
I mean,
it's obviously jokes,
they're jokes.
Jokes are offensive.
That's part of what makes them funny.
I mean,
I mean how it almost all the jokes
offend somebody,
but now you can't even have a sense of
humor.
Everything has to be,
you know,
you can't,
you can't offend anybody,
which you don't have a right not to be
offended.
That's the whole part of freedom of
speech.
People are going to say things and do
things that you might be offended by and
you just gotta you just gotTa deal with
it.
You can't be looking like,
you know,
I,
I got to have a law against that.
Or,
but these,
uh,
these offense merchants,
these people that get offended,
they,
that's their currency.
They,
they,
they trade in being offended and then
once they find something that's in any
way offensive,
they just start writing blogs about it
and making videos about it.
And that's their,
that's their,
in their,
in is finding something Peter Shifts
said about Puerto Rican women women's
offensive because it's just,
this is the world we live in.
A white guy like you wealthy guy,
you're going to talk about Puerto Rican
women,
you fucking piece of shit.
Well,
they're,
I mean they're white,
most of,
I mean there are a little darker skin
and then the most complicated,
but in this day and age that they're
Latino,
they're people of color.
What color am I?
I got to La.
I'm not,
you know,
I got a little color.
To me that's a,
that's an interesting conversation I
just had with a friend of mine who she
claimed she's black.
I'm darker than you.
Oh,
you black.
Yeah.
But it's all like,
it's this whole mentality that people
have now about not being offended is
about feeling that they have a right to
something or not being entitled.
Tyler people confusing a privilege with,
with the.
Right.
So you have all these groups that
demand,
you know,
women's rights or gay rights,
women or gays,
they don't have rights because they're
women,
right?
We all have individual rights and so men
and women have rights because they're
individuals.
They don't get a separate.
Right because they fit into a group.
Right?
All that is about privilege and you
don't have special privileges granted to
you by the constitution.
We all have rights and when people try
to pretend that a privilege or a group
privilege and try to give that the
status of a right,
I know you talked about it on your,
on your podcast when we had the supreme
court ruling recently regarding the gay
couple that wanted a wedding cake and
they,
you know,
they sued because the baker wouldn't
make a wedding cake with a couple of
guys on the top and decorated in a way
that it was obviously for a gay wedding.
There's a bottom is understanding about
that.
And I've read something recently that
not only did they not do that,
but they weren't making custom cakes so
they didn't make custom cakes for
weddings.
So when these,
the,
the gay couple came in so they wanted a
custom cake.
They said,
no,
we don't make that.
Like that was also part of the problem
was they don't,
that's not something they even did.
They could've,
would've sold them a cake theory had one
or two dudes holding hands.
Well,
the bigger problem is first of all,
they.
It's not like you have this gay couple
that just went into a bakery and then
they were denied the ability to buy a
cake.
Right.
They probably went to 100 bakeries to
find the one that wouldn't make the
vacation specifically do that.
Part of the story was that they wanted
someone to deny them.
Yes.
And had a story.
Right.
And of course,
you know,
if you're a baker,
right?
I,
I don't know what the margins are on
wedding cakes,
but wedding cakes are probably like the
holy grail of cakes,
right?
I mean,
you're.
If you're sitting there on the small
bakery shop,
you're waiting for somebody to call for
a wedding cake because those are the
biggest case.
You could make very expensive cake.
So everybody wants to do a wedding cake.
Nobody cares whether there's two guys or
a guy and a girl on the top of it.
You just want to make the money that
you're going to get from baking wedding
cake.
Now you come across a guy who just has a
strong religious conviction.
He just,
you know,
doesn't want to bake a cake for a gay
wedding.
Okay.
I mean,
he's the one that's losing.
He's losing out on the,
the,
the commission to bake the cake.
I mean,
the gay couple isn't hurt by that.
There's so many bakeries that would bake
them.
That cake was this couple.
Were they denied because of religious
reasons?
Is that why the people said they
weren't,
wouldn't make the case that.
Yes,
they said it was religious reasons and
that's what the supreme court I think
went on religious freedom,
but as far as I'm concerned,
it doesn't matter what their religion
is.
Nobody is required to perform a service
for somebody else if they don't want to.
Okay.
What if it was a black couple?
Yes.
And what if these people are racist and
what have they said,
we don't want to bake a cake for a Black
Cup.
Well then the black couple can go find a
bakery that we'll bake them a cake.
I mean,
what's the odds of there being a racist
Baker out there?
But I,
you know,
I mentioned if I was today's Day and
age,
it's less than ever before.
Right?
But let's look.
Look,
I mean,
it's still possible,
right?
I'm Jewish,
Let's say there's an anti Semite Baker,
right?
And if he,
if I go in there and the guy says,
you know,
oh,
I don't want to bake cake for Jews,
fine,
you know,
because let's assume that he knows I'm
Jewish.
He hates Jews and he spits in the cake.
I mean,
I'd like to know,
like right up front that this guy who's
about to bake my cake hates Jews.
So then I'll go and buy my cake from
somebody who doesn't hate Jews because I
don't want to worry about what I'm going
to be putting them in my mouth.
I mean,
why would you want to even force
somebody to bake a cake for you that
you've got to eat if you're forcing it
to do it or you know,
this is all nonsense.
But you know,
the,
the idea that you can't discriminate,
that you can't make choices,
right?
I,
I have a right as an individual to um,
you know,
to do things that I want to do,
but I can't force somebody else.
Writes are about big government.
Could you can't rob from me and you
can't steal from me so you can't take
away from me something that I have,
but I can't force you to give me
something I don't have and just because
I feel a certain way.
Like if you go back to the,
the,
uh,
the gay couple to say,
okay,
you can't discriminate.
How did the Supreme Court ruling that by
the.
Well,
they,
they uphold,
held the right of this individual,
but it wasn't like a real individual to,
to get.
But I think it had to do with some
esoteric state law.
It wasn't a definitive ruling that says
that you have a right to discriminate,
which I believe that.
I believe you do.
I don't think the government should be
discriminating but private individuals.
But the point I was about to make is,
you know,
for,
for gay.
So let's say that you,
Joe Rogan,
we're,
I'm working as a Gigolo.
That was your job.
You just had sex with women and you
charge them money nights.
Yeah.
That's your job.
Now,
what if a dude comes up to you and wants
to partake in your services?
Do you have to serve him?
That's not the job,
sir.
The job was women.
No,
no.
You can't discriminate.
What's right.
That's my point.
Discriminate in terms of having sex with
men.
Well,
not if you're doing it for business.
If it's your business.
Now my job is Gigolo.
Gigolo was a guy,
has sex with women.
I know that's the job.
It's like you're asking a firefighter to
dig a hole for the Gigolo is a guy that
has sex for money.
It matter whether it's a guy or a girl.
No,
that's the point though.
Women Bro.
Well,
but then your business card,
but then you're discriminating against
men.
How could you deny?
How could you deny a man the opportunity
to have sex with you?
Interesting.
Sees the same thing.
You can't look and you can say,
what if?
What if it's not sex?
Okay,
that's mess.
What if it's just massages?
What if your [inaudible] but for some
reason just don't want a massage.
Guys,
you just only want to massage girls.
Shouldn't you be able to do that?
Yes.
Yeah.
I mean,
so what?
And so it's,
it's touching people like you.
If you're a business,
you want your business to be limited.
Oh,
do is massage chicks,
bro.
I don't touch dudes.
Yeah,
why?
But why.
But yeah,
but you should have a right to do that.
But then once you extrapolate it,
you just make a decision.
Now you could make more money if you
massage girls and guys because you have
a bigger market.
But if you want to limit your business
opportunity to just women,
well that hurts you.
Right?
Then it's your right to do that.
Yeah.
Like a massage therapist that doesn't
want a massage guys.
You never hear about those and you don't
get offended.
Men Don't get offended by that.
Guys want massage me.
Well,
but you know,
you could do it as a,
as a customer.
I mean,
I,
you know,
let's just say I'm a,
I want a massage and I can say,
look,
I prefer to get a massage by a woman.
Yes.
I mean most guys would probably prefer
to get a massage by a woman.
Yeah.
Well,
is that that that's totally legal.
They always let the customer,
the customer can discriminate.
The employee can discriminate,
right?
Nobody would say,
you know,
hey,
if I,
let's say I happen to be black and I
want to work for a black boss,
nobody would say that was wrong.
I could go to a white boss and I could
say,
no,
I'm sorry.
I don't want to take the job because I
want to work for some in black bay.
You sue me for not breaking.
You're actively seeking out a black
boss,
which is the difference between that and
being approached by a bunch of white
people and saying,
no,
I hate white people.
No,
no,
no.
The point is,
if a,
if a white person or even a black person
was seeking out a job application of
about,
they would say that's illegal.
You can't discriminate,
but the employer can do it.
All the employee can do it all.
He was right customers,
right.
If I was,
if I was a.
If a gay couple wanted to have a cake
baked and I went and they went into a
bakery and they said yes,
we'd like to have a cake bake,
are you straight or gay because we want
our cake to be baked by a gay baker,
and the straight guy said,
no,
I'm straight.
Sorry.
They find they can keep searching until
they found the gay and no one would say,
and I'm not saying that we should make
that illegal.
I'm just saying the laws should be
consistent.
That means that is interesting that the
employer or rather the customer can
basically go wherever they like and no,
no one says you didn't go into this
restaurant because you don't like gay
people because gay people run this
restaurant.
Nobody ever says that.
Right.
And they can't force you to eat there if
you don't want to go the other way.
They can.
They can force you to use or to have
someone use your services even if you
don't believe in what they stand.
Yeah.
And they.
And then the left always tries to make
it out.
Like if you have this perspective,
right?
Oh,
like,
oh,
you must be a racist if you believe that
people have a right to discriminate.
Look,
I,
I'm,
I believe that people have a right to
say a lot of things that I disagree
with.
I'm not going to stop them from saying
things.
You know,
I believe in free speech,
even if what you're saying is idiotic or
offensive,
and I believe people ever right to
discriminate against it.
The bigger problem is when the
government becomes the thought police
because the minute you make it illegal
to discriminate,
now you have to get into people's minds,
right?
If somebody doesn't promote somebody or
fire somebody and they happened to be
black or a woman or too old or
handicapped,
you assume their motive,
but no,
but now you're going to say,
oh,
you fired that person a b because he's
black,
but what if that had nothing to do with
it?
Right?
You're assuming the motive for firing
people and now I got to prove that I
didn't do something for what I was
thinking,
what I did.
Something.
I mean,
none of that shit.
You know?
All of that too,
makes it so much harder for employers.
I mean,
look at what just happened.
This isn't race,
but it's part of it.
Do you see that story?
Um,
uh,
the other day about trump's driver is
suing him for overtime.
Yes,
I did see that.
Yeah.
So this guy worked for the trump
organization for like 25 years,
drive into his personal driver for
Donald Trump and he's now suing him
because he claims that he worked more
than 40 hours a week and so he wants
more money right now.
Of course he worked for 25 years.
Why didn't he ask for a raise like
during those 25 years?
Right.
But apparently his job,
he had to be on call for maybe,
I don't know,
10 hours a day.
Right.
And an on call doesn't mean he was
actually driving.
He just had to be available to trump if
trump needed them,
but
that,
you know,
he could be on the Internet,
he could be watching a movie,
it could be reading the books and in
emails,
you know,
traded stocks,
whatever he wants to do.
So it's not like it was that,
like he was really working,
but he had to be available so he
couldn't go out of town.
Right.
Um,
but he's going back and he says that,
well,
I had to be available for more than 40
hours a week.
Well maybe it was 50 hours a week or 55
hours a week and now he wants back pay
time and a half.
Right.
Because overtime laws say you got to get
time and a half.
But first of all,
he wasn't even an hourly worker.
The guy collected a salary,
something like 65,
$70,000
a year was his salary and you know,
he knew what the salary was when he took
the job.
He knew what the hours were.
If he didn't like it,
he could have said something to trump.
He could have demanded higher pay or he
could have quit.
Right.
But instead he works without complaint.
And then 25 years later files a big
lawsuit now the toys out of work.
Now he's working there.
He's still working.
There he is.
Yeah.
And he's suing Balis working in which,
you know.
And then of course,
if you fire them when they sue you,
it's like,
oh,
it's retaliation that it makes it worse.
But the problem is,
you know,
trump,
he's got a lot of money.
I mean,
he can deal with this,
but your average small businessman,
you know,
this kind of stuff kills you when people
start suing you,
it costs a lot of money.
And a lot of that happens too with um,
you know,
the,
the discrimination laws,
I mean because a small business owners
are so concerned about getting sued that
they try to hire people that they think
are less likely to sue them.
And then it ends up backfiring because
it works against all the people who are
protected classes who are now able to
sue you.
You know.
But I also wanted to point out on the
overtime laws because so many people
think,
oh,
this is terrible,
right?
I mean he should pay overtime.
Overtime is those laws are probably some
of the worst laws out there because they
don't protect workers,
right?
Because what happens is,
let's say you got a job and you're
working 40 hours a week and you're an
hourly worker and you want,
you want more hours,
you want more money.
Maybe you know,
maybe you want to,
you know,
you,
you're trying to track the higher
caliber of girls who try to get more
money.
You want to work more hours,
so sexist what you just said.
So say in a blog so you can tell it.
You tell your boss,
hey,
can I,
can I work an extra 10 hours a week?
Right?
I want to get some.
I want to make some more money.
Right?
Well your boss says,
well I'm sorry,
I'd like to let you work an extra 10
hours,
but I have to pay a time and a half.
Right?
And the guys look,
well I don't need time and a half.
I'll just work 10 hours for the same
pay.
That's illegal.
Sorry.
I would like to do it,
but I can't.
And if the,
if that boss needs extra workers,
he has to go bring on a part time
worker.
So now let's say if I want to get an
extra 10 hours work,
I got to find another job someplace else
where I can work part time where the,
the,
the time and a half law doesn't apply.
But now I got to get from my full time
job to my part time job.
How long does that
take me?
How common is this though?
That people are denying people extra
world.
It's very needed because they don't want
to pay the time of the half.
Oh,
it happens all the time.
I mean that's,
that's where moonlighting came from.
That's the whole.
I mean obviously people you're going to
have.
You can have people that worked for two
employers and then other people working
in there.
They're going back and forth between the
same company.
So what you're saying is it's weird if
someone has to work extra hours,
why you paying them double the money or
time and a half,
five and a half.
Why paying the extra money?
Because they're doing just just because
they're working more than eight hours a
day.
Well,
but the thing is the employer doesn't
want to pay the extra and he doesn't
have to,
if he can hire somebody part time,
but the point is that all of these,
um,
the,
the details of employment should be
negotiated by the employer and the
employee that government should stay out
of it,
you know,
and that time and a half is a government
law.
Yes,
it's nationwide yet.
Well,
different states can have different
rules and federally they have different
rules over what constitutes a,
how much pay do you have to earn before
the overtime rules apply.
What's also isn't a pretty arbitrary
like this decision that's 40 hours a
week.
Yeah.
Well,
like,
everything the government does is
arbitrary.
That's what laws are.
They have to come up with a number.
But all of this should be free for
discussion.
You know,
it's interesting because you have the
liberals believe that,
hey,
you know,
two people should be able to,
uh,
you know,
have a relationship without the
government interfering,
right?
You know,
they can have a sexual relationship.
It's,
it's none of the government's business.
Uh,
you know,
who you're,
you're sleeping with well,
why don't they have the same belief in
the same freedom when it comes to
economic relationships.
If an employee and employer or having a
relationship,
why doesn't the government just butt out
and let the employer and the employee
negotiate the relationship and the terms
of the relationship that they think is
best for them because there are a lot of
workers that,
oh,
I don't need the overtime,
but maybe there's another benefit that I
would prefer to have a that I could get,
but I can't because of government laws
are requiring things that I don't want.
So you're against minimum wage.
You're against essentially all these
government regulations in terms of what
you paid.
The minimum wage is probably the dumbest
law that we talked about that on the,
on the last podcast.
But it's probably the dumbest law,
uh,
that you can come up with because all it
does is hurt the very people that you
are intending to help you.
You're hurting the least skilled people.
A,
you're preventing people from getting
jobs in the first place and you're,
you're creating extra incentives for
employers to eliminate jobs,
to try to use capital instead of labor
to try to outsource.
I mean,
nobody is going to hire somebody if
they're losing money,
right?
People have a certain amount of
productivity that they can bring to the
table and when an employer makes a
decision on who to hire,
they have to hire somebody that brings
them at least enough productivity
to cover the wages.
And,
and so what happens is when you haven't
been in waves,
let's say the minimum wage is $8 an hour
and I'm an unskilled worker and I have
to convince an employer to pay me $8 an
hour.
I have to also convince him that I can
deliver more than $8 an hour of
productivity to his organization.
And if I can't do that,
I can't get a job.
Now,
what if I can only bring $5 of
productivity?
Well,
that means you can't get hired.
I mean if I could,
if I only have $5 an hour worth of
skills and I can't get a job to improve
my skills,
I'm stuck in unemployment forever.
I mean the worst thing you can do to a
guy with minimal skills is prevent them
from getting a job because it's the job
that's going to enable them to increase
their skills so they can earn more money
in the future.
I know what you're saying,
but the idea is that if you have a
minimum amount that you allow people to
pay the least.
The people that are working for the
company will have a real income where
they can pay their bills and feed
themselves and that this company,
because they have all the power,
they have all the money and a poor
worker who's stepping into the market
for the first time or you know,
just hasn't been been able to acquire
job skills that would allow them to make
much more money per hour that they would
be taken advantage of by this
corporations.
The corporations don't have all the
power because they're not the only
employer.
I mean,
all employers compete with one another
for labor and um,
and,
and they bid up wages.
I mean,
you can't pay people less than the
market value of their labor because
somebody else will hire them,
you know,
so that you could talk about,
oh,
wouldn't it be great if everybody can
earn more money?
Has there ever been a proven example of
this where they've had no minimum wage
and it's been a financial boom?
Oh,
absolutely.
Well,
first of all,
we didn't always have a minimum wage in
the United States.
I mean,
it,
it happened really in the 19 thirties.
But you can look at situations of
countries that have no minimum wage and
they have very low levels of
unemployment and you can look at areas
where the government using this.
Well,
I mean,
you know,
they don't have a minimum wage in,
in,
in Singapore.
Um,
and you know,
and there,
there are countries that,
since Singapore example though,
it's an extremely wealthy country,
right?
Well,
that's one of the reasons they don't,
they,
it's very easy to do business,
but you can look at examples where the
United States has imposed a minimum wage
on other countries.
I mean the minimum wages did a lot of
damage in Puerto Rico,
but you know,
look at another American territory of
American Samoa,
right?
American Samoa.
We basically destroyed American Samoa
with our minimum wage.
I mean,
the Samoans are,
you know,
are furious about it.
This happened years ago actually,
and I,
the reason I even found out about it,
I was watching 60 minutes and they were
doing a report about I think football
players in Samoa.
And um,
and during their report they mentioned
that there was a depression going on in
Somalia and it was like there was 30
percent unemployment and really high
inflation.
And I was like,
what the hell is going on in Samoa?
So I wanted to research that on my own
and I out that we impose the minimum
wage on Samoa and we destroyed all their
jobs.
They're,
the two biggest employers were to a
chicken of the sea and starkist,
they were canning tuna.
And then they were shipping the tune of
back to the mainland,
but the minute they raised the minimum
wage,
they made the production,
uh,
uncompetitive because now you had to pay
the higher wages,
plus the shipping costs to get the tune
it back to the mainland.
So they all,
the canneries shut down and then it
created massive unemployment and then
prices went way up on the island because
they no longer had boats coming back and
forth to pick up the tuna.
So now all of a sudden the shipping cost
of imports went way up.
So they had massive inflation,
sky high unemployment,
all because the minimum wage.
So you could look at examples of how
minimum wage destroys jobs.
Uh,
you know,
right there.
Yet they continued to advocate for these
higher wages because it sounds good.
Oh,
everybody should earn a decent living.
Well,
you know,
not if you don't have any skills,
you can't until of course,
you know,
a lot of kids,
they're 16,
17,
18,
19,
20.
I mean,
people live with their parents.
Still,
the most important thing is getting a
job so you can acquire the skills to get
a better job to,
you know,
to move up the ladder in an organization
to enhance your,
you know,
your value to employers in general.
What's the argument against this?
Against what you're saying about minimum
wage gangsta,
all these ideas that you're,
you're just proposing.
Do you do get a lot of pushback?
I mean,
I'm sure what you're saying,
this free market capitalism approach is,
you know,
there's a lot of people that oppose it.
Of course.
I mean there's a lot of people that
don't think it out.
They think with their mind or are there
others and they don't even get the read.
The origin of the minimum wage was
racism.
I mean the first minimum wages here,
it was designed to keep employers from
hiring the Chinese are from hiring
blacks because they know that that's
where the minimum wage came from,
you know,
to try to prevent employers from hiring
certain people.
So they said,
well,
let's have a minimum wage and that will
reduce our hiring of people who have
less skills.
And,
and,
and so,
and the labor unions,
the biggest supporters of the minimum
wage are the labor unions and none of
the labor unions workers earn the
minimum wage.
So you might think,
why are they,
do they so care about the minimum wage
if they don't get paid a lot higher
than,
than wage?
And it's because you always have a
competition between skilled labor and
unskilled labor,
right?
So let's say a business,
a businessman has the option of hiring a
skilled person to do something and let's
say the skilled person is going to
charge $20 an hour or an unskilled
person and let's say I can hire three
unskilled people for $5 an hour and that
equals 15.
Well,
Hey,
I'd rather hire the unskilled worker.
I can pay three,
$5 an hour to do the same job of one
skilled worker.
But now if the skilled worker can,
could lobby for $7 minimum wage,
now if I have to hire three unskilled
people,
it costs $21.
Aha.
Now all of a sudden I hire the guy with
skills.
So the labor unions benefit by keeping
unskilled people unemployed because they
have more skills and therefore they can,
you know,
they can get more work.
That sounds like a complicated mess to
me.
It is a mess for the,
for the,
for the people that get get priced out
of a job.
Yeah.
Now Democratic Socialism is the thing
right now.
This is the.
You're hearing it all the time.
You're hearing it constantly in the
news.
What do.
What do you attribute that?
Do you think it's a frustration with
this lifelong politicians?
Like what do you think it is that's
causing this upper eyes and upswing?
The woman,
what is her name?
That one in New York?
Yeah.
You know,
she's actually half Puerto Rican.
My mind,
my countrymen,
but yeah,
I forget her name and country.
Puerto Rico.
United States.
No,
actually,
you know,
I,
I found this out as I'm traveling now.
You know,
I still have an American passport,
but when I,
when I mentioned what country I'm from
and where you live,
I always have to select Puerto Rico as a
country.
Even though it's part of America,
it's still considered its own country
even though you still are American
citizens when you live there and you
travel on a,
on a US passport,
it's listed as a separate country from,
uh,
from the battle to the reader name from
a twitter,
Alexandria.
Yeah.
And you know,
Cortez,
28 years old.
Yeah.
Well she beat,
she beat a 10 term incumbent comment and
of course he was a white guy.
That's a,
that's a negative for him,
which is,
but a woman of color.
Yeah.
You know,
Latina woman to actually.
Yeah.
So,
but,
but the thing is people I think in that
community are just voting at a
frustration.
In fact,
I looked at her commercial,
you know,
and it's a very powerful commercial,
Kinda like,
you know about,
you know,
women like me are not supposed to run
for office.
We're not supposed to have court when
this whole bunch of nonsense.
But it's a story that I think resonated
with a lot of people.
Like,
Hey,
let's stick it to the man.
Right.
You know,
and uh,
and that's what they did.
But I think that this,
this wave is going to be bigger than
people think.
I think people are underestimating.
They're like,
oh,
this is unique because,
you know,
she,
um,
she's in a,
you know,
a heavily minority community.
And so that message work better.
But look,
Bernie Sanders
read this here.
Jamie just pulled up.
She won in a district where she didn't
even run.
Yeah.
Progressive candidate
also won a primary and our neighboring
district in the bronx
as a write in for the reform party.
Oh,
well that's alright.
But she won.
She won.
Yeah.
I,
you know,
you think you could have two house seats
simultaneously,
so yeah,
crazy.
But the eyesight.
But if you look at Bernie Sanders
appeal,
it wasn't just,
you know,
poor people and minorities that were,
that were attracted to the sanders
message.
And what was that message that was
attractive?
It was,
you know,
it was,
giving ratios.
And we got,
we got to tax the rich,
we got a tax fusion of wealth and it's
all about getting stuff for free,
right?
It's all about,
uh,
you know,
free healthcare,
free education,
guaranteed jobs.
I mean,
they want,
they want the government to guarantee
everybody at chomp.
Well,
that was one of the things that Bernie
said that he could guarantee people,
Joe,
you can't hear in the country.
How's the governor getting guaranteed
you,
first of all,
where's the government saying,
where's the governor going to get the
money?
They did that in the Soviet Union.
Yeah,
everybody has a job,
but nobody makes anything.
And so everybody is poor.
I mean,
you can't say what they want to
guarantee a $15 an hour job plus
benefits plus vacation plus health care
to do what?
And of course,
what's the governor?
The governor's going to assign jobs to
everybody.
What are they all going to do?
I mean,
people forget that we don't want jobs.
We want the productivity that result
from the job.
So it's about productive employment,
not make work,
right?
We don't want it to government digging
holes and filling them.
We want real jobs.
And,
and how do,
how does the private sector know what
jobs are needed?
It's demand.
It's,
it's individuals that want something,
they're guided by a profit motive.
You know,
the government that have governed
doesn't make a profit.
There's nothing to guide them to
efficiently allocate resources and how's
the government going to just figure out
what people should do and just assign
them,
okay,
this is the job you're going to do.
This is,
you know,
it would destroy employment in this
country if,
if you did that,
which this doesn't even make sense,
that you could offer everyone a job,
like you don't have those jobs first of
all,
and the idea that,
well,
what are we going to do?
We're going to create x amount of
construction jobs and x amount of
dishwashing jobs and x amount of carwash
jobs.
You're not going to,
and where's the money gonna come from to
pay for it.
They're going to,
they're going to have to take the money
from the private sector that would have
created efficient jobs and they're going
to give it to the government to create
inefficient jobs.
It's a disaster,
but the the,
the problem that I mentioned earlier is
the economy is in bad shape because of
all the government.
That's what go went back to the occupy
Wall Street is that the people are
protesting because there are serious
problems in the country.
They don't realize that it's not
capitalism that is creating those
problems.
Capitalism would solve those problems.
It's government interference that is
causing the problems that they're
protesting and so the same thing with
the socialists that they,
they,
they understand that their standard of
living is falling,
right?
Look at one of the things they want to
do is they want to give free education,
right?
Because the liberals are all complaining
about the fact that college is so
expensive and that students have so much
debt.
That's because the government,
before the government got involved,
college was cheap.
I mean government drove up the cost of
college by guaranteeing student loans.
I mean that's how the government got the
votes of students.
They promised the students something for
nothing.
They said,
hey,
vote for me and I'll guarantee I'll make
it easier for you to get a loan to go to
college.
Right?
Well,
the minute colleges knew that people
could get these loans.
They started jacking up the tuition so
they could benefit from all this
government money,
so the college has benefited.
The banking system benefited by making
riskless loans at the taxpayer was on
the hook for,
but the byproduct of all this cheap
money being funneled that the colleges
was that the colleges kept raising the
tuition higher and higher and higher,
and then the politicians kept increasing
the amount of loans they would
subsidize,
and so all of this is the fault of
government.
The government created the problem that
they're not complaining about,
but you,
the students don't understand that.
That's why college is so expensive.
Well,
no one sees a clear way out.
That's part of the problem and that's
one of the reasons why socialism is so
compelling.
It's like this seems like it's an
alternative to what we're currently
experiencing.
So people look at that and go,
maybe that's the solution.
I look.
People want something different.
I said that's why trump was able to
claim that he was going to shake things
up and make America great again because
I'm different because what's working,
what we have now is not working.
That's why I'm so afraid that when
people who voted for trump,
you know,
end up being disillusioned because
nothing changes.
Their lives don't get better,
and you're completely convinced that
this is going to be a crash coming in
the next three years.
Yeah.
I mean,
look,
there's going to be a big recession,
right?
I think it's going to be worse than the
2008 financial crisis.
I mean that because the government was
able to bail everybody out that time,
they were able to print a bunch of money
and go deeper into debt and the
financial crisis.
If you didn't have money in the stock
market and you didn't lose your job,
it wasn't that bad,
right?
I mean,
you know,
you know you were fine,
but this next crisis,
even if you don't lose your job,
you're going to be affected by
inflation.
Prices are gonna go way up because I
think this is going to be a dollar
crisis.
This is going to be a sovereign debt
crisis and investors were bailed out.
The government was able to bail out
investors last time with quantitative
easing and all tarp and all that,
but the next time investors are not
going to get bailed out,
right?
They're going to go down for the count
because if they try and I believe they
will try to reflate the bubbles again by
printing even more money doing another
round of quantitative easing,
it's going to destroy the dollar so
they're not going to reflate the bubble
in stocks.
They're going to prick the bubble in the
dollar and so when the dollar loses
value and prices go up and you have
stagflation,
you have a combination of a,
of a,
of a recession and inflation at the same
time,
and then of course,
what is the Fed going to do in that
circumstance because they,
you know,
their playbook is if you have recession,
you ease.
If you have inflation,
you tighten.
Well.
What if you have them both together?
You know,
they just did these stress tests,
you're here,
these bank stress tests and the Federal
Reserve came out and they said that all
the banks passed.
You know what?
What a shocker,
right?
The Fed came up with a test that
everybody passed,
but if you look at the assumptions that,
that they made about the economy under
the worst case scenario that they
assumed interest rates,
tenure rates go no higher than three
percent.
They don't go.
They don't,
they don't go down,
they just don't go up and they assume
that inflation stays below two percent
under the case scenario,
and they assume that the Fed is able to
lower interest rates to one percent to
zero.
Again,
to stimulate the economy.
Now,
I mean,
what happens if inflation doesn't go
down?
What if it goes up?
But if it goes up to five percent,
eight percent,
you know what?
If interest rates go up to five percent
or eight percent,
10 percent,
what happens then?
Right?
All the banks collapsed because what
happens if we have a recession where the
Fed can't stimulate because inflate,
they have to fight inflation or what
happens if we have a recession and the
government has to raise taxes during the
recession because the budget deficit is
exploding and they don't have the money
to pay the interest on the debt.
What does happen?
Well,
well,
I,
I think that the political politics are
going to play come into play and that
the Fed is going to air on allowing
inflation to run out of control.
They're going to do what they can to try
to prop up the economy and they're going
to sacrifice the dollar.
They're going to say,
well,
inflation is the lesser of the two
evils,
but it's actually gonna end up being the
greater evil and member,
you know,
when Nixon imposed wage and price
controls,
which was a very misguided effort.
And it's Kinda like,
you know,
what trump is doing with the,
uh,
with terrorists trying to cure the trade
deficit.
Rising prices are the result of
inflation.
It's not the cause.
And so price controls don't work.
They simply try to mask the problem
while it while it a while it gets worse,
but I think they're going to let
inflation get a lot worse.
And what that's gonna mean is that,
you know,
people need to prepare for that.
I mean,
people need to do something.
We talked about that when I was on your
show before about buying gold,
you know,
we talked about cryptocurrencies,
I talked about,
you know,
gold money and by the way,
this is when we talked about gold money
on your show before and so many people,
this just shows you how many people
listen to this podcast.
So many people tried to open up accounts
at gold money because of our
conversation that the regulators
actually shut them down.
They actually stopped them from
onboarding new customers because there
was too many people coming onto the
platform and,
and,
and the reason that this is the bay,
this is this,
this,
the system that we're in now.
Because when you have a gold money
account,
right?
It's not like just buying gold,
you have gold that you can actually
transact in.
I can take my golden and I can send it
to anybody I want anywhere in the world
who has an account for free,
so it's like a money transfer.
So gold has to be actually stored.
Some real golden it.
Exactly.
There's gold stored in a brink's vault
and you know,
they have vaults all around the world,
but I can transfer my ownership of that
goal to you or anybody else,
but because I can do that now all of a
sudden the regulations there because
they're worried about terrorists,
they're worried about money laundering
and so everybody who has an account,
there has to be a lot of scrutiny about
those,
those accounts and those transactions.
Just like it was a bank.
And so this,
this and a lot of people got frustrated.
I got a lot of emails from people who
were frustrated.
They try to open up an account and they
didn't realize that it was the
regulators,
you know,
they get mad at gold money because
they're
not opening up their account or
improving their account,
but it's the regulations that are the
cog in the machine.
But the good news is,
I think they've,
they've made,
they've satisfied the regulators
recently,
they've come up with some new systems,
so the process is a lot more efficient
now for people to go online and buy gold
and you don't get,
you can buy know 25,
50 bucks worth 100 bucks worth of gold
and you actually have another store of
value,
another means of transacting with other
people where you can have some
protection against,
uh,
against inflation.
And you know,
I showed you,
I have,
by the way,
they're sending you one of those gold
carts.
I talked to him.
Yeah,
you,
I showed you this car that I have to do,
have to send them some money.
So you're going to have to get,
I'm not sure if they're going to preload
your account,
you know,
I went through,
I brought this card through the,
through the security today.
And of course every time I go through
security with discard it rings.
So I always have to take my wallet out
and put it in a,
uh,
in a little the little bin.
And it freaked out,
you know,
they can never figure out what's going
on because Satan and they see this thing
a metal,
they have no idea what it is.
So it's always like,
uh,
it stops me.
But it's a conversation piece.
But I had about three or four different.
A Tsa guys were all like,
you know,
looking at this card is that gold places
we'll go though.
This is pure gold.
It's actually,
this is.
Yeah.
This is,
this is a 24 karat gold.
So is gold mixed with metal,
right?
Mixed with steel.
It's not mixed with anything.
It's 24 karat gold,
like gold.
It's also mixed with something else as
pure gold.
Yeah.
No,
that's like that.
If you go buy gold jewelry,
right?
You're getting an 18 carat gold or 14
karat gold.
So how much does this card worth?
It's kind of like 14,
1400 bucks.
This would be an issue.
Melted down.
It's heavy.
Yeah.
But I mean compared to other cards,
but you know,
gold money,
another way that people can buy gold
pimps,
labs,
they launched a company called Monet,
right?
The website pulled up.
It's a m,
e n e Dot Com,
and this is a great way for average
people to own gold but also killed two
birds with one stone because when you go
out and buy jewelry,
right,
and you buy typical jewelry,
maybe it's 14 karat gold,
18 carat gold,
the men a jewelry is 24 carat gold and
they sell it by the weight of gold.
So if you,
let's say you went and you went into a
department store and you spent a
thousand dollars on a gold necklace,
right?
Maybe you'd have $100 worth of gold
maybe,
right?
If you spend a thousand dollars at
Manet,
you're going to get $800 worth of gold
and manet will buy that,
that necklace back from you at any point
in time in the future,
two years from now,
five years from now,
10 years from now at whatever the gold
value of the necklaces.
So let's say gold goes up by 30 percent
from the time you buy the necklace,
you can actually sell it back to monet
for more than you paid for it.
Whereas if you know,
if you have used jewelry that you buy at
a department store,
what's it worth on the secondhand
market?
You know,
ten cents on the dollar,
right?
Twenties maybe.
So this allows people to have nice
jewelry but also own real goal that the
same time.
I mean,
you're going to pay a higher premium to
buy
a gold necklace.
I have a pair of gold,
a gold cufflinks that I wear,
my wife,
where's this been a jewelry all the
time.
She wears it every day.
And so it,
you know,
you can buy it instead of buying other
jewelry,
but you know,
you're not throwing your money away.
You're actually,
you're actually getting also p.
But the point is that people need to
protect themselves from the inflation
that's coming because that is where
we're headed,
right?
They,
the government is going to continue to
print money to try to prop everything up
there,
try to delay the day of reckoning for as
long as they can.
And you know,
we've had a rally in the dollar recently
because people think,
oh,
the trade war is good for the dollar.
They're wrong,
it's a disaster for the dollar.
America can't win the trade war.
I mean,
we benefit from the trade deficit right
now.
All we can do is lose in the short run.
If we lose access to all those goods
that we're not having to pay for with
exports,
you know,
they're actually trying to say that the
budget deficit is going up,
is good for the,
a is good for the is good for the
dollar.
When it's not,
I mean big budget deficits are always
bad for the dollar because it means that
government is creating more debt,
they're selling more bonds around the
world.
You're,
you know,
the supply of dollars also includes the
surprise of treasuries.
And so if you're flooding the world with
treasuries,
you're,
you've got a surplus,
a dollar's a dollar is going to lose
value.
And so people have to find a way to
protect themselves and you know,
the average guy,
I mean,
gold is the easiest way to do that.
You know,
and you know,
with the gold money account,
you could do it very,
very inexpensive.
Of course,
if you want to buy bigger amounts of
goal,
if someone wants to put $50,000,
$100,000
with a gold,
I wouldn't spend it on jewelry,
right?
You could just buy regular goal.
I got a company shift gold,
right where I sell a,
you know,
maple leafs,
Krugerrands us a US buying gold jewelry
should be in addition to not,
not a primary investment.
Well,
because of the higher markup,
right?
When I sell gold bullion to people
coins,
we mark it up,
you know,
one,
two percent.
It's a small markup.
The markup on jewelry is higher because
we had to pay to make the jewelry.
It's more expensive to make a gold
necklace or a gold bracelet or a gold
ring than to make a gold coin,
so you wouldn't want to have all your
gold and jewelry,
but to the extent that you're going to
buy jewelry anyway,
you might as well buy real gold because
now you actually have some savings that
has value in addition to having
something you can wear.
I mean,
I don't.
I don't get a lot of value a day to day
by having golden is safe,
but you know,
if you're wearing it right,
I mean,
so then now you're getting an extra
benefit from the fact that you have gold
because you now,
you know,
you get to enjoy it on a daily basis if
you're wearing it and,
and obviously too,
if you don't have that much money,
if someone's not going to buy any goal
that someone has a couple thousand
dollars and that's,
you know,
they were going to spend it on jewelry.
Alright,
we'll spend it on gold jewelry because
at least you still have the money,
right.
At least 80 percent of what you spent.
You still have a.
well it makes sense to me and I don't
know much about gold,
but it's,
it's weird that gold is one of those
things.
It's like universally been thought of as
valuable
like forever.
Yeah,
that's.
Well that's why.
That's why it's money.
I mean gold is always been a or anything
else like that.
Let me.
There are other metals that had been
used as money.
I mean,
silver has been used as money,
right,
but I mean gold has been the choice and
it looks,
central banks own a lot of gold.
I mean not as much as they used to.
Not as much as they should.
Uh,
but central banks own it.
Gold's a monetary metal,
but,
you know,
gold is used in a lot of things.
I mean,
it's in,
in cell phones and computers.
It's used in,
uh,
in,
in medicine and dentistry,
dentistry.
I mean,
so there are a lot of uses for it
because gold has properties that other
metals don't have that gives it value,
not just its physical beauty,
but also the things that you can do with
it.
You know,
you,
you can do things with gold,
uh,
that you can't do with other metals and
gold is not going to tarnish.
It's not,
it's like,
you know,
rust,
so it's,
you know,
you can make something out of it and
it's not going anywhere.
Yeah.
You can also plate things with it.
Rallies.
You can take a small piece of gold.
You could play this entire table.
Exactly.
Yeah.
I mean,
I've never seen that happen,
but I've had it explained to me it seems
very strange.
Yeah.
The property is that it has,
you know,
no other metal can replicate and that's
what are the reasons that it's been so
desirable for so many years,
but it also makes it,
you know,
ideally suited to be money and that's,
one of the things that we know Bitcoin,
bitcoin is trying to digitally replicate
the properties of gold.
I mean,
that's the whole selling point of
bitcoin.
They say it's digital gold,
right?
Um,
and it does have a lot of golds
properties that helped it succeed as
money,
but it doesn't have any of gold physical
properties that gave it so much value in
the first place.
And so you can't separate the intrinsic
value of money from money.
Money has to be a commodity.
It has to have value.
And,
and that that's where bitcoin fails.
You know,
I just had it.
I had a debate.
I'm in New York and Soho last last week,
uh,
on bit coin a bit,
you know,
whether it was going to succeed and a
replace if he at currencies and
basically,
you know,
candidly,
I lost a debate,
but I think it was rigged.
Was it really well because,
you know,
the way,
the way they,
they,
they decide to written the winter is um,
before the debate they have a poll and
they ask everybody where they stand and
then after the debate they asked them
where they stand now to see if people
changed their opinion and since
everybody in there was,
it was a whole bitcoin audience and I
had a confirmed to me from several
sources that basically everybody was
saying,
Hey,
make sure you vote this way before the
debate.
So you can change your mind after the
debate so that the pro bitcoin guy is
going to win.
Why?
Yeah,
yeah.
Yeah.
So did you,
did the initially vote neutral or anti
bitcoin?
No.
So the proposition,
the proposition is we'll bitcoin replace
the dollar or other Fiat currencies
right in the future.
But they wanted to propose it initially
before the debate,
right.
Get your thoughts,
but they rigged it by having these
people have contrary thoughts.
Before the debate was if bitcoin was
evangelize to them,
like,
oh,
now I get it.
The idea is to have as like a bunch of
people were in this debate that didn't
believe bitcoin was the future,
but now after this hour debate,
they were convinced by my opponent that
it was the future.
Because then,
you know,
when I read all the stories and if you
go online,
you read the stories about the debate.
It's always like Peter Shift last.
Peter gets bested shift loses.
So it's all.
It's almost like I got.
I got caught up in the bitcoin
propaganda,
but this is so much like you want to
talk about tribalism,
bitcoin and crypto currency.
Those people are all in.
Oh yeah.
As I said,
my giant group of them that are just.
Yeah,
they're all in.
I said they're all in Puerto Rico now,
so I'm hanging around more of the crypto
guys than I used to.
And what is your take look?
You know,
I feel badly in that.
Well,
first of all,
some of them got very rich,
so I don't feel bad for these guys that,
I mean that,
that got rich.
They put,
you know,
a few thousand dollars in and not
millions of dollars,
you know,
I mean,
obviously I,
I,
you know,
I've missed out on that myself.
Right?
I mean there's a lot of bubbles that I
missed out.
I didn't make anything on the DOTCOM
bubble.
I mean I made money when it came down.
I didn't make any money on the housing
bubble until it went down.
Um,
and you know,
I missed out on the bitcoin bubble butt,
but this bubble was tailor made for me.
If there was ever a bubble that I should
have been part of,
it was this one,
this was all,
it was all for the Libertarians,
right?
Free market guys,
anti a Fiat currency.
So,
you know,
I knew about it early on.
I mean,
not at the very beginning when it was
like pennies,
but I knew about it before it was $10.
I knew about it when it was pretty low.
How much do you have invested in
Bitcoin?
Oh,
zero.
Zero.
Yeah.
I mean,
I,
you know.
Oh actually no.
I got 50 bucks worth because no big
spender.
Well,
you know,
what happened is,
after,
after the,
uh,
the debate,
I went out to dinner with Eric
[inaudible],
who is my opponent,
his wife,
my wife was there,
we had a group of people and so they
gave me to show me how it works.
They gave me $100 with the bitcoin and
then I gave somebody back 50,
but I kept 50 of it.
So I just in case.
Yeah.
Although now it's only worth 40 acres
and it's gone down.
It moves all over the place.
Yeah.
But,
but,
you know,
so I mean,
I don't feel badly that,
you know,
some of these guys looked into having a
lot of money or you know,
it's luck or they took a shot and it
paid off.
Right.
They,
they,
they got in and you know,
and the,
the market exploded and they have an
opportunity to cash out at a profit,
but a lot of them are not cashing out.
They're gonna I think they're going to
go down with the ship.
But um,
when,
when you say that you think it's going
down.
Oh yeah.
Cause it's,
it's look,
it's not going to succeed as money.
It's not going to work.
It's just a highly speculative asset,
you know.
And the last time I did your show,
I mean,
a lot of people are,
you know,
what Peter Shift got wrong on Joe Rogan
about bitcoin.
I mean everybody thinks I don't
understand it and that's why I don't
believe in it.
It's because I do understand it,
but I don't believe that the people who
think it's going to work,
they may understand the technology but
they don't understand money.
Uh,
and so,
but what I talked to these people,
to me,
you know,
it's very much like a cult.
I mean,
they're,
they,
they believe so strongly in this.
They're so caught up in the hype and the
hysteria and maybe they're blinded by
the money they think they're gonna make,
you know,
when this,
these things are a million dollars a
piece or wherever they,
they believed they're going.
So the thing that's going to think it's
going to go to a million,
well there was an article last week,
some guy was saying 100 million,
$100,
million of Bitcoin,
you know,
that's why nobody wants to sell.
Right.
But the smart people are selling the
people that got in early.
You're trying to con people into holding
on so that they can get out of $100
million.
They're talking about $100 million and
it's basically some numbers on.
Did they ever figure out who.
That's a Toshi,
Toshi.
Dr Laura Nakamura.
Yeah.
I Dunno.
I mean I've been at the.
I don't know why the guy hasn't come
forward if it's a guy at all.
Someone said that they think it's the
Elon Musk.
I don't know what.
Whoever you,
whoever it is,
you figure they've got a lot of bitcoin.
If they're real person.
I mean it might have been a group of
people.
I bet.
Of course now it's not just bitcoin,
right?
There's 1500 to 2000 of these other
cryptocurrencies will not just that
there's a bunch of different ones,
right?
There's different variants.
Yeah.
And that's part of the problem because
they think,
oh,
there's 21 million bitcoin and they
think that that means they're scarce.
Well,
they're not scarce.
There's so many other currencies out
there and it's only scarce because it's
coded to be scarce.
Gold is scarce because it really is
scarce.
You know,
bitcoin is scarce because they decided
to make it scarce,
but it's not scarce in that bit.
There's nothing that any other
cryptocurrency can't do that bitcoin is
doing.
I mean,
but they're looking at it as an
alternative not to gold,
but to the currency that we currently
use.
Well no,
they literally,
they look at it as an alternative to
both.
I think a lot of them,
although some people think it's maybe a
compliment of goal,
but you know,
it doesn't have any actual value.
And that's where I get into a lot of
arguments with these crypto guys because
they say,
well,
gold doesn't have any actual value
either,
which is laughable because of course
gold has actual value.
There are lots of things that I can do
with gold and that shows that it has
value.
There's nothing that I can do with
bitcoin other than give it to somebody
else.
I mean,
that's the whole purpose of it is to
give it to somebody else,
but our whole economy's kind of screw.
It's entirely possible that it could
shift over to,
as a Crypto,
coin based economy,
cryptocurrency based economy,
governments could certainly issue crypto
Fiat currency the same way they issue
paper Fiat currency.
In fact,
most of our paper currency transactions
are digital anyway.
I mean,
how much cash do you use on a daily
basis?
You use your credit card and uh,
and so banks are transferring.
They're not,
they're not shipping bills back and
forth.
Mostly it's just numbers on a computer.
Uh,
so the government could certainly do
that.
And I,
you know,
that that would probably give them even
more control over the economy,
which is a negative thing because at
least if you have cash,
I can,
I can give you $100 and the government
doesn't see that transaction.
They're not spying on us.
But if they eliminated all cash and all
transactions were,
then they would know everything I did.
I mean,
every dollar I spent would be recorded
on some government computer and you
know,
that's something that I,
that I don't want.
And I think,
you know,
Libertarians certainly don't want that,
which is one way cryptocurrencies could
backfire is if the governments end up
monopolizing a crypto currency,
um,
and you know,
and an issue cryptocurrency alongside or
instead of the paper currencies that
they issue now.
But I think part of the biggest damage
that's ultimately going to come from it
is when the cryptocurrency currencies
collapsed and people lose a lot of
money,
which is going to happen.
Um,
the government is going to be able to
say,
you see,
we told you to free enterprise
capitalism is no good.
I mean,
look what happens when you trust,
you know,
uh,
the bit coin,
it's gonna,
it's gonna help make the dollar and the
euro and the yen look good by
comparison.
Even though these are fatally fraud
currencies,
they're still going to look better than
the cryptocurrencies to the people who
have lost a lot of money.
See Right now people,
there are a lot of people that like
bitcoin because they bought it real
cheap and even though it's gone down 70
percent from its high,
it got up to 20,000
and now it's about 6,400.
You know,
there's a lot of people that bought it
and still have big profits.
But what about the people that bought it
at 20,000,
18,000,
15,000,
$10,000,
they're losing money and if it keeps
falling and it goes down to 1000 or
lower,
where I think it's going,
you have a lot of people that have lost
a lot of money and so that's going to
create a lot of problems.
And I think the government's gonna come
in with all sorts of new rules and new
regulations on transactions to try to
protect us from ourselves is again,
it's just gonna,
you know,
try to make government look good in the
free market,
look bad.
But you know,
people get caught up in frenzies all the
time.
It doesn't mean that the free market
needs to be shut down just because every
once in awhile you know,
people get greedy and get nuts and it's
not a reason to expand the power of
government because government will do
much more damage to an economy then
small bubbles will do.
When you know,
when you have a boom and a bust because
you have a mania.
Do you think that
there's any cryptocurrencies that are
compelling?
Is there,
is there anyone other than bitcoin that
you go,
well,
this one has a different set of
parameters or different set of rules?
No,
because to me,
I mean,
you know,
you,
you just can't have a,
a,
a digital token that you just create
that's going to have going to be a store
value.
I mean,
money.
Money has to be a store of value.
It has to be a medium of deferred
payment.
So what that means is,
you know,
I have to be able to take my money and
save it for a year,
five years,
10 years.
I have to be able to make a loan.
Like,
I can loan you money,
I can't loan you a bitcoin and you say,
I'll pay the bitcoin back in 10 years
because none of us know what the bitcoin
is going to be worth.
So how do you know what kind of interest
rate to charge a,
you need to have stable money.
Uh,
and I don't think any of these
cryptocurrencies can ever be stable
because there's no real value to
stabilize.
People say it's a store of value,
but there's no value to store.
So the only cryptocurrencies that would
work would be crypto currencies that
were backed by
a real commodity like gold.
And that can work.
But you know,
what gold money does is actually
something better because you don't have
to have a crypto currency,
you just have actual goal.
See the reason that currency existed in
the first place because currency was
always backed by real money.
So let's say I had gold,
uh,
that I was storing at,
at a blacksmith.
I had a bar gold and I had a piece of
paper that said,
you know,
pay to the bear on demand.
You know this bar gold,
right,
and it was written from a reputable
blacksmith.
I could negotiate that piece of paper.
I can give you that piece of paper and
say,
Hey,
I own some goal that this blacksmith
take this piece of paper and now you own
the gold.
Right?
And and so that piece of paper is
functioning as a money substitute as
currency,
but the real money is in a vault.
It's gold,
but it's.
I can't.
It's hard for me to.
I can't break up that bar.
I can't just give you a small portion of
it,
but what gold money is doing is taking
that old blacksmith concept and bring it
into the modern era because I can store
my gold in a vault at breaks through
gold money and now I can transfer any
portion.
I can give you a gram of my goal,
that tiny amount of goal,
I can just send it to you for free and
now you own that goal because now the
ownership register is going to be
changed.
And instead of being in Peter Schiff's
name,
it's going to be in Joe Rogan's name.
And so once you can do that,
once I can take a bar of gold and and
turn it into liquid money that can be
used to buy a cup of coffee and you're
doing all these without having physical
control of the Gold Nano,
some physically holding it in your
hands.
It's in a vault somewhere.
Yeah.
Well somebody has to have physical
control and that's what a lot of the
bitcoin advocates don't like about
something like a gold mine.
I said,
well,
you have to trust a third party to store
your goal.
Yes you do.
I mean,
but people have been trusting third
parties with gold for thousands of years
and you know,
you have reliable third parties that can
hold onto something of real value
because you have to have stability.
I mean that's the big problem that we
have in the world today is we have no
real money.
We just have these Fiat currencies that
governments create out of thin air and
there's no real stability in the
monetary system.
If we had real money,
if we were on a gold standard,
which I believe we will be on again
eventually,
because that is the norm throughout
history,
is to be on a gold standard.
All these experiments with Fiat
currency,
they don't work.
They haven't done in a gold standard
since when the seventies.
Yeah.
We,
well,
we went off at 1971.
Of course,
you know,
w w we were on a pure gold standard,
uh,
you know,
in the 19th century and certainly the
latter part of it.
Uh,
and even think we're going to go back to
that.
I think so because that's what works.
I mean,
what we have now works for government,
but it doesn't work for the people.
It doesn't work for prosperity.
You know,
when,
when trump is out there trying to say we
have the greatest economy in history.
I mean,
it isn't,
it isn't even close.
I mean,
forget about the fact that it's not even
better than it was when Obama was
president and he said that was an
economic wasteland.
But go back to
the period of time,
let's say 18,
70 through 1910 are in there.
I mean,
that was the golden age of America.
that is what created the middle class.
The middle class was,
was a byproduct of the economic growth
that took place in America.
I mean,
we,
we basically had tremendous economic
growth.
We absorbed tens of millions of
immigrants that were coming from all
over the world and they weren't coming
here for welfare and food stamps because
they didn't exist.
There was no minimum wage,
uh,
you know,
there was just freedom here and people
came here from all around the world
because they can be freer in America
than they could be any place else.
And it was those free Americans working
with a gold standard with a solid sound
money that created the greatest amount
of economic growth that the world has
ever seen in the shortest amount of
time.
I mean,
people talk about,
oh,
how great the Chinese economy is,
but,
you know,
look back at the American economy during
that period.
And that was tremendous growth.
And I think,
you know,
we could have great growth again,
to the extent that we do substantially
diminished the size of government,
but part of that would be to return to
sound money and that would be gold.
But the cult of personality,
you know,
it's,
it's one of those things,
man,
I don't know this,
this is such a fascinating conversation
because I would love to have a person
who's equally educated on this stuff
that opposes your viewpoint.
And I'd love to see.
Yeah,
well they're,
they're,
you know,
there's certainly people that have posed
my viewpoint.
There's no shortage of them.
But,
um,
you know,
I'd be happy to come on to show you
don't think they're correct.
No,
no,
they're not.
They're not correct at all.
Oh,
you know,
before I forget too,
I forgot to bring this up because you
mentioned it on the other podcast and
you're like,
I wish somebody would come in and talk
to me about it.
Like,
yeah,
that's.
Got It.
I got to talk about it.
Which is the act 20,
22 in Puerto Rico and whether or not
Puerto Rico is in trouble because you
have a bunch of rich people who were
there who are not paying taxes.
Yeah.
That was the,
the charge,
right?
The reason why it was so difficult to
rebuild the infrastructure post Maria
was that all you rich guys come there
and soaked up the economy and that's why
you're there because you weren't paying
any taxes.
Yeah.
And so first of all,
the,
the tax breaks didn't start until 2012.
And before that,
what was going on in the same,
it changed.
Well,
if you were rich in Puerto Rico,
you paid the same 30 percent tax,
federal tax.
Everybody else,
nobody in Puerto Rico has to pay federal
income taxes.
That is one of the big benefits that
Puerto Rico has.
You don't have to pay the federal income
tax if you live there when you're
working there on the money you earned.
So if I had moved to Puerto Rico in 2010
or 2011,
which I did not do,
but how do I move there?
Then I would have had to pay the same
high Puerto Rican income tax that
everybody else in Puerto Rico's pain.
But what enticed a lot of people to move
to Puerto Rico was the fact that they
reduced the taxes.
Now the taxes are in zero,
right?
You,
if you come there,
you're still gonna pay taxes.
I'm on some of the money that you
weren't like my,
my business pays a four percent
corporate tax.
So it's not zero pay four percent.
I can give myself a dividend that's tax
free,
but the corporations are required to pay
out a certain amount of taxable salary
to the owners.
So some of my salary is taxed as high as
30 percent.
The majority of it is taxed basically at
the four percent,
but four percent of something is better
than 30 percent of nothing.
Plus they're getting 30 percent of
something.
So a lot of the people who have moved to
Puerto Rico over the last,
you know,
five,
six,
seven years that didn't live there
before,
are paying a lot of taxes now to the
Puerto Rican government,
even though the rate is very low,
the dollar amount is very high and each
individual person who was moved there is
paying a lot more taxes than the average
Puerto Rican who's already living there,
paying the higher rate.
So the people who moved there bought,
brought significant tax revenue that
Puerto Rico never was going to get.
Because remember,
if they were taxing people at 30
percent,
people from California wouldn't have
moved their people from New York.
People from New Jersey wouldn't have
moved there.
It was the low taxes that brought all
these people to Puerto Rico who never
would have been there.
And they're now paying taxes.
But more importantly,
they're hiring people who are also
paying taxes.
They're spending a lot of money locally
in the economy generating revenue and
jobs.
Uh,
so they've been a big plus.
And I can tell you the people who have
moved their,
myself included,
we donated a lot of money to the relief
efforts.
I mean as soon as that hurricane was
over,
a lot of the acts 20,
22 people,
which is what they'd be called because
they went there to participate.
They were raising money.
They were helping out.
I mean,
so there's a lot of charity that came to
Puerto Rico that a lot of these people,
they wouldn't have thought of it that
they didn't already live there.
But by bringing a lot of wealthy people
down there to Puerto Rico and they're,
they're living it,
you know,
they're more inclined to help out their
neighbors then when they were still
living in the US.
So Puerto Rico has derive significant
benefit from an influx of wealthy
entrepreneurs who have taken advantage
of them and that you move in there and
just exploiting that place by getting
paid and low taxes and that it's,
it's a,
it's a bad thing for the people that
live there.
That's a false still.
It's a great thing for the people that
lived there because people are coming to
the island,
bringing capital,
bringing businesses,
bringing employment opportunities,
paying taxes that they never would have
paid.
And let me ask you,
is key you ever anticipated.
I mean it seems,
what is Puerto Rico as big as any state
is as big as Rhode Island?
Like how big?
It's small.
I mean,
I mean geographically it may be about
the size is like 30 miles maybe and
that's the length.
It's skinnier than that.
So it's,
it's a small place but you know,
relative to the Caribbean.
I mean if you compare it to other
Caribbean islands,
it's pretty big.
How long is the flight from New York to
Puerto Rico?
Actually in the air it's about three
hours,
but I think the airlines,
you know,
they leave about four.
You know,
if you look at the flight time,
but actually from wheels up to wheels
down,
it's about a three hour flight.
So it's not far and there,
you know,
there are a lot of places that you can
fly direct to go to the west coast.
No,
you gotTa,
you know you got it.
Would there be a way that all these
people coming in,
they could somehow or another fix this,
the whole electrical system that they
have their,
their power grid and.
Yeah,
look,
the power grid,
this just shows you all the people that
think socialism is so great.
Look at Puerto Rico.
That's why they're broke,
right?
The socialist destroyed Puerto Rico,
the socialist in Puerto Rico,
and of course the ones that we have in
Washington because all their problems
aren't self inflicted,
but we created a problem for Puerto Rico
a number,
a number of ways.
First of all,
right?
We have the minimum wage that,
you know,
the average income in Puerto Rico is
half of the poorest state in the United
States,
which I forget.
I forget,
which is the poorest states like
Kentucky,
Kentucky maybe,
but it's,
it's half of half of that.
Right?
But now you've got a minimum wage that's
the same as Kentucky,
so it is basically keeping a lot more
people unemployed.
But then you have,
you still have welfare,
you still have food stamps,
so you have all these people.
Now that are not working because they're
getting paid by the government,
but then you have the Puerto Rican
government,
which is a major employer of gay people
work for the government and a lot of
them are just doing nonsense,
right?
I mean there's so many people that are
working for the government.
They're not productive,
but they're draining resources from the
Puerto Rican economy.
I mean,
part of it was a power company.
You know,
you mean it's a disaster,
but the government is running everything
there and so everything is inefficient
and meanwhile a lot of the productive
people,
people who want jobs have left the
island.
Like if you think a high minimum wages,
great.
All the people who are leaving Puerto
Rico to go to Florida are effectively,
even though it's the same minimum wage,
they're actually going to a state that
has a much lower minimum wage relative
to the medium wage because they can get
jobs in Florida.
They can't get them in in Puerto Rico.
So you have that situation where you
know very few people are actually
employees so you don't have a real tax
space.
And then what America did,
but really screwed them over was we made
all their bonds triple tax free.
We said,
if you're,
if you live in New York and you buy
Puerto Rican government bonds,
you're not going to pay any local income
taxes.
You're not going to pay any federal
income taxes.
It's all tax free.
Now,
if you loan money to a poor Puerto Rican
company,
right?
If you loan money to a private business
in Puerto Rico,
you got to pay taxes on whatever.
They pay you an interest.
But if you loan money to the Puerto
Rican government,
the interest is tax free.
So America subsidized invest in loaning
money to the government in Puerto Rico,
but not to the private.
And so they
made it very easy for Puerto Rican
politicians to go into debt because all
these Muni bond funds all over the
country needed Puerto Rican paper to
increase the yield on their fund.
So you have everybody wants Puerto Rican
government bonds.
So the Puerto Rican government is
creating these bonds and they can now
buy votes.
They can promise all sorts of goodies to
people who vote for them.
They can overpay government workers,
give them all sorts of holidays,
right?
Lots of time off and they can keep
borrowing money so they got deeper and
deeper into debt because we created a,
an incentive for them to do that and and
now they have a debt crisis because all
of a sudden Puerto Rican bondholders
realize that Puerto Rico is never going
to pay back their money.
And then the other thing that we did to
them and I talked about,
I think on the show is the Jones Act,
which if you remember trump suspended it
for like a week or two after Maria,
but the Jones act should be completely
repealed.
And especially if donald trump's going
to be talking about,
well,
there's a number of aspects of it,
but the most significant to Puerto Rico
is that the Jones Act says that if you
want to transport goods from one US port
to another us port,
it has to be an American ship,
right?
So trump is out there talking about free
trade.
We need free trade.
The Jones Act is the opposite of free
trade.
It's complete protectionism.
It's saying that if you want to take
something from Florida,
uh,
to,
you know,
if you want to take something,
no,
if you want to take something a between
the US and Puerto Rico,
you've got to use a US ship.
You can't use a foreign ship,
right?
So there's no competition.
But what this has done is this has
dramatically increased the cost of
living.
So even though the average person in
Puerto Rico earns half of what the
average person in Kentucky earns,
groceries in Puerto Rico are more
expensive than groceries in Kentucky.
So you have lower income but a higher
cost of living that's thanks to the
Jones Act.
And if they repealed the Jones Act,
the cost of living in Puerto Rico and
punch.
And that's one of the reasons too that
the tourism industry,
Puerto Rico is a beautiful island.
I mean,
if you haven't been there,
you should come.
It's a,
it's a magnificent island.
And what's also great about it is it has
a real culture as a real vibe to it.
It's a,
it's a city.
It's like it's a Latin American city on
an island.
It's not just like a remote little
island,
so it's a really nice place to be and
it's one of the only places that I think
you can really live in the Caribbean
and,
and not feel like you're just,
you know,
on Gilligan's island or not,
but just,
you know,
like on vacation all the time.
It's a real city with real stuff going
on.
And I've been there now long enough
that,
you know,
I would go there.
You know,
you even without the tax breaks,
I like being there.
Right.
I look forward to going about crime and
poverty and there's crime there in the
big city in San Juan and certain areas
just like there are in New York and just
like all major US cities.
You've got crime problems and again,
that's there.
There's,
there's a lot of reasons for that.
Again,
it has to do with government,
it has to do with the drug laws and all
the other things.
Although they medical marijuana
in,
in Puerto Rico,
I think eventually they'll probably have
recreational,
but at least they have a,
they have medical.
But um,
what was I,
what was,
I just lost my train of thought.
What was I,
what we're talking about.
Oh,
the Jones Act Jones Act,
right.
And so.
Oh yeah.
So how it hurts the tourism industry.
So the Jones Act makes a Puerto Rican
hotels,
uh,
you know,
unable to compete on the low end with
hotels and other Caribbean islands
because everything is so expensive
because of the Jones Act and because
they have the US minimum wage
specifically is the Jones Act.
How does it,
what does it,
it's on the shipping imports,
right.
So all the food in Puerto Rico is more
expensive.
All the supply.
So hotels have a lot of things.
Were you going to a hotel?
There's all kinds of products.
You got bath products in there has to be
shipped and all the food that you eat,
all the drinks,
all this stuff is shipped in.
And to bring it to Puerto Rico is a lot
more expensive than the bring it to the
Bahamas or bring it to Barbados or
someplace else.
So all these other Caribbean islands can
get a lot of American tourists to go
there.
On for bargain vacations,
but Puerto Rico can't compete on the low
end,
on the real high end.
Oh,
they can compete because their people
are not as concerned about the cost.
But on the lower end,
the budget traveler,
a lot more people would be going to
Puerto Rico if it wasn't for the Jones
Act because they're,
the hotels would be able to cater to,
you know,
a lower price point because they could
hire the chamber maid for less money.
They could,
they could,
they could have lower prices at,
at the restaurant.
So this is really destroying the tourism
industry in,
in Puerto Rico,
which could be thriving,
uh,
but for the Jones Act,
but also it is diminishing the standard
of living of Puerto Rican who are forced
to pay higher prices.
I mean,
what's,
what happens is,
let's say there's a big ship coming in
from China with all sorts of goods and
it's gonna.
It's,
it's,
it's headed for a US port.
If it could stop off at Puerto Rico,
drop a few things off and then continue
on,
you know,
its destination.
That would be great.
It would be inexpensive for,
they can't.
What it has to do is it has to bring all
this stuff that's going to Puerto Rico
to the u s unloaded and then load it
back on a US flag ship and then send it
back to Puerto Rico,
which costs a fortune.
And then the same thing with Puerto
Rican exports.
So their whole.
The whole Puerto Rican international
commerce is being limited by the Jones
Act.
Now this also affects Hawaii.
Hawaii suffers from the Jones Act two,
but Hawaii is much richer than Puerto
Rico.
They have a much higher average income
and so even though it,
you know,
it affects them,
it's not as.
It's not as big a deal.
It's the same thing with Hawaii even
though Hawaii is a state.
Yeah.
Because yeah,
because Hawaii is a US port,
so you know,
Hawaii has to have all these Jones act
ships as well,
but so the.
If something gets delivered to Hawaii,
it has to get delivered to somewhere
first and then shipped
to Hawaii to go to California.
For us,
most stuff that's going to Hawaii,
this coming from the Pacific,
they don't stop off at Hawaii.
They made.
Seems so crazy of Hawaii is actually a
state like Puerto Rican.
No,
because that was a strange thing.
It's right.
It's a territory,
right?
That's.
That's the best thing that Puerto Rico's
got going for it.
If it was a state,
they'd have to pay the state income tax.
They'd have to pay the obamacare tax,
they'd have to pay the federal gas tax.
They're exempt from all that stuff,
but the Jones Act has to do with.
You can't take a ship between two US
ports.
They have.
It has to be a foreign port to a US
port,
so Puerto Rico is not considered a
foreign port.
It's a domestic port.
Hawaii of course is the mess they pick
us for.
Why is the state and so Hawaii things
are very expensive in Hawaii for the
same reason that they're expensive in
Puerto Rico,
but Hawaiians can afford it more because
Hawaiians on average have more money and
so if your average income is higher than
you know,
your,
your food budget is not as important to
you.
So if we got rid of the Jones Act,
that would be a big benefit for Puerto
Rico.
But you know,
the worst thing that can happen to
Puerto Rico is it becomes a state and I
get tired of it.
I keep hearing these politicians say
Puerto Rico needs to be a state and all
the problems will be solved.
Their problems will go through the roof.
The only thing that will happen if
Puerto Rico becomes a state is the
welfare checks will get bigger to people
in Puerto Rico,
but that's the last thing they need is
more welfare.
They need more freedom.
They need more opportunity.
They need more free enterprise and all
that will go away if they become a
state.
Because if you imagine all the problems
a Puerto Rican has now imagine leveling
the income tax on top of that.
Imagine sending the irs to Puerto Rico.
They've mapped their,
not even down there.
Now imagine have an irs agent
with this real support for socialism.
Is there any place where socialism has
worked where there's like some extreme
benefits to the people that lived there
where they can show you?
Because there are guys like you,
the free market capitalist guys.
You're always saying like,
this is,
this is the solution.
You know,
capitalism is solution.
Give people freedom.
Solution deregulation.
That's the solution.
Let businesses thrive.
More people to make money.
Businesses will grow.
People have more opportunity.
Yeah.
You know,
people think it's worked in Scandinavia.
they always want to talk about Sweden as
an example of where socialism works
well,
poc to a suite,
right?
And they'll tell you that it doesn't
work,
but if you want to look at the history
of Swedish socialism,
Sweden became a very wealthy country
before they had that socialism,
right?
They were very much of a free market
economy and it was the freedom that
produced all the wealth,
but then whenever you have wealth and
you have freedom,
you're always going to have any quality,
right?
Because people are smarter than other
people,
more ambitious,
harder working.
So whenever you have freedom,
you're not going to have equality and
outcome.
Even if everybody has an equal
opportunity.
And of course even that's not true,
equal opposite.
Every.
Everybody is equal in the eyes of the,
but there's always going to be
some people that will have an advantage.
You know,
maybe they have better connections.
They were born to parents that are,
you know,
have more money and they can give them,
give them a leg up.
So you're always gonna have unequal
outcomes.
Some people are going to be rich
relative to other people,
but the beauty of,
of capitalism is that everybody is
better off.
When you end up with socialism,
you,
you equalize everybody,
but you equalize them at a lower level.
You redistribute the poverty,
the people who end up wealthy or the
people who have political connections.
So the wealthy people in socialist
countries are,
are,
are the people who have political
connections.
What happened with Sweden?
So let me go up.
Yeah,
I'm going to go back to Sweden.
So Sweden was very rich and then of
course you have the demographics to
politicians who will get votes by
appealing to envy.
Hey,
this guy has more than you.
It's not fair.
And of course,
politicians always promised something
for nothing,
right?
Vote for me and I'll give you this that
you don't have to work for,
right?
I mean that is the problem with a
democracy.
I mean,
people vote for crazy things.
That's why the founding fathers,
when they created America,
they created a republic,
right?
People don't understand the distinction,
but we're not supposed to be a
democracy.
The word democracy does not appear in
the constitution.
It does not appear in the,
in the declaration of independence,
you know,
just read the pledge of allegiance.
I pledge allegiance to the flag of
United States of America and to the
republic,
right?
So we're a republic.
We're not a democracy because the
founding fathers knew the dangers of
democracy.
Well,
democracy is what brought socialism into
Sweden and it's screwed them up.
Right?
It screwed the economy up so much that
in the last 10 years they've gone the
other way in.
They've lowered income taxes.
They've abolish the inheritance tax in
Sweden.
I mean,
you know,
when they got rid of,
does that sound socialists the last 10
years?
So previous to that,
socialism had a stronghold.
Yeah,
it was.
Yeah.
If it was getting bigger and bigger,
you know,
probably going from the seventies,
eighties,
you know,
the sweetest mixed economy,
just like it bankrupted New Zealand.
I mean New Zealand used to be the poster
boy for mixed economy socialism until
they got bankrupt.
So.
And then is the only successful?
No,
they're not sick.
Not Know,
but we're just going to say that that's
the only example that someone can say
they'll cite Norway,
a lot of the Scandinavian countries,
Denmark,
but you have to look at how successful
they were before they became socialist.
And then you also have to look at what
the government is doing there because
the taxes on business are not extreme.
The taxes are on the average guy.
They have,
I think in Sweden,
I think the,
um,
the VAT is about 30 percent sales tax
that you have to pay.
I mean this is a high sales tax and the
income taxes impact average people.
So because they know the Swedes know,
if they really jack up taxes on
businesses,
the businesses will just leave and
they'll destroy their economy.
So at least they're trying to
redistribute the wealth from the middle
class to the middle class,
you know.
But the,
you know,
this stuff doesn't work and you create a
generations of people who now don't want
to work who just want to live off of
other people.
You destroy the initiatives,
you destroy the incentives.
And so the success that Sweden enjoyed
is a byproduct of freedom and
capitalism.
And since they moved in that direction,
they have slowed down that progress.
But the Swedish people have recognized
that and that's why the reforms that
have been made over the last decade or
two had been to turn back the clock,
to move away from those socialist
policies and to try to dismantle.
And now they haven't gone completely the
other way.
Just like New Zealand,
I mean New Zealand went so far.
They became,
they went from like a totally socialist
type economy one that was like,
you know,
this was the example,
if you believed in socialism,
you would point to New Zealand as see
this shows you.
Right?
And then they went bankrupt.
They went through a huge economic crisis
in the eighties bank.
Previous to being socialists were the
successful with capitalism.
Yeah,
of course.
Because if you're always socialist than
you never have any wealth to
redistribute it's capitalism that
creates the wealth that the socialist
want to redistribute.
So let me ask you this though,
because we're going to keep going around
in circles with this year ago,
studied this for a long period of time.
What is it about socialism that's so
appealing to p two people?
If there's no examples of it being
effective?
Well,
you know,
as I keep coming up,
well again,
when is it a lack of education or lack
of understanding of economics?
Like what is it about it that keeps like
when this woman who just won and she
seems like a very nice person when she
talks about being a democratic socialist
and nobody gets fired up.
And is it ignorance like.
Yeah,
look,
it certainly,
it's a lack of understanding of
economics.
Most people don't understand it,
but look,
I mean there are a lot of reasons that
socialism is appealing to people,
especially when they're young,
right?
There's an old saying that if you're not
a socialist or if you're not a liberal
by the time you're 21,
you don't have a heart.
If you're not a conservative,
by the time you're 28,
you don't have a headache.
Right?
So liberals are just people that never
grew up.
Right?
It's like,
it's like,
it's like they still believe in Santa
Claus.
That's what it is.
You,
you just never socialists and
particularly not necessarily liberal
even.
Well,
even people believing in big garbage
because usually what happens is,
you know when you're a kid,
right?
And when you're in high school,
you've never had a job and all this
stuff sounds great until you're out in
the real world paying taxes,
you know,
that's why it was a mistake to lower the
voting age down to 18.
I mean I don't even think 21.
It should be higher.
If you think about the original voting
age when it was 21 100 years ago,
150 years ago,
think about a guy who was 21 back in 18.
50 different person.
I think about.
I mean the guy probably got out of
school when he was 10.
He probably already has been working.
He has got a family.
He's in the real world and I know people
are gonna say,
look,
women were in voting fine,
you know,
whatever.
Like I,
I'm,
I don't think that.
How old do you think it should be?
I think maybe 28,
30.
Look,
look,
let me make it fit.
But that's the reason.
The reason they re,
it's all the reasons would be 28 years
old enough sun.
You know,
the reason,
the reason they raised the voting age
was because of Vietnam,
because of the draft,
right?
They were saying old enough to fight old
enough to vote,
which was a bunch of lower the voting
age.
No,
no,
they.
They lowered it,
right.
Because he used to get drafted when you
were 18 and they were saying,
look,
you know,
I,
if you're going to drop and look,
I don't believe in the draft.
I would rather get rid of the draft and
leave it with you.
That 21 sounds better.
I would say 25 because that's the age to
your frontal cortex develops,
but no.
What?
Ah,
what's,
what's important about voting is not
voting.
Look,
when I moved to Puerto Rico,
I,
I gave up my right to vote.
Right.
That's one of the things I can don't
vote at all for president,
for anything.
No.
I can't vote for congressmen.
They don't have a congress.
There is nobody that is still a state
territory territory.
But.
So if you live in Puerto Rico and you
move to Florida now you can vote for
congressmen in your district.
You can vote for a Florida senator.
How much time to spend in Florida to be
officially living there?
Well,
I mean,
if you kept your place in Puerto Rico,
well I wouldn't want to do that.
But you know,
if you're,
if you're important,
if you're in 100,
83 days is the cutoff for where your
residence is going to be.
But the important thing about voting is
not that you get to vote.
The important thing is to have good
government,
right?
And what is good government?
Good government is government that
respects a private property that
respects that,
you know,
if you go back and look at.
I mentioned this on one of my own
podcast recently,
I talked about the meaning of America
and what government is for in America.
American.
If you go back to the declaration of
independence,
we just had,
we celebrated our independence day,
you know,
just a couple of weeks ago.
Um,
but government is here to protect life,
liberty,
and the pursuit of happiness.
Their government is here to protect our
rights.
It's not here to give us free stuff.
It's not here to take stuff from other
people and give it to us.
It's there to protect us,
right?
It's there protecting life,
liberty,
property.
And so the goal of government or the
goal of an election is to have good
government.
Now,
as far as I'm concerned,
I would rather have good government
where I don't vote then bad government
where I do vote,
right?
Because you know,
one of the things that people said,
oh,
you're going to move to Puerto Rico.
You can't vote.
Who Cares?
I voted for the loser in every election.
What difference does it make when some
idiots are going to outvote me?
And,
and,
and that's basically who's voting in
America.
I mean,
if you think about it,
the elections are decided by the TV
commercials,
right?
Because most people,
you know,
they know who they're gonna vote for.
Can you imagine the person who's,
who decides who's going to vote for
based on a TV commercial?
I mean,
these guys are more on the swing.
The swing voters are determining the
outcome of these elections.
And we ended up with horrible
government.
I mean,
government democracy almost guarantees
horrible government,
but what are the things you want to do
if you're going to have democracy is
okay,
let's have responsible people voting who
understand what they're voting for,
who have actually lived and worked in
the economy,
who have had a job,
who have paid taxes,
who have run businesses,
who have employed people.
If you've never had a job,
if you're still living with your
parents,
why are you voting?
I mean,
we might as well lower the voting age
and let people in kindergarten vote.
I mean,
right?
So they can vote for whoever promises
them free toys and people so you don't.
Oh,
it's unfair.
Look,
if we could have good government without
18 year olds voting,
that's fine.
You know,
but the left wants the young people
voting because they're stupid enough to
vote for their.
Yeah.
And you said,
why is socialism appealing to somebody
who's young?
Because they don't know any better.
They haven't lived and it sounds good,
right?
Oh,
you know,
I care about people.
That's why liberals think conservatives
are mean,
right?
Right.
Conservatives don't think liberals are
me.
They just think they don't understand.
They're misinformed,
right?
They're,
they're,
they don't.
They don't get it.
Right.
That's sort of shifting.
It seems like there's more people that
are thinking that liberals are mean now
than ever before because of the way
they're attacking thing.
Yeah,
because liberals are now so intolerant,
which is the craziest part.
Like they like to pretend that there are
so tolerant,
but they're the most intolerant people
out there.
Only tolerant if you agree with yes.
And to be tolerant,
you have to tolerate intolerance.
Right?
That see,
when we talked earlier about
discrimination,
look,
if somebody is a racist,
I'm going to tolerate that.
Fine.
You can have your own opinion.
I can disagree with your opinion,
but fine.
Live and let live.
I live in a free country.
People can do things I don't like,
but to a liberal,
if you don't,
if you don't think exactly the way they
think,
then,
oh they,
oh yeah,
they're,
you know,
harass you.
So they're becoming evil and mean.
So they used to just be ignorant now.
Now,
now they're.
Now they're ignorant at admin.
Well,
not just mean,
but harassing people,
encouraging people to harass people that
have separate political views and
opinion.
Yes,
it's,
it's very,
it's very strangely.
Anybody who supports the trump
administration or is even a part of it
is people to get harassed at restaurants
and.
Yeah,
and you know,
I wish I could be a bigger supporter of
trump.
I mean I voted for him.
I,
I really liked trump as a candidate a
because he was saying a lot of the same
things I was saying when he was a
candidate.
It's just at the minute he said,
well about the phony economy and you
know,
how we have to,
you know,
the numbers are not right and we have to
shrink government.
So from you economically it made more
sense than Hillary.
Well,
I mean Hillary would be certainly a
disaster,
but the irony of it is why would she be
a disaster because she was just,
you no more big government.
I mean,
you know,
and I think she would have continued the
failed policies,
but unfortunately trump has continued
those policies as well and he could end
up being a bigger disaster if he is the
catalyst to put a Bernie Sanders type
into the White House in response in
response to how much worse the economy
gets and he takes the blame for it.
But do you.
So this is all predicated on your
initial view that the economy's going to
crash inside the next three years.
If it doesn't it,
it does really well.
Well,
it stays in this state that it's,
it's.
Is it doing that well now it's just a
bubble.
It's,
I mean it's,
it's,
it's no different than it was when Obama
was president.
There's just some more optimism that
things are going to change.
But when you were talking about this
before it happened and I remember you
going on these different talk shows
saying this is going to crash and people
weren't listening to you and they were
like,
oh,
Peter Shifts does nobody's talking
about.
And then it did crash and then they,
they listened to you.
You're the only one that's saying it's
going to crash again.
Well,
they never really listened to me.
They kind of tolerated me.
Here's the deal.
They had to.
Because you are right.
Well here's the irony of it all because
you know,
leading up to the 2008 financial crisis
and if you go to my youtube channel,
you could see like my introductory video
is a little montage that I actually shot
as part of my senate campaign when I ran
for Senate in 2010,
but it's a,
a bunch of people you know,
mocking me and then a lot of the shows
that I went on where they said,
hey,
you were right.
You know where the one guy that called
it.
So I used to be on,
I was on television a lot on Fox,
CNBC,
CNN,
Bloomberg,
probably once a week for three or four
years.
I was on something.
And then I used to get the Washington
Post used to call me the New York Times.
You know,
I,
you know,
people magazine articles were written
about me when I was just lone kind of
crazy guy talking about a housing
bubble,
talking about a financial crisis that
was coming.
They at least gave me a platform to air
my views even though they mocked them
and laugh at them.
I was still there.
I was like the gloom and doom guy,
Dr.
Doom.
Um,
I think Time magazine did an article
with me.
I had to pay,
had a sickle in my hand,
you know,
like the grim reaper.
But anyway,
so then,
then we get the financial crisis and all
of a sudden I get a little bit of
notoriety,
you knows,
to Domus Ah,
Peter Schiff was right.
But all in all over the last few years
that nobody will talk to me.
I'm not on any television shows about
it.
Well,
I,
I think that at this point people just
think,
look,
you know,
I've been saying talking about this
problem for so long.
They look,
he doesn't know what he's talking about.
They forget that I was warning about the
problems in the housing market for four
or five years.
You know,
as the prices kept going up,
you know,
it's not like the things that I see
happen immediately,
but I think,
you know,
at this point,
maybe in the past they thought maybe
there was a chance I could be right,
even though it was a slim chance.
Now they probably think it's impossible
that I could be right.
So why even give me any air time.
So I mean like I come on shows like
yours and people actually get to hear
the truth,
but if you go back to what I was
actually predicting,
2008 financial crisis was the beginning
of the end,
not the end.
What I,
what I was predicting.
And I wrote a book about it,
crash proof,
how to profit from the coming economic
collapse.
It came in February.
Oh seven.
I said we have this huge bubble.
We have this housing bubble that the
Federal Reserve created,
right?
Not the,
not the private enterprise.
It was created by government.
And in fact,
after the financial crisis happened,
Congress had a,
um,
a,
a hearing to try to determine why we had
a financial crisis.
And I tried my best to get invited to
testify and they refused to let me be
there because they didn't have anybody
there that predicted it because they
wanted to basically come to a conclusion
that they had already arrived.
That was that it was caused by a lack of
regulation and we need more government.
Right.
So they didn't want me there to say it
was caused by government and we needed
less government,
although by the way,
I have testified at Congress twice since
then and both of my testimonies are on,
on the,
on Youtube.
And you got to watch him.
It's incredible stuff.
And in fact after I was on the first
time I was convinced they would never
invite me back because I don't treat
these guys with the type of respect that
they normally get.
So I thought they would never invite me
back and they actually invited me back.
And then the guy that invited me back on
fire.
Okay.
Yeah.
So I'll never.
There's no way that they're going to
bring me out again.
Much better suited for.
I mean in those talk shows they bring
you on.
You're so much better suited to doing
your own videos or doing something like
this where you could just go on,
well,
yeah,
I mean now,
now see now a complex issues.
Now I have my own platform.
I have a lot more people who listen to
my podcast and who you know then that I
did back then,
but the point that I wanted to make
about the crisis is I wrote back then
that we had this bubble and we were
going to have this crash,
but the economic crisis was not going to
be that.
It was that the collapse that I saw
coming in,
oh,
eight was the beginning.
I said that we have this disease that
the Fed has created and it's manifested
itself in this housing bubble and it's
going to pop and we're going to have the
worst recession since the great
depression.
We're going to have double digit
unemployment.
We're going to have trillion dollar
deficits,
but I said,
that's not what's going to kill us.
I said,
we're not going to die of that disease.
That disease is survivable.
I said,
what's going to kill us is the
government's cure.
They're going to print so much money,
they're going to try to reflate these
bubbles and that's going to cause a
dollar crisis and a bond crisis,
and that was what was gonna destroy the
economy and that's not happened yet.
Now what I did not know at the time,
and I didn't put a date on it,
I didn't know it would take so long.
I mean here we are 10 years later
almost,
and it has.
That hasn't happened yet,
but you think it's got to happen and
what I got wrong,
I said the government was going to try
to reflate the bubbles.
I assume they would fail.
They succeeded.
The bubbles now are bigger than the ones
that popped in.
Oh eight.
And what's the difference between
bubbles and an actual functioning
economy that's sustainable,
right?
So if it's doing well right now,
you agree it's doing well,
not doing well.
It's a mobile.
So the difference between a real
economy,
the real economy grows from production
and savings,
right?
And the real.
We're making stuff and consuming.
Like if you look right now at the
savings rate,
right?
The savings rate is near record low and
the politicians try to say,
oh,
this is because the economy is so good,
right?
Everybody is out there spending.
That's a bunch of nonsense.
If the economy was good,
people would have more savings.
Right?
If,
if,
if you ran into a friend of yours that
you hadn't seen in awhile and you ask
them,
hey,
how you doing?
And he said,
Oh,
well I've maxed out all my credit cards.
I took out a second mortgage on my
house.
You know,
I,
I blew through my retirement account.
Right?
You wouldn't say,
Oh,
you're doing great work.
Whereas if another friend said,
how you do it?
Oh,
I just fully funded my pension.
I got massive savings.
I got,
you know,
I mean,
I paid off all my credit cards.
I own my house free and clear.
That's the guy that's doing well right?
When you're,
when you're doing well,
you,
you get out of debt.
So we're not doing that.
We're all living based on a bubble based
on cheap money being spread out into the
economy.
Right?
Why is the stock market going up?
Because the buybacks.
Why are people spending,
because they're going deeper into debt.
We have record student loans,
record credit card debt record autodebt.
Everybody's loaded up with that.
They just had a survey out.
I think that less than half the people
could come up with like 400 bucks if
they had an emergency.
I mean,
that's nothing.
People have nothing.
They're living paycheck to paycheck and
even that they,
they,
they need credit cards.
We have huge budget deficits.
We have huge trade deficits.
You know,
we got record numbers of people,
older people that,
that are working because they can't
afford to retire.
Meanwhile,
the young people can't get jobs because
they have those skills and they're
still.
So the economy is not real,
right?
It's all,
it's all disillusion.
Just like it was what was going on
before 2008 people were living off their
home equity.
You know,
out here in California,
homes are going up.
People were taking out home equity lines
of credit.
They were taken vacations,
they were buying new cars,
they were remodeling their houses.
All that prosperity was phony.
It wasn't run well upon fake wealth.
Yes.
And then the wealth came down and I
talked about that for years,
what we have even faker prosperity now,
but it's not,
it's even less prosperous.
Even fewer people are feeling the
benefits,
uh,
than before.
So the real economy is getting sicker
and sicker as it takes more and more air
to inflate the bubble because in order
to keep the bubbles from popping,
the government and the central bank has
to keep misdirecting resources out of
the real economy to sustain the bubbles.
All right,
so talk me through two things.
One,
what is going to happen that's going to
cause this big collapse?
You predicted way back in 2007 that
hasn't actually hit yet.
What's going to cause that?
How's it going to go down?
And what can the average person like me
that knows Jack Shit about economics?
What can we do to protect ourselves?
Well,
first of all,
you probably know more about economics
than the average guy with an economics
degree from American University to you.
Well,
yeah,
or just for having common sense.
I mean,
when,
when you go to a US college and you
study economics,
they basically beat all the common sense
out of you,
and by the time you graduate,
you're a complete moron when it comes to
economics,
how do they do?
What would they teach them?
All this nonsense,
you know,
that,
and,
and that's why all the big economists in
academia on Wall Street,
at government,
they're all a bunch of idiots when it
comes to economics.
So you know,
a lot more than they do.
Uh,
not that you're,
you're an idiot.
But I mean,
you just,
you just have to have common sense
because they lack lack,
common sense.
But to get back to your question,
this is horrible.
This is going to go down.
This is how I think it's going to go
down.
So everybody believes that the Fed's
policy of quantitative easing,
uh,
and you know,
and uh,
you know,
low zero percent interest rates,
everybody believes it was a success.
They believe the Fed revive the economy,
that they put out the fire.
That's the narrative,
right?
They still don't realize that the Fed
lit the fire and they didn't really put
it out.
It's just Kinda,
it's simmering and people don't notice
it.
But um,
what,
what's going to happen is the Fed never
was able to normalize interest rates,
right?
Rates or stole two percent.
That's still really,
really low.
And for all the talk about shrinking
their balance sheet,
it really hasn't shrunk,
right?
It's still enormous and I think that the
economy is going to slip into recession,
right?
And when it does,
the Fed never got interest rates back to
five percent or six percent where they
normally bring them.
They never shrink the balance sheet.
So now all of a sudden we go into this
recession,
but it's going to be as a,
a,
a stagflation because inflation is now
really starting to pick up,
you know,
prices rise with a lag.
The inflation is the expansion of the
money supply.
That's what the word inflate means.
It comes,
it's to expand,
right?
You can't expand prices.
Prices can go up and they go down,
they go and expand what expands as the
supply of money.
And so the supply of money expanded and
a lot of that went into financial
assets.
So inflation costs,
stock prices to go up,
it caused real estate,
prices go up,
it caused bond prices go up,
it caused the price of rare art to go up
and all sorts of things went up because
of inflation.
Uh,
ultimately a lot of that inflation that
was going to end up in the supermarket,
right?
You know,
at,
at the,
at the gas station.
And,
and so you're going to have that at the
same time that we have the recession.
Now the Fed is going to have to go back
to the only thing it knows how to do.
We're going to do qe four and we're
going to cut rates back to zero.
But now the markets are going to see
this and they're going to wait a minute.
You never normalized interest rates,
you never shrunk your balance sheet.
And now you're going to expand it again.
Now you're going back to zero.
Wait a minute,
wait a minute.
If you couldn't normalize interest rates
following this last recession,
how are you going to do it in the
future?
I mean if you couldn't shrink a four and
a half trillion dollar balance sheet,
how are you going to drink?
Drink a six or a $7,000,000,000,000
balance sheet if you couldn't raise
interest rates back to normal when the
national debt,
our national debt is not 21 trillion.
What if it goes up to 25 trillion,
30 trillion?
I mean,
one of the reasons the Fed can't raise
rates is because we have too debt.
Nobody can afford to pay the higher
rates when inflation was running out of
control in the 19 seventies and it's
going to be a lot worse now.
Right?
The inflation that we had in the 19
seventies was created in the 19 sixties
by Lyndon Johnson,
right by the great society,
the war on poverty,
the Vietnam War,
going to the moon.
We borrowed all sorts of money.
We ran big deficits and the consequence
was the dollar crashed in the seventies.
Gold went through the roof,
oil went through the roof and finally,
you know,
we had to do something about it at the
end of the seventies because when,
when,
when Nixon came in and uh,
and Ford came in,
they just continued the same policies.
They were know very liberal Republicans,
Rockefeller Republicans,
and we didn't do anything about
inflation until Reagan came in and
Volcker was there.
And so how did they stop the inflation
from running out of control?
Volcker jacked interest rates up to 20
percent,
20 percent.
And we had a recession where the Fed was
raising interest rates,
but that saved the dollar and it,
it,
it broke the inflationary cycle that was
in the economy raising the interest
rates.
Yes they will.
They had to stop the inflation,
right?
They had,
they had,
they had a break and of course,
you know,
Reagan did some other,
tax reform and things like that.
But the Fed really finally,
you know,
got,
got out in front of the inflation curve
and they brought it down.
But if you think about the difference
between the United States in 1980 and
the United States today,
we were still the world's biggest
creditor nation in 1980,
not the world's biggest debtor nation.
The national debt was a fraction of what
it is now.
I don't know,
maybe it was like a half a billion,
500 billion or I don't know the exact
amount,
but well under a trillion,
um,
but the,
the national debt was financed with long
term bonds like 10 year 30 year bonds.
So when interest rates went up to 20
percent,
that didn't affect the majority of the
debt that was out there,
that only increased the cost to the
government of the new debt that came
out,
right?
The new borrowing.
But today the $21,000,000,000,000
national debt is predominantly treasury
bills,
stuff that matures in a year or less.
And,
and so if interest rates had to go up to
let's say 10 percent,
the government would have to pay 10
percent within a few years on the entire
national debt.
So where were the government get all
that money?
And it's not this.
The government corporations have never
been this levered up.
Individuals have never been this level
of.
They didn't have adjustable rate
mortgages back then.
You know,
now you've got to have a lot of people
that have arms,
you know,
we're,
their mortgage debt would go up with.
So at this point the Fed can't really
fight inflation because it doesn't have
the tools because we have so much debt.
If they raised interest rates to fight
inflation,
the collapse would be so much worse than
2008.
All the banks that they bailed,
that would fail again,
but they couldn't bail them out a second
time because they can't bail them out
and fight inflation at the same time
because you can't ease and tightened
simultaneously.
It's one or the other.
So I think when the markets see that
we're going back to Qe,
that we're going back to zero,
they're going to realize that this is
not temporary,
that this is permanent,
that the Fed can never normalize
interest rates.
That the balance sheet is never going to
shrink.
That we're a banana republic,
that we are monetizing our debt,
that the Fed has no ability to drain
that liquidity and no ability to fight
inflation.
That means the dollar is a bottomless
pit.
That means a dollar is going to keep
falling.
That means nobody is going to want to
own it and everybody's going to want to
get out of dollars and everybody's going
to want to get out of any bond that has
dollar denominated in dollars and then
the Federal Reserve in order to keep
interest rates from rising,
they might have to start buying Muni
bonds,
they might have to start buying
corporate bonds.
Otherwise interest rates are going to
skyrocket and that just fuels the
inflationary fire.
And then we get a currency crisis right
where the dollar is plunging.
Prices are skyrocketing,
that is real pain and who knows what
they're going to do.
Maybe they're going to have a price
controls which are just going to
backfire.
Then we're going to have shortages.
We're going to have rationing.
We're going to have civil unrest.
I mean,
this is going to be ugly when it hits
the fan and you know,
it's dangerous to do this and the
backdrop where so many people are
inclined to vote for a socialist because
that's going to be the type of economic
environment where socialism can thrive
because socialists always want to look
for a scapegoat who can we blame this on
and it's very easy to blame it on the
rich or the businesses or the
corporations or the Republicans.
And I think that's what's gonna happen
if this happens,
you know,
sometime over the next few years.
But if it doesn't happen in trump's
first term,
there's no way he finishes his second
term without this happening.
No Way I can ask you this.
If he calls you and says Peter Schiff
had on the Joe Rogan podcast,
it was amazing.
What do I do?
What do you tell them to do?
You know,
I think he has people that were
listening to me on the campaign trail
because I used to,
I would say things on my podcast or
tweet something and the next day I,
you know,
he'd say something pretty similar.
So just like,
because he,
my rhetoric,
uh,
Pete,
he had to appeal to certain voters that,
you know,
and so he was throwing them this type of
red meat.
But look,
look,
I know some of the guys that are close
to him,
you know,
uh,
like Larry Kudlow,
like Steve Moore.
Uh,
I mean,
I,
I know Steve Moore pretty well at
[inaudible].
We speak in a lot of the same things.
I used to be on Larry's show a lot back
in the day when he used to have his,
his,
his show on CNBC.
Um,
so I know some of these guys,
I don't know her as well,
but,
you know,
art laffer,
right?
If you go look at the debate I did with
Art Laffer,
uh,
in 2006 when he said everything was
great,
uh,
and you know,
there's no,
no recession coming and then he bet me a
penny and Wellstar on it.
I mean,
if you can't even send.
Yeah,
well yeah,
he bet me a penny that everything was
great and there was nothing to worry
about and we weren't gonna have a major
decline and you know,
and then he wouldn't even pay up,
you know,
but let me ask you this.
If he calls you up and says,
what do I do,
what does he do?
Well,
at this point,
look,
it would have been better,
as I said,
had he
come clean right away about what does he
do now?
Now he's got to have to come back and
say,
look,
I just listened to the Joe Rogan
podcast.
I listened to Peter Schiff and you guys
guys a genius.
Financial Genius is huge.
I'm not a genius.
I just have common sense.
It's,
it's these other guys that are just,
you know,
they're,
they're so,
their judgment is so clouded by the
bubble.
That's,
you know,
when you get a lot of people that can
see things.
The reason I saw the crisis coming,
uh,
you know,
the housing bubble,
it wasn't that I was so smart,
I just,
I was just thinking clearly everybody
else was so delusional.
But what does he do though?
Yeah,
I mean,
so what he's got to do is basically has
got to come clean now and tell the truth
about how screwed up this country is
after years of big government and after
years of a central bank that is inflated
bubble after bubble and say,
look,
this is what we need to do to really
make America great again.
I said,
we're going to have to shrink
government.
I know I said I wasn't going to cut
entitlements,
but we got to do that.
We can't afford to make these
commitments.
We can't pay all of his social security
benefits that have been promised because
if we try,
we're going to destroy the dollar,
right?
Because if the government tries to give
everybody a social security check,
they can't do it without destroying the
dollar.
So we've got to,
we've got to shrink the program.
We've got a means tested program,
we've got to make it a lot smaller.
We got to end it for the future.
You know,
we can't have this intergenerational
Ponzi scheme,
uh,
that,
you know,
it was a mistake to create it.
I mean,
a lot,
nobody wants to admit that social
security was a mistake,
that Medicare was a mistake.
You know,
one of the things about social security
that's been harped on and on is that one
day it's not going to work.
Well,
it doesn't work.
It's never worked,
but the idea is that you're paying into
it.
Now.
If you're your 30 year old person paying
into it,
now this straight on odds,
you're not going to get it,
but you're not paying into anything.
I mean,
social security is a Ponzi scheme.
It's not a legitimately funded
retirement program.
It's not like your social security money
is putting a real trust funds somewhere
in invested and when you retire,
you're going to get payments out of this
trust fund.
No,
your money is going to the people that
are spending it right now.
Yeah,
and so when it first started,
social security started a long time ago.
The first woman that got a check was,
I'm more fuller or something was her
name,
and she lived to be 100 years old.
And for her social security was a.
was a windfall because she paid into it
for a couple of years.
She collected for like 40 years and when
full security started,
it was a one percent tax on payroll and
it was only a small amount.
And then the employer paid one percent,
which of course comes from the employee.
That's part of the fraud,
right?
I mean the employee pays the whole
thing.
Doesn't matter if the,
if it's considered the employer,
but it didn't.
So,
uh,
I'm self employed.
People weren't even included.
I think we didn't include the self
employed until like the fifties,
Greg,
because the government figured if you're
smart enough to run your own business,
well then you're smart enough to save
for your own retirement.
Uh,
but the government tried to say,
look,
some Americans are not smart enough to
save,
which I think was a mistake because the
government didn't save anything because
what the government did is the minute
they got the money,
they spent it.
But before they spend it,
they write themselves an Iou and they
call it a trust fund.
See what happens is the government
collects the social,
social security money and then they
spend the money on the current
employees,
but what they don't spend,
they,
they put into this so called trust fund,
but then they borrow it right out and
they write themselves an iou call the
government bond.
But if the government owns its own bond,
that's not an asset because they keep
saying,
well the trust funds are going to be
solvent until the year 20,
40 or something like that,
but they're not.
They're insolvent right now because
there's nothing in them.
Because if the government has to tap the
trust fund,
it has to sell a bond to the public,
which is what it would do if there was
no trust when it's like if you wrote me
a check for $10,000,
right?
And I had that check.
That would be an asset to me.
If I had your check for $10,000,
if you wrote yourself a check for
$10,000,
that's not an asset to you because it's
an asset and the liability.
The same time you owe yourself the
money.
So if I,
if I buy a government bond,
if I owned the government bond,
it's an asset to me.
If the government owns its own bond,
it's not an asset at all.
That makes sense.
It's a liability and asset sales.
So the trust funds have been a fiction
from day one.
I mean Roosevelt sold this to the
American public.
It was a con.
That's why they call it social security
contributions.
They call it you're paying premiums.
It's a trust.
They tried to make it sound like
legitimate insurance,
but it was never legitimate insurance
because that would have actually been
unconstitutional.
The reason that the supreme court said
social security was constitutional was
because it wasn't legitimate.
It was.
They said it was like.
It was just like any other welfare
programs.
Okay.
We went off on a deep.
Let's wants you to bring back though,
because we're getting off track.
I really want you to say,
what would you tell them to do?
Yeah.
So social security limit entitlements or
eliminate them.
We've got to,
we've got to start eliminating lots of
government agencies and departments.
Whether it's education,
energy mean they're all,
they're all sorts of government
departments that we need to abolish,
we need to cut back on government
spending,
we need to economize,
we need to make government as lean as
possible because we're broke.
Government is like,
you know,
it's like if you're trying to run a
marathon and you've got a 50 pound sack
on your back,
you know,
you're not going to run very fast.
The secret is to take some of that
weight out of the pack.
So you think that limiting government
and getting rid of all the spending is
going to allow the economy to be more
powerful.
But yes,
but initially we know it's like if,
if,
if you're going to train somebody to
come into your gym and they come in and
they're real fat and they're,
they're,
you know,
they're adequate,
they're overweight,
they have a lousy diet,
right?
And you say,
okay,
I've got a plan for you that's going to
get you into shape in the short run.
They're not going to like that plan.
They can't eat their favorite foods.
They're going to be,
you know,
getting up early and training and so
their lifestyle,
it's not going to be as enjoyable to
them.
It's going to.
There's going to be all this pain,
right?
So in order to do the right thing,
I'm not saying there's a panacea,
right?
In order to fix the economy,
we are going to have to go through a
recession,
a very bad one
in order to reallocate resources to
where they need to be to let the free
market reallocate them.
So when the government gets out of the
way and starts shrinking,
a lot of people who were getting
government checks are not going to get
those checks.
A lot of people who had government jobs
are not going to have jobs.
They're going to have to get productive
jobs in the private sector.
So there's going to be some transition
there.
We're going to also have to get rid of a
lot of regulations that make it so
difficult and expensive to hire people
and train people.
So we have to downsize government.
And again,
they said we have to let interest rates
go up so that people will save.
So that entrepreneurs can get the
capital they need to make the
investments to make the tools that their
workers need to be more productive.
But then we have to let asset prices
fall.
We have to stop trying to create this
phony wealth effects.
Either the central bank thinks what we
need is to make the stock market go up
and then people will think they're rich
and go out and spend money.
Stocks are not supposed to be the stock
price.
Appreciation is not supposed to be the
source of wealth.
It's companies becoming more valuable
because they're earning more in
producing more.
That's supposed to make the price go up
there trying to put the cart before the
horse.
They think that just making the stock
market go up is going to make us richer.
Yeah.
So in your opinion,
deregulation,
smaller business,
all these things are going to help
letting people know that the god that we
are fucked and that this is this,
this whole.
The economy's doing great thing is a
route.
Yeah.
And a lot of people who are not working
half the start working,
they got to start doing stuff.
We got to get people off of,
you know,
the Dole and,
and start and you know,
they're,
they're riding into wagon.
They got to start pulling it like
everybody else
and you think smaller government and
less regulation is going to enhance
of course.
Well that's what's keeping them from
getting jobs in the first place.
I mean it's,
you know,
they make it hard for you to get a job
with rules and regulations and taxes and
then they reward you for not working
with all sorts of subsidies
programs.
I mean end.
There's also a fear of automation.
Automation is going to eliminate a large
amount of jobs including driving jobs.
Yeah.
But you know,
that's all gonna make us richer.
I mean we've had automation,
you know,
since the industrial revolution,
but even before that there was
automation.
I mean,
look at people on the farms,
look at how many people don't work on
farms
now because we have machines,
but people are worried about universal
basic income that this is the only
solution for solution
automation makes us wealthier as a
society because it eliminates work.
Work is not an end in and of itself.
Work is a means to an ends.
Nobody wants to work,
they want the fruits of the labor and so
to the extent that we can have a machine
do the work for us,
that frees us up to do other things.
So you know,
if we have autonomous cars and I don't
have to drive anymore,
you know,
a trump won't have that problem being
sued for overtime by his ex driver
because he won't need somebody to drive.
But imagine if everybody had a self
driving car.
Think of all the free time now that you
have,
you can work while you're in your car or
you can,
you can do other,
you could watch a movie while you're in
the car.
I mean you won't be dreading a long trip
because you'll be to be productive
while you're in there in that car and
you know.
So there's a lot of things that will
happen.
Yes,
we'll eliminate truck driver jobs,
but you know,
we'll,
we'll have safer streets and,
and,
and it'll be less expensive to transport
goods.
But that frees up that worker to do
something else with their time now that
they don't have the drive that truck.
So the idea of universal basic income is
the only solution that isn't appealing
to you because you think that they
really.
The real solution is not to give them
free money.
The real solution is for them to find
something else to do the the physical
attributes of the appeal.
The appeal of universal basic income is
almost like two wrongs make a right.
I mean the problem is the welfare state
discourages people from working at the
highest marginal tax rate that anybody
pays is going from welfare to work.
Because not only do you pay the taxes on
what you earn,
but you lose all the benefits because
you now have a job.
So welfare and the welfare state creates
a huge incentive for people not to work.
So at least the argument with universal
income is,
look,
we're not going to take away your
welfare if you get a job.
So if you improve your lot in life,
if you go out there and you become
productive,
we're not going to punish you by,
uh,
by taking away your welfare.
Well,
the better answer is let's not punish
you for working.
Let's get rid of the income tax.
Let's not tax labor.
Let's get rid of the payroll tax to make
it more.
You ever foresee getting rid of the
income tax?
We,
this country,
and yet we didn't have it,
but since the 19 forties when it was
introduced in 1913,
but nobody really paid it until 1943
when we had the withholding tax.
But we could get rid of the income tax.
Really think that that would ever fly in
this country.
I hope so.
When people are so addicted to that
money,
well,
but people don't.
People don't like paying the income tax,
but we can't get rid of the income tax
unless we shrink government.
I mean back in 1900 government was only
like five percent of the GNP.
All Levels,
state,
federal and local.
Now it's like 40 percent.
So we can't have no income tax and no
payroll tax.
If we want to have all this government,
but if we're willing to do without the
government,
then we don't need the taxes.
But if we don't,
most of this government is ineffective.
Of course.
I mean government,
you know,
it's,
it's always inefficient.
I mean it's a necessary evil,
but that's why you want to minimize.
So what would you want to keep power?
Maintaining streets?
Things about maintenance.
Well,
I know these on a federal level.
Education,
both the federal government should not
be involved in education at all.
And in fact if you look at the
constitution to get the word,
education is not mentioned.
The school is not meant all had buggies
back then and they were feathers,
but they had schools.
They knew what they were.
So what,
so how do you fund education and the
department that the Department of
Education didn't even exist until what
we did.
Was it in the sixties?
I forget when they started it,
but look,
the federal government should be
involved primarily with external
matters.
So we should have a national defense.
I think it should much smaller.
I think that we spend more money than we
need on the military.
I think we could,
we could have a defensive military for a
fraction of what we currently pay,
but I think the federal government
should be predominantly focused on
external matters,
uh,
to the extent that we're going to have
public education or government spending
money on the schools,
let them do it on a state level or local
level.
I mean,
no,
it should not be done at the federal
level,
you know,
those are issues that can be the manage
by stats,
by the state tax money.
Yes.
And you know,
see what happens now is everybody sends
all this money to the federal government
and then they beg to get some of it
back,
right?
They have state aid where you send money
out and you try to get some of it back.
Just don't send it to Washington in the
first place.
I mean,
look at the five richest counties in
America.
They all surround Washington DC.
It's all the lobby lobbyists where all
the power is.
I mean,
we got to get rid of that.
the federal government is like a cancer,
you know,
we have,
we know we now we were talking about,
we got a new nominee for the supreme
court.
Talk about,
you know,
about,
but nobody really talks about the role
of the constitution.
Everybody's like,
oh,
are we going to repeal roe versus Wade
is if the most important thing is
whether or not,
you know,
there's this federal,
uh,
abortion.
The important part of the constitution
is that it is the law that applies to
the government.
It limits the power of government.
Thomas Jefferson said that we will bind
up the con,
the government in the chains of the
constitution.
But at this point the government does
whatever it wants.
The government is not abiding by the
law.
I mean they try to pretend that we're
interpreting the constitution.
It's not up for interpretation.
The constitution is not written in
Chinese.
You don't have to interpret it,
but they,
the government likes to talk about
interpreting the constitution because
they want to ignore it.
They want to do all sorts of things that
are not authorized by the constitution.
The constitution only authorizes a few
powers to the federal government.
There are enumerated in the constitution
and the Constitution doesn't say the
government can do it,
it can't do it,
and almost everything that government
does today is unconstitutional,
is doing so that it has no constantly
authority to do.
And that's what we need a supreme court
for him.
And a lot of people don't like Congress,
very low opinion of Congress.
A lot of people don't necessarily like
the president,
but everybody loves the judiciary,
right?
We have three branches of government,
the executive,
the legislature and the judiciary,
and everybody likes to judiciary,
but I think it's the judiciary that has
sold us out the most because they have
let the government get away with murder.
They are not enforcing the law on the
government and,
and,
and making the government abide by the
law.
I mean the laws that apply to me and you
are up for interpretation,
you know,
they mean what they say,
right?
But somehow the laws that apply to the
government,
you know,
will,
they can be interpreted,
which means they can be ignored,
right?
They want to say,
oh,
the constitution is a living,
breathing document so that it can change
with the times is a way of saying it
means nothing,
so we need to reclaim the republic by
actually forcing the government to live
by the constitution.
That's one of the things trump can do is
say,
look,
we're going to restore constitutional
government to this republic.
We
are going to make sure that government
only does what it's authorized to doing
the constitution and the smaller you
make government,
the freer you make people.
Right?
That's what it's all about.
I said earlier in the podcast about this
whole idea about group privileged.
The more privileges that you give
groups,
the fewer rights that you have for
individuals and the more government you
have,
the less free we are,
so that's the actually the real
definition of freedom is freedom from
government and so the smaller
government,
the less they regulate your activity,
the the and the less money they take
from you,
the more freedom you have and the more
free we are,
the more freely we can interact with one
another,
the more prosperous we're going to be.
Now,
second step,
what does a person like me do to stop or
to mitigate the effects of this bubble?
That's gonna crash.
Well,
I mean,
as I said,
the only thing you can do personally
because politically there's really very
little we can do.
I mean it's gonna hit the fan,
right?
I mean there's nothing we can do about
that.
I mean,
because trump's not going to call me
down to the White House and they will
add to this.
Peter,
I love on the Joe Rogan podcast even
though sometimes he touched shit about
me,
that little weasel,
you know I was,
I was his biggest defender after the
access Hollywood stuff.
I was on podcast.
I was,
I defended him when nobody would defend
them for that because I understood those
comments and how and what he was doing
and I called everybody talking shit.
Yeah,
he look,
he was just being a guy with other guys
and he didn't know he was.
He didn't know he was being.
He wasn't saying that for public
consumption.
Imagine saying something funny and my
friends have said horrible things to me
and I've laughed.
Yes.
And of course the thing that billy billy
Bush got in trouble for sitting next to.
I know laughing.
He didn't.
It wasn't.
He wasn't like taking a stand.
He's in a broadcast next to a guy who's
a crazy person who is literally known
for being a crazy person saying
outrageous stuff.
His tagline is your fire,
you know,
you know some of the stuff that women
say about guys when they're just
together.
Women chatting.
I mean it looks so what?
But now I forgot your question about,
oh,
how do we fix?
How do we personally me?
Yeah,
we,
we're not,
we're not going to prevent it.
What I am hoping like you and people
like me after it collapses,
that if we can at least come out there
with an alternative version of what
happened,
like after the financial crisis
happened.
And I was one of the few people saying
it's not,
it's.
It wasn't the banks,
it wasn't greed.
It was government.
It was the Federal Reserve.
It was Fannie Mae and Freddie Mac.
They were the problem right now.
But the government got away with blaming
capitalism and making government bigger.
What we need to do and what you can do
with your audience,
which is much bigger than mine,
is when it hits the fan again to put the
blame where it belongs on government and
state government did this to us.
It's not an accident that we have all
this government and we have all these
problems and you know it's government
interference in capitalism.
That's the problem,
not capitalism itself.
If the government stayed out,
it would be working beautifully,
so we don't want to throw the baby out
with the bath water.
We want to preserve the baby,
the governments,
the bath water.
So what you can do with your soap box is
get people to understand
the real source.
Now what you can do now,
what your audience can do now to protect
themselves so they don't go broke.
And I think that to the extent that you
don't go broke,
you're in a better position to help the
economy and help the country if you have
resources,
right?
If you're.
I said,
if you know,
if a ship is going to sink and I can get
you off the ship onto a lifeboat,
then when the ship goes down,
you might be able to help some of the
people you know,
out of the water if you're not drowning
yourself.
So what you could do is protect your
finances if you've got a large
portfolio.
Right?
What I do with my own money and what I
advise people,
I manage money at Europe Pacific,
uh,
asset management at my broker dealer,
years of capital is I invest in
countries that,
you know,
I,
I think are relatively better shape,
whether it's Switzerland or Singapore,
you know,
or you know,
New Zealand.
I mean,
even though New Zealand just left a,
a leftist,
you know,
they are calm.
He is strong enough that I think they
can withstand it.
They've made enough progress,
you know,
so there are countries out there that
are not nearly as screwed up.
Nobody is perfect.
Nobody is as good as America used to be.
But there are a lot of countries that
are much better than we are now.
And they have assets that you can own
that are not in bubbles.
You can get good dividends,
you can protect yourself from this
coming stock market crash,
dollar crash,
bond,
market crash,
so you can preserve your wealth.
And as the dollar goes down.
So if you went through the 19 seventies
and you had your portfolio,
because the 19 seventies the stock
market went way down,
but the dollar went down even more,
the dollar lost two thirds of its value.
The reason oil prices went up 10 fold in
the seventies,
the reason gold went from $35 an ounce
to 850 was because the dollar collapsed.
While the dollar is going to have a
bigger collapse this time than it did
last time,
right this time,
I think the dollar is going to lose its
status as the reserve currency.
Last time it didn't lose the status,
it just got marked down because we went
off the gold standard,
but it didn't get knocked out.
I think the next one is gonna be a
knockout.
So you got to invest your money outside
theu ,
s to preserve your wealth when everybody
else is going broke and you got to own
real money,
you got to own gold,
you own physical gold,
right?
Which you can buy larger quantities of
gold through shift goals.
You know,
I got,
you know,
very low prices.
You've got to be careful out there.
There are a lot of companies that'll try
to bait and switch you into collectible
coins.
Rare coins with these huge markups.
Twenty,
30,
40 percent markups,
sometimes 100 percent markups.
Stay away from that.
You know,
you just want to buy bullion and you
want to buy it as cheap as you can over
spot.
The only time you'd want to pay a little
bit more is to get some jewelry because
you want to wear it.
Then it's probably worth it to pay a
little extra if you want to,
you know,
buy something that you can wear it many.
But so you can do that.
I think the stocks that are going to go
up the most,
if you really want to potentially make a
lot of money on this crisis,
it will be gold stocks.
Gold bullion is not about getting rich.
It's about staying rich.
It's about not getting poor.
Buying physical gold is about preserving
the wealth that you have,
but I think that these gold mining
companies,
when the price of gold goes up,
I think some of stocks go up 10,
20 times or more,
so if you're,
if you know you can tolerate the risk,
because if I'm wrong,
you know these stocks would go way down,
but if I'm right,
they're going to go way up.
So a way that you can really profit from
what's gonna happen is by having some
money investing in these coal mining
companies and then when we have a dollar
crisis and the price of gold goes way
up,
these stocks can go ballistic.
The Voice of doom and the voice of
reason.
All in one man,
Peter Schiff.
Ladies and gentlemen,
that was awesome,
man.
Hey,
how long?
We been talking.
Three hours.
Three hours already.
Crazy flies by studios.
Thank you brother.
Oh,
it's my pleasure.
Thanks for everything Peter Schiff.
Folks.