I have dreams.
I have fucking crazy dreams.
I had a dream one time that me and Elvis
walked into his hotel room and there
were four dudes,
but fucking right,
and I just hear me where they were.
Suggestions that might be one of the
best sentences ever created.
It's weird.
Or they're throwing up in Burger King
Cups,
fucking each other,
and then I as wordy when I say this,
I fucking just shut the door.
And I looked at Elvis.
I go,
what the fuck's going on in your room?
He said to me,
what's your Dream Baby?
Oh Shit.
I wake up,
I wake up.
I'm like,
wake up.
Check my,
make sure it's hard.
I'm like,
well,
you don't really flipped me out.
Do you know what really flipped me out?
Not that,
not that the guys were both fucking
right.
They didn't ask.
No.
It was the product placement.
Like what the fuck the Burger can do to
get it?
How the fuck
fucking dream figured it out and you
just don't know that they are.
It's way to interject advertising into
your dream.
It's the burger king in the future right
now.
It's like I got her Chrysler stream
about the Elvis and the buck fucking
Haha.
No,
no,
no.
But what is,
there's a possibility that someone could
insert a product to a dream.
Right?
But they could give you a cheeseburger
and in that cheeseburger with some
experimental thing that would make you
think about burger king in a dream and
see a burger and a dream,
you can do it.
You can do it.
I'm fucking a girl from Geico and shit.
But that doesn't make any sense cause
yeah.
Cause it's Geico eat something to have
this happen to you.
We're still,
we're still missing the whole package.
We're stumbling on something very
brilliant right now.