So Jamie Vernon has some facebook stock
for sale.
He's got,
he's uploaded it to Craig's slowly take
it,
take it off my hands.
I think it will bounce back if you guys
don't know what we're talking about.
Facebook a apparently Jamie,
you were the one who first told me about
it.
Why don't you fill people in?
From what I saw,
there's something going on like the
company's called Cambridge Analytica,
which uh,
what I've also then learned is that
Steve Bannon used to be the vp of this
company,
but that was before he was in the trump
campaign.
And they are responsible for scraping
millions of users.
Personal information,
I think through a couple apps.
Maybe like the,
like a personality APP.
If someone took one of a personality
quiz,
right?
Those online quizzes.
Polls,
yeah.
But let's be,
those are morons that answer those
things.
Right.
For the most part where people that are
super bored and that's how you get most
of the time,
how you get your,
your facebook,
like passwords stolen is from those
things.
So yeah,
or from sneaky emails that tell you your
account's been compromised,
please reenter your password and you
know they were doing
well.
It doesn't say facebook on the url.
They can be sneaky with their urls to
like put something in front of it and
then facebook and you're like,
oh,
it looks like facebook.
You know.
So the FTC is looking into this case
right now apparently as of yesterday.
And what I read is they face up to
potentially $40,000 fine for every
infraction,
which would total over two million two
trillion dollars,
I'm sorry,
with a t trillion.
So it's a,
there's their stock has tanked.
I think it was like 8% yesterday.
It's at eight and a half so far today
it's down to $165 a share.
It was like 185 two days ago.
So,
and then a lot of people that are also
not talking about just getting rid of
their facebook account altogether.
I talked about this last night.
I'm on the actual fence of doing that
just because I can't take it anymore.
That's the only place I go to where it's
just I get annoyed.
I get in fights,
I have to see my sister talk about trump
every day.
You know,
like it's just,
I get it just upsetting now.
It's a very good forum for people that
are into political arguments,
like political arguments,
gay rights arguments.
There's a lot of like,
that's like one of the last places where
it's okay to say that you don't think
gay people should be married.
Yes.
It's like,
you know,
I know,
um,
I just,
I just know some people that are
probably shouldn't know anymore.
Yeah.
And occasionally,
you know,
we're all my real facebook page,
which I never go to.
Like if I go to it once a year,
it's a lot.
And that's where all the fake news stuff
is.
Like I thought Pam Anderson died the
other day and it was just one of those
fake news stories.
And that's always where you find it is
on facebook.
Whenever you go and read an article and
those,
those two things at the bottom that
like,
you should see what she looks like now.
And there's like 30 of them.
Like wait a minute.
Like they just throwing shit at you.
Yeah.
They just literally like,
come on,
you're going to bite on one of these.
Come on.
What is it,
Kevin Costner.
You can't believe what he looks like now
you remember that girl from precious.
You can't believe it often.
Does it work though?
Check.
So every so often right now I don't need
more.
I take got me a few times in the early
days.
Google it.
Yeah.
Well I thought that those were below c.
It's a sneaky thing because they took
the place of real stories.
It's like it used to,
you go to CNN and everything would be
cnn,
but now you go to CNN,
everything's CNN up a dual line and then
below the line it's like sponsored
content.
Like wait,
wait,
wait.
This isn't,
this is so sneaky cause this is barely
an ad.
This is like an article on CNN that
takes you to some new place and every
page,
like you have to keep changing pages.
And every page is like one paragraph,
like one paragraph on what Kevin Costner
looked like in 1980 okay.
What about 81 boom.
Next page in [inaudible] 81 Kevin
Costner started to gain weight.
You're like,
yeah.
And then there's usually not the photo
that you want to see.
You know how like the thumbnail has like
Kevin Costner head blown apart and
you're like,
I want to see that picture.
And it's,
it's not even in there.
It's fake.
Some these sons of bitches clickbait
that insists that and snapchat,
I think it should go.
I might be out done with this to the
snapchat.
Rihanna,
Chris Brown thing is crazy.
The fact that somebody green lit that it
costs them almost a billion dollars.
Like instantly,
weren't they down like some $800 million
or some fucking insane number?
Yeah,
I mean that was,
yeah.
The second time that's happened in a
couple of weeks.
Yeah.
One of them was like Kylie Jenner saying
it sucks.
Right?
The current action.
So 800 million,
they dropped after Rihanna condemned ad
making light of domestic violence.
So the question was in the poll,
would you rather slap Rihanna or punched
Chris Brown?
Like what would you,
what would you look at this?
Look at that.
Of course everyone wants a punched,
like who wants the slippery on it?
There's a lot of dudes,
there's a lot of assholes out there.
There's got to be probably a sizeable
percentage of the people clicked slap
Rihanna just cause they don't like their
life.
Well woke the beach.
I would like to see that.
What the results were of this.
Yeah.
Well you would have to join the band and
administration and then they get you
involved in Cambridge analytics and
you've got to give up your fingerprints.
I don't know how anybody could say yeah,
put that on snapchat.
Like that seems so fucking insane.
That seems like a joke,
like in a movie,
you know,
like can you talk about like a clueless
executive,
you know,
like this is my idea.
What do you think?
Lots of clicks,
lots of clicks,
you know,
cut to him with a sad face holdings,
boxes,
stuff as he's being kicked out of his
office and stay out.
You know.
I mean,
that doesn't seem like something that
something is huge as snapchat.
How could they do that?
They,
they've been fighting,
I mean the whole redesign they did
recently.
It already was confusing and annoying to
begin with,
but don't use it at all now it's even
worse.
And like every,
they even had a,
a,
a website where,
you know,
every,
a petition to the,
to switch back.
I think they got up to a million users
saying,
we want the old snapchat back.
And they were like,
no,
it's,
it's better now.
We're in not listening to you.
Oh,
well instagram
listened,
right?
They went back to things being in
chronological order.
Did they do that?
It's,
it's uh,
the tested it.
I was like a Beta test.
It hasn't happened for everyone yet,
but it probably will happen or it's
going to become an option soon.
Yeah.
Nobody likes this nonsense.
I'll look at my feed from real recent
and it says,
I'll look at someone's post.
I'll say,
this is yesterday.
And then I look at the time it says 26
hours ago.
I'm like,
what the fuck is that?
Hate that.
Why are you showing me something from a
day ago?
Yeah.
Like,
or I'm going to be here tonight and that
was from like three days ago already.
This concert I've ever seen.
This joe just came out recently.
This snapchat,
uh,
opened up their map.
It's called the snap map.
So that,
that word,
the hot zones are where snaps are taking
place right now.
What the universal stories basically
like a stalker map for people that don't
have everything private.
But like this is universal studios,
so it's a hot zone.
This is the Hollywood and highland hot
zone over here in Ucla.
Hodson where the kids are,
right?
So you can like watch where trends are,
things are happening while they're
happening and whatnot.
Makes Sense.
I mean that they can track that.
And those spots,
I would assume,
you know,
like Disneyland,
right?
It's gotta be a hot zone.
Like anywhere there's a giant population
area.
But what,
I don't even know what the fuck a snap
is.
Is it just like a picture?
Just like instagram.
It's like instagram second picture or
video or whatever.
But it goes away if you want it to.
It doesn't have to anymore.
It used to,
I used to be the idea.
Yeah,
just disappeared.
Yeah.
But everyone competed and so now they
have to keep it around.
Right.
So funny how privacy is changed over the
years.
Remember aol one or two where it used to
have member directory where you just
type in your address and will show you
all the users near your house and then
you could just instant message these
people out of the blue and go,
hey,
I you look cute.
I lived down the street from you.
You want to hook up?
Like that's how like they even showed
where you were.
Well,
we were talking to him about this
yesterday with Kurt Metzger.
We were talking about Barry crimmins.
How Barry Crimmins,
you know,
Barry Crimmins has a,
um,
there was a documentary that bobcat made
forum about him called the Co,
the call me lucky.
Is that what it's called?
Or just lucky call me lucky.
Call me lucky.
Anyway,
in the documentary at details,
his battle with AOL where AOL was
allowing people to trade child porn and
they had a policy where if three strikes
and you're out so you could trade trade
child porn,
call me lucky.
Yeah,
you could trade child porn three times
like and it's fucking insane.
And he,
he actually was a big part of that trial
and bringing it to trial.
Yeah.
The thing is insane that that wasn't
that long ago.
That was 20 years ago.
20 years ago you could trade child porn
on AOL.
Jesus.
She like,
and if you got caught they just said,
hey,
don't do that again.
Like now they come to your fucking house
and they lock up.
Like it's really interesting how much
that's advanced.
You know,
this is what I was going to show you
guys a second ago.
I just saw a story yesterday that never
before the thought I funds could be
cracked.
And now this company has this little
box,
which uh,
there's a picture right here.
It's not that expensive.
$15,000 gets the police,
300 uh,
licensed unlocks and then they can spend
double and Gav unlimited unlocks and it
will unlock every iphone and newer than
an iphone five s it said it.
Their pricing structure is weird because
if you get the 15,001,
you're only allowed to do it at a
location that's like Geo fenced in.
You're not allowed to do it anywhere
else.
Hold on.
Sorry.
Can you just said newer than an iphone
five s it can five,
five s and newer and newer up up to
right now,
like you just have a five,
I guess.
Would it be the older operating system?
I think we're going to talk about with
that with phones,
but you might not be able to use those
anymore.
You know,
it's just so convenient to do things on
your phone.
That's part of the problem.
You know what I'd take taking the doing
lately,
using apple pay,
the grocery store,
who,
it's so exciting.
It's very exciting.
It's like I'm living in the future.
I double click it,
sees my face,
you know,
woo.
Oh,
I just bought one of those little square
devices,
you know?
So like if you're selling shirts after a
show or something and it has that built
into it,
so you could just,
people are just using your iphone is on
it.
Whoa.
Yeah.
$20 device you get on Amazon.
That's crazy,
isn't it?
With your Imac is good too.
Yeah.
It's your I Mac,
if you buy something on your Imac and
it's linked to your phone,
it'll just like,
do you wanna use apple pay and then you
pull out your phone and confirmed well
on my laptop,
but it's a fingerprint I don't have for
like for apple pay.
Yeah.
That's retina scans be paid with your
Apple Watch though.
Like a pimp yet cheese.
That's too much.
So I mean like this is gotta be
escalating,
right?
It was.
So the people that are sitting back,
the forecasters,
they're looking like,
what is technology going to be in 10
years?
Like what are they saying?
What's their predictions?
Because this is a,
it's getting into your body somehow.
It's coming in one of the holes.
It's like a dude right now rubbing his
dick on the outside trying to find a
place to stick it in.
He's got it on your wrist,
he's got it in your pocket and he's,
he's trying to get it into,
your body's got it in your ears.
They're,
they're putting,
you know,
earbuds in like those airpods said it
best.
You do fucking Siri with a double tap
and your airpods.
It knows when you're taking him out of
your ear so it pauses your music or
videos.
It's incredible.
They're incredible and they don't fall
out when you work out either.
I thought that was gonna be a problem.
We're not as good.
They're not as good for working out,
but the what,
what is is what's actually even better
to me is that for the sound as those
beats threes,
I got those wireless beats ones.
Those things hook over your ear with
that little rubber thing and they,
they lock in place that you could get a
serious work on him with those on the
airpods there,
they do fall off.
They do fall off occasionally.
They have these skins too to make a
little tighter on Amazon.
Yeah.
It's just like just like generic thing
that goes over it to kind of tighten it
up in your ear.
It's an awesome idea.
It's not perfect.
It would be perfect if they hooked onto
your ear but then they wouldn't be
fitting into that box.
So it's almost like they can't be
perfect cause like part of the thing is
that they fit in a little tiny ass box.
You pop it open,
it's got a little green light on and
it's a battery pack too.
And it's magnetic.
I mean shit that slick.
That's slick.
No one saw that coming either.
That's one of those weird ones where
nobody saw it coming.
You know,
I wasn't really necessary,
but no one saw it in the being necessary
until someone made it.
I think I tell you what's not necessary
is that home pod,
they release that thing is just a dump.
They think stocks.
I mean it sounds amazing but serious.
So stupid compared to Alexa.
It's weird.
Is it Alexis?
Just smart as fuck.
And so Amazon's Alexa,
Siri.
And then there's,
what about the Google home?
Have you tried that one chart?
That one's supposed to be better too,
I think.
I think it probably is.
I mean it's,
if it's the same as the android phone
line,
it's good series.
Like that girl that was really hot but
decided to stop working out,
you know?
And she's like,
she's still pretty hot,
but then all these other girls are going
to the gym all the time.
You look at them and like good or bad
though.
Look at her legs and series,
just kinda series kind of sloppy.
It's pretty annoying now how many times
my Siri and my Alexis go off just from
people going,
Hey Siri,
you know,
like on a podcast or something and it
just ruins everything.
Yeah.
If you have it set like that,
I mean when we've,
we've probably triggered a thought,
a ton of people just you doing that
right there.
People always complain when I say that.
And then there's the,
hey google complaint too.
Same thing.
Say,
hey google and someone's got their
system,
whatever it is.
What is the thing you're supposed to
say?
Hey Google.
Hey,
okay,
go.
You should be able to put anything you
want though by now,
right?
Fuck face.
Yes sir.
It should be fuck face.
That would be the best.
Just call your computer.
Fuck face.
My Alexa dig.
When those things were out of the blue.
I think it was in the news recently
where he just sitting there and then she
just starts laughing and heard about
that too.
Like a witch.
What is that?
I would shoot that thing.
I would take it outside and fill it full
of holes.
Flux.
You,
I can't fucking sleep with a robot
laughing at my house.
Fuck you wake up to get a drink middle
of the night here.
I laugh.
She also,
it's so weird how many Easter eggs she
has.
Like she also has like seven songs and
out like,
like you go,
Hey Siri,
send me a love song.
She will sing you a score on Siri or
Alexa.
Alexa,
sing me a love song.
Love songs.
Ready?
Yeah,
that she sings and she has like a rap
song and she has one about technology.
I always wonder what Stephen Hawking
never upgraded his voice.
You didn't want to.
I think,
yeah.
I think I remember reading that he liked
keeping it that way,
but yeah,
I get,
I get it.
That's why he kept it that way.
But I mean,
what,
what kind of logic behind that is that
maybe he just wanted to keep it creepy.
Like if you,
he didn't want to,
he wanted to keep it obviously
electronic.
Whereas there's some places you can get
to with some these new
voice things there.
What was that movie?
She,
the movers are keen.
Joaquin Phoenix.
That was an interesting movie.
Yeah.
They could have paid anybody to be his
voice.
I would imagine that at the time the
technology figured out he could have
been Samuel Jackson,
but in a,
yeah,
for Stephen Hawking.
Yeah.
But it probably would sound off like
this.
It wouldn't sound like a real
conversation,
you know?
It'd be all,
you know what I mean?
It was like you've heard them do that
with voice.
Like when they take people's voices and
they chop them up and try to piece
together some sort of audio of something
that they didn't really say.
If they're being obvious about it,
but you know there's technology right
now like photoshop that's going to allow
people to Stich audio together and I
believe we've talked about it on the
podcast before.
Yeah,
it's getting better and better.
There's a radio lab episode where they
showed where it's at now and it's one of
those things where it's right now it's
not ready.
It's still like if you heard it you go,
oh that's not Brian.
That's a fake conversation put together
from a bunch of shit.
Brian said it's like that porn,
that fake porn that was,
that's even more crazy cause they could
just take your face like take pictures
and pretty seamlessly stitch your face
onto the character with emotions,
with opening mouth,
long linking and stuff.
I've seen some really good ones.
Like the girl from Harry Potter.
Yeah,
well it's what they're doing with
snapchat.
Right?
When someone pretends to be a rick from
the walking dead,
like Deleah did that and I'm like,
God damn,
that's pretty close.
It's pretty close.
Like I know that it's obviously that
there's a thing going on here but it's
pretty close to what it would really
look like.
Fucks get enough good enough to make you
a whoa.
This wasn't around before.
Like if someone showed you that snapchat
thing that all the girls do where they
put dog faces on and shit and Barf Barf
and pretend to be a puppy dog or
Unicorns or whatever.
Someone showed you that just 10 years
ago you would be holy Shit.
You wouldn't believe it.
You would look at like that thing that
lets you become rick from the walking
dead and you'd go,
what the fuck man,
this is incredible.
If someone showed you that 1998 well how
mind blowing and groundbreaking that
would be.
Now it's a part of an APP that's on your
phone that sits in your pocket like what
happened and how quick did this happen
and which holds it going in.
It's probably going to be a suppository
just so that the ale,
it's like a ironic like that.
The aliens have figured out a way to
mock us while defeating us and the way
is just to give you the most ultimate
bliss with his tiny little robot deck,
you don't even feel it.
It just put this robot dick and your
butt's depository and because your
button does nav like skin,
it's not the same.
It's like open tissue.
That's why it's so good for getting
infected.
So this little robot can just seamlessly
interact with all that open tissue and
that's how you with God,
they're going to talk us in just with
the way they did with these Cambridge
analytics.
They sneak you in the door.
You think it's a personality quiz really
electing a dumb president,
you know,
same thing.
You think,
well I'm just going to go meet God.
No,
you giving birth to the robot empire
through little tiny robot dicks.
It's not impossible to think,
look,
we're willing to put glasses over our
face so we could see better.
Why wouldn't we put little little metal
bullets up our,
but if you found out that it makes life
infinitely better,
they're like,
we can't believe that this is the case.
The only way to do it is up your bud.
You know we've,
we've tried and then people like,
oh come on,
I'm not doing that.
And then a few guys do it and they're
walking around your neighborhood and
fuck it.
Sparkles are coming out of their eyes.
They're so happy.
They couldn't be happier.
And you're like,
God damn it,
I need to try it.
People are flying.
They're flying around your neighborhood
because they have that robot deck.
Yeah.
Like Andy Stumpf from the s in a
wingsuit.
They're doing that around your
neighborhood but they control it
themselves and it's all because of this
robot Dick,
that Ben Space and time just have to do
at once.
Or is it a every day keeping your house
when you take it out of your ass,
then you become a normal human and then
eventually they figured out a way to
keep it in there to keep it in there.
Yeah,
they like bolt it to the wall.
Your asshole strap we should but strap,
yeah,
you've got to get it cleaned out every
now and then cause shit gets caked on
it.
On the way out.
It doesn't,
it doesn't always get the full signal to
your skin,
you know,
do you have to have somebody do it?
I could do it in myself.
I'm not opposed to,
I need to go some doctor sticker,
robot Dick in my butt.
Come on
suck.
If you were like bungee jumping and your
robot dick fell out and all of a sudden,
you know,
sadness in the middle of the day,
that would be crazy.
Look,
we're already doing that with pills,
right?
People that are addicted to Xanax and I
know a few.
That shit apparently makes you feel
great.
Is that the upper or downer?
That's the,
uh,
there's no,
no problems in the world drug.
That's an anxiety reliever.
And the people that take it,
man,
they get hooked on that shit.
Dom irrera is very open about it.
He takes a shit every day.
He's so great.
He's great.
He had him last night on killed Tony.
He's the best of that.
No one's better at killed Tony.
The dumber.
Yeah.
He's so quick,
you know,
and he knows like the most ridiculous
shit to say.
Yeah.
But he,
he likes them.
Xanax.
I know a lot of Stan hope like xanax
too.
It was just joking around about if he
got out of a plane and a kiss the floor
when he,
when he landed in America,
it'd be because he saw xanax on the
ground.
They love those things.
I'm scared of that shit.
I don't want,
I don't want anything that makes me feel
like there's no problems.
I think the only reason why a lot of
people don't do it is because they don't
have a friend that has a bunch of Xanax
that's constantly giving them Xanax or
something.
Cause I'd never see pills or,
you know,
I'm not around that road at all at like,
oh,
I don't even want a xanax.
Looks like,
you know?
Yeah.
But I bet if we had a friend that always
had xanax on,
I'm always [inaudible] Xanax,
you know?
I bet that's how you get into it.
I think somebody just tells you,
you need to relax.
You know,
you're like,
but just,
there's so much anxiety.
I mean,
the world is filled with possibility.
The world is filled with danger.
The world's filled with good things and
bad things.
I mean,
there's a lot of shit going on.
If you don't have some anxiety,
it must be because you're just choosing
to not pay attention.
Like anybody who lives in New York City,
you live in New York City.
I imagine all the shit that's going on
around you all the time while you're
just sitting there.
You're supposed to be aware of it.
Just supposed to hope everybody keeps
together.
He's supposed to have everybody's cool.
You're,
you're in your apartment.
You're on the 13th floor of a 60 floor
building.
It's filled with people.
There's another one right next to it.
There's another one right next to that.
They go all the way down the street.
They're filled with people.
People are fucking everywhere and you're
supposed to just be chilled out.
That doesn't make no sense to me,
man.
I'm,
I'm with you.
If you're nervous,
you're anxious.
You're driving and traffic every day and
people are on their phones and then not
paying attention and everything you eat
gives you cancer.
You're not,
you're not anxious.
Yeah,
I don't understand you.
You should be anxious.
You know,
this is the argument for not living the
way we live.
It's not the argument for taking a pill
that kills that part of your brain that
makes you anxious.
Do you ought to audibly cy a lot?
Mostly for humor.
Yeah.
I don't audibly sigh like by myself like
oh but I'll do it like that.
Like for a joke.
Oh
I catch myself more audible audibly
signing more and more.
The order I get like just like little
things where I'll just like look at
something like,
oh that kind of shit.
But I didn't used to do that.
Like I'm going to go to oil.
Oil is a good one,
but it's like the things I grew up with.
Oil event.
Is it cultural appropriation?
I have to ask my Jewish friends from La
to start saying Oi Bay.
Yeah.
Cause like nobody ever got mad at
anybody who wasn't Italian who'd say
model model and this girl,
nobody cares about those.
You like the use of like fungal.
It's not used that often that it is in
Jersey.
Okay.
Go to the east coast.
Go to where those old school guineas
landed on boats and fucked each other on
the rocks and made a bunch of them and
they all stayed there about fungal.
What's the,
what's the Italian Horn like?
If you're Italian,
you know it's happening and had one of
those
shows you're a moron.
I don't know.
I don't know where it came from.
We all have them in high school though.
It was like if you had a gold chain with
a horn,
like wow,
look at stylish,
did not know that thing existed.
It's called the Costello.
Seen that sperm before,
but that's probably what it is.
Cold sperm,
Little Horn or horn let sometimes
abbreviated to Como.
Isn't Italian amulet or talisman worn to
protect against the evil eye
or Mala Chico and bad luck in general
and historically to promote fertility
and virility.
That's the last thing we need to promote
fertility and kids in high school
wearing those things.
So it is a sperm?
Yeah,
ill Neapolitan.
It's called Kumi sallow or variance
thereof.
We talk.
Wow,
that's crazy.
It is just golden.
TJ's on your chest essentially.
Right?
The Golden Tj's or protect you from the
evil eye.
You get me block,
but I still got my not off.
Oh,
dad gave this to me.
The fucking evil eye over here.
Yeah.
What you're wearing it right where a
pearl necklace with Lynn too.
Yeah,
it's foul.
What a fowl little amulet.
Imagine they talk those kids into
wearing golden tj's around their neck
and all these years they thought,
hey,
that fucking evil.
I could suck my Dick.
How about that?
I'm like,
I'm going to go out and I got a good
amount of gold chains.
I got up.
Good solid fucking horn here.
Look at that.
Can't Catholic priests probably give
them to me it looks like com.
Yeah,
it doesn't even look like a horn.
What kind of fucking Horn is that?
Where it's round at the top like a,
like a sperm head.
Horns aren't rounded at the top.
It's all rounded.
The top.
It looks like it's swimming up stream
and like to the guys.
Madison is going in your mouth.
If you go back,
go back to those pictures of different
ones.
Is there anyone that has a flat top that
looks like a fucking horn?
No.
All of them are rounded at the top.
Like Jizz,
those Italian horns,
they're all rounded at the top.
Like Tj's,
this is insane.
I don't see any of them that look,
I go,
that's not an Italian horn.
That's the wrong,
that's some,
that's some like Gucci Shit.
Like someone,
some designer got ahold of it and the
new take on the Italian horn,
it's all the rage everyone wears.
Everyone was,
yes,
I've got three on.
I can't believe people wear that shit.
They do.
They can't help themselves.
They grow up in those communities.
I did it too.
I wore one.
You're around a bunch of,
uh,
east coast Italian people.
They're all wearing it.
You're all wearing it.
It's like,
God,
you got yet Italian horn.
And when I,
when I saw the guy that had it on,
he took,
I got,
yeah,
I got in and kissed it.
So he kissed the ges.
It's just my good luck,
judge.
God bless you.
What saint be Saint Peter,
right?
Yeah.
Right.
I mean,
it's gotta be which one's attached to
it.
That's like weird.
Like there's always affiliations,
like certain saints are
attached to certain,
you know,
fucking ridiculous.
It's all those ancient immigrant
cultures,
but is it any different really than like
looking back at like aol in 1996
trafficking porn people are just way
different now.
They're just way different.
Like human beings are way more aware of
shit today.
Even if they're misinformed.
They're at least more aware of a lot of
things in 1990 then,
then they were in 1994 [inaudible] 96
it's like,
I would say it's like a several fold
increase and how much we're aware of and
what we actually look out in the world.
It's just,
it's a completely different thing now,
don't you think?
Oh yeah,
I see.
What are we doing today that they're
going to look back on and go,
those fucking morons.
How did they do that besides
circumcision?
Circumcision is a big one.
The one day they can stop cutting baby
decks and they're going to look back and
go,
what the fuck people,
this is crazy,
right?
You hope not.
You're taking a baby day.
You don't want to stand out.
No,
I don't like the uncut ones,
man.
It freaked me out.
I think we've talked about this,
but the way they look,
right?
Yeah.
Just the luck cause I don't really don't
think that affects you.
I've asked you out there sucking dicks
on the sneak.
KIPP asked and I've heard they smell
more than a regular dick.
Why don't I think you should wash your
deck basically.
Overall though,
the advice I'd give anybody's Dick.
Yeah.
Yeah,
but that's still crazy.
I bet if you trim pussy loves to be
easier to take care of that thing too.
It's still crazy.
Told you that.
It's just nuts.
It's,
it's,
it's a nutty thing that we've just
gotten really accustomed to doing.
Cutting skin off your deck.
Like why?
What and the fact that the majority do
that.
What they're going to look back in 2018
they're going to look back at this time
period and they're going to go,
how was that possible that they had the
internet,
they had all this knowledge,
all they had,
all these scientific studies that had
been done.
They knew about psychology and
ideologies.
They knew about the health.
Like what?
Health benefits boat,
bogus fucking health benefits,
all less likely to get the fuck outta
here.
Wash your Dick.
Everybody wash it.
If you're getting AIDS or not getting
aids based on the fact that your
circumstances are not circumcised,
you are dancing on such a fine edge in
your life.
Like I want to see more data from that
study.
I don't want to just see,
do you get aids?
I want to see how fucking,
how crazy are you?
The whole thing is crazy cut and baby
dicks.
That'd be one.
What else?
Tax exempt shots.
Tax exempt status for religions
yet that one cause otherwise,
why can't I start a religion right now
and get tax exempt status?
Why can't you?
You telling me scientology,
you can do it.
How many people makes a religion?
Do you have a number top gimme your
number.
Tell me what your numbers are.
What?
How do you know whether or not someone's
legit?
How do you decide that no one should be
tax exempt,
especially someone who's taking in Shit
fucking ton piles of money.
If you're some sort of church or
whatever and you're getting donations in
the millions and millions of dollars and
you're like one of them,
Benny Hinn assholes out there driving a
Bentley.
Amazon ANC paid zero federal taxes in
2017 gets 789 million windfall from new
tax law.
They paid zero cause I work.
Yeah,
that Kinda Shit shouldn't happen.
That shouldn't happen either.
But the idea is that a corporation,
now,
this is not my idea,
so don't think I'm supporting this.
I have to preface this,
but the idea is that corporations
shouldn't pay tax because all of the
individuals who are making money in that
corporation already pay taxes.
This is the argument that I've heard and
that made me go,
oh,
okay.
And the argument was why might've been
Peter Schiff?
Did he say that to me?
I don't think it was on the air.
Might not have been him.
Shit.
Anyway,
sidetrack.
The idea is that a corporation is not an
individual,
so why should it pay taxes?
It's not a person.
It's a conglomeration of people.
Those people already pay taxes.
The corporation has money that it's,
that's piled up right.
And then like it's got a value and it's
got,
it's on the stock market and it goes up
and it goes down and you know,
and they're always kind of looking to
improve their bottom line and universal
constant growth.
But it's not a person.
I feel like corporations have gotten
rights like people over the last 20 plus
years.
You're right,
they have,
they gotten rights in terms of how much
they could donate to charities to uh,
excuse me,
political campaigns.
And that used to be not the case.
They used to have a limit and now they
are like an individual in which they can
donate as much money as they want to.
Political campaigns and doesn't a
corporation also act to defend itself?
Sort of like,
yes.
Can you google that,
make sure that's true that corporations,
um,
they can donate as much as they want to.
Political campaigns.
Now I think there's,
I want to say this is like
during the Obama administration.
Fucking Obama.
Obama,
yeah,
I think this was during the Obama
administration.
It's a disturbing one.
That's a disturbing one to me because
that is a,
that a sale.
That's a lot of influence where someone
like a Amazon,
I don't think Amazon's evil.
What's the limit wanted to be?
I don't know.
I mean if the limits like hi,
you know,
maxine either thousand dollars,
there's no limit limit to should be a
limit.
But I don't think there is.
There has to be,
well,
I don't know.
How sad is it that I don't know.
I should know.
Okay.
See what we got here.
I've seen various things.
The one I'm right now is that an s
corp can uh,
deduct up to 50% of its adjusted gross
income to be,
uh,
as a qualified yes.
No.
How much money can,
no,
there was a law passed and I'm looking
at,
it's not popping up how much money
there was a law passed that stated how
much money a corporation can donate to
political campaigns.
There was very specific that a
corporation is seen as an individual.
When you look up that corporations seen
as individual for donation,
political campaigns,
it's just,
it's not in anybody's good at,
in anybody's interest that these huge
companies like Amazon or anything that
size that is fucking billions of dollars
that they should just be able to get
together and influence a politician with
a shit ton of money and then the
politician does their bidding and helps
them be bigger and stronger and it may
be fucks over.
Some people gotta be really careful
about that because the politicians could
find a way of arguing it.
Well,
I could see,
but what is that how he would vote
without that influence?
No.
So all these politicians and get into
those positions are all just influence
peddlers.
They're just peddling influence.
The saying,
listen,
you know,
if you help me,
I'll help you scratch my back.
I'll scratch yours.
Then not looking out for the people that
voted them in at all.
They're looking out for the people that
paid all the money to make them more
prominent so that people would vote them
in.
It's very sneaky,
like it should have been fixed a long
time ago.
It's really,
if you think of all the shit like
insider trading,
that is illegal.
Like if,
uh,
if Jamie really did know something about
facebook and then,
uh,
he told us and like,
hey dude,
shit's going down.
Get rid of all your facebook stock right
now and you and I went crazy and got rid
of it.
We could get in trouble.
Like Paul Ryan's in trouble for it now.
Something thing he goes supposedly was
he sold a bunch of stock.
Oh,
so someone told him and he bailed.
Yeah.
See that.
How is that illegal?
But it's not illegal to influence
politicians and have corporations spend
shit,
tons of money and then obviously get
preferential treatment and obviously get
laws pushed.
Here it is.
Paul Ryan's sold shares on same day as
private briefing of banking crisis webs.
That seems like a dumb move,
Dude.
Wow.
You got to take the hit.
So now you've got to take the hit their
fellow.
You can't do that.
That's terrible.
Somebody told me you better sell your
toys are us stock right now.
That's what I hear.
But this thing about this guy,
like when Ken,
he
like trade those stocks.
You have to wait cause that's what
Martha Stewart got in trouble for it to
you.
Right?
Well she lied about doing it.
She got like a,
they found a note that had like the
information on or something.
God Damn my memory's dog shit lately.
It just real quick on the tax thing,
I think there is a limit but then that's
why super pacs became a thing.
So you can donate to another
organization that's not directly to them
and the neck come back group and give
the money as they say,
oh it's just a work around with like a
loophole.
You know what the limit is though?
I believe it's 2,700 for an individual
and then there's like for a company can
give like up to $10,000 or something.
So it's 2,700 for an individual.
That's interesting.
For election.
Lot
of money,
but not as much money as you would think
it would be.
Right.
Look,
you would think it'd be like a million.
Yeah.
You know,
there's a bunch of fucking wackadoos it
would give a million.
The thing is,
man,
there's weird things that happen with
politicians that you don't factor in
when you think about bribery.
And one of the weird ones,
his,
did you ever see that movie about the
financial crisis?
Uh,
which one was it called?
Hmm.
Lot inside job.
Inside job.
It's fucking amazing.
But one of the things that had details
is how many of these guys were
professors that were making these
suggestions,
like working as consultants to the
government making these suggestions that
why not to be horribly irresponsible
financially.
And then those guys get giant jobs
afterwards.
It pay fucking millions of dollars and
you're like,
wait a minute,
what happened here?
You're a professor,
you made these sort of,
you know,
weird suggestions that if you looked at
like in the,
in the movie,
inside job,
he goes over it with these professors
like,
well,
how the fuck could you have thought
this?
Why did you push this?
Like,
why were you,
why were you guys promoting that?
And then they go on to get these
gigantic fucking jobs at banks.
And you're like,
oh,
this is crazy.
This is like a clear path.
Like do the right thing here and then
you're gonna make $5 million a year
here.
And so they all do it and this movie's
really good because in one of the scenes
he's talking to one of these big time
bank guys and in the middle of talking
to him,
the guy realizes what's going on and he
gets a real hostile but he keeps going.
He like he,
his arrogance allows him to like keep
battling sky,
but it keeps like looking dumber and
dumber because the guy who was doing the
interview is really good.
The Guy who put together this
documentary is really good.
It's an,
it's a fascinating documentary that
gives you a real insight into how
complicated,
complicated and fucking distorted the
system is.
Like it's very distorted for those
people that are just like those rich
banker guys.
All they're doing is moving money.
I didn't have all that money and we do
put money over here and then get it
over.
Pick it up.
Aren't you glad you're not doing that
though?
No,
I don't understand it.
Actually,
I couldn't,
I,
I just can't imagine we still use it.
I mean,
I'm sure some of like Peter Shift could
come in school me and explained it to
me,
but I feel like it should be like one
goat equals one piece of gold.
I think it's an issue go higher than
that.
It just,
it soon as you get into speculation and
shorting and oh my God,
buying and selling stock in a company
and a company can crash like that.
And that's like,
unfortunately what's happened to babies
r us and toys r us is that they weren't
getting killed by Amazon.
It was just them taking debt in and like
this finance company that bought them
just pretty much,
you know,
going crazy in depth,
uh,
from bad spending.
And it had nothing to do at the boys are
s's business.
They were doing fine.
It was all about the finance company
that owned them.
That's a sad thing man.
But the,
it might be a good thing for like mom
pop toy stores,
toy stores.
Because here's the thing about toy
stores.
As a parent,
kids love to go to the fucking toy
store.
It's a fun time.
It's like we're gonna that toys dog woo.
Like if my kids would do something good
or would make a promise like,
hey,
if you were going to do this project and
when we're done with this project,
you guys could pick out a toy.
So you give him like a work reward type
situation.
Do they get fucking crazy?
They're running down those aisles is all
his stuffed animals and all these games
and it's an exciting place for little
kids.
You can't replicate that online.
It's just not the same.
You're looking through amazon.com or
something like that.
It's great that it's very convenient.
You can just press,
press one click and have it sent to your
house.
But for toy stores in particular,
this is a colossal,
there's a,
there's an opening for sure.
Uh,
for another company,
there's,
this is the time to start a new toy
start.
Cause Look,
look at all the toy stores are gone.
Like kb toys.
Remember that in the mall that there was
a toy store that was bought by the
company that bought toys are us.
So that's gone too now.
Like all the toy stores are gone.
There was a little place up here in
Calabasas.
It was real nice man.
Real tiny little mom and pop place had
real cool toys.
Their kids used to love it,
but the guy was telling me like,
guy or Gal want a woman?
I'm a sexist.
I don't remember who it was.
I'm thinking of my bid woman them.
But they were saying that no,
it was a guy.
Now I remember he couldn't keep it open,
um,
to make money if he's only doing it for
fun because he enjoyed it.
It was just barely breaking even.
But it's probably one of those toy
stores where it was mostly like puppets
and like,
like you know,
educational toys and it wasn't like Gi
joes.
They had everything.
They had a lot of stuff.
They had regular like action figures for
comic books and stuff like that.
What are you doing?
I just,
there's this documentary on Netflix
right now called the toys that made us,
and it's very interesting and like you
learn so much like I showed the history
of Barbie,
Barbie started off as a hooker.
Like it was a hooker doll.
The in Germany.
Come on.
Yeah.
Swear to God.
Like they uh,
Google please.
Yeah.
There was this tree,
that Barbie doll,
there was a doll that looked exactly
like Barbie that they used to guys used
to like carry around and give to women.
And it was like a way of like a flirting
with a woman.
Like,
Hey I,
this is what I want to see you wearing
later I want.
And so this person came over to Germany
and solve this doll and modeled Barbie
right
after this hooker doll.
And so if you look at the original
Barbie,
but what it was modeled off of it was
just like a creepy looking hooker chick.
I'm sure you can find a picture.
Uh,
but this documentary is so amazing cause
it goes through like all the famous
things in your mind.
I just definitely gonna look into the
history of Barbie.
It's just a documentary.
It just goes to the toys,
the toys that made us,
it's so good.
And it goes through like he man and Gi
Joe Gi Joe is interesting because you
know that back in the day,
you know,
releasing a guy doll like,
no,
we're not going to make no guides.
All,
no one's going to play that.
But Gi joe ended up being like one of
the biggest toys in the whole entire,
and that's,
you had a call and an action figure.
I used to have Steve Austin,
$6 million man action figures.
You had to call it an action figure
that,
and that's where action figures came
from.
Gi Joe.
That was the way around the doll thing.
Yeah.
Smart move.
Because dolls,
yeah,
dolls are not for boys and that funny,
but you could have dinosaurs,
right?
Ah,
what does that sort of doll?
It's a doll.
It's a daughter.
Sarah doll.
One of them was,
which one was it?
No,
gi Joe.
One of those was like a,
they made a whole cartoon and just made
the toy.
He man.
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
It was just designed to as a marketing
tool.
Yeah.
They decided how do,
how are we gonna Fight Star Wars toys?
And we're like,
let's make it bigger and stronger.
So if you see a he man doll next to a
star wars toy,
it's like,
well here's this little pussy doll.
You know,
so and then they made a cartoon around
it and uh,
it's really interesting.
Like you wouldn't think it would be that
interesting.
But even the Barbie part,
it was like,
wow,
this is fascinating.
And how they changed barbies.
Look every year like nadir sexier made
her like her waist.
Like she gets so much shit because her
waist is really small and light stuff.
That's because when you put clothes on
for it to fit and look right,
that's how they had to make her waist
just,
it was more for like the style of the
clothes she was wearing,
not of what it looked like.
It was more like,
like
just to have the doll work.
Right.
It's really cool.
It's got to be fucking super hard to be
a check and look at like those dolls and
look at your body and go,
what in the fuck?
This is not even possible.
You know,
cause a lot of those dolls,
they're not possible.
But what's really funny is one of the
things in the 50s what does the say?
There is the only dog.
Yep.
Build Lilly dollars by lily dog can be
bought and tobacco shops,
bars and adult themes.
Toy stores,
Gerber rights men got Lily Dallas's gag
gifts at bachelor parties.
Put them on their card dashboard,
dangled them from the rear view mirror
or gave them to girlfriends as
suggestive keepsake.
What does that mean?
Suggestive keepsake.
Hey look at this,
but I want to style this.
Prodo Barbie was just shy of a foot tall
with bulging breasts and platinum blonde
ponytail made up for a night on the town
with red puckered lips and blue
eyeshadow.
Wow.
Interesting.
The Journal,
German dolls,
heavy makeup and subjectively arched
eyebrows didn't carry to the American
version.
That's interesting,
Huh?
They tried to lighten it up a little.
Yeah.
Then they even go into like how her eyes
are looking to the side not right at you
and then wants to sneak,
see if she could fuck you in this alley.
Yes.
Saint to becoming,
Oh God,
they're comics for this little adult.
To what?
Yeah,
like a comic.
Oh,
that's hilarious.
Lily was witty,
irreverent and sexually uninhibited.
One stripped summarize by Lord who's
Lord,
Lord of the writer,
the writer.
Okay.
Shows lily covering her naked body with
a newspaper explaining to a friend.
We had a fight and he took back all the
presence he gave me.
Get it.
She's naked.
Another shows lilly in a bikini.
When a police man tells her that two
piece swimsuits are illegal,
she says,
oh,
and in your opinion,
which part should I take off that dirty
bitch.
One interesting thing too is like,
you know how Barbara gets so much shit
for him,
you know like being a fatter woman
having it,
you know the body issues and stuff like
that.
Shit.
There was like a workout Barbie and she
had a little scale and the scale was,
had a sticker on it and it was stuck at
a 110 pounds.
And then there was also a book that came
with it,
like a cookbook or like a book that's
like how to lose weight on the back of
says don't eat instead.
So that
came out.
Dude does dark.
Yeah.
And then it talked about how Malibu
Barbie,
like what's the first one that like have
the eye stare right at you.
So it was like more sexual or something
like that.
It's interesting shit
dude.
You don't want to,
you know,
I mean that's the thing about those
dolls and all that stuff is like you're,
you're putting something in a kid's
head.
This is what an adult looks like,
but I guess you're doing the same thing
with he-man,
right?
Oh yeah.
Like you putting that in a boy's head
and then he gets into the mirror and it
was like,
that's why people flex and have your
Italian horn.
They're looking at their muscles in
their life.
What in comparison to he,
man,
I'm nothing.
You know,
that's the argument too about the rock
or anybody who's like some beautiful
muscular cre creature like that.
It's like how the fuck do you aspire to
that?
But guys don't complain about that Shit.
Like you don't hear a lot of complaints
about male positive body image.
You know,
you don't hear that.
Like people don't care if guys are fat
life guys feel sad because they're fat.
Nobody gives a fuck,
thank God.
But you know what I mean?
I mean it's like a,
it's a big deal like fat shaming men.
When was the last time anybody got
accused of fat shaming a guy?
It's always a woman,
right?
It's always,
if you're fat shaming,
it's implied you're fat shaming a woman
cause he's the only ones who care.
Come on.
Bird Tom at birth.
That was a different kind of fat.
They got locked up because people found
it a target like,
oh well it's,
let's figure out what we can say here.
Oh it's fat shaming.
But just genuinely unlike untrue,
like with,
without it ever being requested by
someone.
Like if you just on your own,
you decided that to say that's fat
shaming.
Like you saw it,
you pointed out and it became an issue
about a public event or a public person
or a public celebrity said,
I'm,
I'm being fat shamed,
and it was a man fucking never tested.
It means that it hasn't happened.
Maybe it has an ID.
I have been paying attention,
but I can't imagine that some guy would
fucking complaint because he has a gut
and someone's fat shaming them publicly.
He would just look at that gut and go,
fuck the right.
I've got to stop eating.
You know,
like the Tom at birth thing,
people really did think they were
serious.
That's where it got weird.
Like people would get angry at Bert or
angry at Tom and they'll pick sides,
but was telling me about this the other
day.
He hired me to like drive him on this
golf cart for this marathon.
Like in between taking instagram photos
like you imagine you get mad.
That's what I found out.
It's crazy.
He ran five 33 that's pretty good.
That's pretty good.
An hour slower than oprah,
but hey,
he's fat and he drinks a lot.
What's interesting is like the guy that,
the first place guy,
the guy that actually,
you know one,
it was like two and a half hours and
says no,
no,
no ones is it that can't be,
and it's,
it's an interest.
So it's two hours that they can't break.
Right.
They can't break two hours.
Yeah.
I was thinking that it's two years,
so like two 1146 that's what he did.
Oh my God,
that's the same what?
Burt was five and a half.
That's insane.
Runs so,
so fast.
That's insane.
I can't,
I've tried to run that fast for like a
mile.
It's,
Oh my God,
I didn't know they did it that fast.
I thought like,
I thought it was one of them.
If I was guessing when you said two 30
or whatever the fuck we thought it was,
I would be like,
well that's like a world record or some
shit.
What did it used to be?
Didn't it used to be three hours,
like a big deal?
I don't know.
I'm,
no,
it was like a three minute mile is the
big deal.
No,
four minute mile.
Right.
Then easiest came out and changed him.
Easiest changed the game.
You got so much more bounce.
How about this?
Go back to the world record marathon.
A world record.
Boston Marathon,
1980 I have a feeling it's like in the
threes.
It probably is.
I mean,
just wouldn't be world record.
Boston marathon.
That's a stupid thing to say.
It's a possum marathon record.
Who's the who want it to someone in
20001120302 yeah,
but that's 2011 I want to go down in
1980 and 19 old record.
It's been replaced.
Right,
but not the record.
Just like what is the result from 1980
Boston marathon result in 1980 I want
to,
I want to say that was probably the last
time I paid attention because I lived in
Boston.
I don't give a fuck about the La
Marathon.
I hear about it and I go,
oh,
can't drive there now,
but I'm not like,
oh,
what a smart thing.
These people were all running on the
street.
I think the reason why you're
remembering that it's because that's
when the woman faked the time.
Oh,
that's right.
That's right.
I forgot about her.
Oh my God.
That was 1980.
That's right.
Well she hopped on the tee and they
busted or people saw her on the tea.
Um,
what was her time?
Wouldn't just show it the pain.
I remember it.
Well,
just you're a terrible person and talked
about this cause you keep taking us down
more and more rabbit holes.
1980 [inaudible] 1980 [inaudible]
popping up.
Okay.
Um,
Boston marathon results.
1980s put an s on that bitch.
Put 1979
results.
If we go,
here we go.
Okay.
What do we got to 2020.
Wow.
Okay.
I'm way off.
What's still 10 minutes?
Six third place.
Two 47 the first place.
Women's top results.
So women do it in two 47 the man was
doing in two 2120.
It's fucking crazy.
That is so crazy.
You can run 26 miles and two hours.
20 minutes.
Ooh.
I would imagine that would have been
like a world record.
I'm so off,
you know,
but it's,
I wonder what they way,
you know,
that's another thing like Bert,
what's really impressive is how big bird
is births like 350 pounds more than
that.
Probably.
Yeah.
He's 800 pounds and he's running out
there.
Did he get a shoe sponsor?
No.
Why not?
Well,
I need to get a shoe sponsor.
Sports Bra should have got some Reebok's
tight,
Reebok's.
We run around that tracking.
They would've,
they would've sent a couple hundred
bucks as well.
Come up with some stuff.
Oh yeah.
There you go.
Oh,
that's right.
He said,
thank you,
Nike.
Yeah,
good move.
They should have gave him that marathon
shoe that they created just so that
someone could break two hours and see a
bird.
Could be the one.
It's supposedly shaves like 4% off of
your time.
That showed the fuck out of here.
How is that possible?
There's like a,
titanium is crazy.
It means you run a hundred miles.
You get there for mild quicker than you
did without that.
That shit's ridiculous.
There's a titanium plate in there.
It's supposed to help propel you
springs.
You run it on spraying.
So remember those air shocks,
those Nike Shox,
you'd have springs in your heels.
Look like frog shares.
I mean a beating this dead horse many
times.
Not a bad idea of beat it one more time.
But I like barefoot running.
I run with the smallest,
tiniest amount of soul and it's changed
my feet.
Like I used to get ice
of completely flat feet.
So if like I stepped in water and then I
stepped like on the tile,
like next to the pool,
it feels like symantec or something that
we could see my footprint.
You would see a flat cave band
footprint.
Same.
But since I've been running with these,
those are used,
those vibrams four fingers shoes and I
use a couple of different,
um,
the vose.
I like those,
those are,
they have real good traction in them.
What about the impact on your knees
though?
And your joints are running on the ball.
You're foot,
you're foot is a natural shock absorber
to thing is people change the way they
ran in the 1970s when Nike came out with
that really thick heel for those running
shoes and the idea was that you would
land on the heel and then go for it.
But that's a terrible way for your foot
to land.
That's all the shock goes straight to
your knee.
There's no give there.
The only give would be the cushioning of
the shoe,
but your foot is naturally designed to
decelerate.
You land on the ball,
your feet,
your foot decelerates and you go
forward.
And what it's done is strengthen all the
muscles in my feet in a crazy way.
Like I mean there's a big difference,
like a big difference and my legs just,
they just work better,
like a more balanced,
it's so crazy like it's,
it's changed.
Like I think about this,
I'm like if I was doing this back when I
was like really involved in martial
arts,
I think it would've changed my footwork.
It would have made my,
my movement in and out better and faster
cause like your feet strength.
The,
they'd be,
your fee becomes so much stronger when
you run hills with no shoes on.
I mean it's basically,
there's shoes,
there's a thin tread,
but there's no cushioning.
I mean it's all just,
the tread is like a layer of protection
from sharp rocks.
That's it.
You're going to try these.
Oh,
I have those in my ass right now and we
pull it out.
Um,
go pull up Vivo,
barefoot trail running shoes.
These are the ones that I've been using
a lot lately and the vibrams five
fingers.
But the,
the problem with the vibrams is they
don't have as much tread and um,
when it's muddy,
you slide all over the fucking place.
And I don't want to fuck my knees up.
No,
I don't,
that's not those,
those are like Ninja toes.
Hoy.
Aw.
Have you tried running barefoot on the
beach yet?
Yes,
I've done.
That.
Has Gotten better for you since you've
done that?
Yeah.
Well it's,
everything's better.
What's interesting is that's what it
looks like on the bottom of those.
Cool.
So it's a good tread on the bottom and
it protects you from sharp rocks.
But that that shoe is super,
super flexible.
Do you have to trail specific one?
Yeah,
because that's all I'm running on.
I'm not running on any hard ground and I
have zero problems with my knees.
Zero,
zero.
Sometimes my ankles are a little,
I'm a little stiff,
like sometimes they're little still sore
when I first start running,
but I'm like,
well,
no,
Duh.
Think about all the,
the beating I'm giving them as her.
Cool.
It was the ones that were now,
but right now,
as soon as it dries up,
because it's been raining a lot out
here,
soon as it dries up,
I'll go back to those vibram five
fingers because those things make you
use your toes,
like your shoe is in a coffin man,
like your or your foot rather in your
shoe.
Is it?
It's like a coffin.
It wraps it up.
It locks it down.
It's a cast and your feet don't move.
Right.
They don't spread out.
Your toes don't grip into the ground and
push off.
And Steve Maxwell was the first one to
tell me about that when in in regards to
weightlifting,
he was like,
you should wait live barefoot and if you
don't want to wait with barefoot where
those like five finger shoes.
And as soon as I started doing that I
started realizing like,
oh yeah,
like you,
you push off those toes,
you feel them dig into the ground and,
and,
and certain exercises.
But if they're all trapped up in a shoe,
it's like it doesn't,
they don't move.
Right.
It's just they don't expand.
They don't grip the ground.
They don't look,
they don't dig in.
But when you're running barefoot,
like my,
my,
like I feel the muscles in my feet,
they like afterwards,
like they get worked out.
Yeah,
like those kinds of things.
That's exactly what those are.
City ones,
Huh?
Those are the ones for wearing around
the city.
Look,
they look gross.
There's no doubt about it.
I mean,
you're used to looking at different
kinds of shoes.
You look at that little tiny slipper
thing on a dude's like,
Hey,
get out of here.
What your weird ideas with your fucking
slipper feet.
But it's just something you got to get
used to.
I prefer them now and if I don't wear
those,
I usually wear shit like this.
Like converse all stars because there's,
there's nothing there.
There's an,
it's like it's totally flat.
You don't have a raised,
he'll see like that.
She right there has a raised he air Max
right there.
Fat,
right?
You're like,
um,
but those,
those heels,
that raised heel,
it shortens your achilles tendon.
If you wear those all the time and
we're,
or wear high heels all the time,
think about it.
You are foot is always in this weird
position where your back,
the back heel is elevated.
So you're 10 is not traveling as far.
So then when you do something where it
does have to travel far,
it can get ruptured like you'd have,
you can have issues with it.
It's just not,
it's not.
It's like you ever heard of like people
that drive cars a lot and they have a
big fat wallet,
they wind up getting problems with their
back.
Like they'll get a disc slippage because
you know they're,
they're kind of getting a bulging disks.
They're always leaning on one side.
You're doing your body a disservice by
keeping it in an in an unnatural
position or in any sort of static
position for long periods of time.
So when you have a static position like
sitting with a big fat wallet and your
ass,
it eventually starts to break you down.
The argument is that that same kind of
shit is happening with heels.
So if you're wearing a sneaker that has
like a heel to it,
that you are constantly,
especially if you're doing explosive
exercises,
you're constantly limiting the range of
your heel.
Does that make sense?
Yeah.
My,
my,
my thing though is that because I also
have bad flat flat feet that if I have
like a congress all star,
I feel like I need more support cause I,
it makes me walk right.
Pig Pig,
you know,
pitch a tent or something like that.
I don't think that's true.
I think you probably just need to
strengthen your feet.
Yeah,
I think,
I mean it's just,
I just don't think that that's where you
get support from.
I mean,
you do get support from that.
If you go on mountaineering or
something,
you know you have to hike.
But if you're looking for like an
overall solution should try to get your
feet stronger.
Yeah.
Doctors,
that Doctor Scholl thing,
you can do it up like put your foot on
it and it tests your walking gait and
they give you the proper insole.
This kind of help a little bit.
Yeah,
those insoles will definitely help your
comfort level.
Right.
The thing is like what's causing the
discomfort?
Is it a lack of strength?
Is it a lack of mobility?
Like what,
what are the issues?
You know,
so it's like if you're going to go
mountaineering next week,
all right,
you should definitely go and get some
fitted in souls.
You could,
you should go get some stiff ass boots
that you know.
I mean that's definitely the way to go,
even if you're mountaineering,
period.
But if we're not talking about that you
want to talk about like a solution for
your life,
like why do your feet hurt when you do
things?
Why it might very well be they're not
conditioned well and they're not,
they're not being used correctly because
you're shoving them into these fucking
casts that we call sneakers.
Hippy talk one on one and my sneakers
have this new material that's been a lot
of shoots for a while,
but this like fly net material.
So it stretches with your foot.
Yeah.
Good.
I mean you don't have to,
they don't need breaking in.
Like she was kind of did for a long time
in the 80s nineties whatever.
Don't get me wrong man.
I'll still wear a pair of running shoes
every now and then if I feel are good,
you know?
But I just don't think they should be
worn every day.
I don't think it's a normal thing.
I just,
I definitely don't think you should work
out in them.
Like in terms of like running in them.
And a lot of the shit that people do,
I mean there's,
they have some shoes.
Like I know a underarmour has a show
called the speed freak that's um,
pretty flat.
You know,
there's a lot of these companies are
making flatter and flatter shoes now,
but people like they sell good,
you know,
you see that big fat,
that big fat.
He'll like go,
Ooh,
look at all that cushioning.
They like,
it sells good if was hard ones for
people that work out like it,
it's a big crossfit shoe.
Like Nike's metcon three I think is what
it is.
It's got that hard plastic and I'm
talking about,
Oh yeah,
that's for squats,
right?
They want you to have a heel for squat.
People do them and converse or barefoot
though.
They're just a good question.
You know,
I've heard,
I know some people step on plates.
They'll put like a 10 pound plate on the
ground and they'll,
they'll put their heel on those plates
and they'll do squats that way I'm not,
I don't know who's right or who's wrong
when it comes to that.
I do everything barefoot,
all lifting,
all lifting.
Either barefoot or with those little
five finger shoes on.
So she was,
aren't you worried about getting
ringworm all over your feet?
No.
Why do you think you get ringworm?
Aren't gems.
Oh,
I guess you haven't yet.
Private Gym,
like Jim said,
you're just like the dirty subsidiary.
But here's the,
the thing,
you know,
ringworm and um,
uh,
athlete's foot at the same thing.
Oh,
okay.
Do you know that?
Yeah,
exactly the same thing.
Yeah.
It's just skin fungus.
The best way to prevent against skin
fungus have healthy skin flora.
So don't fuck with any antibacterial
soaps because when you,
unless you're a doctor obviously,
but when you're using antibacterial
soap,
soap on a regular basis,
you're killing everything.
You're killing all the good bacteria to
which you want is soap that promotes
healthy skin floor,
like defense soap.
They make this soap with tea tree oil
and eucalyptus oil smells good.
Yeah.
And it,
but it's really healthy for your skin.
It's not,
there's no chemicals,
there's no bullshit.
It's just natural oils that promote
healthy bacteria and,
uh,
and they deny the growth of shitty
bacteria somehow or another.
I mean there's a lot of stuff like that
in nature that does teach.
Aerial is a big one for that.
Promotes healthy bacteria,
kills off all the bad shit.
I use it everyday.
And how like just keeping everything
dry,
you know,
like that's good too.
But what if you live in the jungle
bitch,
just make sure you're circumcise too.
Oh yeah,
that's probably right.
Sweaty Dick in the jungle.
A lot of ringworm everywhere you're a,
your body has like a whole system,
you know,
and that,
that whole system is fortified by you
eating fermented foods and things that
are probiotic and yogurt and like,
oh,
this is like strategies that people have
come up with over the years to introduce
probiotic foods into their diet.
And some of it was by accident by just
trying to preserve things and they
fermented and some of it was,
you know,
they figured out like,
Hey,
you know,
we can do this it and I have a better
result with that.
And you know,
that's,
that's really what's the
cause of a lot of skin issues.
I mean,
you're going to get ringworm anyway.
If you're exposed to it all the time and
you have open sores,
you can't get to a shower in time.
It's totally likely that you could get
it.
But I guarantee your recovery time and
the instances that you get,
it will be less likely if you take
acidophilus.
If you take a,
there's a,
I like Kombucha.
There's a bunch of different probiotics
you can take
and it's just very,
it's a very smart thing for your body.
But that's one of the one things about
diet coke.
I think diet coke all as delicious as it
is.
Rex,
you're healthy skin flora within your
gut flora.
Yeah,
it probably does.
I just read the other day,
like if you drink one diet coke a day,
like something about Alzheimer's.
I think it is that where there's like a
direct connection to,
uh,
I forget it.
Fuck it.
What it was,
but uh,
that's pretty,
pretty scary.
Dot cooks so bad.
Took out Tammy Faye Bakker.
Yeah,
that's it.
Took her out,
right?
That coke.
That's what they say.
Just one can triple your risk of stroke.
Meanwhile,
Donald Trump drinks 12 a day.
Done mother fuckers invincible as I
just,
cokes are probably better for it.
Cuffs do Donald's story.
What?
Mysterious.
Loch ness type.
Sea Creature washes ashore and Georgia
beach.
Well,
come on.
It is apparently,
and this just came out yesterday that,
but they still like marine wildlife
experts,
quote unquote don't know what it,
that's the only picture of it.
Yeah.
There's this video of it.
Let me see that again.
Wait,
how big is that?
It's caught five feet long.
I think it's like a plesiosaur.
That's what they said.
They a certain,
uh,
sea mammals can decompose to look like
that.
Wow.
No one,
it just showed up on a beach here
showing that video again.
Oh,
there's the picture.
Get bigger with that.
I blurred out the part where it was like
a gut or something.
Whoa.
It looks like it's just a piece of
seaweed and it's like at one inch long
and it looks,
that's hilarious.
They blurt out the guts.
They're going to show you this dead
body,
but they're blur out the gods.
No,
go back to the picture.
Live video.
No,
no,
no.
Does somebody see it?
Um hmm.
The flippers are very unusual,
like in that long ass neck.
That's a very weird animal.
Whatever that is,
that'd be fucking dope if they found
some new crazy looking in Georgia
dinosaur type fish right off the coast
of Georgia.
There's so much shit down there.
I mean,
you think about how many different
animals and organisms they are,
um,
constantly finding on earth.
Right?
I mean that,
that new crayfish that they found in the
ocean,
that's all female that,
uh,
reproduces by cloning.
If you heard about that one.
There's,
they're finding these fucking things
constantly that's in fresh water and
wheat,
but we have a way better account and
understanding of what's going on in
freshwater and we do of the ocean.
There's so much down there that we don't
know.
There's so many life forms down there
that we're not aware of.
Do you know how much of the ocean floor
has been,
uh,
thinking less than 10% and 5% and why we
work.
I don't understand why we're so
concerned about going to a different
planet when we haven't even figured out
this planet yet.
That's ridiculous.
Then when James Cameron went and as his
movie the movie,
he made it to go as far down as anybody
has gone.
I was looking into this the other day.
He didn't break the record in 1962 guys
got into a submarine and went lower than
he did by like a hundred meters or some
shit.
Whoa,
wait 29,000 feet or something down.
Jesus,
and it's still,
there's still more and I think they just
discovered an area near where they were
going that's lower than what they
thought.
The deepest part of the ocean was.
Top there for a second.
29,000 feet under the ground isn't a
mile.
5,000 feet.
So what?
What are you serious like they're almost
six miles down.
35,797 feet is the actual record.
What in the fuck ban?
That's seven miles.
Is that real?
Yeah.
Think a seven miles.
Seven miles is like here to studio city.
The thing that they did under water,
how far can you see?
You can't see seven miles,
right?
No.
Like the distance of the curve of the
earth.
The curve of the earth.
Like you gotta find the flat too.
Yeah.
But if you're flat,
if you're on like a c level and you're
looking straight,
how far can you see on a clear day?
I think you could probably see seven or
eight mile,
probably farther.
Hmm.
That's nuts man.
It's seven miles.
Is this the guy?
Yeah,
there's two guys actually,
they're still alive.
Uh,
Don Lawson,
jock picard shot and I don't know.
I bet you never recover from something
like that.
You go all the way down there and you're
just like,
what in the fuck?
Fuck what the fuck?
What the fuck are DNA probably changes
like that astronaut guy.
Yes.
Some day explained that,
that that was exaggerated,
that,
that people were,
I'm oversimplifying simplifying the
situation to say that there is DNA
didn't change the way you think it did.
It's probably just like one molecule off
or something like that.
It's probably not that big of a deal.
It's probably off though.
I mean,
what,
what are they saying caused him see,
um,
Google astronauts.
DNA didn't change the way you think it
did.
I think,
um,
we just don't understand like how it
yeah,
no Scott Kelly's DNA did not change in
space.
And this is from wastes.com the way it's
a weight local news station o w a t
e.com is probably just an AP story that
had put up.
Yeah,
I think it exactly is.
Cause I know I saw it on something else.
Get it a little beer so I can read it
here.
Uh,
after the Internet was abuzz about
astronauts,
Scott Kelly's purported altered DNA
after his year in space,
NASA is clarified the findings in their
study.
His DNA did not change by 7%.
He's still an identical twin to his
brother.
Mark.
I want my money back from all those
things I clicked you fuckhead NASA says
University of Tennessee's graduate,
gene's expression changed by about 7%
gene expression is how your body reacts
to your environment and stress
fractures,
fractures.
They said this level of change in gene
expression was within the expected range
for humans in stressful environments
like scuba diving or Mountain Climb,
ag biome,
you fucks.
So every time you go mountain climbing,
you're not an identical twin to your
brother anymore.
We're assholes.
We're just lying to ourselves.
We just lie to ourselves for clicks.
I'm Matt,
I'm Ha,
I've had enough.
It's like these people need to be
punished for their clickbait.
Yeah,
they're doing it on purpose at its worst
on like youtube.
I mean you could put up a little
thumbnail and get people clicking on
stuff and make thousands of dollars just
for that.
That's true.
I went deep on youtube the other day.
Have you ever watched somebody die from
rabies?
Oh No.
There's videos of people dying from
rabies on Youtube.
It's the most fascinating thing ever.
They're like,
I didn't know people still died from
rabies,
but there's like people that have rabies
and if you watch it's haunting,
you pretty much are going crazy.
Why don't they just kill them?
Yeah,
they know why.
Why do we need people to die 100%
naturally?
Like what is that about?
Like look at,
I mean it's,
it's so interesting to watch these
videos,
man.
What year is this?
Seems like an old fifties sixties or
something like that and you just die.
Rabies,
you don't bounce back.
Right and right.
And it's very sad.
You can't hold water in
a,
so you just constantly spit out water.
Oh Shit,
dude.
Um,
this is scary stuff,
man.
He's trying to eat.
Yeah,
it does.
It won't work.
He just puts it in his mouth and it will
spit it out.
Probably.
What a fucked up disease,
man.
Rabies is so crazy because it really is
like a Zombie disease for dogs,
right?
Yeah.
For dogs or animals,
they get it.
They,
oh my God,
look at me foaming at the mouth.
Yeah.
Now let me ask you this.
At what point in time to just give this
guy a lethal dose of morphine and get
this over with right now?
Like why did they let him get this far
gone?
They're just letting them die on his
own.
What is it about people that want people
to die on their own?
Like there's a certain amount we know
about the human body,
right?
When he gets to that sort of a stage.
Got It.
I mean,
the guy's foaming at the mouth,
twitching and bucking while he's
strapped to it.
Bed at.
And.
T.
There's videos of kids.
It's just like little like,
like three year old kids having rabies
like,
and you can't do anything.
Just have to,
they should kill her.
But like it's in,
they do now.
I think they just let him today suffer
today.
I don't think you're allowed to kill
anybody,
you know?
No.
I mean I saw him.
I mean if you have rabies,
do they have a cure?
I think like,
like if as an example,
if you get bit by a raccoon,
you'd have to go through all those like
a hundred shots.
Right.
You know,
type thing.
I don't know how long you have til to do
that.
Anybody that thinks that all
vaccinations are bad is a fucking idiot.
If you really think that it's all some
sort of a big giant conspiracy to ruin
people and make a ton of money,
you're crazy.
If people getting jacked by
vaccinations,
that is an unfortunate side effect of
one of the most spectacular things that
human beings have ever created.
They created a way to combat diseases
that killed untold millions.
Let me think about the fuck of malaria
vaccinations.
They can give you malaria shots,
a bunch of different shit they give you
or malaria pills.
You take pills and then you,
you go over there and you live where
malaria kills everybody.
Polio.
I mean,
they basically wiped out polio.
It did.
It just recently come back.
Just because people aren't vaccinating
the kids anymore.
Yeah.
There's a lot of people that aren't,
uh,
mumps,
measles.
There's a lot of different ones.
They're making their way back.
Yeah.
Mean they figured out,
look,
it's not perfect,
but there's not a damn thing that
involves putting chemicals in your body.
That's perfect.
Not a damn thing.
But what they've done with vaccinations
is fucking amazing.
Now I think I agree with you on flu
shots.
I don't get flu shots.
Okay.
I never had one.
I don't,
I don't think that they don't work.
I think they work sometimes,
but I know people that have taken flu
shots and gotten sick.
Okay.
Yeah.
Cause it's the flu and you're not
supposed to.
But I usually for a couple of days you
might a little sick.
He wants that.
What does this,
it's the disease express itself in two
forms.
Furious rabies,
whoa.
70% of human cases cause hyper excited
behavior,
a strong fear of water and sometimes a
strong fear of flying.
This will eventually result in death by
cardio respiratory arrest,
paralytic rabies.
30% is a less exciting and takes longer
to kill you with it.
Your muscles gradually paralyzed
beginning at the source of the infection
spreading outwards.
What is this article from everything you
want to talk about?
Rabies cause that Gizmodo.
Yeah.
Wow.
With extreme aggression that most
strongly characterize the disease when
the animals have it.
What's fascinating to me is that they
want to bite you,
so which would help spread the disease.
It's almost like the disease uses the
animal system.
It makes the the animal more likely to
bite.
Like it's like piloting the animal and
getting it to attack Zombie.
Yeah.
Have you ever seen the the rat with
rabies chasing the cat?
I mean think we've talked about stop
rabies.
The Rad has toxoplasma.
It's a different thing.
It's a different parasite.
Oh yeah.
That's the thing that's super common
with cats and rats and people get it.
And somewhere around 50 million
Americans have,
it affects your judgment,
uh,
makes you more impulsive in it.
Um,
there's a direct relationship to people
or toxoplasma infected and motorcycle
accidents.
Yeah.
They're more likely to get in motorcycle
accidents.
Robert Sapolsky talked about,
he was on a podcast.
We did.
It's one of my favorite ones,
but it was really quick.
It was only looking at it for us.
It was like an hour.
And so Paul ski is,
um,
just world renowned for his study of
toxo plasma and what it does to people,
but it affects the cats.
Um,
well first of all affects the rats.
sexual reward system hijacks his brain,
gives it a boner to get erect at the
smell of cat urine sometimes.
Wow.
And it takes away their fear of cats
completely.
So they go wander around cat.
The cats kill them and then they get
into the cat that way because they can
only reproduce inside the cat's
digestive system.
It's crazy.
So these worms get into the cat's body.
So they can reproduce and then they shit
out.
Catch it.
People come in contact with the cat
shit.
Sometimes even through their feet,
through walking around barefoot around
cat shit.
The toxo gets in their system and it
affects the way they behave.
Some crazy amount of people in the world
habit like at one point in time at
France it was more than 40% of the
people had it.
Yeah,
it's nuts.
Yeah.
That's what's doing it to that cat.
That was,
there's a lot of those things,
man.
How about that aquatic worm that makes
grasshoppers drown themselves,
grows inside a bug's body and then says,
hey faggot.
Once you go jump in that water,
I will jump in that water and they
jumped in the water and they drown.
It's crazy.
They talk this organism and it killing
itself so that they can pop out in the
water and live.
There's a bunch of things like that in
nature.
We,
you have to wonder like how,
how did this evolve?
Like what kind of,
what is what's going on?
Like what is the actual process that
allows something to evolve into a,
like a plant that can eat a rat.
You ever see that plant that gets her
all slippery and smells good?
So the rats come here and they fall into
the hole and it's into this like this
looks like a like a two lip,
like a giant thick two lip and it just
absorbs the rat.
Like how the fuck did that start?
And that's what it does all the time.
I get tricks,
the rats like what the fuck?
Like what,
what was stage one?
Like what was that thing like in the
beginning?
What did it like?
He did it a catch a bug and the bugs are
cool,
but let's get one of the furry fuckers.
It's always chewing on my leaves,
you know,
does just so many different forms of
life.
And this is all we know about earth.
Like we were talking about exploring the
ocean.
You imagine if we found some crazy
fucking half human looking things that
live on it.
And I think that,
I told you about this before,
but there's this plant,
it's on planet earth two,
so I'm not really going to show the
footage,
but it has these seedlings on this
specific island somewhere that these
birds come and land and they eat the
seeds,
and then they also,
if they get stuck to the bird's bodies
and as they fly around,
that's how it spreads.
But the birds can get them stuck to them
so much that it gets stuck on the ground
and they can't fly anymore and they end
up dying and then being decomposed and
the plants sort of like he throws out of
them.
Yeah.
They're covered in these things,
like the birds trying to clean the
things off him.
Yeah.
The birds eat them.
Oh look,
he's decomposing.
Yeah,
and the trees growing out of them.
Fuck,
that's crazy.
That's insane.
The planner to stuff is awesome.
Oh yeah.
Planet Earth and planet earth two are
both amazing.
Yeah.
I mean when you,
when you see the very bizarre ways that
nature figures out how to,
how to take advantage of a situation.
My favorite one is that cordyceps
mushroom that grows in those,
um,
those ants and the other ants recognize
that this is a problem,
that this thing died with these ants.
These ants died with these mushrooms
growing inside of it.
And the spores will build up inside this
thing's body and then explode and spray
through the air.
And in fact,
all the other ants around it,
like literally,
like,
it's like a bomb.
And somehow or another,
the ants know this.
So the ants take the body and they drag
it out of town.
They're like,
we gotta get 'em out of here before the
poor blows.
I mean,
it's literally like someone throws the
hangry and your car,
you just chuck it out just in time.
It's fucking nuts,
man.
I love shit like that.
It's fucking nuts.
Yeah,
it's fucking nuts.
I mean,
it really is.
How does it know?
I mean,
how these Goddamn ants know that they
have to get this thing out of there so
the thing's dead.
Right.
And then little spores start growing out
of its head.
See the spore grown out of its head.
This is crazy.
That's nuts.
Yeah.
So the mushrooms grow inside their
bodies,
and I don't know how the ants know this,
but the ants know they got to get that
fucking thing out of town.
Wow.
And they drag him away.
Maybe it's like a smell.
I mean,
I don't think answer cannibals,
but look how crazy that is.
This thing grows out of its body.
How is that any different than like
the promethium movie or alien movies?
You know?
I mean,
how was that different?
it's really not.
It's some crazy organism that eats its
host and the ants look mushrooms
mushroom is that thrive off of carbon
monoxide or some day they're just like
us.
They eat oxygen and breathe carbon
dioxide.
Now here's a thing,
the quarter Zips,
mushrooms that get harvested for things
like on it,
shroom tech,
the way they harvest those things is off
caterpillars.
Really?
Yes.
So the,
like this,
he said it to so that,
that,
that those mushrooms wouldn't be
psychedelic like it was in when he tried
to take those little ant mushrooms.
No,
they're not psychedelic become some of,
I mean there's a bunch of different
kinds of quarter subs mushroom,
but what they found is that high
altitude Yak herders or our cattle
herders think it was cattle.
I forget what it was.
They noticed that when their animals
were eating these mushrooms,
they were more active and so they
started feeding their mushrooms,
you know,
feeding the mushrooms to people and they
had some pretty great results with it
and they started noticing that it helps
people and they did some studies on it.
There's,
you can go to on it and you could read
the studies on cordyceps mushrooms or
just google it independently.
There's some interesting studies.
The Chinese,
see that's a little tricky though.
They say that Chinese Olympic team used
him and they want a bunch of metals.
Here's what's tricky about that.
It's entirely likely that they said,
oh yeah,
we were only using them mushrooms.
Definitely no steroids.
You know,
I mean,
in the interest of full disclosure,
you know,
we're in a fucking onnit tee shirt,
right,
right.
It's entirely possible.
They were doing steroids to most likely
that they were doing steroids.
Did you see [inaudible] and you see
they're moving?
I think they're all doing steroids.
I think like especially all those
communist countries that rely so heavily
on propaganda like Russia,
like Russia has been doing state.
They had a state sponsored drug program
100% it's all documented in that,
that Mo,
that movie.
So when China says that they want these
track and field metals because they were
taking this quarter steps mushroom,
I bet it helped,
but it helped.
I take it,
but guess what?
It doesn't feel like a steroid.
When I take shroom tech,
it's like a nice little boost.
They get a little boost,
just a little bit,
not speedy,
but a little boost.
I definitely feel an extra gear,
but it ain't like I'm not,
you know,
there's some else other shit too.
Those guys were doing,
they fucking do everything they can,
man.
Anything they can get away with whatever
the they can get away with.
They do and they're not testing them all
the time.
They're just not.
If there are,
they're hiding shit.
People get busted.
They've already proven that people get
busted and they let them slide.
You know,
there's a lot of influence peddling.
I mean,
maybe it would be less now because
Russia wasn't even allowed to compete
now that people had to compete under the
Olympic flag.
That certain athletes brush is so crazy.
You see that?
Do they killed in England?
The nerve gas?
Is he dead yet?
Does him and his daughter or something
like that or his wife?
The killed him in England with nerve
gas.
Really?
Well,
if he's not dead,
he might as well be dead.
He's on his way to dead.
He's incredibly horrible critical
condition.
It's just like,
this is some spy versus spy shit and
this is some really,
it's like some movie shit.
They're killing them with nerve gas.
They're killing,
you know,
he,
I think he was like a double agent or
something.
Is that what he was supposedly Russia's
now hacking our power grades.
Oh No.
Like I guess he didn't die.
Nathan.
If,
if it was a Russian military grade
agent,
he would have died on the spot,
obviously.
Is what Putin said.
Oh,
that's what Putin said.
Fuck cut.
We should definitely listen to him
always.
What is a remainer chronic critical
condition?
What did pull up a story on him?
Who is he and why?
Why are they trying to whack this dude,
he's in critical condition.
Well,
hold up.
Go Up.
Scroll up.
Putin calls Russian poisoned x by
nonsense and delirium.
Oh,
well then they definitely did it make
that bigger,
uh,
sloughed off the notion that Russia was
behind the poisoning former Russian spy
and his daughter saying any sensible
person would understand that this is
delirium and nonsense.
It is unthinkable that we would do such
a thing.
The first thing that came to mind,
if it was a military grade agent,
he would have died on the spot on.
They would have died on the spot.
Obviously said Putin speaking in the
party headquarters in Moscow shortly
after he spoke to a crowd and central
Moscow.
Russia does not have any such agents.
We destroyed it all.
Okay.
I don't believe that
it puts an asa says he's never met trump
before the election.
And then there's like video from like
three years ago,
trump saying guy,
I met Putin,
you know,
and like,
Oh really?
Yeah.
It's just like,
oh,
bullshit.
Everything's bullshit.
It's a fun time though.
I hate it.
I think this is a fun time.
You like this?
I'm okay.
I'm enjoying it because I think this is
what's fun about this time is,
um,
even with like in this is partly because
we have a guy like trump in office is
that everything seems like there's
nobody at the wheel.
Everything from top to bottom,
ms people scrambling and take the wheel.
I'll take the wheel and right the ship,
but there's no one at the wheel.
It's all craziness right now.
It's crazy.
And it's culturally,
it's craziness.
Politically.
It's craziness economically.
Like none of it makes any sense.
It's racially,
I mean,
people are fighting,
people are mad at Bruno Mars,
Bruno,
Bruno Mars or cultural appropriation.
How's that possible?
I mean,
there's so many different things that
are happening today that are so
outrageous.
Oh,
how about this one?
A guy got fucking,
uh,
sentenced or he got convicted and will
be sent in soon.
I think he gets sentenced in April for,
uh,
getting his dog to make a Hitler salute.
Making a video.
Yes.
It's on my,
uh,
my twitter page.
I retweeted it.
The guy is in Scotland and he's a proud
shit poster.
He's one of those guys,
Jamie loves ship posters.
It's one of his favorite things,
you know.
Um,
but he's one of those guys that just,
he posts stupid shit to get a reaction
from people.
And so just to piss his girlfriend off,
he decided he'd tried to get his dog to
do the Hitler salute,
the Nazi salute.
And uh,
you know,
he,
he gets his dog to do it on this video
and he says gas the Jews apparently,
you know,
like trying to like get his dog to do
this.
Like when he,
I guess,
you know,
he thought it was funny.
Then he puts it on youtube.
Not only does it get him in trouble,
which I get people being mad like,
hey,
that's insensitive.
Okay,
whatever.
It's what he's trying to be insensitive.
They fucking arrested him.
They tried him and they convicted him.
Which country?
Scotland.
The UK.
I mean,
this guy's convicted and now he'll be
sentenced.
Wow.
It's fucking crazy.
If you've seen the video [inaudible]
Jamie,
pull up that video because it's crazy to
watch.
It's not that big a deal thing has been
pushed off up until April time.
Yet next month.
Yeah,
that's what I said.
What is the pull up the video.
Yeah,
he's um,
that's one thing about United States,
man.
You forget about free speech.
Like I was talking to somebody from a
different country recently.
He goes,
you have no idea how big that is.
And we kind of take it for granted.
Giant.
Yeah.
It's giant and it's,
it's everything.
Okay.
It has been identified by Youtube
community is inappropriate and offensive
to some audiences.
I understand.
Please proceed.
Give me some volume.
And so I'll throw out,
I'll be calling them.
And Evie least cute thing that I could
think of.
Oh,
you can't even understand a word.
He says.
Why don't they just speak English?
God Gas the Jews,
the Jews were more gassy juice.
So you always asked the juice.
[inaudible] juice.
[inaudible] juice,
the juice,
the juice.
So He's,
it took them forever to teach this dog
this.
Is this the idea?
Yeah.
That's where we're watching this over
and over again.
Oh God,
Gosh.
Cio.
Oh Wow.
Boy,
he's adorable.
It is very cute.
He taught the to do that.
It's crazy,
man.
It sucks that he's getting,
well,
it's a classic shit post video.
Yeah.
It's like these guys.
This is the whole pepe,
the frog thing.
You can take it down.
This is the whole,
it's all the same shit.
It's a bunch of people that are having
fun sang shit.
That's totally inappropriate.
This is what it is.
That's what that is.
It's the same thing.
And the people that think that,
like anybody who would do that is a
Nazi.
You're not correct.
That's not true.
I guarantee you the guys not a Nazi,
I think.
I don't know.
I'm assuming he's not a Nazi.
I'm assuming he's a shit poster.
He's a guy who's trying to be funny.
I hundred percent.
That's just ignorance.
Yeah,
and that funniness is funny to them.
See,
here's the thing.
You might not like it.
You might think it's,
it's horribly and offensive,
but here's the thing.
No Jews got an ma got gassed during the
making of that video and the worst thing
it did is get racist to laugh.
The best thing it did is get people to
talk about what's appropriate.
There's nothing wrong with that.
I mean it's not good.
I mean I don't like it.
I wouldn't do it.
I wouldn't tell people,
hey this is the most awesome video ever.
Come watch it.
But to put that guy,
not only to put him on trial but the
fucking convict him and Scotland,
how dare you,
you people are supposed to be ahead of
the curve.
Skyland supposed to be a pretty fucking
bad ass place.
That's ridiculous.
Isn't Scotland though?
Like the like the like a place that you,
I think it's Scotland where you can't
even talk about sex on stage.
You can cuss,
you can like show you pull a tid out.
But like if you're talking to,
to talk about sex,
I think it's Scotland.
There's a noble cause.
Billy Connolly's from Scotland to Billy
Connolly's a pretty famous worldwide
comedian.
I think it sweet.
It's pretty outrageous guy.
I might be thinking to Sweden.
Yeah,
Co Cause Connolly's pretty,
he's,
he's like in the line of like popular
American standup comics of his era.
He was a very respected guy and he's
from Scotland.
It must be.
So I think I'm thinking of Sweden maybe.
I don't know.
I don't know Jack Shit about those other
countries that I only visit
occasionally.
Right.
But,
but when you go to,
when you go to these countries to do
comedy,
do you ever have to be like,
Hey,
don't talk about,
no,
I wouldn't go if I went to a place they
told me I couldn't talk about something,
I'd be like,
well why would I go there?
All right,
well I'll just go somewhere,
work and talk about anything.
I don't want to go somewhere where only
talk about certain things.
So like I,
I've done a few,
uh,
air quote clean shows in my day where I
got a Gig,
especially when I was first starting
out.
They're like,
Hey,
can you do a half an hour clean?
And I go,
okay.
Yeah.
And I would just edit.
I'll just edit the shit out of
something.
Use words that you know,
there's like Innuendo that you could get
away with and I could sort of squeak by
with a bullshit half hour set,
you know?
But I would never do that today.
Like I don't want to,
I don't want to,
it's just like what I want to be able to
do is find out what's the best way to
express the thoughts that are in my mind
that are funny.
Does the best way is never by censoring
yourself.
The best way is by figuring out what's
the best way to express yourself.
Sometimes censorship can be a tool
though for writing.
Like if you know that you can't swear or
you know,
like for joke writing,
one of the,
one of the cool things about twitter was
that you had 140 characters.
Now obviously you have more of to 80 but
the one 40 made you write a joke very
concisely.
If you want it to be funny,
you know,
you'd have to have set up punchline cut
out all that.
You're like,
Oh,
I'm 10 10 letters over shit.
And you back it up a little.
Oh just take this out.
And I could say in one word,
it makes you understand that the economy
of words better.
And sometimes that's the case with
writing too.
Like you can get out of a joke easy by
just adding swear words or adding sexual
innuendo or stuff like that.
But that doesn't,
but that,
that's like just an exercise.
Like when you're actually expressing
yourself,
when you're actually doing the work,
like going on stage,
doing a show,
you should be able to do whatever the
fuck you want.
Otherwise it's not stand up and it's
either funny or it's not funny.
I mean it's not funny.
You just weren't funny.
But it's not because it's the subject
matter that's just fucking stupid.
That's stupid.
Cause anything can be almost anything
can be funny.
And I'm sure there's probably a few
things that can't be,
but for the most part,
if you think it's funny,
if you have a point,
it's possible.
Did you see what happened with Hannibal
the other day?
Another thing.
Yeah.
He,
uh,
when he got a Gig at Loyola Chicago and
they cut his mic after he supposedly
said some stuff that they mutually
agreed he shouldn't say,
but what he put the email up on a
projector I guess and was making jokes
about the Catholic church.
Hannibal burress sex standup set is
interrupted at Layola after his sex
abuse joke
and it cut his mic and then everyone
started booing.
Everyone was laughing apparently.
And all the kids are saying,
I'm like,
they should have known what they were
getting themselves into basically.
Well,
you can't do colleges,
man.
I've been telling people you can't do
colleges.
It's not worth it.
It's a lot of money though.
That's the thing.
College is we'll pay you some serious
cash.
When I was coming up in the early days,
um,
I did one of those knacker conferences
and if you like National Association for
College Campus Activities,
I think it is.
And if you get booked by a bunch of
schools Tude it is amazing.
It's amazing.
You make thousands of dollars.
It was great.
Like I'm,
that was the first time I made good
money.
I would travel and go to all these
different weird like fucking Olivet
Michigan,
some university there and some weird
university in the middle of nowhere in
Ohio.
And they take you out to some local
fucking country bar afterwards.
You're doing shots with kids,
go to school there because I was
basically their age or a couple of years
older.
This is when I was like 23 or 24 may me,
you know,
and they were all like 20 so we're all
like in the same wheelhouse.
And then there people that work at the
school that were older,
they come out drink and when you two
different times fan,
but you could make real money like you
do a Gig and you'd make $1,000 or $1,500
or $2,000 like holy shit for one show is
crazy for an unknown comedian.
So everybody like aspired to do those
college gigs.
But back then man,
even back then they were real sensitive.
Kids are real sensitive and they're
always looking to,
they don't have a lot of life experience
right.
So their life experience is limited to
18 years.
Most of it's been under the care of
their parents for most kids.
And then all of a sudden they're at
school and they're flexing their wings
and their muscles and you know the,
the objective things and they've decided
that these things are inappropriate and
these things shouldn't be said.
And this isn't true.
They can't take certain,
they can't take a lot of sarcasm.
They don't know.
I mean they,
they,
they take you literally too often they
think some subjects or just period taboo
because they are period taboo in offices
and in some schools and there's some
things they can't say.
So if they can't say they don't want you
to say it,
it's a very weird time for kids.
You know?
That's why it's so crazy that you have
all these fucking dorks that are stuck
in that system,
that graduated from college,
then started teaching and have these
ridiculous Marxist ideas and loony
fucking left wing ideologies and they're
brainwashing these kids about gender
neutral or gender fluidity and making
safe spaces and all this stupid shit.
Like what what you're doing is,
is like further cushioning and coddling
them and then they're just what,
uh,
what are they gonna do?
They're gonna just gonna join academia
as well.
They're going to get through their
schooling and then teach in this weird
insulated little thought bubble that you
guys have created.
So when people look at these people
screaming and yelling and calling people
Nazis and on school campuses and all
this fucking chaos that's going on,
this is what happens.
This is what happens when you baby
people.
This is what happens when you,
you set up this environment where they
can never ever interface with the real
world.
They just exist in this super
hypersensitive,
hyper progressive bubble where nothing
is produced.
Nothing is created.
You just teaching people ideas and
you're teaching people ideas and the
ideas are being,
they're being promoted by a person who
in a lot of situations has never even
been out in the real world working like
there.
It's a bullshit fucking thing.
And then they have tenure so they can
never be fired.
Whew.
It's crazy.
Nerfing it's fascinating.
It's pretty fascinating.
No,
you know that this,
this,
these are these.
They're in a lot of ways it's kind of
like royalty and a lot of ways it's kind
of like,
like weird political systems that get
corrupt,
like things,
ideas get corrupt as much as like
finances get corrupt.
Like people feel a way to extract social
points for by promoting their ideas and
by,
by forcing their ideas down other
people's throats and having them accept
it and mimic that as well.
And also reinforce it that they're doing
their life right and everybody else is
doing their live wrong.
So it becomes this weird psychological
wrestling match that people are doing
with people.
You know,
in the outside world.
I mean,
I've,
I've had a lot of guests on to talk
about this subject,
but I think this subject,
it's one of the reasons why it rings
true to people is because I think we all
realize this is happening in just in
life in general,
and there's a lot of weird control
battles going on in life in general.
And in telling a guy that he can't have
his dog say,
see,
I can't say sieg heil his dog and his
dog lift his arm up,
telling you the guy that he can't do
that.
It's just stupid because you're,
you're making it a way bigger thing that
it should be.
It should be a stupid video that no one
cares about.
I mean,
it's still up on youtube.
So that shows you how stupid it is.
Yanked Shit left and right.
Like what?
You see what youtube did to a crowder
when Steven crowder went to this,
uh,
they went to a Lbgtq,
a event in Austin and he had a dude show
up and saying that he identifies as a
robot and he says all this really rude
shit.
Twitter,
it got him in trouble now.
Youtube,
youtube was youtube.
Still have it up.
I thought they put it up there.
I thought it was dee dee monetized or
twitter.
Bandom yeah,
but I thought Youtube bandom as well.
Facebook bandom no,
someone has to.
Someone else did too.
It might be youtube check.
Either way.
Um,
people are trying to control what people
do and don't say.
And I think when you do that,
you run into real problems.
Like who the fuck are you?
Who are you,
who you to decide,
you know,
and even know Noam Chomsky said
something about Sam Harrison,
Jordan Peterson that uh,
free speech does not impro does not
apply to hate speech.
Like why?
It's like,
yes it does.
Yes,
it does.
That's crazy that someone who's really
smart can say it doesn't.
Yeah.
Okay.
So it's available on Youtube.
Um,
he say he puts some posting saying that
he was blocked from something.
Doesn't matter.
The point is,
one thing that's been shown is that
they're trying to silence more.
They're trying to stop the spread of
conservative ideology and spread liberal
ideology.
Like they're actively trying to do that.
I feel like there's a real worry that
when you have a platform,
whether it's youtube or something like
that,
that you could get infected,
but like say shit posters,
if ship posters just,
they're more,
they're more prolific right there.
Like,
if you look,
just look at the comments on Youtube,
like in a lot of like really popular
things that comments are horrific,
like way disproportionate to how they
would be in the real world.
Like the comments and the p,
the anger that you find in a lot of
youtube videos,
especially if you look at like the
comments of podcasts.
Holy Shit Dude.
People are opinionated,
right?
They've got some crazy wild fucking
opinion.
Now,
if you were youtube,
you'd be like,
we have to figure out a way to stop
people from saying Faggot or we have to
figure out a way to stop people from
doing this or stop people from,
uh,
from being homophobic.
We have to figure out a way to stop
people from supporting trump.
people from talking about the wall.
You have to figure out a way and as soon
as you start doing that kind of stuff,
you run into a real slippery when you're
deciding what people shouldn't,
shouldn't be able to say,
even if it's legal.
That gets real weird because then you
don't have a free speech platform.
You have a left wing platform like your,
your platform has now left wing,
and I'm not saying you're wrong,
but I'm saying it,
it strengthens the position of the
people that you oppose because they are
being suppressed.
Like you could see there being
suppressed.
Even if they're wrong,
you put a guy in jail because his dog
says,
listen Paul,
when he says see high like boy you,
you just looked real fucking stupid to
most people and now the fight is on and
now it's going to be this swarm of
controversy where people are freaking,
I just found out about it yesterday.
I just found out about it last night I
think might not even,
it might might've been this morning when
I woke up.
Youtube has reported,
did you care about your kids?
Because what this famous conspiracy
theorists,
his videos have been coming up in the
youtube kids app teaching like flat
earth Type Shit and like we didn't get
it.
The planet or moon good stuff.
Yeah,
a good mood.
Getting into a lot of where they can,
Whoa,
this is too much.
Here's the thing about youtube,
now,
this is in defense of them,
because I'd talked though I had dinner
with some big wigs at Youtube and there
was some of the stuff they said was very
annoying and not recalling things,
hate speech that just weren't like,
I'm talking about someone who got a
community guideline strike because they
put a cup,
put a conversation up in their playlist
between Sam Harris and um,
Douglas Murray to intellectuals and
they,
they said that it was because it was
hate speech and I was like,
that is the fact.
They could just say,
that just drove me nuts.
But they're dealing with who knows how
many videos every day.
I mean,
it's insane.
How could they,
how could they possibly even know the
videos?
Okay.
The total number of people use Youtube
is,
what is that number?
Oh my God.
301 billion.
300 million,
300 hours of video uploaded to youtube
every minute.
Almost 5 billion videos are watched on
youtube every single day in an average
month,
eight out of 10 18 to 49 year olds watch
youtube.
One of the things this woman said to me
that I,
I agree with her on and I mean I believe
her because this is not about about
opinion,
is about the way youtube works.
She said,
right now we have very crude tools to
find the offensive hate speech.
They're very crude tools.
Sometimes the Mr Mark and sometimes when
you're dealing with like subtlety,
like humor,
like I could say,
hey you fuck.
And you know people go,
oh,
he was angry.
Like obviously not.
You hear the tone,
you know like someone saying that
they're saying it to friends and they're
joking around,
they're being silly and everybody's
laughing.
Youtube misses that.
They don't,
they don't know what's humor and what's
not.
So are you saying that you can never
make a joke about,
you know,
a guy's Dick or you can never make a
joke about a girl's vagina or you never
big joke about heterosexual sex,
can you?
No,
no,
you can do that.
Okay.
Can I make a joke about gay sex?
No.
No,
you can't.
Oh,
I see.
Because I'm not gay.
Okay.
Can I make a joke about why people,
yes.
Can you make a joke about black people?
No.
Oh,
okay.
What do we do in here?
What are we doing?
You're deciding what people can and
can't say.
And then they're also demonetizing
things.
And we've had some demonetize ones that
were just like,
okay,
there's gotta be some sort of an
algorithm going on here where there's a
word we say and that word triggers some
sort of a response and then they say
that it's up for,
we,
we have it up for manual review
sometimes,
but the,
our Douglas Murray one where we talked
about youtube demonetizing videos,
that one got demonetized he says,
so it's like,
okay,
are they doing that to fuck with us or
are they doing that because he douglas
talked about,
um,
radical fundamentalist Islam.
Like what is it?
And their defense,
it's just that their platform,
they should be able to do whatever they
want.
Should they though,
because what are they then?
If it's,
who is they?
Who is they?
The people they hired like doesn't that
shift?
Like the assumption is that everybody
who works in management,
everybody who works behind the scenes
all shares a mindset.
That's crazy.
That doesn't even make any sense.
That's not even the society like group
think tanks like that.
Like if,
if,
if they all agree,
and this was one of the things that
James Damore pointed out about Google,
it's like they don't leave any room
whatsoever for conservatives.
Like they absolutely discriminate
against conservatives.
I'm not conservative,
but if I was and I worked at a company
like Google,
yeah.
Imagine how fucking on the outside you
would feel like,
is it illegal to be conservative?
Like isn't there a responsible ethical
form of conservatism that's not racist?
Not Homophobic,
but,
but presumes that a conservative person
in power would be more fiscally
responsible,
will have economic policies that they
agree with interventionist policies they
agree with.
I don't,
I don't think that that's outside the
realm of possibility that a reasonable
person could be conservative.
But if you work for any big tech company
that's not in the menu,
you don't get to be that.
Like you don't get to promote that.
You don't get to agree with that.
It's weird.
It's not good because it's not,
it's not open speech.
You're supposed to be able to talk shit
through.
I'm a,
I like to listen to someone who has a
very strong opinion about something and
see if it resonates with me.
Now,
if you stop the stop,
that'll stifle that.
I was just going to demonetizing
monetizing a video though isn't,
uh,
censoring someone.
It's encouraging censorship.
This is why,
because you don't want to be demonetized
if you have a video in that video can
make you $500.
If it's,
um,
if it's up and it gets ads or it can
make you $0 million,
but that's,
that's a $500 incentive for you to not
talk about whatever the fuck got it.
Demonetized right.
But that's,
that then makes your argument,
I'm like,
what were you making the content for in
the first place?
Or you just make it doesn't to me.
No,
no,
no.
It's,
it's a motivation for you to censor your
speech,
whatever you're making it for in the
first place.
You presume that someone was just making
it to make it,
but there's an absolute monetary value
if they put ads on it.
So if they take away the monetary value
and they do it specifically because you
chose a certain subject that is in fact
a form of censorship there,
where they're doing is encouraging you
to self censor in order to make more
money.
They can say,
hey,
you can do whatever the fuck you want.
We're going to decide that if you talk
about fill in the blank,
that subject no money,
so don't talk about that subject
anymore.
They're not going to give you money
because they're sharing that money with
you though.
You could still share that video on your
twitter channel.
You could still share it on your blog
and still make money if you can find her
on advertisers.
There's just,
they see what you're doing.
I see what you're doing,
but it's not a good argument.
The reason why it's not a good argument
is because they made a concerted
decision.
They made a very clear decision to take
away the ads on videos where they don't
like what you're saying.
That just could be because they don't
have advertisers that are willing to pay
them.
That's all.
That's the way I would look at it that
I've advertised.
W didn't willing to pay that because of
like Douglas Murray and Sam Harris
talking.
They just couldn't,
maybe they couldn't find the money for
it and they're like,
I guess what?
This does not monetize.
Okay.
You don't know.
There's this weird making a guess
because you're doing this to try to
reinforce your original opinion.
I don't.
I don't think it is censorship.
It's a form of censorship.
I think that the monetizing is not a
good thing because of other ways,
other reasons that it happens.
I'm on youtube because they then have an
incentive to share monetize videos
because they're making money on them.
I get that,
but it's just because it's democratized.
Understand that you too,
who has a youtube has an incentive to
share monetize videos because they're
sharing in the profit of every single
video monetize video doesn't,
uh,
critters that get 100% of the money,
they get half of the money.
Right?
Youtube gets the other half.
So if a,
if a video is monetized as theirs,
they've been a fitness sharing them.
Right,
right,
right.
So that even reinforces more the idea
that they're censoring.
Yeah,
that's what I'm saying.
But like the third,
they're censoring the ability for it to
share it,
to be shared in the youtube platform,
not on the Internet.
That's true as a whole,
but they're not censoring what they're
doing is promoting self censorship by
giving you a fiscal reward for following
their line.
Again,
that's just where I'm saying like as a
creator,
if you're making content to just make
money on youtube,
then you have to play by their rules.
Yeah,
I understand what you're saying,
but what my point about this is,
is what they're doing is they're there,
they're making their own,
they're making these decisions.
And who is making these decisions that,
that,
that also could be definitely said they
should say these are the rules,
right?
I'm the person responsible for making
that statement.
What are the rules?
Here's they don't say,
they don't say this is what's weird
about it.
It's totally arbitrary.
There's no like written law that you
have to follow.
There's no like,
oh,
you can't say cunt.
Because if you say con,
you know playtex doesn't want to
advertise in your fucking video anymore,
right?
No,
there's not that.
It's weird that they don't tell you what
to do.
Monetize video is like when we get one,
they don't say it's because you guys
talked about about youtube.
No,
they don't say shit.
It's,
it's fucking weird,
man.
Never fucked with me in eight years.
Youtube fucks with me every day.
Right.
But the thing about
Vimeo is the difference in the numbers
is so radical.
Like,
if we have a video that gets a million
hits on Youtube,
it'll get 20,000 on vimeo.
Right?
Like I've been using vimeo live lately.
And you know,
if you have youtube liar,
you look at the chat room in Youtube,
90% just negative,
angry horseshit vimeo community.
Like I think we had like 400 people last
night watching killed Tony.
Everyone was positive,
just nice,
happy,
no negative trolling,
which is like a different popular yet.
Yeah,
but it was a different environment.
Guess that's why they don't get like
youtube,
they don't have things like ip bands.
They're like,
if you get banned on Youtube,
you just get a new gene,
Gmail address and now you have a new
fucking thing where like other places
like vimeo and stuff like that,
you get banned.
You're pretty much band band.
You know?
That's how it should be.
Right?
Right.
Damn fault.
Who should be deciding if you get
banned,
that's going to be an ip band that like
someone was at your house and now you're
banned from using youtube because
someone was over or a neighbor is using
your wifi and they fucked you.
It's also your responsibility to know
that.
I guess it'd be mb.
I mean that's like looking at Kiddie
porn.
Like go to your friend's house and look
at Kitty Porn.
You'd get arrested,
you know,
cause it's your ip address.
Or if you go over a friends house and
watch his Kiddie Porn,
did you get arrested?
If you do it in a car,
you're not supposed to watch it.
Right?
What are you like to listen to it?
That's a good question.
Yeah,
right.
No,
I bet you're not.
I mean,
but that's one of those things where we
decide that people shouldn't have that
in their life,
you know?
But here's the question.
What are they going to do when they have
CGI
that they can program to have very
realistic looking pedophile porn,
but there's no human being involved.
Then it was kind of like those dogs.
You saw those dollars as pd dolls,
pedophile dollars.
Do you,
what do you think about those?
Do you think there should be the sex
doll kid sect stalls?
I don't know about that.
Disney's latest research project can
turn scripts into virtual reality.
What does that something new that it's
definitely not out yet,
but they're just showed this that they
can turn
written scripts into very crude CGI
virtual reality experiences.
Holy Shit.
Yeah,
so this is just the early version of it.
This might take off if they decide to
continue to push money into it and
figure it out.
Get deciphered by the commuter computer,
which creates images.
I believe so.
I was trying to read it to understand
it.
That's sort of what they're saying.
That's sweet.
That's so crazy.
That's a,
but that's inevitable.
This is probably going to be like the
upper level CGI,
like you're going to be able to write
it.
Then you're going to be able to talk
into it and it's going to create things.
You're going to have a fucking headset
on and you're going to be in a room and
you're going to say,
I want to be in the Avatar world and
ride a dragon and I want to be blue and
I want to have a bow and Arrow and I
want to go to the tree of life.
And all that shit is going to be right
in front of you.
Yeah.
They're going to just to be able to do
it with virtual reality based on your
suggestions and then they're gonna
figure out a way to get your brain to
interface with that thing.
Whereas they've already figured out a
way to get a kid to move his car.
Someone was paralyzed and they got this
person to move their cursor.
I don't know if it was a kid.
Um,
they've,
they've had a bunch of different things
where they've used the mind to control
things.
I did a thing on Joe Rogan questions,
everything where I put this headset on
and I got,
um,
uh,
a,
a drone to listen to me.
I could get it to lift up off the ground
if I thought a certain way and that shit
is coming.
It's already out.
Yeah.
But I mean that shit in like in your
mind,
be able to conceive a whole different
world.
Right.
Did you see a,
an isolation?
No.
It's trippy.
It's that.
That's the new movie from the
[inaudible] a guy.
Oh yeah.
Fuck,
that's good.
Okay.
Trippy.
I see that trippy to the point where you
go,
what am we're watching here?
So this,
I think I showed you this once before,
but this is a good video of it.
This is a eye tracking thing that's
built into laptops.
It's built in an alienware laptops now.
Whoa.
This guy's just looking at those dots
and they're exploding.
He's,
Oh,
so he just eyes his eyes just mice.
Oh my God.
And it works really well.
That's crazy.
Yeah.
So your eyes control the mouse.
Yeah,
you can play games with it.
Oh my God.
Justice eyes.
No Way.
That'd be amazing for your eyes.
That seems like an awesome I exercise,
but it's a,
it's not there yet though.
Very,
very new.
And it's already out and they just like
announced the new vibe pro.
Or if you try to play quake on this,
they're gonna fuck you up.
Try to use your shitty eyes and some
dude's holding a mouse.
It's very close to having this like with
either in your phone so you can just
control games on your phone or put that
in a little Ar Vr headset.
I can't say I'm shocked.
Ready player one this Friday.
Is that,
that the book?
Have you read ready player one?
It's about the future.
Uh,
it's new Spielberg movie that comes out
I think Friday.
Uh,
about,
oh,
I've seen the ads for that bad.
Yeah.
That looks crazy in here.
Ooh,
this will describe the whole future.
You keep bringing up and like everyone
lives in a pod locking into
the vr.
It's going to happen.
This is Columbus,
Ohio Dude.
How many people do you run into that are
just not doing good?
They're not living a good life.
Like everything's not going so well.
Like,
I was just in Fresno the other day and
um,
uh,
when we were drought,
Tony and I did a gig up there and when
we're driving around the town,
there's streets filled with homeless
people,
homeless,
like encampments everywhere.
I mean there's,
there's people that just are in a bad
place and they can't,
it's not going to get any better where
they live.
If someone comes along and introduces
something and it's just like a cell
phone,
everybody has it.
And you all lock into that thing.
Yeah.
Columbus,
Ohio to 20,
45 is that we did it.
This is what it's like homeless people,
all the streets put this headset on and
in the world.
Yeah.
The real cool thing I think about the
movie,
which is the plot,
which isn't giveaway much cause I
haven't read the book.
So I don't know.
It sounds like something that could
happen soon is that there's like a bug
in the game and there's a prize for it
that everyone's going after the bug
price ever confined.
It gets on like Willy Wonka style.
Yeah.
You could do the thing.
And what's really interesting is that
the movie also has,
cause you pick an Avatar just like a
video game or facebook.
So people are picking like I went to be
King Kong kongs in,
in like back to the future cars in it,
in the cure is motorcycles in it and you
know the iron giant Senate and oh Freddy
Krueger's in it.
It's just,
you know,
so they,
they've,
they got to use a lot of different
franchise.
There's a speed racer car back to the
future.
Yeah.
I mean it's,
this is,
this is all inevitable.
I mean if they're going to continue the
same path that they're on now,
if you go back and look at the video
games that we used to see when we were
kids,
like can you play mortal Kombat on a
console?
It was kind of cool.
But the,
compared to this,
it's like Pong,
right?
And it's going to happen.
It's just going to keep going.
It's just a matter of where,
where it's going to leave us.
Like what are,
we're not going to be people anymore
real soon.
Cause in a hundred years we're not going
to be people anymore.
We're going to be some weird new thing.
Do you think we'll be here?
I don't think so.
We'll be dead.
Um,
but like that thing that's on the bottom
of the ocean that they found that
dinosaur thing,
we're going to be like one of those
things like,
oh Jesus,
like that thing like it's crazy because
we know that they used to exist.
Right?
So if we find one today,
like wow,
nuts.
I think still here that's going to be
like people,
they find some dude who's living in the
mountains outside of Colorado is like
he'd catch his own fish.
He's 116 years old and they finally
like,
look at this guy.
He's got no electronics and it's all
body.
Do you think it'd be like Amish people
would still ask her that for instance,
or would be,
would that be them?
We'd kill those.
Eat them.
They would have to kill him.
The robot people would have to kill the
moms.
We can't have him around.
They would,
they would think they would say,
well are there like wildlife?
They like wildlife after a certain point
because if we all started out as some
sort of pro hominid back in the early
days of evolution,
right?
We started as some sort of primitive
primate and that eventually evolved to
be what we are now,
but there's still chimps around there
still monkeys around.
There's still a lot of primitive
primates like did they evolve at a later
date?
Did they start later than us to dislike
that they get a different car call time
to the race,
like what happened or did some things
stay the same while other things change
and it's just the rate of change seem so
spectacularly quick,
but it's only because of our
perspective,
but really there could be groups of
people and might be the amish that stay
exactly the same and then the new beings
treat them like colobus monkeys in the
jungle or leg.
Some fucking weird giraffe that you see
when you go on a safari.
Look,
look,
look.
The people that make their own butter,
they're real,
and we'd wave at him,
hello,
I love your wagon.
I mean,
they could become wildlife.
They can become a very primitive form of
wildlife.
They could become like uncontacted
tribes in the Amazon where we just leave
them alone.
We think they're novel.
Look,
look,
they're painted all read their whole
body.
They have a bow and arrow that they made
themselves.
This is amazing.
We get all excited about it,
but it's the same exact shit,
same exact shit to us like then when the
new things take over,
they just keep the amish.
They keep tribes,
people,
they keep the weird shit that's not
going to fuck with them.
Anything that doesn't know how to work
electricity,
all those people that are out there
living without electricity.
You know like those Alaska,
the last frontier shows,
those people would have to all plead for
their life and would be like,
look,
I'm just here homogenous over just
taking care of cattle and I'm not
planning on getting any weapons and we
are.
We like a simple life and we're happy
for our robot overlords.
Congratulations on your victory and just
leave this up here.
Ha Ha,
fuck that.
Right
when I was getting my eyes looked at,
the doctor said that how people's eyes
are a lot worse nowadays and we number.
When you're a kid,
your mom was like,
don't sit so close to your team,
the the TV.
But now we're putting goggles in her
eyes like one inch from our eye.
What's the,
why are we doing that?
Like what?
Why does no one talked about ihealth?
You know,
cause it seems like if my optician or
whatever she's called is telling me
about like how do you should get these
blue blocker things now you're,
everyone's eyes are so stressed
nowadays.
I think that's true.
I think guys are definitely stress,
but it's also that we're getting old.
Yeah.
When you get old your eyes,
you go to shit.
Everybody's always has except like my
friend Cameron Hanes,
he's 50 his fucking eyes are like 2018
or something.
It's crazy.
Like I had a crack on my iphone.
I dropped my iphone and I looked at it.
I'm like,
ah,
I think it's all right.
He goes,
no,
you got to crack.
I go,
really?
He goes,
where?
He goes right in the lower right hand
corner.
I'm like,
motherfucker.
how'd you even see that?
He could see it from my hand,
like my hand over here and he's here.
He's like fucking five feet away from
me.
You can see it.
I got this fucker inches from my face.
I can't see it.
I mean it's been three years since I,
my eyes checked and I used to always be
perfect.
This was the first time where that
bottom row,
I was like,
it's an eight or a zero.
Is that an eight or does he wrong?
You get a menu in a restaurant.
You're like,
okay,
I'm going to have to start a fire and I
see this.
I'm going to have to bust out a little
wider.
Like a fucking concert.
Yeah,
or use the,
the gets super obnoxious if you use your
phone,
that light on your phone or there's a
magnifying app on the phone now it's
like zooms in a little seat.
Dark.
My,
my low light sensitivities way
different.
I'm just,
I think it's probably because my,
my brain is overwhelmed by brightness
too much.
You know,
like staring at a computer screen.
That's one of the things that I like
about that right room app.
I'm going to sneeze.
Unfortunately.
That right room APP gives you a dark
black screen with green lighting,
green writing.
I guess it's a sweat.
These glasses do they block the blue
light?
It's kind of like night mode on your Mac
or,
or your phone where it turns yellow.
Oh,
okay.
But that supposedly way better on your
eyes.
I'm sure it's better,
but we're still falling.
Hameroff fucked.
We're going down.
It's going down.
They're gonna replace her eyes with a
lots of can't wait.
Oh,
that's these drops.
Yeah,
they have seen some news.
New eyedrops they think they're gonna be
able to put in your eye and you never
have to wear glasses again.
What do they do though?
Is it a genetic thing?
Nanoparticles.
So fucking Christ,
that's how they're going to get in to
getting in through your eyes.
So how's it explained how it works prior
to drop them in every couple of weeks or
every week or maybe even every day.
It's not for sure yet,
but it's not even out yet.
Obviously you there?
That's crazy.
And just very new.
It works though.
That's crazy.
Three step process performing the
smartphone or the measurement of the
eyes.
Your fraction.
Okay.
Wow.
And you'll just be able to drop it in
there.
Apply to the eye for less than one
second a laser though.
So then doctors create a very specific
laser pattern which is applied to the
eye for less than one second.
The laser creates tiny grooves in the
surface of the cornea.
Lastly,
special eyedrops or applied.
Whoa.
Like a good idea.
So they get a measurement of your IRA
fraction,
which can then be performed with a smart
phone.
Wow.
That can be performed with the
smartphone.
The first part.
And the doctors create the laser pattern
and then they,
they fucking storm trooper your eyeball,
drop some chemicals on there and the
chemicals get in through the holes that
you've made in your eyeball.
What chicken?
The right.
How amazing is that?
What does that works?
I mean I've been,
I think that's going to happen with that
hearing will probably be get something
for that soon too because what if it's
one of those,
uh,
artificial hip things like artificial
hip is like,
it does work.
But I was like,
I'm always like,
man,
I feel like they're going to figure out
a better way right now.
Like five years.
Like how long can you hang in there?
I feel like there it's so close to
regenerating tissue re,
re the regenerating all sorts of um,
cartilage and people and in certain
people that have had like a,
I know women had bladder cancer,
they regenerated and an entire,
um,
a bladder for her made out of skin
tissue.
They did this all with stem cells and
Mel Gibson's dad and that dude was,
uh,
his dad was 92 and he was like on the
door and it got shot up with stem cells
and now he's not even a wheelchair
anymore.
Yeah,
the whole story,
it was like what?
Like his hip was bothering him so bad.
He was in a wheelchair,
goes,
gets shot up with stem cells.
And then all of a sudden he's walking
around.
Yeah,
yeah.
This and this is like without being able
to be fully explored in the United
States like this is they have to go to
Panama to do this.
They're really weren't that guy.
Dr Neil Riordan is working to try to
bring it to Texas and if anybody would
be like,
we don't give a fuck,
let's do it.
It would be Texas,
you know,
because this is all adult stem cells.
There's no issues with like fetal stem
cells.
So w religious people wouldn't get
involved in it and there's a lot of
folks that have like some serious
fucking injuries.
This shit could really help.
Hell yeah.
Even I heard that you could do things
for the mouth now.
Like teeth re Greek row a my gums and
teeth and you can pretty much do
anything now.
I believe this Tim's house,
I think this is only one step.
I think when,
you know,
we're thinking back like 2030 years ago,
you never heard about this shit and now
you're hearing about it.
Like what?
How much better is it going to be in
2030 years from now?
I mean,
how much of it it's going to be
nanoparticles mixed with stem cells and
they just fucking regenerate your whole
body.
You know,
I think that's what's going to happen.
I think people are going to be able to
not just regenerate limbs,
but I think they're going to be able to
regrow your Bot.
Like refresh your body,
like whatever your old bullshit ass
cells that you have in your body,
they're going to figure out where the
memories are actually stored.
That's going to be,
that's going to be a trip if we find out
that memories are not just in your head,
but also in your body.
So like what if we completely redo the
body but keep the brain and you don't
remember shit.
If your brain,
your brain is just a conduit for these
memories that are stored in your soul
and you've kind of replaced yourself
with some fake Zombie body with Nano
bots and the brain didn't remember shit.
Our shadows memories,
that doesn't make any sense.
They do think that,
um,
the people have,
uh,
neurons in their heart that they might,
that this idea of like following your
heart and thinking with your heart
apparently is more neurons in the heart
and there on the brain.
It's a true and gut and gut.
The heart and gut than there are on the
brain.
Nice.
And my stomach was smarter than my head,
not brain cells.
I don't think that,
well that's no just neurons.
But that makes sense,
right?
Trust your gut like that.
You always heard that says trust your
heart.
40,000 neurons in the heart.
Whoa.
How many is in the brain?
Trust your heart.
Trust your gut.
Trust your mind.
Your mind is the only thing that
controls your perspective.
Weird feeling about this.
Well that's the thing about eating
healthy food.
That's a big thing is that you're,
you're changing the gut bacteria,
which literally changes who you are.
You have to think about it that way.
Like it changes the person you are
because the person you are,
it's all those things have to be in
order.
Your head has to be in order.
You know,
you have to like have the right amount
of certain healthy bacteria in your
system.
Otherwise it doesn't.
It doesn't,
it's not even you anymore.
It's just some crazy takeover of 10 DDA.
It's quite,
according to the article,
I just found about 40,000 and the heart,
100 million in the stomach.
Wow.
Whoa.
100 billion in your brain.
Why Lillian?
Oh,
well that's wrong.
Whoever said that,
it is more in the heart.
That's so wrong.
Boy.
Glad I googled that one.
It says it's in both.
It's in the heart and stomach.
Just not,
there's not more.
What did I fucking,
how did I read that then?
How could someone be that off that I
read it or it was just my memory is that
bad.
I'm going to go with my memory.
Whatever it is.
Um,
imagine that those memories in that
heart remain in the heart and you
transfer your heart into somebody else's
body.
Like that's what happens when people get
heart transplants and certain people
have said that they have certain weird
cravings and they think about things you
know,
that they never thought about before.
It's like you might be literally
interfacing with someone else's
memories,
imagined it in someone else's memories
in your body.
Like people that kick kidney
transplants.
How'd you get some memories along with
that and you're like,
what is this is a dream,
this is a dream or do I remember some
shit I did when I was five but it wasn't
me that Donald Donnie like think about
your memories of being five.
How fleeting,
how,
how like barely visible.
How like in the darkest,
darkest,
darkest corner of what you could
possibly describe as a real memory in
terms of like being able to describe all
the everything around you that this is
like almost nothing.
They're almost nothing there.
Not to give that to somebody else.
Give that to somebody else and they have
that shit just bouncing around their
head and like,
am I crazy to really think this?
Is this a dream or it's the fucking
kidney,
I believe in that shit.
Somebody else's DNA mixing with your
ors?
Well,
I think it's because of the heart thing
because it has neurons.
Yeah.
I mean they don't know,
right where memories are stored.
Do they,
do they know that for sure.
The question would be
every cell in your body reproduces
right.
Every cell in your body changes.
And over the course of seven to eight
years,
you essentially don't have any of the
same cells in your body except your
neurons.
Is that a urban legend or is that 100%
real light?
I think that's 100% real.
I think your body's cells change over.
Yeah.
I've always heard that the neurons do
not,
you have the same neurons forever
apparently.
Yeah.
Which is,
um,
one of the more interesting things about
some of those neuroprotectant plants and
then,
um,
some certain funguses like what does it
lion's mane that promotes neuro
neurological health.
Yeah.
There's certain,
there's certain mushrooms that actually
are really good for your brain's
development.
It's really fascinating.
Hmm.
But,
um,
what's up?
I was just looking around.
They're all,
every part of your body.
It grows at different rates,
but it over the course of eight years is
that they said that.
Yeah.
I mean,
that's every eight years the whole
thing's changed over.
It's like you're a new person every
eight years.
Yeah,
but except your neurons,
your neurons are where the memories are
stored.
That would kind of make sense.
But I think my theory,
and I'm a fucking,
I'm no scientist,
but my theory is that memories that you
have are really just memories of how you
remember your memories that all of our
memories are like,
this is weird.
Whispery stories,
you know,
it's like a copy.
Okay.
Yeah.
Like I,
I just,
there's certain things that I've done in
my life where I'll look back and I'm
like,
I don't even really think that was me.
You know,
like the martial arts stuff particular,
I do not think that's me.
I think that that definitely wasn't me.
Yeah.
Or like even when I watch myself on news
radio,
I'm like,
that isn't even me.
I go watch like a youtube video on my
car,
doesn't even me.
I coat.
That's weird that,
that this is captured and for most
people,
most of their life right up until like
the last hundred or so years,
that was never an option.
It was never an option to go back and
look at yourself from 10 years ago or 20
years ago or 30 years ago.
But now it's super common place.
How much has that affected who people
are because you become so much more self
aware.
Right.
Remember that bit that I was doing last
year about like,
um,
I was doing my last netflix special
about the selfie.
I like somehow along the line people
change the way they pose it pictures.
It does.
You look at the first pictures.
People just stood there and looked
hungry.
I call holds pictures from the 18
hundreds.
They just look skinny and gaunt and
hungry.
And if you saw a picture from like 1860
and there was a girl with her butt out
and she's doing duck lips,
feel like that pitch is a time traveler.
There's no way.
There's no way she could have been
there.
Like there's no way someone at that time
new to pout,
make kissy face and do the peace sign
and stick your ass out.
Just that's a pose.
That's um,
a modern pose.
And it came about because of being
extremely self conscious because so many
people,
I
see images of themselves every,
I mean,
did he charge you Magii the grown
Jumanji they're really pretty.
Girl was obsessed with taking photos of
herself.
That's fucking really shit,
man.
Yeah,
so kids do right away.
One of the best movies,
surprisingly best movies I've seen in a
long time.
Fucking movie.
What a great take on it.
Yes,
I loved it.
Oh,
there's this cat time traveler.
Funny.
Is he a but yeah,
but that's how they lived back then.
He's probably drunk cause like,
well I've got to do shit like this.
Okay.
Yeah.
That's how they look.
They look hungry,
man.
I just sticking it to the,
to her or him.
She's the one of them,
right?
Looks like that one actor that's in all
those.
Imagine being in a small cabin.
Go back up.
Please.
Imagine being in a small cabin with that
dude.
Just playing that stupid guitar and
singing these horrible songs was rotten.
Shit.
Breath.
They didn't even,
they didn't even know what the fuck a
toothbrush was.
Right.
Your teeth just fell out of your fucking
head.
Like everybody else,
that guide below the box here,
it looks like it's not even like he's
trying to like be tough.
He's like,
I'm just doing a defense that's going to
lead away.
She,
I'm not even coming at Ya.
I'm coming at you with Dick First.
That's what they would do.
They would come at your Dick First.
Wow.
This thing looked like he knows how to
fight at all.
Well look away.
They would hold their hands up to,
they held their hands very differently.
But um,
those fights were very different fights
because they had real small gloves.
You couldn't get hit as much.
You couldn't hit each other as much
either.
Like you couldn't just like modern
boxing,
we just flowed with punches and got
crazy with punches.
You couldn't do that.
You'd break your hands.
You had to be much more judicious with
where you hit people and they clinched a
lot.
Those old school boxes,
they would grab each other and wrestle
each other a lot and punch each other.
In the clinch,
there was a,
there was a lot more of that.
And there is now it's different world so
I guess they just cause it in heaven
like tiny gloves or no gloves.
They just decided they're going to try
to lean away from the punches more and
just kind of jab at each other with
knuckles.
You can't just wait in like um,
I mean you could if you were Mike Tyson,
but they just didn't,
they didn't know how to do it right back
then either.
Like even if you watch,
you go,
like if you watch modern boxing,
like you watch like Canelo Alvarez
versus Gennady Golovkin and you see like
the two,
two of the highest level guys in the
game go at each other.
It looks so much different than watching
like old school boxing.
Like old school boxing was like you had
sugar ray Robinson.
It was could have fought and been the
world champion today and then a bunch of
guys that he beat the shit out of.
And then you have a bunch of guys that
have like one kind of style and there's
inconsistencies in the greatness.
Like some of them look like,
like Marvin Hagler could have been a
world champion today.
And then other ones you go back like way
far back and you go,
hmm,
this guy's got like this weird fucking
style.
Like a wonder if the style is just
derived because of the little gloves and
they just didn't know as much about
boxing.
Then like,
watch,
go watch it like an old jim jefferies
fight.
And then imagine what Lennox Lewis would
do to him.
You know,
like there's,
there's levels that guy's got to where
they were just,
they were on
another level,
like clearly who's that referee,
that boxing referee that it's been like
in a video lately on twitter that is
like the funniest shit.
I don't remember his name,
but I know what you're talking about.
Like loves his job and he's just in the
background.
You're like smiling.
Yeah,
it's hilarious.
I forget his name.
Uh,
this was a great video though.
Expressions are fucking hilarious.
Yeah.
Dudes get popped and he goes,
oh dude,
do boxing referee's ever go to the UFC
or this guy,
his name was Steve,
Steve Willis.
He will accept playlists.
I'll fix your,
I don't know why it's not playing.
Oh,
I usually just reload and that the whole
video is still video.
Oh,
it's a still video.
that's probably what it is.
Uh,
he's a hilarious guy.
He gets very excited.
Yeah.
But these are good.
A good referee.
He's great.
And not just enthusiastic.
I mean,
that's a good thing to do to give a guy
a real clear eight count.
Oh,
got the best expressions.
Oh Shit.
Terrence Crawford,
terrence Crawford.
Beat your ass and then talk shit after
you get stopped.
You know,
terrence Crawford is one of the best
pound for pound fighters in the world.
Brian,
better learn.
I started to go beat yourself.
Learned.
What is that?
Oh,
connor talkers up open bed already and
make May.
Whether applying for MMA law license
wants six to eight months to train.
He's screwed.
This is a,
in my opinion,
this is a 40% proposition,
which means it's 40% likely that he
might actually do this.
The reason why he might do this is
because I think they will give him in on
godly som of money.
I mean an ungodly sum and I think they
should.
I think that if the UFC can talk,
floyd mayweather into going into an mma
ring,
first of all,
they should give him everything they can
get their greasy pause on to get them to
fight.
Conor and MMA fight.
Just say,
look,
we can give you cm punk will give you cm
punk for half of them.
Half a bill I half a billion.
It was a lot of money but you can go
through that in five years instead.
How about we give you conor mcgregor for
a full billy and we'll give you six to
eight months to practice Jiu Jitsu.
Six six to eight months to just figure
out how you're going to get fucked up.
You'd be screwed.
He wouldn't just be screwed.
That's like,
that's unfair to like for people that
have been screwed.
You would need a way more way more
outrageous example.
It's not just getting screwed what he's,
he would like someone said it should be
a thousand to one that's not high
enough.
It's not high enough.
If conor mcgregor was going to fight
floyd mayweather in mma,
it is as close to 100%
as anything ever gets ever.
Cause if you think floyd is all of a
sudden going to become this
fucking one punch destroyer like John
the bees Mugabi in the 1980s or wherever
the fuck that was,
if you think that's going to happen out
of nowhere,
you're crazy.
That's not what's going to happen.
What's going to happen is he's probably
gonna Punch Connor in the face a couple
of times.
It's probably going to suck,
but Khan is going to get ahold of him
and then he's going to be like a baby.
And if that doesn't happen,
he'll kick floyd's legs out from under
him.
He'll kick his legs sideways,
he'll kick them from the outside,
will kick them from the inside.
He'll stay way the fuck away from any
sort of arrange where floyd can punch
him.
It'll be a completely alien range for
floyd.
And every time floyd goes in front kick
to the stomach,
boom,
front kick to the stomach,
front kick to the stomach.
How many of those can you take?
Okay,
boom.
Inside leg kick.
Boehm outside leg kick.
He's laughing at you now.
Now he's talking Shit and you realize
you've got to get past those legs.
You could try to close the distance.
Boom,
spinning back,
kick to the liver.
Fuck.
What are you going to do now?
What are you gonna do now?
You're going to be picked apart until he
decides to take you to the ground and
cut your face open with elbows.
How about that?
How about he pins your right arm down
with his left Shin,
gets on top of you and just start
smashing the edge of the elbow into your
eye sockets,
into your nose,
cuts across your forehead slices you
opened like a fucking melon.
You don't have a chance.
No one has a chance that hasn't had a
long history of grappling and getting
kicked.
It's like you're a regular boxer is like
especially the best ever like floyd.
It's phenomenal at what he does,
but if you put takedowns and kicks into
that,
it changes.
Everything,
changes everything.
He'd be fucked.
I wonder if he's done any training at
all.
Well,
I know these talk to Tyron Woodley and
Tyron Woodley was a apparently willing
to help him prepare.
That would be very interesting because
Willie's had some issues with connor.
I don't think he's going to fight conor
though.
I think if he does choose to fight mma,
I really believe the move is the correct
move is you fight someone like cm punk.
Cause with cm you got a guy who's,
he's been training in mma for a long
time now.
It's been a few years,
not a long time,
but a few years now.
He had one mma fight in the UFC but was
very overmatched it.
We really wasn't fair like for him.
Didn't make it that kid.
I mean it's just the difference between
the two of them.
You know,
Micky Gall is a real professional elite
fighter.
I mean he can beat really good guys and
he's just not in that world.
Like cm pucks,
a 40 year old guy who is a professional
entertainer who is basically a beginner.
Right.
But he knows enough where you would,
we would bet money on him.
He knows enough where you're like,
imagine if cm punk who is a big guy,
he cuts down to one 70 and compare it to
floyd floyd's fight it like,
I think he fought it started this
career.
I want to say one 31 35 we'll go to
floyd mayweather's beginning fights,
see what,
but at the very least he's definitely
fought at one 45 as a grown man.
He's fought at one 55
cm punk,
way bigger.
He's just a way bigger guy.
So if he could figure out a way to get
to fight to the ground and like lock in
something simple like a guillotine,
if he has a good Ghia teen,
that's what I would say.
If I was going to work with a guy like
that,
I would say you're going to come,
we're going to concentrate on one
fucking choke and we're going to get
that thing down to like laser beam.
Perfect precision.
So just if you just spent all your time
doing like one Marcello Garcia style
choke,
just figured out one good show,
one where you know that if you get that
Chin down,
you tuck it in and slap it on one choke,
whatever it is that you know how to
close that fucker up 90% of the time on
people that know how to defend.
There's a lot of guys that have that
like maybe they'd have a triangle or
maybe they have a head in our head and
arm choke is a good one.
That's a good one to master.
Some guy just finished most people with
like that one choke if he just had that
and just got fully to the ground and
just got his neck.
It's super super possible that he could
win like it's possible that he could win
but it's also possible the floyd can
win.
That's what makes that interesting cause
floyd is still one of the best boxers of
all time if not the best,
still a fucking elite athlete.
Still light speed in the,
in there,
like with his footwork and his movement,
his head movement,
he's so fast,
he's going to be way faster and cm punk.
So if cm punk can't get ahold of them,
and every time he moves in,
he gets his face lit up with a dude
who's fast as fuck with six ounce
gloves.
Now he's got four ounce gloves on,
very little padding and he's catching
you right on the chin and you can't do
shit about it.
You're trying to close the distance and
he stutter,
step in and move it in front of you and
cm punk is not like the best kicker in
the world.
I'll buy it,
I'll buy it.
Okay.
But he'll have to fight me.
Whether if he comes to mma that would,
you mean you'd have to fight,
um,
or uh,
connor connor?
No.
No,
you wouldn't.
You don't think so.
He'd get killed.
He would literally get killed.
I know,
but that he would get smashed.
She ends up doing it my may.
You know,
everyone wants to see that though.
That's what everybody wants to see.
For sure.
Rhonda and him fight.
That would be a good one.
Yeah.
Um,
I don't think he's going to do it.
I don't think he's gonna Fight Mcgregor
ever and mma,
but I think you might fight cm punk.
I believe that.
I believe that could happen.
I know they're not even,
that's not even like official talk,
but I really believe that can happen.
It sounds crazy.
I know,
but the whole thing sounds crazy.
It sounds crazy to think that he could
fight anybody in mma that he would be
willing to do it.
He must know something
because he could just go into boxing.
He must know that he's his time as a
boxer.
It's just done.
Who Cares?
You have enough money to do what you
want to do,
dude,
you don't understand.
You don't ball that way.
You know ball like you balls.
He's balling on a level that neither of
us could ever understand how much money
you have to spend.
Just fly everywhere in private chats and
have limos everywhere you go and have
five bentleys and six Ferrari's and all
the shit.
That guy has so much money it takes to
maintain that lifestyle.
And then he's got a strip club and he's
got a giant mansion.
He's got a bunch of people working for
him all the time and he spends on
everything.
That dude buys half million dollar
watches.
He's just always buying shit.
He buys the most ridiculous shit and
puts it on his instagram
and gamble's like crazy,
crazy gambling like bet $1 million on a
fucking basketball game.
Yo,
I dunno,
I don't pay attention dude.
I got shit to do.
Believe that the money team time piece,
Oh shit.
Look at that tmt Hubo time pieces.
We'll only appreciate and value.
Go to your nearest tube load boutique
and shop right now for my limited
edition shoe below Hashtag [inaudible]
Hashtag tmt the money team.
Go back to that again.
Please look at that fucking watch man
with a diamonds in that bitch.
Ooh,
if you want to let bitches know that you
got some real shitty taste in jewelry
and a lot of disposable income,
look at that thing that's pretty
actually ethnic.
That's better than the other one.
But the whole tmt thing,
who the fuck's buying that?
Who's going to buy another man's like
braggadocious logo?
I see on a watch.
Not on a watch,
but I,
I when you go to sporting events I
suppose whereas a tee shirt,
maybe I get that big fan of what the
guy's done.
You see the selfie he posted,
I said Nice Romantic,
beautiful,
handsome man.
Kind of hashtags are saying on their
early morning sophie or early morning
selfie.
All right.
Thank you.
Glad you did.
Hey look man,
he's a silly fella,
but he's also the greatest boxer of all
time.
He's also unbelievably physically
talented isolation or uh,
so that's uh,
cryo.
Yeah.
He's got,
he's got to learn about the one where
your whole head gives under.
Yeah.
Is that better?
That they'll feel better?
Yeah,
it's way better.
Okay.
We'll see.
Seen enough money,
team jewelry,
but he's got millions of dollars and
just jewelry to,
it's very interesting,
man.
It's very interesting because what he is
is like a,
he's the most like braggy showy,
like a rich,
rich type guy.
And because of that,
people go to see him fight,
hoping he's going to lose,
and he always wins.
It's genius way to make yourself
exciting because he has a really smart
boxing style.
I like his style is extremely defensive.
Like he's one of the best defensive
boxers,
if not the best of all time.
It's very hard to hit.
So when he's boxing and he's like hardly
ever getting hit and winning decisions,
like there's gotta be a
way to get people to keep coming to
these fights.
And this is the way everybody like
rooting against you have ever.
But look at all this money.
You ain't got shit.
Look at all my money.
Look at this car.
Look at this house.
Ooh.
It's kind of funny.
Brian Red Band Peters out at about an
hour and two hours and 40 minutes and
that's about all you got.
Now
it's everybody.
Everybody gets tired.
Except Kurt Metzger.
We had Kurt Metzger on yesterday.
He had 150 red bulls.
He had 16 different caveman coffee
nitros how many did he have while we
were here?
He had at least two.
I think he,
yeah,
he walked in and drink and one,
I think he had two more early on and a
half.
At least.
He had three total and a poor.
Oh and Benjamin got talked over.
So go to huge penis.com and check out
owens a new special that he released.
He shot it,
filled it himself and released it on his
website,
which is huge pianist because he's huge.
I just forget how big he is.
He said when he came in here and gave me
a hug yesterday,
I was like a little kid.
I'm dick hide on him.
He's six,
seven.
He's almost a foot taller than me.
That's crazy.
He's a giant human in a big barrel.
Fucking,
and then I think he's gotten bigger
since he's moved to the woods.
Oh yeah.
Cause he's been upstate New York.
I feel like he's grown.
It just seems like he's like fitting
into the environment.
You know,
this is a thing that animals do in the
colder,
uh,
the colder parts of their reach or
their,
where they are,
where they roam.
Um,
they get larger.
So like if an animal in the range,
that's the word I was looking for.
Like if an animal has a winter range or
an animal has like a like say like white
tail deer,
like a whitetail deer in Florida is real
tiny thing.
We only have a hundred pounds.
You go to a whitetail deer in
Saskatchewan,
they were like 300 pounds.
They're huge.
They're giant ass fucking deer.
And that's like as big as a white tail
deer gets.
And they di they look massive.
They're just a different animal.
It's because when the colder climates,
they have to have more body mass to stay
warm.
That's why polar bears are the biggest
fucking bears called polar bears.
And then Kodiak Grizzlies I think are
also,
they're pretty close.
But the Kodiak Brown bears,
it's just because there's salmon
everywhere.
They're just feasting these fucking
monsters.
Do your feet grow the older you got?
Because when I've gone up like from like
10 to like now,
almost 12 he takes can't vary too.
Maybe.
So it's Dick Pills and it was idea.
That's a good move to,
um,
I think that,
uh,
what you're carrying around a lot of
weight,
you know,
you think about what you weigh and how
many times your feet are walking around,
I would imagine.
But you didn't your,
you're just in a am I did a half size,
half size.
I used to be a 10 and a half and then
somewhere around 30 ish.
My Shit was like getting cramped in a 10
and a half.
Then I moved to an 11.
Yeah.
Although I have found recently that 10
and a half fits better for me in those
five finger shoes for whatever reason.
I
think I had one.
I think one of them might just getting
stretched out a little bit.
They just get,
I beat the fuck out of those things.
You know,
I'm taking those things on these serious
hills and they get stretched out.
You're working out now,
what are you doing?
Uh,
30 to 40 minutes of Cardio and then
about 20 minutes of weights.
But I just did this new step cardio
thing by mistake the other day and
killed me.
Like the ones where you're kind of
climbing up stairs while doing,
they looked at movie.
Yeah.
Yeah,
I've seen that one.
you're not that.
I did it for like 35 minutes,
which is normal,
but man,
it broke me like I'm in so much pain
right now.
Yeah,
your muscles get sore,
but that's good.
That means you're doing something that's
difficult.
Yeah,
no.
Well just saying Janet,
one Albert's doing today.
Birds dead.
Walking around.
Yeah,
he's hurting.
He was saying that he's super sore.
Wow.
I mean he's,
yeah,
he's a silly boy,
but hey,
that was great that he did that.
It's good that he did and he really
didn't.
I mean it didn't like specifically
prepare for it where he's doing like
half marathons all the time.
You just got over being sick for two
weeks.
Just went to a cryo place.
Looks like for some help
out of control.
Oh,
he,
so he went to crowd healthcare now an
probably 20 minutes ago.
Oh,
okay.
Which one?
That looks like,
I don't know.
Which one that is.
There's a few of those places now.
Do you think that is a fad or do you
think this is going to,
you know,
Bert?
No crap.
No,
no.
There's real benefits.
If it feels good,
it feels really good when you get out
like your,
your body feels good and it's because of
your brain produces really strong
chemicals when you were in there because
it's,
you know,
it's going,
Holy Shit.
We're dying.
The producers,
cold shock proteins,
what they call them and uh,
and it also produces a nor epinephrin,
which is like a version of adrenaline
that's,
or as a cousin of adrenaline.
Isn't that how they described it?
Yeah.
Epinephrin is adrenaline.
Joey Diaz just did it the other day.
This is about the kind of air
conditioning I want in my house.
Ah.
We would go into his hotel room when we
would go on the road with Joey and we'd
open up the door and be like,
Jesus Christ fucking penguins or waddled
around inside of his room,
50 degrees,
whatever.
That when there was a slider and you can
get over to the blue,
that shit would be pegged like at the
coldest it could possibly get that thing
never shut off.
Yeah,
no it does in room ones that would kick
on the real loud and you're like,
no spray on you daughter.
The worst is when they go on and off
intermittently in the night and wake you
up in the middle of the night.
When we were at the Detroit fillmore,
they were talking about how men used to
come in there during,
you know,
like whatever the fuck year it was when
they invented this,
um,
where they built this amazing theater in
Detroit,
but it was the,
one of the first places in town,
they've got air conditioning.
So people would buy a ticket just to
come in and sleep because it was so hot
in the summertime.
And then they'd go there and they'd be
like,
ah.
He would just sit there
snore at,
that's how I,
like,
my gym has 24 hour fitness.
Do you have fucking homeless people will
live in their showers there.
That's what people do,
right?
If they want to live out of their car,
they get a 24 hour fitness membership.
So I like going late at night.
Like sometimes we'll go like at one in
the morning and then you just like,
why is there so many people here?
Oh,
all these people are homeless or to
sleep.
Yeah.
Where do you sleep if you're homeless?
Car Cars.
I have a car,
but that's not,
that's,
let's see,
I just think there's homeless and then
there's,
I've got a car homeless.
Hey.
It's like Damn,
look,
guy's a pimp.
And I was like,
that's the next level
video that's out right now about this
guy who was an ultra marathon runner.
He's 76 years old.
See if you could find,
I found it on dig.
It's called the most elusive man in
North America.
And this dude has a school bus that he
lives in.
He parked the school bus in the woods
and he just runs every day and they're
all like looking for this guy.
I want to say he's like 78 years old.
Does it say
76 76 years old.
He's 76 years old and he runs ultra
marathons and this guy lives in the
forest.
You got to go way till they find them
these,
they had to go and seek this guy out and
do these interviews with him.
There he is right there.
And so all he does is drink beer and run
and eat food.
And I think he lives by himself and he
lives in this tiny little thing.
And but what's fascinating is when you
talk to him,
when you sit and listen to the guy talk,
you'd go,
oh well this is a very intelligent man
and he just finds what he likes.
What he likes to do is create trails.
So he makes his own trails in the woods.
He knocks over sticks and move stuff
aside and,
and creates a path so that he could use
it over and over again and,
and just runs all the time.
It's just constantly pushing himself.
But he's talking about challenging
himself in the things that he does.
And why does it mean he doesn't need
anything more than this bus to live in
and he's just,
he's not.
See the thing is,
you would see someone like that and you
dismiss them and you'd go,
well,
that guy is a fool,
but he's not a fool.
And you listen to him talk and you go,
okay,
so this is his philosophy behind this.
These got,
he's really thought this out to the
point where he's become very comfortable
just living in this bus in the middle of
the forest and he looks good for a guy
who's 76 who runs hundreds of miles.
I mean,
he looks sexy.
Santa.
Yeah,
he doesn't look like,
you know,
he's going to enter in any bodybuilding
competitions,
but he looks like a guy who's got
vitality.
You know,
he's got,
he's got energy
like a creepy old dude.
He's got a lot of time down on with that
skin.
Oh Matt,
Sun damage did this guy never even heard
of sunscreen.
He's just run out there with no shirt
on.
He's out here with no shirt on.
Just running.
He's,
yeah,
it
looks mountain nourished while he's
definitely not eating a lot.
Like,
I mean,
where's he getting his food?
I don't know where he's getting money
from.
I don't,
I don't know how he does this.
Yeah.
I'm not really sure what he does for
funds or if,
you know,
it tries to live off the land and what's
going on unless he just park a bus in
there and just hang out.
Live to good question.
I mean there might be places where you
can,
you have permanent parking.
Oh,
he's got a watch.
It's not a cheap watch.
Yeah,
he hasn't slide that,
watch it.
No.
How much is that?
Watched those gps watch this like five,
600 bucks.
Oh really?
Yeah.
So it was like one of them Garmin's
yeah,
that's still look like.
So he creates these paths that he runs,
so he runs,
he'll break a path down,
like create a trail and then run it over
and over and over again.
Okay.
Which is kind of interesting,
right?
Cause he's like following his own
footprints.
He's got Oakley's on,
but he doesn't have a Sun Tan Sun
Lotion.
Right.
He doesn't give a fuck about skin
cancer.
He tells skin cancer to suck his dick.
Look at him.
He's like,
you can they make leather cancer in
Canada?
That's where all the had all those flags
or DDM?
British Columbia.
Yeah.
Someone,
the mountains of Vernon,
British Columbia lives a 76 year old man
by the name of Dag Abi.
How do you say that?
Abi Dag Abby,
his no cell phone or email address
revered by locals for having escaped
from the shackles of modern society.
He's the champion of the 80 mile ultra
marathon,
aptly named the death race.
Abby is the oldest person to have ever
finished the race.
Okay,
very fascinating man.
But these,
here's the thing,
the guy seems content.
How many 76 year olds do you run into
that are depressed,
that don't seem content,
that don't seem to have any vitality?
I mean,
we have to accept what life is going to
give all of us.
And it's a fucking an end where your
body's failing.
And you and I are starting to see that
now with our shit vision.
You know,
I see it now with um,
my,
uh,
my ability to recover from injuries like
special,
especially this tendonitis of have this
tendonitis in my elbow.
It's really shocking because I never had
like real tendonitis before.
I didn't know how long it takes.
I figured out it's like a pulled muscle.
Give it a couple of months,
we'll be all right.
No,
no.
A couple months later I still feel that
fucking thing.
I've done a lot of shit to it.
To stem cells.
PRP,
Regena keen.
It's getting better,
but shit is not quick to heal.
It takes forever and you gotta be real
delicate with it.
I have that with my hands.
Also.
If I get out of shape now I get out of
shape.
It takes way longer to get back into
Takes like double the time.
Like um,
when I did that,
a hot yoga challenge,
I hardly ever ran.
I didn't do any and I lost like a big
step.
It took me a solid two weeks to get back
to our was before doing yoga.
We're going,
it's going down just like that old man
living in the forest,
but he's got it right.
He knows it's going down.
He's leaving behind nothing.
Jeremiah walking.
It's just lost all of the way that he
gained during that.
Wait,
it took them three months to lose it.
We should make Tony get fat.
We should force feed them.
We feed them that you just can't get
fat.
He's one of those guys.
I mean,
I think his whole life he's been had
that problem where he can eat as much as
you want.
He will never get fat.
That's not true.
And he will definitely get fat,
especially if each sugar.
But Tony eats pretty healthy.
He doesn't eat a lot of sugar.
It doesn't fuck around with anything
stupid.
And he'll,
he'll occasionally put like sugar in his
coffee or something like that,
but he's got a pretty good diet.
You know?
I just think that he's just,
you know,
it's,
that contest was bullshit.
Bullshit,
bullshit.
He wasn't really trying to gain weight.
He was like trying to let Jeremiah when
look at that,
how it was before and now after he lost
it all good for him.
It's not easy to lose weight.
Brian,
I'll tell you,
you deal,
you lost 70 at one point.
Well now it's,
you know,
I'm so happy with the relationship.
Me and my girlfriend cooks so nice.
It's,
it's,
it's more of me just going,
hey,
wait,
there's a new quarter pounder.
I know.
It's hard and a quarter pounder though.
Whoa.
Is it that good?
Yeah.
They're using good about it.
They're doing what Wendy's has always
done.
They're using real meat.
You know,
just go to Wendy frozen.
Yeah,
but it's heavy burger.
Like I was like,
Whoa,
this is not like a bitch ass
quarterpounder anymore.
This is,
it feels different.
It feels heavier.
That's like probably got more and more
moisture.
Yeah.
Well you know those places like in and
out and five guys,
they're always going to be a step ahead,
but you can't just pull in and grab one.
Think about Wendy's is,
you can pull in and grab one.
Like it's like boom,
boom,
boom.
It takes two minutes and all of a sudden
you've got a cheeseburger.
Shake shack.
If you've got to shake shack yet.
Yeah,
I've been to shake shack.
It's okay.
Shut the fuck up.
There's no way a compares to,
to black in and out.
Oh my goodness.
Oh yeah.
You think so.
Tainted has a water burger guy.
He thinks waterbirds it better.
But definitely shake shack is posted as
the Chili with the spaghetti.
No shaking steak and shake states.
Ohio does fucked up.
I fucked up.
Pardon me?
Shake shack and wasn't even thinking
about doing shake.
I'm thinking to steak and shake,
which also has cheeseburgers.
Right.
You were saying those little thin
patties that are like right.
I thought you were saying those words.
Good.
Okay.
My bad.
I fucked up.
I,
yeah,
shake shack.
I like way better than,
and I,
I'm not a fan of in and out.
I'm a five guys fan.
I love five guys.
If I'm going to go off the rails and
cheat,
I'm going to get a,
uh,
a double cheeseburger with Bacon and
Jalapenos.
Woo.
We sell it.
Call it to their burger is a double
burger by default.
By default.
If you want a single,
you've got to order it now to find out
the fries though.
I mean,
a lot of people love their fries,
know if they're fried boring
ass fries,
fool shit.
You got to get them spicy Cajun ones.
Yeah,
I got that.
You like to all of them and I'm like,
that's good.
It's just tech rally fries.
It's just I don't like too much
seasoning.
Those are actually supposed to be pretty
good.
That's not food.
That might as well be a stationary store
to me when I pass by I'm like,
Oh,
I'm not eating anything in there.
Yeah,
Mcdonald's fries all day though.
I'm not a McDonald's fries fan.
I'm an in and out guys fry's fan.
I'm habit burger.
Mcdonald's fries.
I think that it's,
in my world it's five guys and in and
out or basically neck and neck.
I bet if I didn't live around so many in
and outs,
I would prefer in and out more than I
do,
but I'm only around like a couple of
five guys or five guys has some novelty,
but five guys also has Jalapenos.
There's a lot of good.
I like about five guys said either fries
I like better.
You don't like Wendy's as much as,
as much as in and out?
No.
No chance.
Not as good.
If I were to take 10 burgers here in
blindfold,
you know,
I would know.
What's the difference you'd be able to,
if you just got it from a regular store,
you remember?
I used to do a joke about actors being a
lot like cheeseburgers cause he never
looked like their pictures,
especially actresses.
Um,
but you never get a cheeseburger from
Wendy's that doesn't look like it's been
stuffed into one of those fucking foil
things and press down pickles on the
side so it makes it fresh every time.
Oh you're tricky.
Pickles on the side.
Tricky boy.
You sure they don't open that bitch up
and just take some pickles out there so
fast that Wendy's somehow that's a hack.
It's a hack the pickles on the side of
hack by writing their fats because
they're never frozen.
Jamie.
They're good.
I think they're good.
I mean I like Wendy's,
don't get me wrong,
but I just don't think they can ever
fuck with it.
Doesn't taste as good.
It's like five guys or they don't really
cook it right when you ask.
Yeah.
Like when you asked for it,
if five guys,
they go,
what do you want?
Okay.
And he see the guy take the patties,
put it on the grill and start cooking
it.
That's just a different experience.
Yeah.
I mean Burgers at Burger for the most
part,
but I just don't get the in and out shit
at all.
You know what the best is that nobody,
nobody respects anymore.
Fuddruckers oh,
we used to go to flood again.
Ostrich burgers.
Holy Shit.
I went last week,
man.
It's still good and they have to Nacho
cheese too.
They get scored that she's done.
Why does fuddruckers not get more love?
I think there's that many of them
around.
They need to expand.
Burberry.
Eddie Bravo and I used to go to 24 hour
fitness and I'm,
what the fuck is that one in?
Not duty on the way to encino in that
area.
What does that,
what was that called?
Sherman oaks and the Sherman Oaks
Galleria.
That's where it is 25 we'd go to eat
there we go lift weights and then we go
and eat at a fuddruckers and get ostrich
burgers.
Dude,
they're phenomenal.
It's an ostrich is you do not feel bad
for ostriches.
They,
I had an ostrich peck me in the fucking
head.
Once they're,
they're ruthless little cunt.
What's Oscar's tastes like?
I don't think I've ever had issues.
It's a red meat,
which is weird.
Huh?
Ostrich is a red meat.
Like it looks like buffalo or something.
It's a dark red meat.
It's really good.
It's supposed to be really high in
nutrients to and ostrich eggs as well.
Ostrich eggs like this fucking big too.
They're huge.
We made people eat him on fear factor.
They had to eat a whole egg.
They didn't drink a whole raw.
Probably terrible for you.
Right.
Let's wrap this up.
Uh,
next Tuesday I'll be on Brian's show.
That's at the Improv in Hollywood.
It's at eight o'clock,
eight o'clock on Tuesday night.
Then I'll be at Sam triply show with a
store right afterwards.
I'm fucking crazy.
I'm total it up.
And uh,
when,
when did your neck shows?
Do you have a,
you do an ice house on Friday doing a
holly's house Friday,
but also me and Tony are going on the
road with kill Tony.
We're going to be in Phoenix next week,
April 5th and then Nashville Comedy
Festival for 20.
Oh Shit.
Abbott,
where a lot of dates on the road though.
I'll be in the ice house as well,
Brent next door.
So we'll be broke both working together.
Oh,
Friday night and Saturday.
I'm there this week.
Nice.
All right.
You fucked.
So death squad.
Dot TV for hats.
Tee shirts on our stuff for dates,
everything.
All right folks.
We'll be back tomorrow with a MMA
pioneer.
Pat Miletich.
Very excited.
Very excited to talk to Pat.
That should be fun.
And then a vinny shoreman and Liam
Harrison going to come on Thursday.
When I say that guy.
What's that?
Oh,
the mosaic guy who gave him a shout out
already on Instagram,
but um,
what is,
uh,
we got this dope mosaic.
What does his name is Ted months.
mosaic.com or m?
U.
N.
T.
Z.
Yeah.
Or Munz.
M.
U.
N.
Z.
Munz.
Amazing.
It's on my instagram.
Dude.
Made an awesome mural.
A cool mosaic mural of the logo.
All right,
thanks everybody.
Bye Bye.