Hello Freak bitches.
So you now have taken some time off from
fighting because of concussions.
Right.
And tell me about that.
So yeah,
it was actually,
I think you were at my last fight.
It was a,
I fought mark the bond,
you know,
rest in peace.
I remember we talked about the,
yeah,
what happened to us?
Did they find out what happened to him?
I didn't know.
A lot of this stuff is coming out is in
Dutch and Dutch newspapers.
And I'm asking all of the Dutch
community kind of what's happening and
they don't really know.
You hear different things and rumors,
but I don't want to listen to rumors.
I don't want to hear it from like a
concrete source.
And we went missing and then they found
his body.
Then they basically found his body.
Yeah.
So why or who knows?
But he was a great,
Carrie wrote,
he was amazing.
Excellent,
excellent fighter,
you know?
And uh,
he was another guy.
But boy,
you know,
you look at him,
he looked like a computer programmer.
Yeah.
You know what I mean?
It's a,
it's interesting how it looks.
Can Be so deceiving.
It's super,
super high level guy.
Yeah.
But that was my last fight.
And um,
from there was actually a really tough,
I never really opened up about it to be
honest with you.
And it was,
uh,
a very tough experience.
Um,
you know,
you've got to think,
I just win the world title and I'm going
home to Canada,
which my concussion was pretty bad where
I shouldn't have even gone on a plane
home.
And next thing you know,
I'm at home and just the concussion
concussions got really bad.
I had to be hospitalized for a few days
and uh,
I was in a dark room for three weeks.
Man,
I could not get out of a dark room for
three weeks.
I couldn't walk.
Um,
I guess something with a concussion and
started causing some neurons,
but I'm nervous,
you know,
nerve damage.
That could be me.
Yeah.
So it can cause some nerve damage.
I have X.
I was like in a bed,
man.
Couldn't even look out.
I had a little red light on my phone
charger was too much.
Really?
It was bad,
man in red light on the phone charger
would hurt your head.
I couldn't even look at a thing.
So it was at that point,
it was like,
man,
it's like I just win this world title.
And it was a really tough time.
And this is actually the first time I've
really opened up about it,
but it was a tough experience and it
being in that,
you know,
downstate where you're basically in a
dark room for three weeks.
Um,
doctors were just,
you know,
handy me over shit ton of percosets and
oxies to kind of deal with the pain.
And it was,
uh,
it was,
it was a tough time,
man.
And it really,
I think what was the hardest was what
was happening mentally.
I'm sitting there and being like,
man,
I just want a world.
I don't want to get back in there.
I want to,
you know,
do so much in this sport.
And my goal was to be a legend in the
sport,
but,
you know,
and then it got to the point I saw my
family and how much it was affecting my
family.
And that's when I decided that,
you know what,
let's put this,
uh,
unrest for a little bit.
So you win the fight and after the fight
is over,
was it immediately that you knew
something was wrong?
It honestly,
I had some adrenaline rush and I did the
post fight press conference.
Everything was fine.
I was just,
when I got back to the hotel room and I
was throwing up and couldn't leave my
room and I was surprised that even got
on an airplane home,
the doctors in Canada or like,
how the heck did you get on an airplane
home?
So it was scary times,
man.
And it took a lot of good mental
strength,
uh,
to get out of it.
And now I'm actually in a,
in a position where I'm super happy and
I'm loving it.
I got that whole color commentary role
with Gloria,
which has been incredible.
But you know,
the Pr,
I think the problem was that saturated
fat was demonized.
Well,
it was demonized in a very corrupt way,
which is the,
the,
the recent New York Times article that
was released,
which was a mindblower,
which detailed how the sugar industry
had bribed scientists to release data,
blaming saturated fat for heart disease
and obesity and all these issues when it
was in fact sugar that was causing all
that.
So they were literally rigging the
system and paying scientists and it was
a horrible article because that
propaganda and these lies that they
spread.
I believe it was in the 50s.
Here it is,
how the sugar industry shifted the blame
to fat.
And it's if you get a chance and you
want to feel sick at what can be done
with money,
watch or read that because it's just,
it's awful.
It is really awful.
And um,
it was an internal sugar industry
document that was discovered by a
researcher at the University of
California in San Francisco and it was
published,
it said Monday when this was out,
I believe it was a couple of months ago.
Um,
but it was amazing.
It suggested that five decades of
research into the role of nutrition in
heart disease,
including many of today's dietary
recommendations may have been largely
shaped by the sugar industry and
propaganda and money.
They spent money to literally bribe
scientists to release false data.
It's horrible.
It's really nasty,
but I mean the thing is not that much
money either.
Here's a cold,
go back to it.
Here.
They paid three Harvard scientists,
the equivalent of $50,000 in today's
dollars to publish in 1967 review of
research on sugar,
fat,
and heart disease.
The studies using the review were
handpicked by the Sugar Group and the
article which is published in the
prestigious new New England Journal of
medicine,
minimize the link between sugar and
heart health and cast aspirations on the
role of saturated fat.
Even though the influence peddling
revealed and documents dates back to
nearly 50 years.
More recent reports show that the food
industry has continued to influence
nutrition science.
You know,
I'm obviously a big,
easy target for a guy who works the door
here.
He's going to destroy me,
you know,
like of course how the mighty will fall,
but I still think it would be fun
anyway.
What does it feel like knowing that you
roasted the president of the United
States,
you rose to trump is it is totally,
totally a weird feeling.
And I saw him a couple of weeks ago.
I saw him down in Florida and exchanged
pleasantries and I'll let you take your
kid and you were just talking about that
on stage.
I saw him,
uh,
in Palm Beach and uh,
his golf course.
You're doing it as golf course.
Having lunch.
I always stand your life.
Jeff Ross is,
is like nobody else's.
I follow him on fucking instagram and
like,
Hey,
every night he's in a different city
with a different set of cool people.
Well,
when you're a successful man,
you don't have children.
I'm not married.
You can do whatever the fuck you want.
Jesus.
What a life.
Yeah,
you really do have a good life in that
regard.
You're free as a bird.
It is cool.
How the fuck have you managed to not get
tied down?
I'm ready to get tied down and you're
ready.
I wish I'd say they say that.
Who could?
Who could do that are around us?
That's not true.
I would like to settle down.
Really?
Yeah.
I haven't met the right person.
Hmm.
Well,
how come you haven't met the right
person?
You're in a new city every night.
You fuck constantly travel.
Maybe.
Yeah.
Maybe I'm looking in the wrong way.
Do you think you came close a couple
times?
Do you think you'll have a little jeff
someday?
I really hope so.
Yeah.
50 yeah.
That's all right.
Why?
Because your as bad.
I really think so.
If it tasted,
it's probably better sound.
No,
freak me out.
Don't freak me out.
You already told me that Bruce Lee video
wasn't where he thought.
The Bruce Lee video.
Bruce Lee playing ping pong with
nunchucks.
He thought that was rude.
How are you serious?
They're round.
No checks are brown and blue.
Fuck is back.
Good time it you'd have to time like the
ping pong.
It's not like a paddle.
This like a rigid thing where you can
kind of hit it.
You get the time to swing it a thing?
Well,
he was definitely a bad ass,
no doubt about it,
Huh?
Yeah.